<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 22:16:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with European External Action Service Secretary General Sannino</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-european-external-action-service-secretary-general-sannino-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 22:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=326795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Wendy Sherman spoke today with European External Action Service Secretary General Stefano Sannino to continue close U.S.-EU coordination to support Ukraine and hold the Russian Federation accountable for Putin’s unprovoked war and unconscionable attacks that continue to kill civilians in Ukraine. They also affirmed their continued commitment to strengthen the U.S.-EU partnership and work together to confront global challenges.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Wendy Sherman spoke today with European External Action Service Secretary General Stefano Sannino to continue close U.S.-EU coordination to support Ukraine and hold the Russian Federation accountable for Putin’s unprovoked war and unconscionable attacks that continue to kill civilians in Ukraine. They also affirmed their continued commitment to strengthen the U.S.-EU partnership and work together to confront global challenges.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Government Support for the Eastern Tropical Pacific Marine Corridor</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-government-support-for-the-eastern-tropical-pacific-marine-corridor/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 21:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=326747</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On March 22, the Governments of Colombia, Costa Rica, Ecuador, Panama, and the United States of America held a high-level dialogue on the Eastern Tropical Pacific Marine Corridor (CMAR) in San José, Costa Rica. During the dialogue, Under Secretary Jose W. Fernandez and Assistant Secretary Monica P. Medina announced U.S. government support for the CMAR. The U.S. Government will work with the governments of the four CMAR countries to identify opportunities for U.S. engagement.</p>
<p>The CMAR, announced by the Presidents of Colombia, Costa Rica, Ecuador, and Panama at COP26, is an initiative to link several existing marine protected areas and create an uninterrupted, sustainably managed biological corridor spanning more than 500,000 square kilometers. The CMAR initiative comprises a world-renowned ecosystem and will connect the Cocos, Coiba, Galápagos, Gorgona, and Malpelo Islands in a marine biosphere reserve.</p>
<p>The CMAR initiative will contribute to the goal of conserving 30 percent of the global ocean by 2030; preserve migratory routes for sea turtles, whales, sharks, and rays; address ocean ecosystem degradation, overfishing, and illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing; enhance conservation of the marine habitat; and help protect marine biodiversity from the impacts of climate change.</p>
<p>For additional information, please see the Fact Sheet on U.S. Government Activities in the Eastern Tropical Pacific Seascape and the <a href="https://www.state.gov/opening-remarks-at-the-high-level-dialogue-on-the-eastern-tropical-pacific-marine-corridor/">Opening Remarks from Under Secretary Jose W. Fernandez and Assistant Secretary Monica P. Medina</a>.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact OES-PA-DG@state.gov.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On March 22, the Governments of Colombia, Costa Rica, Ecuador, Panama, and the United States of America held a high-level dialogue on the Eastern Tropical Pacific Marine Corridor (CMAR) in San José, Costa Rica. During the dialogue, Under Secretary Jose W. Fernandez and Assistant Secretary Monica P. Medina announced U.S. government support for the CMAR. The U.S. Government will work with the governments of the four CMAR countries to identify opportunities for U.S. engagement.</p>
<p>The CMAR, announced by the Presidents of Colombia, Costa Rica, Ecuador, and Panama at COP26, is an initiative to link several existing marine protected areas and create an uninterrupted, sustainably managed biological corridor spanning more than 500,000 square kilometers. The CMAR initiative comprises a world-renowned ecosystem and will connect the Cocos, Coiba, Galápagos, Gorgona, and Malpelo Islands in a marine biosphere reserve.</p>
<p>The CMAR initiative will contribute to the goal of conserving 30 percent of the global ocean by 2030; preserve migratory routes for sea turtles, whales, sharks, and rays; address ocean ecosystem degradation, overfishing, and illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing; enhance conservation of the marine habitat; and help protect marine biodiversity from the impacts of climate change.</p>
<p>For additional information, please see the Fact Sheet on U.S. Government Activities in the Eastern Tropical Pacific Seascape and the <a href="https://www.state.gov/opening-remarks-at-the-high-level-dialogue-on-the-eastern-tropical-pacific-marine-corridor/">Opening Remarks from Under Secretary Jose W. Fernandez and Assistant Secretary Monica P. Medina</a>.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact OES-PA-DG@state.gov.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Government Activities in the Eastern Tropical Pacific Seascape</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-government-activities-in-the-eastern-tropical-pacific-seascape/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 21:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=326746</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>At a high-level dialogue on March 22 in San José, Costa Rica, Under Secretary Jose W. Fernandez and Assistant Secretary Monica P. Medina announced U.S. government support for the Eastern Tropical Pacific Marine Corridor.</p>
<p>Key U.S. government activities in the Eastern Tropical Pacific Seascape are highlighted below.</p>
<p><strong>Regional:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Signed in late 2021, the Partnership for Sustainably Managed Fisheries initiative from the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) will help train port authorities and strengthen the ability of Colombia, Ecuador, and Peru to address illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing. NOAA and other federal agencies are also beginning to engage with partners in the region to strengthen sustainable marine protected area management as well as conservation and restoration of blue carbon habitats.</li>
<li>The U.S. Government has provided Colombia, Ecuador, and Panama with access to SeaVision, a Department of Transportation-led program that enables partner countries to access and share U.S. maritime domain awareness information and collaborate with maritime partners.</li>
<li>U.S. Southern Command partnered with Florida International University is working with NGO Global Fishing Watch to advance awareness, detection, and deterrence of IUU fishing in the region and to further enable counter IUU fishing efforts through data sharing and subject matter exchanges.</li>
<li>To operationalize the high seas boarding and inspection procedures from the 1995 United Nations Fish Stocks Agreement in the South Pacific Regional Fisheries Management Organization and to combat IUU fishing in the region, the U.S. Coast Guard (USCG) deployed the Cutter Stone last fall in Colombia, Costa Rica, Ecuador, and Panama, expanding regional interoperability and patrolling sovereign waters to deter illegal fishing.</li>
<li>The USCG and State Department support Colombia’s and Ecuador’s Coast Guards with Mobile Training Teams. Mobile Training Teams offer host nations a variety of program specialties including search and rescue, law enforcement, boat operations, outboard motor maintenance, maritime operations and planning, and IUU fishing.</li>
<li>The Department of Labor awarded a $5 million grant in December 2021 for an International Labour Organization project in Ecuador and Peru to strengthen working conditions and combat IUU fishing in coastal communities.</li>
<li>In Fiscal Year 2021, the U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) flew 6,590 maritime patrol hours with Colombian, Costa Rican, Ecuadorian, and Panamanian partners. These efforts resulted in the interdiction of approximately 201,450 pounds of cocaine and 49,820 pounds of marijuana.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Colombia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The U.S. Navy installed automatic identification system antennas along the Colombian coast to support maritime domain awareness efforts.</li>
<li>The State Department is installing a radar and constructing a coast guard station and pier on Gorgona Island, purchasing $2.6 million in boat engines to improve the Colombian Coast Guard’s operational readiness, and funding the upgrade of the Colombian Navy’s maritime patrol aircraft.</li>
<li>The Enterprise for the Americas Initiative and the Tropical Forest Conservation Act provide annual funding for Fundación Malpelo to protect the Malpelo Fauna and Flora Sanctuary.</li>
<li>The USCG provides resident maritime boarding officer training to Colombia using International Military Education Training funds and conducted Key Leader Engagements with Colombian Navy leadership to discuss the rollout and implementation plan of the USCG’s 2021 IUU Fishing Strategic Outlook.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Costa Rica:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The State Department facilitated the donation of 200 vessel monitoring system transponders for the national fishing fleet and awarded two Central America Regional Security Initiative grants totaling $500,000 to Costa Rican NGOs to promote transparent fisheries governance and data accessibility in 2021.</li>
<li>The State Department and the Costa Rican Coast Guard (CRCG) created a 10-year strategic plan that includes creation of major engineering maintenance facilities on the Pacific and Caribbean coasts and the establishment of a small boat Center of Excellence maintenance training center and maintenance/supply depot.</li>
<li>Two State Department-funded USCG Curriculum Advisors support the CRCG’s engineering and maritime law enforcement curriculum and specialty training at the CRCG Academy.</li>
<li>The USCG supports Costa Rican maritime law enforcement operations by embarking shipriders and providing USCG law enforcement detachments to serve aboard Costa Rican surface assets. The USCG also transferred former USCG Cutters Long Island and Roanoke Island to the CRCG in 2017 through the Excess Defense Articles Program and transferred a third cutter in 2018 to be used for parts.  The cutters have extended Costa Rica’s maritime coverage.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Ecuador:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The State Department funds several Ecuadorian Coast Guard capacity-building initiatives and equipment repairs and plans to provide sensors and communication equipment to the Ecuadorian Navy to expand maritime domain awareness and help counter IUU fishing.</li>
<li>USAID and the State Department fund trainings for prosecutors to prosecute IUU fishing and wildlife trafficking. For example, two Ecuadorian prosecutors from the Galápagos participated in a wildlife crime scene investigation course in October 2021, and the Ecuadorian environmental police unit received counter-wildlife trafficking training in November 2021.</li>
<li>Since 2018, the U.S. government has provided a Lockheed P-3 Orion aircraft and a Boeing 707 carrying an airborne warning and control system to periodically conduct operations and gather information on illicit activities related to drug trafficking and illegal fishing.</li>
<li>In August 2020, the USCG Cutter Bertholf and the Ecuadorian naval vessel LAE Isla San Cristobal jointly patrolled over 3,000 square nautical miles of Ecuadorian and international waters to detect and deter illegal fishing near the Galápagos Islands. In November 2021, Ecuadorian observers embarked the USCG Cutter Mohawk as part of a joint patrol in the Galápagos to counter illicit drug trafficking and IUU fishing.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Panama:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>In 2021, the Department of Defense (DoD) donated a Near Coastal Patrol Vessel, naval maintenance equipment, and spare parts for high-speed interceptor boats operated by Panama’s National Aeronaval Service (SENAN). The State Department donated equipment to SENAN to support their large vessel maintenance facility.  The DoD plans to donate a maritime patrol aircraft in 2022, and the State Department plans to donate two interceptor boats in 2022 and two more interceptor boats in 2023.</li>
<li>Under the Port Enforcement Task Force, a joint operational entity, Panamanian customs and law enforcement agencies and U.S. counterparts, including DEA, HSI, and CBP, have expanded collaborative capabilities in the targeting, inspection, interdiction, and seizure of undeclared merchandise and narcotics and illegally fished species.</li>
<li>In February 2021, Panama’s Ministry of Public Security codified a U.S-led initiative to design and construct a Joint Regional Air and Navy Operations Center (CROAN) and form a Joint Maritime Force (JMF-Panama) to counter narcotics and IUU fishing.</li>
<li>The State Department funds regional NGO MarViva to build enforcement capabilities and awareness, with a focus on deterring IUU fishing in the Gulf of Chiriqui.</li>
<li>In April 2022, the State Department will hold a joint workshop in Panama on smart ports and the prevention of the exploitation of critical assets within the maritime sector as part of the Strategic Ports Initiative<em>.</em></li>
</ul>
<p>For additional information, please see the Media Note on U.S. Government Support for the Eastern Tropical Pacific Marine Corridor and the <a href="https://www.state.gov/opening-remarks-at-the-high-level-dialogue-on-the-eastern-tropical-pacific-marine-corridor/">Opening Remarks from Under Secretary Jose W. Fernandez and Assistant Secretary Monica P. Medina</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>At a high-level dialogue on March 22 in San José, Costa Rica, Under Secretary Jose W. Fernandez and Assistant Secretary Monica P. Medina announced U.S. government support for the Eastern Tropical Pacific Marine Corridor.</p>
<p>Key U.S. government activities in the Eastern Tropical Pacific Seascape are highlighted below.</p>
<p><strong>Regional:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Signed in late 2021, the Partnership for Sustainably Managed Fisheries initiative from the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) will help train port authorities and strengthen the ability of Colombia, Ecuador, and Peru to address illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing. NOAA and other federal agencies are also beginning to engage with partners in the region to strengthen sustainable marine protected area management as well as conservation and restoration of blue carbon habitats.</li>
<li>The U.S. Government has provided Colombia, Ecuador, and Panama with access to SeaVision, a Department of Transportation-led program that enables partner countries to access and share U.S. maritime domain awareness information and collaborate with maritime partners.</li>
<li>U.S. Southern Command partnered with Florida International University is working with NGO Global Fishing Watch to advance awareness, detection, and deterrence of IUU fishing in the region and to further enable counter IUU fishing efforts through data sharing and subject matter exchanges.</li>
<li>To operationalize the high seas boarding and inspection procedures from the 1995 United Nations Fish Stocks Agreement in the South Pacific Regional Fisheries Management Organization and to combat IUU fishing in the region, the U.S. Coast Guard (USCG) deployed the Cutter Stone last fall in Colombia, Costa Rica, Ecuador, and Panama, expanding regional interoperability and patrolling sovereign waters to deter illegal fishing.</li>
<li>The USCG and State Department support Colombia’s and Ecuador’s Coast Guards with Mobile Training Teams. Mobile Training Teams offer host nations a variety of program specialties including search and rescue, law enforcement, boat operations, outboard motor maintenance, maritime operations and planning, and IUU fishing.</li>
<li>The Department of Labor awarded a $5 million grant in December 2021 for an International Labour Organization project in Ecuador and Peru to strengthen working conditions and combat IUU fishing in coastal communities.</li>
<li>In Fiscal Year 2021, the U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) flew 6,590 maritime patrol hours with Colombian, Costa Rican, Ecuadorian, and Panamanian partners. These efforts resulted in the interdiction of approximately 201,450 pounds of cocaine and 49,820 pounds of marijuana.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Colombia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The U.S. Navy installed automatic identification system antennas along the Colombian coast to support maritime domain awareness efforts.</li>
<li>The State Department is installing a radar and constructing a coast guard station and pier on Gorgona Island, purchasing $2.6 million in boat engines to improve the Colombian Coast Guard’s operational readiness, and funding the upgrade of the Colombian Navy’s maritime patrol aircraft.</li>
<li>The Enterprise for the Americas Initiative and the Tropical Forest Conservation Act provide annual funding for Fundación Malpelo to protect the Malpelo Fauna and Flora Sanctuary.</li>
<li>The USCG provides resident maritime boarding officer training to Colombia using International Military Education Training funds and conducted Key Leader Engagements with Colombian Navy leadership to discuss the rollout and implementation plan of the USCG’s 2021 IUU Fishing Strategic Outlook.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Costa Rica:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The State Department facilitated the donation of 200 vessel monitoring system transponders for the national fishing fleet and awarded two Central America Regional Security Initiative grants totaling $500,000 to Costa Rican NGOs to promote transparent fisheries governance and data accessibility in 2021.</li>
<li>The State Department and the Costa Rican Coast Guard (CRCG) created a 10-year strategic plan that includes creation of major engineering maintenance facilities on the Pacific and Caribbean coasts and the establishment of a small boat Center of Excellence maintenance training center and maintenance/supply depot.</li>
<li>Two State Department-funded USCG Curriculum Advisors support the CRCG’s engineering and maritime law enforcement curriculum and specialty training at the CRCG Academy.</li>
<li>The USCG supports Costa Rican maritime law enforcement operations by embarking shipriders and providing USCG law enforcement detachments to serve aboard Costa Rican surface assets. The USCG also transferred former USCG Cutters Long Island and Roanoke Island to the CRCG in 2017 through the Excess Defense Articles Program and transferred a third cutter in 2018 to be used for parts.  The cutters have extended Costa Rica’s maritime coverage.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Ecuador:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The State Department funds several Ecuadorian Coast Guard capacity-building initiatives and equipment repairs and plans to provide sensors and communication equipment to the Ecuadorian Navy to expand maritime domain awareness and help counter IUU fishing.</li>
<li>USAID and the State Department fund trainings for prosecutors to prosecute IUU fishing and wildlife trafficking. For example, two Ecuadorian prosecutors from the Galápagos participated in a wildlife crime scene investigation course in October 2021, and the Ecuadorian environmental police unit received counter-wildlife trafficking training in November 2021.</li>
<li>Since 2018, the U.S. government has provided a Lockheed P-3 Orion aircraft and a Boeing 707 carrying an airborne warning and control system to periodically conduct operations and gather information on illicit activities related to drug trafficking and illegal fishing.</li>
<li>In August 2020, the USCG Cutter Bertholf and the Ecuadorian naval vessel LAE Isla San Cristobal jointly patrolled over 3,000 square nautical miles of Ecuadorian and international waters to detect and deter illegal fishing near the Galápagos Islands. In November 2021, Ecuadorian observers embarked the USCG Cutter Mohawk as part of a joint patrol in the Galápagos to counter illicit drug trafficking and IUU fishing.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Panama:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>In 2021, the Department of Defense (DoD) donated a Near Coastal Patrol Vessel, naval maintenance equipment, and spare parts for high-speed interceptor boats operated by Panama’s National Aeronaval Service (SENAN). The State Department donated equipment to SENAN to support their large vessel maintenance facility.  The DoD plans to donate a maritime patrol aircraft in 2022, and the State Department plans to donate two interceptor boats in 2022 and two more interceptor boats in 2023.</li>
<li>Under the Port Enforcement Task Force, a joint operational entity, Panamanian customs and law enforcement agencies and U.S. counterparts, including DEA, HSI, and CBP, have expanded collaborative capabilities in the targeting, inspection, interdiction, and seizure of undeclared merchandise and narcotics and illegally fished species.</li>
<li>In February 2021, Panama’s Ministry of Public Security codified a U.S-led initiative to design and construct a Joint Regional Air and Navy Operations Center (CROAN) and form a Joint Maritime Force (JMF-Panama) to counter narcotics and IUU fishing.</li>
<li>The State Department funds regional NGO MarViva to build enforcement capabilities and awareness, with a focus on deterring IUU fishing in the Gulf of Chiriqui.</li>
<li>In April 2022, the State Department will hold a joint workshop in Panama on smart ports and the prevention of the exploitation of critical assets within the maritime sector as part of the Strategic Ports Initiative<em>.</em></li>
</ul>
<p>For additional information, please see the Media Note on U.S. Government Support for the Eastern Tropical Pacific Marine Corridor and the <a href="https://www.state.gov/opening-remarks-at-the-high-level-dialogue-on-the-eastern-tropical-pacific-marine-corridor/">Opening Remarks from Under Secretary Jose W. Fernandez and Assistant Secretary Monica P. Medina</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Announcing the Special Presidential Envoy for Compact Negotiations</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/announcing-the-special-presidential-envoy-for-compact-negotiations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 21:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=326763</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States has a special and longstanding relationship with the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau – collectively known as the Freely Associated States (FAS). We are currently engaged in negotiating amendments to certain provisions of the Compacts of Free Association with the FAS, and completing the negotiations is a priority for this Administration.</p>
<p>In light of the critical nature of these complex negotiations, President Biden is appointing Ambassador Joseph Yun as Special Presidential Envoy for Compact Negotiations. Ambassador Yun has more than 33 years of diplomatic experience, including as the U.S. special representative for North Korea policy and as the United States Ambassador to Malaysia.</p>
<p>The Compacts reflect the close relationships between the United States and the FAS and are a critical source of regional security, stability, and prosperity. Through these negotiations, we will strengthen our enduring partnerships with our close Pacific Island partners and ensure a free and open and prosperous Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States has a special and longstanding relationship with the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau – collectively known as the Freely Associated States (FAS). We are currently engaged in negotiating amendments to certain provisions of the Compacts of Free Association with the FAS, and completing the negotiations is a priority for this Administration.</p>
<p>In light of the critical nature of these complex negotiations, President Biden is appointing Ambassador Joseph Yun as Special Presidential Envoy for Compact Negotiations. Ambassador Yun has more than 33 years of diplomatic experience, including as the U.S. special representative for North Korea policy and as the United States Ambassador to Malaysia.</p>
<p>The Compacts reflect the close relationships between the United States and the FAS and are a critical source of regional security, stability, and prosperity. Through these negotiations, we will strengthen our enduring partnerships with our close Pacific Island partners and ensure a free and open and prosperous Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aleksey Navalny Unjustly Convicted Again</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/aleksey-navalny-unjustly-convicted-again/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 20:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=326739</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We condemn Russian authorities’ politically-motivated conviction and sentencing of opposition leader Aleksey Navalny on additional spurious charges to nine more years in a high security prison. This outlandish prison term is a continuation of the Kremlin’s years-long assault on Navalny and on his movement for government transparency and accountability. Of course, Navalny’s true crime in the eyes of the Kremlin is his work as an anti-corruption activist and opposition politician, for which he and his associates have been branded “extremists” by Russian authorities.</p>
<p>Despite his near-fatal poisoning with a nerve agent in 2020 by Russia’s security services and his unjust imprisonment since January 2020, Navalny has continued to speak out against the Kremlin’s suppression of freedom of expression in Russia, and the increasing restrictions on the ability of Russia’s citizens to access information and communicate freely with each other and the outside world. This campaign has intensified as the Kremlin seeks to hide the truth of its brutal war against Ukraine from its own people. More than 15,000 citizens of Russia have been detained for taking part in anti-war protests since February 24. Russia’s communications authority has blocked access to nearly all independent news outlets and several social media platforms, and threatened journalists and average citizens alike with jail time if they dare to discuss the war against Ukraine using anything other than Kremlin-approved euphemisms.</p>
<p>We urge the Russian Federation to immediately and unconditionally release Aleksey Navalny and to end its campaign against his organizations and associates. Navalny’s case is sadly one of many the Kremlin continues to brazenly pursue as it systematically ignores the constitutional rights of the Russian people and its international commitments to respect and ensure human rights and fundamental freedoms. Now more than ever, the people of Russia must be able to hear voices of courage and integrity that tell the truth about the Kremlin’s wrongdoing at home and abroad.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We condemn Russian authorities’ politically-motivated conviction and sentencing of opposition leader Aleksey Navalny on additional spurious charges to nine more years in a high security prison. This outlandish prison term is a continuation of the Kremlin’s years-long assault on Navalny and on his movement for government transparency and accountability. Of course, Navalny’s true crime in the eyes of the Kremlin is his work as an anti-corruption activist and opposition politician, for which he and his associates have been branded “extremists” by Russian authorities.</p>
<p>Despite his near-fatal poisoning with a nerve agent in 2020 by Russia’s security services and his unjust imprisonment since January 2020, Navalny has continued to speak out against the Kremlin’s suppression of freedom of expression in Russia, and the increasing restrictions on the ability of Russia’s citizens to access information and communicate freely with each other and the outside world. This campaign has intensified as the Kremlin seeks to hide the truth of its brutal war against Ukraine from its own people. More than 15,000 citizens of Russia have been detained for taking part in anti-war protests since February 24. Russia’s communications authority has blocked access to nearly all independent news outlets and several social media platforms, and threatened journalists and average citizens alike with jail time if they dare to discuss the war against Ukraine using anything other than Kremlin-approved euphemisms.</p>
<p>We urge the Russian Federation to immediately and unconditionally release Aleksey Navalny and to end its campaign against his organizations and associates. Navalny’s case is sadly one of many the Kremlin continues to brazenly pursue as it systematically ignores the constitutional rights of the Russian people and its international commitments to respect and ensure human rights and fundamental freedoms. Now more than ever, the people of Russia must be able to hear voices of courage and integrity that tell the truth about the Kremlin’s wrongdoing at home and abroad.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-nato-secretary-general-stoltenberg-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 20:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=326727</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg about ongoing efforts to fortify NATO’s Eastern Flank and preparations for the March 24 Extraordinary NATO Summit.  The Secretary reaffirmed the need for a strong and united Transatlantic response to the Russian government’s war against Ukraine and welcomed ongoing work to strengthen NATO’s deterrence and defense.  Secretary Blinken reiterated the United States’ steadfast commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of President Putin’s brutal war of choice.  They also discussed the significant humanitarian and security assistance NATO Allies are providing bilaterally to Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg about ongoing efforts to fortify NATO’s Eastern Flank and preparations for the March 24 Extraordinary NATO Summit.  The Secretary reaffirmed the need for a strong and united Transatlantic response to the Russian government’s war against Ukraine and welcomed ongoing work to strengthen NATO’s deterrence and defense.  Secretary Blinken reiterated the United States’ steadfast commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of President Putin’s brutal war of choice.  They also discussed the significant humanitarian and security assistance NATO Allies are providing bilaterally to Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Polish Foreign Minister Rau</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-polish-foreign-minister-rau-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 19:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=326708</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Polish Foreign Minister Zbigniew Rau. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Rau discussed continued international efforts to support Ukraine and to respond to the devastating humanitarian crisis caused by Putin’s premeditated, unjustified, and unprovoked war. They also discussed the March 24 Extraordinary NATO Summit and President Biden’s upcoming visit to Poland.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Polish Foreign Minister Zbigniew Rau. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Rau discussed continued international efforts to support Ukraine and to respond to the devastating humanitarian crisis caused by Putin’s premeditated, unjustified, and unprovoked war. They also discussed the March 24 Extraordinary NATO Summit and President Biden’s upcoming visit to Poland.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with French, German, Italian, and UK Counterparts</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-french-german-italian-and-uk-counterparts-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 16:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=326584</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with French MFA Secretary General Francois Delattre, German MFA Political Director Tjorven Bellmann, Italian MFA Secretary General Ettore Sequi, and UK Minister of State for Europe and North America James Cleverly. Deputy Secretary Sherman condemned President Putin’s increasingly brutal tactics that continue to kill civilians in this unjustified and unprovoked war of choice. The participants discussed the importance of providing further military and humanitarian aid to Ukraine. They also discussed additional economic measures to hold the Russian Federation and Belarus accountable. All participants agreed to continue to work to isolate the Russian Federation on the international stage given its flagrant violation of international law and principles.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with French MFA Secretary General Francois Delattre, German MFA Political Director Tjorven Bellmann, Italian MFA Secretary General Ettore Sequi, and UK Minister of State for Europe and North America James Cleverly. Deputy Secretary Sherman condemned President Putin’s increasingly brutal tactics that continue to kill civilians in this unjustified and unprovoked war of choice. The participants discussed the importance of providing further military and humanitarian aid to Ukraine. They also discussed additional economic measures to hold the Russian Federation and Belarus accountable. All participants agreed to continue to work to isolate the Russian Federation on the international stage given its flagrant violation of international law and principles.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Evacuation of Pediatric Oncology Patients to St. Jude Children’s Research Hospital</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-evacuation-of-pediatric-oncology-patients-to-st-jude-childrens-research-hospital/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 15:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=326553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Our partnership with, and commitment to, the people of Ukraine is steadfast and enduring. To that end, the Department of State has coordinated with St. Jude Children’s Research Hospital to provide necessary life-saving and immediate care to four Ukrainian children whose ongoing cancer treatment was disrupted by President Putin’s war of choice. The Department supported airlift of these pediatric oncology patients and some of their immediate family members from Poland to Memphis International Airport, where they were met and transported to St. Jude. There, the patients will be able to safely resume critical cancer therapy disrupted by the Kremlin’s aggression. They will receive the specialized care they desperately need, and their family members will be afforded sustenance, security, and support from St. Jude.</p>
<p>Children are among the most vulnerable in a crisis, and these pediatric oncology patients need urgent and highly specialized medical care. We are proud to stand with European partners who are also treating children whose life-saving care in Ukraine has been made impossible by Putin’s war. We recognize, however, that the children transported represent a small proportion of the thousands of patients whose cancer treatment has been interrupted and, who, even amid a pandemic and with compromised immune systems, were forced to flee their homes. That is why, together with our allies and partners, we will continue to support our Ukrainian partners as we seek to save lives and bring this needless war to a close.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Our partnership with, and commitment to, the people of Ukraine is steadfast and enduring. To that end, the Department of State has coordinated with St. Jude Children’s Research Hospital to provide necessary life-saving and immediate care to four Ukrainian children whose ongoing cancer treatment was disrupted by President Putin’s war of choice. The Department supported airlift of these pediatric oncology patients and some of their immediate family members from Poland to Memphis International Airport, where they were met and transported to St. Jude. There, the patients will be able to safely resume critical cancer therapy disrupted by the Kremlin’s aggression. They will receive the specialized care they desperately need, and their family members will be afforded sustenance, security, and support from St. Jude.</p>
<p>Children are among the most vulnerable in a crisis, and these pediatric oncology patients need urgent and highly specialized medical care. We are proud to stand with European partners who are also treating children whose life-saving care in Ukraine has been made impossible by Putin’s war. We recognize, however, that the children transported represent a small proportion of the thousands of patients whose cancer treatment has been interrupted and, who, even amid a pandemic and with compromised immune systems, were forced to flee their homes. That is why, together with our allies and partners, we will continue to support our Ukrainian partners as we seek to save lives and bring this needless war to a close.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>World Water Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/world-water-day-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 13:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=326479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Water is one of the world’s most precious resources. Whether mitigating and adapting to climate change impacts, strengthening global health security, improving access to food, or securing energy resources, water is essential to addressing these issues and building a better future. Millions of people around the world lack access to safe drinking water and sanitation, and water supplies are increasingly scarce and unpredictable. And, of course, water is vital to all life on earth and to the conservation and restoration of nature. We must act to strengthen water security for all.</p>
<p>Many of our goals – and those of our partners – cannot be achieved without water security. The United States is investing in water resources and infrastructure at home and abroad through the U.S. Global Water Strategy, a whole-of-government approach to advance our vision for a water-secure world. We are also integrating water security and water management into our climate adaptation efforts. Through our commitment to conserve 30 percent of our land and waters by 2030, we will help maintain the ecosystems that are so crucial for water security. Additionally, the President’s Emergency Plan for Adaptation and Resilience (PREPARE) will support climate adaptation efforts for more than half a billion people around the world. Investing in adaptation addresses immediate water challenges and builds a resilient future.</p>
<p>On this World Water Day, we recognize that our future depends on protecting this essential resource, and we celebrate everyone who is working to build a more water-secure world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Water is one of the world’s most precious resources. Whether mitigating and adapting to climate change impacts, strengthening global health security, improving access to food, or securing energy resources, water is essential to addressing these issues and building a better future. Millions of people around the world lack access to safe drinking water and sanitation, and water supplies are increasingly scarce and unpredictable. And, of course, water is vital to all life on earth and to the conservation and restoration of nature. We must act to strengthen water security for all.</p>
<p>Many of our goals – and those of our partners – cannot be achieved without water security. The United States is investing in water resources and infrastructure at home and abroad through the U.S. Global Water Strategy, a whole-of-government approach to advance our vision for a water-secure world. We are also integrating water security and water management into our climate adaptation efforts. Through our commitment to conserve 30 percent of our land and waters by 2030, we will help maintain the ecosystems that are so crucial for water security. Additionally, the President’s Emergency Plan for Adaptation and Resilience (PREPARE) will support climate adaptation efforts for more than half a billion people around the world. Investing in adaptation addresses immediate water challenges and builds a resilient future.</p>
<p>On this World Water Day, we recognize that our future depends on protecting this essential resource, and we celebrate everyone who is working to build a more water-secure world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
