<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 19:54:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Joint Statement by the Trilateral Working Group on Violence against Indigenous Women and Girls, Following the 21st session of UN Permanent Forum for Indigenous Issues</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-by-the-trilateral-working-group-on-violence-against-indigenous-women-and-girls-following-the-21st-session-of-un-permanent-forum-for-indigenous-issues/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 19:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344754</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the governments of Canada, Mexico, and the United States following the 21st session of the UN Permanent Forum for Indigenous Issues, which was held from April 25th to May 6th, 2022.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>We recognize that Indigenous women, young women, and girls in all their diversity, and two-spirit and gender-diverse individuals face disproportionately high rates of gender-based violence. This violence is a multidimensional phenomenon that is predicated on histories of abuse and perpetuated by ongoing discrimination and racism, including multiple and intersecting forms of discrimination.  The violence includes, but is not limited to, murders, sexual assault, trafficking, and intimate-partner violence. Too often, the disappearance or murder of Indigenous women, young women, and girls in all their diversity and two-spirit and gender-diverse individuals is not met with swift, effective, and culturally relevant action, including the lack of processes in Indigenous languages, by government institutions to investigate and resolve these cases.  Much work needs to be done to enhance intervention, access to justice, and to strengthen prevention efforts.</p>
<p>Statistics Canada indicates that 56 percent of Indigenous women in Canada have experienced physical assault while 46 percent have experienced sexual assault. According to the latest National Survey on the Dynamics of Household Relationships (ENDIREH), carried out in 2016 by the National Institute of Geography and Statistics in Mexico, it is estimated that 59 percent of Indigenous women have experienced some type of violence (emotional, physical, sexual, economic, patrimonial or labor discrimination) throughout their lives.  According to the U.S. National Institute of Justice, 84 percent of Native American women in the United States have experienced physical, sexual, or psychological violence in their lifetime, often at the hands of non-Native perpetrators. Emerging data from UN Women shows that impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic have intensified gender-based violence globally.</p>
<p>We know this is not a problem limited to our three countries or our region, and we welcome cooperation from other governments, civil-society organizations, and other entities in the elimination of all forms of discrimination and gender-based violence perpetrated against Indigenous women and girls in diverse communities.</p>
<p>First established as an outcome of the June 2016 North American Leaders’ Summit, the Trilateral Working Group on Violence Against Indigenous Women and Girls (Trilateral Working Group) is an initiative to reaffirm and to advance our respective national and regional commitments to prevent and respond to gender-based violence impacting Indigenous peoples in North America through increased access to justice and services, with an intersectional, gender-responsive, human rights and culturally-responsive approaches.</p>
<p>In July 2022, the governments of Canada, Mexico, and the United States will convene the fourth meeting of the Trilateral Working Group, hosted by the United States. This dialogue, which will include the participation of Indigenous women experts, leaders, and advocates, will address the multi-faceted aspects, including root causes that increase vulnerability to gender-based violence, access to justice and enhanced accountability, and increased resources for survivors.</p>
<p>The themes of the 4th Trilateral Working Group meeting will be:</p>
<ul>
<li>Strengthening access to justice, culturally appropriate approaches to safety and healing, and addressing the crisis of missing and murdered Indigenous women, young women, and girls in all their diversity and two-spirit and gender-diverse individuals, including trafficking in persons;</li>
<li>Advancing Indigenous women’s leadership and representation at all levels; and</li>
<li>Addressing the root causes of gender-based violence against Indigenous women, girls and two-spirit and gender-diverse individuals, including economic security and food insecurity related to the climate crisis.</li>
</ul>
<p>The Members of the Permanent Forum on Indigenous Issues issued recommendations in 2018 urging the Canada, Mexico, and the United States, to organize an international expert group meeting by 2021 on the issue of ongoing violence against Indigenous women and girls in the region, including trafficking, as well as the continuing crisis of missing and murdered Indigenous women, girls and two-spirit and gender-diverse individuals.</p>
<p>At the North American Leaders’ Summit on November 18, President Biden, President Lopez Obrador, and Prime Minister Trudeau committed to convene a meeting of Indigenous women leaders as part of the Trilateral Working Group on Violence Against Indigenous Women and Girls.  To this end, in November 2021, we convened Indigenous women leaders from across the three countries of North America for a virtual engagement to center their expertise and recommendations on addressing these issues.  The themes identified for the upcoming 4th Trilateral Working Group arose directly from this convening. We welcome opportunities in the future to engage with international experts from other regions following this next meeting of the Trilateral Working Group.</p>
<p>We recognize that ending violence against Indigenous women and girls requires a holistic, multidimensional, and multi-sectoral approach. We reiterate our unwavering commitment as our three countries continue working together, in partnership with Indigenous peoples from our three countries, to eliminate this epidemic of gender-based violence and attain our goals of safety, security, well-being, and empowerment for all members of Indigenous communities.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the governments of Canada, Mexico, and the United States following the 21st session of the UN Permanent Forum for Indigenous Issues, which was held from April 25th to May 6th, 2022.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>We recognize that Indigenous women, young women, and girls in all their diversity, and two-spirit and gender-diverse individuals face disproportionately high rates of gender-based violence. This violence is a multidimensional phenomenon that is predicated on histories of abuse and perpetuated by ongoing discrimination and racism, including multiple and intersecting forms of discrimination.  The violence includes, but is not limited to, murders, sexual assault, trafficking, and intimate-partner violence. Too often, the disappearance or murder of Indigenous women, young women, and girls in all their diversity and two-spirit and gender-diverse individuals is not met with swift, effective, and culturally relevant action, including the lack of processes in Indigenous languages, by government institutions to investigate and resolve these cases.  Much work needs to be done to enhance intervention, access to justice, and to strengthen prevention efforts.</p>
<p>Statistics Canada indicates that 56 percent of Indigenous women in Canada have experienced physical assault while 46 percent have experienced sexual assault. According to the latest National Survey on the Dynamics of Household Relationships (ENDIREH), carried out in 2016 by the National Institute of Geography and Statistics in Mexico, it is estimated that 59 percent of Indigenous women have experienced some type of violence (emotional, physical, sexual, economic, patrimonial or labor discrimination) throughout their lives.  According to the U.S. National Institute of Justice, 84 percent of Native American women in the United States have experienced physical, sexual, or psychological violence in their lifetime, often at the hands of non-Native perpetrators. Emerging data from UN Women shows that impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic have intensified gender-based violence globally.</p>
<p>We know this is not a problem limited to our three countries or our region, and we welcome cooperation from other governments, civil-society organizations, and other entities in the elimination of all forms of discrimination and gender-based violence perpetrated against Indigenous women and girls in diverse communities.</p>
<p>First established as an outcome of the June 2016 North American Leaders’ Summit, the Trilateral Working Group on Violence Against Indigenous Women and Girls (Trilateral Working Group) is an initiative to reaffirm and to advance our respective national and regional commitments to prevent and respond to gender-based violence impacting Indigenous peoples in North America through increased access to justice and services, with an intersectional, gender-responsive, human rights and culturally-responsive approaches.</p>
<p>In July 2022, the governments of Canada, Mexico, and the United States will convene the fourth meeting of the Trilateral Working Group, hosted by the United States. This dialogue, which will include the participation of Indigenous women experts, leaders, and advocates, will address the multi-faceted aspects, including root causes that increase vulnerability to gender-based violence, access to justice and enhanced accountability, and increased resources for survivors.</p>
<p>The themes of the 4th Trilateral Working Group meeting will be:</p>
<ul>
<li>Strengthening access to justice, culturally appropriate approaches to safety and healing, and addressing the crisis of missing and murdered Indigenous women, young women, and girls in all their diversity and two-spirit and gender-diverse individuals, including trafficking in persons;</li>
<li>Advancing Indigenous women’s leadership and representation at all levels; and</li>
<li>Addressing the root causes of gender-based violence against Indigenous women, girls and two-spirit and gender-diverse individuals, including economic security and food insecurity related to the climate crisis.</li>
</ul>
<p>The Members of the Permanent Forum on Indigenous Issues issued recommendations in 2018 urging the Canada, Mexico, and the United States, to organize an international expert group meeting by 2021 on the issue of ongoing violence against Indigenous women and girls in the region, including trafficking, as well as the continuing crisis of missing and murdered Indigenous women, girls and two-spirit and gender-diverse individuals.</p>
<p>At the North American Leaders’ Summit on November 18, President Biden, President Lopez Obrador, and Prime Minister Trudeau committed to convene a meeting of Indigenous women leaders as part of the Trilateral Working Group on Violence Against Indigenous Women and Girls.  To this end, in November 2021, we convened Indigenous women leaders from across the three countries of North America for a virtual engagement to center their expertise and recommendations on addressing these issues.  The themes identified for the upcoming 4th Trilateral Working Group arose directly from this convening. We welcome opportunities in the future to engage with international experts from other regions following this next meeting of the Trilateral Working Group.</p>
<p>We recognize that ending violence against Indigenous women and girls requires a holistic, multidimensional, and multi-sectoral approach. We reiterate our unwavering commitment as our three countries continue working together, in partnership with Indigenous peoples from our three countries, to eliminate this epidemic of gender-based violence and attain our goals of safety, security, well-being, and empowerment for all members of Indigenous communities.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Turkish Deputy Foreign Minister Onal</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-turkish-deputy-foreign-minister-onal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 19:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344747</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today in Washington with Turkish Deputy Foreign Minister Sedat Onal. They reaffirmed the strategic relationship between Turkey and the United States and discussed the two countries’ many areas of bilateral cooperation. Deputy Secretary Sherman thanked Deputy Foreign Minister Onal for Turkey’s strong and vocal support of Ukraine and discussed the need for solidarity among NATO Allies and partners in confronting Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine and in imposing real costs on Putin and his cronies.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today in Washington with Turkish Deputy Foreign Minister Sedat Onal. They reaffirmed the strategic relationship between Turkey and the United States and discussed the two countries’ many areas of bilateral cooperation. Deputy Secretary Sherman thanked Deputy Foreign Minister Onal for Turkey’s strong and vocal support of Ukraine and discussed the need for solidarity among NATO Allies and partners in confronting Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine and in imposing real costs on Putin and his cronies.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary Zeya’s travel to India and Nepal</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-zeyas-travel-to-india-and-nepal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 18:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights and U.S. Special Coordinator for Tibetan Issues Uzra Zeya will travel May 17 – 22 to India and Nepal to deepen cooperation on human rights and democratic governance goals, and to advance humanitarian priorities. She will also discuss partnering with India and Nepal during this Year of Action for the Summit for Democracy. The delegation will include USAID Deputy Assistant Administrator for Asia Anjali Kaur.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:sca-press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sca-press@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights and U.S. Special Coordinator for Tibetan Issues Uzra Zeya will travel May 17 – 22 to India and Nepal to deepen cooperation on human rights and democratic governance goals, and to advance humanitarian priorities. She will also discuss partnering with India and Nepal during this Year of Action for the Summit for Democracy. The delegation will include USAID Deputy Assistant Administrator for Asia Anjali Kaur.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:sca-press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sca-press@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New U.S. APEC Business Advisory Council Member Appointment</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/new-u-s-apec-business-advisory-council-member-appointment-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 18:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the appointment of Laura Lane, Executive Vice President (EVP) and Chief Corporate Affairs Officer at the United Parcel Service (UPS), to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) Business Advisory Council (ABAC).</p>
<p>Ms. Lane and her ABAC counterparts from the other APEC economies will advise APEC Leaders on issues affecting the continued growth of the region’s economy. In this role, Ms. Lane will provide recommendations reflecting the perspective of U.S. stakeholders. ABAC, created in 1995, consists of up to three business representatives from each APEC economy and is a key component of APEC’s multi-stakeholder approach to trade and economic policies. ABAC meets throughout the year to discuss policy recommendations, undertakes activities to promote trade and investment, as well as sustainable and inclusive growth, and reports annually to APEC Leaders.</p>
<p>In her role as EVP and Chief Corporate Affairs Officer and a critical member of UPS’s Executive Leadership Team, Ms. Lane oversees the company’s Public Policy and Government Affairs, Communications, Sustainability, Community Relations Division, as well as The UPS Foundation. Ms. Lane has served in both the U.S. private and public sectors, with extensive experience in government, financial services, media and information-communications, and logistics, enabling her to represent the broad range of interests of U.S. businesses, including small-and women-owned businesses.</p>
<p>Prior to joining UPS, Ms. Lane served as Managing Director and Head of International Government Affairs at Citigroup and Vice President for Global Public Policy at Time Warner. In her government career, Ms. Lane served as a trade negotiator in the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative and as a diplomat in the U.S. Foreign Service. Ms. Lane currently serves as a member of the board of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees USA (UNHCR-USA) and the CDC Foundation, in addition to several other U.S. business associations and nonprofits, including the Atlantic Council, The Woodruff Arts Center, and the German-American Business Council.</p>
<p>For more than 30 years APEC has served as the premier economic platform for the United States to engage our regional partners on structural issues to advance an economic and trade architecture that opens markets, promotes high standards, and promotes sustainable and inclusive growth.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact the U.S. APEC Team at <a href="mailto:DOSAPEC@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DOSAPEC@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the appointment of Laura Lane, Executive Vice President (EVP) and Chief Corporate Affairs Officer at the United Parcel Service (UPS), to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) Business Advisory Council (ABAC).</p>
<p>Ms. Lane and her ABAC counterparts from the other APEC economies will advise APEC Leaders on issues affecting the continued growth of the region’s economy. In this role, Ms. Lane will provide recommendations reflecting the perspective of U.S. stakeholders. ABAC, created in 1995, consists of up to three business representatives from each APEC economy and is a key component of APEC’s multi-stakeholder approach to trade and economic policies. ABAC meets throughout the year to discuss policy recommendations, undertakes activities to promote trade and investment, as well as sustainable and inclusive growth, and reports annually to APEC Leaders.</p>
<p>In her role as EVP and Chief Corporate Affairs Officer and a critical member of UPS’s Executive Leadership Team, Ms. Lane oversees the company’s Public Policy and Government Affairs, Communications, Sustainability, Community Relations Division, as well as The UPS Foundation. Ms. Lane has served in both the U.S. private and public sectors, with extensive experience in government, financial services, media and information-communications, and logistics, enabling her to represent the broad range of interests of U.S. businesses, including small-and women-owned businesses.</p>
<p>Prior to joining UPS, Ms. Lane served as Managing Director and Head of International Government Affairs at Citigroup and Vice President for Global Public Policy at Time Warner. In her government career, Ms. Lane served as a trade negotiator in the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative and as a diplomat in the U.S. Foreign Service. Ms. Lane currently serves as a member of the board of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees USA (UNHCR-USA) and the CDC Foundation, in addition to several other U.S. business associations and nonprofits, including the Atlantic Council, The Woodruff Arts Center, and the German-American Business Council.</p>
<p>For more than 30 years APEC has served as the premier economic platform for the United States to engage our regional partners on structural issues to advance an economic and trade architecture that opens markets, promotes high standards, and promotes sustainable and inclusive growth.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact the U.S. APEC Team at <a href="mailto:DOSAPEC@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DOSAPEC@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Counselor Chollet’s Travel to Moldova, Georgia, and the United Kingdom</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/counselor-chollets-travel-to-moldova-georgia-and-the-united-kingdom/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 14:06:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Counselor of the Department Derek Chollet will lead an interagency delegation to Chisinau, Moldova, from May 17 to 18. He will meet with Moldovan government officials to discuss the impact of the war in Ukraine on Moldova, continue discussions of our 30-year U.S.-Moldovan partnership under the framework of our Strategic Dialogue, and meet with refugees fleeing Russia’s war against Ukraine. Counselor Chollet’s visit will reinforce U.S. support for Moldova’s democracy, prosperity, and security.</p>
<p>Counselor Chollet will travel to Tbilisi, Georgia, from May 18 to 19 to for consultations with our Georgian partners about European security and democratic development. He will meet with government, opposition, and civil society representatives for discussions on Russia’s continuing occupation of parts of Georgia, on the Kremlin’s brutal war against Ukraine, and on how to advance the people of Georgia’s aspirations for a democratic, peaceful, prosperous, and Euro-Atlantic future.</p>
<p>Counselor Chollet will then travel to London, the United Kingdom on May 20 to meet with UK partners to discuss our joint efforts to address shared global priorities, including Euro-Atlantic security in light of Russia’s war of aggression on Ukraine, and our continued close cooperation in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Counselor of the Department Derek Chollet will lead an interagency delegation to Chisinau, Moldova, from May 17 to 18. He will meet with Moldovan government officials to discuss the impact of the war in Ukraine on Moldova, continue discussions of our 30-year U.S.-Moldovan partnership under the framework of our Strategic Dialogue, and meet with refugees fleeing Russia’s war against Ukraine. Counselor Chollet’s visit will reinforce U.S. support for Moldova’s democracy, prosperity, and security.</p>
<p>Counselor Chollet will travel to Tbilisi, Georgia, from May 18 to 19 to for consultations with our Georgian partners about European security and democratic development. He will meet with government, opposition, and civil society representatives for discussions on Russia’s continuing occupation of parts of Georgia, on the Kremlin’s brutal war against Ukraine, and on how to advance the people of Georgia’s aspirations for a democratic, peaceful, prosperous, and Euro-Atlantic future.</p>
<p>Counselor Chollet will then travel to London, the United Kingdom on May 20 to meet with UK partners to discuss our joint efforts to address shared global priorities, including Euro-Atlantic security in light of Russia’s war of aggression on Ukraine, and our continued close cooperation in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Senior Official for Public Diplomacy and Public Affairs Allen’s Travel to France</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/senior-official-for-public-diplomacy-and-public-affairs-allens-travel-to-france/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 13:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344617</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Senior Official for Public Diplomacy and Public Affairs Elizabeth Allen will travel to Paris, France May 17-18 to participate in the State Department’s Bureau of African Affairs Public Affairs Officer Workshop and engage with diplomatic, cultural, and multilateral partners and counterparts on key priorities. In addition to working together with our public affairs professionals to advance U.S. public diplomacy objectives in Africa, Senior Official Allen will also meet with a range of interlocutors in France, including French senior government officials and Ukrainian students, to discuss collaboration on cultural programming and efforts to counter disinformation.</p>
<p>For further information, please follow Senior Official Allen on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/UnderSecPD" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener">@UnderSecPD </a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Senior Official for Public Diplomacy and Public Affairs Elizabeth Allen will travel to Paris, France May 17-18 to participate in the State Department’s Bureau of African Affairs Public Affairs Officer Workshop and engage with diplomatic, cultural, and multilateral partners and counterparts on key priorities. In addition to working together with our public affairs professionals to advance U.S. public diplomacy objectives in Africa, Senior Official Allen will also meet with a range of interlocutors in France, including French senior government officials and Ukrainian students, to discuss collaboration on cultural programming and efforts to counter disinformation.</p>
<p>For further information, please follow Senior Official Allen on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/UnderSecPD" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener">@UnderSecPD </a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>31st UN Commission on Crime Prevention and Criminal Justice</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/31st-un-commission-on-crime-prevention-and-criminal-justice/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 12:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344580</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>A U.S. delegation will participate in the 31<sup>st</sup> UN Commission on Crime Prevention and Criminal Justice (CCPCJ) May 16-20 in Vienna, Austria to advance international cooperation on important anti-crime and criminal justice issues.  Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs Jim Walsh will lead the U.S. delegation, which includes representatives from the Department of State, Department of Justice, and Department of Homeland Security.</p>
<p>The 31<sup>st</sup> CCPCJ’s theme is centered on “strengthening the use of digital evidence in criminal justice and countering cybercrime, including the abuse and exploitation of minors in illegal activities with use of the Internet.”  The United States will speak on the CCPCJ’s thematic panel and host a side event on a multinational cybercrime operation.</p>
<p>For further information, contact <a href="mailto:INL-PAPD@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">INL-PAPD@state.gov</a> and follow INL on Twitter at @StateINL.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>A U.S. delegation will participate in the 31<sup>st</sup> UN Commission on Crime Prevention and Criminal Justice (CCPCJ) May 16-20 in Vienna, Austria to advance international cooperation on important anti-crime and criminal justice issues.  Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs Jim Walsh will lead the U.S. delegation, which includes representatives from the Department of State, Department of Justice, and Department of Homeland Security.</p>
<p>The 31<sup>st</sup> CCPCJ’s theme is centered on “strengthening the use of digital evidence in criminal justice and countering cybercrime, including the abuse and exploitation of minors in illegal activities with use of the Internet.”  The United States will speak on the CCPCJ’s thematic panel and host a side event on a multinational cybercrime operation.</p>
<p>For further information, contact <a href="mailto:INL-PAPD@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">INL-PAPD@state.gov</a> and follow INL on Twitter at @StateINL.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcoming the Resumption of Flights Between Sana’a and Amman</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/welcoming-the-resumption-of-flights-between-sanaa-and-amman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 12:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344577</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes today’s flight between Sana’a, Yemen, and Amman, Jordan, the first commercial flight from Sana’a since 2016.  We hope it will enable Yemenis to travel to see loved ones, seek medical care, and find respite from the conflict.</p>
<p>The United States appreciates the Republic of Yemen Government and the UN Special Envoy’s efforts to enable this flight and thanks the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia and the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan for their support.  We look forward to regular flights to and from Sana’a as called for in the UN-led truce.  We urge all parties to adhere to the terms of the truce and make progress on other steps to bring relief to Yemenis &#8211; including urgently opening roads to Taiz, the third largest city with hundreds of thousands of Yemenis in need of humanitarian assistance, and other contested areas, where Yemenis have suffered for far too long.</p>
<p>The United States encourages the parties to seize this opportunity to advance broader peace efforts for the sake of the Yemeni people.  The United States is committed to supporting Yemeni efforts to shape a brighter future for the country.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes today’s flight between Sana’a, Yemen, and Amman, Jordan, the first commercial flight from Sana’a since 2016.  We hope it will enable Yemenis to travel to see loved ones, seek medical care, and find respite from the conflict.</p>
<p>The United States appreciates the Republic of Yemen Government and the UN Special Envoy’s efforts to enable this flight and thanks the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia and the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan for their support.  We look forward to regular flights to and from Sana’a as called for in the UN-led truce.  We urge all parties to adhere to the terms of the truce and make progress on other steps to bring relief to Yemenis &#8211; including urgently opening roads to Taiz, the third largest city with hundreds of thousands of Yemenis in need of humanitarian assistance, and other contested areas, where Yemenis have suffered for far too long.</p>
<p>The United States encourages the parties to seize this opportunity to advance broader peace efforts for the sake of the Yemeni people.  The United States is committed to supporting Yemeni efforts to shape a brighter future for the country.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with French Foreign Minister Le Drian  </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-french-foreign-minister-le-drian-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 19:44:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344501</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian today in Paris-Saclay, France, ahead of the U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council ministerial dinner.  The two discussed issues of importance in the bilateral relationship, especially the urgent need to confront global food insecurity exacerbated by Russia’s unjust and unprovoked invasion of Ukraine.  The Secretary highlighted the Global Food Security Call to Action, which will take place at UN headquarters in New York City on May 18. The two also talked about efforts to achieve a mutual return to full JCPOA implementation with Iran.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian today in Paris-Saclay, France, ahead of the U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council ministerial dinner.  The two discussed issues of importance in the bilateral relationship, especially the urgent need to confront global food insecurity exacerbated by Russia’s unjust and unprovoked invasion of Ukraine.  The Secretary highlighted the Global Food Security Call to Action, which will take place at UN headquarters in New York City on May 18. The two also talked about efforts to achieve a mutual return to full JCPOA implementation with Iran.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Indonesian Foreign Minister Retno</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-indonesian-foreign-minister-retno/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 19:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344498</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met Friday with Indonesian Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi in Washington, D.C. The Secretary and the Foreign Minister discussed outcomes for the U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit and the second Global COVID-19 Summit, which Indonesia co-hosted.  The Secretary thanked Indonesia for its leadership on global health issues and highlighted how the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework will help create a more open, interconnected, and prosperous region. The two also discussed the importance of rights for women and girls in Afghanistan and how the United States and Indonesia can cooperate to strengthen our strategic partnership.  Finally, the Secretary and Foreign Minister Retno exchanged views on how our two countries can collaborate to ensure Indonesia has a successful G20 host year.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met Friday with Indonesian Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi in Washington, D.C. The Secretary and the Foreign Minister discussed outcomes for the U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit and the second Global COVID-19 Summit, which Indonesia co-hosted.  The Secretary thanked Indonesia for its leadership on global health issues and highlighted how the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework will help create a more open, interconnected, and prosperous region. The two also discussed the importance of rights for women and girls in Afghanistan and how the United States and Indonesia can cooperate to strengthen our strategic partnership.  Finally, the Secretary and Foreign Minister Retno exchanged views on how our two countries can collaborate to ensure Indonesia has a successful G20 host year.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
