<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 17:28:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with UK Foreign Secretary Truss</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-uk-foreign-secretary-truss-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 17:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330597</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Truss emphasized the continued importance of Transatlantic unity to support Ukraine and coordinate further swift, consequential actions against those who support President Putin’s war of choice on Ukraine. The two discussed the upcoming NATO Foreign Ministerial meeting and developing additional possible actions to ratchet up our response to Putin’s continued assault on the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Truss emphasized the continued importance of Transatlantic unity to support Ukraine and coordinate further swift, consequential actions against those who support President Putin’s war of choice on Ukraine. The two discussed the upcoming NATO Foreign Ministerial meeting and developing additional possible actions to ratchet up our response to Putin’s continued assault on the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Jamaican Prime Minister Andrew Holness Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-jamaican-prime-minister-andrew-holness-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 15:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330557</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong>ECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good morning, everyone.  It’s a great pleasure to welcome Prime Minister Holness to Washington, to the State Department.  Great to have you here.  We now 60 years of independence to celebrate, 60 years of our own diplomatic relationship, but especially the work that we’re doing together, today, that really is making a difference and making a difference in the lives of people in both our countries.</p>
<p>I really want to applaud, Mr. Prime Minister, your very strong economic leadership in Jamaica, and our partnership in the Caribbean, which I think is never been better, and that’s in large part due to your engagement and your leadership.  So, we’re very pleased to have you here to talk about many of the issues that bring us together in our own region, but also issues that are affecting people globally – from climate to COVID, to other things.  And we’re of course, very much forward to working together on the Summit of the Americas, which is coming up.</p>
<p>So thank you very much for being here.  I’m looking forward to a good conversation.  Welcome.</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER HOLNESS:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. President, for your warm – Mr. – I keep making this (inaudible).  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>I won’t tell my boss.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for the warm welcome for me and my delegation.  We have had several meetings, which have gone very well, including a meeting with the Vice President.</p>
<p>Jamaica and the United States have had a very long and strong relationship, particularly on the people-to-people side of things.  From government-to-government perspective, Jamaica and the United States have shared values and needs.  We’re both strong democracies.  And in an era where democracy is not necessarily (inaudible) state of nations, it is very important that democracies work together to strengthen their partnerships and to explore ways in which we can help each other.</p>
<p>I am pleased to report that Jamaica has made significant progress in its microeconomic development, particularly with its fiscal stability and sustainability and debt reduction.  We were able to do this with significant help and facilitation by the United States, and we are here to express our gratitude for that help.</p>
<p>We are now at a point where we can pivot to other areas of our economic and social development, our human capital development.  Jamaica has been a net exporter of talent to the United States, and I think our longstanding people-to-people relationship, with migration back and forth, would have been mutually beneficial.  But Jamaica is in a state now where its growth potential, its growth horizon, could potentially be limited by its human resource development.  And this is an area in which we want to explore ways in which we can further partnership.</p>
<p>The present global and geopolitical instabilities have highlighted the vulnerabilities of small island developing states.  We take great note of yesterday’s announcement by President Biden regarding the release of strategic reserves.  We hope that that will have a positive effect on the reduction of oil prices, and hopefully it will be beneficial to small island countries and developing states, like Jamaica, who are facing a really very difficult time just coming out of the pandemic and then being hit with these other geopolitical issues over which we have no control or (inaudible).  We have to also discuss matters of climate change.  We met in COP, and we had very good discussions as to how small island, developing countries could be assisted and facilitated.</p>
<p>And then there is always the issue of our national security and your security interests in the region.  We are in a region which is considered near third world, and the ability of states within the region to control their domain, control their maritime borders and their land borders, is critical.  Obviously, crime and violence, (inaudible) – these are areas in which we can have great discussions and great partnerships.</p>
<p>And then there is the issue of how do we convert our democracies into prosperous economies.  That is the real challenge.  How do we get our democracies to be prosperous for our people? And And I think for smaller and developing states like Jamaica, a small shift in policy – economic policy, could result in gains that are significant both for our economies, but for your economies as well.  Jamaica considers itself to be a friendly near-shore destination for investments and production capacity.  And I think that it would be in the U.S.’s interest to look at countries like Jamaica, to position strategic production capacity which could be beneficial for the stability of production chains and supply of goods and services.</p>
<p>So Mr. President – Mr. Vice President – (laughter).  Mr. Secretary.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>PARTICIPANT:</strong>  You’re almost there.  (Laughter.)  One more step.</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER HOLNESS:</strong>  We look forward to the Summit of the Americas, and Jamaica will be attending in full force.  And I must say that we were very happy to be invited and participate in the Summit for Democracy.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong>ECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good morning, everyone.  It’s a great pleasure to welcome Prime Minister Holness to Washington, to the State Department.  Great to have you here.  We now 60 years of independence to celebrate, 60 years of our own diplomatic relationship, but especially the work that we’re doing together, today, that really is making a difference and making a difference in the lives of people in both our countries.</p>
<p>I really want to applaud, Mr. Prime Minister, your very strong economic leadership in Jamaica, and our partnership in the Caribbean, which I think is never been better, and that’s in large part due to your engagement and your leadership.  So, we’re very pleased to have you here to talk about many of the issues that bring us together in our own region, but also issues that are affecting people globally – from climate to COVID, to other things.  And we’re of course, very much forward to working together on the Summit of the Americas, which is coming up.</p>
<p>So thank you very much for being here.  I’m looking forward to a good conversation.  Welcome.</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER HOLNESS:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. President, for your warm – Mr. – I keep making this (inaudible).  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>I won’t tell my boss.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for the warm welcome for me and my delegation.  We have had several meetings, which have gone very well, including a meeting with the Vice President.</p>
<p>Jamaica and the United States have had a very long and strong relationship, particularly on the people-to-people side of things.  From government-to-government perspective, Jamaica and the United States have shared values and needs.  We’re both strong democracies.  And in an era where democracy is not necessarily (inaudible) state of nations, it is very important that democracies work together to strengthen their partnerships and to explore ways in which we can help each other.</p>
<p>I am pleased to report that Jamaica has made significant progress in its microeconomic development, particularly with its fiscal stability and sustainability and debt reduction.  We were able to do this with significant help and facilitation by the United States, and we are here to express our gratitude for that help.</p>
<p>We are now at a point where we can pivot to other areas of our economic and social development, our human capital development.  Jamaica has been a net exporter of talent to the United States, and I think our longstanding people-to-people relationship, with migration back and forth, would have been mutually beneficial.  But Jamaica is in a state now where its growth potential, its growth horizon, could potentially be limited by its human resource development.  And this is an area in which we want to explore ways in which we can further partnership.</p>
<p>The present global and geopolitical instabilities have highlighted the vulnerabilities of small island developing states.  We take great note of yesterday’s announcement by President Biden regarding the release of strategic reserves.  We hope that that will have a positive effect on the reduction of oil prices, and hopefully it will be beneficial to small island countries and developing states, like Jamaica, who are facing a really very difficult time just coming out of the pandemic and then being hit with these other geopolitical issues over which we have no control or (inaudible).  We have to also discuss matters of climate change.  We met in COP, and we had very good discussions as to how small island, developing countries could be assisted and facilitated.</p>
<p>And then there is always the issue of our national security and your security interests in the region.  We are in a region which is considered near third world, and the ability of states within the region to control their domain, control their maritime borders and their land borders, is critical.  Obviously, crime and violence, (inaudible) – these are areas in which we can have great discussions and great partnerships.</p>
<p>And then there is the issue of how do we convert our democracies into prosperous economies.  That is the real challenge.  How do we get our democracies to be prosperous for our people? And And I think for smaller and developing states like Jamaica, a small shift in policy – economic policy, could result in gains that are significant both for our economies, but for your economies as well.  Jamaica considers itself to be a friendly near-shore destination for investments and production capacity.  And I think that it would be in the U.S.’s interest to look at countries like Jamaica, to position strategic production capacity which could be beneficial for the stability of production chains and supply of goods and services.</p>
<p>So Mr. President – Mr. Vice President – (laughter).  Mr. Secretary.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>PARTICIPANT:</strong>  You’re almost there.  (Laughter.)  One more step.</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER HOLNESS:</strong>  We look forward to the Summit of the Americas, and Jamaica will be attending in full force.  And I must say that we were very happy to be invited and participate in the Summit for Democracy.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Recognizing National Arab American Heritage Month</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/recognizing-national-arab-american-heritage-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 15:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>This month, we recognize National Arab American Heritage Month and honor the contributions of this diverse community to America. Immigrants with origins from the Arab world have been arriving to the United States since before our country’s independence and have contributed to our nation’s advancements in science, business, technology, foreign policy, and national security. The litany is long and includes Private Nathan Badeen, a Syrian immigrant who fought and gave his life during the American Revolution. At the State Department, we recognize tremendous diplomats such as Ambassador Philip Habib, former Under Secretary for Political Affairs, who played a prominent role in the Vietnam peace talks resulting in the 1973 Paris Peace Accords and later successfully pursued a ceasefire in Lebanon. We also recognize Ambassador Selwa “Lucky” Roosevelt, who served the President and Secretary of State as the Chief of Protocol of the United States from 1982-1989, nearly 7 years and longer than anyone else prior. The Department is fortunate to have had these and so many other talented Arab American colleagues, who strive every day to protect and promote the interests and values of the American people, while representing the United States to the world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>This month, we recognize National Arab American Heritage Month and honor the contributions of this diverse community to America. Immigrants with origins from the Arab world have been arriving to the United States since before our country’s independence and have contributed to our nation’s advancements in science, business, technology, foreign policy, and national security. The litany is long and includes Private Nathan Badeen, a Syrian immigrant who fought and gave his life during the American Revolution. At the State Department, we recognize tremendous diplomats such as Ambassador Philip Habib, former Under Secretary for Political Affairs, who played a prominent role in the Vietnam peace talks resulting in the 1973 Paris Peace Accords and later successfully pursued a ceasefire in Lebanon. We also recognize Ambassador Selwa “Lucky” Roosevelt, who served the President and Secretary of State as the Chief of Protocol of the United States from 1982-1989, nearly 7 years and longer than anyone else prior. The Department is fortunate to have had these and so many other talented Arab American colleagues, who strive every day to protect and promote the interests and values of the American people, while representing the United States to the world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability: Priority Countries and Region</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-u-s-strategy-to-prevent-conflict-and-promote-stability-priority-countries-and-region/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 13:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330519</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is being released jointly by the U.S. Department of State, the U.S. Department of the Treasury, the U.S. Department of Defense, and the U.S. Agency for International Development.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The U.S. Government is moving forward in the spirit of partnership with four countries and a regional grouping of countries to implement the ten-year U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.  This represents an important milestone and next step in the realization of the goals of the landmark Global Fragility Act, which continues to enjoy strong bipartisan Congressional support for innovative efforts to foster a more peaceful and stable world.  In light of the horrific events unfolding in Ukraine caused by Putin’s unprovoked and brutal war, the United States reaffirms its commitment to strengthen global resiliency and democratic renewal, and promote peaceful, self-reliant nations that become U.S. economic and security partners.</p>
<p>Our partner countries under the Strategy include Haiti, Libya, Mozambique, Papua New Guinea, and a grouping of Coastal West African countries comprised of Benin, Côte d’Ivoire, Ghana, Guinea, and Togo.  Each collaboration presents a unique opportunity to leverage lessons learned from decades of U.S. involvement overseas, to enhance the way the U.S. Government engages in challenging environments, and to jointly build resilience against political, economic, and natural shocks.</p>
<p>The U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability outlines a ten-year, whole-of-government effort to foster peace and long-term stability through integrated diplomacy, development, and security-sector engagement.  The Strategy builds upon and strengthens the work done to implement the U.S. Strategy on Women, Peace, and Security, the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act, and ongoing efforts to prevent and counter violent extremism.  It will leverage and advance other priorities, such as to promote democracy, good governance, and respect for human rights; advance gender equality; counter corruption; reduce the risks of the climate crisis; and bring an end to the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>The Strategy’s flexible approach is designed to take into account and address the underlying causes of violence and instability before conflicts and crises can break out or deteriorate.  The Strategy seeks to tailor our shared approach to the unique circumstances of each local and regional context, and to elevate local voices to jointly seek on-the-ground solutions to prevent conflict.  The United States will take a long-term view, working closely with like-minded and committed local partners.  Pursuant to the Strategy, we will support stabilization in areas where violence impedes development and threatens U.S. and partner strategic interests.  These efforts will improve lives and livelihoods in the process.</p>
<p>Our work is rooted in a deep and abiding commitment to put diplomacy and shared values first.  Success will require strong leadership, patience, creativity, and a constructive relationship with our international and local partners.  Peacebuilding and conflict prevention are needed now more than ever, and the United States looks forward to working with others to create a more peaceful world.</p>
<p>The full Strategy can be viewed at <a href="https://www.state.gov/stability-strategy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.state.gov/stability-strategy/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1648905471357000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3lbRpBvdN7fpQzGLzjFm3l">https://www.state.gov/<wbr />stability-strategy/</a>.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p>FOR MORE INFORMATION, MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT <a href="mailto:CSOPublicAffairs1@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSOPublicAffairs1@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is being released jointly by the U.S. Department of State, the U.S. Department of the Treasury, the U.S. Department of Defense, and the U.S. Agency for International Development.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The U.S. Government is moving forward in the spirit of partnership with four countries and a regional grouping of countries to implement the ten-year U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.  This represents an important milestone and next step in the realization of the goals of the landmark Global Fragility Act, which continues to enjoy strong bipartisan Congressional support for innovative efforts to foster a more peaceful and stable world.  In light of the horrific events unfolding in Ukraine caused by Putin’s unprovoked and brutal war, the United States reaffirms its commitment to strengthen global resiliency and democratic renewal, and promote peaceful, self-reliant nations that become U.S. economic and security partners.</p>
<p>Our partner countries under the Strategy include Haiti, Libya, Mozambique, Papua New Guinea, and a grouping of Coastal West African countries comprised of Benin, Côte d’Ivoire, Ghana, Guinea, and Togo.  Each collaboration presents a unique opportunity to leverage lessons learned from decades of U.S. involvement overseas, to enhance the way the U.S. Government engages in challenging environments, and to jointly build resilience against political, economic, and natural shocks.</p>
<p>The U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability outlines a ten-year, whole-of-government effort to foster peace and long-term stability through integrated diplomacy, development, and security-sector engagement.  The Strategy builds upon and strengthens the work done to implement the U.S. Strategy on Women, Peace, and Security, the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act, and ongoing efforts to prevent and counter violent extremism.  It will leverage and advance other priorities, such as to promote democracy, good governance, and respect for human rights; advance gender equality; counter corruption; reduce the risks of the climate crisis; and bring an end to the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>The Strategy’s flexible approach is designed to take into account and address the underlying causes of violence and instability before conflicts and crises can break out or deteriorate.  The Strategy seeks to tailor our shared approach to the unique circumstances of each local and regional context, and to elevate local voices to jointly seek on-the-ground solutions to prevent conflict.  The United States will take a long-term view, working closely with like-minded and committed local partners.  Pursuant to the Strategy, we will support stabilization in areas where violence impedes development and threatens U.S. and partner strategic interests.  These efforts will improve lives and livelihoods in the process.</p>
<p>Our work is rooted in a deep and abiding commitment to put diplomacy and shared values first.  Success will require strong leadership, patience, creativity, and a constructive relationship with our international and local partners.  Peacebuilding and conflict prevention are needed now more than ever, and the United States looks forward to working with others to create a more peaceful world.</p>
<p>The full Strategy can be viewed at <a href="https://www.state.gov/stability-strategy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.state.gov/stability-strategy/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1648905471357000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3lbRpBvdN7fpQzGLzjFm3l">https://www.state.gov/<wbr />stability-strategy/</a>.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p>FOR MORE INFORMATION, MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT <a href="mailto:CSOPublicAffairs1@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSOPublicAffairs1@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States-Kazakhstan Open Skies Air Transport Agreement Enters into Force</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-kazakhstan-open-skies-air-transport-agreement-enters-into-force/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 13:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330507</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S.-Kazakhstan Air Transport Agreement signed on December 30, 2019, has entered into force.  This bilateral Agreement establishes a modern civil aviation relationship with Kazakhstan consistent with U.S. Open Skies international aviation policy and with U.S. commitments to high standards of aviation safety and security.  The Agreement includes provisions that allow for unrestricted capacity and frequency of services, open route rights, a liberal charter regime, and open code-sharing opportunities.</p>
<p>This Agreement between the United States and Kazakhstan is also a step forward in liberalizing the international civil aviation sector in Central Asia.  It will further expand our strong economic and commercial partnership; promote people-to-people ties; and create new opportunities for airlines, travel companies, and customers.  Air carriers can provide more affordable, convenient, and efficient air services to travelers and shippers, which in turn promotes tourism and commerce.</p>
<p>Information on U.S. aviation policy and our Open Skies air transport agreements is available on the Department of State’s website here: <a href="https://www.state.gov/civil-air-transport-agreements" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">https://www.state.gov/civil-air-transport-agreements//</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S.-Kazakhstan Air Transport Agreement signed on December 30, 2019, has entered into force.  This bilateral Agreement establishes a modern civil aviation relationship with Kazakhstan consistent with U.S. Open Skies international aviation policy and with U.S. commitments to high standards of aviation safety and security.  The Agreement includes provisions that allow for unrestricted capacity and frequency of services, open route rights, a liberal charter regime, and open code-sharing opportunities.</p>
<p>This Agreement between the United States and Kazakhstan is also a step forward in liberalizing the international civil aviation sector in Central Asia.  It will further expand our strong economic and commercial partnership; promote people-to-people ties; and create new opportunities for airlines, travel companies, and customers.  Air carriers can provide more affordable, convenient, and efficient air services to travelers and shippers, which in turn promotes tourism and commerce.</p>
<p>Information on U.S. aviation policy and our Open Skies air transport agreements is available on the Department of State’s website here: <a href="https://www.state.gov/civil-air-transport-agreements" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">https://www.state.gov/civil-air-transport-agreements//</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Spirit of Partnership:  Implementing the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-spirit-of-partnership-implementing-the-u-s-strategy-to-prevent-conflict-and-promote-stability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 13:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330504</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is committed to strengthening global resiliency and democratic renewal, and promoting peaceful, self-reliant nations that become strong economic and security partners capable of addressing shared challenges.  To that end, the U.S. Government is moving forward in the spirit of partnership with Haiti, Libya, Mozambique, Papua New Guinea, and five countries in the Coastal West Africa region (Benin, Côte d’Ivoire, Ghana, Guinea, and Togo) to implement the ten-year U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.</p>
<p>Along with our friends and allies and the wider international community, we are facing destabilizing transnational challenges, which disrupt ways of life, economies, and whole societies.  Democratic governance and respect for human rights are increasingly under threat as violent extremists and practitioners of oppression assert their authoritarian will through coercion and violence.  Through this Strategy, we will confront these negative global trends and create new models for broader cooperation, grounded in mutual accountability and enduring stability.</p>
<p>We are fully committed to successful implementation of the Strategy and look forward to working together with the selected countries to create and implement long-term, locally-led plans to build resilience, strengthen the roots of stability, and prevent conflict.  We will factor in the sometimes difficult lessons learned from decades of U.S. involvement in stabilization efforts and apply them to how we engage through our new approach.</p>
<p>The State Department will lead this whole-of-government Strategy to align U.S. capabilities in diplomacy, development, and the security sector.  Working closely with in-country partners, businesses, and civil society organizations at the national and local levels, we will shape a common purpose to harness all the tools at our disposal in support of the Strategy, through our Embassies overseas, our country and technical experts in Washington, and with integrated and intentional planning and monitoring, evaluation, and learning across the U.S. Government.</p>
<p>I am grateful to the U.S. Congress for its passage of the landmark bipartisan Global Fragility Act that underpins this Strategy and demands a fundamental shift in how we work to prevent conflict globally.  I also appreciate those in civil society and expert communities who advocated for the Act and will be crucial to help us turn it into action.  Thanks to all of these efforts, we now have an ambitious framework for engaging creatively with our global partners to anticipate and prevent conflict and promote stability.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is committed to strengthening global resiliency and democratic renewal, and promoting peaceful, self-reliant nations that become strong economic and security partners capable of addressing shared challenges.  To that end, the U.S. Government is moving forward in the spirit of partnership with Haiti, Libya, Mozambique, Papua New Guinea, and five countries in the Coastal West Africa region (Benin, Côte d’Ivoire, Ghana, Guinea, and Togo) to implement the ten-year U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.</p>
<p>Along with our friends and allies and the wider international community, we are facing destabilizing transnational challenges, which disrupt ways of life, economies, and whole societies.  Democratic governance and respect for human rights are increasingly under threat as violent extremists and practitioners of oppression assert their authoritarian will through coercion and violence.  Through this Strategy, we will confront these negative global trends and create new models for broader cooperation, grounded in mutual accountability and enduring stability.</p>
<p>We are fully committed to successful implementation of the Strategy and look forward to working together with the selected countries to create and implement long-term, locally-led plans to build resilience, strengthen the roots of stability, and prevent conflict.  We will factor in the sometimes difficult lessons learned from decades of U.S. involvement in stabilization efforts and apply them to how we engage through our new approach.</p>
<p>The State Department will lead this whole-of-government Strategy to align U.S. capabilities in diplomacy, development, and the security sector.  Working closely with in-country partners, businesses, and civil society organizations at the national and local levels, we will shape a common purpose to harness all the tools at our disposal in support of the Strategy, through our Embassies overseas, our country and technical experts in Washington, and with integrated and intentional planning and monitoring, evaluation, and learning across the U.S. Government.</p>
<p>I am grateful to the U.S. Congress for its passage of the landmark bipartisan Global Fragility Act that underpins this Strategy and demands a fundamental shift in how we work to prevent conflict globally.  I also appreciate those in civil society and expert communities who advocated for the Act and will be crucial to help us turn it into action.  Thanks to all of these efforts, we now have an ambitious framework for engaging creatively with our global partners to anticipate and prevent conflict and promote stability.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Omani Foreign Minister Al-Busaidi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-omani-foreign-minister-al-busaidi-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 21:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330385</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Omani Foreign Minister Sayyid Badr al-Busaidi. The Secretary thanked Oman for its support on a range of issues and especially on Yemen.  The Secretary encouraged further efforts to build support for a truce leading to a ceasefire in Yemen. The UN truce proposal could serve as a first step towards a comprehensive ceasefire and a new, more inclusive political process.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Omani Foreign Minister Sayyid Badr al-Busaidi. The Secretary thanked Oman for its support on a range of issues and especially on Yemen.  The Secretary encouraged further efforts to build support for a truce leading to a ceasefire in Yemen. The UN truce proposal could serve as a first step towards a comprehensive ceasefire and a new, more inclusive political process.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement from The Working Group on Resettlement to Showcase U.S. Resettlement Programs Nationally and in Colorado</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-from-the-working-group-on-resettlement-to-showcase-u-s-resettlement-programs-nationally-and-in-colorado/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 20:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330342</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On Tuesday, March 29, representatives from the United States and nine other governments, alongside additional non-governmental organizations from the United States and other countries, the UN High Commissioner for Refugees, local government, and academia convened a three-day workshop to share best practices and innovations in refugee resettlement.</p>
<p>This Working Group on Resettlement is being held in Denver, Colorado to showcase U.S. resettlement programs locally and nationally that assist newly arrived refugees to integrate into U.S. communities. The Working Group will highlight the process of reception and integration of refugees, the strong partnerships between federal, state, and local governments, the critical role played by the non-governmental sector in service delivery, and the recent overwhelming response from private citizens to help support the large numbers of Afghans and other refugees being assisted throughout the United States.</p>
<p>Successful refugee resettlement would not be possible without the support of local communities; faith-based organizations; local and state governments; and congressional offices.  We are grateful for the hospitality and welcome that the people of Denver and Colorado more broadly have provided to us this week, as well as the generous welcome communities across the United States provide to refugees who have fled persecution and are making a new life for themselves and their families.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On Tuesday, March 29, representatives from the United States and nine other governments, alongside additional non-governmental organizations from the United States and other countries, the UN High Commissioner for Refugees, local government, and academia convened a three-day workshop to share best practices and innovations in refugee resettlement.</p>
<p>This Working Group on Resettlement is being held in Denver, Colorado to showcase U.S. resettlement programs locally and nationally that assist newly arrived refugees to integrate into U.S. communities. The Working Group will highlight the process of reception and integration of refugees, the strong partnerships between federal, state, and local governments, the critical role played by the non-governmental sector in service delivery, and the recent overwhelming response from private citizens to help support the large numbers of Afghans and other refugees being assisted throughout the United States.</p>
<p>Successful refugee resettlement would not be possible without the support of local communities; faith-based organizations; local and state governments; and congressional offices.  We are grateful for the hospitality and welcome that the people of Denver and Colorado more broadly have provided to us this week, as well as the generous welcome communities across the United States provide to refugees who have fled persecution and are making a new life for themselves and their families.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Additional Sanctions on Russia’s Technology Companies and Cyber Actors</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/additional-sanctions-on-russias-technology-companies-and-cyber-actors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 15:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330131</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States will continue to impose severe costs on the Russian Federation in response to President Putin’s illegal war.  Today, we are targeting entities and individuals in our efforts to shut down the Kremlin’s sanctions evasion networks, which play an important role in the Russian Federation’s ability to continue its unconscionable war on the citizens of Ukraine.  This follows our March 15 and March 24 designations of individuals and companies in Russia’s defense-industrial base that are directly supporting Putin’s war machine.</p>
<p>Today, the United States is designating 21 entities and 13 individuals.  Of those being designated, 10 of those individuals and 17 entities are involved in sanctions evasion networks to procure of western technology.  These designations will further impede Russia’s access to western technology and the international financial system.  We will continue to target President Putin’s war machine with sanctions from every angle, until this senseless war of choice is over.  The Russian Federation not only continues to violate the sovereignty of Ukraine with its attacks, but it is escalating the devastation of population centers, including schools, hospitals, residential areas, and places where civilians are taking shelter from the Russian bombardment.</p>
<p>The United States is also designating three individuals for their involvement in malicious cyber activities, one of whom the Department of Justice <a class="external-link" href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/four-russian-government-employees-charged-two-historical-hacking-campaigns-targeting-critical" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">indicted</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> last week.  The United States will continue to hold President Putin’s cyber actors to account for disruptive, destructive, or otherwise destabilizing cyber activity targeting the United States and its allies and partners.</p>
<p>In addition to the sanctions imposed today, the Department of the Treasury is also expanding its Russia sanctions authorities.  The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with me, identified the aerospace, marine, and electronics sectors of the Russian Federation economy pursuant to section 1(a)(i) of Executive Order 14024.  This allows for sanctions to be imposed on any individual or entity determined to operate or have operated in any of those sectors and provides an expanded ability to swiftly impose additional economic costs on Russia for its war of choice in Ukraine.</p>
<p>These actions demonstrate our resolve to hold the Russian Federation accountable for its aggression against Ukraine and commitment to take further actions against persons supporting evasion of the sanctions that the United States and our allies and partners have put in place.  We will use all authorities at our disposal to enforce sanctions, expose and identify malicious actors, and promote accountability for President Putin’s war of choice.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0692" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States will continue to impose severe costs on the Russian Federation in response to President Putin’s illegal war.  Today, we are targeting entities and individuals in our efforts to shut down the Kremlin’s sanctions evasion networks, which play an important role in the Russian Federation’s ability to continue its unconscionable war on the citizens of Ukraine.  This follows our March 15 and March 24 designations of individuals and companies in Russia’s defense-industrial base that are directly supporting Putin’s war machine.</p>
<p>Today, the United States is designating 21 entities and 13 individuals.  Of those being designated, 10 of those individuals and 17 entities are involved in sanctions evasion networks to procure of western technology.  These designations will further impede Russia’s access to western technology and the international financial system.  We will continue to target President Putin’s war machine with sanctions from every angle, until this senseless war of choice is over.  The Russian Federation not only continues to violate the sovereignty of Ukraine with its attacks, but it is escalating the devastation of population centers, including schools, hospitals, residential areas, and places where civilians are taking shelter from the Russian bombardment.</p>
<p>The United States is also designating three individuals for their involvement in malicious cyber activities, one of whom the Department of Justice <a class="external-link" href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/four-russian-government-employees-charged-two-historical-hacking-campaigns-targeting-critical" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">indicted</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> last week.  The United States will continue to hold President Putin’s cyber actors to account for disruptive, destructive, or otherwise destabilizing cyber activity targeting the United States and its allies and partners.</p>
<p>In addition to the sanctions imposed today, the Department of the Treasury is also expanding its Russia sanctions authorities.  The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with me, identified the aerospace, marine, and electronics sectors of the Russian Federation economy pursuant to section 1(a)(i) of Executive Order 14024.  This allows for sanctions to be imposed on any individual or entity determined to operate or have operated in any of those sectors and provides an expanded ability to swiftly impose additional economic costs on Russia for its war of choice in Ukraine.</p>
<p>These actions demonstrate our resolve to hold the Russian Federation accountable for its aggression against Ukraine and commitment to take further actions against persons supporting evasion of the sanctions that the United States and our allies and partners have put in place.  We will use all authorities at our disposal to enforce sanctions, expose and identify malicious actors, and promote accountability for President Putin’s war of choice.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0692" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department of State Begins Construction on New U.S. Consulate General in Lagos, Nigeria</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/department-of-state-begins-construction-on-new-u-s-consulate-general-in-lagos-nigeria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 12:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330016</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><a href="https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Lagos_Nigeria_Embassy_Mockup.jpeg"><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-330335 aligncenter" src="https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Lagos_Nigeria_Embassy_Mockup.jpeg" alt="" width="100%" height="" srcset="https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Lagos_Nigeria_Embassy_Mockup.jpeg 2048w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Lagos_Nigeria_Embassy_Mockup-300x162.jpeg 300w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Lagos_Nigeria_Embassy_Mockup-1024x552.jpeg 1024w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Lagos_Nigeria_Embassy_Mockup-768x414.jpeg 768w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Lagos_Nigeria_Embassy_Mockup-1536x828.jpeg 1536w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Lagos_Nigeria_Embassy_Mockup-89x48.jpeg 89w" sizes="(max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px" /></a>At a historic groundbreaking ceremony highlighting the enduring bilateral friendship and partnership between the United States and Nigeria, Lagos State Governor Babajide Sanwo-Olu joined U.S. Ambassador Mary Beth Leonard and U.S. Consul General Claire Pierangelo on Thursday to officially mark the beginning of construction of a new, modern U.S. Consulate General in Lagos.</p>
<p>Located on a 12.2-acre site in the rapidly developing Eko Atlantic City on Victoria Island, the new U.S. Consulate General in Lagos will support diplomatic and commercial relations between the United States and Nigeria and will provide U.S. and Nigerian Consulate employees with a safe, secure, sustainable, and modern workplace.  The construction project will take approximately five years, with completion expected in 2027.<u></u></p>
<p>Ennead Architects LLP of New York is the design architect, Pernix Federal, LLC of Lombard, Illinois, is the design/build contractor, and EYP, Inc. of Albany, New York, is the architect of record.  A variety of energy efficiency strategies will be incorporated into the site and building design to address varied seasonal conditions and to significantly reduce energy demand.</p>
<p>The new Consulate construction project will directly benefit the Nigerian people.  Over the course of construction, an estimated $95 million will be invested in the local economy through local subcontractors, and suppliers.  Overall, the project will employ approximately 2,500 Nigerian citizens, including engineers, architects, artisans, construction workers, and administrative staff.</p>
<p>Since the start of the Department’s Capital Security Construction Program in 1999, OBO has completed 171 new diplomatic facilities.  OBO currently has more than 50 active projects either in the design phase or under construction worldwide.</p>
<p>OBO provides safe, secure, functional, and resilient facilities that represent the U.S. government to the host nation and that support U.S. diplomats in advancing U.S. foreign policy objectives abroad.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact Christine Foushee at <a href="mailto:FousheeCT@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FousheeCT@state.gov</a> or visit <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureaus-offices/bureau-of-overseas-buildings-operations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMzEuNTU3MTMwNTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi9vYm8ifQ.rldUgB_KO6f-3AX4NCpYY8zER6WflPP5QfHTEY106tc/s/2171565732/br/128923697670-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1648814508762000&amp;usg=AOvVaw11qwrV5fNNF1-covCwhM87">www.state.gov/obo</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><a href="https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Lagos_Nigeria_Embassy_Mockup.jpeg"><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-330335 aligncenter" src="https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Lagos_Nigeria_Embassy_Mockup.jpeg" alt="" width="100%" height="" srcset="https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Lagos_Nigeria_Embassy_Mockup.jpeg 2048w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Lagos_Nigeria_Embassy_Mockup-300x162.jpeg 300w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Lagos_Nigeria_Embassy_Mockup-1024x552.jpeg 1024w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Lagos_Nigeria_Embassy_Mockup-768x414.jpeg 768w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Lagos_Nigeria_Embassy_Mockup-1536x828.jpeg 1536w, https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Lagos_Nigeria_Embassy_Mockup-89x48.jpeg 89w" sizes="(max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px" /></a>At a historic groundbreaking ceremony highlighting the enduring bilateral friendship and partnership between the United States and Nigeria, Lagos State Governor Babajide Sanwo-Olu joined U.S. Ambassador Mary Beth Leonard and U.S. Consul General Claire Pierangelo on Thursday to officially mark the beginning of construction of a new, modern U.S. Consulate General in Lagos.</p>
<p>Located on a 12.2-acre site in the rapidly developing Eko Atlantic City on Victoria Island, the new U.S. Consulate General in Lagos will support diplomatic and commercial relations between the United States and Nigeria and will provide U.S. and Nigerian Consulate employees with a safe, secure, sustainable, and modern workplace.  The construction project will take approximately five years, with completion expected in 2027.<u></u></p>
<p>Ennead Architects LLP of New York is the design architect, Pernix Federal, LLC of Lombard, Illinois, is the design/build contractor, and EYP, Inc. of Albany, New York, is the architect of record.  A variety of energy efficiency strategies will be incorporated into the site and building design to address varied seasonal conditions and to significantly reduce energy demand.</p>
<p>The new Consulate construction project will directly benefit the Nigerian people.  Over the course of construction, an estimated $95 million will be invested in the local economy through local subcontractors, and suppliers.  Overall, the project will employ approximately 2,500 Nigerian citizens, including engineers, architects, artisans, construction workers, and administrative staff.</p>
<p>Since the start of the Department’s Capital Security Construction Program in 1999, OBO has completed 171 new diplomatic facilities.  OBO currently has more than 50 active projects either in the design phase or under construction worldwide.</p>
<p>OBO provides safe, secure, functional, and resilient facilities that represent the U.S. government to the host nation and that support U.S. diplomats in advancing U.S. foreign policy objectives abroad.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact Christine Foushee at <a href="mailto:FousheeCT@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FousheeCT@state.gov</a> or visit <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureaus-offices/bureau-of-overseas-buildings-operations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMzEuNTU3MTMwNTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi9vYm8ifQ.rldUgB_KO6f-3AX4NCpYY8zER6WflPP5QfHTEY106tc/s/2171565732/br/128923697670-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1648814508762000&amp;usg=AOvVaw11qwrV5fNNF1-covCwhM87">www.state.gov/obo</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
