<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 17:43:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The United States Welcomes the Appointment of Hans Grundberg as the New UN Special Envoy for Yemen</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-welcomes-the-appointment-of-hans-grundberg-as-the-new-un-special-envoy-for-yemen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 17:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268507</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the appointment of Hans Grundberg as the new UN Special Envoy for Yemen. Grundberg brings considerable expertise on Yemen and the region, and we look forward to working closely with him to advance a durable resolution to the conflict in Yemen.</p>
<p>Now is the time for peace. Seven years of war and instability have devastated Yemen’s economy and eroded even the most basic services, leading to one of the worst humanitarian crises in the world. There is unprecedented international and regional consensus on the need to end the Houthi offensive on Marib and other fighting, and on placing renewed emphasis on political talks to finally bring relief to the Yemeni people and allow them to determine a brighter future for their country.</p>
<p>The United States thanks former UN Special Envoy Martin Griffiths for his efforts to resolve the conflict in Yemen. We look forward to continuing to work with Griffiths in his new position as the Under-Secretary-General for Humanitarian Affairs and Emergency Relief Coordinator.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the appointment of Hans Grundberg as the new UN Special Envoy for Yemen. Grundberg brings considerable expertise on Yemen and the region, and we look forward to working closely with him to advance a durable resolution to the conflict in Yemen.</p>
<p>Now is the time for peace. Seven years of war and instability have devastated Yemen’s economy and eroded even the most basic services, leading to one of the worst humanitarian crises in the world. There is unprecedented international and regional consensus on the need to end the Houthi offensive on Marib and other fighting, and on placing renewed emphasis on political talks to finally bring relief to the Yemeni people and allow them to determine a brighter future for their country.</p>
<p>The United States thanks former UN Special Envoy Martin Griffiths for his efforts to resolve the conflict in Yemen. We look forward to continuing to work with Griffiths in his new position as the Under-Secretary-General for Humanitarian Affairs and Emergency Relief Coordinator.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marking U.S. Engagement with the Association of Southeast Asian Nations on Its 54th Anniversary</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/marking-u-s-engagement-with-the-association-of-southeast-asian-nations-on-its-54th-anniversary/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 15:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268443</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I am honored to congratulate the 10 member states of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) and the ASEAN Secretariat on the 54th anniversary of the organization’s founding on August 8.</p>
<p>U.S.-ASEAN engagement is now in its fifth decade as it continues to foster a more stable, prosperous, and peaceful region. The strategic partnership between the United States and ASEAN contributes to our shared vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific, with ASEAN and ASEAN-led mechanisms as a centerpiece of regional architecture.</p>
<p>This week I had the privilege to participate in the U.S-ASEAN, East Asia Summit (EAS), ASEAN Regional Forum (ARF), Mekong-U.S. Partnership, and Friends of the Mekong ministerial meetings. I value deeply the opportunity to interact with our friends at the ASEAN Secretariat, with the representatives from the nations that make up ASEAN, with other important regional stakeholders, and with partners and allies around the world interested in shaping a positive, peaceful and productive future for the ASEAN region.</p>
<p>At these meetings, and in this week’s U.S.-Indonesia Strategic Dialogue with Indonesian Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi, I reaffirmed the United States’ commitment to ASEAN and underscored the central role ASEAN has in our collective vision for a free and open Indo-Pacific. To that end, we look forward to additional fruitful engagement in the region when Vice President Harris travels to Singapore and Vietnam this month to continue to discuss our cooperation on pressing regional and international challenges as well as on deepening ties between the people of the United States and the people of the nations of Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>I also reaffirmed that the United States would continue to be partners with the countries of ASEAN in the fight against COVID-19. The United States has provided more than 23 million vaccine doses and over $158 million in health and humanitarian assistance to date to ASEAN members to support their response to the pandemic. We will also be there to support the region to build back better from the economic damage wrought by the pandemic by helping drive a green recovery and ensure readiness for future outbreaks. And we continue to be a champion for strong people-to-people ties between the combined one billion population between our countries, demonstrated through our ongoing support for the Young Southeast Asian Leaders Initiative (YSEALI) and other cultural, academic, and professional exchanges.</p>
<p>I congratulate ASEAN on its 54th anniversary and look forward to many more years of friendship and collaboration with the organization and the people of Southeast Asia.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I am honored to congratulate the 10 member states of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) and the ASEAN Secretariat on the 54th anniversary of the organization’s founding on August 8.</p>
<p>U.S.-ASEAN engagement is now in its fifth decade as it continues to foster a more stable, prosperous, and peaceful region. The strategic partnership between the United States and ASEAN contributes to our shared vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific, with ASEAN and ASEAN-led mechanisms as a centerpiece of regional architecture.</p>
<p>This week I had the privilege to participate in the U.S-ASEAN, East Asia Summit (EAS), ASEAN Regional Forum (ARF), Mekong-U.S. Partnership, and Friends of the Mekong ministerial meetings. I value deeply the opportunity to interact with our friends at the ASEAN Secretariat, with the representatives from the nations that make up ASEAN, with other important regional stakeholders, and with partners and allies around the world interested in shaping a positive, peaceful and productive future for the ASEAN region.</p>
<p>At these meetings, and in this week’s U.S.-Indonesia Strategic Dialogue with Indonesian Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi, I reaffirmed the United States’ commitment to ASEAN and underscored the central role ASEAN has in our collective vision for a free and open Indo-Pacific. To that end, we look forward to additional fruitful engagement in the region when Vice President Harris travels to Singapore and Vietnam this month to continue to discuss our cooperation on pressing regional and international challenges as well as on deepening ties between the people of the United States and the people of the nations of Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>I also reaffirmed that the United States would continue to be partners with the countries of ASEAN in the fight against COVID-19. The United States has provided more than 23 million vaccine doses and over $158 million in health and humanitarian assistance to date to ASEAN members to support their response to the pandemic. We will also be there to support the region to build back better from the economic damage wrought by the pandemic by helping drive a green recovery and ensure readiness for future outbreaks. And we continue to be a champion for strong people-to-people ties between the combined one billion population between our countries, demonstrated through our ongoing support for the Young Southeast Asian Leaders Initiative (YSEALI) and other cultural, academic, and professional exchanges.</p>
<p>I congratulate ASEAN on its 54th anniversary and look forward to many more years of friendship and collaboration with the organization and the people of Southeast Asia.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>G7 Foreign Ministers’ Statement on the MV Mercer Street Attack</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/g7-foreign-ministers-statement-on-the-mv-mercer-street-attack/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 15:16:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268436</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom and the United States of America and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom and the United States of America and the High Representative of the European Union stand united in our commitment to maritime security and the protection of commercial shipping. We condemn the unlawful attack committed on a merchant vessel off the coast of Oman on 29 July, which killed a British and a Romanian national. This was a deliberate and targeted attack, and a clear violation of international law. All available evidence clearly points to Iran. There is no justification for this attack.</p>
<p>Vessels must be allowed to navigate freely in accordance with international law. We will continue to do our utmost to protect all shipping, upon which the global economy depends, so that it is able to operate freely and without being threatened by irresponsible and violent acts.</p>
<p>Iran’s behaviour, alongside its support to proxy forces and non-state armed actors, threatens international peace and security. We call on Iran to stop all activities inconsistent with relevant UN Security Council resolutions, and call on all parties to play a constructive role in fostering regional stability and peace.</p>
<p><i>End Text.</i></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom and the United States of America and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom and the United States of America and the High Representative of the European Union stand united in our commitment to maritime security and the protection of commercial shipping. We condemn the unlawful attack committed on a merchant vessel off the coast of Oman on 29 July, which killed a British and a Romanian national. This was a deliberate and targeted attack, and a clear violation of international law. All available evidence clearly points to Iran. There is no justification for this attack.</p>
<p>Vessels must be allowed to navigate freely in accordance with international law. We will continue to do our utmost to protect all shipping, upon which the global economy depends, so that it is able to operate freely and without being threatened by irresponsible and violent acts.</p>
<p>Iran’s behaviour, alongside its support to proxy forces and non-state armed actors, threatens international peace and security. We call on Iran to stop all activities inconsistent with relevant UN Security Council resolutions, and call on all parties to play a constructive role in fostering regional stability and peace.</p>
<p><i>End Text.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States Restricts Visas of 50 Additional Nicaraguan Individuals Affiliated With Ortega-Murillo Regime</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-restricts-visas-of-50-additional-nicaraguan-individuals-affiliated-with-ortega-murillo-regime/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 15:14:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268433</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department of State has imposed visa restrictions on 50 immediate family members of Nicaraguan National Assembly representatives and Nicaraguan prosecutors and judges. As these actions demonstrate, the United States is committed to promoting broad accountability for anyone responsible for or benefiting from the Ortega-Murillo regime’s attacks on democratic institutions.</p>
<p>In these last two months alone, the regime has arrested 32 political opponents and pro-democracy actors, including seven presidential candidates, a vice-presidential candidate, student activists, private sector leaders, defense attorneys, and others. This includes the detention just this week of 27-year-old Berenice Quezada, a brave Nicaraguan who courageously stepped forward to run for vice president as an opposition candidate despite the increasing repression. Ortega and Murillo once again demonstrated that they are afraid of running against anyone who they feel might win the support of the Nicaraguan people.</p>
<p>In response, on July 12 the Secretary announced visa restrictions against 100 Nicaraguan legislators, judges, prosecutors, and family members of those officials under a visa restriction policy that applies to Nicaraguans believed to be responsible for, or complicit in, undermining democracy, including those with responsibility for, or complicity in, the suppression of peaceful protests or abuse of human rights, and the immediate family members of such persons. Today we are announcing visa restrictions against a further 50 individuals, all immediate family members of regime-affiliated officials who have directly contributed to measures adopted by the Government of Nicaragua that do not meet the conditions for transparent, free, and fair elections to which all OAS member states have committed under the Inter-American Democratic Charter.</p>
<p>As demonstrated by these visa actions and recent sanctions, the United States will continue to use diplomatic and economic tools to promote accountability for those who enable Ortega and Murillo’s repression.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department of State has imposed visa restrictions on 50 immediate family members of Nicaraguan National Assembly representatives and Nicaraguan prosecutors and judges. As these actions demonstrate, the United States is committed to promoting broad accountability for anyone responsible for or benefiting from the Ortega-Murillo regime’s attacks on democratic institutions.</p>
<p>In these last two months alone, the regime has arrested 32 political opponents and pro-democracy actors, including seven presidential candidates, a vice-presidential candidate, student activists, private sector leaders, defense attorneys, and others. This includes the detention just this week of 27-year-old Berenice Quezada, a brave Nicaraguan who courageously stepped forward to run for vice president as an opposition candidate despite the increasing repression. Ortega and Murillo once again demonstrated that they are afraid of running against anyone who they feel might win the support of the Nicaraguan people.</p>
<p>In response, on July 12 the Secretary announced visa restrictions against 100 Nicaraguan legislators, judges, prosecutors, and family members of those officials under a visa restriction policy that applies to Nicaraguans believed to be responsible for, or complicit in, undermining democracy, including those with responsibility for, or complicity in, the suppression of peaceful protests or abuse of human rights, and the immediate family members of such persons. Today we are announcing visa restrictions against a further 50 individuals, all immediate family members of regime-affiliated officials who have directly contributed to measures adopted by the Government of Nicaragua that do not meet the conditions for transparent, free, and fair elections to which all OAS member states have committed under the Inter-American Democratic Charter.</p>
<p>As demonstrated by these visa actions and recent sanctions, the United States will continue to use diplomatic and economic tools to promote accountability for those who enable Ortega and Murillo’s repression.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Participation in the ASEAN Regional Forum Foreign Ministers’ Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-participation-in-the-asean-regional-forum-foreign-ministers-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 15:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268430</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with the foreign ministers of the 26 ARF participating countries, the ASEAN Secretary General, and the EU High Commissioner at the 28th Annual ASEAN Regional Forum (ARF) Ministerial Meeting hosted by ASEAN Chair Brunei Darussalam.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken underscored the importance of democracy, transparency, and accountability in the Indo-Pacific. He outlined U.S. efforts to address the COVID-19 pandemic, including providing more than 500 million safe and effective vaccine doses to Gavi for distribution by COVAX and 80 million vaccines from the U.S. supply to help countries in need, including 23 million doses for the Indo-Pacific. Secretary Blinken highlighted that the social effects of the COVID-19 pandemic have had unique impacts on women and girls and voiced support for a gender-responsive approach to the pandemic. Secretary Blinken called on the PRC to abide by its obligations under the international law of the sea and cease its provocative behavior in the South China Sea. He raised serious concerns about ongoing human rights abuses in Tibet, Hong Kong, and Xinjiang.</p>
<p>The Secretary also noted deep concern with the rapid growth of the PRC’s nuclear arsenal which highlights how Beijing has sharply deviated from its decades-old nuclear strategy based on minimum deterrence. Secretary Blinken then joined other countries in calling for the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. The Secretary urged all ARF member states to press the military regime in Burma to end violence and support the people of Burma as they work to return to democratic governance.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with the foreign ministers of the 26 ARF participating countries, the ASEAN Secretary General, and the EU High Commissioner at the 28th Annual ASEAN Regional Forum (ARF) Ministerial Meeting hosted by ASEAN Chair Brunei Darussalam.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken underscored the importance of democracy, transparency, and accountability in the Indo-Pacific. He outlined U.S. efforts to address the COVID-19 pandemic, including providing more than 500 million safe and effective vaccine doses to Gavi for distribution by COVAX and 80 million vaccines from the U.S. supply to help countries in need, including 23 million doses for the Indo-Pacific. Secretary Blinken highlighted that the social effects of the COVID-19 pandemic have had unique impacts on women and girls and voiced support for a gender-responsive approach to the pandemic. Secretary Blinken called on the PRC to abide by its obligations under the international law of the sea and cease its provocative behavior in the South China Sea. He raised serious concerns about ongoing human rights abuses in Tibet, Hong Kong, and Xinjiang.</p>
<p>The Secretary also noted deep concern with the rapid growth of the PRC’s nuclear arsenal which highlights how Beijing has sharply deviated from its decades-old nuclear strategy based on minimum deterrence. Secretary Blinken then joined other countries in calling for the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. The Secretary urged all ARF member states to press the military regime in Burma to end violence and support the people of Burma as they work to return to democratic governance.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Japanese Foreign Minister Motegi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-japanese-foreign-minister-motegi-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 14:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268416</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Japanese Foreign Minister Motegi Toshimitsu. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Motegi reaffirmed the U.S.-Japan Alliance as the cornerstone of peace, security, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific and across the globe. The Secretary and the Foreign Minister discussed strengthening cooperation to address the pressing challenges of the 21st century, including the climate crisis. Secretary Blinken also thanked Foreign Minister Motegi for Japan’s commitment to hosting safe and secure Olympic and Paralympic games.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Japanese Foreign Minister Motegi Toshimitsu. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Motegi reaffirmed the U.S.-Japan Alliance as the cornerstone of peace, security, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific and across the globe. The Secretary and the Foreign Minister discussed strengthening cooperation to address the pressing challenges of the 21st century, including the climate crisis. Secretary Blinken also thanked Foreign Minister Motegi for Japan’s commitment to hosting safe and secure Olympic and Paralympic games.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Republic of Singapore National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/republic-of-singapore-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 13:17:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268374</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Singapore on the occasion of your National Day on August 9.</p>
<p>This year, the United States and Singapore celebrate 55 years of diplomatic relations.  Singapore is a longstanding partner and friend.  Our two countries’ close security, economic, and people-to-people ties lie at the heart of this enduring relationship and bring strength and stability to the United States, Singapore, and the entire Indo-Pacific region.  We look forward to strengthening this partnership and to deepening our cooperation on our shared interests and challenges for many more years to come.</p>
<p>Congratulations on your 56th anniversary and best wishes for a year filled with peace, prosperity, and happiness.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Singapore on the occasion of your National Day on August 9.</p>
<p>This year, the United States and Singapore celebrate 55 years of diplomatic relations.  Singapore is a longstanding partner and friend.  Our two countries’ close security, economic, and people-to-people ties lie at the heart of this enduring relationship and bring strength and stability to the United States, Singapore, and the entire Indo-Pacific region.  We look forward to strengthening this partnership and to deepening our cooperation on our shared interests and challenges for many more years to come.</p>
<p>Congratulations on your 56th anniversary and best wishes for a year filled with peace, prosperity, and happiness.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jamaica’s Independence Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/jamaicas-independence-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 12:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268360</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Jamaica as you celebrate your independence this August 6.</p>
<p>The United States and Jamaica share deep historical ties, an enduring friendship, and common values.  Our longstanding partnership enables us to work closely as we confront some of the most pressing challenges facing the Western Hemisphere, from the climate crisis to the COVID-19 pandemic.  Through initiatives such as the U.S.-Caribbean Resilience Partnership and the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative, we will work together to further our shared goals of economic prosperity, regional security, health, and disaster resilience, as well as advance democracy and human rights in the hemisphere.</p>
<p>We extend our congratulations and best wishes to Jamaica in your 59<sup>th</sup> year of independence.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Jamaica as you celebrate your independence this August 6.</p>
<p>The United States and Jamaica share deep historical ties, an enduring friendship, and common values.  Our longstanding partnership enables us to work closely as we confront some of the most pressing challenges facing the Western Hemisphere, from the climate crisis to the COVID-19 pandemic.  Through initiatives such as the U.S.-Caribbean Resilience Partnership and the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative, we will work together to further our shared goals of economic prosperity, regional security, health, and disaster resilience, as well as advance democracy and human rights in the hemisphere.</p>
<p>We extend our congratulations and best wishes to Jamaica in your 59<sup>th</sup> year of independence.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bolivia’s Independence Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/bolivias-independence-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 12:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">On behalf of the Government of the United States and the American people, I congratulate the people of Bolivia on the 196th anniversary of your independence.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The United States and Bolivia have long maintained important cultural and economic ties, and we have built our relationship on the democratic values our people share.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We have strengthened our sense of solidarity and the bonds between our countries in the face of the COVID-19 pandemic.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The United States provided approximately $7 million in support to the Bolivian health sector, including the recent donation of more than one million doses of the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine through COVAX.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We will continue to work together to overcome this global pandemic and accelerate our region’s economic recovery.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">On this anniversary of Bolivia’s independence, the United States expresses its respect for the Bolivian people’s commitment to democratic and participative values, including inclusion, freedom of expression, and the protection of human rights and due process for all, under the rule of law.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We continue to build on our close relationship with Bolivia and look forward to working together, realizing our shared goals of inclusive and equitable economic prosperity.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">On behalf of the Government of the United States and the American people, I congratulate the people of Bolivia on the 196th anniversary of your independence.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The United States and Bolivia have long maintained important cultural and economic ties, and we have built our relationship on the democratic values our people share.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We have strengthened our sense of solidarity and the bonds between our countries in the face of the COVID-19 pandemic.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The United States provided approximately $7 million in support to the Bolivian health sector, including the recent donation of more than one million doses of the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine through COVAX.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We will continue to work together to overcome this global pandemic and accelerate our region’s economic recovery.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">On this anniversary of Bolivia’s independence, the United States expresses its respect for the Bolivian people’s commitment to democratic and participative values, including inclusion, freedom of expression, and the protection of human rights and due process for all, under the rule of law.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We continue to build on our close relationship with Bolivia and look forward to working together, realizing our shared goals of inclusive and equitable economic prosperity.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken to Deliver Remarks on Domestic Renewal as a Foreign Policy Priority</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinken-to-deliver-remarks-on-domestic-renewal-as-a-foreign-policy-priority/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 12:09:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268357</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will deliver remarks on the importance of investing in the infrastructure of tomorrow here at home in order to promote U.S. national security and our ability to compete globally on Monday, August 9, 2021 at 2:00 p.m. at the University of Maryland’s A. James Clark School of Engineering in College Park, MD. He will make the case that what we do now in terms of our long-term domestic investments will cement for decades to come our global competitiveness, including vis-à-vis China and the rest of the world, and demonstrate that our democracy can deliver for our people. Prior to his speech, Secretary Blinken will tour the Advanced Fabrication Lab, a state-of-the-art 3D design and printing lab.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Secretary Blinken’s remarks and tour will be pooled press coverage only. The remarks will be live streamed on <a href="http://state.gov">www.state.gov</a>.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">For more information, please contact the Office of Press Relations at <a href="mailto:PAPressDuty@state.gov">PAPressDuty@state.gov</a>.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will deliver remarks on the importance of investing in the infrastructure of tomorrow here at home in order to promote U.S. national security and our ability to compete globally on Monday, August 9, 2021 at 2:00 p.m. at the University of Maryland’s A. James Clark School of Engineering in College Park, MD. He will make the case that what we do now in terms of our long-term domestic investments will cement for decades to come our global competitiveness, including vis-à-vis China and the rest of the world, and demonstrate that our democracy can deliver for our people. Prior to his speech, Secretary Blinken will tour the Advanced Fabrication Lab, a state-of-the-art 3D design and printing lab.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Secretary Blinken’s remarks and tour will be pooled press coverage only. The remarks will be live streamed on <a href="http://state.gov">www.state.gov</a>.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">For more information, please contact the Office of Press Relations at <a href="mailto:PAPressDuty@state.gov">PAPressDuty@state.gov</a>.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
