<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 16:59:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Japanese Foreign Minister Yoshimasa Hayashi Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-japanese-foreign-minister-yoshimasa-hayashi-before-their-meeting-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 16:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332622</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p>NATO Headquarters</p>
<p align="left"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a great pleasure to meet my friend, the foreign minister.  We’ve been together in all different parts of the world, but it’s particularly good to have colleagues from the Asia Pacific here at NATO.  We are building stronger ties between NATO and our Asia Pacific partners, starting with Japan.  And we also had Korea; we had Australia and New Zealand here today.  And this is something that will carry through to the summit in Madrid, building greater coherence, greater collaboration, greater cooperation between Europe and Asia, between NATO and Asia Pacific partners.</p>
<p>We’ll also have a chance to talk about so much of the work we’re doing together around the world, and also looking very much forward to President Biden and Prime Minister Kishida getting together and seeing each other.</p>
<p>So, Yogi, good to be with you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:  </b>Thank you very much (inaudible).  But it’s always nice to see you, Secretary Blinken.  And actually, as you mentioned, this is the – for Japanese foreign ministers to come to NATO, this is the first time.  So like you said, it’s very important facing those – Russian aggression against Ukraine, we have to strengthen our international cooperation.  And on the topic (inaudible) to us, the U.S.-Japan alliance, it’s very (inaudible).  So thank you very much again.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks, everyone.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p>NATO Headquarters</p>
<p align="left"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a great pleasure to meet my friend, the foreign minister.  We’ve been together in all different parts of the world, but it’s particularly good to have colleagues from the Asia Pacific here at NATO.  We are building stronger ties between NATO and our Asia Pacific partners, starting with Japan.  And we also had Korea; we had Australia and New Zealand here today.  And this is something that will carry through to the summit in Madrid, building greater coherence, greater collaboration, greater cooperation between Europe and Asia, between NATO and Asia Pacific partners.</p>
<p>We’ll also have a chance to talk about so much of the work we’re doing together around the world, and also looking very much forward to President Biden and Prime Minister Kishida getting together and seeing each other.</p>
<p>So, Yogi, good to be with you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:  </b>Thank you very much (inaudible).  But it’s always nice to see you, Secretary Blinken.  And actually, as you mentioned, this is the – for Japanese foreign ministers to come to NATO, this is the first time.  So like you said, it’s very important facing those – Russian aggression against Ukraine, we have to strengthen our international cooperation.  And on the topic (inaudible) to us, the U.S.-Japan alliance, it’s very (inaudible).  So thank you very much again.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks, everyone.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-ukrainian-foreign-minister-dmytro-kuleba-before-their-meeting-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 16:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332591</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p>NATO Headquarters</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s always a pleasure to be with my friend and colleague, Dmytro Kuleba.  It’s especially a pleasure to see him now, to see him in person, especially under the circumstances.  I just have to say, as we were saying in the NATO meeting that we just came from, Dmytro, your personal courage is emblematic of that of the Ukrainian people.  We have great admiration for you, for all of our Ukrainian friends in this incredibly difficult time.</p>
<p>But I think what you heard today from all of our allies and partners from the Asia-Pacific region as well was a tremendous sense of solidarity in support of Ukraine against Russia’s outrageous aggression, and doing everything that we can to continue not only to sustain our support to Ukraine, but to build on it; not only to continue the pressure that we’re exerting against Russia, but to build on it; and to see to it that Ukraine’s sovereignty and independence is fully asserted and protected in advance.</p>
<p>So there’s a lot of work that goes into that, but this was a very, very good opportunity to hear directly from you about your assessment of the situation on the ground, and then the work that we’re doing together between the United States and Ukraine but also amongst so many different countries that support Ukraine in this difficult moment.  So, good to see you, my friend.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER KULEBA:</strong>  Likewise.  We speak regularly, we meet regularly, and I appreciate that you and I can talk on literally any given moment when the need arises.  This is how a relationship between two real friends and strategic partners should evolve.</p>
<p>Ukraine is grateful to the United States for ironclad diplomatic and military support, and for the leadership in – of the United States in initiating, imposing, and enforcing sanctions against Russia.  I have told you once that the recipe of Ukrainian victory in this war – it’s the Ukrainian stamina plus Western weapons and sanctions against Russia.</p>
<p>And I am satisfied with the dynamics of our cooperation on weapons and on sanctions as well, but when it comes to sanction – to weapons – and this is the point that I made today to all allies – we have no doubts that in the end, Ukraine will get everything that it needs and will overcome all the reluctance and hesitation coming from some allies when it comes to specific weapons.  But the issue of timeline is crucial, and I’m looking forward to our conversation today to discuss the timeline of supplies of the weapons which are needed to defend Ukraine.</p>
<p>I would also like to thank you for reaching out to third countries who haven’t taken their firm stance on the Russian aggression against Ukraine, and for explaining to them not only what happened – what is happening, but also the global repercussions of the Russian aggression against my country.  It’s important to mobilize the entire world that stands for democracy and respect of the rule-based order.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you, everyone.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p>NATO Headquarters</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s always a pleasure to be with my friend and colleague, Dmytro Kuleba.  It’s especially a pleasure to see him now, to see him in person, especially under the circumstances.  I just have to say, as we were saying in the NATO meeting that we just came from, Dmytro, your personal courage is emblematic of that of the Ukrainian people.  We have great admiration for you, for all of our Ukrainian friends in this incredibly difficult time.</p>
<p>But I think what you heard today from all of our allies and partners from the Asia-Pacific region as well was a tremendous sense of solidarity in support of Ukraine against Russia’s outrageous aggression, and doing everything that we can to continue not only to sustain our support to Ukraine, but to build on it; not only to continue the pressure that we’re exerting against Russia, but to build on it; and to see to it that Ukraine’s sovereignty and independence is fully asserted and protected in advance.</p>
<p>So there’s a lot of work that goes into that, but this was a very, very good opportunity to hear directly from you about your assessment of the situation on the ground, and then the work that we’re doing together between the United States and Ukraine but also amongst so many different countries that support Ukraine in this difficult moment.  So, good to see you, my friend.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER KULEBA:</strong>  Likewise.  We speak regularly, we meet regularly, and I appreciate that you and I can talk on literally any given moment when the need arises.  This is how a relationship between two real friends and strategic partners should evolve.</p>
<p>Ukraine is grateful to the United States for ironclad diplomatic and military support, and for the leadership in – of the United States in initiating, imposing, and enforcing sanctions against Russia.  I have told you once that the recipe of Ukrainian victory in this war – it’s the Ukrainian stamina plus Western weapons and sanctions against Russia.</p>
<p>And I am satisfied with the dynamics of our cooperation on weapons and on sanctions as well, but when it comes to sanction – to weapons – and this is the point that I made today to all allies – we have no doubts that in the end, Ukraine will get everything that it needs and will overcome all the reluctance and hesitation coming from some allies when it comes to specific weapons.  But the issue of timeline is crucial, and I’m looking forward to our conversation today to discuss the timeline of supplies of the weapons which are needed to defend Ukraine.</p>
<p>I would also like to thank you for reaching out to third countries who haven’t taken their firm stance on the Russian aggression against Ukraine, and for explaining to them not only what happened – what is happening, but also the global repercussions of the Russian aggression against my country.  It’s important to mobilize the entire world that stands for democracy and respect of the rule-based order.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you, everyone.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Press Announcement</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-india-22-ministerial-press-announcement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 12:41:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332450</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">On April 11, Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken and Secretary of Defense Lloyd J. Austin III will welcome Minister of External Affairs Dr. S. Jaishankar and Indian Minister of Defense Rajnath Singh to Washington, D.C. for the fourth U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue.  This year’s event will celebrate 75 years of diplomatic relations and reaffirm the importance of the U.S.-India Comprehensive and Global Strategic Partnership in ensuring international peace and security. It will reaffirm our shared commitment to a free, open, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p align="left">The 2+2 Ministerial is an important opportunity to advance our shared objectives across the breadth of the U.S.-India Strategic Partnership, including enhancing our people-to-people ties and education cooperation, building diverse, resilient supply chains for critical and emerging technology, scaling up our climate action and public health cooperation, and developing a trade and investment partnership to increase prosperity for working families in both countries.  It is also a chance to highlight the growing Major Defense Partnership between the United States and India.  The relationship between the world’s largest democracies is built on a foundation of common values and resilient democratic institutions, and the shared Indo-Pacific interests of a rules-based international order that safeguards sovereignty and territorial integrity, upholds human rights, and expands regional and global peace and prosperity.</p>
<p align="left">For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:SCA-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SCA-Press@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">On April 11, Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken and Secretary of Defense Lloyd J. Austin III will welcome Minister of External Affairs Dr. S. Jaishankar and Indian Minister of Defense Rajnath Singh to Washington, D.C. for the fourth U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue.  This year’s event will celebrate 75 years of diplomatic relations and reaffirm the importance of the U.S.-India Comprehensive and Global Strategic Partnership in ensuring international peace and security. It will reaffirm our shared commitment to a free, open, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p align="left">The 2+2 Ministerial is an important opportunity to advance our shared objectives across the breadth of the U.S.-India Strategic Partnership, including enhancing our people-to-people ties and education cooperation, building diverse, resilient supply chains for critical and emerging technology, scaling up our climate action and public health cooperation, and developing a trade and investment partnership to increase prosperity for working families in both countries.  It is also a chance to highlight the growing Major Defense Partnership between the United States and India.  The relationship between the world’s largest democracies is built on a foundation of common values and resilient democratic institutions, and the shared Indo-Pacific interests of a rules-based international order that safeguards sovereignty and territorial integrity, upholds human rights, and expands regional and global peace and prosperity.</p>
<p align="left">For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:SCA-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SCA-Press@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>G7 Foreign Ministers’ Statement on Russia’s War of Aggression Against Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/g7-foreign-ministers-statement-on-russias-war-of-aggression-against-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 11:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p align="left"><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p align="left">We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union, condemn in the strongest terms the atrocities committed by the Russian armed forces in Bucha and a number of other Ukrainian towns. Haunting images of civilian deaths, victims of torture, and apparent executions, as well as reports of sexual violence and destruction of civilian infrastructure show the true face of Russia’s brutal war of aggression against Ukraine and its people. The massacres in the town of Bucha and other Ukrainian towns will be inscribed in the list of atrocities and severe violations of international law, including international humanitarian law and human rights, committed by the aggressor on Ukrainian soil.</p>
<p align="left">In the presence of the Foreign Minister of Ukraine, Dmytro Kuleba, we expressed today our heart-felt solidarity with the Ukrainian people and our deepest condolences to the victims of this war and their families. We underline our unwavering support for Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders and express our readiness to assist further, including with military equipment and financial means, to allow Ukraine to defend itself against Russia’s aggression and to rebuild Ukraine.</p>
<p align="left">We underscore that those responsible for these heinous acts and atrocities, including any attacks targeting civilians and destruction of civilian infrastructure, will be held accountable and prosecuted. We welcome and support the ongoing work to investigate and gather evidence of these and other potential war crimes and crimes against humanity, including by the ICC Office of the Prosecutor, the Commission of Inquiry mandated by the UN Human Rights Council, the Human Rights Monitoring Mission Ukraine of the OHCHR, and the OSCE’s mission of experts mandated by OSCE Participating States. We will provide investigative support, technical experts and funding. We will continue to promote accountability for all those complicit in Moscow’s war of choice, including the Lukashenka regime in Belarus. We are convinced that now is the time to suspend Russian membership of the Human Rights Council.</p>
<p align="left">Russia must immediately comply with the legally binding order of the International Court of Justice (ICJ) to suspend the military operations that it commenced on 24 February 2022 in the territory of Ukraine. Further, we urge Russia to withdraw completely its military forces and equipment from the entire territory of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders.</p>
<p align="left">We warn against any threat or use of chemical, biological or nuclear weapons. We recall Russia’s obligations under international treaties of which it is a party, and which protect us all. Any use by Russia of such a weapon would be unacceptable and result in severe consequences. We condemn Russia’s unsubstantiated claims and false allegations against Ukraine, a respected member of the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention and the Chemical Weapons Convention that is in compliance with its legal obligations under those instruments. We express concern about other countries and actors that have amplified Russia’s disinformation campaign.</p>
<p align="left">We express our gravest concern with Russia forcefully seizing control of nuclear facilities, and other violent actions in connection with a number of nuclear facilities, nuclear and other radioactive material, which have caused and continue to pose serious and direct threats to the safety and security of these facilities and their civilian personnel, significantly raising the risk of a nuclear accident or incident, which endangers the population of Ukraine, neighboring States and the international community.</p>
<p align="left">We reiterate our demand that Russia upholds its obligations under international humanitarian law and desists from further blatant abuses. The Russian leadership must immediately provide for safe, rapid and unimpeded humanitarian access and make safe passages work, enabling humanitarian aid to be delivered to besieged cities and civilians to reach safety.</p>
<p align="left">We commit to supporting the Government of Ukraine’s humanitarian coordination structure and to disburse humanitarian support quickly. We ask others to join in this effort. A humanitarian push including more funding is urgently needed for Ukraine and beyond as Russia’s ruthless war and actions are having massive consequences on global commodity and food prices. The resulting rise in food insecurity is being felt disproportionately by the most vulnerable. We stand in solidarity with our partners across the world who have to bear the rising price of President Putin’s unilateral choice to wage war in Europe. We will make coherent use of all instruments and funding mechanisms to address food insecurity, keep markets open, and build resilience in the agriculture sector on all continents. We will actively counter Russia’s narrative that Western sanctions have caused the rise in global food prices and call it out for what it is: a blatant lie.</p>
<p align="left">In light of Russia’s ongoing aggression against Ukraine, carried out with Belarus’ complicity, we have already adopted unprecedented and coordinated economic and financial sanctions against Russia that impose a significant cost on its economy. We stress the necessity of further increasing the economic pressure inflicted on Russia and the Lukashenka regime in Belarus. Together with international partners, the G7 will sustain and increase pressure on Russia by imposing coordinated additional restrictive measures to effectively thwart Russian abilities to continue the aggression against Ukraine. We will work together to stop any attempts to circumvent sanctions or to aid Russia by other means. We are taking further steps to expedite plans to reduce our reliance on Russian energy, and will work together to this end.</p>
<p align="left">We commend those neighboring states to Ukraine that demonstrated great solidarity and humanity by welcoming Ukrainian refugees and third country nationals affected by the conflict. We confirm the need for increased international assistance and will continue to support these countries, including by receiving more refugees. President Putin’s war of aggression against Ukraine has already forced millions of civilians, especially women, children, and elderly, to flee their homes. Over 4.2 million crossed the border to other countries, almost all of them to the EU and the Republic of Moldova. We reiterate our concern about the risk to this vulnerable population, including the risk of human trafficking and our commitment to protect these refugees.</p>
<p align="left">Ministers paid special attention to the Republic of Moldova, which hosts the largest group of refugees from Ukraine per capita. The Ministers agreed to further coordinate their assistance for Moldova’s humanitarian response and long-term resilience following the Moldova Support Conference co-hosted by Germany, France and Romania on 5 April in Berlin and the establishment of the Moldova Support Platform.</p>
<p align="left"><i>End Text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p align="left"><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p align="left">We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union, condemn in the strongest terms the atrocities committed by the Russian armed forces in Bucha and a number of other Ukrainian towns. Haunting images of civilian deaths, victims of torture, and apparent executions, as well as reports of sexual violence and destruction of civilian infrastructure show the true face of Russia’s brutal war of aggression against Ukraine and its people. The massacres in the town of Bucha and other Ukrainian towns will be inscribed in the list of atrocities and severe violations of international law, including international humanitarian law and human rights, committed by the aggressor on Ukrainian soil.</p>
<p align="left">In the presence of the Foreign Minister of Ukraine, Dmytro Kuleba, we expressed today our heart-felt solidarity with the Ukrainian people and our deepest condolences to the victims of this war and their families. We underline our unwavering support for Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders and express our readiness to assist further, including with military equipment and financial means, to allow Ukraine to defend itself against Russia’s aggression and to rebuild Ukraine.</p>
<p align="left">We underscore that those responsible for these heinous acts and atrocities, including any attacks targeting civilians and destruction of civilian infrastructure, will be held accountable and prosecuted. We welcome and support the ongoing work to investigate and gather evidence of these and other potential war crimes and crimes against humanity, including by the ICC Office of the Prosecutor, the Commission of Inquiry mandated by the UN Human Rights Council, the Human Rights Monitoring Mission Ukraine of the OHCHR, and the OSCE’s mission of experts mandated by OSCE Participating States. We will provide investigative support, technical experts and funding. We will continue to promote accountability for all those complicit in Moscow’s war of choice, including the Lukashenka regime in Belarus. We are convinced that now is the time to suspend Russian membership of the Human Rights Council.</p>
<p align="left">Russia must immediately comply with the legally binding order of the International Court of Justice (ICJ) to suspend the military operations that it commenced on 24 February 2022 in the territory of Ukraine. Further, we urge Russia to withdraw completely its military forces and equipment from the entire territory of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders.</p>
<p align="left">We warn against any threat or use of chemical, biological or nuclear weapons. We recall Russia’s obligations under international treaties of which it is a party, and which protect us all. Any use by Russia of such a weapon would be unacceptable and result in severe consequences. We condemn Russia’s unsubstantiated claims and false allegations against Ukraine, a respected member of the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention and the Chemical Weapons Convention that is in compliance with its legal obligations under those instruments. We express concern about other countries and actors that have amplified Russia’s disinformation campaign.</p>
<p align="left">We express our gravest concern with Russia forcefully seizing control of nuclear facilities, and other violent actions in connection with a number of nuclear facilities, nuclear and other radioactive material, which have caused and continue to pose serious and direct threats to the safety and security of these facilities and their civilian personnel, significantly raising the risk of a nuclear accident or incident, which endangers the population of Ukraine, neighboring States and the international community.</p>
<p align="left">We reiterate our demand that Russia upholds its obligations under international humanitarian law and desists from further blatant abuses. The Russian leadership must immediately provide for safe, rapid and unimpeded humanitarian access and make safe passages work, enabling humanitarian aid to be delivered to besieged cities and civilians to reach safety.</p>
<p align="left">We commit to supporting the Government of Ukraine’s humanitarian coordination structure and to disburse humanitarian support quickly. We ask others to join in this effort. A humanitarian push including more funding is urgently needed for Ukraine and beyond as Russia’s ruthless war and actions are having massive consequences on global commodity and food prices. The resulting rise in food insecurity is being felt disproportionately by the most vulnerable. We stand in solidarity with our partners across the world who have to bear the rising price of President Putin’s unilateral choice to wage war in Europe. We will make coherent use of all instruments and funding mechanisms to address food insecurity, keep markets open, and build resilience in the agriculture sector on all continents. We will actively counter Russia’s narrative that Western sanctions have caused the rise in global food prices and call it out for what it is: a blatant lie.</p>
<p align="left">In light of Russia’s ongoing aggression against Ukraine, carried out with Belarus’ complicity, we have already adopted unprecedented and coordinated economic and financial sanctions against Russia that impose a significant cost on its economy. We stress the necessity of further increasing the economic pressure inflicted on Russia and the Lukashenka regime in Belarus. Together with international partners, the G7 will sustain and increase pressure on Russia by imposing coordinated additional restrictive measures to effectively thwart Russian abilities to continue the aggression against Ukraine. We will work together to stop any attempts to circumvent sanctions or to aid Russia by other means. We are taking further steps to expedite plans to reduce our reliance on Russian energy, and will work together to this end.</p>
<p align="left">We commend those neighboring states to Ukraine that demonstrated great solidarity and humanity by welcoming Ukrainian refugees and third country nationals affected by the conflict. We confirm the need for increased international assistance and will continue to support these countries, including by receiving more refugees. President Putin’s war of aggression against Ukraine has already forced millions of civilians, especially women, children, and elderly, to flee their homes. Over 4.2 million crossed the border to other countries, almost all of them to the EU and the Republic of Moldova. We reiterate our concern about the risk to this vulnerable population, including the risk of human trafficking and our commitment to protect these refugees.</p>
<p align="left">Ministers paid special attention to the Republic of Moldova, which hosts the largest group of refugees from Ukraine per capita. The Ministers agreed to further coordinate their assistance for Moldova’s humanitarian response and long-term resilience following the Moldova Support Conference co-hosted by Germany, France and Romania on 5 April in Berlin and the establishment of the Moldova Support Platform.</p>
<p align="left"><i>End Text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with UK National Security Adviser Lovegrove</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-uk-national-security-adviser-lovegrove/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 01:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332346</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with UK National Security Adviser Sir Stephen Lovegrove today in Washington.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and NSA Lovegrove continued their close coordination in responding to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine and atrocities the Russian Federation forces have committed.  The Deputy Secretary and NSA Lovegrove reaffirmed the strategic importance of the Indo-Pacific region and ensuring the AUKUS partnership delivers critical security and technology capabilities to address challenges in the Indo-Pacific and beyond.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with UK National Security Adviser Sir Stephen Lovegrove today in Washington.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and NSA Lovegrove continued their close coordination in responding to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine and atrocities the Russian Federation forces have committed.  The Deputy Secretary and NSA Lovegrove reaffirmed the strategic importance of the Indo-Pacific region and ensuring the AUKUS partnership delivers critical security and technology capabilities to address challenges in the Indo-Pacific and beyond.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-nato-secretary-general-stoltenberg-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 21:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg in Brussels.  The leaders discussed efforts to provide security and other forms of assistance to our Ukrainian partners in response to the Russian Federation’s unprovoked war against Ukraine. They also noted preparations for the June 29-30 NATO Summit in Madrid and reaffirmed support for NATO’s Asia-Pacific partners, Australia, Japan, the Republic of Korea, and New Zealand, attending the Ministerial for the first time. Secretary Blinken reiterated U.S. support for the development of a new NATO Strategic Concept that addresses current and future threats to the international rules-based order.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg in Brussels.  The leaders discussed efforts to provide security and other forms of assistance to our Ukrainian partners in response to the Russian Federation’s unprovoked war against Ukraine. They also noted preparations for the June 29-30 NATO Summit in Madrid and reaffirmed support for NATO’s Asia-Pacific partners, Australia, Japan, the Republic of Korea, and New Zealand, attending the Ministerial for the first time. Secretary Blinken reiterated U.S. support for the development of a new NATO Strategic Concept that addresses current and future threats to the international rules-based order.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary Medina’s Travel to Honolulu, Hawaii</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-medinas-travel-to-honolulu-hawaii/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 21:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica P. Medina will travel to Honolulu, Hawaii, April 7-9 to meet with officials from United States Indo-Pacific Command and the United States Coast Guard to discuss their work combating illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing.  In addition, she will visit the Hawai‘i Institute for Marine Biology to learn more about its research on climate change and marine wildlife conservation and meet with Hawaiian community leaders and nongovernmental organizations working to preserve unique island ecosystems.</p>
<p align="left">Following these activities, Assistant Secretary Medina will continue her travels to the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference,</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> which the United States will co-host with Palau in Koror, April 13-14.</p>
<p align="left">For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov.</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica P. Medina will travel to Honolulu, Hawaii, April 7-9 to meet with officials from United States Indo-Pacific Command and the United States Coast Guard to discuss their work combating illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing.  In addition, she will visit the Hawai‘i Institute for Marine Biology to learn more about its research on climate change and marine wildlife conservation and meet with Hawaiian community leaders and nongovernmental organizations working to preserve unique island ecosystems.</p>
<p align="left">Following these activities, Assistant Secretary Medina will continue her travels to the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference,</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> which the United States will co-host with Palau in Koror, April 13-14.</p>
<p align="left">For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov.</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with French, German, Italian, and UK Counterparts</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-french-german-italian-and-uk-counterparts-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 21:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332290</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian, German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock, Italian Foreign Minister Luigi Di Maio, and UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss today in Brussels, where they reiterated their commitment to supporting Ukraine in the face of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.  The Secretary again strongly condemned the reported atrocities by President Putin’s forces in Bucha and across Ukraine and called for accountability. He and his counterparts discussed how best to continue working to isolate the Russian Federation on the international stage for its flagrant violation of international law and principles, to increase pressure on the Kremlin, and to advance a swift end its devastating war against Ukraine.  They also discussed plans to provide additional humanitarian and security assistance to Ukraine.</p>
<p>Prior to this meeting, Secretary Blinken met with his E3 counterparts to discuss our common resolve to ensure that Iran never acquires a nuclear weapon. They agreed that a diplomatic solution entailing a mutual return to full implementation of the JCPOA is the best outcome, but noted that we are prepared for other scenarios if necessary.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian, German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock, Italian Foreign Minister Luigi Di Maio, and UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss today in Brussels, where they reiterated their commitment to supporting Ukraine in the face of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.  The Secretary again strongly condemned the reported atrocities by President Putin’s forces in Bucha and across Ukraine and called for accountability. He and his counterparts discussed how best to continue working to isolate the Russian Federation on the international stage for its flagrant violation of international law and principles, to increase pressure on the Kremlin, and to advance a swift end its devastating war against Ukraine.  They also discussed plans to provide additional humanitarian and security assistance to Ukraine.</p>
<p>Prior to this meeting, Secretary Blinken met with his E3 counterparts to discuss our common resolve to ensure that Iran never acquires a nuclear weapon. They agreed that a diplomatic solution entailing a mutual return to full implementation of the JCPOA is the best outcome, but noted that we are prepared for other scenarios if necessary.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Targeting Additional Russian Financial Institutions, Officials, and Other Individuals</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/targeting-additional-russian-financial-institutions-officials-and-other-individuals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 19:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332151</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is united with our allies and partners to ensure the Government of Russia pays a severe price for causing such death and destruction in Ukraine, and particularly for the horrors in Bucha and elsewhere.  In furtherance of this goal, today we are implementing full blocking sanctions on two key Russian financial institutions: Sberbank, Russia’s largest financial institution, and its subsidiaries and Alfa Bank, one of the largest private banks in Russia, and its subsidiaries. These entities continue to sustain President Putin’s aggression against Ukraine.  Accordingly, all U.S. persons are generally prohibited from engaging in transactions with Sberbank or Alfa Bank.</p>
<p>In addition, we are imposing sanctions on the adult children of President Vladimir Putin, Katerina Tikhonova and Maria Vorontsova, as well as Maria Lavrova, the wife of Russia’s Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov, and Ekaterina Lavrova, his adult child.</p>
<p>The United States is also designating 21 members of Russia’s National Security Council, including former President Dmitry Medvedev and Prime Minister Mikhail Mishustin, for their role and authority in crafting the Kremlin’s brutal policies and resulting abuses.</p>
<p>And finally, President Biden’s Executive Order today bans new investment in Russia – forcing Russia further down the road of financial and economic isolation.</p>
<p>This announcement of new economic sanctions follows our approval last night of $100 million in new security assistance to help Ukraine meet a continued need for additional anti-armor systems.  This is only the most recent of six drawdowns of arms, equipment, and supplies from Department of Defense inventories for Ukraine since August 2021, and brings U.S. military assistance to almost $2.5 billion since September, and $4.5 billion since 2014.  The United States commends the continued support of our allies and partners across the world in the face of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.  We stand with Ukraine and recognize the bravery and heroism of its people and they defend their country and their freedom against Russia’s brutal war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>United with our Allies and partners, the United States will continue to impose economic costs on Russia for their actions through economic sanctions and provide security assistance in support of Ukraine’s defense, as well as economic support and humanitarian aid for communities across Ukraine devastated by Russia’s ruthless brutality.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0705" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is united with our allies and partners to ensure the Government of Russia pays a severe price for causing such death and destruction in Ukraine, and particularly for the horrors in Bucha and elsewhere.  In furtherance of this goal, today we are implementing full blocking sanctions on two key Russian financial institutions: Sberbank, Russia’s largest financial institution, and its subsidiaries and Alfa Bank, one of the largest private banks in Russia, and its subsidiaries. These entities continue to sustain President Putin’s aggression against Ukraine.  Accordingly, all U.S. persons are generally prohibited from engaging in transactions with Sberbank or Alfa Bank.</p>
<p>In addition, we are imposing sanctions on the adult children of President Vladimir Putin, Katerina Tikhonova and Maria Vorontsova, as well as Maria Lavrova, the wife of Russia’s Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov, and Ekaterina Lavrova, his adult child.</p>
<p>The United States is also designating 21 members of Russia’s National Security Council, including former President Dmitry Medvedev and Prime Minister Mikhail Mishustin, for their role and authority in crafting the Kremlin’s brutal policies and resulting abuses.</p>
<p>And finally, President Biden’s Executive Order today bans new investment in Russia – forcing Russia further down the road of financial and economic isolation.</p>
<p>This announcement of new economic sanctions follows our approval last night of $100 million in new security assistance to help Ukraine meet a continued need for additional anti-armor systems.  This is only the most recent of six drawdowns of arms, equipment, and supplies from Department of Defense inventories for Ukraine since August 2021, and brings U.S. military assistance to almost $2.5 billion since September, and $4.5 billion since 2014.  The United States commends the continued support of our allies and partners across the world in the face of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.  We stand with Ukraine and recognize the bravery and heroism of its people and they defend their country and their freedom against Russia’s brutal war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>United with our Allies and partners, the United States will continue to impose economic costs on Russia for their actions through economic sanctions and provide security assistance in support of Ukraine’s defense, as well as economic support and humanitarian aid for communities across Ukraine devastated by Russia’s ruthless brutality.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0705" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department of State Offers Reward for Information to Bring Transnational Criminal to Justice</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/department-of-state-offers-reward-for-information-to-bring-transnational-criminal-to-justice/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 17:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332090</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department of State is offering a reward of up to $5 million for information leading to the arrest and/or conviction of Semion Mogilevich, a longtime transnational criminal currently living in Russia.  Mogilevich is wanted in the United States for his alleged participation between 1993 and 1998 in a multi-million dollar scheme to defraud thousands of investors related to a public company headquartered in Newtown, Pennsylvania.  The scheme collapsed in 1998 after thousands of investors lost more than $150 million.  Mogilevich was indicted in 2002 and again in 2003.</p>
<p>This reward is offered under the Department of State’s Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program (TOCRP), which the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs manages in close coordination with federal law enforcement partners and other U.S. government agencies.  More than 75 transnational criminals and major narcotics traffickers have been brought to justice under the TOCRP and the Narcotics Rewards Program (NRP) since the NRP’s inception in 1986, with the Department paying more than $135 million in rewards for information to-date.</p>
<p>Any information in response this reward offer should be directed to the FBI at +1-800-225-5324 (Voice), +1-215-839-6844 (WhatsApp), or online at <a class="external-link" href="https://tips.fbi.gov/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://tips.fbi.gov</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>For more information on the individuals listed above and the TOCRP, please see <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs/inl-rewards-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDYuNTYwMjY2NTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1LW9mLWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtbmFyY290aWNzLWFuZC1sYXctZW5mb3JjZW1lbnQtYWZmYWlycy9pbmwtcmV3YXJkcy1wcm9ncmFtLyJ9.vHtJLrWOE85p_foIC5JMihAc3jp6Ej2zlBJckG0Ua7Q/s/2171565732/br/129423737675-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649350926158000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1zFb-C9EQYSZOe9QiTX1IU">https://www.state.gov/bureau-<wbr />of-international-narcotics-<wbr />and-law-enforcement-affairs/<wbr />inl-rewards-program/</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department of State is offering a reward of up to $5 million for information leading to the arrest and/or conviction of Semion Mogilevich, a longtime transnational criminal currently living in Russia.  Mogilevich is wanted in the United States for his alleged participation between 1993 and 1998 in a multi-million dollar scheme to defraud thousands of investors related to a public company headquartered in Newtown, Pennsylvania.  The scheme collapsed in 1998 after thousands of investors lost more than $150 million.  Mogilevich was indicted in 2002 and again in 2003.</p>
<p>This reward is offered under the Department of State’s Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program (TOCRP), which the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs manages in close coordination with federal law enforcement partners and other U.S. government agencies.  More than 75 transnational criminals and major narcotics traffickers have been brought to justice under the TOCRP and the Narcotics Rewards Program (NRP) since the NRP’s inception in 1986, with the Department paying more than $135 million in rewards for information to-date.</p>
<p>Any information in response this reward offer should be directed to the FBI at +1-800-225-5324 (Voice), +1-215-839-6844 (WhatsApp), or online at <a class="external-link" href="https://tips.fbi.gov/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://tips.fbi.gov</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>For more information on the individuals listed above and the TOCRP, please see <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs/inl-rewards-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDYuNTYwMjY2NTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1LW9mLWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtbmFyY290aWNzLWFuZC1sYXctZW5mb3JjZW1lbnQtYWZmYWlycy9pbmwtcmV3YXJkcy1wcm9ncmFtLyJ9.vHtJLrWOE85p_foIC5JMihAc3jp6Ej2zlBJckG0Ua7Q/s/2171565732/br/129423737675-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649350926158000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1zFb-C9EQYSZOe9QiTX1IU">https://www.state.gov/bureau-<wbr />of-international-narcotics-<wbr />and-law-enforcement-affairs/<wbr />inl-rewards-program/</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
