<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 19:16:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Malawian President Lazarus Chakwera Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-malawian-president-lazarus-chakwera-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Lazarus Chakwera, Malawian President]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 19:16:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325904</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Lazarus Chakwera, Malawian President</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a real pleasure to welcome President Chakwera here to the State Department, to Washington.</p>
<p>We deeply appreciate the relationship, the partnership between the United States and Malawi, a remarkable democratic success story.  The strong leadership of the president, particularly in pursuing important reforms, sends a very strong message not only in Malawi and the continent, but around the world.  And we heard that as well through your participation in the Summit for Democracy at the end of last year.</p>
<p>But we greatly appreciate the partnership, across a number of issues, including global issues – Ukraine and Russia’s aggression against Ukraine right now – and look very much forward to talking about the work we’re doing to deepen the partnership between us as well as the work that we’re doing together around the world.</p>
<p>So, Mr. President, welcome.  It’s very, very good to have you and your team here.</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT CHAKWERA:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, thank you so very much.  It is a great honor for me to be here today, and to be received in such a magnanimous way.</p>
<p>Our relations with the U.S. date back to our time of independence way back in 1964, so it has been a long story of real partnership, collaboration, and help.  And in recent times our democratic journey is maturing because of the partnership and encouragement from friends like you.  And our systems are strengthened, the judicial systems, even the civic space, that has been – even the government’s institutions even stronger – the rule of law we pursue, and then the fight against corruption that is being supported.</p>
<p>We feel like we are onto the path of real development.  We have carved out a vision for an inclusively wealthy, self-reliant nation by 2063, but then we divided it up and we have a plan for 10 years, and then recovery plans for three years because of the COVID thing, which has really devastated us.  Recently, climate change issues and Cyclone Ana has left a trail of devastation and death.  And then, of course, what is happening in Europe now is of great concern.</p>
<p>So all of these things, we count on our partners to help us with.  In SADC, we believe that we do need involvement in the context of peace.  And so, we are working to deal with issues of support.  They are issues of human trafficking, issues of child labor, issues that have affected us for years, and sometimes accepted as the norm.  And we want to say no to this.  We want to be able to develop in a way that says Malawians can have their dignity and their place in the sun, alongside other nations, because we have seen that collaboration is the way to go.  Multilateralism is the way to go.  We need to side with those who want justice, who want human rights.  And we find that the U.S. is a great friend.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you very much.  It is great to be with you, great to have you here.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Lazarus Chakwera, Malawian President</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a real pleasure to welcome President Chakwera here to the State Department, to Washington.</p>
<p>We deeply appreciate the relationship, the partnership between the United States and Malawi, a remarkable democratic success story.  The strong leadership of the president, particularly in pursuing important reforms, sends a very strong message not only in Malawi and the continent, but around the world.  And we heard that as well through your participation in the Summit for Democracy at the end of last year.</p>
<p>But we greatly appreciate the partnership, across a number of issues, including global issues – Ukraine and Russia’s aggression against Ukraine right now – and look very much forward to talking about the work we’re doing to deepen the partnership between us as well as the work that we’re doing together around the world.</p>
<p>So, Mr. President, welcome.  It’s very, very good to have you and your team here.</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT CHAKWERA:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, thank you so very much.  It is a great honor for me to be here today, and to be received in such a magnanimous way.</p>
<p>Our relations with the U.S. date back to our time of independence way back in 1964, so it has been a long story of real partnership, collaboration, and help.  And in recent times our democratic journey is maturing because of the partnership and encouragement from friends like you.  And our systems are strengthened, the judicial systems, even the civic space, that has been – even the government’s institutions even stronger – the rule of law we pursue, and then the fight against corruption that is being supported.</p>
<p>We feel like we are onto the path of real development.  We have carved out a vision for an inclusively wealthy, self-reliant nation by 2063, but then we divided it up and we have a plan for 10 years, and then recovery plans for three years because of the COVID thing, which has really devastated us.  Recently, climate change issues and Cyclone Ana has left a trail of devastation and death.  And then, of course, what is happening in Europe now is of great concern.</p>
<p>So all of these things, we count on our partners to help us with.  In SADC, we believe that we do need involvement in the context of peace.  And so, we are working to deal with issues of support.  They are issues of human trafficking, issues of child labor, issues that have affected us for years, and sometimes accepted as the norm.  And we want to say no to this.  We want to be able to develop in a way that says Malawians can have their dignity and their place in the sun, alongside other nations, because we have seen that collaboration is the way to go.  Multilateralism is the way to go.  We need to side with those who want justice, who want human rights.  And we find that the U.S. is a great friend.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you very much.  It is great to be with you, great to have you here.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inaugural Meeting of the Clean Energy Resources Advisory Committee</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/inaugural-meeting-of-the-clean-energy-resources-advisory-committee/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 19:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary of State for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment Jose W. Fernandez hosted the inaugural meeting of the Clean Energy Resources Advisory Committee (CERAC), a new private sector advisory group, on March 15.</p>
<p>The 15 CERAC member entities represent a range of sectors – including automotive; mining and processing; battery manufacturing; recycling; traceability; mining standards; and mineral investments – and will advise the Department of State’s Bureau of Energy Resources on strategies, programs, and policies related to clean energy mineral supply chains.</p>
<p>Through Executive Order 14017, America’s Supply Chains, and a range of other initiatives, the Biden-Harris Administration is taking an action-based approach to bolstering supply chains key to U.S. economic interests and – in the case of minerals for clean technologies – U.S. climate objectives.  Private sector engagement and partnership is vital to these efforts, and CERAC will strengthen the Department of State’s robust engagement with private sector entities working in the critical minerals space.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:ENR-PD-Clearances@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ENR-PD-Clearances@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary of State for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment Jose W. Fernandez hosted the inaugural meeting of the Clean Energy Resources Advisory Committee (CERAC), a new private sector advisory group, on March 15.</p>
<p>The 15 CERAC member entities represent a range of sectors – including automotive; mining and processing; battery manufacturing; recycling; traceability; mining standards; and mineral investments – and will advise the Department of State’s Bureau of Energy Resources on strategies, programs, and policies related to clean energy mineral supply chains.</p>
<p>Through Executive Order 14017, America’s Supply Chains, and a range of other initiatives, the Biden-Harris Administration is taking an action-based approach to bolstering supply chains key to U.S. economic interests and – in the case of minerals for clean technologies – U.S. climate objectives.  Private sector engagement and partnership is vital to these efforts, and CERAC will strengthen the Department of State’s robust engagement with private sector entities working in the critical minerals space.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:ENR-PD-Clearances@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ENR-PD-Clearances@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Roundtable with Journalists</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-roundtable-with-journalists/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 19:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325900</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>U.S. Department of State</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone.  Thanks very much for joining.  This is Ned Price with the Department of State.  We’re very pleased to see so many of you on screen today and we’re really gratified to have the opportunity.  As you know, this will be an on-the-record (inaudible) to speak with Secretary Blinken.  He’ll have some opening remarks and then he’ll go into taking your questions.</p>
<p>With that, I’ll turn it over to the Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Ned, thanks very much.  Hey, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s good to either – to see some of you, to see names for those I can’t see, and really wanted to thank you for joining and getting together this afternoon.</p>
<p>(Break.)</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I think you’re muted, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Oh, all right.  Sorry about that.  So let me start again with apologies.  Two years into this, we’re still having challenges with Zoom and the like, but anyway, I was just saying first it’s – really appreciate everyone coming together this afternoon.  I was making a bad joke about how, when you usually talk to a secretary of state, it’s probably about elections, not necessarily about geopolitics.  But there’s a real reason that I was looking forward to getting together with this group.</p>
<p>One of the things we’ve been trying to do at the department is really connect up what we’re doing to the actual lives of our fellow citizens, and to connect with them in ways that we might not normally connect with them, and particularly to connect with them through the main institutions where they actually get their news, get their information, and that’s you all.  So that’s a big piece of it.</p>
<p>Second, there’s kind of this mystery or mystique about foreign policy as being something that is happening halfway around the world and that doesn’t have a real bearing necessarily on the lives of our fellow citizens.  Now, of course – and I’ll come to this – Russia-Ukraine has been dominating our papers and our screens for the last few weeks, but in the normal course of business, it’s not something that’s necessarily readily apparent.  But to us it is, and it’s something that we really want to continue to have a conversation about.</p>
<p>First, one of the principles that we’ve been inspired by, animated by, is that when we’re not engaged in the world, when the United States is not leading, at the table, in the room, then one of two things: either someone else is and doing things in a way that may not actually advance the interests of the American people or the values that we hold, or maybe no one is and then you tend to have vacuums and chaos and that usually has a way of coming back and biting us.  At least that’s the lesson that we take from our history.  So we think and we’re trying to help fellow citizens understand why just being out there and engaged as the United States is important.</p>
<p>And then there’s a second part that’s so important to that, at least from our perspective, is when we’re thinking about the things that are really having an impact on the lives of our fellow citizens, not a single one of them can be effectively addressed by us either going into a corner of our own or acting on our own.</p>
<p>And so when you think about it, if you’re concerned about climate change, well, we’re 15 percent of global emissions, so even if we did everything right at home, we’re still not dealing with the 85 percent of emissions that are coming from other countries.  We have to be working with them and that’s why we spent so much time not only getting back into the Paris Agreement, but working through many, many efforts to try to move things forward and getting other countries to lift their ambitions and do things even as we’re doing things.</p>
<p>If you care about COVID, we keep learning this the hard way:  No matter what we do at home, if we’re not also helping to ensure that the world is vaccinated, we know what’s going to happen.  We’re going to get another variant that may come back and bite us and maybe do it in a way that defeats the vaccines that we have.  So there’s a real premium on being out there and working with the world to try, even as we’re doing what we can at home, to make sure that other countries are doing the same.</p>
<p>And then this technology that’s dominating our lives and that’s allowing us to get together today, all of the emerging tech that is literally shaping people’s lives, we can’t shape the way it’s used by ourselves.  There are rules that go with it.  There are norms and standards that go with it.  And increasingly, those are shaped not just by us, but by other countries around the world and international institutions, et cetera.  And again, if we’re not in there doing it and leading it, all of those rules and norms and standards that go with how technology is actually used in terms of privacy, in terms of security – all of those things will happen in a way that escapes our own efforts to shape it and may come back and be harmful to our own citizens.</p>
<p>So I can go across the board, but most of the big things that are really affecting people, we need to be engaged with others, we need to be engaged with international institutions.  That’s the best way to advance what we’re trying to do in the interests of Americans around the world.  And that’s why it’s really important for me to try and for all of my colleagues to try to connect the dots to what we’re doing around the world to what people are actually experiencing in their own lives.  And of course, I think people have known that for a long time when it comes to economic issues and particularly when it comes to trade.</p>
<p>That brings me – and I want to – really want to open it up for any questions that people have.  That brings us to what is dominating the news cycle right now, and that’s Russia-Ukraine.  I think people are moved by what they’re seeing on their iPhones, on their TVs or reading about in their newspapers, because on a human level, it’s very powerful.  We’re seeing one very big country commit a war of aggression against a neighbor that’s done nothing to, in any way, deserve that.  And we see the human suffering that’s going on before our very eyes and that moves a lot of people.  We see the flood of refugees.  This is now the biggest refugee crisis in Europe since World War II.  That’s how many people are on the move as a result of this aggression.  We see it in the buildings destroyed and lives blown apart by the bombs and rockets and mortars.  And we see it in the women, the kids who are being so directly affected.</p>
<p>So I think it’s touching people, but one of the things that we tried to also underscore and underline is that as much as this is about what’s going on in Ukraine, it’s also about something bigger, which is why we’re so invested in it.  Because what really happened over the last century is we went through a couple of world wars, both of them ultimately drew the United States in, and we tried to do everything we could – after the second one – to put in place some basic rules and understandings to make it less likely we’d ever see another one.  And all of the things that happened back in the late 1940s and early 1950s about standing up the United Nations and standing up the international financial institutions, standing up NATO – all of these things were really about making sure that we had some basic understandings about how countries relate to one another that made it a little less likely that there would be conflict, that there would be war, and that we’d get drawn into something again.</p>
<p>One of the key – obviously, the key things was the United Nations, the Security Council.  The Security Council and the five permanent members – the United States, Russia, China, the UK, France – were – is charged with one mission above all, above all others.  The responsibility each member has is to do everything possible to maintain international peace and security.</p>
<p>So here we have one of the permanent members of that Council not only not maintaining international peace and security, but exploding it by attacking another country, and attacking some of the basic principles that are at the heart of the United Nations Charter and these international understandings that were designed to prevent wars from happening again, like states deserve to have their sovereignty respected; like they need to have their territorial integrity respected; one country can’t simply go in and change the borders of another by force, or dictate to it its choices, its future, its policies, with whom it’s going to associate.</p>
<p>So all those things are in play.  And in our view, at least, if we are not standing strongly for them, and if we’re allowing them to be challenged with impunity, it risks opening a Pandora’s box, not just in Europe but around the world.  That makes conflict and war and chaos more likely and, ultimately, affects – will affect us in profound ways.  We’ve seen the effect already of this war that is in Ukraine, that it’s having on everything from gasoline prices to food prices.  And we know also that it is taking us away from doing many of the things that we need to do on climate, on COVID, you name it.</p>
<p>So these things are, in a world that has become more and more interconnected over many years, they’re inescapable.  And so we have a real interest in trying to shape them to the best of our ability in ways that don’t come and bite us.</p>
<p>And that brings me back to where I started and where I’ll finish, which is it really does start with American engagement, with American leadership.  One of the main responsibilities that we were given by President Biden when we started this was to try to revitalize, re-energize, reinvigorate our alliances and partnerships by actually showing up, rolling up our sleeves, working with our partners, listening to them, consulting with them, and just doing that day in, day out, relentlessly on the phone, in person, by video, building cooperation and habits of working together.</p>
<p>And we did a lot of that.  We really made that investment.  And I think we see now that it pays off in the crunch.  We’ve done more with our European partners cooperatively in dealing with the Russian aggression in Ukraine than I think anyone expected, and certainly more than we’ve seen in many years.  And that means the burden is shared, the results are there, and we’re more effective.</p>
<p>But it doesn’t just happen by itself; it happens because we make these investments in time and resources and energy to build these relationships and to be able to work together effectively.</p>
<p>So…the end of the day, that’s part of the story that we’re trying to tell, that we want to tell.  And one of the ways I think we can most effectively do that is by talking to you, because you’re how so many people in our country are getting their stories, hearing what’s going on.  That’s the narrative, and you’re the ones who are delivering it and, in many ways, shaping it.</p>
<p>So with that, let me stop talking at you and start listening.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll now take questions.  If you have a question, feel free to unmute yourself or raise your hand, either digital or real.</p>
<p>Yeah, Liz, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hey, Mr. Secretary, thanks so much for doing this.  I had a question basically about how President Biden is approaching this moment, this kind of perilous moment.  I think we’ve – you mentioned what people back home are hearing, and I think they do hear from some lawmakers that they feel like President Biden is acting too scared of Putin, that in some of the moves on the jets, for example, that he’s being too cautious.  And President Biden has this long history dealing with Putin on this issue of Ukraine and in general.  So I’m wondering if you could speak at all to how he views Putin, like, as sort of an adversary in this moment and if that’s informing any of that caution that we’re seeing.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Sure, thanks.  Let me say a couple of things.  First of all, there may be a natural tendency sometimes to look at something that we’re not doing, which of course jumps over what we are doing.  And let me start there because it’s important.</p>
<p>Well before the aggression that Russia committed took place, we saw this coming; we worked very hard to try to keep it on a diplomatic track, dialogue, avert this aggression.  But even as we were doing that, we were preparing for the possibility and, increasingly, the likelihood that Russia would reject diplomacy and dialogue and pursue the aggression.  And so well before they went in, over the previous year, President Biden provided more security assistance to Ukraine in that year than in any previous year.  And as a result, the Ukrainians had in their hands when the Russians came in the very kind of equipment that has been incredibly effective in dealing with planes attacking from the air, tanks firing from the ground, missiles and rockets, et cetera.  All of that stuff – the anti-air equipment, the anti-armor equipment – much of that was already there because he had made that commitment and followed through on it.</p>
<p>Similarly, we said for months that if Russia committed an act – this act of aggression, there would be massive consequences, including unprecedented economic sanctions.  And I think some folks thought, well, that sounds good but what are we really going to see if it happens.  I think we’ve demonstrated that when we said there would be massive consequences, there were, there have been.  As a result of these sanctions, done in an unprecedented way in terms of their coordination with other countries, we’re basically seeing Russia’s economy in a freefall.  The ruble is through the floor.  Russia’s credit rating is junk status.  The stock market’s been closed for three weeks.  We’ve seen an exodus of virtually every leading company, brand, firm from Russia over the last few weeks such that basically in the space of a few weeks, 30 years of Russia opening to the world and creating greater economic opportunity for our people has vanished as a result of President Putin’s terrible actions.</p>
<p>So all of that’s happening, and of course we remain the leading provider of humanitarian assistance to Ukrainians, whether in Ukraine or those who have been forced to flee.  So when it comes to the things that are making the Ukrainians most effective in dealing with this onslaught from Russia, we’ve been providing it, and you heard the President yesterday describe in some detail another $800 million in security assistance and everything that that actually translates into.  So that’s really important.</p>
<p>The Pentagon, when they looked at this, we – there’s a lot of talk about the airplanes.  And by the way, President Zelenskyy is, as I think we’ve all seen, extraordinary and his leadership is both inspiring and genuinely heroic because he’s remained right in harm’s way leading his people.  And if I’m in his shoes, I’m going to be doing – I’m going to be asking for everything that I can possibly get.  I totally understand that.  We have to make judgments and determinations about what makes the most sense when it comes to the airplanes, for example.  The Pentagon made a determination that these would actually not be the most effective things that Ukraine could get, that what is effective is exactly what we’re doing and doing even more of, which are these anti-air and anti-armor systems that are actually shooting down planes and destroying tanks and armored vehicles.  That’s what’s working.</p>
<p>Second, I’d just say this:  We obviously have an incentive in trying to end this war as quickly as possible, not expand it, including to places beyond Ukraine.  And at the end of the day, all of us, every single one of us, except for one person, can – has the freedom to say oh, we should do this, that, or the other thing, and in very good faith, but only one person bears the ultimate responsibility for making that decision, for deciding, and with the responsibility of what is in the interest of the United States and our people, and that’s the President.  The buck stops there.  So I can advise something; Senator X can advise something, Congressman Y, a newspaper columnist, whatever.  But ultimately the responsibility, the burden of the decision falls on the President, and he is best placed to make the judgment about what’s ultimately in the interest of the American people.  That’s how he’s looking at it.</p>
<p>So we’re determined to support Ukraine, and we are.  We’re determined to exert extraordinary pressure on Russia, and we are.  But the most important thing is he’s got to do all that, making a judgment about what’s fundamentally in our interest, and that’s how he’s proceeded.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And on that point of his insight into Vladimir Putin?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Liz, we’re just going to move around, and if we have time we’ll come back.  But we’ll go to Ashley Murray.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, Secretary Blinken.  Thank you so much for your time.  I have two questions.  First is I understand – you just explained and I’ve read that the U.S. is the leading provider of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  But I’m wondering if you can comment on the U.S.’s possible plan or anything in the works to extend that to other countries surrounding Ukraine as they face the refugee crisis flooding over the borders, and possibly even to Europe beyond the eastern flank.</p>
<p>And then secondly, many of the persons and entities on the sanctions list now, specially designated persons and banks, Russian banks – we’re also (inaudible).  Can you comment on how these (inaudible) round would do anything (inaudible) they’re more effective?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So Ashley, I’m sorry, I didn’t quite get the second part of your question about the sanctions and the different entities.  Could you repeat it, because you were breaking up a little?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So sorry.  Why these (inaudible) of sanctions would be more effective than the ones announced in 2014 or even some in 2018.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Got it.  Thanks.  Got it.  Thank you.  So with regard to the humanitarian assistance piece of this, the supplemental funding that Congress has provided, which is very, very significant and powerful – we got about $13.6 billion – of that about $4 billion goes to humanitarian assistance for Ukraine.  But that includes, significantly, not just assistance that we’re trying to get into Ukraine to help Ukrainians who are still there but also to help Ukrainians who have been forced to flee to the neighboring countries, as well as helping those countries sort of support the burden that they’re bearing of taking in so many people as refugees, for however long that lasts.</p>
<p>So there’s significant resources going to that, that are going to neighboring countries to help them, that are going to organizations like UNHCR to support the work that they’re doing directly.  And as we’re doing that, we’re also working – I was on, for example, a call today with my counterparts from the G7 countries.  These are the world’s leading democratic economies, and so it’s France, it’s Germany, it’s the UK, it’s Italy, it’s Canada, it’s Japan, as well as the European Union.  And one of the things we’re talking about today is how we can effectively channel our resources to support countries, particularly the neighboring countries that are bearing such a burden – Poland, little Moldova, Romania, others.  And we’re very focused on doing that and making sure they have the resources they need.</p>
<p>We’re also looking when it comes to refugees about what we can do ourselves and talking both to UNHCR about that, looking what we can do in a sort of coordinated way with these other leading countries to try to deal with some of the burden that refugees will pose to these countries.  So more on that in the days to come, but already a big chunk of our assistance is actually going to neighboring countries.</p>
<p>On the sanctions piece, what’s different this time is – there are a number of things that are different, but first and foremost, I think what you’ve seen take place with the sanctions on virtually all of the leading Russian financial institutions, the banks and others, have been devastating to their ability to do business.  The sanctions on the central bank have meant that even though Russia built up a lot of reserves, they’ve been unable to use those reserves to prop up the ruble.  They can’t go and buy rubles abroad because they’re sanctioned, and the value of the currency has plummeted.  As I mentioned, the stock market’s been closed for three weeks as well.</p>
<p>The elites that we’ve sanctioned, well, not only are we preventing them from doing things, but we’re – much more aggressively than we’ve ever done in the past – actually going after them. And there is a whole task force that was set up with other countries to freeze and seize their assets – the mega yachts, the fancy apartments, the sports cars – in ways that they’re going to feel very directly.  Many of them are finding it impossible to do business with anyone anymore.</p>
<p>And then we’ve seen something extraordinary that is not the direct result of the sanctions, but has been incredibly powerful, and that is this exodus of virtually every leading company from Russia.  I mean, if you – I had a document that a few days ago was probably eight or nine pages long – it’s probably almost double that by now – with this list of everyone from McDonald’s to Apple to Coca Cola to Toyota to Netflix to MasterCard and Visa to you name it.  And that is actually having a very dramatic impact on Russians in their day-to-day lives – not something any of us do or see with any joy or pleasure, not at all.  But we have to maximize the impact that we’re having on Putin and his decision making, and that’s one way to do it.</p>
<p>Last thing I’ll say on the sanctions is that one of the things you’re going to see have an impact over time are the export controls that we put in place with other countries to deny Russia the technology that it needs to modernize critical industries – defense, aerospace, energy exploration. And as a result, they will not be able to modernize, to develop these sectors in ways that will help their economy advance or help strengthen their strategic interests or position.  That’s going to be felt increasingly over time.  And then to the extent that they are a supplier of such equipment and technologies to other countries, those countries are not going to be interested in taking stuff that is increasingly outdated and ineffective.</p>
<p>So there’s a huge immediate impact, and an impact that’s going to build over time for as long as this goes on.  Of course, the purpose of all of this is not to have these things in perpetuity.  The purpose of the sanctions is to change their conduct, along with everything else that we’re doing. And so that’s what we hope happens.  But I think by just about any objective measure, the sanctions themselves are unprecedented when you go through each and every one of them, and the impact they’re already having is unprecedented – look at every metric of the Russian economy and you can see that things are going through the floor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>(Inaudible) Secretary.  Thank you for doing the call.  When you talk about sanctions and the impact, obviously, as you put it, they have had an impact but they haven’t been able to deter Putin from invading, from targeting civilians, hospitals.  And you’ve talked about now the possibility of chemical weapons being used.  What you have on the table that could either deter him or that you could do beyond what’s already been done to increase the punishments if he does use chemical weapons?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>So, of course, you hope that the prospect of sanctions – of economic measures – will prove to be a deterrent and actually prevent the aggression that you’re trying to prevent.  And certainly, as we worked on these for many months and coordinated these with allies and partners and made very clear that there would be massive consequences, our first hope was that that would help deter the aggression.  It didn’t.  So now there are two things that are in play.  One is – we’ve demonstrated that when we said there would be massive consequences, there are.  That’s being felt more and more each day.  And so at some point, that price, that burden, that impact may have the effect of stopping what Putin has started.</p>
<p>But ultimately, I think what is really having an impact there is the extraordinary resistance, courage, bravery of the Ukrainian people, supported by us and many other countries, in terms of the impact that they’re having on this Russian onslaught.  And we’re seeing that virtually everything happening on the ground in Ukraine is not going according to Putin’s plan – far from it.  And, again, you’re all seeing it, reporting it pretty much every day.  The cumulative impact of all of that – the pressure being brought to bear and the resistance that is having a powerful impact on the invading forces – that at some point in time we hope will push Russia to do something different.  The problem is it’s not flipping a light switch.  It does take time for them to reassess, calculate their interests, and to see that what they’re doing is profoundly not in their own interest.</p>
<p>So I think that will build.  That’s why I was saying earlier that we also have to, I think tragically, be prepared for this to go on for some time, because it – again, it’s not like flipping a switch.  It accumulates, the pressure builds, the consequences build, and ultimately, countries have to reckon with that and change what they’re doing as a result of that.</p>
<p>So that’s where we are, and it’s unfortunately a process, not a – not something that’s automatic.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Jerry, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Secretary Blinken, thank you for doing this.  It’s very helpful.  I have kind of a multi-pronged question about the refugee crisis.  First of all, I’m wondering what your sense is, at this point in time, whether there will be large numbers of Ukrainian refugees who would like to resettle in the U.S., what your approach to that may be, whether it’ll be through the UNHCR process or something else, and whether they’ll be going to the kind of metro areas that have been very welcoming over time to refugees, such as Buffalo.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Couple of things on that.  First, just to emphasize, this is already the largest refugee crisis in Europe since World War II just in terms of numbers.  And I think there’s every expectation that it’s going to grow.  And so we’re well north of 2.5 million people at this point, not to mention those who are displaced within Ukraine.  And as long as this goes on, the brutality continues, more and more people will leave.  That’s the situation we’re dealing with now, but it’s also the expectation that we have going forward.</p>
<p>And it’s why countries are coming together to figure out what we can do, both individually but also collectively, to help care for, welcome, support those who are refugees – either by supporting other countries that are taking them in or taking people in ourselves.  That’s – and so a lot of work is going into addressing that right now, making sure the resources are there, making sure that the lead organizations like UNHCR are where they need to be and have the support that they need to have, et cetera.</p>
<p>What we’re seeing right now – but this is likely to change at some point, but – as the numbers grow bigger – right now the strong desire of most people leaving is to stay as close to Ukraine as they can, and certainly to stay within Europe, for a couple of reasons.  One is, I think as you know, the people leaving now are almost all women and children.  Adult men, men between the ages of 18 and 60, are asked to stay in Ukraine to fight for their country.  And so the women and children who are leaving and separating from husbands and sons and brothers, they want to stay, if they can, as close at hand as possible in the hopes that they can be quickly reunited and in the hopes that the war will end quickly and they can go home.  Second, many Ukrainians have family, relatives in Europe, and once you’re in Europe, you have a fair bit of freedom of movement.  And so their second impulse is to get together with family and others in Europe itself.</p>
<p>Having said that, given the numbers that we’re looking at, there is almost certainly going to be an interest, a demand on countries far from Europe – including the United States – to take people in.  In the first instance, we have the referral process that I know you’re familiar with, where someone goes to UNHCR, seeks refugee status, and then people get referred to us.  But that’s a lengthy process, and what we’re looking at is whether there are more near-term steps that we can take that would help do our part in bringing people to the United States – for example, family reunification.  This is one of the things we’re looking at right now.</p>
<p>I expect that we’ll have more to say about that in the coming days as we really plunge into this, but we’re determined to do our part in showing that we’re a place of refuge and welcome as well, and particularly because there are such strong Ukrainian American communities here, I know that people would be very welcoming.  But more in the coming days.  For now, we’re focused on helping countries that are already taking in refugees, supporting UNHCR, and looking at some near-term ways that we can do things like family reunification.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yvonne, go ahead.  Yvonne, I think you’re still on mute.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks so much for doing this, Secretary.  What is the State Department doing to try to allow for Brittney Griner to meet with consular officials in Russia?  Why have requests for such a meeting been denied thus far?  And can you give us a sense of what difference such a meeting would make?  Separately, can you give us a sense of what her condition is?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks.  So we – whenever an American is detained anywhere, our job, our responsibility, our determination is to make sure that we’re doing everything possible to help them, to defend their rights, and to see what assistance, if any, they need.  And that’s anywhere in the world where this happens in one way or the other.</p>
<p>In Brittney’s case, in the first instance, we weren’t talking about it with any specificity because there were privacy concerns that we needed to respect.  Now, what I can tell you is that we’re in very active contact with her team, with – literally with the WNBA, as well as with her lawyers and other representatives.  We are and have been seeking consular access because we want to see firsthand how she’s doing.  We want to make sure that we know that she’s okay.</p>
<p>And this is, by the way, required under international law.  The Russians are required to give us that access.  They have not; it has been denied.  So we are working very hard on getting it, on being able to get access to her, to hear directly from her how she’s doing, and to make sure we’re doing everything we can to see to it that her rights are being respected and upheld in the Russian system and in terms of international law.</p>
<p>So it’s a work very much in progress.  I wish I had something positive to report in terms of actually getting access.  To date we’ve not been able to do that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  All right, seeing no other hands, want to thank everyone for taking part in this.  We do want to make this a regular occurrence, and even when the Secretary isn’t available, please do know that you can come to us at any time.  I think you all know how to reach our – me and our press office.  If you don’t, we’re happy to pass along that information, but thank you all very much for taking part and we look forward to seeing you again before long.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, everyone.  Appreciate it.  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>U.S. Department of State</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone.  Thanks very much for joining.  This is Ned Price with the Department of State.  We’re very pleased to see so many of you on screen today and we’re really gratified to have the opportunity.  As you know, this will be an on-the-record (inaudible) to speak with Secretary Blinken.  He’ll have some opening remarks and then he’ll go into taking your questions.</p>
<p>With that, I’ll turn it over to the Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Ned, thanks very much.  Hey, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s good to either – to see some of you, to see names for those I can’t see, and really wanted to thank you for joining and getting together this afternoon.</p>
<p>(Break.)</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I think you’re muted, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Oh, all right.  Sorry about that.  So let me start again with apologies.  Two years into this, we’re still having challenges with Zoom and the like, but anyway, I was just saying first it’s – really appreciate everyone coming together this afternoon.  I was making a bad joke about how, when you usually talk to a secretary of state, it’s probably about elections, not necessarily about geopolitics.  But there’s a real reason that I was looking forward to getting together with this group.</p>
<p>One of the things we’ve been trying to do at the department is really connect up what we’re doing to the actual lives of our fellow citizens, and to connect with them in ways that we might not normally connect with them, and particularly to connect with them through the main institutions where they actually get their news, get their information, and that’s you all.  So that’s a big piece of it.</p>
<p>Second, there’s kind of this mystery or mystique about foreign policy as being something that is happening halfway around the world and that doesn’t have a real bearing necessarily on the lives of our fellow citizens.  Now, of course – and I’ll come to this – Russia-Ukraine has been dominating our papers and our screens for the last few weeks, but in the normal course of business, it’s not something that’s necessarily readily apparent.  But to us it is, and it’s something that we really want to continue to have a conversation about.</p>
<p>First, one of the principles that we’ve been inspired by, animated by, is that when we’re not engaged in the world, when the United States is not leading, at the table, in the room, then one of two things: either someone else is and doing things in a way that may not actually advance the interests of the American people or the values that we hold, or maybe no one is and then you tend to have vacuums and chaos and that usually has a way of coming back and biting us.  At least that’s the lesson that we take from our history.  So we think and we’re trying to help fellow citizens understand why just being out there and engaged as the United States is important.</p>
<p>And then there’s a second part that’s so important to that, at least from our perspective, is when we’re thinking about the things that are really having an impact on the lives of our fellow citizens, not a single one of them can be effectively addressed by us either going into a corner of our own or acting on our own.</p>
<p>And so when you think about it, if you’re concerned about climate change, well, we’re 15 percent of global emissions, so even if we did everything right at home, we’re still not dealing with the 85 percent of emissions that are coming from other countries.  We have to be working with them and that’s why we spent so much time not only getting back into the Paris Agreement, but working through many, many efforts to try to move things forward and getting other countries to lift their ambitions and do things even as we’re doing things.</p>
<p>If you care about COVID, we keep learning this the hard way:  No matter what we do at home, if we’re not also helping to ensure that the world is vaccinated, we know what’s going to happen.  We’re going to get another variant that may come back and bite us and maybe do it in a way that defeats the vaccines that we have.  So there’s a real premium on being out there and working with the world to try, even as we’re doing what we can at home, to make sure that other countries are doing the same.</p>
<p>And then this technology that’s dominating our lives and that’s allowing us to get together today, all of the emerging tech that is literally shaping people’s lives, we can’t shape the way it’s used by ourselves.  There are rules that go with it.  There are norms and standards that go with it.  And increasingly, those are shaped not just by us, but by other countries around the world and international institutions, et cetera.  And again, if we’re not in there doing it and leading it, all of those rules and norms and standards that go with how technology is actually used in terms of privacy, in terms of security – all of those things will happen in a way that escapes our own efforts to shape it and may come back and be harmful to our own citizens.</p>
<p>So I can go across the board, but most of the big things that are really affecting people, we need to be engaged with others, we need to be engaged with international institutions.  That’s the best way to advance what we’re trying to do in the interests of Americans around the world.  And that’s why it’s really important for me to try and for all of my colleagues to try to connect the dots to what we’re doing around the world to what people are actually experiencing in their own lives.  And of course, I think people have known that for a long time when it comes to economic issues and particularly when it comes to trade.</p>
<p>That brings me – and I want to – really want to open it up for any questions that people have.  That brings us to what is dominating the news cycle right now, and that’s Russia-Ukraine.  I think people are moved by what they’re seeing on their iPhones, on their TVs or reading about in their newspapers, because on a human level, it’s very powerful.  We’re seeing one very big country commit a war of aggression against a neighbor that’s done nothing to, in any way, deserve that.  And we see the human suffering that’s going on before our very eyes and that moves a lot of people.  We see the flood of refugees.  This is now the biggest refugee crisis in Europe since World War II.  That’s how many people are on the move as a result of this aggression.  We see it in the buildings destroyed and lives blown apart by the bombs and rockets and mortars.  And we see it in the women, the kids who are being so directly affected.</p>
<p>So I think it’s touching people, but one of the things that we tried to also underscore and underline is that as much as this is about what’s going on in Ukraine, it’s also about something bigger, which is why we’re so invested in it.  Because what really happened over the last century is we went through a couple of world wars, both of them ultimately drew the United States in, and we tried to do everything we could – after the second one – to put in place some basic rules and understandings to make it less likely we’d ever see another one.  And all of the things that happened back in the late 1940s and early 1950s about standing up the United Nations and standing up the international financial institutions, standing up NATO – all of these things were really about making sure that we had some basic understandings about how countries relate to one another that made it a little less likely that there would be conflict, that there would be war, and that we’d get drawn into something again.</p>
<p>One of the key – obviously, the key things was the United Nations, the Security Council.  The Security Council and the five permanent members – the United States, Russia, China, the UK, France – were – is charged with one mission above all, above all others.  The responsibility each member has is to do everything possible to maintain international peace and security.</p>
<p>So here we have one of the permanent members of that Council not only not maintaining international peace and security, but exploding it by attacking another country, and attacking some of the basic principles that are at the heart of the United Nations Charter and these international understandings that were designed to prevent wars from happening again, like states deserve to have their sovereignty respected; like they need to have their territorial integrity respected; one country can’t simply go in and change the borders of another by force, or dictate to it its choices, its future, its policies, with whom it’s going to associate.</p>
<p>So all those things are in play.  And in our view, at least, if we are not standing strongly for them, and if we’re allowing them to be challenged with impunity, it risks opening a Pandora’s box, not just in Europe but around the world.  That makes conflict and war and chaos more likely and, ultimately, affects – will affect us in profound ways.  We’ve seen the effect already of this war that is in Ukraine, that it’s having on everything from gasoline prices to food prices.  And we know also that it is taking us away from doing many of the things that we need to do on climate, on COVID, you name it.</p>
<p>So these things are, in a world that has become more and more interconnected over many years, they’re inescapable.  And so we have a real interest in trying to shape them to the best of our ability in ways that don’t come and bite us.</p>
<p>And that brings me back to where I started and where I’ll finish, which is it really does start with American engagement, with American leadership.  One of the main responsibilities that we were given by President Biden when we started this was to try to revitalize, re-energize, reinvigorate our alliances and partnerships by actually showing up, rolling up our sleeves, working with our partners, listening to them, consulting with them, and just doing that day in, day out, relentlessly on the phone, in person, by video, building cooperation and habits of working together.</p>
<p>And we did a lot of that.  We really made that investment.  And I think we see now that it pays off in the crunch.  We’ve done more with our European partners cooperatively in dealing with the Russian aggression in Ukraine than I think anyone expected, and certainly more than we’ve seen in many years.  And that means the burden is shared, the results are there, and we’re more effective.</p>
<p>But it doesn’t just happen by itself; it happens because we make these investments in time and resources and energy to build these relationships and to be able to work together effectively.</p>
<p>So…the end of the day, that’s part of the story that we’re trying to tell, that we want to tell.  And one of the ways I think we can most effectively do that is by talking to you, because you’re how so many people in our country are getting their stories, hearing what’s going on.  That’s the narrative, and you’re the ones who are delivering it and, in many ways, shaping it.</p>
<p>So with that, let me stop talking at you and start listening.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll now take questions.  If you have a question, feel free to unmute yourself or raise your hand, either digital or real.</p>
<p>Yeah, Liz, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hey, Mr. Secretary, thanks so much for doing this.  I had a question basically about how President Biden is approaching this moment, this kind of perilous moment.  I think we’ve – you mentioned what people back home are hearing, and I think they do hear from some lawmakers that they feel like President Biden is acting too scared of Putin, that in some of the moves on the jets, for example, that he’s being too cautious.  And President Biden has this long history dealing with Putin on this issue of Ukraine and in general.  So I’m wondering if you could speak at all to how he views Putin, like, as sort of an adversary in this moment and if that’s informing any of that caution that we’re seeing.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Sure, thanks.  Let me say a couple of things.  First of all, there may be a natural tendency sometimes to look at something that we’re not doing, which of course jumps over what we are doing.  And let me start there because it’s important.</p>
<p>Well before the aggression that Russia committed took place, we saw this coming; we worked very hard to try to keep it on a diplomatic track, dialogue, avert this aggression.  But even as we were doing that, we were preparing for the possibility and, increasingly, the likelihood that Russia would reject diplomacy and dialogue and pursue the aggression.  And so well before they went in, over the previous year, President Biden provided more security assistance to Ukraine in that year than in any previous year.  And as a result, the Ukrainians had in their hands when the Russians came in the very kind of equipment that has been incredibly effective in dealing with planes attacking from the air, tanks firing from the ground, missiles and rockets, et cetera.  All of that stuff – the anti-air equipment, the anti-armor equipment – much of that was already there because he had made that commitment and followed through on it.</p>
<p>Similarly, we said for months that if Russia committed an act – this act of aggression, there would be massive consequences, including unprecedented economic sanctions.  And I think some folks thought, well, that sounds good but what are we really going to see if it happens.  I think we’ve demonstrated that when we said there would be massive consequences, there were, there have been.  As a result of these sanctions, done in an unprecedented way in terms of their coordination with other countries, we’re basically seeing Russia’s economy in a freefall.  The ruble is through the floor.  Russia’s credit rating is junk status.  The stock market’s been closed for three weeks.  We’ve seen an exodus of virtually every leading company, brand, firm from Russia over the last few weeks such that basically in the space of a few weeks, 30 years of Russia opening to the world and creating greater economic opportunity for our people has vanished as a result of President Putin’s terrible actions.</p>
<p>So all of that’s happening, and of course we remain the leading provider of humanitarian assistance to Ukrainians, whether in Ukraine or those who have been forced to flee.  So when it comes to the things that are making the Ukrainians most effective in dealing with this onslaught from Russia, we’ve been providing it, and you heard the President yesterday describe in some detail another $800 million in security assistance and everything that that actually translates into.  So that’s really important.</p>
<p>The Pentagon, when they looked at this, we – there’s a lot of talk about the airplanes.  And by the way, President Zelenskyy is, as I think we’ve all seen, extraordinary and his leadership is both inspiring and genuinely heroic because he’s remained right in harm’s way leading his people.  And if I’m in his shoes, I’m going to be doing – I’m going to be asking for everything that I can possibly get.  I totally understand that.  We have to make judgments and determinations about what makes the most sense when it comes to the airplanes, for example.  The Pentagon made a determination that these would actually not be the most effective things that Ukraine could get, that what is effective is exactly what we’re doing and doing even more of, which are these anti-air and anti-armor systems that are actually shooting down planes and destroying tanks and armored vehicles.  That’s what’s working.</p>
<p>Second, I’d just say this:  We obviously have an incentive in trying to end this war as quickly as possible, not expand it, including to places beyond Ukraine.  And at the end of the day, all of us, every single one of us, except for one person, can – has the freedom to say oh, we should do this, that, or the other thing, and in very good faith, but only one person bears the ultimate responsibility for making that decision, for deciding, and with the responsibility of what is in the interest of the United States and our people, and that’s the President.  The buck stops there.  So I can advise something; Senator X can advise something, Congressman Y, a newspaper columnist, whatever.  But ultimately the responsibility, the burden of the decision falls on the President, and he is best placed to make the judgment about what’s ultimately in the interest of the American people.  That’s how he’s looking at it.</p>
<p>So we’re determined to support Ukraine, and we are.  We’re determined to exert extraordinary pressure on Russia, and we are.  But the most important thing is he’s got to do all that, making a judgment about what’s fundamentally in our interest, and that’s how he’s proceeded.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And on that point of his insight into Vladimir Putin?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Liz, we’re just going to move around, and if we have time we’ll come back.  But we’ll go to Ashley Murray.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, Secretary Blinken.  Thank you so much for your time.  I have two questions.  First is I understand – you just explained and I’ve read that the U.S. is the leading provider of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  But I’m wondering if you can comment on the U.S.’s possible plan or anything in the works to extend that to other countries surrounding Ukraine as they face the refugee crisis flooding over the borders, and possibly even to Europe beyond the eastern flank.</p>
<p>And then secondly, many of the persons and entities on the sanctions list now, specially designated persons and banks, Russian banks – we’re also (inaudible).  Can you comment on how these (inaudible) round would do anything (inaudible) they’re more effective?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So Ashley, I’m sorry, I didn’t quite get the second part of your question about the sanctions and the different entities.  Could you repeat it, because you were breaking up a little?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So sorry.  Why these (inaudible) of sanctions would be more effective than the ones announced in 2014 or even some in 2018.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Got it.  Thanks.  Got it.  Thank you.  So with regard to the humanitarian assistance piece of this, the supplemental funding that Congress has provided, which is very, very significant and powerful – we got about $13.6 billion – of that about $4 billion goes to humanitarian assistance for Ukraine.  But that includes, significantly, not just assistance that we’re trying to get into Ukraine to help Ukrainians who are still there but also to help Ukrainians who have been forced to flee to the neighboring countries, as well as helping those countries sort of support the burden that they’re bearing of taking in so many people as refugees, for however long that lasts.</p>
<p>So there’s significant resources going to that, that are going to neighboring countries to help them, that are going to organizations like UNHCR to support the work that they’re doing directly.  And as we’re doing that, we’re also working – I was on, for example, a call today with my counterparts from the G7 countries.  These are the world’s leading democratic economies, and so it’s France, it’s Germany, it’s the UK, it’s Italy, it’s Canada, it’s Japan, as well as the European Union.  And one of the things we’re talking about today is how we can effectively channel our resources to support countries, particularly the neighboring countries that are bearing such a burden – Poland, little Moldova, Romania, others.  And we’re very focused on doing that and making sure they have the resources they need.</p>
<p>We’re also looking when it comes to refugees about what we can do ourselves and talking both to UNHCR about that, looking what we can do in a sort of coordinated way with these other leading countries to try to deal with some of the burden that refugees will pose to these countries.  So more on that in the days to come, but already a big chunk of our assistance is actually going to neighboring countries.</p>
<p>On the sanctions piece, what’s different this time is – there are a number of things that are different, but first and foremost, I think what you’ve seen take place with the sanctions on virtually all of the leading Russian financial institutions, the banks and others, have been devastating to their ability to do business.  The sanctions on the central bank have meant that even though Russia built up a lot of reserves, they’ve been unable to use those reserves to prop up the ruble.  They can’t go and buy rubles abroad because they’re sanctioned, and the value of the currency has plummeted.  As I mentioned, the stock market’s been closed for three weeks as well.</p>
<p>The elites that we’ve sanctioned, well, not only are we preventing them from doing things, but we’re – much more aggressively than we’ve ever done in the past – actually going after them. And there is a whole task force that was set up with other countries to freeze and seize their assets – the mega yachts, the fancy apartments, the sports cars – in ways that they’re going to feel very directly.  Many of them are finding it impossible to do business with anyone anymore.</p>
<p>And then we’ve seen something extraordinary that is not the direct result of the sanctions, but has been incredibly powerful, and that is this exodus of virtually every leading company from Russia.  I mean, if you – I had a document that a few days ago was probably eight or nine pages long – it’s probably almost double that by now – with this list of everyone from McDonald’s to Apple to Coca Cola to Toyota to Netflix to MasterCard and Visa to you name it.  And that is actually having a very dramatic impact on Russians in their day-to-day lives – not something any of us do or see with any joy or pleasure, not at all.  But we have to maximize the impact that we’re having on Putin and his decision making, and that’s one way to do it.</p>
<p>Last thing I’ll say on the sanctions is that one of the things you’re going to see have an impact over time are the export controls that we put in place with other countries to deny Russia the technology that it needs to modernize critical industries – defense, aerospace, energy exploration. And as a result, they will not be able to modernize, to develop these sectors in ways that will help their economy advance or help strengthen their strategic interests or position.  That’s going to be felt increasingly over time.  And then to the extent that they are a supplier of such equipment and technologies to other countries, those countries are not going to be interested in taking stuff that is increasingly outdated and ineffective.</p>
<p>So there’s a huge immediate impact, and an impact that’s going to build over time for as long as this goes on.  Of course, the purpose of all of this is not to have these things in perpetuity.  The purpose of the sanctions is to change their conduct, along with everything else that we’re doing. And so that’s what we hope happens.  But I think by just about any objective measure, the sanctions themselves are unprecedented when you go through each and every one of them, and the impact they’re already having is unprecedented – look at every metric of the Russian economy and you can see that things are going through the floor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>(Inaudible) Secretary.  Thank you for doing the call.  When you talk about sanctions and the impact, obviously, as you put it, they have had an impact but they haven’t been able to deter Putin from invading, from targeting civilians, hospitals.  And you’ve talked about now the possibility of chemical weapons being used.  What you have on the table that could either deter him or that you could do beyond what’s already been done to increase the punishments if he does use chemical weapons?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>So, of course, you hope that the prospect of sanctions – of economic measures – will prove to be a deterrent and actually prevent the aggression that you’re trying to prevent.  And certainly, as we worked on these for many months and coordinated these with allies and partners and made very clear that there would be massive consequences, our first hope was that that would help deter the aggression.  It didn’t.  So now there are two things that are in play.  One is – we’ve demonstrated that when we said there would be massive consequences, there are.  That’s being felt more and more each day.  And so at some point, that price, that burden, that impact may have the effect of stopping what Putin has started.</p>
<p>But ultimately, I think what is really having an impact there is the extraordinary resistance, courage, bravery of the Ukrainian people, supported by us and many other countries, in terms of the impact that they’re having on this Russian onslaught.  And we’re seeing that virtually everything happening on the ground in Ukraine is not going according to Putin’s plan – far from it.  And, again, you’re all seeing it, reporting it pretty much every day.  The cumulative impact of all of that – the pressure being brought to bear and the resistance that is having a powerful impact on the invading forces – that at some point in time we hope will push Russia to do something different.  The problem is it’s not flipping a light switch.  It does take time for them to reassess, calculate their interests, and to see that what they’re doing is profoundly not in their own interest.</p>
<p>So I think that will build.  That’s why I was saying earlier that we also have to, I think tragically, be prepared for this to go on for some time, because it – again, it’s not like flipping a switch.  It accumulates, the pressure builds, the consequences build, and ultimately, countries have to reckon with that and change what they’re doing as a result of that.</p>
<p>So that’s where we are, and it’s unfortunately a process, not a – not something that’s automatic.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Jerry, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Secretary Blinken, thank you for doing this.  It’s very helpful.  I have kind of a multi-pronged question about the refugee crisis.  First of all, I’m wondering what your sense is, at this point in time, whether there will be large numbers of Ukrainian refugees who would like to resettle in the U.S., what your approach to that may be, whether it’ll be through the UNHCR process or something else, and whether they’ll be going to the kind of metro areas that have been very welcoming over time to refugees, such as Buffalo.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Couple of things on that.  First, just to emphasize, this is already the largest refugee crisis in Europe since World War II just in terms of numbers.  And I think there’s every expectation that it’s going to grow.  And so we’re well north of 2.5 million people at this point, not to mention those who are displaced within Ukraine.  And as long as this goes on, the brutality continues, more and more people will leave.  That’s the situation we’re dealing with now, but it’s also the expectation that we have going forward.</p>
<p>And it’s why countries are coming together to figure out what we can do, both individually but also collectively, to help care for, welcome, support those who are refugees – either by supporting other countries that are taking them in or taking people in ourselves.  That’s – and so a lot of work is going into addressing that right now, making sure the resources are there, making sure that the lead organizations like UNHCR are where they need to be and have the support that they need to have, et cetera.</p>
<p>What we’re seeing right now – but this is likely to change at some point, but – as the numbers grow bigger – right now the strong desire of most people leaving is to stay as close to Ukraine as they can, and certainly to stay within Europe, for a couple of reasons.  One is, I think as you know, the people leaving now are almost all women and children.  Adult men, men between the ages of 18 and 60, are asked to stay in Ukraine to fight for their country.  And so the women and children who are leaving and separating from husbands and sons and brothers, they want to stay, if they can, as close at hand as possible in the hopes that they can be quickly reunited and in the hopes that the war will end quickly and they can go home.  Second, many Ukrainians have family, relatives in Europe, and once you’re in Europe, you have a fair bit of freedom of movement.  And so their second impulse is to get together with family and others in Europe itself.</p>
<p>Having said that, given the numbers that we’re looking at, there is almost certainly going to be an interest, a demand on countries far from Europe – including the United States – to take people in.  In the first instance, we have the referral process that I know you’re familiar with, where someone goes to UNHCR, seeks refugee status, and then people get referred to us.  But that’s a lengthy process, and what we’re looking at is whether there are more near-term steps that we can take that would help do our part in bringing people to the United States – for example, family reunification.  This is one of the things we’re looking at right now.</p>
<p>I expect that we’ll have more to say about that in the coming days as we really plunge into this, but we’re determined to do our part in showing that we’re a place of refuge and welcome as well, and particularly because there are such strong Ukrainian American communities here, I know that people would be very welcoming.  But more in the coming days.  For now, we’re focused on helping countries that are already taking in refugees, supporting UNHCR, and looking at some near-term ways that we can do things like family reunification.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yvonne, go ahead.  Yvonne, I think you’re still on mute.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks so much for doing this, Secretary.  What is the State Department doing to try to allow for Brittney Griner to meet with consular officials in Russia?  Why have requests for such a meeting been denied thus far?  And can you give us a sense of what difference such a meeting would make?  Separately, can you give us a sense of what her condition is?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks.  So we – whenever an American is detained anywhere, our job, our responsibility, our determination is to make sure that we’re doing everything possible to help them, to defend their rights, and to see what assistance, if any, they need.  And that’s anywhere in the world where this happens in one way or the other.</p>
<p>In Brittney’s case, in the first instance, we weren’t talking about it with any specificity because there were privacy concerns that we needed to respect.  Now, what I can tell you is that we’re in very active contact with her team, with – literally with the WNBA, as well as with her lawyers and other representatives.  We are and have been seeking consular access because we want to see firsthand how she’s doing.  We want to make sure that we know that she’s okay.</p>
<p>And this is, by the way, required under international law.  The Russians are required to give us that access.  They have not; it has been denied.  So we are working very hard on getting it, on being able to get access to her, to hear directly from her how she’s doing, and to make sure we’re doing everything we can to see to it that her rights are being respected and upheld in the Russian system and in terms of international law.</p>
<p>So it’s a work very much in progress.  I wish I had something positive to report in terms of actually getting access.  To date we’ve not been able to do that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  All right, seeing no other hands, want to thank everyone for taking part in this.  We do want to make this a regular occurrence, and even when the Secretary isn’t available, please do know that you can come to us at any time.  I think you all know how to reach our – me and our press office.  If you don’t, we’re happy to pass along that information, but thank you all very much for taking part and we look forward to seeing you again before long.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, everyone.  Appreciate it.  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary Medina’s Travel to Costa Rica and Mexico</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-medinas-travel-to-costa-rica-and-mexico/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 18:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325882</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Assistant Secretary Monica P. Medina will travel to Costa Rica, March 20-23, to join Under Secretary of State for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment Jose W. Fernandez in discussions on the Eastern Tropical Pacific Marine Corridor (CMAR).  The Assistant Secretary will also engage on important conservation efforts and advocate for further action to preserve nature on land and in the ocean.</p>
<p>From March 23-25, Assistant Secretary Medina will travel to Mexico to reinforce our bilateral relationship on a range of environmental issues, including marine conservation, plastic pollution, and illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing.  She will also meet with women in STEM fields from industry, academia, and civil society, and discuss space cooperation with representatives of the Mexican Space Agency.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov.</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Assistant Secretary Monica P. Medina will travel to Costa Rica, March 20-23, to join Under Secretary of State for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment Jose W. Fernandez in discussions on the Eastern Tropical Pacific Marine Corridor (CMAR).  The Assistant Secretary will also engage on important conservation efforts and advocate for further action to preserve nature on land and in the ocean.</p>
<p>From March 23-25, Assistant Secretary Medina will travel to Mexico to reinforce our bilateral relationship on a range of environmental issues, including marine conservation, plastic pollution, and illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing.  She will also meet with women in STEM fields from industry, academia, and civil society, and discuss space cooperation with representatives of the Mexican Space Agency.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov.</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department of State Offers Reward for Information to Bring Guatemalan Drug Trafficker to Justice</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/department-of-state-offers-reward-for-information-to-bring-guatemalan-drug-trafficker-to-justice/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 14:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325776</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State is offering a reward of up to $10 million for information leading to the arrest or conviction of Eugenio Darío Molina-López (“Molina”), a Guatemalan international drug trafficker.  Molina is a leader of a Transnational Criminal Organization (TCO) known as Los Huistas.  Los Huistas is primarily based in the Huehuetenango region of Northwest Guatemala that borders Mexico.  Molina’s leadership within Los Huistas is well known to the U.S. and Guatemalan governments, and we are working together to bring him to justice.</p>
<p>This reward offer complements a Department of Justice indictment against Molina and other co-conspirators, as well as a Department of the Treasury action taken by the Office of Foreign Assets Control to impose financial sanctions on Molina and other individuals and entities associated with Los Huistas under Executive Order 14059.  This is another example of the U.S. government’s coordinated approach to fighting transnational organized crime in Central America.</p>
<p>This reward is offered under the Department of State’s Narcotics Rewards Program (NRP), which the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs manages in close coordination with federal law enforcement partners and other U.S. government agencies. More than 75 transnational criminals and major narcotics traffickers have been brought to justice with the help of the NRP since its inception in 1986, with the Department paying more than $135 million in rewards to-date.</p>
<p>Any tips should be provided to DHS Homeland Security Investigations (HSI) via WhatsApp, Telegram, or Signal at +1-619-350-2012 or by email at <a href="mailto:molina.tips@ice.dhs.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">molina.tips@ice.dhs.gov</a>.</p>
<p>For more information on the individuals listed above and the NRP, please see <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs/inl-rewards-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMTguNTUxMTM1ODEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1LW9mLWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtbmFyY290aWNzLWFuZC1sYXctZW5mb3JjZW1lbnQtYWZmYWlycy9pbmwtcmV3YXJkcy1wcm9ncmFtLyJ9.IEbSfLh_TqTrrF1wTTKal9ZfB7YHaHQd_Ux-8wh8dh0/s/1039202793/br/128343856986-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1647700478541000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1cuLPfz_KDcq94pZ63qiWk">https://www.state.gov/bureau-<wbr />of-international-narcotics-<wbr />and-law-enforcement-affairs/<wbr />inl-rewards-program/</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State is offering a reward of up to $10 million for information leading to the arrest or conviction of Eugenio Darío Molina-López (“Molina”), a Guatemalan international drug trafficker.  Molina is a leader of a Transnational Criminal Organization (TCO) known as Los Huistas.  Los Huistas is primarily based in the Huehuetenango region of Northwest Guatemala that borders Mexico.  Molina’s leadership within Los Huistas is well known to the U.S. and Guatemalan governments, and we are working together to bring him to justice.</p>
<p>This reward offer complements a Department of Justice indictment against Molina and other co-conspirators, as well as a Department of the Treasury action taken by the Office of Foreign Assets Control to impose financial sanctions on Molina and other individuals and entities associated with Los Huistas under Executive Order 14059.  This is another example of the U.S. government’s coordinated approach to fighting transnational organized crime in Central America.</p>
<p>This reward is offered under the Department of State’s Narcotics Rewards Program (NRP), which the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs manages in close coordination with federal law enforcement partners and other U.S. government agencies. More than 75 transnational criminals and major narcotics traffickers have been brought to justice with the help of the NRP since its inception in 1986, with the Department paying more than $135 million in rewards to-date.</p>
<p>Any tips should be provided to DHS Homeland Security Investigations (HSI) via WhatsApp, Telegram, or Signal at +1-619-350-2012 or by email at <a href="mailto:molina.tips@ice.dhs.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">molina.tips@ice.dhs.gov</a>.</p>
<p>For more information on the individuals listed above and the NRP, please see <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs/inl-rewards-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMTguNTUxMTM1ODEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1LW9mLWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtbmFyY290aWNzLWFuZC1sYXctZW5mb3JjZW1lbnQtYWZmYWlycy9pbmwtcmV3YXJkcy1wcm9ncmFtLyJ9.IEbSfLh_TqTrrF1wTTKal9ZfB7YHaHQd_Ux-8wh8dh0/s/1039202793/br/128343856986-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1647700478541000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1cuLPfz_KDcq94pZ63qiWk">https://www.state.gov/bureau-<wbr />of-international-narcotics-<wbr />and-law-enforcement-affairs/<wbr />inl-rewards-program/</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aruba National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/aruba-national-day-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 14:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States government, I congratulate the people of Aruba on your National Day celebrating the 36th anniversary of Aruba’s <em>Status Aparte</em>.</p>
<p>We deeply value the strong ties between our two countries and commend Aruba’s steadfast support for Ukraine and readiness to take action with allies to protect and defend democracy.  The signing of Aruba’s historic energy deal with an American company for your transition to clean energy further highlights our shared vision for a more prosperous and sustainable future.  We welcome the opportunity to promote educational opportunities for Aruba’s youth at our EducationUSA Advising Center and to facilitate secure travel through a strong U.S. Customs and Border Protection program.</p>
<p>In appreciation of the strong relationship that we share, I wish all Arubans a happy National Anthem and Flag Day.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States government, I congratulate the people of Aruba on your National Day celebrating the 36th anniversary of Aruba’s <em>Status Aparte</em>.</p>
<p>We deeply value the strong ties between our two countries and commend Aruba’s steadfast support for Ukraine and readiness to take action with allies to protect and defend democracy.  The signing of Aruba’s historic energy deal with an American company for your transition to clean energy further highlights our shared vision for a more prosperous and sustainable future.  We welcome the opportunity to promote educational opportunities for Aruba’s youth at our EducationUSA Advising Center and to facilitate secure travel through a strong U.S. Customs and Border Protection program.</p>
<p>In appreciation of the strong relationship that we share, I wish all Arubans a happy National Anthem and Flag Day.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary Nuland’s Travel to Bangladesh, India, and Sri Lanka</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-nulands-travel-to-bangladesh-india-and-sri-lanka/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 12:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325707</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland will travel March 19-23 to Bangladesh, India, and Sri Lanka with an interagency delegation to underscore U.S. commitment to, and cooperation with, Indo-Pacific partners.  Under Secretary Nuland will hold Partnership Dialogues in Bangladesh and Sri Lanka and Foreign Office Consultations in New Delhi.  On each stop, Under Secretary Nuland and the delegation will meet with civil society and business leaders to strengthen economic partnerships and deepen ties in the pursuit of peace, prosperity, and security in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p>Other senior members of the delegation include Assistant Secretary for South and Central Asian Affairs Donald Lu and Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Policy Amanda Dory.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:sca-press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sca-press@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland will travel March 19-23 to Bangladesh, India, and Sri Lanka with an interagency delegation to underscore U.S. commitment to, and cooperation with, Indo-Pacific partners.  Under Secretary Nuland will hold Partnership Dialogues in Bangladesh and Sri Lanka and Foreign Office Consultations in New Delhi.  On each stop, Under Secretary Nuland and the delegation will meet with civil society and business leaders to strengthen economic partnerships and deepen ties in the pursuit of peace, prosperity, and security in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p>Other senior members of the delegation include Assistant Secretary for South and Central Asian Affairs Donald Lu and Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Policy Amanda Dory.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:sca-press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sca-press@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-Croatia Joint Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-croatia-joint-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 22:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><i>The following is the text of a joint statement by the United States of America and the Republic of Croatia on the occasion of the U.S. Croatia Strategic Dialogue</i><i>.</i></p>
<p><i>Begin text:</i></p>
<p>The Governments of the United States and Croatia held a Strategic Dialogue in Washington, D.C. on March 17, 2022, which underscored the deepening cooperation between the United States and Croatia and sets the vision for our shared goals of promoting peace, security, and prosperity in both Europe and globally.</p>
<p>The Strategic Dialogue comes as the United States and Croatia mark the 30th anniversary of diplomatic relations.</p>
<p>Croatian Ministry of Foreign and European Affairs Director for Political Affairs Petar Mihatov and U.S. Assistant Secretary of State for European and Eurasian Affairs Dr. Karen Donfried led the Strategic Dialogue, which included discussions on six key pillars of the bilateral relationship:  Global Issues, Defense and Security, Energy and Climate Change, Regional Cooperation, Trade and Investment, and People-to-People Ties.</p>
<p><b>Global Issues </b></p>
<p>The United States and Croatia committed to work together to advance shared foreign policy goals, intensify bilateral cooperation and strengthen the Transatlantic bond.  They also committed to promote democracy, rule of law, and fundamental human rights both regionally and globally, building on pledges made during President Biden’s Summit for Democracy in December 2021.  The United States and Croatia underscored their strong support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and called on Russia to cease its unprovoked war.  They underscored a joint desire to defend the common values of the Euro-Atlantic community and stressed the importance of preserving the rules-based international order, supporting good governance, and protecting democratic societies.  The United States welcomed Croatia’s entry as the 40th member of the Visa Waiver program and affirmed Croatia has made great progress toward becoming a partner country in the Global Entry Program.  The United States welcomed Croatia’s commitment to fully empower a Holocaust envoy with a view to intensifying dialogue on all related issues, including property wrongfully seized during the Holocaust.</p>
<p><b>Defense and Security </b></p>
<p>As NATO Allies and strategic partners, the United States and Croatia underscored their commitment to promoting peace and stability in Southeast Europe and Europe as a whole.  Both sides emphasized the continued importance of developing high-end defense capabilities, conducting bilateral exercises and training activities to improve interoperability and readiness, and the importance of meeting NATO commitments in support of our collective security.  The United States and Croatia reaffirmed that the most recent cooperation resulting in Croatian procurement of M2A2 Bradley vehicles is a significant step toward meeting one of Croatia’s priority NATO Capability Target requirements.  The two countries intend to work closely on the future Strategic Concept of NATO, with a view to strengthening the Alliance in fulfilling its mission as the guarantor of peace and security in Europe.  Both parties underlined the importance of EU-NATO cooperation, ensuring complementarity and strengthening interoperability, and recognized NATO as the foundation of Euro-Atlantic security and the essential forum for collective defense of the transatlantic community.  The United States and Croatia underscored the importance of cybersecurity and intend to look to strengthen cooperation in this field.</p>
<p><b>Energy and Climate Change </b></p>
<p>The United States and Croatia recommitted to their shared goals of increasing energy diversification and security and tackling climate change through decarbonization and clean energy policies, as well as the adaptation of our societies to climate change.  The United States lauded Croatia for its leadership on energy diversification through the opening of the floating liquefied natural gas terminal off Krk island and noted the shared goal that Croatia support energy diversification for the broader region through projects like the Southern Connector to Bosnia and Herzegovina.  The two sides explored opportunities for strengthening cooperation in renewable energy production and distribution.  Croatia reiterated its commitment to phase out coal by 2033, and the United States praised Croatia’s goal to achieve net zero emissions by 2050 and join the Global Methane Pledge.  Both sides committed to deepen bilateral and regional cooperation on energy and climate through the Partnership for Transatlantic Energy and Climate Cooperation (P-TECC).</p>
<p><b>Regional Cooperation </b></p>
<p>The United States and Croatia emphasized their joint commitment to advance the Euro-Atlantic perspective of the Western Balkans countries, and to see Croatia’s neighbors firmly anchored in a Europe free, whole, and at peace.  The United States and Croatia recognized that the countries of the Western Balkans must meet the strict criteria to join the EU and NATO while underscoring that the door to these organizations must remain open and viable to incentivize necessary reforms to promote lasting stability and security.  The United States and Croatia concurred on the importance of preserving the stability and territorial integrity of Bosnia and Herzegovina, and the need to secure electoral and limited constitutional reforms aimed at eliminating all forms of discrimination and ensuring the equality of three constituent peoples and rights of all citizens.  They also concurred on the need to eliminate fraud, corruption, and pressure on voters, and to ensure election outcomes reflect the will of the people.  The United States and Croatia highlighted the importance of Western Balkans countries resolving near-term legacy and open issues as an essential step on their Euro-Atlantic path.  The United States thanked Croatia for its leadership on joint efforts to fight corruption and protect the rule of law through the INL-funded Department of Justice law enforcement educational partnership and prosecutor training in the Western Balkans.</p>
<p><b>Trade and Investment </b></p>
<p>The two sides reaffirmed their shared commitment to broaden and deepen bilateral economic and commercial cooperation, expressing satisfaction with reaching a final stage of negotiations and recognizing the desire for a swift conclusion of a treaty for the avoidance of double taxation.  They shared ideas on increasing trade and investment across various sectors.  The United States welcomed Croatia’s invitation to begin the accession process to the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development.  Croatia and the United States exchanged ideas and concrete plans for intensifying cooperation taking into account the growing urgency for development and humanitarian aid for countries in need.</p>
<p><b>People-to-People Ties   </b></p>
<p>The United States and Croatia share extensive and meaningful people-to-people connections that promote mutual understanding between the people of both nations.  Both countries remain committed to expanding educational, cultural, and professional exchange opportunities, including through the Fulbright Program.  The two sides look forward to collaboration on STEM programming and enhanced connections between U.S. and Croatian universities.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><i>The following is the text of a joint statement by the United States of America and the Republic of Croatia on the occasion of the U.S. Croatia Strategic Dialogue</i><i>.</i></p>
<p><i>Begin text:</i></p>
<p>The Governments of the United States and Croatia held a Strategic Dialogue in Washington, D.C. on March 17, 2022, which underscored the deepening cooperation between the United States and Croatia and sets the vision for our shared goals of promoting peace, security, and prosperity in both Europe and globally.</p>
<p>The Strategic Dialogue comes as the United States and Croatia mark the 30th anniversary of diplomatic relations.</p>
<p>Croatian Ministry of Foreign and European Affairs Director for Political Affairs Petar Mihatov and U.S. Assistant Secretary of State for European and Eurasian Affairs Dr. Karen Donfried led the Strategic Dialogue, which included discussions on six key pillars of the bilateral relationship:  Global Issues, Defense and Security, Energy and Climate Change, Regional Cooperation, Trade and Investment, and People-to-People Ties.</p>
<p><b>Global Issues </b></p>
<p>The United States and Croatia committed to work together to advance shared foreign policy goals, intensify bilateral cooperation and strengthen the Transatlantic bond.  They also committed to promote democracy, rule of law, and fundamental human rights both regionally and globally, building on pledges made during President Biden’s Summit for Democracy in December 2021.  The United States and Croatia underscored their strong support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and called on Russia to cease its unprovoked war.  They underscored a joint desire to defend the common values of the Euro-Atlantic community and stressed the importance of preserving the rules-based international order, supporting good governance, and protecting democratic societies.  The United States welcomed Croatia’s entry as the 40th member of the Visa Waiver program and affirmed Croatia has made great progress toward becoming a partner country in the Global Entry Program.  The United States welcomed Croatia’s commitment to fully empower a Holocaust envoy with a view to intensifying dialogue on all related issues, including property wrongfully seized during the Holocaust.</p>
<p><b>Defense and Security </b></p>
<p>As NATO Allies and strategic partners, the United States and Croatia underscored their commitment to promoting peace and stability in Southeast Europe and Europe as a whole.  Both sides emphasized the continued importance of developing high-end defense capabilities, conducting bilateral exercises and training activities to improve interoperability and readiness, and the importance of meeting NATO commitments in support of our collective security.  The United States and Croatia reaffirmed that the most recent cooperation resulting in Croatian procurement of M2A2 Bradley vehicles is a significant step toward meeting one of Croatia’s priority NATO Capability Target requirements.  The two countries intend to work closely on the future Strategic Concept of NATO, with a view to strengthening the Alliance in fulfilling its mission as the guarantor of peace and security in Europe.  Both parties underlined the importance of EU-NATO cooperation, ensuring complementarity and strengthening interoperability, and recognized NATO as the foundation of Euro-Atlantic security and the essential forum for collective defense of the transatlantic community.  The United States and Croatia underscored the importance of cybersecurity and intend to look to strengthen cooperation in this field.</p>
<p><b>Energy and Climate Change </b></p>
<p>The United States and Croatia recommitted to their shared goals of increasing energy diversification and security and tackling climate change through decarbonization and clean energy policies, as well as the adaptation of our societies to climate change.  The United States lauded Croatia for its leadership on energy diversification through the opening of the floating liquefied natural gas terminal off Krk island and noted the shared goal that Croatia support energy diversification for the broader region through projects like the Southern Connector to Bosnia and Herzegovina.  The two sides explored opportunities for strengthening cooperation in renewable energy production and distribution.  Croatia reiterated its commitment to phase out coal by 2033, and the United States praised Croatia’s goal to achieve net zero emissions by 2050 and join the Global Methane Pledge.  Both sides committed to deepen bilateral and regional cooperation on energy and climate through the Partnership for Transatlantic Energy and Climate Cooperation (P-TECC).</p>
<p><b>Regional Cooperation </b></p>
<p>The United States and Croatia emphasized their joint commitment to advance the Euro-Atlantic perspective of the Western Balkans countries, and to see Croatia’s neighbors firmly anchored in a Europe free, whole, and at peace.  The United States and Croatia recognized that the countries of the Western Balkans must meet the strict criteria to join the EU and NATO while underscoring that the door to these organizations must remain open and viable to incentivize necessary reforms to promote lasting stability and security.  The United States and Croatia concurred on the importance of preserving the stability and territorial integrity of Bosnia and Herzegovina, and the need to secure electoral and limited constitutional reforms aimed at eliminating all forms of discrimination and ensuring the equality of three constituent peoples and rights of all citizens.  They also concurred on the need to eliminate fraud, corruption, and pressure on voters, and to ensure election outcomes reflect the will of the people.  The United States and Croatia highlighted the importance of Western Balkans countries resolving near-term legacy and open issues as an essential step on their Euro-Atlantic path.  The United States thanked Croatia for its leadership on joint efforts to fight corruption and protect the rule of law through the INL-funded Department of Justice law enforcement educational partnership and prosecutor training in the Western Balkans.</p>
<p><b>Trade and Investment </b></p>
<p>The two sides reaffirmed their shared commitment to broaden and deepen bilateral economic and commercial cooperation, expressing satisfaction with reaching a final stage of negotiations and recognizing the desire for a swift conclusion of a treaty for the avoidance of double taxation.  They shared ideas on increasing trade and investment across various sectors.  The United States welcomed Croatia’s invitation to begin the accession process to the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development.  Croatia and the United States exchanged ideas and concrete plans for intensifying cooperation taking into account the growing urgency for development and humanitarian aid for countries in need.</p>
<p><b>People-to-People Ties   </b></p>
<p>The United States and Croatia share extensive and meaningful people-to-people connections that promote mutual understanding between the people of both nations.  Both countries remain committed to expanding educational, cultural, and professional exchange opportunities, including through the Fulbright Program.  The two sides look forward to collaboration on STEM programming and enhanced connections between U.S. and Croatian universities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at a Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-press-availability-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 21:33:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325622</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Press Briefing Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone.</p>
<p>Three weeks ago, Russia launched its unprovoked war on Ukraine.</p>
<p>With every day that passes, the numbers of civilians, including children, killed and wounded continues to climb.</p>
<p>Russia continues to attack civilian sites, including – this week alone – a hospital, three schools, a boarding school for visually impaired kids in the Luhansk region of Ukraine.</p>
<p>Yesterday Russian forces bombed a theater in Mariupol, where hundreds of people had been taking shelter.</p>
<p>The word “children” had been written in Russian in giant white letters on the pavement outside the building, so that you could know from the air that there were children inside.</p>
<p>Russian forces also opened fire on 10 civilians in who were waiting in line for bread.</p>
<p>These incidents join a long list of attacks on civilian – not military – locations across Ukraine, including apartment buildings, public squares, and, last week, a maternity hospital in Mariupol.</p>
<p>I doubt that any of us who saw those images will ever forget them.</p>
<p>We’ve seen Russia use similar tactics before in Grozny and Aleppo.  They stepped up their bombardment with the goal of breaking the will of the people.</p>
<p>Yesterday President Biden said that, in his opinion, war crimes have been committed in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Personally, I agree.</p>
<p>Intentionally targeting civilians is a war crime.</p>
<p>After all the destruction of the past three weeks, I find it difficult to conclude that the Russians are doing otherwise.</p>
<p>The consequences of Moscow’s war are being felt around the world – in rising food costs, concerns about fuel supplies, more broadly in worries about how this war will affect the global economy and the fight against COVID-19.</p>
<p>These are serious issues that the global community urgently needs to address.  This war is making that much more difficult.</p>
<p>In this way, Russia’s actions are having an impact on every person on the planet, wherever they live.</p>
<p>We also feel the impact right here in this room.</p>
<p>There should be a seat reserved here today for Benjamin Hall from Fox News, who was injured badly when his vehicle came under attack near Kyiv.</p>
<p>Many of us, myself included, have gotten to know Ben very well as part of the traveling press corps.</p>
<p>He’s an incredibly talented reporter, always asking tough questions.  He’s a lovely person, as well.</p>
<p>Our thoughts – my thoughts – are with him and his family, including his three little kids.</p>
<p>Two of Ben’s Fox News colleagues, Pierre Zokchefski and Sasha Koofshenova, were killed in the attack.  And Brent Renaud, a reporter on assignment with <i>Time Magazine</i>, was killed in a separate attack a day earlier.</p>
<p>I know that everyone in this room, in particular, feels these losses deeply.</p>
<p>Being a war correspondent is vital work; they make sure that the world knows what’s really happening when armies move in and bombs start falling.</p>
<p>It also takes incredible courage; they go into war zones when others, understandably, are heading out as fast as possible.</p>
<p>So these are huge losses, of course, for families, for friends, but also for their colleagues, their profession, their readers and viewers who understand world events because of them.</p>
<p>Our experts are in the process of documenting and evaluating potential war crimes being committed in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Beth Van Schaack, whom the Senate finally confirmed this week as our Ambassador at Large for Global Criminal Justice, will be leading that effort within the State Department.</p>
<p>We’ll make sure that our findings help international efforts to investigate war crimes and hold those responsible accountable.</p>
<p>I’d also mention that there are several other nominations before the Senate with a direct bearing on our ability to support Ukraine, including for Assistant Secretary of State for Population, Refugees, and Migration; Assistant Secretary of State for International Security and Non-Proliferation; and our Coordinator for Sanctions Policy.</p>
<p>So I urge the Senate to confirm these nominees quickly, so that they can get to work as soon as possible.</p>
<p>A few weeks ago, just days before Russia’s invasion began, I went to the United Nations Security Council to lay out what we believed was about to happen.</p>
<p>Again today, we have a strong sense of what Russia could do next.</p>
<p>We believe that Moscow may be setting the stage to use a chemical weapon, and then falsely blame Ukraine to justify escalating its attacks on the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p>Manufacturing events and creating false narratives of genocide to justify greater use of military force is a tactic that Russia has used before, including in Georgia.</p>
<p>We believe Russia will bring its mercenaries from private military groups and foreign countries to Ukraine.</p>
<p>President Putin acknowledged as much over the weekend when he authorized the recruitment of additional forces from the Middle East and elsewhere – another indication that his war effort is not going as he hoped it would.</p>
<p>They are also likely to systematically kidnap local officials and replace them with puppets.</p>
<p>Again, this has already begun.</p>
<p>The mayor of Melitopol was grabbed off the street several days ago, released yesterday in a prisoner exchange.</p>
<p>The mayor of another city in southern Ukraine was also kidnapped; he hasn’t yet been let go.</p>
<p>This is a terror tactic – grab local officials, depose local governments, put proxies in their place.</p>
<p>After devastating Ukrainian cities, Moscow may bring in officials from Russia to serve as local government officials, and surge what they describe as “economic support” in an attempt to make the people dependent on Moscow for survival.</p>
<p>Again, something that Russia did in Georgia.</p>
<p>President Putin’s invasion of Ukraine is not going to plan.</p>
<p>The Ukrainian people haven’t welcomed the Russian military.  They haven’t submitted.</p>
<p>On the contrary.  They’re fighting with extraordinary courage to protect their homes, their families, their country.</p>
<p>Russia has been hit by unprecedented sanctions and cut off from the global economy.</p>
<p>Its own economy is in free fall.</p>
<p>Hundreds of corporations have closed operations.</p>
<p>In a matter of weeks, President Putin has destroyed 30 years of opening to the world and economic opportunity for the Russian people.</p>
<p>Dozens of members of the Kremlin’s corrupt power base have been sanctioned; several have lost their mega yachts and villas.</p>
<p>President Putin has derided those sanctions, using recent public diatribes to mock Russians living abroad as too dependent, as he said, on “foie gras and oysters.”</p>
<p>Meanwhile, he sits in his mansions, having accumulated billions taking wealth from the Russian people, while they stand in long lines to access cash and watch as stores close and the ruble plummets in value.</p>
<p>It’s no wonder that brave Russians continue to protest the war and be beaten and arrested for it.</p>
<p>And Russian journalists are resigning from their jobs at state media outlets, because they can’t stomach parroting the Kremlin’s lies any longer.</p>
<p>Still, President Putin is not relenting and in fact may be growing more desperate.</p>
<p>And so yesterday, President Biden authorized – announced, excuse me, not authorized – another $800 million in military aid to Ukraine.</p>
<p>That brings our support for Ukraine’s frontline defenders to more than $2 billion during this administration – one billion in the last week alone.</p>
<p>We’re grateful to have a determined and generous partner in Congress, which this week provided more than $13 billion in urgent support to Ukraine.</p>
<p>And we’ll continue to work with lawmakers to support Ukraine and hold the Kremlin to account.</p>
<p>As President Biden described, this new security assistance package includes 800 anti-aircraft systems, to stop attacking planes and helicopters before they destroy more of Ukraine; 9,000 anti-armor systems to destroy tanks and armored vehicles; 7,000 small arms, including machine guns and grenade launchers; and 20 million rounds of ammunition.</p>
<p>We’re also helping Ukraine acquire longer-range anti-aircraft systems and munitions, at President Zelenskyy’s request.</p>
<p>And I have been in almost daily contact with Foreign Minister Kuleba, coordinating to respond swiftly to Ukraine’s most urgent needs.</p>
<p>Our allies and partners continue to step up with their own significant shipments of security assistance.</p>
<p>I’ve authorized more than a dozen countries to provide U.S.-origin equipment, and dozens more around the world have provided security assistance of their own.</p>
<p>I’d also note that, in addition to assistance from the Department of Defense, we’re sending support from other agencies, including $10 million worth of armored vehicles from our own Diplomatic Security Service.</p>
<p>And yesterday I announced another $186 million in humanitarian assistance to help the more than 3 million refugees who have fled Ukraine in the past three weeks – the fastest-growing refugee crisis in Europe since World War II – as well as internally displaced people still in Ukraine.</p>
<p>This brings our total humanitarian aid since last month to $293 million.</p>
<p>And of the more than $13 billion for Ukraine that Congress is putting forward, more than 4 billion of that will go to humanitarian assistance.</p>
<p>Ukraine’s neighbors in Europe are generously welcoming, supporting refugees.  The United States will do our part to help those governments and the humanitarian organizations on the ground meet this tremendous need.</p>
<p>All the steps that we and our allies and partners are taking are aimed at one goal: to end the war.</p>
<p>The support we’re providing Ukraine, as well as our financial and economic measures against Moscow, will strengthen Ukraine’s hand at the diplomatic table.</p>
<p>And we commend Ukraine for staying at that table and continuing to pursue diplomacy while the Kremlin’s brutal aggression continues.</p>
<p>We’ll support Ukraine’s diplomatic efforts however we can.</p>
<p>We continue to call on all nations, especially those with direct influence with Russia, to use whatever leverage they have to compel Moscow to end this war of choice.</p>
<p>We believe China in particular has a responsibility to use its influence with President Putin and to defend the international rules and principles that it professes to support.</p>
<p>Instead, it appears that China is moving in the opposite direction by refusing to condemn this aggression while seeking to portray itself as a neutral arbiter – and we’re concerned that they are considering directly assisting Russia with military equipment to use in Ukraine.</p>
<p>President Biden will be speaking to President Xi tomorrow and will make clear that China will bear responsibility for any actions it takes to support Russia’s aggression, and we will not hesitate to impose costs.</p>
<p>Let me close by saying that President Zelenskyy’s message to Congress and to the American people yesterday was incredibly powerful.</p>
<p>He’s asked for more help, which we are providing and will continue to provide.</p>
<p>And he said that the people of Ukraine want the same things for themselves that we want for ourselves – democracy, independence, freedom.</p>
<p>No one who’s watched the events of the past three weeks could ever doubt the depth of Ukraine’s commitment to these ideals.</p>
<p>We’ll continue to stand with Ukraine as it fights for its future.</p>
<p>We’ll continue to increase the costs on Russia until it ends this war of choice.</p>
<p>And we’ll continue to provide life-saving aid to the Ukrainian people as they endure the brutal consequences of Russia’s aggression.</p>
<p>With that, happy to take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Paul.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Sir, what do you think about the talks between Ukraine and Russia?  Are they making any progress?  President Zelenskyy seems to suggest there are things they are talking about.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So we’re in close contact, as I said, with Ukraine’s leaders, including in my case Foreign Minister Kuleba.  We’re in close contact with other countries that have, in one way or another, been engaging on diplomacy.</p>
<p>And to date I have to say, on the one hand, we commend Ukraine for being at the table, despite being under bombardment every minute of that day.  At the same time, I have not seen any meaningful efforts by Russia to bring this war that it’s perpetrating to a conclusion through diplomacy.</p>
<p>We support Ukraine’s efforts to try to de-escalate through diplomacy, to reach a ceasefire, and of course the withdrawal of Russian forces.  We appreciate the efforts of other countries, including France, Germany, Israel, Turkey, and others.  But again, from where I sit, diplomacy requires both sides engaging in good faith to de-escalate, and I don’t see signs right now that Putin is prepared to stop.</p>
<p>On the contrary, if you listen to, just for example, his most recent remarks yesterday, that suggests that he is moving in the opposite direction.  But never mind the words.   What we’re really focused on is actions, and the actions that we’re seeing Russia take every single day, virtually every minute of every day, are in total contrast to any serious diplomatic effort to end the war.</p>
<p>So we’re looking to see Russia take meaningful actions to de-escalate, to stop the violence that it’s perpetrating on Ukraine, and to engage in good-faith talks.  We will support any effort that Ukraine makes to do that.  We’re certainly doing everything we can to back them, but also to make sure that they have the strongest possible hand, if there are any real negotiations and if diplomacy does advance – hence the support that we’re giving to Ukraine as well as the pressure that we continue to put and even increase on Russia.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Kylie.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you, Secretary.  There is – this department is confirming that an American has died in Ukraine today, so I’m wondering if you can share any more with us about the circumstances, about who that person is, and if there’ll be specific consequences for Russia because an American died.</p>
<p>And then second, earlier this week you said on CNN that one way or another Ukraine will be there and at some point Putin won’t.  But we’re watching every day Ukrainians are getting killed; their cities are being demolished.  So how can you be so confident to say something like that?  And are you suggesting that Putin should be removed as the leader of Russia?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Kylie, first, with regard to the American citizen, I can confirm that an American citizen was killed.  I don&#8217;t have any more details for you than that, but I can confirm that.</p>
<p>Second, it is I think not only clear to me but clear to the world that an independent Ukraine will be there long after Vladimir Putin.  And it’s also clear that this could horrifically go on for some time.  But when all is said and done, an independent Ukraine will be there, and at some point Vladimir Putin will not.  The real question is how much death and destruction is going to occur in the meantime.  And we’re doing everything we can to bring this war, perpetrated by Russia, to the quickest possible end.  That’s where the support for Ukraine comes in; that’s where the pressure on Russia comes in; that’s where the work, the coordination that we’re doing with countries around the world comes in.</p>
<p>But I think the world has seen this.  The world has seen the absolute determination of the Ukrainian people to hold onto their country, to hold onto their future, to hold onto their freedom.  And there is nothing that Vladimir Putin can do to subjugate that to his will.  But as I said, this could go on for some time, and we’re going to continue to work to bring it to an end as quickly as we can.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And should Putin remain the leader of Russia?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Kylie, we’re going to try and move around.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, you described what you called Russia’s terror tactics.  Is the State Department considering designating Russia a state sponsor – excuse me – of terrorism?</p>
<p>And then second, everything that you described, the words that the President has used in recent days – war criminal, murderous dictator, pure thug – do you think that there can ever be normal relations between the United States and Russia so long as Vladimir Putin is in power?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So our focus first and foremost is on doing everything we can to help bring this war to a quick end, to stop the suffering of the Ukrainian people that’s the result of Russia’s aggression on Ukraine.  That’s our focus.  As we’re doing that, and as I said earlier, we’re also looking very carefully at what is happening, what is being done, and in particular looking at the question of whether war crimes are being committed.</p>
<p>And, among other things, the intentional targeting of civilians would constitute a war crime.  You heard President Biden speak to this yesterday.  You heard what I said a few minutes ago.  So we are documenting.  We welcome the efforts of various groups, institutions, organizations that focus on this to bring all of the evidence together, to continue to document things, and then for there to be accountability one way or the other.</p>
<p>In terms of other designations based on actions that Russia’s taking, we are and we will look at everything.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yulia Yarmolenko.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  On the second question?  I’m sorry.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I’m sorry, remind me.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  As long as Putin is in power, can there be normal relations between Russia and the United States?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Again, our focus is on ending this war.  I don’t want to speculate about the future, but there’s going to have to be, one way or another, accountability for this war of aggression.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yulia Yarmolenko, VOA Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  So on possible negotiations between Ukraine and Russia, if Russia agrees to stop attacks and withdraw its forces from Ukraine, are there any security formats that will guarantee that Russia would not renew its aggression against Ukraine?  If it’s not membership in NATO for Ukraine, then what?</p>
<p>And another question.  President Biden said that U.S. will accept Ukrainian refugees with open arms, and so far there is no official visa or other program for Ukrainians who are fleeing war or who want to come to the United States or reunite with their families.  Is Department of State working on some special expedited program for Ukrainian refugees?  And if yes, when it might be launched?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  First, on the diplomacy, look, I’m not going to speculate on the substance of any negotiations, where that might go.  As I said, we fully and strongly support whatever the Government of Ukraine – the democratically elected Government of Ukraine – does.  We very much welcome sentiments that we’ve heard expressed for trying to bring this to a diplomatic end as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>I think in the first instance what Ukraine needs is de-escalation.  It needs Russian forces out of Ukraine.  It needs to have its basic freedom and independence returned, but I leave it to Ukrainian partners to work on advancing the diplomacy if that’s – if they believe that can be productive.  We will look at whatever we can do to support that.</p>
<p>And if there are issues that wind up being negotiated that require in some fashion our participation, of course we will look at that and see where we can be helpful.  We want to be able in the first instance to do what we’re doing, which is to support the Government of Ukraine, the Ukrainian people, along with putting pressure on Russia.  If diplomacy finally carries the day and there are things that we can do to support that diplomacy and to support any outcomes that restore Ukraine’s independence, we will, of course, look at that and I’m sure do that.</p>
<p>With regard to refugees, a couple of things.  First, as I said, this is the largest refugee crisis in Europe since World War II.  The numbers are staggering.  And, of course, what gets lost sometimes behind these numbers are the real lives that are at stake and that are being changed, maybe not forever, but are being changed in profound ways.</p>
<p>I saw some of that firsthand when I was on the border between Poland and Ukraine with a number of you just a couple of weeks ago, talking to people who had made the journey across the border, looking for safety in the face of this Russian onslaught.  And in many cases – most cases, women and children – the men staying behind to fight.</p>
<p>And we see the impact, of course, in Ukraine.  We see the impact on neighboring countries – Poland, Moldova, Romania, others – that are taking in very large numbers of refugees.  The generosity I think is extraordinary.  But the numbers are growing.  The challenge is growing.  I was on a call, a video conference, this morning with our G7 partners, and this is one of the things that we talked about – having a coordinated approach to dealing with and helping refugees coming over.</p>
<p>The United States is already and will remain the largest provider of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  Part of the package that is in the supplemental includes about $4 billion in humanitarian assistance, and that will go both directly to Ukraine.  It will also go to neighboring countries and others – and Ukrainians outside of Ukraine – to support them.</p>
<p>Second, we are working closely with UNHCR to see how we can support this effort.</p>
<p>Finally, we’re looking at things that we can do ourselves and do directly – for example, looking at steps we may be able to take on family reunification and other things that we can do to be supportive and to really take part in this effort.</p>
<p>Last thing I’ll say is this:  What – and of course, there is the refugee referral process, but that takes time.  But if people apply for refugee status and seek to come to the United States, of course we will take referrals.  But we’re looking at steps that we can take in the near term.</p>
<p>Last thing is this:  I think what we’re seeing, at least initially, is that so many people coming out of Ukraine understandably want to stay close to home.  They hope – we hope – that they’ll be able to return home as soon as possible.  They also want to stay close to home because, as I said, in many cases it’s women and children who have left behind spouses, husbands, fathers, brothers, and they want to be reunited as quickly as possible, so they want to stay as close as possible.  But as this and if this goes on, as the numbers increase, as the burden increases for European partners, we will certainly do everything we can to help.  So I suspect we’ll have more to say on this in the coming – in the coming days.  It’s something we’re very focused on right now.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Time for one final, quick question from Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, you’ve outlined, recounted a litany of horrific attacks on civilians.  You’ve said you agree with the President’s comment that they’re war crimes, as the UN ambassador said last week.  I know there has to be an investigation, but where will the accountability be?  What should happen to Vladimir Putin if he is found guilty, since he is the state?  What should happen to this (inaudible)?  Tell the world.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So, Andrea, a few things.  First, we’re all seeing what – and you’re showing, powerfully, on television – these devastating images coming out of Ukraine, and we are seeing the destruction of so much of the country by Russian bombs, artillery.  We’re seeing civilian sites being devastated; we’re seeing people being killed – hundreds, thousands of people, civilians.  And yes, as I – again, as the President said yesterday, in his opinion, war crimes are being committed.  I agree with that.  After all the destruction that we’ve seen, it’s really hard to conclude otherwise.</p>
<p>But what we’re doing is this – and I’ll come to your question – we are in the first instance supporting the very important work that’s being done, the evidentiary process to bring the evidence together, to document what’s happened, to support and to work with human rights activists, with civil society, with independent media as well as with the appropriate organizations and institutions that look into this.  So we need to go through this process of compiling the evidence, collecting the evidence, understanding the evidence.  We’ll share that – and our allies and partners I’m sure will do the same with all of the investigations that are ongoing – to support accountability using every tool that we have available.</p>
<p>I’m not going to get ahead of, first of all, what the outcome will be or what the consequences will be, but I can say with conviction that there will be accountability for any war crimes that are determined to have occurred.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  How can you say that after Aleppo and Grozny?  He does it repeatedly.  He’s a repeat offender as a war criminal.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Andrea, when we said before Russia’s aggression that there would be massive consequences for that aggression, including unprecedented sanctions on Russia, I know some people had their doubts.  I think we’ve demonstrated that we’ve been good to our word.  When we said that there would be sustained, powerful support for Ukraine in its efforts to defend itself, we’ve demonstrated that we’re good to our word.  So when I tell you that there will be accountability and consequences for any war crimes that have been committed, I hope you’ll take me at my word, but actions always speak louder than words.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Thanks.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Press Briefing Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone.</p>
<p>Three weeks ago, Russia launched its unprovoked war on Ukraine.</p>
<p>With every day that passes, the numbers of civilians, including children, killed and wounded continues to climb.</p>
<p>Russia continues to attack civilian sites, including – this week alone – a hospital, three schools, a boarding school for visually impaired kids in the Luhansk region of Ukraine.</p>
<p>Yesterday Russian forces bombed a theater in Mariupol, where hundreds of people had been taking shelter.</p>
<p>The word “children” had been written in Russian in giant white letters on the pavement outside the building, so that you could know from the air that there were children inside.</p>
<p>Russian forces also opened fire on 10 civilians in who were waiting in line for bread.</p>
<p>These incidents join a long list of attacks on civilian – not military – locations across Ukraine, including apartment buildings, public squares, and, last week, a maternity hospital in Mariupol.</p>
<p>I doubt that any of us who saw those images will ever forget them.</p>
<p>We’ve seen Russia use similar tactics before in Grozny and Aleppo.  They stepped up their bombardment with the goal of breaking the will of the people.</p>
<p>Yesterday President Biden said that, in his opinion, war crimes have been committed in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Personally, I agree.</p>
<p>Intentionally targeting civilians is a war crime.</p>
<p>After all the destruction of the past three weeks, I find it difficult to conclude that the Russians are doing otherwise.</p>
<p>The consequences of Moscow’s war are being felt around the world – in rising food costs, concerns about fuel supplies, more broadly in worries about how this war will affect the global economy and the fight against COVID-19.</p>
<p>These are serious issues that the global community urgently needs to address.  This war is making that much more difficult.</p>
<p>In this way, Russia’s actions are having an impact on every person on the planet, wherever they live.</p>
<p>We also feel the impact right here in this room.</p>
<p>There should be a seat reserved here today for Benjamin Hall from Fox News, who was injured badly when his vehicle came under attack near Kyiv.</p>
<p>Many of us, myself included, have gotten to know Ben very well as part of the traveling press corps.</p>
<p>He’s an incredibly talented reporter, always asking tough questions.  He’s a lovely person, as well.</p>
<p>Our thoughts – my thoughts – are with him and his family, including his three little kids.</p>
<p>Two of Ben’s Fox News colleagues, Pierre Zokchefski and Sasha Koofshenova, were killed in the attack.  And Brent Renaud, a reporter on assignment with <i>Time Magazine</i>, was killed in a separate attack a day earlier.</p>
<p>I know that everyone in this room, in particular, feels these losses deeply.</p>
<p>Being a war correspondent is vital work; they make sure that the world knows what’s really happening when armies move in and bombs start falling.</p>
<p>It also takes incredible courage; they go into war zones when others, understandably, are heading out as fast as possible.</p>
<p>So these are huge losses, of course, for families, for friends, but also for their colleagues, their profession, their readers and viewers who understand world events because of them.</p>
<p>Our experts are in the process of documenting and evaluating potential war crimes being committed in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Beth Van Schaack, whom the Senate finally confirmed this week as our Ambassador at Large for Global Criminal Justice, will be leading that effort within the State Department.</p>
<p>We’ll make sure that our findings help international efforts to investigate war crimes and hold those responsible accountable.</p>
<p>I’d also mention that there are several other nominations before the Senate with a direct bearing on our ability to support Ukraine, including for Assistant Secretary of State for Population, Refugees, and Migration; Assistant Secretary of State for International Security and Non-Proliferation; and our Coordinator for Sanctions Policy.</p>
<p>So I urge the Senate to confirm these nominees quickly, so that they can get to work as soon as possible.</p>
<p>A few weeks ago, just days before Russia’s invasion began, I went to the United Nations Security Council to lay out what we believed was about to happen.</p>
<p>Again today, we have a strong sense of what Russia could do next.</p>
<p>We believe that Moscow may be setting the stage to use a chemical weapon, and then falsely blame Ukraine to justify escalating its attacks on the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p>Manufacturing events and creating false narratives of genocide to justify greater use of military force is a tactic that Russia has used before, including in Georgia.</p>
<p>We believe Russia will bring its mercenaries from private military groups and foreign countries to Ukraine.</p>
<p>President Putin acknowledged as much over the weekend when he authorized the recruitment of additional forces from the Middle East and elsewhere – another indication that his war effort is not going as he hoped it would.</p>
<p>They are also likely to systematically kidnap local officials and replace them with puppets.</p>
<p>Again, this has already begun.</p>
<p>The mayor of Melitopol was grabbed off the street several days ago, released yesterday in a prisoner exchange.</p>
<p>The mayor of another city in southern Ukraine was also kidnapped; he hasn’t yet been let go.</p>
<p>This is a terror tactic – grab local officials, depose local governments, put proxies in their place.</p>
<p>After devastating Ukrainian cities, Moscow may bring in officials from Russia to serve as local government officials, and surge what they describe as “economic support” in an attempt to make the people dependent on Moscow for survival.</p>
<p>Again, something that Russia did in Georgia.</p>
<p>President Putin’s invasion of Ukraine is not going to plan.</p>
<p>The Ukrainian people haven’t welcomed the Russian military.  They haven’t submitted.</p>
<p>On the contrary.  They’re fighting with extraordinary courage to protect their homes, their families, their country.</p>
<p>Russia has been hit by unprecedented sanctions and cut off from the global economy.</p>
<p>Its own economy is in free fall.</p>
<p>Hundreds of corporations have closed operations.</p>
<p>In a matter of weeks, President Putin has destroyed 30 years of opening to the world and economic opportunity for the Russian people.</p>
<p>Dozens of members of the Kremlin’s corrupt power base have been sanctioned; several have lost their mega yachts and villas.</p>
<p>President Putin has derided those sanctions, using recent public diatribes to mock Russians living abroad as too dependent, as he said, on “foie gras and oysters.”</p>
<p>Meanwhile, he sits in his mansions, having accumulated billions taking wealth from the Russian people, while they stand in long lines to access cash and watch as stores close and the ruble plummets in value.</p>
<p>It’s no wonder that brave Russians continue to protest the war and be beaten and arrested for it.</p>
<p>And Russian journalists are resigning from their jobs at state media outlets, because they can’t stomach parroting the Kremlin’s lies any longer.</p>
<p>Still, President Putin is not relenting and in fact may be growing more desperate.</p>
<p>And so yesterday, President Biden authorized – announced, excuse me, not authorized – another $800 million in military aid to Ukraine.</p>
<p>That brings our support for Ukraine’s frontline defenders to more than $2 billion during this administration – one billion in the last week alone.</p>
<p>We’re grateful to have a determined and generous partner in Congress, which this week provided more than $13 billion in urgent support to Ukraine.</p>
<p>And we’ll continue to work with lawmakers to support Ukraine and hold the Kremlin to account.</p>
<p>As President Biden described, this new security assistance package includes 800 anti-aircraft systems, to stop attacking planes and helicopters before they destroy more of Ukraine; 9,000 anti-armor systems to destroy tanks and armored vehicles; 7,000 small arms, including machine guns and grenade launchers; and 20 million rounds of ammunition.</p>
<p>We’re also helping Ukraine acquire longer-range anti-aircraft systems and munitions, at President Zelenskyy’s request.</p>
<p>And I have been in almost daily contact with Foreign Minister Kuleba, coordinating to respond swiftly to Ukraine’s most urgent needs.</p>
<p>Our allies and partners continue to step up with their own significant shipments of security assistance.</p>
<p>I’ve authorized more than a dozen countries to provide U.S.-origin equipment, and dozens more around the world have provided security assistance of their own.</p>
<p>I’d also note that, in addition to assistance from the Department of Defense, we’re sending support from other agencies, including $10 million worth of armored vehicles from our own Diplomatic Security Service.</p>
<p>And yesterday I announced another $186 million in humanitarian assistance to help the more than 3 million refugees who have fled Ukraine in the past three weeks – the fastest-growing refugee crisis in Europe since World War II – as well as internally displaced people still in Ukraine.</p>
<p>This brings our total humanitarian aid since last month to $293 million.</p>
<p>And of the more than $13 billion for Ukraine that Congress is putting forward, more than 4 billion of that will go to humanitarian assistance.</p>
<p>Ukraine’s neighbors in Europe are generously welcoming, supporting refugees.  The United States will do our part to help those governments and the humanitarian organizations on the ground meet this tremendous need.</p>
<p>All the steps that we and our allies and partners are taking are aimed at one goal: to end the war.</p>
<p>The support we’re providing Ukraine, as well as our financial and economic measures against Moscow, will strengthen Ukraine’s hand at the diplomatic table.</p>
<p>And we commend Ukraine for staying at that table and continuing to pursue diplomacy while the Kremlin’s brutal aggression continues.</p>
<p>We’ll support Ukraine’s diplomatic efforts however we can.</p>
<p>We continue to call on all nations, especially those with direct influence with Russia, to use whatever leverage they have to compel Moscow to end this war of choice.</p>
<p>We believe China in particular has a responsibility to use its influence with President Putin and to defend the international rules and principles that it professes to support.</p>
<p>Instead, it appears that China is moving in the opposite direction by refusing to condemn this aggression while seeking to portray itself as a neutral arbiter – and we’re concerned that they are considering directly assisting Russia with military equipment to use in Ukraine.</p>
<p>President Biden will be speaking to President Xi tomorrow and will make clear that China will bear responsibility for any actions it takes to support Russia’s aggression, and we will not hesitate to impose costs.</p>
<p>Let me close by saying that President Zelenskyy’s message to Congress and to the American people yesterday was incredibly powerful.</p>
<p>He’s asked for more help, which we are providing and will continue to provide.</p>
<p>And he said that the people of Ukraine want the same things for themselves that we want for ourselves – democracy, independence, freedom.</p>
<p>No one who’s watched the events of the past three weeks could ever doubt the depth of Ukraine’s commitment to these ideals.</p>
<p>We’ll continue to stand with Ukraine as it fights for its future.</p>
<p>We’ll continue to increase the costs on Russia until it ends this war of choice.</p>
<p>And we’ll continue to provide life-saving aid to the Ukrainian people as they endure the brutal consequences of Russia’s aggression.</p>
<p>With that, happy to take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Paul.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Sir, what do you think about the talks between Ukraine and Russia?  Are they making any progress?  President Zelenskyy seems to suggest there are things they are talking about.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So we’re in close contact, as I said, with Ukraine’s leaders, including in my case Foreign Minister Kuleba.  We’re in close contact with other countries that have, in one way or another, been engaging on diplomacy.</p>
<p>And to date I have to say, on the one hand, we commend Ukraine for being at the table, despite being under bombardment every minute of that day.  At the same time, I have not seen any meaningful efforts by Russia to bring this war that it’s perpetrating to a conclusion through diplomacy.</p>
<p>We support Ukraine’s efforts to try to de-escalate through diplomacy, to reach a ceasefire, and of course the withdrawal of Russian forces.  We appreciate the efforts of other countries, including France, Germany, Israel, Turkey, and others.  But again, from where I sit, diplomacy requires both sides engaging in good faith to de-escalate, and I don’t see signs right now that Putin is prepared to stop.</p>
<p>On the contrary, if you listen to, just for example, his most recent remarks yesterday, that suggests that he is moving in the opposite direction.  But never mind the words.   What we’re really focused on is actions, and the actions that we’re seeing Russia take every single day, virtually every minute of every day, are in total contrast to any serious diplomatic effort to end the war.</p>
<p>So we’re looking to see Russia take meaningful actions to de-escalate, to stop the violence that it’s perpetrating on Ukraine, and to engage in good-faith talks.  We will support any effort that Ukraine makes to do that.  We’re certainly doing everything we can to back them, but also to make sure that they have the strongest possible hand, if there are any real negotiations and if diplomacy does advance – hence the support that we’re giving to Ukraine as well as the pressure that we continue to put and even increase on Russia.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Kylie.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you, Secretary.  There is – this department is confirming that an American has died in Ukraine today, so I’m wondering if you can share any more with us about the circumstances, about who that person is, and if there’ll be specific consequences for Russia because an American died.</p>
<p>And then second, earlier this week you said on CNN that one way or another Ukraine will be there and at some point Putin won’t.  But we’re watching every day Ukrainians are getting killed; their cities are being demolished.  So how can you be so confident to say something like that?  And are you suggesting that Putin should be removed as the leader of Russia?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Kylie, first, with regard to the American citizen, I can confirm that an American citizen was killed.  I don&#8217;t have any more details for you than that, but I can confirm that.</p>
<p>Second, it is I think not only clear to me but clear to the world that an independent Ukraine will be there long after Vladimir Putin.  And it’s also clear that this could horrifically go on for some time.  But when all is said and done, an independent Ukraine will be there, and at some point Vladimir Putin will not.  The real question is how much death and destruction is going to occur in the meantime.  And we’re doing everything we can to bring this war, perpetrated by Russia, to the quickest possible end.  That’s where the support for Ukraine comes in; that’s where the pressure on Russia comes in; that’s where the work, the coordination that we’re doing with countries around the world comes in.</p>
<p>But I think the world has seen this.  The world has seen the absolute determination of the Ukrainian people to hold onto their country, to hold onto their future, to hold onto their freedom.  And there is nothing that Vladimir Putin can do to subjugate that to his will.  But as I said, this could go on for some time, and we’re going to continue to work to bring it to an end as quickly as we can.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And should Putin remain the leader of Russia?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Kylie, we’re going to try and move around.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, you described what you called Russia’s terror tactics.  Is the State Department considering designating Russia a state sponsor – excuse me – of terrorism?</p>
<p>And then second, everything that you described, the words that the President has used in recent days – war criminal, murderous dictator, pure thug – do you think that there can ever be normal relations between the United States and Russia so long as Vladimir Putin is in power?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So our focus first and foremost is on doing everything we can to help bring this war to a quick end, to stop the suffering of the Ukrainian people that’s the result of Russia’s aggression on Ukraine.  That’s our focus.  As we’re doing that, and as I said earlier, we’re also looking very carefully at what is happening, what is being done, and in particular looking at the question of whether war crimes are being committed.</p>
<p>And, among other things, the intentional targeting of civilians would constitute a war crime.  You heard President Biden speak to this yesterday.  You heard what I said a few minutes ago.  So we are documenting.  We welcome the efforts of various groups, institutions, organizations that focus on this to bring all of the evidence together, to continue to document things, and then for there to be accountability one way or the other.</p>
<p>In terms of other designations based on actions that Russia’s taking, we are and we will look at everything.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yulia Yarmolenko.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  On the second question?  I’m sorry.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I’m sorry, remind me.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  As long as Putin is in power, can there be normal relations between Russia and the United States?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Again, our focus is on ending this war.  I don’t want to speculate about the future, but there’s going to have to be, one way or another, accountability for this war of aggression.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yulia Yarmolenko, VOA Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  So on possible negotiations between Ukraine and Russia, if Russia agrees to stop attacks and withdraw its forces from Ukraine, are there any security formats that will guarantee that Russia would not renew its aggression against Ukraine?  If it’s not membership in NATO for Ukraine, then what?</p>
<p>And another question.  President Biden said that U.S. will accept Ukrainian refugees with open arms, and so far there is no official visa or other program for Ukrainians who are fleeing war or who want to come to the United States or reunite with their families.  Is Department of State working on some special expedited program for Ukrainian refugees?  And if yes, when it might be launched?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  First, on the diplomacy, look, I’m not going to speculate on the substance of any negotiations, where that might go.  As I said, we fully and strongly support whatever the Government of Ukraine – the democratically elected Government of Ukraine – does.  We very much welcome sentiments that we’ve heard expressed for trying to bring this to a diplomatic end as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>I think in the first instance what Ukraine needs is de-escalation.  It needs Russian forces out of Ukraine.  It needs to have its basic freedom and independence returned, but I leave it to Ukrainian partners to work on advancing the diplomacy if that’s – if they believe that can be productive.  We will look at whatever we can do to support that.</p>
<p>And if there are issues that wind up being negotiated that require in some fashion our participation, of course we will look at that and see where we can be helpful.  We want to be able in the first instance to do what we’re doing, which is to support the Government of Ukraine, the Ukrainian people, along with putting pressure on Russia.  If diplomacy finally carries the day and there are things that we can do to support that diplomacy and to support any outcomes that restore Ukraine’s independence, we will, of course, look at that and I’m sure do that.</p>
<p>With regard to refugees, a couple of things.  First, as I said, this is the largest refugee crisis in Europe since World War II.  The numbers are staggering.  And, of course, what gets lost sometimes behind these numbers are the real lives that are at stake and that are being changed, maybe not forever, but are being changed in profound ways.</p>
<p>I saw some of that firsthand when I was on the border between Poland and Ukraine with a number of you just a couple of weeks ago, talking to people who had made the journey across the border, looking for safety in the face of this Russian onslaught.  And in many cases – most cases, women and children – the men staying behind to fight.</p>
<p>And we see the impact, of course, in Ukraine.  We see the impact on neighboring countries – Poland, Moldova, Romania, others – that are taking in very large numbers of refugees.  The generosity I think is extraordinary.  But the numbers are growing.  The challenge is growing.  I was on a call, a video conference, this morning with our G7 partners, and this is one of the things that we talked about – having a coordinated approach to dealing with and helping refugees coming over.</p>
<p>The United States is already and will remain the largest provider of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  Part of the package that is in the supplemental includes about $4 billion in humanitarian assistance, and that will go both directly to Ukraine.  It will also go to neighboring countries and others – and Ukrainians outside of Ukraine – to support them.</p>
<p>Second, we are working closely with UNHCR to see how we can support this effort.</p>
<p>Finally, we’re looking at things that we can do ourselves and do directly – for example, looking at steps we may be able to take on family reunification and other things that we can do to be supportive and to really take part in this effort.</p>
<p>Last thing I’ll say is this:  What – and of course, there is the refugee referral process, but that takes time.  But if people apply for refugee status and seek to come to the United States, of course we will take referrals.  But we’re looking at steps that we can take in the near term.</p>
<p>Last thing is this:  I think what we’re seeing, at least initially, is that so many people coming out of Ukraine understandably want to stay close to home.  They hope – we hope – that they’ll be able to return home as soon as possible.  They also want to stay close to home because, as I said, in many cases it’s women and children who have left behind spouses, husbands, fathers, brothers, and they want to be reunited as quickly as possible, so they want to stay as close as possible.  But as this and if this goes on, as the numbers increase, as the burden increases for European partners, we will certainly do everything we can to help.  So I suspect we’ll have more to say on this in the coming – in the coming days.  It’s something we’re very focused on right now.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Time for one final, quick question from Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, you’ve outlined, recounted a litany of horrific attacks on civilians.  You’ve said you agree with the President’s comment that they’re war crimes, as the UN ambassador said last week.  I know there has to be an investigation, but where will the accountability be?  What should happen to Vladimir Putin if he is found guilty, since he is the state?  What should happen to this (inaudible)?  Tell the world.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So, Andrea, a few things.  First, we’re all seeing what – and you’re showing, powerfully, on television – these devastating images coming out of Ukraine, and we are seeing the destruction of so much of the country by Russian bombs, artillery.  We’re seeing civilian sites being devastated; we’re seeing people being killed – hundreds, thousands of people, civilians.  And yes, as I – again, as the President said yesterday, in his opinion, war crimes are being committed.  I agree with that.  After all the destruction that we’ve seen, it’s really hard to conclude otherwise.</p>
<p>But what we’re doing is this – and I’ll come to your question – we are in the first instance supporting the very important work that’s being done, the evidentiary process to bring the evidence together, to document what’s happened, to support and to work with human rights activists, with civil society, with independent media as well as with the appropriate organizations and institutions that look into this.  So we need to go through this process of compiling the evidence, collecting the evidence, understanding the evidence.  We’ll share that – and our allies and partners I’m sure will do the same with all of the investigations that are ongoing – to support accountability using every tool that we have available.</p>
<p>I’m not going to get ahead of, first of all, what the outcome will be or what the consequences will be, but I can say with conviction that there will be accountability for any war crimes that are determined to have occurred.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  How can you say that after Aleppo and Grozny?  He does it repeatedly.  He’s a repeat offender as a war criminal.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Andrea, when we said before Russia’s aggression that there would be massive consequences for that aggression, including unprecedented sanctions on Russia, I know some people had their doubts.  I think we’ve demonstrated that we’ve been good to our word.  When we said that there would be sustained, powerful support for Ukraine in its efforts to defend itself, we’ve demonstrated that we’re good to our word.  So when I tell you that there will be accountability and consequences for any war crimes that have been committed, I hope you’ll take me at my word, but actions always speak louder than words.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Thanks.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Qatari Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Foreign Affairs Al-Thani</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-qatari-deputy-prime-minister-and-minister-of-foreign-affairs-al-thani-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 16:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325460</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke yesterday with Qatari Minister of Foreign Affairs Mohammed bin Abdulrahman Al-Thani.  Secretary Blinken affirmed that the United States and Qatar are united in their efforts to provide humanitarian assistance to the Ukrainian people. The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Qatar’s continued support for Ukraine’s sovereignty.  The two also discussed Afghanistan and other important regional issues.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke yesterday with Qatari Minister of Foreign Affairs Mohammed bin Abdulrahman Al-Thani.  Secretary Blinken affirmed that the United States and Qatar are united in their efforts to provide humanitarian assistance to the Ukrainian people. The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Qatar’s continued support for Ukraine’s sovereignty.  The two also discussed Afghanistan and other important regional issues.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
