<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 04:05:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing – February 2, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-february-2-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:25:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=311114</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon. Before I take your questions, just one element at the top.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Not about Groundhog Day.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, it is about Groundhog Day. It is about Groundhog Day, in fact. Matt, you stole my thunder.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh, sorry.</p>
<p><a id="post-311114-DEPARTMENT"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> But today is Groundhog Day, and I raise that not only because it sounds like we’re in store for six more weeks of winter, nor because, as some of you might allege, I stand up here every day and say the same thing over and over again; I say that as a way to note the fact that this is the one-year anniversary of the resumption of the daily press briefing at the Department of State. We have literally been doing the same thing over and over again at the department every day we’re here, here in this room, and we’re proud of that. We wouldn’t have it any other way.</p>
<p>As many of you will recall, it was a pledge of then-Candidate Biden, long before he was sworn in as President, to resume daily press briefings in his administration, and he made that pledge because it is so fundamentally important in any number of ways. Whether an ally, a partner, a competitor, or adversary, the world needs to know where the United States stands. Just as importantly, the American people deserve to know what their government is doing, what we are doing to protect and to promote their interests around the world, how we’re confronting threats and seizing opportunities. That is, after all, why we’re here.</p>
<p>I also made the point exactly a year ago that the model we set here conveys well beyond our own borders. If the values of transparency and responsibility and accountability are to – are going to be more than just buzzwords in our global engagement, we have to practice what we preach here at home. And we need an engaged, active press corps to hold our feet to the fire. A year later I can say you all have lived up to your end of the bargain, perhaps too much so, done too good of a job. And I promised a year ago that we’d always seek to be transparent, accurate, and respectful; I hope that we, too, have lived up to ours.</p>
<p>So one year down, many more briefings to go. And with that, turn over to you, Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, thanks. Yeah, one year down and, what, three to go? Or two? Or two or one? Whatever. Anyway, thank you. And just to note that yes, it is appreciated that you’re up here every day, or at least when you’re in town, not on official travel, up here every day answering questions. Whether or not we like the answers or think that the answers are satisfactory or not is a different question.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Understood.</p>
<p><a id="post-311114-URRAINE"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But at least you’re – at least you’re taking them, so that’s appreciated.</p>
<p>Can I start with Ukraine once again, speaking of Groundhog Day? So the Pentagon have made its announcement this morning; I don’t expect you to have any additional details about that. But then – on that. But I’m just wondering if the Russian reaction to that deployment that was announced has been that you guys are escalating, now escalating tensions. And I’m pretty sure I know what your response will be to that, but I’d like to get it anyway.</p>
<p>And then secondly, your colleague at the White House just said that you are no longer – the administration is no longer going to refer to or is no longer referring to a potential Russian invasion as “imminent” because that might send the wrong signal. And I’m just wondering, especially in the context of you saying that this is the year anniversary of getting up and telling us what the U.S. policy is, if – was it a mistake to be calling it imminent in the first place? If you didn’t really know, what was the point? Why were you describing this as something that could, like, happen at the snap of a finger if now – was it what Putin said yesterday? What was it? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So – thank you, Matt. Well, first, on your first question: Look, I don’t think anyone here is going to be surprised by the reaction you’ve noted of the Russian Federation. I mean, this is literally their playbook, to turn the reality upside down. The metaphor we’ve used, that my colleague at the White House used, paraphrasing our boss here at the State Department: this is literally the fox claiming that it had no choice but to attack the henhouse. This is – talk about Groundhog Day &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, but it’s actually in the fox’s nature to attack the henhouse. That’s what foxes do. So maybe that’s &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Is that a statement about the country or &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, no. I just think it’s a – it might be a poor analogy because the fox &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Okay. Well, I will let you choose your analogy, but I think you get the underlying point. And one other analogy, other words, is – our concern is this idea of Groundhog Day, because we have seen this before; we have seen something like this before, at least. It was eight years ago, just about, when the Russians amassed troops on Ukraine’s borders; the Russians engaged in misinformation, in disinformation, in propaganda, seeking to portray Ukraine as the aggressor. The Russians then took it one step further, manufactured pretextual provocation that they then cited as a means by which to aggress against Ukraine and to undertake an incursion into sovereign Ukrainian territory.</p>
<p>So what we are doing – and my colleague at the Pentagon spoke to this at the orders of the President – these are about deterrent and defensive measures. These are measures that we have spoken to in broad strokes over several weeks, noting that – given what we are seeing: the amassing of troops, the bellicose rhetoric, the history that is at play here – it is only prudent for us to take steps in the past several weeks to provide defensive security assistance to our Ukrainian partners, and we’ve done that at an unprecedented level that we’ve spoken to in some detail. And the President also made clear that both in the event of a Russian invasion, and as a means to deter and to defend our allies on the eastern flank against broader aggression, we would be taking defensive and deterrent steps. And that is precisely what the Pentagon spoke to today.</p>
<p>Many of these force, as you heard, are already in the European theater. These are not permanent moves; they are in – precisely in response to the current security environment in light of this increasing threatening behavior by the Russian Federation. These troops, as you all know, they are not going to fight in Ukraine; they are going to ensure the robust defense of NATO territory. That is something to which we have a solemn commitment – solemn commitment under Article 5. This is just another unmistakable signal to the rest of the world, to any countries that would threaten that collective security, that collective defense of our NATO Allies, that we are committed to the Alliance, we’re committed to our Allies, we’re committed to Article 5.</p>
<p>When it comes to the second part of your question – What comes next? – Matt, we’ve always been clear there’s only one person who knows what the Russians may have in store. We don’t believe that individual, who happens to be the president of the Russian Federation, has made a decision one way or another. What has been our concern is what we have spoken to since November: these unusual movements of Russian troops; the massive buildup along the Ukrainian border; the inflow of Russian forces into what should be a sovereign, independent country – the country of Belarus – all of these steps have positioned the Russians to be able to move quickly should they so choose.</p>
<p>No one, I don’t believe, has been encouraging panic. No one has been saying an invasion is a foregone conclusion. What we have been doing is speaking to our concern. It has been a growing level of concern as Moscow’s aggressiveness and assertiveness has itself grown. But what we are doing is preparing for that. We are engaging in dialogue and diplomacy just as we pursue the path of defense and deterrence.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So you have no – there were no concerns that you’re getting people worked up for – not nothing, but getting people worked up and panicking? That’s not why you’re stepping away from the “imminence” thing?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, what we’ve been doing for weeks now is far from seeking to sow panic; we have been seeking to explain our concern and to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, but you got a lot of people’s attention by saying “imminence” and “we think that this is a” &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, this is something that should have people’s attention. We believe &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, I’m not saying it shouldn’t, but I – but you guys used the – very deliberately used those words, like this could happen, like, in the snap of a finger, and now it seems less. So I’m just wondering &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t think you are going to hear us say this is off the table; I don’t think you are going to hear us say this is a foregone conclusion.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, I know. But &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You will – you will hear us saying, and you have heard us say, that we are taking preparations for whichever path Vladimir Putin chooses.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Got you. I get that. But, I mean, is the decision not to use – not to describe this as “imminent” based on what President Putin said yesterday, or is it based on something else? What is it based on? Or is it based on the complaints from the Ukrainians that you’re getting people stoked up and put into a panic? Why?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Our language, Matt, is always calibrated to what we’re seeing. What we’ve seen ‑‑</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So it’s less imminent now than it was yesterday?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I think you are – I think you are reading far too much into &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, I guess &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; into what you may have heard.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All right.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Humeyra.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So I am actually going to follow up a little bit on that, maybe from a slightly different angle. So you guys were waiting for Putin’s remarks yesterday. Obviously, you monitored it very closely where he basically blamed the West. And you just said that there is one person and he still hasn’t made up his mind yet. So after watching Putin yesterday, the United States still thinks that he still has not made a decision to invade or not, is that correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Our assessment has not changed. We have made the point – I alluded to this yesterday – that Kremlinologists in this country and around the world are going to parse every single syllable, every word, every utterance, every sentence that came out of Putin’s mouth. If you were to do so, you could find reasons for optimism, you could find reasons for pessimism.</p>
<p>For our part, we are not optimistic, neither are we pessimistic. We’re clear-eyed about the stakes. We’re resolute in our determination to engage in diplomacy if we have a good-faith partner on the other side doing so in tandem with our partners and allies, just as we pursue simultaneously that path of defense and deterrence.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So indulge me a little bit more. His comments were pretty defiant, and like, he accused the West of trying to lure him into war. You said we’re not pessimistic, we’re not optimistic. Watching that, did those comments make you a little bit more hopeful about the diplomatic path? I mean, you must have, like, swung one way or the other. You can’t be – like it cannot have happened right in the middle.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m just not in a position to provide color commentary of the Russian president’s remarks yesterday.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> It’s not color commentary.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Did you say that people are – in this town are not parsing?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Are, are, are.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh, they are parsing &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Are.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; every single word, syllable, that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I assume that is the case.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So we’ve gone back to the Soviet reviewing stand school of analysis?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I assume – you’re probably, in fact, are speaking to some of these people. I know some of you in this room are.</p>
<p>But look, Humeyra, this is the point. We – there are people here, to acknowledge, who are watching very closely and listening very closely to what the Russians are saying. We are in the position of knowing something that was confirmed in the Secretary’s call with Foreign Minister Lavrov yesterday – that the Russians are preparing a written response to our non-paper. That is a response that will be reviewed and presumably approved by President Putin. That is a response that we assume will convey in detail, in writing, in specific language specifically what the – where the Russians are, what they are willing to engage in, what for them seems like a viable path, what doors may be closed.</p>
<p>It remains our hope, as Foreign Minister Lavrov seemed to indicate yesterday, that there will be an opportunity following the receipt of that Russian response for further diplomatic engagement. We don’t yet know the form; we don’t yet know the timing. What we do know is that any further diplomatic engagement, which we hope occurs, will be done for our part in the closest of coordination with partners and allies. We hope it is done in good faith by the Russian Federation, but we’ll be in a position to judge and we’ll be able to judge based primarily on one criterion, and that is if it takes place in a broader context of de-escalation.</p>
<p>We can talk. There are no preconditions to talking. But this diplomacy is not going to go anywhere. It is not going to address our security concerns. It is not going to address the concerns of the transatlantic community; that is to say our allies and partners on the other side of the Atlantic. And it won’t address the stated concerns of the Russian Federation if it doesn’t take place in this broader context of de-escalation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you have any indication over the past 24 hours when that response might be coming from the Russians?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> No. There has been – we don’t have anything additional to add beyond what we said yesterday in the aftermath of the call.</p>
<p>Yes, Michele.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> There are reports that Russian mercenaries are leaving the Central African Republic – these are the Wagner mercenaries – and perhaps headed to Ukraine. I’m wondering if you can tell me anything about that. Is that something that you’re seeing?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have anything to add on those reports. We have made our position on Russian mercenaries in Africa well known. These are forces that tend not to improve the security situation, and on the other hand, tend to leave countries less stable, poorer, more prone to violence. These are not constructive forces or elements. But I don’t have anything to add in terms of reports that they may be moving to other theaters.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Like Iraq or Afghanistan or &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Kylie.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m just wonderuing how the lack of substantial progress on the diplomatic side impacted the decision today to send more U.S. troops to Europe.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Kylie, we have made the point that we’re going to do these things simultaneously. Until and unless we see a de-escalation, until and unless we see an indication that Russia’s preparations for potential aggression have stopped and have been rolled back, it is only prudent for us to continue to take steps in the vein of defense and deterrence. That’s what we’ll continue to do. That’s what we’ve been doing for several weeks now.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And so even if Russia starts to engage in a more substantive way in the ideas you guys have put on the table, that won’t in any way impact the presence of U.S. troops in the future in European countries?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I will let my colleague at the Pentagon speak to this in greater detail, but our presence, our force posture around the world, is calibrated to the security environment that we face. And if we face a security environment that is prone to disruption, that is prone to destabilization, that is prone to threats, we are going to take steps in the vein of defense and deterrence. That is what we’re doing here. If that security environment changes – that is to say, if there is de-escalation when it comes to what we’re seeing from the Russian Federation – we will, of course, evaluate that and we will evaluate the implications of that on our force posture.</p>
<p>Ben.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Putin has made very clear that the U.S. has not addressed their main security concerns, and so with that in mind, is what the U.S. handed over sort of the final offer? Or have you got more things in the bag that you can offer if they come back and say this is a non-starter, we need more?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So, Ben, I think everyone in this room is probably in a better position to judge today than they were yesterday what it is exactly that we have conveyed to the Russian Federation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Why is that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I will let you – that is your job, to ask questions. It is my job to answer questions.</p>
<p>So I will just make the broad point that the ideas we have put forward – these are ideas. These are essentially proposals for additional discussion. So we have never and we have not been in a position to hand over to the Russian Federation, NATO has not been in a position to hand over to the Russian Federation an exact roadmap of what it is precisely that we are prepared to do across every realm.</p>
<p>What we have conveyed, what NATO has conveyed, the ideas that we’ve conveyed in close coordination and consultation with one another are proposals for further diplomatic engagement. This will require engagement in good faith, some concerted, fairly technical discussions if they are going to result in anything.</p>
<p>But it remains our posture and remains our preference to take part in that diplomacy, one, because it has the potential to redound positively on our security concerns, on the concerns of our European allies and partners, but also to address what the Russians have put on the table; and two, if it were to take place in the context of de-escalation, it would certainly seek to mitigate some of the tensions, some of our concerns that we’ve seen with this massive buildup of Russian forces around Ukraine and in Belarus.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So the door remains open for potentially more dialogue, more things in this document than are already there. I mean, you have more to offer them if they wanted it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The door remains open to discuss the ideas that are in this document. The ideas that we conveyed, the ideas that NATO conveyed – again, they are very high-level ideas. Those ideas are not spelled out in terms of what it would look like in practice, how it would be executed, the reciprocity that would need to be entailed for each of these steps. What we said very clearly is that’s something we wish to continue to discuss, but it needs to be a discussion that takes place in the context of de-escalation if it is to work.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The French president has had two calls with Vladimir Putin in the last week. The Italian president had a call yesterday, Boris Johnson today. Has the State Department gotten readouts from these governments of their engagements with the Russians?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So I would make a couple points on that. One, Conor, as you know, we have engaged bilaterally with the Russian Federation ourselves. President Biden has had now a couple conversations with President Putin in recent weeks. Secretary Blinken, as we’ve spoken to recently, has met with and engaged with Foreign Minister Lavrov, and there have been other engagements in that vein.</p>
<p>Every time we do so, we do so in full consultation and coordination with our allies and partners. And in advance of the Strategic Stability Dialogue, in advance of Secretary Blinken’s meeting with Foreign Minister Lavrov last month in Geneva, we have heard from our partners and allies of really the unprecedented level of coordination and consultation which has put them in a position to voice strong support for the type of bilateral engagement that we are undertaking with the Russian Federation.</p>
<p>That is the kind of dialogue and diplomacy, when done across the board by our partners and allies, that we think has the potential to lead to a de-escalation of tensions. So it’s something we support when it’s done in that vein. Without getting into the specifics of any diplomatic conversations, I can tell you that we are constantly on the phone with our European allies. We have representatives of this building and the administration constantly on the ground in Europe. The Secretary just yesterday had an opportunity to speak to the NATO secretary general, to the chairman in office of the OSCE, to Josep Borrell as well of the EU. So there is a constant sharing of feedback and dialogue, but just can’t get into those specific conversations.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You’re not seeing the same kind of reciprocal basis from these European – like, you’re not seeing the same level of calls. Or maybe they are taking place, you’re not reading them out?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We are reading out those calls that take place at the level of the Secretary, but there is a lot that goes on in this building and in this administration that we don’t always issue a formal written readout for.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But is there any concern that President Biden hasn’t spoken to President Putin in over a month, and he hasn’t had a call with President Macron after his two calls in the last week?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The President had an opportunity to speak to the French president not all that long ago. The Secretary spoke to Foreign Minister Le Drian not all that long ago. We have a number of people – we have, fortunately for us, an entire bureau that engages on a day-to-day basis with their French counterparts. So we have excellent coordination with our French allies.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On the 30,000 troops that may move into Belarus, is that still the assessment of the U.S. Government? Has that changed at all given this debate around imminence?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t believe there’s been any change in that assessment.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Before we leave Ukraine, could I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah, sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Extremely briefly. So Conor mentioned some of the European – but what about Orbán? Do you expect to hear anything from the Hungarians?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, look, I’ll leave it to the Hungarians to speak to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, no, no. I don’t want you to leave it to the Hungarians. I want to know if you, the United States, expects to hear from the Hungarians, your NATO Ally, about the prime minister’s meeting with President Putin. Don’t leave it to the Hungarians to tell me whether you expect &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I can tell you, Matt, is that if the Secretary has an opportunity to speak to his Hungarian counterpart, I imagine you will hear about that. We &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; are in regular dialogue with our Hungarian &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>ANNOUNCEMENT*:</strong> Please leave the building by the nearest exit or exit stairway.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Lovely. And then just one – just to get this on the record before –</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; before we all – that – get evacuated here, the – your Pentagon counterpart seemed to confirm this, but I just want to see if we can get – the documents that were published by <em>El País</em> this morning are, in fact, the documents that you – that you gave to the Russians last Wednesday, or not?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Assuming we don’t need to evacuate, I’m happy to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That was a false alarm.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; happy to take this question. So what I would say on that question, Matt, is that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Because they do seem to – what the contents of these documents seem to mirror, identically, what you guys have been saying in public. So if they’re not legit, they’re – someone is a pretty good forger.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I’ll say on this, Matt, is that we did not make these documents public, but now that they are, we can confirm what we have always said: We are united with our NATO Allies in our resolve to engage in an open, constructive, serious set of diplomatic engagements. We have gone the extra mile to seek, to find, to test the proposition that there is a diplomatic solution to this crisis. If Russia actually wants to negotiate a solution, as it claims, these documents – to go back to what I was discussing with Ben – make clear that there is a path forward to do so.</p>
<p>Look, if the source of these documents – whoever that source may be – thought that by leaking them that they would embarrass the United States, that they would drive a wedge between the United States and NATO, I think they will find that they were sorely mistaken in their effort to do so. What they – what the world can now see is that the United States and our NATO Allies are in extraordinarily close coordination, that the ideas we put forward are complementary, are symmetrical. You can probably deduce from the documents that they were closely coordinated with one another.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Right. Can you just say in a simple declarative sentence that yes, this – these were the documents that were &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Because you’ve said – you’ve gone around it – “we did not make these documents public, but now that they are” public – well, so can you just say yes or no?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I have seen nothing to suggest these documents are not authentic.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You talk about coordinating with NATO Allies in this document, and I just want to read a part of it. It says that you have “prepared to discuss” the transparency mechanisms to “confirm the absence of Tomahawk cruise missiles,” then it goes on to say, “we must consult with NATO Allies…on this issue.” So is that something you had not discussed with NATO Allies in advance, or you had?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, to be clear, NATO Allies saw our response in advance. We sought their feedback – we incorporated their feedback into the document before we provided it to the Russian Federation.</p>
<p>I think the passage you’re alluding to speaks to the fact that – speaks to the phase of implementation and how we might operationalize something like this. And goes back to the discussion you and I were having just a second ago. These were broad proposals. These were ideas – ideas that would need to be fleshed out in some detail, including in some technical detail, if they were to be set in motion.</p>
<p>So if that is something that the Russian Federation would be interested in pursuing on a reciprocal basis with the United States, it is something that we are willing to discuss. And if we were to get to a stage where it would be operationalized, that is something we would consult very closely with our NATO Allies on.</p>
<p>Who haven’t we called on? Yes, sir.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Paul from AFP.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thanks. A couple of questions, one going back to “imminent.” It was almost daily the Pentagon says that the Russian – Russia is enlarging its positions on the border. That suggests the threat is growing. So is the threat not more imminent? Or is there some reason that the word “imminence” is dropped that change that – changed that picture?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, for some time now, Paul, our concern has been that the Russian Federation is in a position to be able to move quickly if it made the decision to do so. With the amassing of forces along Ukraine’s borders, with the dispatch of troops and forces into Belarus, the Russian Federation has for some time now been in a position to move in a very dangerous and destabilizing way if that decision were made.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. Then after these calls with President Putin and discussions is there – is it possible – is it right that maybe NATO’s – NATO Allies and Ukraine have asked the U.S. to drop the word “imminent” because it’s kind of provocative? Did you do this at the – in response to Allies’ requests?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Everything we have done has been in the vein of defense and deterrence, if not diplomacy and dialogue. Our rhetoric, as opposed to what we are hearing from the other side of the Atlantic, far on the other side of the Atlantic, has been in the vein of defense and deterrence, diplomacy and dialogue. We have not sought to do anything, whether it is in terms of our actions or our rhetoric, to ratchet up tensions. And actually, to the contrary, we have sought &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But after speaking – I’m sorry, after speaking with Putin, these talks with Putin by NATO Allies, this comes – is this in response to requests from Allies to tone it down?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We coordinate with our Allies and partners on a daily basis on everything from our actions to our rhetoric. I don’t have anything to add to that. But we have simply been describing in accurate terms what it is we are seeing and the steps that we have been taking in response to that on a defensive and deterrent basis.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, one other thing, can I just &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yep.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong> Is it – from what I understood, you said before the ball is in Russia’s park in terms of responding to the letters from the West, and you said it has to go to President Putin to respond. Given the discussions that NATO Allies have had with Putin and that he’s going to Beijing, when do you – what are you hearing that he might respond? After he goes to Beijing, within a day, within two days? When’s the next move going to happen?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So just to be clear, I was relaying what we had heard from the Russian Federation. It was conveyed to Secretary Blinken yesterday by Foreign Minister Lavrov that a written response would be forthcoming, it would have carried the imprimatur of President Putin, and we would be in receipt of it. We didn’t receive a timeframe, but when the Russians are ready and prepared to send it over we’ll be ready and prepared to evaluate it.</p>
<p>Will.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah, I just wanted to ask about the Minsk process. Russia’s ambassador to the UN mentioned both during the Security Council debate and yesterday when they took over the presidency – the Security Council – that – pointed out that Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield didn’t mention the Minsk process while the other Security Council members did during the debate. Does the U.S. still see the Minsk 2 Agreement as any kind of a roadmap or a peace plan? Or is that something that that you think has moved on, is not the best blueprint for the &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, we absolutely do. We have encouraged full implementation by all parties of the Minsk agreements. The fact remains that one party to these agreements has been responsible for the vast majority of violations, but all parties need to adhere to the Minsk agreements as a way to de-escalate tensions, especially in this environment. That’s precisely why we have continued to support the Normandy Format as a means by which to discuss how all parties might be in a position to fully adhere to the agreements.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And a quick one on sanctions. The U.S. has talked about massive sanctions and sanctions that would start at the top and go down, but don’t you have to calibrate the sanctions to some degree? There’s debate in Congress, there’s debate among allies, about whether the most severe financial sanctions cutting off the top Russian banks or the entire Russian financial system would be something that it would make sense to use even at the beginning, whether – is that a debate in this administration, whether it makes sense for the U.S. as the kind of guarantor and custodian of the world financial system to some degree to make – to do something starting literally at the top with cutting off an entire nation’s financial system, if Russia goes into Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, if you’re talking about an invasion, we have been very clear that any renewed invasion would be met with a swift, severe, and united response from the United States and our allies. We have made no bones about that, neither have our allies and partners, including in the formal statements that have emanated from the European Commission, from NATO, from the G7, and from countries on a bilateral basis.</p>
<p>The point we have made is that the stakes here and the precedent here could not be more important, because we are talking about, were the Russians to invade Ukraine, an assault on the core principles that for some 70 years have undergirded the rules-based international order – the rules-based international order that have – that has enabled unprecedented levels of stability, security, and prosperity, not only in Europe but around the world.</p>
<p>So the fact is that not only are we in a position to enact these swift, severe sanctions, we are ready to given the stakes of the matter. And yes, you’ve heard from my colleagues that these sanctions and economic measures would be different from ones we, the United States Government, has levied in the past, and – on a couple of levels in terms of their scope, in terms of their strength. These would be measures that we, the United States, intentionally did not pursue in 2014, but also in the way they’re implemented – because they would start at the top of the escalatory ladder as we need – would need to send a very strong signal to Russia and countries around the world that might seek to undermine the rules-based international order that this is something that the United States and our allies and partners around the world would not countenance.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Wouldn’t you want Congress to tell you what’s the top and where to start with the financial sanctions, or does this administration prefer to calibrate its response to avoid collateral damage?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We prefer to continue collaborating and coordinating with Congress very closely, because one of the most important things we can do – and one of the most important things we have done – is to send a message to the Russian Federation that the United States is solidly against and would stand against what Vladimir Putin might have in mind. The United States is united, regardless of political party, regardless – regardless of political stripes, and we’ve seen that message be conveyed. There have been bipartisan congressional delegations that have gone to Ukraine. We have seen bipartisan members of Congress, House and the Senate, speak out very clearly and forcefully supporting what the administration is doing, but also echoing the admonitions that any Russian invasion of Ukraine would be met with a strong, swift, and united response.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I follow up with you on the Minsk Agreement thing? You said again that you want full implementation, but Oleksiy Danilov, Ukraine’s security chief, said yesterday in an interview with the Associated Press that fulfilling those obligations – fulfilling the Minsk agreements – would mean destruction for Ukraine, and he said it was impossible for them to do so. Do you have any response to that? Why is he wrong that it would destroy the country?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The Minsk agreements – and we’ve heard this from Ukrainian leaders as well – they do provide a blueprint that would serve to de-escalate tensions. The fact is that one party is primarily responsible for most of the violations, and that’s the Russian Federation. But the Minsk agreements as a whole were negotiated in good faith, they were signed on to by the parties, and we continue to believe – along with our European allies and our Ukrainian partners – that they do provide a blueprint to de-escalate tensions.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Kim Dozier. I wanted to change the subject for a minute. So I understand the Senate Foreign Relations Committee is holding a classified hearing today on Afghanistan. So I wanted to give you a chance to give us an update on Afghan evacuees – not just the American citizens, legal permanent residents, and those who have already had approved SIV applications, but the would-be evacuees who are still stuck inside Afghanistan who can’t start their P-1 of P-2 process until they physically leave the country. I’ve spoken to a number of volunteer groups. They’ve manifested entire plane-loads of people, but they can’t find third countries will to take those people, and they – those third countries, according to diplomatic go-betweens, have said the State Department has actively discouraged them from taking these Afghans.</p>
<p>So I want to hear your take on that, and do you encourage other countries to allow these people in so that they can be processed?</p>
<p><a id="post-311114-AFGAN"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So, Kim, first, to take a step back: You heard from us during the course of the U.S. Government evacuation prior to August 31st and the end of the U.S. military mission that our commitment to American citizens who chose to remain behind or who were not able to leave at that time, to lawful permanent residents, to Afghans to whom we have a special commitment, would be enduring. And I think over the past several months you have seen us make good on that pledge. When it comes to U.S. citizens and lawful permanent residents, we have directly relocated nearly a thousand.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. And that’s all great news, but I’m still talking to groups who have thousands of people manifested, who have gone through the preliminary State Department okay that – they didn’t have any red flags – and they can’t move them off the X, still. And they say when they reach out to the State Department, they get silence.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Kim, I think what you may be hearing, first of all, to be very clear, we are in many different ways supporting the Afghan people. We are supporting the Afghan people in their humanitarian needs and we have continued to lead the world in doing so.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That’s great, but that’s not getting P-1 and P-2 people out to start their applications going.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> That’s right, and what I can say is that it is an environment in which the U.S. Government is not in a position to operate. We don’t have an on-the-ground presence, so we are not in a position to undertake the same sort of operations that we were doing prior to August 31st.</p>
<p>As you know, we have an entire office here, the so-called CARE team, whose mission it is to work with a number of stakeholders, including private groups, working with them, doing all we can to support their efforts, working in turn with third countries, many of whom – and more than two dozen of whom – during the evacuation and in the weeks after showed extraordinary generosity in hosting Afghans. And many of these countries are still hosting Afghans who were relocated. That is something we continue to support.</p>
<p>When it comes to the P-1 and P-2 program, the P-2 program, as you know, it was introduced in early August precisely so that we would have another avenue by which Afghans who met the criteria would be able to enter the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program pipeline. It was a complement to the traditional P-1 program that has been longstanding.</p>
<p>It is also the case, Kim, for a number of reasons, that these programs we have always known would be useful, would be complementary to our broader efforts, but these are programs that this administration has had essentially to build up from – not quite from scratch, but programs that were decimated over the past four years.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You’ve eloquently explained the backlog and that these are things that are just started. What I’m asking about is that piece of getting – still getting more people off the X to third countries. Are you actively working with new third countries right now who would take these people?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We are actively working with a number of countries in the region, in the Middle East, around the world, as we have been. I believe, over the course of this operation, these are countries spread across four continents who have displayed this extraordinary generosity in hosting Afghans.</p>
<p>There are many pieces to this equation. Part of it is impressing upon the Taliban the imperative that they live up to the right of free passage. Part of it is the operational component, ensuring that there is a means by which – usually by air – for individuals to depart Afghanistan if they so choose. There is the charter element that goes along with that. There is a longstanding effort that some of our partners are working on with the Taliban to get Kabul International Airport stood up to regularize the flow of civilian aircraft in and out of Kabul. There is the refugee pipeline. There is a third country pipeline.</p>
<p>So yes, there are many pieces to this, and it is impossible to say that one piece is the weak link. We’re working on all of them. We’re working on all of them because we have a commitment to American citizens, to lawful permanent residents, to Afghans to whom we have a special commitment, Afghans who primarily have worked for us over the years. But also we do have these so-called P-1 and P-2 programs as part of the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program that this administration has prioritized. In the case of the P-2 program, it’s a program that we specifically stood up knowing the needs of the Afghan people.</p>
<p>I say all of that not wanting to discount what it is that we are doing as the world’s humanitarian leader for Afghanistan, to support those many Afghans – millions of Afghans – who remain in Afghanistan and who are in need of nutrition, in need of shelter, in need of provision of health care and other basic human needs. Those Afghans are Afghans who are also benefiting from the generosity of the American people, but who are also benefiting from our leadership on the world stage, encouraging countries around the world to raise their ambition when it comes to humanitarian donations, when it comes to what they are doing on behalf of the Afghan people on a financial basis. But also on a political basis, to make very clear to the Taliban that there needs to be unhindered humanitarian aid and access, that they need to respect the basic human rights of the Afghan people, and they also need to respect the commitment they have made – to your point – to allow safe passage and freedom of movement for Afghans who do wish to leave the country.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And of course, you did get women back – partially back to school today?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> This is something that we have been pressing for. I know that there have been various statements made by the Taliban. What we’ll be watching for are the actions and the follow-through when it comes to the rights of women, the human rights of Afghanistan’s women, girls, its minorities. It’s something that we have prioritized to a great degree. I know that our Special Representative for Afghanistan Tom West in every engagement he has had with the Taliban has raised this question of human rights, and specifically the rights of women and girls. We have a senior official here in our Office of Global Women’s Issues, Rina Amiri, whose sole job it is to focus on the human rights of Afghanistan’s women and girls. As you know, she was recently in Oslo with Tom West where this was a core point of discussion with the Taliban. The Taliban are under no illusions about the priority we attach to this issue, the priority we have attached and we will attach going forward.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-311114-__DdeLink__63_1164776770"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Muath Alamri from <em>Asharq al Awsat</em> newspaper.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good to see you.</p>
<p><a id="post-311114-YEMEN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Your colleague at the Pentagon announced some military support to the UAE in response to the recent Houthi attacks. What can the State Department politically offer since the President Biden promised to hold the Houthis accountable? And I have another question, but after your answer.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What kind of security assistance can we offer?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The military support.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah. So as you have heard from my colleague at the Pentagon, we have spoken in recent days to our partnership with our Gulf partners, two of whom, the UAE and Saudi Arabia, who have recently come under attack from these Houthi terrorist attacks. These cross-border attacks, the missile attacks that we’ve seen – have seen, these are operations that we have condemned in the strongest terms. We know that our partners have been able to deter and to prevent some of these attacks, including by calling on some of the technology and supplies that the United States has provided to them.</p>
<p>In the case of Saudi Arabia, we understand that our Saudi partners are now in a position to prevent about 90 percent of these incoming projectiles. Of course, we want to raise that to 100 percent. And we’re committed to working with the UAE and Saudi Arabia to help them bolster their defenses. We’re doing that through security cooperation, through arms transfers, defense trade, exercises, training, and exchanges. And those exchanges are in terms of security and defense, but also in terms of human rights and the protection of civilians, including civilian harm mitigation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Senator Menendez yesterday warned that Iran may obtain nuclear weapons in three to four weeks, and he criticized the administration approach to Iran in order to get back to the 2015 deal. What’s your assessment in that period of time, and what is your next move in Vienna negotiation?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, you heard from one of my colleagues just the other day about our concerns that Iran has made in terms of its nuclear program. These are advancements that Iran has been in a position to make ever since the last administration decided to leave the Iran deal, a deal that was verifiably and permanently preventing Iran from ever obtaining a nuclear weapon. When the Iran deal was fully implemented, the so-called breakout time to which you refer was one year, meaning that it would take Iran one year to accumulate the fissile material necessary for a nuclear weapon if it chose to do so.</p>
<p>Now, that is separate and apart from the weaponization process. We’re very concerned with both of these processes. But purely from an enrichment standpoint, that breakout time was a year. Now – my colleague alluded to this a couple days ago – that breakout time is significantly less. And that is precisely because of the decision to leave the JCPOA that was working to elongate that breakout time.</p>
<p>So we find ourself – we find ourselves with an unfortunate set of circumstances, a set of circumstances that means that the window we have in Vienna, to answer the second part of your question, is very, very short. And that window is very, very short precisely because once Iran reaches the point where its nuclear advances have obviated the nonproliferation benefits that the JCPOA conveyed, that’s a point at which it will no longer make sense, from our national security interests and the national security interests of our allies and partners around the world, to pursue a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA and we’ll have to pursue another course.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, just to be clear, the reason that the breakout time is less than a year now isn’t because of anything that any U.S. administration did. It’s because the Iranians decided to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The reason – the reason &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But – no, no, no. Hold on a second. The Trump administration pulling out of the deal didn’t force Iran to do anything. They’ve done it on their own. Right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The reason &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The reason the breakout time is – can be measured in weeks instead of months is precisely because Iran did not feel encumbered by the deal that the previous administration chose to abandon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, you can attribute motive. But they could have done it anyway, regardless. But anyway &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> They – well, they couldn’t have. If they did, there would have been severe consequences, as you know.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Right. Severe consequences similar to the sanctions that the Trump administration put on them, which didn’t stop them from doing it anyway. But that’s not – I don’t want to get into that. Can I get – I just need to ask you &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Okay. We need to wrap up shortly, so &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes. Exactly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Let me – we have not taken a question &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’ve got two Africa ones, but they are one sentence.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Okay. We do need to – yes. Yes, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks. Can I follow up with a few Yemen questions? Friday will mark a year since President Biden announced he was cutting certain support for the coalition while promising to step up diplomacy to end the war. I’m wondering, first, if you can reflect on a year out whether you believe this administration’s diplomatic approach to Yemen is working.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We believe that there must be a diplomatic approach to Yemen. We believe that diplomacy is the only durable and sustainable means by which to resolve the conflict in Yemen that has allowed the Houthis to leverage the power vacuum that has worsened what is, by many accounts, the world’s worst humanitarian emergency, where more than 16 million Yemenis are suffering from food insecurity.</p>
<p>You are right that this is a diplomatic challenge that we have prioritized from essentially day one of this administration. One of the first policy – one of the first senior personnel appointments that President Biden himself announced when he was here on his first visit to the State Department was the appointment of Tim Lenderking as our envoy to this challenge. So we are committed to this mission; we believe a diplomatic solution is the only way to resolve the conflict. We’ve always known that a diplomatic solution is not going to be easy. After all, this has been a conflict – in fact, a civil war – that has transcended administrations, going back almost a decade now.</p>
<p>The Houthis’ Marib offensive, including repeated attacks on civilians in Marib over the past year, has been the primary obstacle to these peace efforts, and recent events should make it clear that this offensive will bring only further suffering, will only worsen the humanitarian plight of the Yemeni people. Now is the time, we think – and we think in coordination with our partners, including the UN special envoy – for the parties to listen to the voices of the people and the international consensus calling for a halt to this violence and a resumption of political talks.</p>
<p>At the heart, this is a civil war. This is a conflict among Yemenis, and a durable, Yemeni-led solution is needed to end this conflict and to reverse the humanitarian crisis. So we are very much supporting the parties. We are working closely with the UN special envoy to try to achieve such a diplomatic solution.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And then just a quick follow-up: Can you say whether the U.S. has made a decision on re-designating the Houthis, and can you speak to whether sanctions imposed this year on individual Houthi leaders have been at all effective in creating leverage or deterring the group?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So you heard from the President last month now that this is a decision that is under review in terms of the FTO designation of the Ansarallah movement as a whole, but what I will say is that we will not relent in designating Houthi leaders and entities involved in military offensives that are threatening civilians and regional stability, perpetuating the conflict, committing human rights abuses or violating international humanitarian law, exacerbating the humanitarian crisis, or seeking to profit from the suffering of the Yemeni people. We’ve taken a number of such actions, including in recent weeks and months alone, and I suspect we will be in a position to take additional action given the reprehensible attacks that we’ve seen emanate from Yemen from the Houthis in recent days and weeks.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, to quickly follow up on Yemen, you condemned those attacks from the Houthis. You’ve condemned their Marib offensive. Would you take this occasion to condemn the Saudi coalition’s strikes in the last week and a half, including the one that appeared to take off – to take out Yemen’s internet connection, the other that killed scores of Yemenis in a prison, including several migrants?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Conor, we issued a statement in the Secretary’s name on this just several days ago, and we made a point that the escalation in violence, including the attacks that have emanated from the Houthis and the deaths of potentially civilians and noncombatants – it is something that we are deeply concerned about. As &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Deeply concerned, though. But you’ve condemned specifically these things from the Houthis. Do you condemn these kinds of airstrikes?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I think you have to distinguish them. One is an intentional effort to target civilians and civilian infrastructure in a third country. Another is an effort to take on a threat that our Emirati and Saudi partners face from the Houthis.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But that first phrase could be &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So I think you have to distinguish these on an analytic level, but in our engagement with our partners, we continue to stress the need to prevent civilian harm, the need to protect civilian life in these operations. We’ve also taken steps to end our support for – our offensive support to the coalition, but we continue to engage our partners on this.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But that phrase, though, deliberately targeting civilian infrastructure, could equally be applied to the airstrike that took out Yemen’s internet connection.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Conor, we have had these discussions with our partners. They know the importance we attach to the protection of civilian life, the protection of civilian infrastructure, but I think you have to distinguish between terrorist attacks and operations seeking to dismantle threats to Saudi and Emirati security.</p>
<p><a id="post-311114-URRAINE1"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. If you could quickly go back to Ukraine? Because Conor’s question made me remember about Turkish President Erdogan is going to Ukraine tomorrow. Do you guys find that useful? I realize that you have been in touch with a number of European leaders about Ukraine, but there hasn’t been the same amount of traffic with Turkey, which has offered to mediate this crisis. They have a complicated relationship with Russia, but also selling drones to Ukraine. Do you find this trip useful, and what role in your eyes should they play? They’re a NATO Ally but have a complicated relationship with the U.S. as well.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Turkey is an important NATO Ally. I will leave it to our Turkish allies to speak to the objectives of this trip. But we certainly &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you find it useful?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We certainly support any effort on the part of a NATO Ally or any country around the world to show their solidarity with Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> What is the reason that you haven’t been more in communication with the Turks about Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I think &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is it because of the strained bilateral relationship?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You will have seen that in every engagement we have had, including our recent engagements with the Turks, we have raised Russia &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; we have raised Russia and Ukraine. Turkey is a valued NATO Ally; Turkey is a member of the NATO Alliance; Turkey has signed its name to the very strong statements that have emanated from NATO on this question.</p>
<p><a id="post-311114-CHINA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> One more on China?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We need to wrap up very quickly here. Yes, sir; I haven’t taken a question from you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’ll go to India. So Indian opposition leader Rahul Gandhi, he made a remark in the Indian parliament today suggesting – saying, stating that it is due to Prime Minister Narendra Modi’s ineffective foreign policies that Pakistan and China are closer than ever. Does the State Department agree with that assessment?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I will leave it to the Pakistanis and the PRC to speak to their relationship. I certainly would not – would not endorse those remarks.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. And a follow-up to that. Why do you think Pakistan is working so closely with China? I mean, do you think they’re – they feel abandoned by the U.S.?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ve made the point all along that it is not a requirement for any country around the world to choose between the United States and China. It is our intention to provide choices to countries when it comes to what the relationship with the United States looks like. And we think partnership with the United States conveys a series of advantages that countries typically would not find when it comes to the sorts of partnerships that – “partnerships” may be the wrong term; the sorts of relationships that the PRC has seeked to – has sought to have around the world.</p>
<p>Pakistan is a strategic partner of the United States. We have an important relationship with the government in Islamabad, and it’s a relationship that we value across a number of fronts.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> What’s the State Department’s guidance to U.S. athletes who want to express any opposition to China’s human rights abuses while they’re in Beijing for the Olympics?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, so first I will say you know our position when it comes to the Olympics in Beijing. Of course, we don’t have any official diplomatic representation on the ground. We’ve also made clear we were not and are not coordinating a global campaign regarding participation in the Olympics. We know that the PRC uses disinformation to veil ongoing genocide in Xinjiang and other human rights abuses. We know that the PRC has made various accusations, including against U.S. athletes, and we know that’s what’s going on here.</p>
<p>U.S. athletes are entitled to express themselves freely in line with the spirit and charter of the Olympics, which includes advancing human rights. We call on the PRC to respect human rights and fundamental freedoms, including that very freedom of expression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And just when and where are U.S. athletes allowed to do that while they’re in Beijing? Because the IOC Rule 50.2 says that they can’t – they can’t publicly demonstrate while they’re at Olympic sites or venues, but it seems to leave open interpretation for places outside of those sites or venues, or on social media. So are American athletes allowed to use those venues to express opposition to Chinese human rights abuses?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I will reiterate precisely what I said: U.S. athletes are entitled to express themselves freely in line with the spirit and charter of the Olympics.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just say: Did you have any more specificity on the Burkina Faso situation, in terms of the amount of aid that you have put on pause, whether a decision has been made about whether it was a coup or not? And then also just wondering if you have an update on Guinea-Bissau.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have an update in terms of our provision of aid to the Government of Burkina Faso. As you and I discussed yesterday, we have put a pause on most of that assistance that was going &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But you don’t – you can’t tell me how much?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I cannot.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Very quick last question?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> NATO?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Three thousand U.S. troops that have been deployed to Europe – that’s a U.S. deployment. Why not wait until NATO activates its defense forces?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> As we said, we can and will do both. So you heard from my colleague at the Pentagon that this is – this is, as you said, a U.S. deployment. This 3,000 service members that you noted is separate and apart from the 8,500 U.S. service members who are at a heightened state of readiness and who can be called upon by a decision by the North Atlantic Council.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:12 p.m.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon. Before I take your questions, just one element at the top.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Not about Groundhog Day.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, it is about Groundhog Day. It is about Groundhog Day, in fact. Matt, you stole my thunder.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh, sorry.</p>
<p><a id="post-311114-DEPARTMENT"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> But today is Groundhog Day, and I raise that not only because it sounds like we’re in store for six more weeks of winter, nor because, as some of you might allege, I stand up here every day and say the same thing over and over again; I say that as a way to note the fact that this is the one-year anniversary of the resumption of the daily press briefing at the Department of State. We have literally been doing the same thing over and over again at the department every day we’re here, here in this room, and we’re proud of that. We wouldn’t have it any other way.</p>
<p>As many of you will recall, it was a pledge of then-Candidate Biden, long before he was sworn in as President, to resume daily press briefings in his administration, and he made that pledge because it is so fundamentally important in any number of ways. Whether an ally, a partner, a competitor, or adversary, the world needs to know where the United States stands. Just as importantly, the American people deserve to know what their government is doing, what we are doing to protect and to promote their interests around the world, how we’re confronting threats and seizing opportunities. That is, after all, why we’re here.</p>
<p>I also made the point exactly a year ago that the model we set here conveys well beyond our own borders. If the values of transparency and responsibility and accountability are to – are going to be more than just buzzwords in our global engagement, we have to practice what we preach here at home. And we need an engaged, active press corps to hold our feet to the fire. A year later I can say you all have lived up to your end of the bargain, perhaps too much so, done too good of a job. And I promised a year ago that we’d always seek to be transparent, accurate, and respectful; I hope that we, too, have lived up to ours.</p>
<p>So one year down, many more briefings to go. And with that, turn over to you, Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, thanks. Yeah, one year down and, what, three to go? Or two? Or two or one? Whatever. Anyway, thank you. And just to note that yes, it is appreciated that you’re up here every day, or at least when you’re in town, not on official travel, up here every day answering questions. Whether or not we like the answers or think that the answers are satisfactory or not is a different question.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Understood.</p>
<p><a id="post-311114-URRAINE"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But at least you’re – at least you’re taking them, so that’s appreciated.</p>
<p>Can I start with Ukraine once again, speaking of Groundhog Day? So the Pentagon have made its announcement this morning; I don’t expect you to have any additional details about that. But then – on that. But I’m just wondering if the Russian reaction to that deployment that was announced has been that you guys are escalating, now escalating tensions. And I’m pretty sure I know what your response will be to that, but I’d like to get it anyway.</p>
<p>And then secondly, your colleague at the White House just said that you are no longer – the administration is no longer going to refer to or is no longer referring to a potential Russian invasion as “imminent” because that might send the wrong signal. And I’m just wondering, especially in the context of you saying that this is the year anniversary of getting up and telling us what the U.S. policy is, if – was it a mistake to be calling it imminent in the first place? If you didn’t really know, what was the point? Why were you describing this as something that could, like, happen at the snap of a finger if now – was it what Putin said yesterday? What was it? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So – thank you, Matt. Well, first, on your first question: Look, I don’t think anyone here is going to be surprised by the reaction you’ve noted of the Russian Federation. I mean, this is literally their playbook, to turn the reality upside down. The metaphor we’ve used, that my colleague at the White House used, paraphrasing our boss here at the State Department: this is literally the fox claiming that it had no choice but to attack the henhouse. This is – talk about Groundhog Day &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, but it’s actually in the fox’s nature to attack the henhouse. That’s what foxes do. So maybe that’s &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Is that a statement about the country or &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, no. I just think it’s a – it might be a poor analogy because the fox &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Okay. Well, I will let you choose your analogy, but I think you get the underlying point. And one other analogy, other words, is – our concern is this idea of Groundhog Day, because we have seen this before; we have seen something like this before, at least. It was eight years ago, just about, when the Russians amassed troops on Ukraine’s borders; the Russians engaged in misinformation, in disinformation, in propaganda, seeking to portray Ukraine as the aggressor. The Russians then took it one step further, manufactured pretextual provocation that they then cited as a means by which to aggress against Ukraine and to undertake an incursion into sovereign Ukrainian territory.</p>
<p>So what we are doing – and my colleague at the Pentagon spoke to this at the orders of the President – these are about deterrent and defensive measures. These are measures that we have spoken to in broad strokes over several weeks, noting that – given what we are seeing: the amassing of troops, the bellicose rhetoric, the history that is at play here – it is only prudent for us to take steps in the past several weeks to provide defensive security assistance to our Ukrainian partners, and we’ve done that at an unprecedented level that we’ve spoken to in some detail. And the President also made clear that both in the event of a Russian invasion, and as a means to deter and to defend our allies on the eastern flank against broader aggression, we would be taking defensive and deterrent steps. And that is precisely what the Pentagon spoke to today.</p>
<p>Many of these force, as you heard, are already in the European theater. These are not permanent moves; they are in – precisely in response to the current security environment in light of this increasing threatening behavior by the Russian Federation. These troops, as you all know, they are not going to fight in Ukraine; they are going to ensure the robust defense of NATO territory. That is something to which we have a solemn commitment – solemn commitment under Article 5. This is just another unmistakable signal to the rest of the world, to any countries that would threaten that collective security, that collective defense of our NATO Allies, that we are committed to the Alliance, we’re committed to our Allies, we’re committed to Article 5.</p>
<p>When it comes to the second part of your question – What comes next? – Matt, we’ve always been clear there’s only one person who knows what the Russians may have in store. We don’t believe that individual, who happens to be the president of the Russian Federation, has made a decision one way or another. What has been our concern is what we have spoken to since November: these unusual movements of Russian troops; the massive buildup along the Ukrainian border; the inflow of Russian forces into what should be a sovereign, independent country – the country of Belarus – all of these steps have positioned the Russians to be able to move quickly should they so choose.</p>
<p>No one, I don’t believe, has been encouraging panic. No one has been saying an invasion is a foregone conclusion. What we have been doing is speaking to our concern. It has been a growing level of concern as Moscow’s aggressiveness and assertiveness has itself grown. But what we are doing is preparing for that. We are engaging in dialogue and diplomacy just as we pursue the path of defense and deterrence.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So you have no – there were no concerns that you’re getting people worked up for – not nothing, but getting people worked up and panicking? That’s not why you’re stepping away from the “imminence” thing?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, what we’ve been doing for weeks now is far from seeking to sow panic; we have been seeking to explain our concern and to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, but you got a lot of people’s attention by saying “imminence” and “we think that this is a” &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, this is something that should have people’s attention. We believe &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, I’m not saying it shouldn’t, but I – but you guys used the – very deliberately used those words, like this could happen, like, in the snap of a finger, and now it seems less. So I’m just wondering &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t think you are going to hear us say this is off the table; I don’t think you are going to hear us say this is a foregone conclusion.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, I know. But &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You will – you will hear us saying, and you have heard us say, that we are taking preparations for whichever path Vladimir Putin chooses.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Got you. I get that. But, I mean, is the decision not to use – not to describe this as “imminent” based on what President Putin said yesterday, or is it based on something else? What is it based on? Or is it based on the complaints from the Ukrainians that you’re getting people stoked up and put into a panic? Why?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Our language, Matt, is always calibrated to what we’re seeing. What we’ve seen ‑‑</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So it’s less imminent now than it was yesterday?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I think you are – I think you are reading far too much into &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, I guess &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; into what you may have heard.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All right.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Humeyra.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So I am actually going to follow up a little bit on that, maybe from a slightly different angle. So you guys were waiting for Putin’s remarks yesterday. Obviously, you monitored it very closely where he basically blamed the West. And you just said that there is one person and he still hasn’t made up his mind yet. So after watching Putin yesterday, the United States still thinks that he still has not made a decision to invade or not, is that correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Our assessment has not changed. We have made the point – I alluded to this yesterday – that Kremlinologists in this country and around the world are going to parse every single syllable, every word, every utterance, every sentence that came out of Putin’s mouth. If you were to do so, you could find reasons for optimism, you could find reasons for pessimism.</p>
<p>For our part, we are not optimistic, neither are we pessimistic. We’re clear-eyed about the stakes. We’re resolute in our determination to engage in diplomacy if we have a good-faith partner on the other side doing so in tandem with our partners and allies, just as we pursue simultaneously that path of defense and deterrence.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So indulge me a little bit more. His comments were pretty defiant, and like, he accused the West of trying to lure him into war. You said we’re not pessimistic, we’re not optimistic. Watching that, did those comments make you a little bit more hopeful about the diplomatic path? I mean, you must have, like, swung one way or the other. You can’t be – like it cannot have happened right in the middle.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m just not in a position to provide color commentary of the Russian president’s remarks yesterday.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> It’s not color commentary.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Did you say that people are – in this town are not parsing?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Are, are, are.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh, they are parsing &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Are.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; every single word, syllable, that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I assume that is the case.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So we’ve gone back to the Soviet reviewing stand school of analysis?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I assume – you’re probably, in fact, are speaking to some of these people. I know some of you in this room are.</p>
<p>But look, Humeyra, this is the point. We – there are people here, to acknowledge, who are watching very closely and listening very closely to what the Russians are saying. We are in the position of knowing something that was confirmed in the Secretary’s call with Foreign Minister Lavrov yesterday – that the Russians are preparing a written response to our non-paper. That is a response that will be reviewed and presumably approved by President Putin. That is a response that we assume will convey in detail, in writing, in specific language specifically what the – where the Russians are, what they are willing to engage in, what for them seems like a viable path, what doors may be closed.</p>
<p>It remains our hope, as Foreign Minister Lavrov seemed to indicate yesterday, that there will be an opportunity following the receipt of that Russian response for further diplomatic engagement. We don’t yet know the form; we don’t yet know the timing. What we do know is that any further diplomatic engagement, which we hope occurs, will be done for our part in the closest of coordination with partners and allies. We hope it is done in good faith by the Russian Federation, but we’ll be in a position to judge and we’ll be able to judge based primarily on one criterion, and that is if it takes place in a broader context of de-escalation.</p>
<p>We can talk. There are no preconditions to talking. But this diplomacy is not going to go anywhere. It is not going to address our security concerns. It is not going to address the concerns of the transatlantic community; that is to say our allies and partners on the other side of the Atlantic. And it won’t address the stated concerns of the Russian Federation if it doesn’t take place in this broader context of de-escalation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you have any indication over the past 24 hours when that response might be coming from the Russians?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> No. There has been – we don’t have anything additional to add beyond what we said yesterday in the aftermath of the call.</p>
<p>Yes, Michele.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> There are reports that Russian mercenaries are leaving the Central African Republic – these are the Wagner mercenaries – and perhaps headed to Ukraine. I’m wondering if you can tell me anything about that. Is that something that you’re seeing?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have anything to add on those reports. We have made our position on Russian mercenaries in Africa well known. These are forces that tend not to improve the security situation, and on the other hand, tend to leave countries less stable, poorer, more prone to violence. These are not constructive forces or elements. But I don’t have anything to add in terms of reports that they may be moving to other theaters.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Like Iraq or Afghanistan or &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Kylie.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m just wonderuing how the lack of substantial progress on the diplomatic side impacted the decision today to send more U.S. troops to Europe.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Kylie, we have made the point that we’re going to do these things simultaneously. Until and unless we see a de-escalation, until and unless we see an indication that Russia’s preparations for potential aggression have stopped and have been rolled back, it is only prudent for us to continue to take steps in the vein of defense and deterrence. That’s what we’ll continue to do. That’s what we’ve been doing for several weeks now.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And so even if Russia starts to engage in a more substantive way in the ideas you guys have put on the table, that won’t in any way impact the presence of U.S. troops in the future in European countries?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I will let my colleague at the Pentagon speak to this in greater detail, but our presence, our force posture around the world, is calibrated to the security environment that we face. And if we face a security environment that is prone to disruption, that is prone to destabilization, that is prone to threats, we are going to take steps in the vein of defense and deterrence. That is what we’re doing here. If that security environment changes – that is to say, if there is de-escalation when it comes to what we’re seeing from the Russian Federation – we will, of course, evaluate that and we will evaluate the implications of that on our force posture.</p>
<p>Ben.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Putin has made very clear that the U.S. has not addressed their main security concerns, and so with that in mind, is what the U.S. handed over sort of the final offer? Or have you got more things in the bag that you can offer if they come back and say this is a non-starter, we need more?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So, Ben, I think everyone in this room is probably in a better position to judge today than they were yesterday what it is exactly that we have conveyed to the Russian Federation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Why is that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I will let you – that is your job, to ask questions. It is my job to answer questions.</p>
<p>So I will just make the broad point that the ideas we have put forward – these are ideas. These are essentially proposals for additional discussion. So we have never and we have not been in a position to hand over to the Russian Federation, NATO has not been in a position to hand over to the Russian Federation an exact roadmap of what it is precisely that we are prepared to do across every realm.</p>
<p>What we have conveyed, what NATO has conveyed, the ideas that we’ve conveyed in close coordination and consultation with one another are proposals for further diplomatic engagement. This will require engagement in good faith, some concerted, fairly technical discussions if they are going to result in anything.</p>
<p>But it remains our posture and remains our preference to take part in that diplomacy, one, because it has the potential to redound positively on our security concerns, on the concerns of our European allies and partners, but also to address what the Russians have put on the table; and two, if it were to take place in the context of de-escalation, it would certainly seek to mitigate some of the tensions, some of our concerns that we’ve seen with this massive buildup of Russian forces around Ukraine and in Belarus.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So the door remains open for potentially more dialogue, more things in this document than are already there. I mean, you have more to offer them if they wanted it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The door remains open to discuss the ideas that are in this document. The ideas that we conveyed, the ideas that NATO conveyed – again, they are very high-level ideas. Those ideas are not spelled out in terms of what it would look like in practice, how it would be executed, the reciprocity that would need to be entailed for each of these steps. What we said very clearly is that’s something we wish to continue to discuss, but it needs to be a discussion that takes place in the context of de-escalation if it is to work.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The French president has had two calls with Vladimir Putin in the last week. The Italian president had a call yesterday, Boris Johnson today. Has the State Department gotten readouts from these governments of their engagements with the Russians?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So I would make a couple points on that. One, Conor, as you know, we have engaged bilaterally with the Russian Federation ourselves. President Biden has had now a couple conversations with President Putin in recent weeks. Secretary Blinken, as we’ve spoken to recently, has met with and engaged with Foreign Minister Lavrov, and there have been other engagements in that vein.</p>
<p>Every time we do so, we do so in full consultation and coordination with our allies and partners. And in advance of the Strategic Stability Dialogue, in advance of Secretary Blinken’s meeting with Foreign Minister Lavrov last month in Geneva, we have heard from our partners and allies of really the unprecedented level of coordination and consultation which has put them in a position to voice strong support for the type of bilateral engagement that we are undertaking with the Russian Federation.</p>
<p>That is the kind of dialogue and diplomacy, when done across the board by our partners and allies, that we think has the potential to lead to a de-escalation of tensions. So it’s something we support when it’s done in that vein. Without getting into the specifics of any diplomatic conversations, I can tell you that we are constantly on the phone with our European allies. We have representatives of this building and the administration constantly on the ground in Europe. The Secretary just yesterday had an opportunity to speak to the NATO secretary general, to the chairman in office of the OSCE, to Josep Borrell as well of the EU. So there is a constant sharing of feedback and dialogue, but just can’t get into those specific conversations.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You’re not seeing the same kind of reciprocal basis from these European – like, you’re not seeing the same level of calls. Or maybe they are taking place, you’re not reading them out?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We are reading out those calls that take place at the level of the Secretary, but there is a lot that goes on in this building and in this administration that we don’t always issue a formal written readout for.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But is there any concern that President Biden hasn’t spoken to President Putin in over a month, and he hasn’t had a call with President Macron after his two calls in the last week?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The President had an opportunity to speak to the French president not all that long ago. The Secretary spoke to Foreign Minister Le Drian not all that long ago. We have a number of people – we have, fortunately for us, an entire bureau that engages on a day-to-day basis with their French counterparts. So we have excellent coordination with our French allies.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On the 30,000 troops that may move into Belarus, is that still the assessment of the U.S. Government? Has that changed at all given this debate around imminence?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t believe there’s been any change in that assessment.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Before we leave Ukraine, could I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah, sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Extremely briefly. So Conor mentioned some of the European – but what about Orbán? Do you expect to hear anything from the Hungarians?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, look, I’ll leave it to the Hungarians to speak to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, no, no. I don’t want you to leave it to the Hungarians. I want to know if you, the United States, expects to hear from the Hungarians, your NATO Ally, about the prime minister’s meeting with President Putin. Don’t leave it to the Hungarians to tell me whether you expect &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I can tell you, Matt, is that if the Secretary has an opportunity to speak to his Hungarian counterpart, I imagine you will hear about that. We &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; are in regular dialogue with our Hungarian &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>ANNOUNCEMENT*:</strong> Please leave the building by the nearest exit or exit stairway.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Lovely. And then just one – just to get this on the record before –</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; before we all – that – get evacuated here, the – your Pentagon counterpart seemed to confirm this, but I just want to see if we can get – the documents that were published by <em>El País</em> this morning are, in fact, the documents that you – that you gave to the Russians last Wednesday, or not?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Assuming we don’t need to evacuate, I’m happy to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That was a false alarm.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; happy to take this question. So what I would say on that question, Matt, is that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Because they do seem to – what the contents of these documents seem to mirror, identically, what you guys have been saying in public. So if they’re not legit, they’re – someone is a pretty good forger.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I’ll say on this, Matt, is that we did not make these documents public, but now that they are, we can confirm what we have always said: We are united with our NATO Allies in our resolve to engage in an open, constructive, serious set of diplomatic engagements. We have gone the extra mile to seek, to find, to test the proposition that there is a diplomatic solution to this crisis. If Russia actually wants to negotiate a solution, as it claims, these documents – to go back to what I was discussing with Ben – make clear that there is a path forward to do so.</p>
<p>Look, if the source of these documents – whoever that source may be – thought that by leaking them that they would embarrass the United States, that they would drive a wedge between the United States and NATO, I think they will find that they were sorely mistaken in their effort to do so. What they – what the world can now see is that the United States and our NATO Allies are in extraordinarily close coordination, that the ideas we put forward are complementary, are symmetrical. You can probably deduce from the documents that they were closely coordinated with one another.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Right. Can you just say in a simple declarative sentence that yes, this – these were the documents that were &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Because you’ve said – you’ve gone around it – “we did not make these documents public, but now that they are” public – well, so can you just say yes or no?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I have seen nothing to suggest these documents are not authentic.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You talk about coordinating with NATO Allies in this document, and I just want to read a part of it. It says that you have “prepared to discuss” the transparency mechanisms to “confirm the absence of Tomahawk cruise missiles,” then it goes on to say, “we must consult with NATO Allies…on this issue.” So is that something you had not discussed with NATO Allies in advance, or you had?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, to be clear, NATO Allies saw our response in advance. We sought their feedback – we incorporated their feedback into the document before we provided it to the Russian Federation.</p>
<p>I think the passage you’re alluding to speaks to the fact that – speaks to the phase of implementation and how we might operationalize something like this. And goes back to the discussion you and I were having just a second ago. These were broad proposals. These were ideas – ideas that would need to be fleshed out in some detail, including in some technical detail, if they were to be set in motion.</p>
<p>So if that is something that the Russian Federation would be interested in pursuing on a reciprocal basis with the United States, it is something that we are willing to discuss. And if we were to get to a stage where it would be operationalized, that is something we would consult very closely with our NATO Allies on.</p>
<p>Who haven’t we called on? Yes, sir.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Paul from AFP.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thanks. A couple of questions, one going back to “imminent.” It was almost daily the Pentagon says that the Russian – Russia is enlarging its positions on the border. That suggests the threat is growing. So is the threat not more imminent? Or is there some reason that the word “imminence” is dropped that change that – changed that picture?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, for some time now, Paul, our concern has been that the Russian Federation is in a position to be able to move quickly if it made the decision to do so. With the amassing of forces along Ukraine’s borders, with the dispatch of troops and forces into Belarus, the Russian Federation has for some time now been in a position to move in a very dangerous and destabilizing way if that decision were made.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. Then after these calls with President Putin and discussions is there – is it possible – is it right that maybe NATO’s – NATO Allies and Ukraine have asked the U.S. to drop the word “imminent” because it’s kind of provocative? Did you do this at the – in response to Allies’ requests?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Everything we have done has been in the vein of defense and deterrence, if not diplomacy and dialogue. Our rhetoric, as opposed to what we are hearing from the other side of the Atlantic, far on the other side of the Atlantic, has been in the vein of defense and deterrence, diplomacy and dialogue. We have not sought to do anything, whether it is in terms of our actions or our rhetoric, to ratchet up tensions. And actually, to the contrary, we have sought &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But after speaking – I’m sorry, after speaking with Putin, these talks with Putin by NATO Allies, this comes – is this in response to requests from Allies to tone it down?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We coordinate with our Allies and partners on a daily basis on everything from our actions to our rhetoric. I don’t have anything to add to that. But we have simply been describing in accurate terms what it is we are seeing and the steps that we have been taking in response to that on a defensive and deterrent basis.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, one other thing, can I just &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yep.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong> Is it – from what I understood, you said before the ball is in Russia’s park in terms of responding to the letters from the West, and you said it has to go to President Putin to respond. Given the discussions that NATO Allies have had with Putin and that he’s going to Beijing, when do you – what are you hearing that he might respond? After he goes to Beijing, within a day, within two days? When’s the next move going to happen?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So just to be clear, I was relaying what we had heard from the Russian Federation. It was conveyed to Secretary Blinken yesterday by Foreign Minister Lavrov that a written response would be forthcoming, it would have carried the imprimatur of President Putin, and we would be in receipt of it. We didn’t receive a timeframe, but when the Russians are ready and prepared to send it over we’ll be ready and prepared to evaluate it.</p>
<p>Will.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah, I just wanted to ask about the Minsk process. Russia’s ambassador to the UN mentioned both during the Security Council debate and yesterday when they took over the presidency – the Security Council – that – pointed out that Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield didn’t mention the Minsk process while the other Security Council members did during the debate. Does the U.S. still see the Minsk 2 Agreement as any kind of a roadmap or a peace plan? Or is that something that that you think has moved on, is not the best blueprint for the &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, we absolutely do. We have encouraged full implementation by all parties of the Minsk agreements. The fact remains that one party to these agreements has been responsible for the vast majority of violations, but all parties need to adhere to the Minsk agreements as a way to de-escalate tensions, especially in this environment. That’s precisely why we have continued to support the Normandy Format as a means by which to discuss how all parties might be in a position to fully adhere to the agreements.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And a quick one on sanctions. The U.S. has talked about massive sanctions and sanctions that would start at the top and go down, but don’t you have to calibrate the sanctions to some degree? There’s debate in Congress, there’s debate among allies, about whether the most severe financial sanctions cutting off the top Russian banks or the entire Russian financial system would be something that it would make sense to use even at the beginning, whether – is that a debate in this administration, whether it makes sense for the U.S. as the kind of guarantor and custodian of the world financial system to some degree to make – to do something starting literally at the top with cutting off an entire nation’s financial system, if Russia goes into Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, if you’re talking about an invasion, we have been very clear that any renewed invasion would be met with a swift, severe, and united response from the United States and our allies. We have made no bones about that, neither have our allies and partners, including in the formal statements that have emanated from the European Commission, from NATO, from the G7, and from countries on a bilateral basis.</p>
<p>The point we have made is that the stakes here and the precedent here could not be more important, because we are talking about, were the Russians to invade Ukraine, an assault on the core principles that for some 70 years have undergirded the rules-based international order – the rules-based international order that have – that has enabled unprecedented levels of stability, security, and prosperity, not only in Europe but around the world.</p>
<p>So the fact is that not only are we in a position to enact these swift, severe sanctions, we are ready to given the stakes of the matter. And yes, you’ve heard from my colleagues that these sanctions and economic measures would be different from ones we, the United States Government, has levied in the past, and – on a couple of levels in terms of their scope, in terms of their strength. These would be measures that we, the United States, intentionally did not pursue in 2014, but also in the way they’re implemented – because they would start at the top of the escalatory ladder as we need – would need to send a very strong signal to Russia and countries around the world that might seek to undermine the rules-based international order that this is something that the United States and our allies and partners around the world would not countenance.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Wouldn’t you want Congress to tell you what’s the top and where to start with the financial sanctions, or does this administration prefer to calibrate its response to avoid collateral damage?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We prefer to continue collaborating and coordinating with Congress very closely, because one of the most important things we can do – and one of the most important things we have done – is to send a message to the Russian Federation that the United States is solidly against and would stand against what Vladimir Putin might have in mind. The United States is united, regardless of political party, regardless – regardless of political stripes, and we’ve seen that message be conveyed. There have been bipartisan congressional delegations that have gone to Ukraine. We have seen bipartisan members of Congress, House and the Senate, speak out very clearly and forcefully supporting what the administration is doing, but also echoing the admonitions that any Russian invasion of Ukraine would be met with a strong, swift, and united response.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I follow up with you on the Minsk Agreement thing? You said again that you want full implementation, but Oleksiy Danilov, Ukraine’s security chief, said yesterday in an interview with the Associated Press that fulfilling those obligations – fulfilling the Minsk agreements – would mean destruction for Ukraine, and he said it was impossible for them to do so. Do you have any response to that? Why is he wrong that it would destroy the country?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The Minsk agreements – and we’ve heard this from Ukrainian leaders as well – they do provide a blueprint that would serve to de-escalate tensions. The fact is that one party is primarily responsible for most of the violations, and that’s the Russian Federation. But the Minsk agreements as a whole were negotiated in good faith, they were signed on to by the parties, and we continue to believe – along with our European allies and our Ukrainian partners – that they do provide a blueprint to de-escalate tensions.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Kim Dozier. I wanted to change the subject for a minute. So I understand the Senate Foreign Relations Committee is holding a classified hearing today on Afghanistan. So I wanted to give you a chance to give us an update on Afghan evacuees – not just the American citizens, legal permanent residents, and those who have already had approved SIV applications, but the would-be evacuees who are still stuck inside Afghanistan who can’t start their P-1 of P-2 process until they physically leave the country. I’ve spoken to a number of volunteer groups. They’ve manifested entire plane-loads of people, but they can’t find third countries will to take those people, and they – those third countries, according to diplomatic go-betweens, have said the State Department has actively discouraged them from taking these Afghans.</p>
<p>So I want to hear your take on that, and do you encourage other countries to allow these people in so that they can be processed?</p>
<p><a id="post-311114-AFGAN"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So, Kim, first, to take a step back: You heard from us during the course of the U.S. Government evacuation prior to August 31st and the end of the U.S. military mission that our commitment to American citizens who chose to remain behind or who were not able to leave at that time, to lawful permanent residents, to Afghans to whom we have a special commitment, would be enduring. And I think over the past several months you have seen us make good on that pledge. When it comes to U.S. citizens and lawful permanent residents, we have directly relocated nearly a thousand.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. And that’s all great news, but I’m still talking to groups who have thousands of people manifested, who have gone through the preliminary State Department okay that – they didn’t have any red flags – and they can’t move them off the X, still. And they say when they reach out to the State Department, they get silence.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Kim, I think what you may be hearing, first of all, to be very clear, we are in many different ways supporting the Afghan people. We are supporting the Afghan people in their humanitarian needs and we have continued to lead the world in doing so.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That’s great, but that’s not getting P-1 and P-2 people out to start their applications going.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> That’s right, and what I can say is that it is an environment in which the U.S. Government is not in a position to operate. We don’t have an on-the-ground presence, so we are not in a position to undertake the same sort of operations that we were doing prior to August 31st.</p>
<p>As you know, we have an entire office here, the so-called CARE team, whose mission it is to work with a number of stakeholders, including private groups, working with them, doing all we can to support their efforts, working in turn with third countries, many of whom – and more than two dozen of whom – during the evacuation and in the weeks after showed extraordinary generosity in hosting Afghans. And many of these countries are still hosting Afghans who were relocated. That is something we continue to support.</p>
<p>When it comes to the P-1 and P-2 program, the P-2 program, as you know, it was introduced in early August precisely so that we would have another avenue by which Afghans who met the criteria would be able to enter the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program pipeline. It was a complement to the traditional P-1 program that has been longstanding.</p>
<p>It is also the case, Kim, for a number of reasons, that these programs we have always known would be useful, would be complementary to our broader efforts, but these are programs that this administration has had essentially to build up from – not quite from scratch, but programs that were decimated over the past four years.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You’ve eloquently explained the backlog and that these are things that are just started. What I’m asking about is that piece of getting – still getting more people off the X to third countries. Are you actively working with new third countries right now who would take these people?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We are actively working with a number of countries in the region, in the Middle East, around the world, as we have been. I believe, over the course of this operation, these are countries spread across four continents who have displayed this extraordinary generosity in hosting Afghans.</p>
<p>There are many pieces to this equation. Part of it is impressing upon the Taliban the imperative that they live up to the right of free passage. Part of it is the operational component, ensuring that there is a means by which – usually by air – for individuals to depart Afghanistan if they so choose. There is the charter element that goes along with that. There is a longstanding effort that some of our partners are working on with the Taliban to get Kabul International Airport stood up to regularize the flow of civilian aircraft in and out of Kabul. There is the refugee pipeline. There is a third country pipeline.</p>
<p>So yes, there are many pieces to this, and it is impossible to say that one piece is the weak link. We’re working on all of them. We’re working on all of them because we have a commitment to American citizens, to lawful permanent residents, to Afghans to whom we have a special commitment, Afghans who primarily have worked for us over the years. But also we do have these so-called P-1 and P-2 programs as part of the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program that this administration has prioritized. In the case of the P-2 program, it’s a program that we specifically stood up knowing the needs of the Afghan people.</p>
<p>I say all of that not wanting to discount what it is that we are doing as the world’s humanitarian leader for Afghanistan, to support those many Afghans – millions of Afghans – who remain in Afghanistan and who are in need of nutrition, in need of shelter, in need of provision of health care and other basic human needs. Those Afghans are Afghans who are also benefiting from the generosity of the American people, but who are also benefiting from our leadership on the world stage, encouraging countries around the world to raise their ambition when it comes to humanitarian donations, when it comes to what they are doing on behalf of the Afghan people on a financial basis. But also on a political basis, to make very clear to the Taliban that there needs to be unhindered humanitarian aid and access, that they need to respect the basic human rights of the Afghan people, and they also need to respect the commitment they have made – to your point – to allow safe passage and freedom of movement for Afghans who do wish to leave the country.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And of course, you did get women back – partially back to school today?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> This is something that we have been pressing for. I know that there have been various statements made by the Taliban. What we’ll be watching for are the actions and the follow-through when it comes to the rights of women, the human rights of Afghanistan’s women, girls, its minorities. It’s something that we have prioritized to a great degree. I know that our Special Representative for Afghanistan Tom West in every engagement he has had with the Taliban has raised this question of human rights, and specifically the rights of women and girls. We have a senior official here in our Office of Global Women’s Issues, Rina Amiri, whose sole job it is to focus on the human rights of Afghanistan’s women and girls. As you know, she was recently in Oslo with Tom West where this was a core point of discussion with the Taliban. The Taliban are under no illusions about the priority we attach to this issue, the priority we have attached and we will attach going forward.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-311114-__DdeLink__63_1164776770"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Muath Alamri from <em>Asharq al Awsat</em> newspaper.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good to see you.</p>
<p><a id="post-311114-YEMEN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Your colleague at the Pentagon announced some military support to the UAE in response to the recent Houthi attacks. What can the State Department politically offer since the President Biden promised to hold the Houthis accountable? And I have another question, but after your answer.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What kind of security assistance can we offer?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The military support.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah. So as you have heard from my colleague at the Pentagon, we have spoken in recent days to our partnership with our Gulf partners, two of whom, the UAE and Saudi Arabia, who have recently come under attack from these Houthi terrorist attacks. These cross-border attacks, the missile attacks that we’ve seen – have seen, these are operations that we have condemned in the strongest terms. We know that our partners have been able to deter and to prevent some of these attacks, including by calling on some of the technology and supplies that the United States has provided to them.</p>
<p>In the case of Saudi Arabia, we understand that our Saudi partners are now in a position to prevent about 90 percent of these incoming projectiles. Of course, we want to raise that to 100 percent. And we’re committed to working with the UAE and Saudi Arabia to help them bolster their defenses. We’re doing that through security cooperation, through arms transfers, defense trade, exercises, training, and exchanges. And those exchanges are in terms of security and defense, but also in terms of human rights and the protection of civilians, including civilian harm mitigation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Senator Menendez yesterday warned that Iran may obtain nuclear weapons in three to four weeks, and he criticized the administration approach to Iran in order to get back to the 2015 deal. What’s your assessment in that period of time, and what is your next move in Vienna negotiation?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, you heard from one of my colleagues just the other day about our concerns that Iran has made in terms of its nuclear program. These are advancements that Iran has been in a position to make ever since the last administration decided to leave the Iran deal, a deal that was verifiably and permanently preventing Iran from ever obtaining a nuclear weapon. When the Iran deal was fully implemented, the so-called breakout time to which you refer was one year, meaning that it would take Iran one year to accumulate the fissile material necessary for a nuclear weapon if it chose to do so.</p>
<p>Now, that is separate and apart from the weaponization process. We’re very concerned with both of these processes. But purely from an enrichment standpoint, that breakout time was a year. Now – my colleague alluded to this a couple days ago – that breakout time is significantly less. And that is precisely because of the decision to leave the JCPOA that was working to elongate that breakout time.</p>
<p>So we find ourself – we find ourselves with an unfortunate set of circumstances, a set of circumstances that means that the window we have in Vienna, to answer the second part of your question, is very, very short. And that window is very, very short precisely because once Iran reaches the point where its nuclear advances have obviated the nonproliferation benefits that the JCPOA conveyed, that’s a point at which it will no longer make sense, from our national security interests and the national security interests of our allies and partners around the world, to pursue a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA and we’ll have to pursue another course.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, just to be clear, the reason that the breakout time is less than a year now isn’t because of anything that any U.S. administration did. It’s because the Iranians decided to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The reason – the reason &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But – no, no, no. Hold on a second. The Trump administration pulling out of the deal didn’t force Iran to do anything. They’ve done it on their own. Right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The reason &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The reason the breakout time is – can be measured in weeks instead of months is precisely because Iran did not feel encumbered by the deal that the previous administration chose to abandon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, you can attribute motive. But they could have done it anyway, regardless. But anyway &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> They – well, they couldn’t have. If they did, there would have been severe consequences, as you know.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Right. Severe consequences similar to the sanctions that the Trump administration put on them, which didn’t stop them from doing it anyway. But that’s not – I don’t want to get into that. Can I get – I just need to ask you &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Okay. We need to wrap up shortly, so &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes. Exactly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Let me – we have not taken a question &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’ve got two Africa ones, but they are one sentence.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Okay. We do need to – yes. Yes, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks. Can I follow up with a few Yemen questions? Friday will mark a year since President Biden announced he was cutting certain support for the coalition while promising to step up diplomacy to end the war. I’m wondering, first, if you can reflect on a year out whether you believe this administration’s diplomatic approach to Yemen is working.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We believe that there must be a diplomatic approach to Yemen. We believe that diplomacy is the only durable and sustainable means by which to resolve the conflict in Yemen that has allowed the Houthis to leverage the power vacuum that has worsened what is, by many accounts, the world’s worst humanitarian emergency, where more than 16 million Yemenis are suffering from food insecurity.</p>
<p>You are right that this is a diplomatic challenge that we have prioritized from essentially day one of this administration. One of the first policy – one of the first senior personnel appointments that President Biden himself announced when he was here on his first visit to the State Department was the appointment of Tim Lenderking as our envoy to this challenge. So we are committed to this mission; we believe a diplomatic solution is the only way to resolve the conflict. We’ve always known that a diplomatic solution is not going to be easy. After all, this has been a conflict – in fact, a civil war – that has transcended administrations, going back almost a decade now.</p>
<p>The Houthis’ Marib offensive, including repeated attacks on civilians in Marib over the past year, has been the primary obstacle to these peace efforts, and recent events should make it clear that this offensive will bring only further suffering, will only worsen the humanitarian plight of the Yemeni people. Now is the time, we think – and we think in coordination with our partners, including the UN special envoy – for the parties to listen to the voices of the people and the international consensus calling for a halt to this violence and a resumption of political talks.</p>
<p>At the heart, this is a civil war. This is a conflict among Yemenis, and a durable, Yemeni-led solution is needed to end this conflict and to reverse the humanitarian crisis. So we are very much supporting the parties. We are working closely with the UN special envoy to try to achieve such a diplomatic solution.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And then just a quick follow-up: Can you say whether the U.S. has made a decision on re-designating the Houthis, and can you speak to whether sanctions imposed this year on individual Houthi leaders have been at all effective in creating leverage or deterring the group?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So you heard from the President last month now that this is a decision that is under review in terms of the FTO designation of the Ansarallah movement as a whole, but what I will say is that we will not relent in designating Houthi leaders and entities involved in military offensives that are threatening civilians and regional stability, perpetuating the conflict, committing human rights abuses or violating international humanitarian law, exacerbating the humanitarian crisis, or seeking to profit from the suffering of the Yemeni people. We’ve taken a number of such actions, including in recent weeks and months alone, and I suspect we will be in a position to take additional action given the reprehensible attacks that we’ve seen emanate from Yemen from the Houthis in recent days and weeks.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, to quickly follow up on Yemen, you condemned those attacks from the Houthis. You’ve condemned their Marib offensive. Would you take this occasion to condemn the Saudi coalition’s strikes in the last week and a half, including the one that appeared to take off – to take out Yemen’s internet connection, the other that killed scores of Yemenis in a prison, including several migrants?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Conor, we issued a statement in the Secretary’s name on this just several days ago, and we made a point that the escalation in violence, including the attacks that have emanated from the Houthis and the deaths of potentially civilians and noncombatants – it is something that we are deeply concerned about. As &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Deeply concerned, though. But you’ve condemned specifically these things from the Houthis. Do you condemn these kinds of airstrikes?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I think you have to distinguish them. One is an intentional effort to target civilians and civilian infrastructure in a third country. Another is an effort to take on a threat that our Emirati and Saudi partners face from the Houthis.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But that first phrase could be &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So I think you have to distinguish these on an analytic level, but in our engagement with our partners, we continue to stress the need to prevent civilian harm, the need to protect civilian life in these operations. We’ve also taken steps to end our support for – our offensive support to the coalition, but we continue to engage our partners on this.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But that phrase, though, deliberately targeting civilian infrastructure, could equally be applied to the airstrike that took out Yemen’s internet connection.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Conor, we have had these discussions with our partners. They know the importance we attach to the protection of civilian life, the protection of civilian infrastructure, but I think you have to distinguish between terrorist attacks and operations seeking to dismantle threats to Saudi and Emirati security.</p>
<p><a id="post-311114-URRAINE1"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. If you could quickly go back to Ukraine? Because Conor’s question made me remember about Turkish President Erdogan is going to Ukraine tomorrow. Do you guys find that useful? I realize that you have been in touch with a number of European leaders about Ukraine, but there hasn’t been the same amount of traffic with Turkey, which has offered to mediate this crisis. They have a complicated relationship with Russia, but also selling drones to Ukraine. Do you find this trip useful, and what role in your eyes should they play? They’re a NATO Ally but have a complicated relationship with the U.S. as well.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Turkey is an important NATO Ally. I will leave it to our Turkish allies to speak to the objectives of this trip. But we certainly &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you find it useful?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We certainly support any effort on the part of a NATO Ally or any country around the world to show their solidarity with Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> What is the reason that you haven’t been more in communication with the Turks about Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I think &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is it because of the strained bilateral relationship?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You will have seen that in every engagement we have had, including our recent engagements with the Turks, we have raised Russia &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; we have raised Russia and Ukraine. Turkey is a valued NATO Ally; Turkey is a member of the NATO Alliance; Turkey has signed its name to the very strong statements that have emanated from NATO on this question.</p>
<p><a id="post-311114-CHINA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> One more on China?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We need to wrap up very quickly here. Yes, sir; I haven’t taken a question from you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’ll go to India. So Indian opposition leader Rahul Gandhi, he made a remark in the Indian parliament today suggesting – saying, stating that it is due to Prime Minister Narendra Modi’s ineffective foreign policies that Pakistan and China are closer than ever. Does the State Department agree with that assessment?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I will leave it to the Pakistanis and the PRC to speak to their relationship. I certainly would not – would not endorse those remarks.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. And a follow-up to that. Why do you think Pakistan is working so closely with China? I mean, do you think they’re – they feel abandoned by the U.S.?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ve made the point all along that it is not a requirement for any country around the world to choose between the United States and China. It is our intention to provide choices to countries when it comes to what the relationship with the United States looks like. And we think partnership with the United States conveys a series of advantages that countries typically would not find when it comes to the sorts of partnerships that – “partnerships” may be the wrong term; the sorts of relationships that the PRC has seeked to – has sought to have around the world.</p>
<p>Pakistan is a strategic partner of the United States. We have an important relationship with the government in Islamabad, and it’s a relationship that we value across a number of fronts.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> What’s the State Department’s guidance to U.S. athletes who want to express any opposition to China’s human rights abuses while they’re in Beijing for the Olympics?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, so first I will say you know our position when it comes to the Olympics in Beijing. Of course, we don’t have any official diplomatic representation on the ground. We’ve also made clear we were not and are not coordinating a global campaign regarding participation in the Olympics. We know that the PRC uses disinformation to veil ongoing genocide in Xinjiang and other human rights abuses. We know that the PRC has made various accusations, including against U.S. athletes, and we know that’s what’s going on here.</p>
<p>U.S. athletes are entitled to express themselves freely in line with the spirit and charter of the Olympics, which includes advancing human rights. We call on the PRC to respect human rights and fundamental freedoms, including that very freedom of expression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And just when and where are U.S. athletes allowed to do that while they’re in Beijing? Because the IOC Rule 50.2 says that they can’t – they can’t publicly demonstrate while they’re at Olympic sites or venues, but it seems to leave open interpretation for places outside of those sites or venues, or on social media. So are American athletes allowed to use those venues to express opposition to Chinese human rights abuses?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I will reiterate precisely what I said: U.S. athletes are entitled to express themselves freely in line with the spirit and charter of the Olympics.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just say: Did you have any more specificity on the Burkina Faso situation, in terms of the amount of aid that you have put on pause, whether a decision has been made about whether it was a coup or not? And then also just wondering if you have an update on Guinea-Bissau.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have an update in terms of our provision of aid to the Government of Burkina Faso. As you and I discussed yesterday, we have put a pause on most of that assistance that was going &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But you don’t – you can’t tell me how much?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I cannot.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Very quick last question?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> NATO?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Three thousand U.S. troops that have been deployed to Europe – that’s a U.S. deployment. Why not wait until NATO activates its defense forces?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> As we said, we can and will do both. So you heard from my colleague at the Pentagon that this is – this is, as you said, a U.S. deployment. This 3,000 service members that you noted is separate and apart from the 8,500 U.S. service members who are at a heightened state of readiness and who can be called upon by a decision by the North Atlantic Council.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:12 p.m.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Statement on the Hack of the ICRC</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-statement-on-the-hack-of-the-icrc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 23:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=311111</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">We are concerned by the breach, announced last month, of sensitive data held by the International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC).  For 150 years, the ICRC and the wider Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement have played a unique and essential role in protecting vulnerable populations from the harms of armed conflicts, natural disasters, and other emergencies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">To fulfill that role, the ICRC often does what no one else can — accessing detained persons in conflict zones or crossing frontlines to reach those in need.  Its independence and impartiality have long allowed it to have access to confidential information and data, including data on conflict victims and other victims of armed violence, the forcibly displaced, missing persons, and other vulnerable populations.  The information it acquires and uses is critical to fulfilling its functions to provide medical services and humanitarian protection and assistance — functions that all states have pledged to support in instruments such as the Geneva Conventions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">Targeting the Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement’s sensitive and confidential data is a dangerous development.  It has real consequences: this cyber incident has harmed the global humanitarian network’s ability to locate missing people and reconnect families.  This is why it is so vital that humanitarian data be respected and only used for intended purposes.   </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">To ensure states and vulnerable people can continue to trust and rely on the Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement for the help they need, states should join the ICRC in raising the alarm about this breach.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">We are concerned by the breach, announced last month, of sensitive data held by the International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC).  For 150 years, the ICRC and the wider Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement have played a unique and essential role in protecting vulnerable populations from the harms of armed conflicts, natural disasters, and other emergencies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">To fulfill that role, the ICRC often does what no one else can — accessing detained persons in conflict zones or crossing frontlines to reach those in need.  Its independence and impartiality have long allowed it to have access to confidential information and data, including data on conflict victims and other victims of armed violence, the forcibly displaced, missing persons, and other vulnerable populations.  The information it acquires and uses is critical to fulfilling its functions to provide medical services and humanitarian protection and assistance — functions that all states have pledged to support in instruments such as the Geneva Conventions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">Targeting the Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement’s sensitive and confidential data is a dangerous development.  It has real consequences: this cyber incident has harmed the global humanitarian network’s ability to locate missing people and reconnect families.  This is why it is so vital that humanitarian data be respected and only used for intended purposes.   </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">To ensure states and vulnerable people can continue to trust and rely on the Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement for the help they need, states should join the ICRC in raising the alarm about this breach.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rewards for Justice – Reward Offer for Information on Iranian Cyber Actors’ Interference with 2020 U.S. Presidential Election</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/rewards-for-justice-reward-offer-for-information-on-iranian-cyber-actors-interference-with-2020-u-s-presidential-election/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 18:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=311023</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State’s Rewards for Justice (RFJ) program, which is administered by the Diplomatic Security Service, is offering a reward of up to $10 million for information on any person who, while acting at the direction of or under the control of a foreign government, interferes with U.S. elections by violating the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act (CFAA).</p>
<p>The Department seeks information on Iranian cyber actors Seyyed Mohammad Hosein Musa Kazemi and Sajjad Kashian – contractors employed by Iranian cyber company Emennet Pasargad – who participated in an Iranian state-sponsored, multi-phased online operation that attempted to interfere with the 2020 U.S. presidential election. This malicious cyber operation ran from at least August through November 2020 and sought to sow discord and undermine voters’ faith in the U.S. electoral process. In November 2021, these individuals and their employer, Emennet Pasargad, were designated under Executive Order 13848 for their role in attempting to influence the 2020 U.S. presidential election.</p>
<p>Kazemi helped to carry out the voter intimidation and influence campaign by compromising servers, which were used to send the threatening voter emails, preparing emails for the voter threat email campaign, and compromising the email accounts of an American media company.</p>
<p>Kashian managed computer network infrastructure used to conduct the voter intimidation and influence campaign and sought to purchase social media accounts in furtherance of the voter intimidation and influence campaign.</p>
<p>Both individuals face sanctions and federal criminal charges in connection with their activities.</p>
<p>More information about this reward offer is located on the Rewards for Justice website at <a href="https://rewardsforjustice.net/terrorist-rewards/foreign-interference-in-us-elections/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener">https://rewardsforjustice.net/english/election_interference.html </a>. We encourage anyone with information on Kashian and Kazemi to contact the Rewards for Justice office via our Tor-based tips-reporting channel at: he5dybnt7sr6cm32xt77pazmtm65fl<wbr />qy6irivtflruqfc5ep7eiodiad.<wbr />onion (Tor browser required).</p>
<p>Since its inception in 1984, the program has paid in excess of $200 million to more than 100 people across the globe who provided actionable information that helped prevent terrorism, bring terrorist leaders to justice, and resolve threats to U.S. national security. Follow us on Twitter at <a href="https://twitter.com/RFJ_USA" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener">https://twitter.com/RFJ_USA </a><wbr />.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State’s Rewards for Justice (RFJ) program, which is administered by the Diplomatic Security Service, is offering a reward of up to $10 million for information on any person who, while acting at the direction of or under the control of a foreign government, interferes with U.S. elections by violating the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act (CFAA).</p>
<p>The Department seeks information on Iranian cyber actors Seyyed Mohammad Hosein Musa Kazemi and Sajjad Kashian – contractors employed by Iranian cyber company Emennet Pasargad – who participated in an Iranian state-sponsored, multi-phased online operation that attempted to interfere with the 2020 U.S. presidential election. This malicious cyber operation ran from at least August through November 2020 and sought to sow discord and undermine voters’ faith in the U.S. electoral process. In November 2021, these individuals and their employer, Emennet Pasargad, were designated under Executive Order 13848 for their role in attempting to influence the 2020 U.S. presidential election.</p>
<p>Kazemi helped to carry out the voter intimidation and influence campaign by compromising servers, which were used to send the threatening voter emails, preparing emails for the voter threat email campaign, and compromising the email accounts of an American media company.</p>
<p>Kashian managed computer network infrastructure used to conduct the voter intimidation and influence campaign and sought to purchase social media accounts in furtherance of the voter intimidation and influence campaign.</p>
<p>Both individuals face sanctions and federal criminal charges in connection with their activities.</p>
<p>More information about this reward offer is located on the Rewards for Justice website at <a href="https://rewardsforjustice.net/terrorist-rewards/foreign-interference-in-us-elections/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener">https://rewardsforjustice.net/english/election_interference.html </a>. We encourage anyone with information on Kashian and Kazemi to contact the Rewards for Justice office via our Tor-based tips-reporting channel at: he5dybnt7sr6cm32xt77pazmtm65fl<wbr />qy6irivtflruqfc5ep7eiodiad.<wbr />onion (Tor browser required).</p>
<p>Since its inception in 1984, the program has paid in excess of $200 million to more than 100 people across the globe who provided actionable information that helped prevent terrorism, bring terrorist leaders to justice, and resolve threats to U.S. national security. Follow us on Twitter at <a href="https://twitter.com/RFJ_USA" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener">https://twitter.com/RFJ_USA </a><wbr />.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department of State Offers Reward for Information to Bring Bolivian Narcotics Trafficker to Justice</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/department-of-state-offers-reward-for-information-to-bring-bolivian-narcotics-trafficker-to-justice/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 18:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=311005</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State is announcing a reward of up to $5 million for information leading to the conviction of Maximiliano Dávila Perez, a Bolivian national.  Dávila is the former Director of the Bolivian Special Forces for the Fight Against Drug Trafficking (Fuerza Especial de Lucha Contra el Narcotráfico, or FELCN).  During his time as FELCN Director, Dávila is believed to have used his position to safeguard aircraft used to transport cocaine through third countries for distribution in the United States.  Moreover, both prior to and during his time as FELCN Director, Dávila was allegedly involved in narcotics trafficking and money laundering.</p>
<p>On September 22, 2020, Dávila and associates were indicted by a federal grand jury in the Southern District of New York.  The indictment charges Dávila with conspiring to import cocaine into the United States and conspiring to use or carry machine guns during and in relation to, and to possess machine guns in furtherance of, the drug trafficking conspiracy.</p>
<p>This reward is offered under the Department of State’s Narcotics Rewards Program (NRP), which the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs (INL) manages in close coordination with U.S. federal law enforcement partners and other U.S. government agencies.  More than 75 transnational criminals and major narcotics traffickers have been brought to justice with the help of the NRP and the Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program (TOCRP) since 1986, with the Department paying more than $135 million in rewards to date.</p>
<p>For more information on the individual listed above and the NRP and TOCRP, please see <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs/inl-rewards-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAyMDIuNTI3ODE5MzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1LW9mLWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtbmFyY290aWNzLWFuZC1sYXctZW5mb3JjZW1lbnQtYWZmYWlycy9pbmwtcmV3YXJkcy1wcm9ncmFtLyJ9.2I1FiEdAjjG77-JL1K2KugOUoVNsRvFcjzra7V_zSoA/s/1039202793/br/126024838373-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1643912981706000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2piJa_uKV1HxanAkTHAOIH">Department of State INL AntiCrime Rewards Program</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State is announcing a reward of up to $5 million for information leading to the conviction of Maximiliano Dávila Perez, a Bolivian national.  Dávila is the former Director of the Bolivian Special Forces for the Fight Against Drug Trafficking (Fuerza Especial de Lucha Contra el Narcotráfico, or FELCN).  During his time as FELCN Director, Dávila is believed to have used his position to safeguard aircraft used to transport cocaine through third countries for distribution in the United States.  Moreover, both prior to and during his time as FELCN Director, Dávila was allegedly involved in narcotics trafficking and money laundering.</p>
<p>On September 22, 2020, Dávila and associates were indicted by a federal grand jury in the Southern District of New York.  The indictment charges Dávila with conspiring to import cocaine into the United States and conspiring to use or carry machine guns during and in relation to, and to possess machine guns in furtherance of, the drug trafficking conspiracy.</p>
<p>This reward is offered under the Department of State’s Narcotics Rewards Program (NRP), which the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs (INL) manages in close coordination with U.S. federal law enforcement partners and other U.S. government agencies.  More than 75 transnational criminals and major narcotics traffickers have been brought to justice with the help of the NRP and the Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program (TOCRP) since 1986, with the Department paying more than $135 million in rewards to date.</p>
<p>For more information on the individual listed above and the NRP and TOCRP, please see <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs/inl-rewards-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAyMDIuNTI3ODE5MzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1LW9mLWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtbmFyY290aWNzLWFuZC1sYXctZW5mb3JjZW1lbnQtYWZmYWlycy9pbmwtcmV3YXJkcy1wcm9ncmFtLyJ9.2I1FiEdAjjG77-JL1K2KugOUoVNsRvFcjzra7V_zSoA/s/1039202793/br/126024838373-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1643912981706000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2piJa_uKV1HxanAkTHAOIH">Department of State INL AntiCrime Rewards Program</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-japanese-foreign-minister-hayashi-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 02:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=310838</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Yoshimasa.  Secretary Blinken condemned the DPRK’s recent ballistic missile launches, which were in violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions, and committed to trilateral cooperation with Japan and the Republic of Korea towards the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister Hayashi discussed Ukraine and the need to deter Russia from further military action or other aggressive acts.  Secretary Blinken, building on the successful outcomes of the January 6 U.S.-Japan Security Consultative Committee, reaffirmed the U.S.-Japan Alliance’s critical role as the cornerstone of peace, security, and prosperity and underscored our shared commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific region and world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Yoshimasa.  Secretary Blinken condemned the DPRK’s recent ballistic missile launches, which were in violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions, and committed to trilateral cooperation with Japan and the Republic of Korea towards the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister Hayashi discussed Ukraine and the need to deter Russia from further military action or other aggressive acts.  Secretary Blinken, building on the successful outcomes of the January 6 U.S.-Japan Security Consultative Committee, reaffirmed the U.S.-Japan Alliance’s critical role as the cornerstone of peace, security, and prosperity and underscored our shared commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific region and world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with Republic of Korea First Vice Foreign Minister Choi and Japanese Vice Foreign Minister Mori</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-republic-of-korea-first-vice-foreign-minister-choi-and-japanese-vice-foreign-minister-mori/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 02:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=310835</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Republic of Korea (ROK) First Vice Foreign Minister Choi Jong Kun and Japanese Vice Foreign Minister Mori Takeo.  The Deputy Secretary and vice foreign ministers reaffirmed the importance of trilateral cooperation between the United States, the ROK, and Japan in tackling pressing challenges in the region and across the globe.  Deputy Secretary Sherman denounced the DPRK’s recent and escalatory ballistic missile launches as violations of UN Security Council resolutions and destabilizing to the region and discussed ongoing efforts to achieve the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  The Deputy Secretary highlighted the United States’ continued readiness to engage in serious and sustained diplomacy with the DPRK in order to make tangible progress.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Republic of Korea (ROK) First Vice Foreign Minister Choi Jong Kun and Japanese Vice Foreign Minister Mori Takeo.  The Deputy Secretary and vice foreign ministers reaffirmed the importance of trilateral cooperation between the United States, the ROK, and Japan in tackling pressing challenges in the region and across the globe.  Deputy Secretary Sherman denounced the DPRK’s recent and escalatory ballistic missile launches as violations of UN Security Council resolutions and destabilizing to the region and discussed ongoing efforts to achieve the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  The Deputy Secretary highlighted the United States’ continued readiness to engage in serious and sustained diplomacy with the DPRK in order to make tangible progress.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing – February 1, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-february-1-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 23:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=310797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon. Happy Tuesday. One item at the top, and then look forward to taking your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-QATAR"></a> Yesterday, on the occasion of His Highness the Amir of Qatar Sheikh Tamim bin Hamad Al Thani’s visit to Washington D.C., President Biden announced that he intends to designate Qatar as a Major Non-NATO Ally. The President’s decision is a symbol of the strong relationship and strategic partnership between our two countries.</p>
<p>Qatar served as the first and primary transit destination for over 60,000 evacuees from Afghanistan, including U.S. citizens, Lawful Permanent Residents, Special Immigrant Visa applicants, and our Afghan partners last August, and it continues to act as our protecting power in Afghanistan.</p>
<p>Qatar stands with us as a member of the D-ISIS Coalition, is a member of the Riyadh-based Terrorist Financing Targeting Center, and has actively participated in five rounds of multilateral sanctions designations against major U.S. and UN-designated terrorist organizations.</p>
<p>Yesterday’s signing of a more than $20 billion deal between Boeing and Qatar Airways Group, which will support tens of thousands of U.S. manufacturing jobs, also highlights the strong economic and commercial partnership Qatar and the United States share.</p>
<p>As we celebrate the 50th anniversary of U.S.-Qatar diplomatic relations this year, we look forward to building on our strong foundation with an eye to the next 50 years of partnership between the United States and Qatar.</p>
<p>With that, happy to take your questions on this or anything else.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I think it won’t surprise you that I would like to move to Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Although if someone does have a question about Qatar and Major Non-NATO Ally status, I’m happy to defer. But if not, Ukraine.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-UKRAINERUSSIA"></a> So recognizing that a lot has been said today about Ukraine by President Putin, by Foreign Minister Lavrov, by Secretary Blinken on Twitter, by senior U.S. officials, is there anything new that you can report to us in terms of the diplomacy and what that will look like going forward? You will have seen that Putin said that he was open to continued talks, but there doesn’t seem to be any kind of – at least not yet, there doesn’t seem to be any kind of definite timetable for that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So Matt, as you know, we issued a written readout of the Secretary’s call with Foreign Minister Lavrov earlier today. I won’t go through that, as everyone has it now, but I’ll make a couple other broad points.</p>
<p>The Secretary made clear to Foreign Minister Lavrov, as he has before, that we are prepared to engage in serious diplomacy with the Russian Federation on a reciprocal basis. He also made clear that the non-paper we sent over – our response to the so-called treaties that the Russian Federation published the other week – contain a wide range of serious, substantive proposals. And we believe when you think about the Venn diagram between our security concerns, the collective security concerns of the United States and the transatlantic community, and in the stated security concerns of the Russian Federation, we believe that there is an intersection there where we can address those mutual concerns on a reciprocal basis. Those, of course, include our concerns, the concerns of our allies and partners, but also the stated security concerns of the Russians.</p>
<p>Now, that will require intensive, substantive, serious, sustained diplomacy if we are to get there. We are prepared for that. The Secretary also made the point that this diplomacy, if it is to bear fruit, will need to take place in a context of de-escalation. That is something, of course, that we have yet to see.</p>
<p>We heard from Foreign Minister Lavrov this morning – and I will primarily leave it to the Russians to characterize their response, but that – we heard again that they are working on a formal response to the U.S. non-paper that was sent over the other day. That draft will go to President Putin, as we have known and expected all along. And when President Putin has a chance to review it and approve it, it will be coming to the United States. We understand that once that takes place, the Russians too are willing to engage in continued dialogue. As to what form, as to the timing, that will depend on the receipt of the Russian response to our response.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So you keep talking about this Venn diagram with the overlapping areas, but the thing is is that President Putin said today that you guys have ignored their main requests. And that’s not exactly true; you guys haven’t ignored them, you’ve just flat-out rejected them and told them that they’re non-starters and that you’re not going to – so you’re well aware of what they are, and you’re not ignoring them; you’re just saying no, we’re not going to go there. So I’m just wondering if – do – given that, if you think that there is still an opportunity to resolve this without getting into what the Russians’ main concerns are.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we heard from President Putin a variety of things. I will leave it to the Kremlinologists out there – budding, professional, amateur, or otherwise – to read the tea leaves and try to interpret the significance of those remarks. For our part, we don’t necessarily need to do that because we know that a formal response from the Russian Federation is forthcoming. We heard that again today from Foreign Minister Lavrov.</p>
<p>So we have been clear and consistent since we started this process that there are areas where we believe there is maneuverability, that there is room to engage in substantive discussions, together with our allies and partners, with the Russian Federation on areas where, frankly, we have security concerns; the Russians will put their concerns on the table, and again, in full coordination with our allies and partners, we’ll see if there is room to address those concerns. We believe there is.</p>
<p>Now to your question, the response that we provided to the Russian Federation the other day, it did address the points that had been raised by the Russian Federation. That doesn’t necessarily mean that the Russians will agree with the way in which they were addressed. And I think, as you’ve heard us say all along, it will not come as a surprise to you that there are some areas where we think diplomacy can lead to progress, can redound positively on the security interests of the United States, of the transatlantic community, but also potentially Russia, while other areas are nonstarters. And those areas that we’ve said all along are nonstarters, the idea that a country – any other country can impinge on the security arrangements, the alliances, the partnerships of another country; the inviolability of international borders, sovereignty, territorial integrity. You’re right that there is no trade space, none, when it comes to those issues. That should not – and I assume did not – come as a surprise to the Russian Federation or to anyone else as we described what was in our response, because we’ve been crystal clear about that.</p>
<p>Francesco.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> How do you envision this intensive, substantive, sustained – what am I missing – serious diplomacy we’re talking about? Is this going into rounds of negotiations in Geneva over one, two years with Russia? Is that what you’re envisioning?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t think that that timeframe is what any of us have in mind as an initial matter, at least. What I can say is that for the past several weeks we have been, together with our allies and partners, engaged in diplomacy with the Russian Federation in a variety of venues and fora. We have done this bilaterally through the Strategic Stability Dialogue that Deputy Secretary Sherman engaged in with her Russian counterpart, Mr. Ryabkov, in Geneva the other week. We have done this in the context of the NATO-Russia Council, together with our NATO Allies. We’ve done this in the context of the OSCE with all of the participating member states of the OSCE of course, which – of which Russia is a member. And Secretary Blinken had an opportunity, again bilaterally but outside the formal SSD context, the context of the Strategic Stability Dialogue, to engage with Foreign Minister Lavrov in Geneva the other week.</p>
<p>So we are prepared to continue through all of those venues, through all of those fora. What matters most to us is that our diplomacy, our collective engagement with the Russian Federation, continues to be conducted in full consultation and coordination with our partners and allies. Oftentimes that will take place, we expect, with our allies and partners sitting next to us at the table, as would happen at the NATO-Russia Council, at the OSCE.</p>
<p>If it were to involve another bilateral engagement, which we are open to, we will continue to do that in full consultation and coordination with our allies and partners. Nothing about without. That is not a mantra that we are ever going to abandon or discount in any way. And I think you actually saw that today. After Secretary Blinken had an opportunity to speak with Foreign Minister Lavrov, he then immediately picked up the phone and spoke with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg, OSCE Chairman-in-Office Zbigniew, EU High Representative Josep Borrell. The Secretary thought it was important to engage them immediately on his discussion with Foreign Minister Lavrov. They had an opportunity to discuss that engagement. They also had an opportunity to discuss our approach to the Russian Federation going forward, both in terms of diplomacy and dialogue, which remains our preferred course, but the alternative course that we are continuing to pursue, the course of defense and deterrence.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are you in any way more confident today after hearing from Foreign Minister Lavrov, after hearing President Putin at his press conference, that an aggression against Ukraine can be avoided by diplomacy?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I’d make a couple points. One, this is not about optimism, this is not about pessimism. This is about a clear-eyed approach to what – to us and what to our allies and partners – is a clear threat to international peace and security. So these emotions, these orientations one way or another – to us, it is about the stakes of this, and the stakes for us are very clear.</p>
<p>Number two, again, we are just not going to be in the business of parsing, certainly not publicly, statements we hear from senior Russian officials, because we understand again today that we’ll be in receipt of a formal response that has been approved by President Putin that, presumably, will detail precisely and in specific language where the Russian Federation stands.</p>
<p>Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. Is there – speaking of timeframes, is there a timeframe beyond which if you don’t see any signs of de-escalation there could be a number of steps – there’s pressure from the Senate, in fact, for sanctions before any kind of kinetic action. Could the U.S. – is there some limit to how long you’re going to have 130,000-plus troops and other military equipment, missiles in Belarus?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well &#8212;</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-DEPARTMENT1"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And if I may just say something also on a point of personal privilege, I don’t know what else has been said in this room, but I just want to say that a remark on the passing of a real pioneer, one of your predecessors, Phyllis Oakley, who was just such – I don’t know, such an inspiration to women in this building and to the reporters who cover this building, because of the written and, most importantly, the unwritten rules of gender discrimination in the Foreign Service. And she really persevered and broke through, so she was a great standard bearer.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Among other titles, she was an assistant secretary of state. She was also a deputy spokesperson, spent some time speaking to your predecessors as well. So she is someone who has really left her mark on this institution. You saw that the department issued condolences to her family and to her loved ones and noted the legacy she leaves behind, a legacy that was integral to doing what was long overdue: ensuring that women were fully engaged, able to be fully engaged in this work, and that married women had the same rights as their male counterparts. So we do note her passing and appreciate you raising that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-UKRAINERUSSIA2"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> In terms of the timeframe, our goal here is to forestall, is to prevent, is to deter a Russian – a further Russian invasion of Ukraine. So only the Russian Federation can determine how long this goes on for. We are ready either way. We are ready if the Russians are willing to continue down the path of diplomacy and dialogue in good faith – again, knowing that this is a process that, if it is to be effective, has to take place in the context of de-escalation.</p>
<p>We are equally ready, however, if the Russians determine that they are set on the path of further and renewed aggression. This is a path that we have been walking simultaneously as we have an outstretched hand for diplomacy and dialogue. This is the path we’ve been walking simultaneously with our partners and allies.</p>
<p>We’ve spent some time in recent days speaking to the long track record we have when it comes to this deepening sense of concern that has developed over almost three months now. It was in November, early November if I recall, where we first started talking about this publicly. We started to engage allies and partners late last year as the intelligence and information emerged of the Russian military buildup along the Ukrainian border, as our own concerns grew based on information that was then private and has since been made public.</p>
<p>So this is something we have been at for some time. But again, our goal is to forestall, to deter, to do everything we can to see to it that there is not renewed Russian aggression against Ukraine. But again, our charge is to be prepared with whatever course Vladimir Putin decides.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah, Ned.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>What was the main achievement between (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, it was an opportunity – first, this was a moment that was agreed to by the two individuals in Geneva, coming out of the Secretary’s meeting with Foreign Minister Lavrov in Geneva last month now. It was agreed that the two would have a follow-on conversation in the coming days. It was shortly after that engagement in Geneva where we submitted what we call our non-paper, the written response to the so-called Russian treaties. And that was done.</p>
<p>We – the Russian Federation has now had that document for some time. We understand that they are studying it. We understand that Vladimir Putin has had an opportunity to – at least an opportunity to see it, and we know now that he will have an opportunity to approve the response that comes back from the Russian Federation.</p>
<p>So the point was at least twofold. One, it was to confer on the road ahead. and we did come away with a clearer sense of what we can expect in the coming days or weeks as – however long it takes for the Russians to provide us with their response. We know from there that the Russians appear amenable to continue to engage in dialogue. As we’ve said, we far prefer that course even as we know it needs to take place, if it is to be successful, in the context of de-escalation.</p>
<p>But it was also an opportunity for the Secretary to reiterate the messages that the Russians have heard for some time now: that even as we far prefer the course of diplomacy and dialogue, we are continuing to prepare down the course of defense and deterrence. And so we had an opportunity again today to reinforce the idea of the high cost, the substantial cost, the sudden cost, that would befall the Russian Federation if this aggression were to go forward.</p>
<p>Simon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I wondered now that Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Lavrov have now spoken twice, they’ve exchanged papers, now you’ve said there’s a – the response will go through Putin and then afterwards Blinken and Lavrov will speak again. I wondered is it then time – because there doesn’t seem to be anything changing in terms of both sides’ positions, is it then time for the two presidents to speak again after that response has come? Does it need to escalate to that level?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It really depends on where we are. You’ve heard repeatedly from President Biden, I believe most recently during his press conference last month now, that he and we remain open and amenable to another leader-level engagement between President Biden and President Putin. They’ve had an opportunity to speak on the phone. They have seen each other on screen within recent weeks. If we believe we’re at a moment where another leader-level engagement has the potential to move the ball forward when it comes to this diplomacy, that is certainly something we are open to and amenable to. But it will just depend on where we are after this next step.</p>
<p>Ben.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I hate to say it, but it sounds very much like Groundhog Day. I mean, we’ve been here for a month. You say the same thing; Russia says the same thing. Can you point to any one thing that shows, that suggests Russia is open to real dialogue? Anything? Anything practical that suggests they really want to change their actions?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Ben, that’s not incumbent on us. That’s incumbent on Moscow. So &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So you’ve seen nothing?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, it is true, as you have heard from us, we have not seen concrete, tangible signs of de-escalation. That is what we have continued to convey that we need to see if this dialogue, if this diplomacy, is going to bear fruit.</p>
<p>But to your question, we are not waiting on signs of de-escalation. We are not sitting on our hands calling for de-escalation. And we are moving forward as quickly and resolutely as we can to proceed down this path of defense and deterrence. Again, this is about defensive steps that we are taking as an Alliance, as a NATO Alliance; defensive steps that we are taking to shore up the defenses of our partner Ukraine; steps that we are taking to deter a Russian invasion or renewed Russian aggression against Ukraine. Some of that is consistent with the defensive steps that we’ve taken. Some of that lies in the fact that we’ve been very clear – not only the United States but our European allies and others – about the massive costs – economic, financial, and otherwise – that would befall the Russian Federation if an invasion, renewed aggression, were to go forward.</p>
<p>You have already seen manifestations of those costs even in advance of the imposition of any new sanctions or authorities on the Russian Federation. We’ve talked about this before, but the Russian stock market has declined significantly, the value of the ruble has declined significantly. Market participants are growing increasingly pessimistic about the implications of the sanctions and the economic measures that we’ve talked about were they to go forward. So that, I think, is just a preview of what would – what would transpire were these measures to be fully put into place.</p>
<p>So to recap, that is a question that is best addressed to Moscow. It’s incumbent on Moscow to de-escalate. We are not waiting for de-escalation. We are open and prepared to engage, continue to engage, in diplomacy. But we are also moving ahead swiftly down the path of defense and deterrence.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And just – there was some confusion about the letter was received yesterday. A few senior administration officials appeared to say that was the letter from Russia they were expecting, it was reported – and does that suggest that you don’t know what’s coming in that letter, that it – that well could have been the letter when you first saw it? Why the confusion?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> No, there was never an intention to suggest that was the formal response from the Russian Federation. What one of your colleagues reported and what you heard from senior State Department officials yesterday is that we received a follow-up from the Russian Federation. I will leave it to Foreign Minister Lavrov and the Russians to characterize what exactly they intended by that. But Foreign Minister Lavrov spoke to this missive publicly over the weekend, and we understand again today that we’ll be receiving a formal response from the Russian Federation once it has been approved by President Putin.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just warn you, though, that Ben’s first question – since tomorrow literally is Groundhog Day, you should expect the same question again.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I may have a similar answer. Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> In which case it would just &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It would be &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; in keeping with &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; prove the prophecy true.</p>
<p>Yes, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Marcin Wrona, TVN Discovery from Poland.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Andrea mentioned sanctions, and as diplomacy seems to be going nowhere now, isn’t it high time to start strengthening the eastern flank of NATO? And you mentioned Polish Foreign Minister Zbigniew Rau a moment ago. He is coming here tomorrow, and he will be talking about that. And he’s also meeting with Secretary Blinken later this week, so could you preview those talks with the Secretary, between the minister and the Secretary?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So to your first question, isn’t it time to strengthen the eastern flank of NATO, the answer is unambiguously yes. We have been talking about that for weeks now, and in fact, we have taken concrete steps, some of which have been announced by the Department of Defense, to place thousands of troops, U.S. service members, at a heightened state of readiness, should they be called into service by the North Atlantic Council. We have worked concertedly with our NATO Allies, including our allies on the eastern flank, to work with them to prepare for the eventuality, possibility of further Russian aggression. We will continue to take steps to reassure, to reinforce – defensive steps – NATO’s eastern flank because we agree it is important.</p>
<p>When it comes to the Polish foreign minister, as you noted, as I noted earlier, the Secretary had an opportunity to speak both with him, with the EU High Representative Josep Borrell, and the NATO secretary general today. We will continue to engage with our Polish allies both in the context of the OSCE – and the engagement today was in the foreign minister’s role as the chairman-in-office of the OSCE – but also as a valued and important NATO Ally. I don’t want to get ahead of those discussions, but this gets back to your question. We will continue to show our support in many different forms for our NATO Allies, those on the eastern flank, our NATO Allies throughout the continent.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Now, what you said was putting those troops on heightened alert. What about sending troops now to the eastern flank before the – any aggression that Russia may perpetrate?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I don’t want to speak for the Department of Defense; I don’t want to speak for the White House. But I will tell you that we are taking and are considering a number of steps that will reinforce the message of defense and deterrence. Some of that is with regard to the unprecedented levels of defensive security assistance that we’ve provided to our Ukrainian partners; some of that is in the authorization – the expedited authorization – that we provide to – provided to our NATO Allies, including our Baltic allies, to provide U.S. origin equipment to Ukraine. But again, we are taking steps in the vein of defense and deterrence, working closely with our allies on the eastern flank to reassure and to reinforce their own defenses.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> In terms of NATO and U.S.-European unity, do you find that Viktor Orbán visit to Moscow and press conference with Putin is helpful in any way?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, look, we know that a number of our counterparts around the world have engaged with the Russian Federation, some with Foreign Minister Lavrov, some with President Putin directly. We have consistently said that we support dialogue, we support diplomacy that is conducted, as we have, in full coordination and consultation with the alliance. That has been the North Star of our engagement with the Russians when our allies are not sitting next to us physically at the table – nothing about Europe without Europe, nothing about Ukraine without Ukraine. So any dialogue, any diplomacy that is conducted in a similar vein is something that we would support, especially if it’s something that has the potential to produce tangible signs of de-escalation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Was it the case for the Hungarian prime minister visit?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I will leave it to our Hungarian allies to characterize their engagement with the Russian Federation.</p>
<p>Courtney.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks. Just another follow-up on Andrea’s question earlier, I mean, about the deadline for de-escalation, rather. I mean, you’ve referred to economic and other penalties in the event of further and renewed aggression, but does that mean that the status quo can endure indefinitely as you continue hoping for a diplomatic breakthrough?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t think anyone wants to see the status quo endure indefinitely, and I say that because this massive Russian buildup along the border with Ukraine, the dispatch of troops into what should be sovereign, independent territory of Belarus – all of this heightens tensions. All of this increases the possibility of, whether by accident, whether by miscalculation, whether by the fabrication of a pretext, that this buildup gives way to conflict. That is certainly not something we want to see happen.</p>
<p>So no one is happy about the current situation. No one wants to see this buildup remain as it is for any longer than is necessary. That’s why we’ve continued to call for de-escalation and why we have continued to call for tangible signs of de-escalation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can we move &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Let me move back to the – Peter.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, I wanted to – actually to follow up on that same point, I mean, because all of this seems to put the U.S. in a very kind of reactive position where there’s a risk of State Department priorities being set by Vladimir Putin. Is there a point at which this diplomatic process taking up so much of the Secretary’s time, so much of other senior officials’ time, and ultimately surely detracting from efforts to pivot to Asia or – and focus on competition with China – is there a point at which this just needs to end?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’re a large country. We’re a large department. Not to use once more an overused metaphor, but we can walk and chew gum at the same time. In recent days alone, you’ve seen the President, you’ve seen the Secretary engage with the amir of Qatar. You’re seeing him today with his Cypriot counterpart. You’re seeing us engage on any number of challenges and opportunities in the region.</p>
<p>So it is not the case that even as we are intently focused on a challenge, even something we might call a crisis like this, that it crowds out our ability to focus on the other challenges, the other opportunities that faces the United States.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So there’s no time limit?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, we do not want to see this escalation of tensions last any longer than is necessary. We are calling for immediate de-escalation. That is what we want to see happen.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, were you able to achieve an agreement with Qatar regarding providing Europe with gas in case of (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> This is something, when we talk about the contingency planning that we do – not necessarily in the vein of defense and deterrence, but in the vein of prudent planning – that we have discussed with a number of energy-producing countries around the world. We know that the strength, we know that the severity, we know that the suddenness of the measures that we are prepared to put in place on the Russian Federation could have impacts well beyond Russia, including in terms of energy supplies. And so that’s why we have had regular, frequent, substantive conversations with countries around the world on how we might mitigate some of those impacts, and we believe – we certainly believe we’ll be in a position to do so.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-ISRAELPALESTINIANS"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Going with Israel, Amnesty came out with this report accusing Israel of imposing apartheid on the Palestinians with policies of segregation, dispossession, and exclusion that amount to crimes against humanity. What’s the U.S. Government’s response to that? Do you agree with the conclusions of this report, and do you share those concerns about the situation there in Israel?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, Simon, you know that as a general matter we don’t offer public comprehensive evaluations of reports by outside groups. We have our own rigorous standards and processes for making determinations on potential human rights abuses, for documenting what we see take place around the world, including on an annual basis in the Human Rights Report.</p>
<p>What I will say, however, is that we reject the view that Israel’s actions constitute apartheid. The department’s own reports have never used such terminology. We are committed to promoting respect for human rights in Israel and the West Bank and the Gaza Strip. We have an enduring partnership with Israel, and we discuss a wide range of issues with our Israeli counterparts, including those related to human rights.</p>
<p>We support the efforts of the Israeli Government, of the Palestinian Authority, alongside human rights activists to ensure accountability for human rights violations and abuses. And we continue to emphasize to Israel and to the Palestinian Authority the need to refrain, as you’ve heard us say repeatedly, from unilateral actions that exacerbate tensions. This includes the annexation of territory, settlement activity, demolitions, incitement of violence, and the providing of compensations for individuals imprisoned for acts of terrorism. We take all allegations of human rights abuses seriously – that is true around the world – including allegations of arbitrary detention, and we continue around the world to urge respect for human rights.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> A follow-up on &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you think it comes from a place of anti-Semitism to make those accusations? That’s what Israel’s response to Amnesty has been.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have had an opportunity to speak about this with our Israeli counterparts. They have conveyed their objections to the report. As we’ve noted, we don’t offer our own public comprehensive evaluations of reports, but we certainly reject the label that has been attached to this.</p>
<p>When speaking about Israel – one other point here – we think that it is important as the world’s only Jewish state that the Jewish people must not be denied their right to self-determination, and we must ensure there isn’t a double standard being applied.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, it may be true that you don’t offer public comprehensive evaluations of outside reports, but you certainly cite them quite a bit in your own Human Rights Report. And I went back and looked, and in terms of just the last Human Rights Report cited Amnesty International on Ethiopia, on Cuba, on China and Xinjiang, on Iran, on Burma, on Syria, on Cuba. And that – those references are endorsements of what this group, Amnesty, and then other groups as well that are cited, have found. Why is it that – without taking a stand or making a judgment about the findings of this particular report, why is it that all criticism of Israel is – from these groups is almost always rejected by the U.S., and yet accepted, welcomed, and endorsed when it comes – when it comes out, when the criticism is of other countries, notably countries with which you have significant policy differences?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, I would make a couple points. Number one, when we include a footnote in something like &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> These aren’t footnotes, Ned. These are – these are full-on citations.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> When we cite – when we cite, which it’s a game of semantics, I suppose, but whether you call it a citation or a footnote &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, when it says in the report, Amnesty International found this, X &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; in Xinjiang with the Uyghurs, and we – and we determine that we think that it’s a genocide, and you guys come out and cite that, and say, well, we also agree that it’s a genocide &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> That is a far cry, Matt, from saying – from saying that we have &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m not saying it’s the same thing, but &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; comprehensive agreement with a third-party report that was produced by an outside group.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So it’s just – so it’s just when it’s criticism of Israel that you feel free to disagree? Where have you ever disagreed with an Amnesty report or a Human Rights Report on a country such as Iran or China?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> This is not – Matt, this is not about any outside group. This is about our vehement disagreement with a certain finding in a report by an outside group.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There are plenty of times where we cite, as you said, outside groups in our own reports. We cite the facts that they have uncovered, that they have put forward. But I don’t think you’re going to find any citation in any State Department document – and I don’t think I’ll regret saying this – that says the department agrees on a comprehensive basis with absolutely everything that’s in this report.</p>
<p>Barbara.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is it the department’s view that human rights abuses resulting from occupation are discrete events rather than resulting from discriminatory policies or discriminatory systems that are backed up by law?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Barbara, we document this comprehensively in our own Human Rights Reports. And we document allegations of and what we have found in terms of Israel, and the West Bank, and the Gaza Strip comprehensively on an annual basis. So I will leave it to that document to speak to our framework for this. I think you have heard us on a number of occasions when we have heard reports of or been in position to corroborate human rights abuses in this region that we have not hesitated to speak out.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I got two really brief ones on Israel (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> One is you may have seen that the Israeli military today said it was censuring or reprimanding a couple – several soldiers for their role in the death of – or leading to the death of a Palestinian American. Is – I’ve been asking for a couple days now about whether you’re satisfied with your request for clarification for – does this do it? Have you gotten from – have you gotten this information from the Israelis, and are you satisfied with the response?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I expect you’ll – we’ll have a little bit more to say on this later today, but let me say that we continue, as I said yesterday and last week, to be concerned by the circumstances of the death of Mr. Omar Assad. He, of course, was a U.S. citizen who was found dead on January 12th after Israeli soldiers detained him in the West Bank.</p>
<p>We do note the public statement on the report of the IDF, the Israeli Defense Forces, commanders’ investigation into the case and its findings, including the determination that, quote, “the incident showed a clear lapse of moral judgment,” and a failure to, quote, “protect the sanctity of any human life.” The IDF public summary of the investigation further states that the disciplinary action is being taken against the commander of the Netzah Yehuda Battalion and other officers responsible for the unit involved in the incident, and that the military police criminal investigation division investigation of the case is ongoing. We expect a thorough criminal investigation and full accountability in this case, and we welcome receiving additional information on these efforts as soon as possible. We continue to discuss this troubling incident with the Israeli Government.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. So this – what the IDF announced today is not satisfactory in and of itself; you want a criminal investigation?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have – we are continuing to discuss this. These are public statements that have come from the IDF. Again, we know that the investigation itself is ongoing, so it’s something I expect we’ll continue to discuss with our Israeli counterparts.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All right. And then one other one, and this is really brief, and it’s kind of minor, but it has attracted some attention, and that is yesterday after his conversation with Foreign Minister Lapid, it was – the Secretary’s conversation with – that Secretary – was it yesterday or maybe it was the day before?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It was yesterday.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But anyway, he tweeted something, and identified Foreign Minister Lapid as “Alternate Prime Minister,” which is something that he’s – in the tweet, right. And he’s never called him that before. So I’m just – is there a reason for that, instead of calling him &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> My understanding is that his – that’s his formal title.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, his title is also foreign minister.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, so you’ve just decided to use his formal title starting yesterday? I don’t know.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There has been no change &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; in how we view Mr. Lapid. He is the alternate prime minister and foreign minister.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Gotcha.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-CUBA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, on Cuba, any comment on the recent mass trials of Cubans that participated in the protests for political reform last year? Almost 800 people has been charged with more than 170 already convicted, some of them facing jails or prisons. Is there a space for new sanctions? Can we expect, like, a response for the U.S. Government, as you have praised the demonstrators last year?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, it is true that ever since the protests that began on July 11th of last year, we have seen the Cuban Government respond with their trademark brand of repression of their own citizens. We believe – and you’ve heard from us – that the Cuban people, just like people around the world, have every right to continue to voice their desire for fundamental freedoms, and we condemn the failures of the Cuban Government to protect those universal rights and the failure of the Cuban Government to meet the most basic needs of the people. Again, rather than focusing on its own provision of services, its own governance, the protection of rights within Cuban society, the Cuban regime has responded with repression. And it was just last month that the so-called <em>Damas de Blanco</em> were imprisoned for doing nothing more than exercising what should be a universal right.</p>
<p>We support the rights of Cubans and people everywhere to exercise their freedom of expression and peaceful assembly. We call on the Cuban Government to respect these rights and to release those unjustly detained for peacefully protesting. No one should face prosecution, no one should face imprisonment, for exercising a right that is as universal in Cuba as it would be anywhere else.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But is the U.S. Government think about new sanction, or is there a space for new sanction, given the big scope of they are already in place – that are already in place?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, ever since July 11th of last year, we have enacted a series of measures to promote accountability against those individuals and entities within the Cuban Government who are responsible for this repression, who are responsible for the violent crackdowns on peaceful protesters last summer and in the ensuing weeks. So we will continue to look to ways to promote accountability and to uphold and protect and promote what should be the universal rights of the Cuban people.</p>
<p>Yes, Ben.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-DEPARTMENT"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yesterday <em>The New York Times</em> sued the State Department over some Freedom of Information requests that the State Department hasn’t been responding to. These are in relation to Romanian embassy emails sent between 2015 and 2019 that mention a number of international businesspeople, including the President’s son, Hunter Biden. Do you have any comment on that? Why is it taking so long to release these emails?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have a comment on pending litigation. As you know, Ben, when it comes to FOIA requests, we process these as expeditiously as we can. We are committed to and we always do follow the law when it comes to that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But administration – the family members of administration officials should not be able to reach out to the State Department for their own personal business dealings, correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Ben, I don’t know to what you’re referring specifically. We &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The content of these emails suggests that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You have heard from Secretary Blinken that this department is committed to exercising and wielding the highest standards of conduct in office. The only thing that undergirds our decisions and decision making is the national interest.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-INDIARUSSIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Two questions. Yesterday at the UN Security Council, India abstained from the vote on whether to pursue the discussion. Russian officials have thanked India for this abstention. Were you disappointed?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, I think what we saw in the Security Council yesterday were countries from around the world voicing their concern with this Russian military buildup that has needlessly provoked a crisis, an international crisis, an international threat to peace and security, the very reason the UN Security Council took this matter up in the first place. And you heard from a variety of countries that the international community is firmly behind a – the path of diplomacy and dialogue. That’s what we heard coming out loud and clear of the UN session yesterday.</p>
<p>Sure.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-BURKINAFASO"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Two brief asks and then I’ll just – one, have you guys yet decided whether or not what happened in Burkina Faso was a coup? And the reason I’m asking this again today is because the Millennium Challenge Corporation says that it has suspended – it’s more than 400 million, but it might be 450 million – but anyway, they’ve suspended a big chunk of their program to Burkina Faso. So has the State Department made a determination on this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So we are evaluating the impact of what we’ve seen transpire in Burkina Faso in recent days on our engagement with the country. It’s too soon for us to get into specifics in great detail, but we’ve called for restraint by all actors as we carefully review the events on the ground for potential impact on our assistance. What I can say now is that we have paused most assistance for the Government of Burkina Faso as we continue to monitor the situation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, can you be a little bit more specific about that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I can’t.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> When you say “most,” what does that mean?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Most means most. It means the majority. I can come up with other synonyms, but no, I just – I’m not in a position now to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m not looking for a synonym for “most.” I’m looking for like a number, and what exactly is it? I mean, is it FMF? Is it &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m just not in a position to – I’m not in a position to do that today, but we’re continuing to evaluate what’s transpired and the appropriate impact on our assistance to the government.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All right. Well, so, do you have less high standards or stringent standards than the Millennium Challenge Corporation does?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have our own standards, and we have a standard &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Your standard is set by law, actually, so it’s not really your standard; it’s Congress’s standard, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It is – you are not incorrect, but yes, it is a standard that we hew to.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And so that standard has not yet been met.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, it is a standard against which we are evaluating what has transpired. So when we’re in – if we are in a position to offer an evaluation against the standard, we will let you know.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-GUINEABISSAU"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All right. And then do you know – you’ve seen, probably, reports about what’s happening in Guinea-Bissau.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you have anything to say about &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’re monitoring those reports closely. They just began to emerge several hours ago, so we are continuing to watch closely.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-MALI"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> To remain in the region, what do you make of the huge differences appearing every day between Mali, the government – the junta in Mali and France and Europe? And do you fear this could be a real blow to the counterterrorism operations in the region, in the Sahel?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, as you know, our French allies are indispensable partners in the counterterrorism effort, whether it is in the region or beyond, but certainly in the region. When it comes to what we have seen transpire between the Government of Mali and our French allies, I would refer to them for any comment.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:57 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon. Happy Tuesday. One item at the top, and then look forward to taking your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-QATAR"></a> Yesterday, on the occasion of His Highness the Amir of Qatar Sheikh Tamim bin Hamad Al Thani’s visit to Washington D.C., President Biden announced that he intends to designate Qatar as a Major Non-NATO Ally. The President’s decision is a symbol of the strong relationship and strategic partnership between our two countries.</p>
<p>Qatar served as the first and primary transit destination for over 60,000 evacuees from Afghanistan, including U.S. citizens, Lawful Permanent Residents, Special Immigrant Visa applicants, and our Afghan partners last August, and it continues to act as our protecting power in Afghanistan.</p>
<p>Qatar stands with us as a member of the D-ISIS Coalition, is a member of the Riyadh-based Terrorist Financing Targeting Center, and has actively participated in five rounds of multilateral sanctions designations against major U.S. and UN-designated terrorist organizations.</p>
<p>Yesterday’s signing of a more than $20 billion deal between Boeing and Qatar Airways Group, which will support tens of thousands of U.S. manufacturing jobs, also highlights the strong economic and commercial partnership Qatar and the United States share.</p>
<p>As we celebrate the 50th anniversary of U.S.-Qatar diplomatic relations this year, we look forward to building on our strong foundation with an eye to the next 50 years of partnership between the United States and Qatar.</p>
<p>With that, happy to take your questions on this or anything else.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I think it won’t surprise you that I would like to move to Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Although if someone does have a question about Qatar and Major Non-NATO Ally status, I’m happy to defer. But if not, Ukraine.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-UKRAINERUSSIA"></a> So recognizing that a lot has been said today about Ukraine by President Putin, by Foreign Minister Lavrov, by Secretary Blinken on Twitter, by senior U.S. officials, is there anything new that you can report to us in terms of the diplomacy and what that will look like going forward? You will have seen that Putin said that he was open to continued talks, but there doesn’t seem to be any kind of – at least not yet, there doesn’t seem to be any kind of definite timetable for that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So Matt, as you know, we issued a written readout of the Secretary’s call with Foreign Minister Lavrov earlier today. I won’t go through that, as everyone has it now, but I’ll make a couple other broad points.</p>
<p>The Secretary made clear to Foreign Minister Lavrov, as he has before, that we are prepared to engage in serious diplomacy with the Russian Federation on a reciprocal basis. He also made clear that the non-paper we sent over – our response to the so-called treaties that the Russian Federation published the other week – contain a wide range of serious, substantive proposals. And we believe when you think about the Venn diagram between our security concerns, the collective security concerns of the United States and the transatlantic community, and in the stated security concerns of the Russian Federation, we believe that there is an intersection there where we can address those mutual concerns on a reciprocal basis. Those, of course, include our concerns, the concerns of our allies and partners, but also the stated security concerns of the Russians.</p>
<p>Now, that will require intensive, substantive, serious, sustained diplomacy if we are to get there. We are prepared for that. The Secretary also made the point that this diplomacy, if it is to bear fruit, will need to take place in a context of de-escalation. That is something, of course, that we have yet to see.</p>
<p>We heard from Foreign Minister Lavrov this morning – and I will primarily leave it to the Russians to characterize their response, but that – we heard again that they are working on a formal response to the U.S. non-paper that was sent over the other day. That draft will go to President Putin, as we have known and expected all along. And when President Putin has a chance to review it and approve it, it will be coming to the United States. We understand that once that takes place, the Russians too are willing to engage in continued dialogue. As to what form, as to the timing, that will depend on the receipt of the Russian response to our response.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So you keep talking about this Venn diagram with the overlapping areas, but the thing is is that President Putin said today that you guys have ignored their main requests. And that’s not exactly true; you guys haven’t ignored them, you’ve just flat-out rejected them and told them that they’re non-starters and that you’re not going to – so you’re well aware of what they are, and you’re not ignoring them; you’re just saying no, we’re not going to go there. So I’m just wondering if – do – given that, if you think that there is still an opportunity to resolve this without getting into what the Russians’ main concerns are.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we heard from President Putin a variety of things. I will leave it to the Kremlinologists out there – budding, professional, amateur, or otherwise – to read the tea leaves and try to interpret the significance of those remarks. For our part, we don’t necessarily need to do that because we know that a formal response from the Russian Federation is forthcoming. We heard that again today from Foreign Minister Lavrov.</p>
<p>So we have been clear and consistent since we started this process that there are areas where we believe there is maneuverability, that there is room to engage in substantive discussions, together with our allies and partners, with the Russian Federation on areas where, frankly, we have security concerns; the Russians will put their concerns on the table, and again, in full coordination with our allies and partners, we’ll see if there is room to address those concerns. We believe there is.</p>
<p>Now to your question, the response that we provided to the Russian Federation the other day, it did address the points that had been raised by the Russian Federation. That doesn’t necessarily mean that the Russians will agree with the way in which they were addressed. And I think, as you’ve heard us say all along, it will not come as a surprise to you that there are some areas where we think diplomacy can lead to progress, can redound positively on the security interests of the United States, of the transatlantic community, but also potentially Russia, while other areas are nonstarters. And those areas that we’ve said all along are nonstarters, the idea that a country – any other country can impinge on the security arrangements, the alliances, the partnerships of another country; the inviolability of international borders, sovereignty, territorial integrity. You’re right that there is no trade space, none, when it comes to those issues. That should not – and I assume did not – come as a surprise to the Russian Federation or to anyone else as we described what was in our response, because we’ve been crystal clear about that.</p>
<p>Francesco.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> How do you envision this intensive, substantive, sustained – what am I missing – serious diplomacy we’re talking about? Is this going into rounds of negotiations in Geneva over one, two years with Russia? Is that what you’re envisioning?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t think that that timeframe is what any of us have in mind as an initial matter, at least. What I can say is that for the past several weeks we have been, together with our allies and partners, engaged in diplomacy with the Russian Federation in a variety of venues and fora. We have done this bilaterally through the Strategic Stability Dialogue that Deputy Secretary Sherman engaged in with her Russian counterpart, Mr. Ryabkov, in Geneva the other week. We have done this in the context of the NATO-Russia Council, together with our NATO Allies. We’ve done this in the context of the OSCE with all of the participating member states of the OSCE of course, which – of which Russia is a member. And Secretary Blinken had an opportunity, again bilaterally but outside the formal SSD context, the context of the Strategic Stability Dialogue, to engage with Foreign Minister Lavrov in Geneva the other week.</p>
<p>So we are prepared to continue through all of those venues, through all of those fora. What matters most to us is that our diplomacy, our collective engagement with the Russian Federation, continues to be conducted in full consultation and coordination with our partners and allies. Oftentimes that will take place, we expect, with our allies and partners sitting next to us at the table, as would happen at the NATO-Russia Council, at the OSCE.</p>
<p>If it were to involve another bilateral engagement, which we are open to, we will continue to do that in full consultation and coordination with our allies and partners. Nothing about without. That is not a mantra that we are ever going to abandon or discount in any way. And I think you actually saw that today. After Secretary Blinken had an opportunity to speak with Foreign Minister Lavrov, he then immediately picked up the phone and spoke with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg, OSCE Chairman-in-Office Zbigniew, EU High Representative Josep Borrell. The Secretary thought it was important to engage them immediately on his discussion with Foreign Minister Lavrov. They had an opportunity to discuss that engagement. They also had an opportunity to discuss our approach to the Russian Federation going forward, both in terms of diplomacy and dialogue, which remains our preferred course, but the alternative course that we are continuing to pursue, the course of defense and deterrence.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are you in any way more confident today after hearing from Foreign Minister Lavrov, after hearing President Putin at his press conference, that an aggression against Ukraine can be avoided by diplomacy?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I’d make a couple points. One, this is not about optimism, this is not about pessimism. This is about a clear-eyed approach to what – to us and what to our allies and partners – is a clear threat to international peace and security. So these emotions, these orientations one way or another – to us, it is about the stakes of this, and the stakes for us are very clear.</p>
<p>Number two, again, we are just not going to be in the business of parsing, certainly not publicly, statements we hear from senior Russian officials, because we understand again today that we’ll be in receipt of a formal response that has been approved by President Putin that, presumably, will detail precisely and in specific language where the Russian Federation stands.</p>
<p>Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. Is there – speaking of timeframes, is there a timeframe beyond which if you don’t see any signs of de-escalation there could be a number of steps – there’s pressure from the Senate, in fact, for sanctions before any kind of kinetic action. Could the U.S. – is there some limit to how long you’re going to have 130,000-plus troops and other military equipment, missiles in Belarus?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well &#8212;</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-DEPARTMENT1"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And if I may just say something also on a point of personal privilege, I don’t know what else has been said in this room, but I just want to say that a remark on the passing of a real pioneer, one of your predecessors, Phyllis Oakley, who was just such – I don’t know, such an inspiration to women in this building and to the reporters who cover this building, because of the written and, most importantly, the unwritten rules of gender discrimination in the Foreign Service. And she really persevered and broke through, so she was a great standard bearer.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Among other titles, she was an assistant secretary of state. She was also a deputy spokesperson, spent some time speaking to your predecessors as well. So she is someone who has really left her mark on this institution. You saw that the department issued condolences to her family and to her loved ones and noted the legacy she leaves behind, a legacy that was integral to doing what was long overdue: ensuring that women were fully engaged, able to be fully engaged in this work, and that married women had the same rights as their male counterparts. So we do note her passing and appreciate you raising that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-UKRAINERUSSIA2"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> In terms of the timeframe, our goal here is to forestall, is to prevent, is to deter a Russian – a further Russian invasion of Ukraine. So only the Russian Federation can determine how long this goes on for. We are ready either way. We are ready if the Russians are willing to continue down the path of diplomacy and dialogue in good faith – again, knowing that this is a process that, if it is to be effective, has to take place in the context of de-escalation.</p>
<p>We are equally ready, however, if the Russians determine that they are set on the path of further and renewed aggression. This is a path that we have been walking simultaneously as we have an outstretched hand for diplomacy and dialogue. This is the path we’ve been walking simultaneously with our partners and allies.</p>
<p>We’ve spent some time in recent days speaking to the long track record we have when it comes to this deepening sense of concern that has developed over almost three months now. It was in November, early November if I recall, where we first started talking about this publicly. We started to engage allies and partners late last year as the intelligence and information emerged of the Russian military buildup along the Ukrainian border, as our own concerns grew based on information that was then private and has since been made public.</p>
<p>So this is something we have been at for some time. But again, our goal is to forestall, to deter, to do everything we can to see to it that there is not renewed Russian aggression against Ukraine. But again, our charge is to be prepared with whatever course Vladimir Putin decides.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah, Ned.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>What was the main achievement between (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, it was an opportunity – first, this was a moment that was agreed to by the two individuals in Geneva, coming out of the Secretary’s meeting with Foreign Minister Lavrov in Geneva last month now. It was agreed that the two would have a follow-on conversation in the coming days. It was shortly after that engagement in Geneva where we submitted what we call our non-paper, the written response to the so-called Russian treaties. And that was done.</p>
<p>We – the Russian Federation has now had that document for some time. We understand that they are studying it. We understand that Vladimir Putin has had an opportunity to – at least an opportunity to see it, and we know now that he will have an opportunity to approve the response that comes back from the Russian Federation.</p>
<p>So the point was at least twofold. One, it was to confer on the road ahead. and we did come away with a clearer sense of what we can expect in the coming days or weeks as – however long it takes for the Russians to provide us with their response. We know from there that the Russians appear amenable to continue to engage in dialogue. As we’ve said, we far prefer that course even as we know it needs to take place, if it is to be successful, in the context of de-escalation.</p>
<p>But it was also an opportunity for the Secretary to reiterate the messages that the Russians have heard for some time now: that even as we far prefer the course of diplomacy and dialogue, we are continuing to prepare down the course of defense and deterrence. And so we had an opportunity again today to reinforce the idea of the high cost, the substantial cost, the sudden cost, that would befall the Russian Federation if this aggression were to go forward.</p>
<p>Simon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I wondered now that Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Lavrov have now spoken twice, they’ve exchanged papers, now you’ve said there’s a – the response will go through Putin and then afterwards Blinken and Lavrov will speak again. I wondered is it then time – because there doesn’t seem to be anything changing in terms of both sides’ positions, is it then time for the two presidents to speak again after that response has come? Does it need to escalate to that level?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It really depends on where we are. You’ve heard repeatedly from President Biden, I believe most recently during his press conference last month now, that he and we remain open and amenable to another leader-level engagement between President Biden and President Putin. They’ve had an opportunity to speak on the phone. They have seen each other on screen within recent weeks. If we believe we’re at a moment where another leader-level engagement has the potential to move the ball forward when it comes to this diplomacy, that is certainly something we are open to and amenable to. But it will just depend on where we are after this next step.</p>
<p>Ben.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I hate to say it, but it sounds very much like Groundhog Day. I mean, we’ve been here for a month. You say the same thing; Russia says the same thing. Can you point to any one thing that shows, that suggests Russia is open to real dialogue? Anything? Anything practical that suggests they really want to change their actions?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Ben, that’s not incumbent on us. That’s incumbent on Moscow. So &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So you’ve seen nothing?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, it is true, as you have heard from us, we have not seen concrete, tangible signs of de-escalation. That is what we have continued to convey that we need to see if this dialogue, if this diplomacy, is going to bear fruit.</p>
<p>But to your question, we are not waiting on signs of de-escalation. We are not sitting on our hands calling for de-escalation. And we are moving forward as quickly and resolutely as we can to proceed down this path of defense and deterrence. Again, this is about defensive steps that we are taking as an Alliance, as a NATO Alliance; defensive steps that we are taking to shore up the defenses of our partner Ukraine; steps that we are taking to deter a Russian invasion or renewed Russian aggression against Ukraine. Some of that is consistent with the defensive steps that we’ve taken. Some of that lies in the fact that we’ve been very clear – not only the United States but our European allies and others – about the massive costs – economic, financial, and otherwise – that would befall the Russian Federation if an invasion, renewed aggression, were to go forward.</p>
<p>You have already seen manifestations of those costs even in advance of the imposition of any new sanctions or authorities on the Russian Federation. We’ve talked about this before, but the Russian stock market has declined significantly, the value of the ruble has declined significantly. Market participants are growing increasingly pessimistic about the implications of the sanctions and the economic measures that we’ve talked about were they to go forward. So that, I think, is just a preview of what would – what would transpire were these measures to be fully put into place.</p>
<p>So to recap, that is a question that is best addressed to Moscow. It’s incumbent on Moscow to de-escalate. We are not waiting for de-escalation. We are open and prepared to engage, continue to engage, in diplomacy. But we are also moving ahead swiftly down the path of defense and deterrence.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And just – there was some confusion about the letter was received yesterday. A few senior administration officials appeared to say that was the letter from Russia they were expecting, it was reported – and does that suggest that you don’t know what’s coming in that letter, that it – that well could have been the letter when you first saw it? Why the confusion?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> No, there was never an intention to suggest that was the formal response from the Russian Federation. What one of your colleagues reported and what you heard from senior State Department officials yesterday is that we received a follow-up from the Russian Federation. I will leave it to Foreign Minister Lavrov and the Russians to characterize what exactly they intended by that. But Foreign Minister Lavrov spoke to this missive publicly over the weekend, and we understand again today that we’ll be receiving a formal response from the Russian Federation once it has been approved by President Putin.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just warn you, though, that Ben’s first question – since tomorrow literally is Groundhog Day, you should expect the same question again.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I may have a similar answer. Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> In which case it would just &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It would be &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; in keeping with &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; prove the prophecy true.</p>
<p>Yes, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Marcin Wrona, TVN Discovery from Poland.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Andrea mentioned sanctions, and as diplomacy seems to be going nowhere now, isn’t it high time to start strengthening the eastern flank of NATO? And you mentioned Polish Foreign Minister Zbigniew Rau a moment ago. He is coming here tomorrow, and he will be talking about that. And he’s also meeting with Secretary Blinken later this week, so could you preview those talks with the Secretary, between the minister and the Secretary?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So to your first question, isn’t it time to strengthen the eastern flank of NATO, the answer is unambiguously yes. We have been talking about that for weeks now, and in fact, we have taken concrete steps, some of which have been announced by the Department of Defense, to place thousands of troops, U.S. service members, at a heightened state of readiness, should they be called into service by the North Atlantic Council. We have worked concertedly with our NATO Allies, including our allies on the eastern flank, to work with them to prepare for the eventuality, possibility of further Russian aggression. We will continue to take steps to reassure, to reinforce – defensive steps – NATO’s eastern flank because we agree it is important.</p>
<p>When it comes to the Polish foreign minister, as you noted, as I noted earlier, the Secretary had an opportunity to speak both with him, with the EU High Representative Josep Borrell, and the NATO secretary general today. We will continue to engage with our Polish allies both in the context of the OSCE – and the engagement today was in the foreign minister’s role as the chairman-in-office of the OSCE – but also as a valued and important NATO Ally. I don’t want to get ahead of those discussions, but this gets back to your question. We will continue to show our support in many different forms for our NATO Allies, those on the eastern flank, our NATO Allies throughout the continent.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Now, what you said was putting those troops on heightened alert. What about sending troops now to the eastern flank before the – any aggression that Russia may perpetrate?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I don’t want to speak for the Department of Defense; I don’t want to speak for the White House. But I will tell you that we are taking and are considering a number of steps that will reinforce the message of defense and deterrence. Some of that is with regard to the unprecedented levels of defensive security assistance that we’ve provided to our Ukrainian partners; some of that is in the authorization – the expedited authorization – that we provide to – provided to our NATO Allies, including our Baltic allies, to provide U.S. origin equipment to Ukraine. But again, we are taking steps in the vein of defense and deterrence, working closely with our allies on the eastern flank to reassure and to reinforce their own defenses.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> In terms of NATO and U.S.-European unity, do you find that Viktor Orbán visit to Moscow and press conference with Putin is helpful in any way?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, look, we know that a number of our counterparts around the world have engaged with the Russian Federation, some with Foreign Minister Lavrov, some with President Putin directly. We have consistently said that we support dialogue, we support diplomacy that is conducted, as we have, in full coordination and consultation with the alliance. That has been the North Star of our engagement with the Russians when our allies are not sitting next to us physically at the table – nothing about Europe without Europe, nothing about Ukraine without Ukraine. So any dialogue, any diplomacy that is conducted in a similar vein is something that we would support, especially if it’s something that has the potential to produce tangible signs of de-escalation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Was it the case for the Hungarian prime minister visit?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I will leave it to our Hungarian allies to characterize their engagement with the Russian Federation.</p>
<p>Courtney.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks. Just another follow-up on Andrea’s question earlier, I mean, about the deadline for de-escalation, rather. I mean, you’ve referred to economic and other penalties in the event of further and renewed aggression, but does that mean that the status quo can endure indefinitely as you continue hoping for a diplomatic breakthrough?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t think anyone wants to see the status quo endure indefinitely, and I say that because this massive Russian buildup along the border with Ukraine, the dispatch of troops into what should be sovereign, independent territory of Belarus – all of this heightens tensions. All of this increases the possibility of, whether by accident, whether by miscalculation, whether by the fabrication of a pretext, that this buildup gives way to conflict. That is certainly not something we want to see happen.</p>
<p>So no one is happy about the current situation. No one wants to see this buildup remain as it is for any longer than is necessary. That’s why we’ve continued to call for de-escalation and why we have continued to call for tangible signs of de-escalation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can we move &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Let me move back to the – Peter.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, I wanted to – actually to follow up on that same point, I mean, because all of this seems to put the U.S. in a very kind of reactive position where there’s a risk of State Department priorities being set by Vladimir Putin. Is there a point at which this diplomatic process taking up so much of the Secretary’s time, so much of other senior officials’ time, and ultimately surely detracting from efforts to pivot to Asia or – and focus on competition with China – is there a point at which this just needs to end?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’re a large country. We’re a large department. Not to use once more an overused metaphor, but we can walk and chew gum at the same time. In recent days alone, you’ve seen the President, you’ve seen the Secretary engage with the amir of Qatar. You’re seeing him today with his Cypriot counterpart. You’re seeing us engage on any number of challenges and opportunities in the region.</p>
<p>So it is not the case that even as we are intently focused on a challenge, even something we might call a crisis like this, that it crowds out our ability to focus on the other challenges, the other opportunities that faces the United States.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So there’s no time limit?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, we do not want to see this escalation of tensions last any longer than is necessary. We are calling for immediate de-escalation. That is what we want to see happen.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, were you able to achieve an agreement with Qatar regarding providing Europe with gas in case of (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> This is something, when we talk about the contingency planning that we do – not necessarily in the vein of defense and deterrence, but in the vein of prudent planning – that we have discussed with a number of energy-producing countries around the world. We know that the strength, we know that the severity, we know that the suddenness of the measures that we are prepared to put in place on the Russian Federation could have impacts well beyond Russia, including in terms of energy supplies. And so that’s why we have had regular, frequent, substantive conversations with countries around the world on how we might mitigate some of those impacts, and we believe – we certainly believe we’ll be in a position to do so.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-ISRAELPALESTINIANS"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Going with Israel, Amnesty came out with this report accusing Israel of imposing apartheid on the Palestinians with policies of segregation, dispossession, and exclusion that amount to crimes against humanity. What’s the U.S. Government’s response to that? Do you agree with the conclusions of this report, and do you share those concerns about the situation there in Israel?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, Simon, you know that as a general matter we don’t offer public comprehensive evaluations of reports by outside groups. We have our own rigorous standards and processes for making determinations on potential human rights abuses, for documenting what we see take place around the world, including on an annual basis in the Human Rights Report.</p>
<p>What I will say, however, is that we reject the view that Israel’s actions constitute apartheid. The department’s own reports have never used such terminology. We are committed to promoting respect for human rights in Israel and the West Bank and the Gaza Strip. We have an enduring partnership with Israel, and we discuss a wide range of issues with our Israeli counterparts, including those related to human rights.</p>
<p>We support the efforts of the Israeli Government, of the Palestinian Authority, alongside human rights activists to ensure accountability for human rights violations and abuses. And we continue to emphasize to Israel and to the Palestinian Authority the need to refrain, as you’ve heard us say repeatedly, from unilateral actions that exacerbate tensions. This includes the annexation of territory, settlement activity, demolitions, incitement of violence, and the providing of compensations for individuals imprisoned for acts of terrorism. We take all allegations of human rights abuses seriously – that is true around the world – including allegations of arbitrary detention, and we continue around the world to urge respect for human rights.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> A follow-up on &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you think it comes from a place of anti-Semitism to make those accusations? That’s what Israel’s response to Amnesty has been.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have had an opportunity to speak about this with our Israeli counterparts. They have conveyed their objections to the report. As we’ve noted, we don’t offer our own public comprehensive evaluations of reports, but we certainly reject the label that has been attached to this.</p>
<p>When speaking about Israel – one other point here – we think that it is important as the world’s only Jewish state that the Jewish people must not be denied their right to self-determination, and we must ensure there isn’t a double standard being applied.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, it may be true that you don’t offer public comprehensive evaluations of outside reports, but you certainly cite them quite a bit in your own Human Rights Report. And I went back and looked, and in terms of just the last Human Rights Report cited Amnesty International on Ethiopia, on Cuba, on China and Xinjiang, on Iran, on Burma, on Syria, on Cuba. And that – those references are endorsements of what this group, Amnesty, and then other groups as well that are cited, have found. Why is it that – without taking a stand or making a judgment about the findings of this particular report, why is it that all criticism of Israel is – from these groups is almost always rejected by the U.S., and yet accepted, welcomed, and endorsed when it comes – when it comes out, when the criticism is of other countries, notably countries with which you have significant policy differences?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, I would make a couple points. Number one, when we include a footnote in something like &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> These aren’t footnotes, Ned. These are – these are full-on citations.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> When we cite – when we cite, which it’s a game of semantics, I suppose, but whether you call it a citation or a footnote &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, when it says in the report, Amnesty International found this, X &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; in Xinjiang with the Uyghurs, and we – and we determine that we think that it’s a genocide, and you guys come out and cite that, and say, well, we also agree that it’s a genocide &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> That is a far cry, Matt, from saying – from saying that we have &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m not saying it’s the same thing, but &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; comprehensive agreement with a third-party report that was produced by an outside group.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So it’s just – so it’s just when it’s criticism of Israel that you feel free to disagree? Where have you ever disagreed with an Amnesty report or a Human Rights Report on a country such as Iran or China?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> This is not – Matt, this is not about any outside group. This is about our vehement disagreement with a certain finding in a report by an outside group.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There are plenty of times where we cite, as you said, outside groups in our own reports. We cite the facts that they have uncovered, that they have put forward. But I don’t think you’re going to find any citation in any State Department document – and I don’t think I’ll regret saying this – that says the department agrees on a comprehensive basis with absolutely everything that’s in this report.</p>
<p>Barbara.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is it the department’s view that human rights abuses resulting from occupation are discrete events rather than resulting from discriminatory policies or discriminatory systems that are backed up by law?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Barbara, we document this comprehensively in our own Human Rights Reports. And we document allegations of and what we have found in terms of Israel, and the West Bank, and the Gaza Strip comprehensively on an annual basis. So I will leave it to that document to speak to our framework for this. I think you have heard us on a number of occasions when we have heard reports of or been in position to corroborate human rights abuses in this region that we have not hesitated to speak out.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I got two really brief ones on Israel (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> One is you may have seen that the Israeli military today said it was censuring or reprimanding a couple – several soldiers for their role in the death of – or leading to the death of a Palestinian American. Is – I’ve been asking for a couple days now about whether you’re satisfied with your request for clarification for – does this do it? Have you gotten from – have you gotten this information from the Israelis, and are you satisfied with the response?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I expect you’ll – we’ll have a little bit more to say on this later today, but let me say that we continue, as I said yesterday and last week, to be concerned by the circumstances of the death of Mr. Omar Assad. He, of course, was a U.S. citizen who was found dead on January 12th after Israeli soldiers detained him in the West Bank.</p>
<p>We do note the public statement on the report of the IDF, the Israeli Defense Forces, commanders’ investigation into the case and its findings, including the determination that, quote, “the incident showed a clear lapse of moral judgment,” and a failure to, quote, “protect the sanctity of any human life.” The IDF public summary of the investigation further states that the disciplinary action is being taken against the commander of the Netzah Yehuda Battalion and other officers responsible for the unit involved in the incident, and that the military police criminal investigation division investigation of the case is ongoing. We expect a thorough criminal investigation and full accountability in this case, and we welcome receiving additional information on these efforts as soon as possible. We continue to discuss this troubling incident with the Israeli Government.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. So this – what the IDF announced today is not satisfactory in and of itself; you want a criminal investigation?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have – we are continuing to discuss this. These are public statements that have come from the IDF. Again, we know that the investigation itself is ongoing, so it’s something I expect we’ll continue to discuss with our Israeli counterparts.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All right. And then one other one, and this is really brief, and it’s kind of minor, but it has attracted some attention, and that is yesterday after his conversation with Foreign Minister Lapid, it was – the Secretary’s conversation with – that Secretary – was it yesterday or maybe it was the day before?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It was yesterday.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But anyway, he tweeted something, and identified Foreign Minister Lapid as “Alternate Prime Minister,” which is something that he’s – in the tweet, right. And he’s never called him that before. So I’m just – is there a reason for that, instead of calling him &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> My understanding is that his – that’s his formal title.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, his title is also foreign minister.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, so you’ve just decided to use his formal title starting yesterday? I don’t know.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There has been no change &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; in how we view Mr. Lapid. He is the alternate prime minister and foreign minister.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Gotcha.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-CUBA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, on Cuba, any comment on the recent mass trials of Cubans that participated in the protests for political reform last year? Almost 800 people has been charged with more than 170 already convicted, some of them facing jails or prisons. Is there a space for new sanctions? Can we expect, like, a response for the U.S. Government, as you have praised the demonstrators last year?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, it is true that ever since the protests that began on July 11th of last year, we have seen the Cuban Government respond with their trademark brand of repression of their own citizens. We believe – and you’ve heard from us – that the Cuban people, just like people around the world, have every right to continue to voice their desire for fundamental freedoms, and we condemn the failures of the Cuban Government to protect those universal rights and the failure of the Cuban Government to meet the most basic needs of the people. Again, rather than focusing on its own provision of services, its own governance, the protection of rights within Cuban society, the Cuban regime has responded with repression. And it was just last month that the so-called <em>Damas de Blanco</em> were imprisoned for doing nothing more than exercising what should be a universal right.</p>
<p>We support the rights of Cubans and people everywhere to exercise their freedom of expression and peaceful assembly. We call on the Cuban Government to respect these rights and to release those unjustly detained for peacefully protesting. No one should face prosecution, no one should face imprisonment, for exercising a right that is as universal in Cuba as it would be anywhere else.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But is the U.S. Government think about new sanction, or is there a space for new sanction, given the big scope of they are already in place – that are already in place?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, ever since July 11th of last year, we have enacted a series of measures to promote accountability against those individuals and entities within the Cuban Government who are responsible for this repression, who are responsible for the violent crackdowns on peaceful protesters last summer and in the ensuing weeks. So we will continue to look to ways to promote accountability and to uphold and protect and promote what should be the universal rights of the Cuban people.</p>
<p>Yes, Ben.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-DEPARTMENT"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yesterday <em>The New York Times</em> sued the State Department over some Freedom of Information requests that the State Department hasn’t been responding to. These are in relation to Romanian embassy emails sent between 2015 and 2019 that mention a number of international businesspeople, including the President’s son, Hunter Biden. Do you have any comment on that? Why is it taking so long to release these emails?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have a comment on pending litigation. As you know, Ben, when it comes to FOIA requests, we process these as expeditiously as we can. We are committed to and we always do follow the law when it comes to that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But administration – the family members of administration officials should not be able to reach out to the State Department for their own personal business dealings, correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Ben, I don’t know to what you’re referring specifically. We &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The content of these emails suggests that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You have heard from Secretary Blinken that this department is committed to exercising and wielding the highest standards of conduct in office. The only thing that undergirds our decisions and decision making is the national interest.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-INDIARUSSIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Two questions. Yesterday at the UN Security Council, India abstained from the vote on whether to pursue the discussion. Russian officials have thanked India for this abstention. Were you disappointed?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, I think what we saw in the Security Council yesterday were countries from around the world voicing their concern with this Russian military buildup that has needlessly provoked a crisis, an international crisis, an international threat to peace and security, the very reason the UN Security Council took this matter up in the first place. And you heard from a variety of countries that the international community is firmly behind a – the path of diplomacy and dialogue. That’s what we heard coming out loud and clear of the UN session yesterday.</p>
<p>Sure.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-BURKINAFASO"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Two brief asks and then I’ll just – one, have you guys yet decided whether or not what happened in Burkina Faso was a coup? And the reason I’m asking this again today is because the Millennium Challenge Corporation says that it has suspended – it’s more than 400 million, but it might be 450 million – but anyway, they’ve suspended a big chunk of their program to Burkina Faso. So has the State Department made a determination on this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So we are evaluating the impact of what we’ve seen transpire in Burkina Faso in recent days on our engagement with the country. It’s too soon for us to get into specifics in great detail, but we’ve called for restraint by all actors as we carefully review the events on the ground for potential impact on our assistance. What I can say now is that we have paused most assistance for the Government of Burkina Faso as we continue to monitor the situation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, can you be a little bit more specific about that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I can’t.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> When you say “most,” what does that mean?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Most means most. It means the majority. I can come up with other synonyms, but no, I just – I’m not in a position now to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m not looking for a synonym for “most.” I’m looking for like a number, and what exactly is it? I mean, is it FMF? Is it &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m just not in a position to – I’m not in a position to do that today, but we’re continuing to evaluate what’s transpired and the appropriate impact on our assistance to the government.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All right. Well, so, do you have less high standards or stringent standards than the Millennium Challenge Corporation does?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have our own standards, and we have a standard &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Your standard is set by law, actually, so it’s not really your standard; it’s Congress’s standard, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It is – you are not incorrect, but yes, it is a standard that we hew to.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And so that standard has not yet been met.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, it is a standard against which we are evaluating what has transpired. So when we’re in – if we are in a position to offer an evaluation against the standard, we will let you know.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-GUINEABISSAU"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All right. And then do you know – you’ve seen, probably, reports about what’s happening in Guinea-Bissau.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you have anything to say about &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’re monitoring those reports closely. They just began to emerge several hours ago, so we are continuing to watch closely.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-310797-MALI"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> To remain in the region, what do you make of the huge differences appearing every day between Mali, the government – the junta in Mali and France and Europe? And do you fear this could be a real blow to the counterterrorism operations in the region, in the Sahel?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, as you know, our French allies are indispensable partners in the counterterrorism effort, whether it is in the region or beyond, but certainly in the region. When it comes to what we have seen transpire between the Government of Mali and our French allies, I would refer to them for any comment.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:57 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Representative for the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea Kim’s Calls with Republic of Korea Special Representative Noh and Japan Director General Funakoshi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-representative-for-the-democratic-peoples-republic-of-korea-kims-calls-with-republic-of-korea-special-representative-noh-and-japan-director-general-funakoshi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 22:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=310785</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>On January 29 and 30, Special Representative for the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK) Sung Kim held calls with Japanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs Director General for Asian and Oceanian Affairs Bureau Funakoshi Takehiro and ROK Special Representative for Korean Peninsula Peace and Security Affairs Noh Kyu-duk.</p>
<p>In the calls, Special Representative Kim discussed with Director General Funakoshi and Special Representative Noh the DPRK’s January 29 ballistic missile launch.  Special Representative Kim condemned the DPRK’s ballistic missile launches as violations of UN Security Council resolutions and destabilizing to the region. Special Representative Kim also reaffirmed the U.S. commitment to the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and our ironclad commitment to the defense of the ROK and Japan.</p>
<p>Special Representative Kim underscored the United States’ continued readiness to engage in serious and sustained diplomacy with the DPRK in order to make tangible progress and reiterated our commitment to continued close coordination with our ROK and Japanese allies.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>On January 29 and 30, Special Representative for the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK) Sung Kim held calls with Japanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs Director General for Asian and Oceanian Affairs Bureau Funakoshi Takehiro and ROK Special Representative for Korean Peninsula Peace and Security Affairs Noh Kyu-duk.</p>
<p>In the calls, Special Representative Kim discussed with Director General Funakoshi and Special Representative Noh the DPRK’s January 29 ballistic missile launch.  Special Representative Kim condemned the DPRK’s ballistic missile launches as violations of UN Security Council resolutions and destabilizing to the region. Special Representative Kim also reaffirmed the U.S. commitment to the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and our ironclad commitment to the defense of the ROK and Japan.</p>
<p>Special Representative Kim underscored the United States’ continued readiness to engage in serious and sustained diplomacy with the DPRK in order to make tangible progress and reiterated our commitment to continued close coordination with our ROK and Japanese allies.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Republic of Cyprus Foreign Minister Ioannis Kasoulides Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-republic-of-cyprus-foreign-minister-ioannis-kasoulides-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Ioannis Kasoulides, Republic of Cyprus Foreign Minister]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 20:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=310702</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Ioannis Kasoulides, Republic of Cyprus Foreign Minister</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a great pleasure to welcome Foreign Minister Kasoulides here to the State Department – familiar territory.  The foreign minister is just recently on the job, but for the third time.  I can’t even begin to imagine (inaudible).  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>But we’re so, so pleased to have you and especially so pleased by the relationship between the United States and Cyprus.  I think the bilateral relationship is stronger than it’s ever been.  We’re seeing cooperation in a whole variety of areas, to include security but also to include science and technology.  It really runs the gamut.  We remain resolutely in support of a bi-zonal, bi-communal federation, and we will continue to work in that direction.  And I have to say we were pleased by the renewal of the mandate at the United Nations just a week ago.</p>
<p>But we have a lot to talk about, and I think it’s really a reflection of the fact that on so many different levels this relationship has gotten broader but also deeper.  And it’s wonderful to have you here, Mr. Minister.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER KASOULIDES:</b>  Thank you,  Mr. Secretary.  And it is my intention to use this meeting to find and explore areas – to find and explore areas where we can make the relationship even stronger and even deeper.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I welcome that.  Thank you.  Thank you, everyone.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Ioannis Kasoulides, Republic of Cyprus Foreign Minister</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a great pleasure to welcome Foreign Minister Kasoulides here to the State Department – familiar territory.  The foreign minister is just recently on the job, but for the third time.  I can’t even begin to imagine (inaudible).  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>But we’re so, so pleased to have you and especially so pleased by the relationship between the United States and Cyprus.  I think the bilateral relationship is stronger than it’s ever been.  We’re seeing cooperation in a whole variety of areas, to include security but also to include science and technology.  It really runs the gamut.  We remain resolutely in support of a bi-zonal, bi-communal federation, and we will continue to work in that direction.  And I have to say we were pleased by the renewal of the mandate at the United Nations just a week ago.</p>
<p>But we have a lot to talk about, and I think it’s really a reflection of the fact that on so many different levels this relationship has gotten broader but also deeper.  And it’s wonderful to have you here, Mr. Minister.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER KASOULIDES:</b>  Thank you,  Mr. Secretary.  And it is my intention to use this meeting to find and explore areas – to find and explore areas where we can make the relationship even stronger and even deeper.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I welcome that.  Thank you.  Thank you, everyone.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Republic of Cyprus Foreign Minister Kasoulides</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-republic-of-cyprus-foreign-minister-kasoulides/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 20:25:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=310699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Republic of Cyprus Foreign Minister Ioannis Kasoulides today in Washington, D.C.  Secretary Blinken congratulated Foreign Minister Kasoulides on his return to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and reiterated the U.S. commitment to deepening cooperation with the Republic of Cyprus, including through the 3+1 mechanism with Greece and Israel.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed a range of bilateral and regional issues, including the importance of coordinating actions in support of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.  They also underscored the importance of increasing scientific collaboration on issues such as climate change and emerging technology through the upcoming signing of a bilateral Science and Technology Agreement.</p>
<p>The Secretary expressed continued U.S. support to Cypriot-led, UN-facilitated efforts to reunify the island as a bizonal, bicommunal federation with political equality to benefit all Cypriots.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Republic of Cyprus Foreign Minister Ioannis Kasoulides today in Washington, D.C.  Secretary Blinken congratulated Foreign Minister Kasoulides on his return to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and reiterated the U.S. commitment to deepening cooperation with the Republic of Cyprus, including through the 3+1 mechanism with Greece and Israel.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed a range of bilateral and regional issues, including the importance of coordinating actions in support of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.  They also underscored the importance of increasing scientific collaboration on issues such as climate change and emerging technology through the upcoming signing of a bilateral Science and Technology Agreement.</p>
<p>The Secretary expressed continued U.S. support to Cypriot-led, UN-facilitated efforts to reunify the island as a bizonal, bicommunal federation with political equality to benefit all Cypriots.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
