<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 20:08:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom Rashad Hussain on the 2021 Report on International Religious Freedom</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-ambassador-at-large-for-international-religious-freedom-rashad-hussain-on-the-2021-report-on-international-religious-freedom/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom Rashad Hussain]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 20:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=349216</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom Rashad Hussain</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room</p>
<p><center></center></p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Good morning, everyone. Today, the State Department is releasing the 2021 International Religious Freedom Report. This report offers a thorough, fact-based review of the state of religious freedom in nearly 200 countries and territories around the world. We produce this document every year since 1998, starting under the leadership of then Secretary Albright, whose life and legacy we continue to celebrate.</p>
<p>Back then, the Office of International Religious Freedom, which leads this annual process of drafting the report, was the only government entity in the world charged with monitoring and defending international religious freedom. Now, more than two decades later, we have more than 35 governments and multilateral organizations that have created offices that are dedicated to this goal.</p>
<p>And I’d like to thank the office for its efforts again this year under the leadership of Ambassador Rashad Hussain. This team has done remarkable work, and I very much appreciate the efforts.</p>
<p>I also want to thank the hundreds of State Department officials around the world who gather information, conduct the fact-finding that’s actually at the heart of this report. And all of us – all of us – are indebted to civil society, faith leaders, religious organizations, human rights groups, journalists, and others who share their perspectives and analysis, and who do the critical work of promoting religious freedom every day in every part of the world.</p>
<p>When Secretary Albright first introduced this report, she noted that from our earliest days, Americans had believed, and I quote, “that nations are stronger, and the lives of their people richer, when citizens have the freedom to choose, proclaim, and exercise their religious identity.”</p>
<p>Indeed, religious freedom is the first freedom enshrined in our Constitution’s Bill of Rights. It’s been recognized by nations around the world as a human right, including in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</p>
<p>Respect for religious freedom isn’t only one of the deepest held values and a fundamental right. It’s also, from my perspective, a vital foreign policy priority. Here’s why. We know that when the fundamental right of each person to practice their faith or to choose not to observe a faith is respected, people can make their fullest contributions to their community’s successes; entire societies are better off.</p>
<p>On the other hand, when governments deny this right, it ignites tension, it sows division, it often leads to instability and conflict.</p>
<p>This year’s report includes several countries where we see notable progress, thanks to the work of governments, civil society organizations, and citizens. For example, last year the Kingdom of Morocco launched an initiative to renovate Jewish heritage sites like synagogues and cemeteries, and to include Jewish history in the Moroccan public school curriculum.</p>
<p>In Taiwan, authorities are making it easier to report employers who refuse to give their workers a weekly rest day in order to attend religious services.</p>
<p>In Timor-Leste, the new president, Ramos-Horta, recently pledged to defend the rights of all citizens regardless of religious background.</p>
<p>And in Iraq, national leaders welcomed Pope Francis for the first ever papal visit to the country, where he conducted Christian and interfaith ceremonies in Baghdad, in Mosul, and in the Iraqi Kurdish region.</p>
<p>One local leader from the city of Nasiriyah, Sheikh Haider al-Dubaisi, later reflected on the Pope’s visit, and he said, and I quote, “He came even though he could barely walk. He sent a message not only to Iraqis, but to the whole world, that Islam and other religions can sit together peacefully.”</p>
<p>Sitting together peacefully. Ultimately, this report is about spreading that kind of progress to more parts of the world.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, the report also shows that we have more work to do. In many parts of the world, governments are failing to respect their citizens’ basic rights. Some governments continue to use blasphemy and apostacy laws, which banned defamation and renunciation of religion, to police the language of religious minorities. Others curtail expressions of religious belief like restrictions on religious attire.</p>
<p>And all societies, including our own and across Europe, must do more to combat rising forms of hate, including anti-Semitism and anti-Muslim sentiment.</p>
<p>To highlight a few examples, in March, based on extensive legal review of the evidence, I made the determination that Burma’s military committed genocide and crimes against humanity with the intent to destroy predominantly Muslim Rohingya in 2017 – intent that was evidenced by, among other things, attacks on mosques, the use of religious and ethnic slurs, the desecration of Korans, among, again, many other actions.</p>
<p>In Eritrea, only four religious groups are permitted to practice their faith freely, while members of other religious minority groups have been detained, arrested, forced to renounce their faith as a precondition for their release.</p>
<p>In Saudi Arabia, we recognize the important recent moves to increase interfaith dialogue and religious tolerance. However, publicly practicing any faith other than Islam remains illegal, and the government continues to discriminate against members of religious minority communities.</p>
<p>China continues its genocide and repression of predominately Muslim Uyghurs and other religious minority groups. Since April 2017, more than 1 million Uyghurs, ethnic Kazakhs, Kyrgyz and others have been detained in internment camps in Xinjiang. The PRC continues to harass adherents of other religions that it deems out of line with Chinese Community Party doctrine, including by destroying Buddhist, Christian, Islamic, and Taoist houses of worship and by erecting barriers to employment and housing for Christians, Muslims, Tibetan Buddhists, and Falun Gong practitioners.</p>
<p>In Afghanistan, conditions for religious freedom have deteriorated dramatically under the Taliban, particularly as they crack down on the basic rights of women and girls to get an education, to work, to engage in society, often under the banner of religion. Meanwhile, ISIS-K is conducting increasingly violent attacks against religious minorities, particularly Shia Hazaras.</p>
<p>In Pakistan, at least 16 individuals accused of blasphemy were sentenced to death by Pakistani courts in 2021, though none of these sentences has yet to be carried out.</p>
<p>Beyond these countries, the report documents how religious freedom and the rights of religious minorities are under threat in communities around the world.</p>
<p>For example, in India, the world’s largest democracy and home to a great diversity of faiths, we’ve seen rising attacks on people and places of worship; in Vietnam, where authorities harass members of unregistered religious communities; in Nigeria, where several state governments are using antidefamation and blasphemy laws to punish people for expressing their beliefs.</p>
<p>The United States will continue to stand up for religious freedom around the world. We’ll keep working alongside other governments, multilateral organizations, civil society to do so, including next month at the United Kingdom’s Ministerial to Advance Religious Freedom.</p>
<p>At its core, our work is about ensuring that all people have the freedom to pursue the spiritual tradition that most adds meaning to their time on Earth. It’s about giving people the chance to express themselves freely, which is part of being their fullest selves. That’s the progress. That’s the progress that this report hopes to help create.</p>
<p>So once again, I’d like to thank everybody whose hard work made this report possible. And with that, I want to turn the floor over to the person who’s maybe worked the hardest, Ambassador Hussain, to highlight a few themes from this year’s report. Rashad, over to you. (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>AMBASSADOR HUSSAIN:</strong> Thank you so much, Mr. Secretary. I’d like to thank President Biden, Vice President Harris, Secretary Blinken for leading United States global efforts to defend and advance human rights, including international religious freedom for all people everywhere. And I’m grateful to our colleagues in governments and to thousands of civil society partners in the United States and around the globe, partners from all political and faith backgrounds, who were instrumental in developing the report.</p>
<p>Religious freedom is a critical part of the American story. Our nation was founded centuries around by individuals fleeing religious persecution. It is natural then that freedom of religion was enshrined in America’s founding documents, including in the First Amendment to our Constitution in our Bill of Rights. Freedom of religion is also a universal right enshrined in several international instruments and covenants, including in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</p>
<p>Earlier today, we transmitted this year’s 2000-plus page Report on International Religious Freedom to Congress. And I’d like to thank Bob Boehme, his editing team, and our colleagues at embassies and posts around the world for their tireless work in collecting the information that’s in this year’s report.</p>
<p>The report gives voice to countless individuals around the world who have been killed, beaten, threatened, harassed, or jailed for seeking to exercise their beliefs in accordance with the dictates of their conscience. The United States will continue to stand for those who are oppressed all over the world.</p>
<p>On the pages of this year’s report are stories of individuals who have endured unspeakable persecution, governments that have sought to restrict religious belief, practice, and expression for people across a wide range of belief traditions. Non-state actors have targeted religious groups, attacked places of worship, and vilified religious, ethnic, and racial groups in their hateful narratives, including on social media platforms. From Jehovah’s Witnesses in Russia; Jews in Europe; Baha’is in Iran; Christians in North Korea, Nigeria, and Saudi Arabia; Muslims in Burma and China; Catholics in Nicaragua; and atheists and humanists around the world, no community has been immune from these abuses.</p>
<p>I’d like to lay out three key themes in the report.</p>
<p>First, too many governments use discriminatory laws and policies and abuse their own people. We have seen two genocides of religious minority communities in recent years – in China and in Burma.</p>
<p>Second, rising societal intolerance and hatred are fueling violence and conflict around the world. Governments must not sit silent or stand idly by in the face of such oppression.</p>
<p>Third, powerful collaboration among civil society, governments, and multilateral partners has led to some progress and provides hope in addressing these complex challenges.</p>
<p>To provide concrete examples of how these themes are playing out around the world: first, far too many governments remain undeterred in the repression of their citizens. It comes as no surprise that the People’s Republic of China is a glaring example here. The PRC Government continue to commit genocide and crimes against humanity against Uyghurs who are predominantly Muslim and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups. The PRC uses sophisticated emerging technologies such as AI and facial recognition to surveil and maintain control of its open-air prison in Xinjiang. Behind all the evidence and data, the many reports of deaths in custody, torture, and physical abuse, there are thousands of Uyghur family members – daughters and sons are desperate to know where their parents are, but are terrified of what news they could discover and are wondering whether they will ever be safely reunited.</p>
<p>The PRC Government also continued its crackdown on Tibetan Buddhists. Authorities arrested, tortured, and committed other abuses against Tibetans who promoted their language and culture, possessed pictures and writings of the Dalai Lama, or practiced their religion at Buddhist monasteries. Secretary Blinken recently determined that the Burmese military committed genocide and crimes against humanity against Rohingya. Throughout Burma, already vulnerable communities, including civil society leaders and members of religious and ethnic minority groups, continue to face heightened risk of atrocities and other abuses.</p>
<p>Following its designation as a Country of Particular Concern for the first time last year, Russia has doubled down on its violations of religious freedom rather than reverse course. Russian courts regularly reach new milestones for excessive prison sentences against individuals exercising their religious freedom, and Russian authorities carry out hundreds of home raids against suspected extremists that frequently include violence. President Putin sought to justify the unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine through the blatantly false pretext of de-Nazification. The world clearly sees through this lie and is instead witnessing Russia’s brutal suppression, including suppression of religious leaders and the appalling destruction of religious sites.</p>
<p>Religious Freedom conditions in Afghanistan have deteriorated since the Taliban seized control. The Taliban regime and rival militant group ISIS-K have detained, intimidated, threatened, and attacked members of religious minority communities. And as the Secretary stated, in India some officials are ignoring or even supporting rising attacks on people and places of worship.</p>
<p>To elaborate further on the report’s second theme, there are a number of ways that rising societal intolerance and hatred are fueling violence and conflict around the world. Governments must speak out and protect the vulnerable and marginalized. Anti-Semitism, anti-Muslim hatred, and xenophobia are on the rise in many countries. Democratic backsliding and the rise of nationalism and nativist rhetoric and policies have been used to justify violence towards members of ethnic or religious minority groups and historically marginalized peoples. Social media platforms are used to spread hate speech and to incite violence by vilifying and threatening members of religious minorities.</p>
<p>And finally, I’d like to say a little bit more about the report’s third theme, how collaboration between civil society and government has created some progress. While this report paints a challenging picture of the state of religious freedom around the world, we remain hopeful about the future. Civil society groups and countries all over the world are essential to this report and to our work. Their advocacy changes laws, it lifts up the names of prisoners, provides lawyers to fight against spurious charges, and pushes governments including our own to do the right thing. I’ve had the opportunity to work with civil society on powerful initiatives, such as the Marrakesh Declaration, which affirms the rights of Christians and other religious minorities in Muslim-majority countries, and the Istanbul Process, which rejects criminalization of blasphemy.</p>
<p>Independent and strong civil societies help governments solve problems and better serve their people by shining a light on the issues that matter most. Where civil society thrives, governments operate with more transparency and accountability, creating a tangible impact on the lives of everyday citizens. We must listen to and empower the voices of civil society, including those who dissent from majority views or criticize the government, as we work towards a more just and peaceful future for us all. Change is only possible with the hard work of the groups and individuals dedicated to fighting for these rights. Today, more than ever, we have tools at our disposal to facilitate the flow of information to keep individuals informed. We have mechanisms to shed light on abuses taking place, and we have the means to hold bad actors accountable.</p>
<p>We have more partners in this effort now than ever before, including religious leaders. And religion can be such a powerful force for good, and it should never be used to harm people. Our greatest hope is that together we can unite our efforts to ensure respect for freedom of religion or belief for all people around the globe, and we continue to stand in solidarity with all people seeking to exercise their beliefs.</p>
<p>Thank you. (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Thank you all. Appreciate the good work. (Applause.)</p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom Rashad Hussain</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room</p>
<p><center></center></p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Good morning, everyone. Today, the State Department is releasing the 2021 International Religious Freedom Report. This report offers a thorough, fact-based review of the state of religious freedom in nearly 200 countries and territories around the world. We produce this document every year since 1998, starting under the leadership of then Secretary Albright, whose life and legacy we continue to celebrate.</p>
<p>Back then, the Office of International Religious Freedom, which leads this annual process of drafting the report, was the only government entity in the world charged with monitoring and defending international religious freedom. Now, more than two decades later, we have more than 35 governments and multilateral organizations that have created offices that are dedicated to this goal.</p>
<p>And I’d like to thank the office for its efforts again this year under the leadership of Ambassador Rashad Hussain. This team has done remarkable work, and I very much appreciate the efforts.</p>
<p>I also want to thank the hundreds of State Department officials around the world who gather information, conduct the fact-finding that’s actually at the heart of this report. And all of us – all of us – are indebted to civil society, faith leaders, religious organizations, human rights groups, journalists, and others who share their perspectives and analysis, and who do the critical work of promoting religious freedom every day in every part of the world.</p>
<p>When Secretary Albright first introduced this report, she noted that from our earliest days, Americans had believed, and I quote, “that nations are stronger, and the lives of their people richer, when citizens have the freedom to choose, proclaim, and exercise their religious identity.”</p>
<p>Indeed, religious freedom is the first freedom enshrined in our Constitution’s Bill of Rights. It’s been recognized by nations around the world as a human right, including in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</p>
<p>Respect for religious freedom isn’t only one of the deepest held values and a fundamental right. It’s also, from my perspective, a vital foreign policy priority. Here’s why. We know that when the fundamental right of each person to practice their faith or to choose not to observe a faith is respected, people can make their fullest contributions to their community’s successes; entire societies are better off.</p>
<p>On the other hand, when governments deny this right, it ignites tension, it sows division, it often leads to instability and conflict.</p>
<p>This year’s report includes several countries where we see notable progress, thanks to the work of governments, civil society organizations, and citizens. For example, last year the Kingdom of Morocco launched an initiative to renovate Jewish heritage sites like synagogues and cemeteries, and to include Jewish history in the Moroccan public school curriculum.</p>
<p>In Taiwan, authorities are making it easier to report employers who refuse to give their workers a weekly rest day in order to attend religious services.</p>
<p>In Timor-Leste, the new president, Ramos-Horta, recently pledged to defend the rights of all citizens regardless of religious background.</p>
<p>And in Iraq, national leaders welcomed Pope Francis for the first ever papal visit to the country, where he conducted Christian and interfaith ceremonies in Baghdad, in Mosul, and in the Iraqi Kurdish region.</p>
<p>One local leader from the city of Nasiriyah, Sheikh Haider al-Dubaisi, later reflected on the Pope’s visit, and he said, and I quote, “He came even though he could barely walk. He sent a message not only to Iraqis, but to the whole world, that Islam and other religions can sit together peacefully.”</p>
<p>Sitting together peacefully. Ultimately, this report is about spreading that kind of progress to more parts of the world.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, the report also shows that we have more work to do. In many parts of the world, governments are failing to respect their citizens’ basic rights. Some governments continue to use blasphemy and apostacy laws, which banned defamation and renunciation of religion, to police the language of religious minorities. Others curtail expressions of religious belief like restrictions on religious attire.</p>
<p>And all societies, including our own and across Europe, must do more to combat rising forms of hate, including anti-Semitism and anti-Muslim sentiment.</p>
<p>To highlight a few examples, in March, based on extensive legal review of the evidence, I made the determination that Burma’s military committed genocide and crimes against humanity with the intent to destroy predominantly Muslim Rohingya in 2017 – intent that was evidenced by, among other things, attacks on mosques, the use of religious and ethnic slurs, the desecration of Korans, among, again, many other actions.</p>
<p>In Eritrea, only four religious groups are permitted to practice their faith freely, while members of other religious minority groups have been detained, arrested, forced to renounce their faith as a precondition for their release.</p>
<p>In Saudi Arabia, we recognize the important recent moves to increase interfaith dialogue and religious tolerance. However, publicly practicing any faith other than Islam remains illegal, and the government continues to discriminate against members of religious minority communities.</p>
<p>China continues its genocide and repression of predominately Muslim Uyghurs and other religious minority groups. Since April 2017, more than 1 million Uyghurs, ethnic Kazakhs, Kyrgyz and others have been detained in internment camps in Xinjiang. The PRC continues to harass adherents of other religions that it deems out of line with Chinese Community Party doctrine, including by destroying Buddhist, Christian, Islamic, and Taoist houses of worship and by erecting barriers to employment and housing for Christians, Muslims, Tibetan Buddhists, and Falun Gong practitioners.</p>
<p>In Afghanistan, conditions for religious freedom have deteriorated dramatically under the Taliban, particularly as they crack down on the basic rights of women and girls to get an education, to work, to engage in society, often under the banner of religion. Meanwhile, ISIS-K is conducting increasingly violent attacks against religious minorities, particularly Shia Hazaras.</p>
<p>In Pakistan, at least 16 individuals accused of blasphemy were sentenced to death by Pakistani courts in 2021, though none of these sentences has yet to be carried out.</p>
<p>Beyond these countries, the report documents how religious freedom and the rights of religious minorities are under threat in communities around the world.</p>
<p>For example, in India, the world’s largest democracy and home to a great diversity of faiths, we’ve seen rising attacks on people and places of worship; in Vietnam, where authorities harass members of unregistered religious communities; in Nigeria, where several state governments are using antidefamation and blasphemy laws to punish people for expressing their beliefs.</p>
<p>The United States will continue to stand up for religious freedom around the world. We’ll keep working alongside other governments, multilateral organizations, civil society to do so, including next month at the United Kingdom’s Ministerial to Advance Religious Freedom.</p>
<p>At its core, our work is about ensuring that all people have the freedom to pursue the spiritual tradition that most adds meaning to their time on Earth. It’s about giving people the chance to express themselves freely, which is part of being their fullest selves. That’s the progress. That’s the progress that this report hopes to help create.</p>
<p>So once again, I’d like to thank everybody whose hard work made this report possible. And with that, I want to turn the floor over to the person who’s maybe worked the hardest, Ambassador Hussain, to highlight a few themes from this year’s report. Rashad, over to you. (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>AMBASSADOR HUSSAIN:</strong> Thank you so much, Mr. Secretary. I’d like to thank President Biden, Vice President Harris, Secretary Blinken for leading United States global efforts to defend and advance human rights, including international religious freedom for all people everywhere. And I’m grateful to our colleagues in governments and to thousands of civil society partners in the United States and around the globe, partners from all political and faith backgrounds, who were instrumental in developing the report.</p>
<p>Religious freedom is a critical part of the American story. Our nation was founded centuries around by individuals fleeing religious persecution. It is natural then that freedom of religion was enshrined in America’s founding documents, including in the First Amendment to our Constitution in our Bill of Rights. Freedom of religion is also a universal right enshrined in several international instruments and covenants, including in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</p>
<p>Earlier today, we transmitted this year’s 2000-plus page Report on International Religious Freedom to Congress. And I’d like to thank Bob Boehme, his editing team, and our colleagues at embassies and posts around the world for their tireless work in collecting the information that’s in this year’s report.</p>
<p>The report gives voice to countless individuals around the world who have been killed, beaten, threatened, harassed, or jailed for seeking to exercise their beliefs in accordance with the dictates of their conscience. The United States will continue to stand for those who are oppressed all over the world.</p>
<p>On the pages of this year’s report are stories of individuals who have endured unspeakable persecution, governments that have sought to restrict religious belief, practice, and expression for people across a wide range of belief traditions. Non-state actors have targeted religious groups, attacked places of worship, and vilified religious, ethnic, and racial groups in their hateful narratives, including on social media platforms. From Jehovah’s Witnesses in Russia; Jews in Europe; Baha’is in Iran; Christians in North Korea, Nigeria, and Saudi Arabia; Muslims in Burma and China; Catholics in Nicaragua; and atheists and humanists around the world, no community has been immune from these abuses.</p>
<p>I’d like to lay out three key themes in the report.</p>
<p>First, too many governments use discriminatory laws and policies and abuse their own people. We have seen two genocides of religious minority communities in recent years – in China and in Burma.</p>
<p>Second, rising societal intolerance and hatred are fueling violence and conflict around the world. Governments must not sit silent or stand idly by in the face of such oppression.</p>
<p>Third, powerful collaboration among civil society, governments, and multilateral partners has led to some progress and provides hope in addressing these complex challenges.</p>
<p>To provide concrete examples of how these themes are playing out around the world: first, far too many governments remain undeterred in the repression of their citizens. It comes as no surprise that the People’s Republic of China is a glaring example here. The PRC Government continue to commit genocide and crimes against humanity against Uyghurs who are predominantly Muslim and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups. The PRC uses sophisticated emerging technologies such as AI and facial recognition to surveil and maintain control of its open-air prison in Xinjiang. Behind all the evidence and data, the many reports of deaths in custody, torture, and physical abuse, there are thousands of Uyghur family members – daughters and sons are desperate to know where their parents are, but are terrified of what news they could discover and are wondering whether they will ever be safely reunited.</p>
<p>The PRC Government also continued its crackdown on Tibetan Buddhists. Authorities arrested, tortured, and committed other abuses against Tibetans who promoted their language and culture, possessed pictures and writings of the Dalai Lama, or practiced their religion at Buddhist monasteries. Secretary Blinken recently determined that the Burmese military committed genocide and crimes against humanity against Rohingya. Throughout Burma, already vulnerable communities, including civil society leaders and members of religious and ethnic minority groups, continue to face heightened risk of atrocities and other abuses.</p>
<p>Following its designation as a Country of Particular Concern for the first time last year, Russia has doubled down on its violations of religious freedom rather than reverse course. Russian courts regularly reach new milestones for excessive prison sentences against individuals exercising their religious freedom, and Russian authorities carry out hundreds of home raids against suspected extremists that frequently include violence. President Putin sought to justify the unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine through the blatantly false pretext of de-Nazification. The world clearly sees through this lie and is instead witnessing Russia’s brutal suppression, including suppression of religious leaders and the appalling destruction of religious sites.</p>
<p>Religious Freedom conditions in Afghanistan have deteriorated since the Taliban seized control. The Taliban regime and rival militant group ISIS-K have detained, intimidated, threatened, and attacked members of religious minority communities. And as the Secretary stated, in India some officials are ignoring or even supporting rising attacks on people and places of worship.</p>
<p>To elaborate further on the report’s second theme, there are a number of ways that rising societal intolerance and hatred are fueling violence and conflict around the world. Governments must speak out and protect the vulnerable and marginalized. Anti-Semitism, anti-Muslim hatred, and xenophobia are on the rise in many countries. Democratic backsliding and the rise of nationalism and nativist rhetoric and policies have been used to justify violence towards members of ethnic or religious minority groups and historically marginalized peoples. Social media platforms are used to spread hate speech and to incite violence by vilifying and threatening members of religious minorities.</p>
<p>And finally, I’d like to say a little bit more about the report’s third theme, how collaboration between civil society and government has created some progress. While this report paints a challenging picture of the state of religious freedom around the world, we remain hopeful about the future. Civil society groups and countries all over the world are essential to this report and to our work. Their advocacy changes laws, it lifts up the names of prisoners, provides lawyers to fight against spurious charges, and pushes governments including our own to do the right thing. I’ve had the opportunity to work with civil society on powerful initiatives, such as the Marrakesh Declaration, which affirms the rights of Christians and other religious minorities in Muslim-majority countries, and the Istanbul Process, which rejects criminalization of blasphemy.</p>
<p>Independent and strong civil societies help governments solve problems and better serve their people by shining a light on the issues that matter most. Where civil society thrives, governments operate with more transparency and accountability, creating a tangible impact on the lives of everyday citizens. We must listen to and empower the voices of civil society, including those who dissent from majority views or criticize the government, as we work towards a more just and peaceful future for us all. Change is only possible with the hard work of the groups and individuals dedicated to fighting for these rights. Today, more than ever, we have tools at our disposal to facilitate the flow of information to keep individuals informed. We have mechanisms to shed light on abuses taking place, and we have the means to hold bad actors accountable.</p>
<p>We have more partners in this effort now than ever before, including religious leaders. And religion can be such a powerful force for good, and it should never be used to harm people. Our greatest hope is that together we can unite our efforts to ensure respect for freedom of religion or belief for all people around the globe, and we continue to stand in solidarity with all people seeking to exercise their beliefs.</p>
<p>Thank you. (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Thank you all. Appreciate the good work. (Applause.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with UK Foreign Secretary Truss</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-uk-foreign-secretary-truss-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 18:04:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=349136</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Truss discussed the urgency of continued support to Ukraine, including vital humanitarian and security assistance.  The Secretary reconfirmed the importance of transatlantic unity in holding those who support the Kremlin’s war of choice to account, as well as ensuring vital agricultural commodities can leave Ukraine to provide the world critical food supplies.</span></p>
<p><span>The two discussed the importance of peace and prosperity in Northern Ireland, and the Secretary encouraged continued dialogue between the UK and the EU.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Truss also discussed pandemic preparedness, and the Secretary stressed the importance of increased funding to the Global Fund, emphasizing the critical role it plays in strengthening health systems and fighting HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria around the world. </span></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Truss discussed the urgency of continued support to Ukraine, including vital humanitarian and security assistance.  The Secretary reconfirmed the importance of transatlantic unity in holding those who support the Kremlin’s war of choice to account, as well as ensuring vital agricultural commodities can leave Ukraine to provide the world critical food supplies.</span></p>
<p><span>The two discussed the importance of peace and prosperity in Northern Ireland, and the Secretary encouraged continued dialogue between the UK and the EU.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Truss also discussed pandemic preparedness, and the Secretary stressed the importance of increased funding to the Global Fund, emphasizing the critical role it plays in strengthening health systems and fighting HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria around the world. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States Welcomes the Truce Extension in Yemen</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-welcomes-the-truce-extension-in-yemen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 16:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=349100</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes today’s announcement by the UN on the extension of the truce in Yemen. This 60-day extension is another important step toward peace and will bring further relief to millions of Yemenis. We are grateful for the efforts of UN Special Envoy Hans Grundberg as well as those of our own Special Envoy, Tim Lenderking, who has worked closely across our government and with the UN and our international partners to achieve this extension. We also appreciate the support of the Governments of Saudi Arabia, Jordan, Egypt, and Oman in helping secure the truce.</p>
<p>The United States urges the parties to cooperate fully with Special Envoy Grundberg as he builds on the truce toward a comprehensive and inclusive peace process. The parties must continue to uphold their responsibilities under the truce and work together to improve the lives of Yemenis, to include immediately opening roads to the city of Taiz, where hundreds of thousands of Yemenis have suffered for far too long. The first two months of the truce witnessed a dramatic reduction in civilian casualties, improved freedom of movement and humanitarian access, and increased access to fuel and basic goods.  These benefits should continue and expand.</p>
<p>The United States remains committed to an inclusive, durable resolution to the conflict that alleviates the suffering of Yemenis, that empowers them to determine the future of their country without foreign interference, and that addresses Yemenis’ calls for justice and accountability.  The Yemeni parties have an opportunity to listen to the demands of the people and choose peace over continued suffering, destruction, and war. We urge them to seize this pivotal moment to begin a comprehensive peace process.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes today’s announcement by the UN on the extension of the truce in Yemen. This 60-day extension is another important step toward peace and will bring further relief to millions of Yemenis. We are grateful for the efforts of UN Special Envoy Hans Grundberg as well as those of our own Special Envoy, Tim Lenderking, who has worked closely across our government and with the UN and our international partners to achieve this extension. We also appreciate the support of the Governments of Saudi Arabia, Jordan, Egypt, and Oman in helping secure the truce.</p>
<p>The United States urges the parties to cooperate fully with Special Envoy Grundberg as he builds on the truce toward a comprehensive and inclusive peace process. The parties must continue to uphold their responsibilities under the truce and work together to improve the lives of Yemenis, to include immediately opening roads to the city of Taiz, where hundreds of thousands of Yemenis have suffered for far too long. The first two months of the truce witnessed a dramatic reduction in civilian casualties, improved freedom of movement and humanitarian access, and increased access to fuel and basic goods.  These benefits should continue and expand.</p>
<p>The United States remains committed to an inclusive, durable resolution to the conflict that alleviates the suffering of Yemenis, that empowers them to determine the future of their country without foreign interference, and that addresses Yemenis’ calls for justice and accountability.  The Yemeni parties have an opportunity to listen to the demands of the people and choose peace over continued suffering, destruction, and war. We urge them to seize this pivotal moment to begin a comprehensive peace process.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Targeting Russia’s Oligarchs and Vessels</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/targeting-russias-oligarchs-and-vessels/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 16:22:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=349084</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin launched a full-scale further invasion of Ukraine on February 24, leading to civilian casualties and widespread reports of war crimes and other atrocities perpetrated by Russia’s forces in Ukraine. The world has seen the extraordinary bravery of the people of Ukraine in the face of Russia’s brutality. The United States will continue to work with our partners and allies to impose severe costs on the Government of the Russian Federation for its aggression against Ukraine and utter disregard for human rights and fundamental freedoms. The Department of State is designating more Russian oligarchs and elites today, in addition to family members and entities associated with those oligarchs and elites.</p>
<p>Specifically, we are designating God Nisanov, one of the richest men in Europe and a close associate of several Russian officials, pursuant to Executive Order (E.O.) 14024. The Department of State is similarly designating Evgeny Novitskiy, a Russian elite with close ties to the Government of the Russian Federation.</p>
<p>We are also designating Maria Zakharova, the spokesperson of the Russian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, for her role as an official of the Government of the Russian Federation. The EU, UK, Japan, Australia, and New Zealand have previously designated Maria Zakharova. The Department is designating Sergei Gorkov for his role in the Government of the Russian Federation as the head of RosGeo.</p>
<p>Finally, the Department is designating Alexey Mordashov, the leader of Severgroup and one of Russia’s wealthiest billionaires, along with his wife and two adult children. The EU, Australia, New Zealand, and the UK previously designated Alexey Mordashov. Four of Mordashov’s companies are also being designated, including: Severgroup, a multi-billion-dollar investment company operating in metallurgy, engineering, tourism, banking, technology, media and finance; Severstal, which is among Russia’s leading domestic steel producers; Algoritm, a Russian technology, media, and advertising company; and Nord Gold, which is a gold mining company with operations in Russia, Africa, South America, and North America.</p>
<p>Additionally, the Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) is taking further action to degrade the networks allowing Russia’s elites, including President Putin, to anonymously make use of luxury assets around the globe. OFAC’s action targets close associate of President Putin and money-manager, Sergei Roldugin, further designates entities connected to Russian elites, and identifies yachts and aircraft in which Russia’s elites maintain interests.</p>
<p>President Putin’s war against Ukraine is also an attack on the principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity, enshrined in the UN Charter. Ukraine is fighting valiantly to defend its people and its independence with unprecedented assistance from the United States and countries around the world. The United States will continue to support the people of Ukraine while promoting accountability for President Putin and those enabling Russian aggression.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0802" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> and State Department <a href="https://www.state.gov/promoting-accountability-and-imposing-costs-on-the-russian-federation-and-its-enablers-for-putins-aggression-against-ukraine/">Fact Sheet</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin launched a full-scale further invasion of Ukraine on February 24, leading to civilian casualties and widespread reports of war crimes and other atrocities perpetrated by Russia’s forces in Ukraine. The world has seen the extraordinary bravery of the people of Ukraine in the face of Russia’s brutality. The United States will continue to work with our partners and allies to impose severe costs on the Government of the Russian Federation for its aggression against Ukraine and utter disregard for human rights and fundamental freedoms. The Department of State is designating more Russian oligarchs and elites today, in addition to family members and entities associated with those oligarchs and elites.</p>
<p>Specifically, we are designating God Nisanov, one of the richest men in Europe and a close associate of several Russian officials, pursuant to Executive Order (E.O.) 14024. The Department of State is similarly designating Evgeny Novitskiy, a Russian elite with close ties to the Government of the Russian Federation.</p>
<p>We are also designating Maria Zakharova, the spokesperson of the Russian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, for her role as an official of the Government of the Russian Federation. The EU, UK, Japan, Australia, and New Zealand have previously designated Maria Zakharova. The Department is designating Sergei Gorkov for his role in the Government of the Russian Federation as the head of RosGeo.</p>
<p>Finally, the Department is designating Alexey Mordashov, the leader of Severgroup and one of Russia’s wealthiest billionaires, along with his wife and two adult children. The EU, Australia, New Zealand, and the UK previously designated Alexey Mordashov. Four of Mordashov’s companies are also being designated, including: Severgroup, a multi-billion-dollar investment company operating in metallurgy, engineering, tourism, banking, technology, media and finance; Severstal, which is among Russia’s leading domestic steel producers; Algoritm, a Russian technology, media, and advertising company; and Nord Gold, which is a gold mining company with operations in Russia, Africa, South America, and North America.</p>
<p>Additionally, the Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) is taking further action to degrade the networks allowing Russia’s elites, including President Putin, to anonymously make use of luxury assets around the globe. OFAC’s action targets close associate of President Putin and money-manager, Sergei Roldugin, further designates entities connected to Russian elites, and identifies yachts and aircraft in which Russia’s elites maintain interests.</p>
<p>President Putin’s war against Ukraine is also an attack on the principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity, enshrined in the UN Charter. Ukraine is fighting valiantly to defend its people and its independence with unprecedented assistance from the United States and countries around the world. The United States will continue to support the people of Ukraine while promoting accountability for President Putin and those enabling Russian aggression.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0802" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> and State Department <a href="https://www.state.gov/promoting-accountability-and-imposing-costs-on-the-russian-federation-and-its-enablers-for-putins-aggression-against-ukraine/">Fact Sheet</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Telephonic Press Briefing with Juan Gonzalez, National Security Council Senior Director for the Western Hemisphere and Brian A. Nichols, Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere Affairs, Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/telephonic-press-briefing-with-juan-gonzalez-national-security-council-senior-director-for-the-western-hemisphere-and-brian-a-nichols-assistant-secretary-of-state-for-western-hemisphere-affairs-bu/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian A. Nichols, Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere AffairsBureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs, Juan Gonzalez, National Security Council Senior Director for the Western Hemisphere]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 15:24:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=349067</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Brian A. Nichols, Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere AffairsBureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs</p>
<p>Juan Gonzalez, National Security Council Senior Director for the Western Hemisphere</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Moderator: </b> Greetings to everyone from the U.S. Department of State Media Hub of the Americas in Miami, Florida.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I would like to welcome our participants who have dialed in from the United States and across the region.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>This is an on-the-record press briefing with NSC Senior Director for the Western Hemisphere Juan Gonzalez and Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs Brian Nichols.</p>
<p>Senior Director Gonzalez and Assistant Secretary Nichols will discuss the upcoming 9th Summit of the Americas.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>They each will give opening remarks and take questions from participating journalists.</p>
<p>And with that, I’ll turn it over to NSC Senior Director Juan Gonzalez.</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Good afternoon, everybody, and it’s always a privilege to share a stage with our senior diplomat for the Western Hemisphere, Brian Nichols, who has been a partner through and through.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I would like to start by, I think, first welcoming you all to the call and for your patience as we head toward what we know will be an incredible Summit of the Americas next week.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>You know that the President, as you know, incredibly values personal engagement and looks forward to speaking with and engaging with the leaders and other representatives that will be attending.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The President is very much looking to hosting the 9th<span> </span>summit representatives from government, civil society, and the private sector to advance our common goals and find common ground.</p>
<p>The President specifically really sees an opportunity for leaders and key stakeholders to come together to address some of the core challenging challenges facing the people of the hemisphere, including economic prosperity, climate change, the migration crisis, and the COVID-19 pandemic.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>No other part of the world impacts the security and prosperity of the United States more directly than the Western Hemisphere, and that is why the President has consistently said that he sees the objective of U.S. policy to advance a vision of a region that is secure, middle class, and democratic as something that is fundamentally in the national security interest of the United States.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>But of course, we are joined with the hemisphere not just by geography but our economic ties, democratic principles, cultural connections, and familial bonds.</p>
<p>First, look, there’s 28 years have passed since the United States has hosted the 1st Summit of the Americas, and we’re obviously living in very different times.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Today we have the – we’re meeting against the backdrop of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, a region that is still reeling from the impact of the pandemic, the lasting socioeconomic impacts of the pandemic and obviously the inflationary impacts of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And in a time when even before the pandemic there were ongoing protests by populations throughout the hemisphere that were really starting to question the value of democracy.</p>
<p>So against that backdrop, the President has really challenged the U.S. Government and engaged with partners to try to develop an ambitious agenda for the summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And the United States will announce some key actions that we intend to accomplish along five specific areas for the summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Without going into too much detail or getting out ahead of the President, I’ll go through them very quickly.</p>
<p>The first is our economic agenda, recognizing the connection between the region’s success and that of our own.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>As I had mentioned, the President will use the summit to align regional leaders, the private sector, and civil society behind a new and ambitious economic agenda that builds upon our existing free trade agreements in the hemisphere to really help address some of the dislocations of trade, but addressing issues of equity and equality, supporting the global energy transition, the adoption of technology.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Health and health security systems are going to be fundamental, I think, that taking very concrete steps at the summit to make sure that we’re moving forward to build upon our existing free trade agreements.</p>
<p>Also developing – we’re updating tools that we’ve had.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We have, obviously, a multilateral system that was developed decades ago, and we need new tools to really help a predominantly middle-income region address some – a once-in-a-century economic crisis that has been the pandemic.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So that’s something that I think we’re very much looking forward to the President announcing.</p>
<p>The other is health, as a top national security priority for this administration to ensure that millions don’t continue to die from the COVID-19 pandemic.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>That is why the United States has donated now nearly 70 million vaccines to the hemisphere without any strings attached, and at the summit the President will also launch an effort to promote health systems and health security in the region to prepare for future pandemics, strengthen the region’s health systems, and bolster health security supply chains.</p>
<p>The President will also announce a new partnership on climate and energy with Caribbean nations and will ask the Vice President to lead this effort just as he did as vice president with the Caribbean Energy Security Initiative in 2013.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The focus is on responding to the increasing climate energy challenges facing our Caribbean partners.</p>
<p>And we have also on food security and its effects on vulnerable populations.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>This is a regional priority and directly linked to our cooperative efforts on migration and ensuring an equitable and sustainable-driven economic pandemic recovery in the hemisphere.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We have invested in key social safety nets to help reduce poverty and food shocks in the region through Feed the Future and other agricultural programs.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The United States is proud to contribute more funding for migration and food security needs that will improve the quality of life for people across the region.</p>
<p>And of course, closely tied to the economic agenda and everything else that I mentioned is really addressing the historic migration crisis in a way that is unprecedented for the United States and for the region, recognizing that migration is a symptom of a much broader challenge brought on by the economic and security challenges that the hemisphere has been facing for the last couple years.</p>
<p>Now, for the last couple of months the President has and the Secretary of State and Secretary of Homeland Security, the Vice President, and others have been all-hands-on-deck to mobilize leaders around a bold new plan centered on responsibility sharing and economic support for countries that have been most impacted by refugee and migration flows.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>On the margins of the summit, the President will join other heads of state to sign a migration declaration, sending a strong signal of unity and resolve to bring the regional migration crisis under control.</p>
<p>While, again, I’m not going to get into the specifics of the deliverables that you can expect from the President, what I can tell you is that we’re looking forward to having you all join us and learn from him directly at the summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I’d just like to note that the five action areas I just talked about are different than the five political commitments, which have been a function of the Summit Implementation Review Group process that are also going to be at the core of what comes out of the summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And there’s also an overlap here significantly with what the President’s announcing with the political commitments, particularly in areas of democracy, governance, climate, energy, health, and digitalization.</p>
<p>And that concludes, I think, the main points.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I will now pass the conversation to my colleague, Assistant Secretary of State for the Western Hemisphere Brian Nichols, who will speak to the collaborative work that the region’s governments will commit to and which are currently being finalized at the Summit Implementation Review Group.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thanks.</p>
<p><b>Assistant Secretary Nichols:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thanks so much, Juan, and it’s a great pleasure to work with you on this, and so your energy, creativity, and drive to help our hemisphere.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I’d also like to recognize the great work that our senior advisors Chris Dodd and Debbie Mucarsel-Powell have been working on as well as our summit coordinator Kevin O’Reilly, who is in L.A. now working on the final negotiations for the Summit Implementation Review Group.</p>
<p>Before I take your questions, I’d like to briefly preview what you can expect in terms of the political commitments from the 9th Summit of the Americas, as Juan said.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The United States is hosting the summit one week from today in Los Angeles, California, and we’re focusing on how we’ll deliver for average people in our region.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Juan talked about the action that our President is taking in five key areas.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Some of those are similar to the political commitments that I will discuss, but the difference is that those actions are the U.S. priorities for the region and things that President Biden is specifically going to deliver.</p>
<p>From June 8th to 10th, the heads of state and government from across the Americas will come together to adopt five leader-level political commitments which will set forth our mandate for building a sustainable, resilient, and equitable future by proposing and implementing actions under the summit’s five political commitments: democratic governance, health and resilience, the clean energy transition, our green future, and digital transformation.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Our region’s leaders and stakeholders can improve the lives of the people of our hemisphere in a demonstrable and meaningful way.</p>
<p>First, on democratic governance, the United States knows we all have to work – we all have work to do on building strong and inclusive democracies in the hemisphere, including here at home.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>At the summit, our collective action can demonstrate our commitment to enhancing transparent and accountable governments that deliver democracy to the people of the Americas.</p>
<p>To this end, we will adopt a Plan of Action that calls for reaffirming our commitment to the Inter-American Democratic Charter, including establishing mechanisms to address new challenges to democracy; supporting the work of electoral observation missions, following up on our commitment at the 8th Summit of the Americas to promote transparency, accountability, and combat corruption; enhancing protections of human rights defenders, environmental defenders, members of the press, and whistleblowers; increasing the participation of civil society, private sector, and new stakeholders in democratic processes and decision-making.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>These are just a few of the ways in which we’re working to bolster democratic governance as a region and build on the commitment we made 20 years ago when we adopted the Inter-American Democratic Charter.</p>
<p>Second, on health and pandemic resilience, the United States will propose that the hemisphere’s leaders take a whole-of-government approach to address systemic health issues by agreeing to draft an action plan on health and resilience to be implemented by 10th summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Components of the action plan will include: expanding quality people- and community-centered health services, strengthening of educational and training programs in the field of medicine, public health, nutrition, and biomedical science research; and examining financial systems to more efficiently, effectively, sustainably, equitably, and transparently improve public financing related to health systems.</p>
<p>Third, on the clean energy transition, we will discuss implementation of renewable energy goals and ways that the hemisphere can share technical knowledge and best practices to put the Americas at the forefront of the global clean energy transition.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>These include:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>collaborating with the private sector and other stakeholders to identify opportunities for manufacture or trade in clean energy goods and services; fostering the enabling conditions for the scale-up of renewable energy; and advancing sustainable, attainable, and responsible mining sector principles and securing the integration of mineral supply chains in our hemisphere.</p>
<p>Fourth, on climate change, our hemisphere will build our longstanding commitments on climate resilience and sustainability to strengthen the hemisphere’s resilience and adaptive capacity to withstand the impacts of climate change and extreme weather events.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Our regional political commitment on our green future will include measures such as:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>advancing the Glasgow Leaders Declaration on Forest and Land Use to halt and reverse deforestation; decreasing the amount of carbon emitted from land use activities and increasing carbon storage; harnessing the role of oceans and other bodies of water to mitigate climate change, as well as combatting ocean plastic pollution; accelerating climate change adaption and resilience by implementing national adaption plans or strategies.</p>
<p>Fifth and finally, on digital transformation, leaders will identify shared priorities and commit to specific actions building digital ecosystems.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>This first-ever regional agenda for digital transformation creates a framework for governments and stakeholders to collaboratively create the jobs and industries of the future based on interoperable, resilient, secure, and reliable telecommunications networks which will drive innovation and expand access to goods, services, and information in new ways.</p>
<p>These include:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>promoting policies to expand the internet access, particularly in historically marginalized communities, and drive digital innovation and social inclusion through increased access to digital government services; expanding digital technology’s role in promoting quality education, digital literacy, and digital citizenry; increasing a regulatory harmonization in areas like spectrum management and digital trade.</p>
<p>We look forward to sharing more details on these political commitments at the summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And both Juan and I will now take your questions.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We will now begin the question-and-answer portion of today’s call.</p>
<p>Our first question was submitted by Mark Stevenson from the Associated Press.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And the question is:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>“Have Nicaragua, Venezuela, Mexico, or Cuba been confirmed as attending the Americas Summit, and who will they be sending?”</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>So I’m happy to take that one.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So we still have some final considerations, but we will, I think, inform people publicly soon about the final invitation list.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I think what’s really important for us in terms of the summit is why we are gathering, and that is to focus on our collective responsibilities to forge a more inclusive and prosperous future for the hemisphere.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So we’ve not been so focused on the – on who is and is not invited, and more really on the outcomes that we want to achieve at the summit.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Our next question will go to David Alandete.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Operator, please open line 95.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>David.</p>
<p><b>Question:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Yes.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>Moderator:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Yes, please go ahead.</p>
<p><b>Question:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Can you hear me now?</p>
<p><b>Moderator:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Yes, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>Question:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Sorry about that.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So yeah, I have two questions.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>One of them is like besides the fact that some details are still being finalized, I wanted to ask Mr. Gonzalez if in any case the option of inviting someone from the Cuban regime is still on the table, if it’s something that is being debated.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>It’s something like quite important from the point of view of the whole continent.</p>
<p>And the second one is like the presence of Venezuela.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Could you explain how Mr. Guaido is invited, and when is he going to address the other leaders if he – or what is the nature of his invitation to the summit?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you so much.</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Thanks.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So I mean, again, I’m not going to enter the details, but what I’ll say is that we have just had very respectful and active conversations with Mexico and the Mexican president’s request that Cuba attend the summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The United States and Mexico have really partnered very closely on a number of issues, and the approach that we’ve taken is to talk with the leaders of the region, talk to Mexico.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>But again, I’ll go back to the previous answer where I’ll just say that we’re still having some final considerations.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And then as soon as we &#8212; as soon as the White House makes a final decision on final invites, that’s something that we’ll be happy to brief folks and to provide our rationale.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thanks.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Our next question was submitted by Jason Calderon from NTN 24.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The questions is:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>“What does the document for the Regional Migration Pact that President Joe Biden will propose as the main objective of the Summit of the Americas include?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And what is in the &#8212; what is new in this proposal?”</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Yes, I can – so I’ll take the first part, and then Assistant Secretary Nichols has also been engaged on this.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We’ll invite him to say &#8212; to speak to this as well.</p>
<p>So look, while migration is, first, an important topic that’ll be discussed at the summit, it’s one of the several focus areas, all of which are important to the hemisphere.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>But I think the key here is – point here is that irregular migration is a regional problem that touches nearly every country in the region, and often a symptom of other challenges that I’ve mentioned facing Latin America and the Caribbean.</p>
<p>So what we are hoping to do is – and have been, as I mentioned, engaging on this very actively with our regional counterparts is to look at the regional challenge from the context of responsibility sharing and the need to provide economic support to countries to have been impacted by refugee and migration flows, but also the importance of avenues and in-country processing avenues, expanding refugee protections, and also addressing, I think, some of the core drivers of migration, which are lack of economic opportunities and insecurity.</p>
<p>I will say also there is just a robust initiative to combat smuggling in there as well.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>But at the – at its core, what this is, is something that is unprecedented in that the leaders of the region that are either source, transit, or destination countries for migration are really coming together behind a plan that recognizes that the migration challenge is not one that is – that is at the U.S. border, but it’s one that is actually impacting all the countries in the Americas, and that we need to work together to address it in a way that treats migrants with dignity, invests in creating opportunities that would dissuade migrants from leaving their homes in the first place, and provide the protections that migrants deserve.</p>
<p><b>Assistant Secretary Nichols:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Yeah, I’ll just add to that that this builds on Secretary Blinken’s participation in co-hosting of ministerial-level meetings in Colombia and Panama to talk about this unprecedented challenge globally.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>There are more than 94 million people on the move as migrants.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>This poses a challenge to nations around the world, but particularly in our own hemisphere.</p>
<p>And this declaration is going to allow us to focus on promoting stabilization in communities that are hosting migrants; helping those communities and the migrants that they are hosting; ensuring things like access to legal documentation and public services; promoting pathways for legal, orderly migration when appropriate; to ensure ethical recruitment for employment, for example; promoting humane migration management; and a shared approach to mitigating and managing irregular migration.</p>
<p>Those are some of the things that we’re focusing on.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And it builds on not only the ministerial meetings that have taken place, but the many agreements that have come both within our region and around the world to promote safe, orderly, humane migration.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Our next question, we’ll go to Rafael Mathus from <i>La Nacion</i>.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Operator, please open line 30.</p>
<p><b>Question:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Thank you very much for doing this call and for taking my question.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>About the invitations for Cuba, Nicaragua, Venezuela, and so on, Juan, can you specifically say what are the final considerations of the government on this topic, because it has been discussed for several months now?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And what are your thoughts on the damage these issues are creating on both the summit and the agenda of the summit?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thanks.</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Well, look, I mean, I’m not going to get into the specifics of the considerations because I think fundamentally what this administration has done, whether it’s on this topic or on any topic, is treated the countries of the region as our partners that – whose views we have to take into serious account.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And certainly with Mexico and with others that have expressed a view, we have tried to engage in a conversation and been very respectful of the different perspectives.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And ultimately, it’s something that as the host’s prerogative we’ll make the final decision, and we’ll announce that once the decision has been made.</p>
<p>Is it a distraction from the summit itself?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Look, I don’t think so.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>It’s hard to, I think, confirm anything until it actually happens.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>But we are really confident that the summit will be well-attended, that our relationship with Mexico is – remains and will continue to remain positive.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We very much want President Lopez Obrador there.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The President of the United States very personally wants the President of Mexico there.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And that I think once folks see what is announced at the summit we’ll see that we’re really actually addressing, I think, what are rising to the challenge that is – that are many of the different economic, pandemic-related, and other challenges that the region is facing.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So I think we’ll let the results speak for themselves.</p>
<p><b>Assistant Secretary Nichols:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Yeah, I’d just like to add that we’re very much focused on addressing the issues that affect people in their daily lives in our hemisphere.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We will have attendance from leaders throughout our hemisphere, but we’re also going to have attendance from private sector leaders and CEOs, from members of civil society, from youth from across the hemisphere.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>They are coming together in an unprecedented way, literally thousands of people, to talk about the issues of concern that affect people in their daily lives.</p>
<p>Can they get access to health care?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Can their kids get a good education?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Do they have the economic opportunities they need?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Are they able to benefit from broadband internet technology?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>What are we doing to mitigate the shock caused by Russia’s invasion of Ukraine and ensure people have reliable, affordable access to food?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And what are we doing to reorient supply chains to make sure that the disruptions that we’ve seen over the past few years are not repeated?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I think that’s what average people care about, and that’s what we’re focused on.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We will now go to Raquel Krahenbul from TV Globo.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Operator, please open line 7.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Question:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Yes, hello.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I am with Raquel.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>She is just out of the room for one minute.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Can you please call on her in just another minute?</p>
<p><b>Moderator:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Sure.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Operator, thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We will now go to Priscilla Alvarez from CNN.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We go to line 61, please.</p>
<p><b>Question:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Hi.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>Moderator:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Yes.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Please go ahead.</p>
<p><b>Question:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Thank you for doing this.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>You mention throughout the call that this is about creating regional partnership to address issues systemic to the hemisphere.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>But if you are missing key partners like Mexico or Guatemala, Honduras, El Salvador, how do you – do you anticipate success or an outcome from this?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I mean, those are key partners.</p>
<p>And then also you mentioned earlier, and I just want to clarify, the Mexican president’s request that Cuba attend the summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Is that currently the state of play with those discussions, whether Cuba attends, and no longer a discussion about Nicaragua and Venezuela?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Sure.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I mean, I’ll be brief, and then Brian will have his views.</p>
<p>Look, I mean, with Mexico and those others, we have made very clear that participation won’t impact cooperation or even a level of ambition certainly before – well before the summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>On the issue of migration, we’ve had very close cooperation with Mexico, and that will continue to be the case.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And just again on the invitations, we’re just – we’re still looking through – it’s continuing to engage in conversations with different countries.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And once we make a final decision, we’ll make an announcement.</p>
<p><b>Assistant Secretary Nichols: </b> I’ll just add that countries throughout our hemisphere have been playing an active role in the Summit Implementation Review Group negotiation of the five political commitments that will be approved at the summit, and that includes Mexico.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The engagement across many levels, from ambassadors and department representatives to the Organization of American States to senior ministry officials to foreign ministers, around the goals for this summit has been active and intense and very constructive.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And I think we’re going to leave this summit with an incredibly strong mandate from this hemisphere to work on the issues that matter to people.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We will now go to Jaqueline Charles from <i>The Miami Herald</i>.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Operator, please open line 83.</p>
<p><b>Question:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Hi, thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>In regards to Haiti, which today is undergoing multiple crises and we are seeing it playing itself out with the migration both at the land and the sea borders, what will be a specific message or focus as far as Haiti is concerned during this summit, and what can we expect as far as deliverables in regard to Haiti?</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Brian, do you want to take this?</p>
<p><b>Assistant Secretary Nichols:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So we’re focused on a number of things that will benefit Haiti.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Access to health care is one.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Changes to the way that we approach our engagement on some economic issues to ensure that we’re leveraging all the tools that we can to support partner nations throughout our hemisphere, which will benefit Haiti.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Obviously, migration is an area where we have to do more to support and engage Haiti, and I think we’re going to have some interesting things in that area.</p>
<p>And then more broadly, the commitments around democracy will benefit Haiti as it moves towards elections in the future, things like strengthening electoral oversight authorities in our hemisphere, support to candidates and political parties, respect for the role of ombudsmen and transparency-related authorities in country – all are directly applicable to Haiti.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And by taking those commitments and working them both bilaterally with Haiti among the countries of our hemisphere, multilaterally through the Organization of American States, through UN bodies, I think we’re going to be able to translate this into specific and concrete further assistance for the Haitian people who need it very much.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We will now go to Beatriz Bulla from Estradao.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Operator, please open line 63.</p>
<p><b>Question:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Hi, thank you all for doing this.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So I’d like to ask about the position of the Brazilian president, Jair Bolsonaro.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>You mention that the summit will discuss the core challenges to the people of the hemisphere, and democracy is one of them.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I’ll like to ask if President Biden wants to raise concerns or express his confidence on the Brazilian electoral process, considering that President Bolsonaro has made some comments about the Brazilian electoral process, and also because last year when the NSA Jake Sullivan was here in Brazil with Bolsonaro, you – the U.S. expressed great confidence in the Brazilian institutions and society with Bolsonaro, the importance of not undermining trust in this process.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So is the Brazilian electoral – is it going to be a topic during the summit or during the bilateral meeting with Biden and Bolsonaro?</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So I’ll say the issue of the Brazilian elections is really up for the Brazilians to decide, and the United States does have confidence in Brazil’s electoral institutions, which have proved robust.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And – but the conversation with – between the President and President Bolsonaro is going to cover a wide range of topics that are bilateral and, frankly, global in nature given the importance of the U.S. relationship.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So whether it’s tackling food insecurity and economic response to the pandemic, health and health security, every single priority for the summit that we have are areas where Brazil plays an incredibly important role.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The topic of climate change as well is something that the President has made clear is a priority, is something that’s – so there is a very long list of issues that are going to be up for discussion between the President and President Bolsonaro.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We have time for one last question.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The last question goes to Jorge Agobian from Voice of America.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Operator, please open line 48.</p>
<p><b>Question:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you so much for doing this.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We really appreciate it.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I have a question.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>If the United States recognizes the government of Juan Guaido in Venezuela as the legit government of that country, why are there still additional considerations to be decided in this specific point?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And why haven’t they been invited to the summit, and how should it be interpreted?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Then, if they were not invited as the representative of Venezuelan government, if U.S. actually recognizes Guaido as the president?</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So the United States does continue to recognize interim President Juan Guaido as the legitimately elected president of the – of the national assembly, which was the last democratically elected institution in that country.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And we engage actively with him, with his ambassador and his government as well as the representatives of the unity platform and we’re actually supporting a dialogue that produces outcomes that lead to free and fair elections in the country.</p>
<p>I’m not going to talk about the considerations with regard to invitations except to just underscore that there are – governments have different views on some of these topics, and we engage and consult with them.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And ultimately the host prerogative is important, but we also are wanting to facilitate a broad hemispheric discussion and want to make sure that we’re integrating all of the views of the members of the Organization of American States.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So again, we’re – for us, it’s most important that we’re gathering together and that the focus is on our collective responsibility to forge a more inclusive and prosperous future for the hemisphere, and that includes one for the people of Venezuela.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>That concludes today’s call.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I want to thank Senior Director Gonzalez and Assistant Secretary Nichols for joining us and thank all of our callers for participating.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>If you have any questions about today’s call, you may contact the Miami Media Hub at MiamiHub@state.gov.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you and have a good day.</p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brian A. Nichols, Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere AffairsBureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs</p>
<p>Juan Gonzalez, National Security Council Senior Director for the Western Hemisphere</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Moderator: </b> Greetings to everyone from the U.S. Department of State Media Hub of the Americas in Miami, Florida.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I would like to welcome our participants who have dialed in from the United States and across the region.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>This is an on-the-record press briefing with NSC Senior Director for the Western Hemisphere Juan Gonzalez and Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs Brian Nichols.</p>
<p>Senior Director Gonzalez and Assistant Secretary Nichols will discuss the upcoming 9th Summit of the Americas.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>They each will give opening remarks and take questions from participating journalists.</p>
<p>And with that, I’ll turn it over to NSC Senior Director Juan Gonzalez.</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Good afternoon, everybody, and it’s always a privilege to share a stage with our senior diplomat for the Western Hemisphere, Brian Nichols, who has been a partner through and through.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I would like to start by, I think, first welcoming you all to the call and for your patience as we head toward what we know will be an incredible Summit of the Americas next week.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>You know that the President, as you know, incredibly values personal engagement and looks forward to speaking with and engaging with the leaders and other representatives that will be attending.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The President is very much looking to hosting the 9th<span> </span>summit representatives from government, civil society, and the private sector to advance our common goals and find common ground.</p>
<p>The President specifically really sees an opportunity for leaders and key stakeholders to come together to address some of the core challenging challenges facing the people of the hemisphere, including economic prosperity, climate change, the migration crisis, and the COVID-19 pandemic.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>No other part of the world impacts the security and prosperity of the United States more directly than the Western Hemisphere, and that is why the President has consistently said that he sees the objective of U.S. policy to advance a vision of a region that is secure, middle class, and democratic as something that is fundamentally in the national security interest of the United States.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>But of course, we are joined with the hemisphere not just by geography but our economic ties, democratic principles, cultural connections, and familial bonds.</p>
<p>First, look, there’s 28 years have passed since the United States has hosted the 1st Summit of the Americas, and we’re obviously living in very different times.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Today we have the – we’re meeting against the backdrop of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, a region that is still reeling from the impact of the pandemic, the lasting socioeconomic impacts of the pandemic and obviously the inflationary impacts of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And in a time when even before the pandemic there were ongoing protests by populations throughout the hemisphere that were really starting to question the value of democracy.</p>
<p>So against that backdrop, the President has really challenged the U.S. Government and engaged with partners to try to develop an ambitious agenda for the summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And the United States will announce some key actions that we intend to accomplish along five specific areas for the summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Without going into too much detail or getting out ahead of the President, I’ll go through them very quickly.</p>
<p>The first is our economic agenda, recognizing the connection between the region’s success and that of our own.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>As I had mentioned, the President will use the summit to align regional leaders, the private sector, and civil society behind a new and ambitious economic agenda that builds upon our existing free trade agreements in the hemisphere to really help address some of the dislocations of trade, but addressing issues of equity and equality, supporting the global energy transition, the adoption of technology.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Health and health security systems are going to be fundamental, I think, that taking very concrete steps at the summit to make sure that we’re moving forward to build upon our existing free trade agreements.</p>
<p>Also developing – we’re updating tools that we’ve had.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We have, obviously, a multilateral system that was developed decades ago, and we need new tools to really help a predominantly middle-income region address some – a once-in-a-century economic crisis that has been the pandemic.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So that’s something that I think we’re very much looking forward to the President announcing.</p>
<p>The other is health, as a top national security priority for this administration to ensure that millions don’t continue to die from the COVID-19 pandemic.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>That is why the United States has donated now nearly 70 million vaccines to the hemisphere without any strings attached, and at the summit the President will also launch an effort to promote health systems and health security in the region to prepare for future pandemics, strengthen the region’s health systems, and bolster health security supply chains.</p>
<p>The President will also announce a new partnership on climate and energy with Caribbean nations and will ask the Vice President to lead this effort just as he did as vice president with the Caribbean Energy Security Initiative in 2013.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The focus is on responding to the increasing climate energy challenges facing our Caribbean partners.</p>
<p>And we have also on food security and its effects on vulnerable populations.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>This is a regional priority and directly linked to our cooperative efforts on migration and ensuring an equitable and sustainable-driven economic pandemic recovery in the hemisphere.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We have invested in key social safety nets to help reduce poverty and food shocks in the region through Feed the Future and other agricultural programs.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The United States is proud to contribute more funding for migration and food security needs that will improve the quality of life for people across the region.</p>
<p>And of course, closely tied to the economic agenda and everything else that I mentioned is really addressing the historic migration crisis in a way that is unprecedented for the United States and for the region, recognizing that migration is a symptom of a much broader challenge brought on by the economic and security challenges that the hemisphere has been facing for the last couple years.</p>
<p>Now, for the last couple of months the President has and the Secretary of State and Secretary of Homeland Security, the Vice President, and others have been all-hands-on-deck to mobilize leaders around a bold new plan centered on responsibility sharing and economic support for countries that have been most impacted by refugee and migration flows.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>On the margins of the summit, the President will join other heads of state to sign a migration declaration, sending a strong signal of unity and resolve to bring the regional migration crisis under control.</p>
<p>While, again, I’m not going to get into the specifics of the deliverables that you can expect from the President, what I can tell you is that we’re looking forward to having you all join us and learn from him directly at the summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I’d just like to note that the five action areas I just talked about are different than the five political commitments, which have been a function of the Summit Implementation Review Group process that are also going to be at the core of what comes out of the summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And there’s also an overlap here significantly with what the President’s announcing with the political commitments, particularly in areas of democracy, governance, climate, energy, health, and digitalization.</p>
<p>And that concludes, I think, the main points.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I will now pass the conversation to my colleague, Assistant Secretary of State for the Western Hemisphere Brian Nichols, who will speak to the collaborative work that the region’s governments will commit to and which are currently being finalized at the Summit Implementation Review Group.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thanks.</p>
<p><b>Assistant Secretary Nichols:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thanks so much, Juan, and it’s a great pleasure to work with you on this, and so your energy, creativity, and drive to help our hemisphere.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I’d also like to recognize the great work that our senior advisors Chris Dodd and Debbie Mucarsel-Powell have been working on as well as our summit coordinator Kevin O’Reilly, who is in L.A. now working on the final negotiations for the Summit Implementation Review Group.</p>
<p>Before I take your questions, I’d like to briefly preview what you can expect in terms of the political commitments from the 9th Summit of the Americas, as Juan said.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The United States is hosting the summit one week from today in Los Angeles, California, and we’re focusing on how we’ll deliver for average people in our region.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Juan talked about the action that our President is taking in five key areas.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Some of those are similar to the political commitments that I will discuss, but the difference is that those actions are the U.S. priorities for the region and things that President Biden is specifically going to deliver.</p>
<p>From June 8th to 10th, the heads of state and government from across the Americas will come together to adopt five leader-level political commitments which will set forth our mandate for building a sustainable, resilient, and equitable future by proposing and implementing actions under the summit’s five political commitments: democratic governance, health and resilience, the clean energy transition, our green future, and digital transformation.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Our region’s leaders and stakeholders can improve the lives of the people of our hemisphere in a demonstrable and meaningful way.</p>
<p>First, on democratic governance, the United States knows we all have to work – we all have work to do on building strong and inclusive democracies in the hemisphere, including here at home.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>At the summit, our collective action can demonstrate our commitment to enhancing transparent and accountable governments that deliver democracy to the people of the Americas.</p>
<p>To this end, we will adopt a Plan of Action that calls for reaffirming our commitment to the Inter-American Democratic Charter, including establishing mechanisms to address new challenges to democracy; supporting the work of electoral observation missions, following up on our commitment at the 8th Summit of the Americas to promote transparency, accountability, and combat corruption; enhancing protections of human rights defenders, environmental defenders, members of the press, and whistleblowers; increasing the participation of civil society, private sector, and new stakeholders in democratic processes and decision-making.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>These are just a few of the ways in which we’re working to bolster democratic governance as a region and build on the commitment we made 20 years ago when we adopted the Inter-American Democratic Charter.</p>
<p>Second, on health and pandemic resilience, the United States will propose that the hemisphere’s leaders take a whole-of-government approach to address systemic health issues by agreeing to draft an action plan on health and resilience to be implemented by 10th summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Components of the action plan will include: expanding quality people- and community-centered health services, strengthening of educational and training programs in the field of medicine, public health, nutrition, and biomedical science research; and examining financial systems to more efficiently, effectively, sustainably, equitably, and transparently improve public financing related to health systems.</p>
<p>Third, on the clean energy transition, we will discuss implementation of renewable energy goals and ways that the hemisphere can share technical knowledge and best practices to put the Americas at the forefront of the global clean energy transition.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>These include:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>collaborating with the private sector and other stakeholders to identify opportunities for manufacture or trade in clean energy goods and services; fostering the enabling conditions for the scale-up of renewable energy; and advancing sustainable, attainable, and responsible mining sector principles and securing the integration of mineral supply chains in our hemisphere.</p>
<p>Fourth, on climate change, our hemisphere will build our longstanding commitments on climate resilience and sustainability to strengthen the hemisphere’s resilience and adaptive capacity to withstand the impacts of climate change and extreme weather events.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Our regional political commitment on our green future will include measures such as:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>advancing the Glasgow Leaders Declaration on Forest and Land Use to halt and reverse deforestation; decreasing the amount of carbon emitted from land use activities and increasing carbon storage; harnessing the role of oceans and other bodies of water to mitigate climate change, as well as combatting ocean plastic pollution; accelerating climate change adaption and resilience by implementing national adaption plans or strategies.</p>
<p>Fifth and finally, on digital transformation, leaders will identify shared priorities and commit to specific actions building digital ecosystems.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>This first-ever regional agenda for digital transformation creates a framework for governments and stakeholders to collaboratively create the jobs and industries of the future based on interoperable, resilient, secure, and reliable telecommunications networks which will drive innovation and expand access to goods, services, and information in new ways.</p>
<p>These include:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>promoting policies to expand the internet access, particularly in historically marginalized communities, and drive digital innovation and social inclusion through increased access to digital government services; expanding digital technology’s role in promoting quality education, digital literacy, and digital citizenry; increasing a regulatory harmonization in areas like spectrum management and digital trade.</p>
<p>We look forward to sharing more details on these political commitments at the summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And both Juan and I will now take your questions.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We will now begin the question-and-answer portion of today’s call.</p>
<p>Our first question was submitted by Mark Stevenson from the Associated Press.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And the question is:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>“Have Nicaragua, Venezuela, Mexico, or Cuba been confirmed as attending the Americas Summit, and who will they be sending?”</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>So I’m happy to take that one.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So we still have some final considerations, but we will, I think, inform people publicly soon about the final invitation list.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I think what’s really important for us in terms of the summit is why we are gathering, and that is to focus on our collective responsibilities to forge a more inclusive and prosperous future for the hemisphere.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So we’ve not been so focused on the – on who is and is not invited, and more really on the outcomes that we want to achieve at the summit.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Our next question will go to David Alandete.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Operator, please open line 95.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>David.</p>
<p><b>Question:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Yes.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>Moderator:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Yes, please go ahead.</p>
<p><b>Question:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Can you hear me now?</p>
<p><b>Moderator:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Yes, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>Question:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Sorry about that.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So yeah, I have two questions.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>One of them is like besides the fact that some details are still being finalized, I wanted to ask Mr. Gonzalez if in any case the option of inviting someone from the Cuban regime is still on the table, if it’s something that is being debated.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>It’s something like quite important from the point of view of the whole continent.</p>
<p>And the second one is like the presence of Venezuela.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Could you explain how Mr. Guaido is invited, and when is he going to address the other leaders if he – or what is the nature of his invitation to the summit?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you so much.</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Thanks.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So I mean, again, I’m not going to enter the details, but what I’ll say is that we have just had very respectful and active conversations with Mexico and the Mexican president’s request that Cuba attend the summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The United States and Mexico have really partnered very closely on a number of issues, and the approach that we’ve taken is to talk with the leaders of the region, talk to Mexico.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>But again, I’ll go back to the previous answer where I’ll just say that we’re still having some final considerations.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And then as soon as we &#8212; as soon as the White House makes a final decision on final invites, that’s something that we’ll be happy to brief folks and to provide our rationale.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thanks.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Our next question was submitted by Jason Calderon from NTN 24.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The questions is:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>“What does the document for the Regional Migration Pact that President Joe Biden will propose as the main objective of the Summit of the Americas include?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And what is in the &#8212; what is new in this proposal?”</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Yes, I can – so I’ll take the first part, and then Assistant Secretary Nichols has also been engaged on this.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We’ll invite him to say &#8212; to speak to this as well.</p>
<p>So look, while migration is, first, an important topic that’ll be discussed at the summit, it’s one of the several focus areas, all of which are important to the hemisphere.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>But I think the key here is – point here is that irregular migration is a regional problem that touches nearly every country in the region, and often a symptom of other challenges that I’ve mentioned facing Latin America and the Caribbean.</p>
<p>So what we are hoping to do is – and have been, as I mentioned, engaging on this very actively with our regional counterparts is to look at the regional challenge from the context of responsibility sharing and the need to provide economic support to countries to have been impacted by refugee and migration flows, but also the importance of avenues and in-country processing avenues, expanding refugee protections, and also addressing, I think, some of the core drivers of migration, which are lack of economic opportunities and insecurity.</p>
<p>I will say also there is just a robust initiative to combat smuggling in there as well.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>But at the – at its core, what this is, is something that is unprecedented in that the leaders of the region that are either source, transit, or destination countries for migration are really coming together behind a plan that recognizes that the migration challenge is not one that is – that is at the U.S. border, but it’s one that is actually impacting all the countries in the Americas, and that we need to work together to address it in a way that treats migrants with dignity, invests in creating opportunities that would dissuade migrants from leaving their homes in the first place, and provide the protections that migrants deserve.</p>
<p><b>Assistant Secretary Nichols:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Yeah, I’ll just add to that that this builds on Secretary Blinken’s participation in co-hosting of ministerial-level meetings in Colombia and Panama to talk about this unprecedented challenge globally.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>There are more than 94 million people on the move as migrants.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>This poses a challenge to nations around the world, but particularly in our own hemisphere.</p>
<p>And this declaration is going to allow us to focus on promoting stabilization in communities that are hosting migrants; helping those communities and the migrants that they are hosting; ensuring things like access to legal documentation and public services; promoting pathways for legal, orderly migration when appropriate; to ensure ethical recruitment for employment, for example; promoting humane migration management; and a shared approach to mitigating and managing irregular migration.</p>
<p>Those are some of the things that we’re focusing on.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And it builds on not only the ministerial meetings that have taken place, but the many agreements that have come both within our region and around the world to promote safe, orderly, humane migration.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Our next question, we’ll go to Rafael Mathus from <i>La Nacion</i>.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Operator, please open line 30.</p>
<p><b>Question:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Thank you very much for doing this call and for taking my question.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>About the invitations for Cuba, Nicaragua, Venezuela, and so on, Juan, can you specifically say what are the final considerations of the government on this topic, because it has been discussed for several months now?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And what are your thoughts on the damage these issues are creating on both the summit and the agenda of the summit?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thanks.</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Well, look, I mean, I’m not going to get into the specifics of the considerations because I think fundamentally what this administration has done, whether it’s on this topic or on any topic, is treated the countries of the region as our partners that – whose views we have to take into serious account.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And certainly with Mexico and with others that have expressed a view, we have tried to engage in a conversation and been very respectful of the different perspectives.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And ultimately, it’s something that as the host’s prerogative we’ll make the final decision, and we’ll announce that once the decision has been made.</p>
<p>Is it a distraction from the summit itself?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Look, I don’t think so.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>It’s hard to, I think, confirm anything until it actually happens.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>But we are really confident that the summit will be well-attended, that our relationship with Mexico is – remains and will continue to remain positive.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We very much want President Lopez Obrador there.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The President of the United States very personally wants the President of Mexico there.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And that I think once folks see what is announced at the summit we’ll see that we’re really actually addressing, I think, what are rising to the challenge that is – that are many of the different economic, pandemic-related, and other challenges that the region is facing.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So I think we’ll let the results speak for themselves.</p>
<p><b>Assistant Secretary Nichols:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Yeah, I’d just like to add that we’re very much focused on addressing the issues that affect people in their daily lives in our hemisphere.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We will have attendance from leaders throughout our hemisphere, but we’re also going to have attendance from private sector leaders and CEOs, from members of civil society, from youth from across the hemisphere.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>They are coming together in an unprecedented way, literally thousands of people, to talk about the issues of concern that affect people in their daily lives.</p>
<p>Can they get access to health care?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Can their kids get a good education?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Do they have the economic opportunities they need?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Are they able to benefit from broadband internet technology?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>What are we doing to mitigate the shock caused by Russia’s invasion of Ukraine and ensure people have reliable, affordable access to food?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And what are we doing to reorient supply chains to make sure that the disruptions that we’ve seen over the past few years are not repeated?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I think that’s what average people care about, and that’s what we’re focused on.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We will now go to Raquel Krahenbul from TV Globo.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Operator, please open line 7.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Question:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Yes, hello.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I am with Raquel.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>She is just out of the room for one minute.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Can you please call on her in just another minute?</p>
<p><b>Moderator:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Sure.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Operator, thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We will now go to Priscilla Alvarez from CNN.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We go to line 61, please.</p>
<p><b>Question:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Hi.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>Moderator:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Yes.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Please go ahead.</p>
<p><b>Question:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Thank you for doing this.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>You mention throughout the call that this is about creating regional partnership to address issues systemic to the hemisphere.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>But if you are missing key partners like Mexico or Guatemala, Honduras, El Salvador, how do you – do you anticipate success or an outcome from this?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I mean, those are key partners.</p>
<p>And then also you mentioned earlier, and I just want to clarify, the Mexican president’s request that Cuba attend the summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Is that currently the state of play with those discussions, whether Cuba attends, and no longer a discussion about Nicaragua and Venezuela?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Sure.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I mean, I’ll be brief, and then Brian will have his views.</p>
<p>Look, I mean, with Mexico and those others, we have made very clear that participation won’t impact cooperation or even a level of ambition certainly before – well before the summit.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>On the issue of migration, we’ve had very close cooperation with Mexico, and that will continue to be the case.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And just again on the invitations, we’re just – we’re still looking through – it’s continuing to engage in conversations with different countries.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And once we make a final decision, we’ll make an announcement.</p>
<p><b>Assistant Secretary Nichols: </b> I’ll just add that countries throughout our hemisphere have been playing an active role in the Summit Implementation Review Group negotiation of the five political commitments that will be approved at the summit, and that includes Mexico.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The engagement across many levels, from ambassadors and department representatives to the Organization of American States to senior ministry officials to foreign ministers, around the goals for this summit has been active and intense and very constructive.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And I think we’re going to leave this summit with an incredibly strong mandate from this hemisphere to work on the issues that matter to people.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We will now go to Jaqueline Charles from <i>The Miami Herald</i>.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Operator, please open line 83.</p>
<p><b>Question:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Hi, thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>In regards to Haiti, which today is undergoing multiple crises and we are seeing it playing itself out with the migration both at the land and the sea borders, what will be a specific message or focus as far as Haiti is concerned during this summit, and what can we expect as far as deliverables in regard to Haiti?</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Brian, do you want to take this?</p>
<p><b>Assistant Secretary Nichols:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So we’re focused on a number of things that will benefit Haiti.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Access to health care is one.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Changes to the way that we approach our engagement on some economic issues to ensure that we’re leveraging all the tools that we can to support partner nations throughout our hemisphere, which will benefit Haiti.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Obviously, migration is an area where we have to do more to support and engage Haiti, and I think we’re going to have some interesting things in that area.</p>
<p>And then more broadly, the commitments around democracy will benefit Haiti as it moves towards elections in the future, things like strengthening electoral oversight authorities in our hemisphere, support to candidates and political parties, respect for the role of ombudsmen and transparency-related authorities in country – all are directly applicable to Haiti.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And by taking those commitments and working them both bilaterally with Haiti among the countries of our hemisphere, multilaterally through the Organization of American States, through UN bodies, I think we’re going to be able to translate this into specific and concrete further assistance for the Haitian people who need it very much.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We will now go to Beatriz Bulla from Estradao.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Operator, please open line 63.</p>
<p><b>Question:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Hi, thank you all for doing this.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So I’d like to ask about the position of the Brazilian president, Jair Bolsonaro.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>You mention that the summit will discuss the core challenges to the people of the hemisphere, and democracy is one of them.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I’ll like to ask if President Biden wants to raise concerns or express his confidence on the Brazilian electoral process, considering that President Bolsonaro has made some comments about the Brazilian electoral process, and also because last year when the NSA Jake Sullivan was here in Brazil with Bolsonaro, you – the U.S. expressed great confidence in the Brazilian institutions and society with Bolsonaro, the importance of not undermining trust in this process.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So is the Brazilian electoral – is it going to be a topic during the summit or during the bilateral meeting with Biden and Bolsonaro?</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So I’ll say the issue of the Brazilian elections is really up for the Brazilians to decide, and the United States does have confidence in Brazil’s electoral institutions, which have proved robust.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And – but the conversation with – between the President and President Bolsonaro is going to cover a wide range of topics that are bilateral and, frankly, global in nature given the importance of the U.S. relationship.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So whether it’s tackling food insecurity and economic response to the pandemic, health and health security, every single priority for the summit that we have are areas where Brazil plays an incredibly important role.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The topic of climate change as well is something that the President has made clear is a priority, is something that’s – so there is a very long list of issues that are going to be up for discussion between the President and President Bolsonaro.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We have time for one last question.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The last question goes to Jorge Agobian from Voice of America.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Operator, please open line 48.</p>
<p><b>Question:</b><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you so much for doing this.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We really appreciate it.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I have a question.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>If the United States recognizes the government of Juan Guaido in Venezuela as the legit government of that country, why are there still additional considerations to be decided in this specific point?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And why haven’t they been invited to the summit, and how should it be interpreted?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Then, if they were not invited as the representative of Venezuelan government, if U.S. actually recognizes Guaido as the president?</p>
<p><b>Mr. Gonzalez:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>Thank you.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So the United States does continue to recognize interim President Juan Guaido as the legitimately elected president of the – of the national assembly, which was the last democratically elected institution in that country.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And we engage actively with him, with his ambassador and his government as well as the representatives of the unity platform and we’re actually supporting a dialogue that produces outcomes that lead to free and fair elections in the country.</p>
<p>I’m not going to talk about the considerations with regard to invitations except to just underscore that there are – governments have different views on some of these topics, and we engage and consult with them.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>And ultimately the host prerogative is important, but we also are wanting to facilitate a broad hemispheric discussion and want to make sure that we’re integrating all of the views of the members of the Organization of American States.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>So again, we’re – for us, it’s most important that we’re gathering together and that the focus is on our collective responsibility to forge a more inclusive and prosperous future for the hemisphere, and that includes one for the people of Venezuela.</p>
<p><b>Moderator:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span></b>That concludes today’s call.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I want to thank Senior Director Gonzalez and Assistant Secretary Nichols for joining us and thank all of our callers for participating.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>If you have any questions about today’s call, you may contact the Miami Media Hub at MiamiHub@state.gov.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Thank you and have a good day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Promoting Accountability and Imposing Costs on the Russian Federation and Its Enablers for Putin’s Aggression Against Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/promoting-accountability-and-imposing-costs-on-the-russian-federation-and-its-enablers-for-putins-aggression-against-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 14:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=349052</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department of State is taking additional steps to target Russia’s oligarchs and elites, in close coordination with partners and allies, with the goal of imposing severe costs on the Government of the Russian Federation and limiting the Kremlin’s ability to fund Putin’s war of aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p><b><u>INDIVIDUALS AND ENTITIES DESIGNATED BY THE STATE DEPARTMENT</u></b></p>
<ul>
<li>God Nisanov, an oligarch with close ties to numerous Russian officials, is being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 section 1(a)(vii). Nisanov is a real estate investor and one of the richest people in Europe.</li>
<li>Evgeny Novitskiy, a Russian elite with close ties to the Government of Russia, is being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 section 1(a)(vii).</li>
<li>Maria Zakharova is being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 section 1(a)(iii)(A) for her role as an official of the Government of the Russian Federation as the spokesperson for the Foreign Ministry. The EU, UK, Japan, Australia, and New Zealand have previously designated Maria Zakharova.</li>
<li>Sergey Gorkov, the head of RosGeo and a former executive of sanctioned banks, is being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 section 1(a)(iii)(A) for his involvement in the Government of the Russian Federation via RosGeo.</li>
<li>Severgroup is a multi-billion-dollar Russia’s investment company with holdings and subsidiaries in metallurgy, engineering, mining, tourism, banking, technology, media, and finance, among other sectors. Severgroup is being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 Section 1(a)(i) because it operates or has operated in the financial services sector of the Russian Federation economy.</li>
<li>Alexey Mordashov, the leader of Severgroup Limited Liability Company and one of Russia’s wealthiest billionaires, is being designated, pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024, for being a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of Severgroup, an entity whose property or interests in property are blocked pursuant to E.O. 14024 section 1(a)(i). The EU, Australia, New Zealand, and the UK previously designated Alexey Mordashov.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Family members of Alexey Mordashov who are being designated pursuant to section 1(a)(v) of E.O. 14024 for being the spouse or adult child of a person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to section 1(a)(ii) or 1(a)(iii) of E.O. 14024 are:
<ul>
<li>Marina Mordashova</li>
<li>Nikita Mordashov</li>
<li>Kirill Mordashov</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Entities designated for relation to Alexey Mordashov include:
<ul>
<li>Severstal is among Russia’s leading domestic steel producers. Severstal is being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 Section 1(a)(vii) because it is owned or controlled by Alexey Mordashov, a person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
<li>Algoritm is a holding company that controls dozens of Russian technology, media, and advertising companies. Algoritm is being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 section 1(a)(vii) because it is owned or controlled by Alexey Mordashov, a person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
<li>Nord Gold is a gold mining company with assets and operations around the world, including in the Russian Federation, Burkina Faso, French Guiana, Guinea, Kazakhstan, and Canada. Nord Gold is being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 section 1(a)(vii) because it is owned or controlled by Alexey Mordashov, a person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>In addition, the Department of the Treasury issued two new general licenses (“GL”) and amended one GL in connection with the Department’s designations of Severstal, Nord Gold, and Alogritm. Specifically:
<ul>
<li>Under GL 36, all transactions prohibited by E.O. 14024 that are ordinarily incident and necessary to the wind down of transactions involving Public Joint Stock Company Severstal or any entity in which Public Joint Stock Company Severstal owns, directly or indirectly, a 50 percent or greater interest, are authorized through 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time, August 31, 2022, provided that any payment to Public Joint Stock Company Severstal or any other blocked person must be made into a blocked account in accordance with the Russian Harmful Foreign Activities Sanctions Regulations, 31 CFR part 587 (RuHSR)</li>
<li>Under GL 37, all transactions prohibited by E.O. 14024 that are ordinarily incident and necessary to the wind down of transactions involving Nord Gold PLC, or any entity in which Nord Gold PLC owns, directly or indirectly, a 50 percent or greater interest, are authorized through 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time, July 1, 2022, provided that any payment to Nord Gold PLC or any other blocked person must be made into a blocked account in accordance with the RuHSR.</li>
<li>GL 25 was amended to exclude Algorithm, an entity that will be designated pursuant to E.O. 14024, from the scope of the authorization. GL 25 authorizes all transactions ordinarily incident and necessary to the receipt or transmission of telecommunications involving the Russian Federation that are prohibited by the RuHSR.  Additionally, GL 25 authorizes the exportation or re-exportation, sale, or supply, directly or indirectly, from the United States or by U.S. persons, wherever located, to the Russian Federation of services, software, hardware, or technology incident to the exchange of communications over the internet, such as instant messaging, videoconferencing, chat and email, social networking, sharing of photos, movies, and documents, web browsing, blogging, web hosting, and domain name registration services, that is prohibited by the RuHSR.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><b><u>SANCTIONS IMPLICATIONS</u></b></p>
<p>The Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) will add the entities and vessels above to the list of Specially Designated Nationals and Blocked Persons.  As a result of today’s action, all property and interests in property of the entities above that are in the United States or in the possession or control of U.S. persons are blocked and must be reported to OFAC.  In addition, any entities that are owned, directly or indirectly, 50 percent or more by one or more blocked persons are also blocked.  All transactions by U.S. persons or within (or transiting) the United States that involve any property or interests in property of designated or otherwise blocked persons are prohibited unless authorized by a general or specific license issued by OFAC or exempt.  These prohibitions include the making of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services by, to, or for the benefit of any blocked person and the receipt of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services from any such person.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department of State is taking additional steps to target Russia’s oligarchs and elites, in close coordination with partners and allies, with the goal of imposing severe costs on the Government of the Russian Federation and limiting the Kremlin’s ability to fund Putin’s war of aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p><b><u>INDIVIDUALS AND ENTITIES DESIGNATED BY THE STATE DEPARTMENT</u></b></p>
<ul>
<li>God Nisanov, an oligarch with close ties to numerous Russian officials, is being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 section 1(a)(vii). Nisanov is a real estate investor and one of the richest people in Europe.</li>
<li>Evgeny Novitskiy, a Russian elite with close ties to the Government of Russia, is being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 section 1(a)(vii).</li>
<li>Maria Zakharova is being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 section 1(a)(iii)(A) for her role as an official of the Government of the Russian Federation as the spokesperson for the Foreign Ministry. The EU, UK, Japan, Australia, and New Zealand have previously designated Maria Zakharova.</li>
<li>Sergey Gorkov, the head of RosGeo and a former executive of sanctioned banks, is being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 section 1(a)(iii)(A) for his involvement in the Government of the Russian Federation via RosGeo.</li>
<li>Severgroup is a multi-billion-dollar Russia’s investment company with holdings and subsidiaries in metallurgy, engineering, mining, tourism, banking, technology, media, and finance, among other sectors. Severgroup is being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 Section 1(a)(i) because it operates or has operated in the financial services sector of the Russian Federation economy.</li>
<li>Alexey Mordashov, the leader of Severgroup Limited Liability Company and one of Russia’s wealthiest billionaires, is being designated, pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024, for being a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of Severgroup, an entity whose property or interests in property are blocked pursuant to E.O. 14024 section 1(a)(i). The EU, Australia, New Zealand, and the UK previously designated Alexey Mordashov.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Family members of Alexey Mordashov who are being designated pursuant to section 1(a)(v) of E.O. 14024 for being the spouse or adult child of a person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to section 1(a)(ii) or 1(a)(iii) of E.O. 14024 are:
<ul>
<li>Marina Mordashova</li>
<li>Nikita Mordashov</li>
<li>Kirill Mordashov</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Entities designated for relation to Alexey Mordashov include:
<ul>
<li>Severstal is among Russia’s leading domestic steel producers. Severstal is being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 Section 1(a)(vii) because it is owned or controlled by Alexey Mordashov, a person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
<li>Algoritm is a holding company that controls dozens of Russian technology, media, and advertising companies. Algoritm is being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 section 1(a)(vii) because it is owned or controlled by Alexey Mordashov, a person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
<li>Nord Gold is a gold mining company with assets and operations around the world, including in the Russian Federation, Burkina Faso, French Guiana, Guinea, Kazakhstan, and Canada. Nord Gold is being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 section 1(a)(vii) because it is owned or controlled by Alexey Mordashov, a person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>In addition, the Department of the Treasury issued two new general licenses (“GL”) and amended one GL in connection with the Department’s designations of Severstal, Nord Gold, and Alogritm. Specifically:
<ul>
<li>Under GL 36, all transactions prohibited by E.O. 14024 that are ordinarily incident and necessary to the wind down of transactions involving Public Joint Stock Company Severstal or any entity in which Public Joint Stock Company Severstal owns, directly or indirectly, a 50 percent or greater interest, are authorized through 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time, August 31, 2022, provided that any payment to Public Joint Stock Company Severstal or any other blocked person must be made into a blocked account in accordance with the Russian Harmful Foreign Activities Sanctions Regulations, 31 CFR part 587 (RuHSR)</li>
<li>Under GL 37, all transactions prohibited by E.O. 14024 that are ordinarily incident and necessary to the wind down of transactions involving Nord Gold PLC, or any entity in which Nord Gold PLC owns, directly or indirectly, a 50 percent or greater interest, are authorized through 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time, July 1, 2022, provided that any payment to Nord Gold PLC or any other blocked person must be made into a blocked account in accordance with the RuHSR.</li>
<li>GL 25 was amended to exclude Algorithm, an entity that will be designated pursuant to E.O. 14024, from the scope of the authorization. GL 25 authorizes all transactions ordinarily incident and necessary to the receipt or transmission of telecommunications involving the Russian Federation that are prohibited by the RuHSR.  Additionally, GL 25 authorizes the exportation or re-exportation, sale, or supply, directly or indirectly, from the United States or by U.S. persons, wherever located, to the Russian Federation of services, software, hardware, or technology incident to the exchange of communications over the internet, such as instant messaging, videoconferencing, chat and email, social networking, sharing of photos, movies, and documents, web browsing, blogging, web hosting, and domain name registration services, that is prohibited by the RuHSR.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><b><u>SANCTIONS IMPLICATIONS</u></b></p>
<p>The Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) will add the entities and vessels above to the list of Specially Designated Nationals and Blocked Persons.  As a result of today’s action, all property and interests in property of the entities above that are in the United States or in the possession or control of U.S. persons are blocked and must be reported to OFAC.  In addition, any entities that are owned, directly or indirectly, 50 percent or more by one or more blocked persons are also blocked.  All transactions by U.S. persons or within (or transiting) the United States that involve any property or interests in property of designated or otherwise blocked persons are prohibited unless authorized by a general or specific license issued by OFAC or exempt.  These prohibitions include the making of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services by, to, or for the benefit of any blocked person and the receipt of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services from any such person.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Action Plan on Global Water Security</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-action-plan-on-global-water-security/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 13:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=348990</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Water is the source of life, and it nurtures and sustains livelihoods and civilizations. Secure and sustainable access to safe water is an essential element of national security, and the Department of State is working together with our partners and allies to facilitate water cooperation and engagement on water management across our development programming and diplomatic efforts.  – is fundamental to human well-being and central to international peace and national security. When water is scarce, it becomes more difficult for communities to produce food, to prevent the spread of disease and protect public health, and to drive economic growth.  Water stress contributes to regional instability, drives mass migration, and can lead to broader conflict.</p>
<p>Vice President Harris launched the <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MDIuNTg3OTE3NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2djYzAyLnNhZmVsaW5rcy5wcm90ZWN0aW9uLm91dGxvb2suY29tLz91cmw9aHR0cHMlM0ElMkYlMkZ3d3cud2hpdGVob3VzZS5nb3YlMkZ3cC1jb250ZW50JTJGdXBsb2FkcyUyRjIwMjIlMkYwNiUyRndhdGVyLWFjdGlvbi1wbGFuX2ZpbmFsX2Zvcm1hdHRlZC5wZGYmZGF0YT0wNSU3QzAxJTdDUGVhYm9keVZXJTQwc3RhdGUuZ292JTdDNTAxOWI1MWI0MGZlNDA4MGEwMGEwOGRhNDQzNGUxYjIlN0M2NmNmNTA3NDVhZmU0OGQxYTY5MWExMmIyMTIxZjQ0YiU3QzAlN0MwJTdDNjM3ODk3MjkxMTY3MzkzMTg0JTdDVW5rbm93biU3Q1RXRnBiR1pzYjNkOGV5SldJam9pTUM0d0xqQXdNREFpTENKUUlqb2lWMmx1TXpJaUxDSkJUaUk2SWsxaGFXd2lMQ0pYVkNJNk1uMCUzRCU3QzMwMDAlN0MlN0MlN0Mmc2RhdGE9ZE5SaEtmOHl5Tmh5NndVVEl5VG1JaE51TzEwJTJCR0s3dVBET1hCZVN2NUZrJTNEJnJlc2VydmVkPTAifQ.9IzUUZvrnw57g-WRMEObLKQ8npj0t25D-NDq5vFt13E/s/1436012980/br/132284022753-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MDIuNTg3OTE3NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2djYzAyLnNhZmVsaW5rcy5wcm90ZWN0aW9uLm91dGxvb2suY29tLz91cmw9aHR0cHMlM0ElMkYlMkZ3d3cud2hpdGVob3VzZS5nb3YlMkZ3cC1jb250ZW50JTJGdXBsb2FkcyUyRjIwMjIlMkYwNiUyRndhdGVyLWFjdGlvbi1wbGFuX2ZpbmFsX2Zvcm1hdHRlZC5wZGYmZGF0YT0wNSU3QzAxJTdDUGVhYm9keVZXJTQwc3RhdGUuZ292JTdDNTAxOWI1MWI0MGZlNDA4MGEwMGEwOGRhNDQzNGUxYjIlN0M2NmNmNTA3NDVhZmU0OGQxYTY5MWExMmIyMTIxZjQ0YiU3QzAlN0MwJTdDNjM3ODk3MjkxMTY3MzkzMTg0JTdDVW5rbm93biU3Q1RXRnBiR1pzYjNkOGV5SldJam9pTUM0d0xqQXdNREFpTENKUUlqb2lWMmx1TXpJaUxDSkJUaUk2SWsxaGFXd2lMQ0pYVkNJNk1uMCUzRCU3QzMwMDAlN0MlN0MlN0Mmc2RhdGE9ZE5SaEtmOHl5Tmh5NndVVEl5VG1JaE51TzEwJTJCR0s3dVBET1hCZVN2NUZrJTNEJnJlc2VydmVkPTAifQ.9IzUUZvrnw57g-WRMEObLKQ8npj0t25D-NDq5vFt13E%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F132284022753-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C6cc48c70d7bd4d0de9bf08da4498fd42%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C1%7C637897721122137965%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=Oc1hUGuZpb25K6%2B%2BLzDHIecUx7MLbNognP27fXhQbOk%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="0">White House Action Plan on Global Water Security</a>, a landmark whole-of-government effort to achieve a water-secure world.  The plan covers the full spectrum of global water issues and advances United States leadership on water security.</p>
<p>Secure and sustainable access to safe water is an essential element of national security, and the Department of State is working together with our partners and allies to facilitate water cooperation and engagement on water management across our development programming and diplomatic efforts.  Through the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs’ Office of Conservation and Water, we are coordinating with the U.S. Agency for International Development to update the U.S. Global Water Strategy, which outlines a whole-of-government approach to create a more water-secure world, where people and nations have the water they need to be healthy, prosperous, and resilient.</p>
<p>As the Vice President said, water scarcity is a global problem, and the State Department, together with our partners, will work to help achieve a global solution.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Water is the source of life, and it nurtures and sustains livelihoods and civilizations. Secure and sustainable access to safe water is an essential element of national security, and the Department of State is working together with our partners and allies to facilitate water cooperation and engagement on water management across our development programming and diplomatic efforts.  – is fundamental to human well-being and central to international peace and national security. When water is scarce, it becomes more difficult for communities to produce food, to prevent the spread of disease and protect public health, and to drive economic growth.  Water stress contributes to regional instability, drives mass migration, and can lead to broader conflict.</p>
<p>Vice President Harris launched the <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MDIuNTg3OTE3NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2djYzAyLnNhZmVsaW5rcy5wcm90ZWN0aW9uLm91dGxvb2suY29tLz91cmw9aHR0cHMlM0ElMkYlMkZ3d3cud2hpdGVob3VzZS5nb3YlMkZ3cC1jb250ZW50JTJGdXBsb2FkcyUyRjIwMjIlMkYwNiUyRndhdGVyLWFjdGlvbi1wbGFuX2ZpbmFsX2Zvcm1hdHRlZC5wZGYmZGF0YT0wNSU3QzAxJTdDUGVhYm9keVZXJTQwc3RhdGUuZ292JTdDNTAxOWI1MWI0MGZlNDA4MGEwMGEwOGRhNDQzNGUxYjIlN0M2NmNmNTA3NDVhZmU0OGQxYTY5MWExMmIyMTIxZjQ0YiU3QzAlN0MwJTdDNjM3ODk3MjkxMTY3MzkzMTg0JTdDVW5rbm93biU3Q1RXRnBiR1pzYjNkOGV5SldJam9pTUM0d0xqQXdNREFpTENKUUlqb2lWMmx1TXpJaUxDSkJUaUk2SWsxaGFXd2lMQ0pYVkNJNk1uMCUzRCU3QzMwMDAlN0MlN0MlN0Mmc2RhdGE9ZE5SaEtmOHl5Tmh5NndVVEl5VG1JaE51TzEwJTJCR0s3dVBET1hCZVN2NUZrJTNEJnJlc2VydmVkPTAifQ.9IzUUZvrnw57g-WRMEObLKQ8npj0t25D-NDq5vFt13E/s/1436012980/br/132284022753-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MDIuNTg3OTE3NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2djYzAyLnNhZmVsaW5rcy5wcm90ZWN0aW9uLm91dGxvb2suY29tLz91cmw9aHR0cHMlM0ElMkYlMkZ3d3cud2hpdGVob3VzZS5nb3YlMkZ3cC1jb250ZW50JTJGdXBsb2FkcyUyRjIwMjIlMkYwNiUyRndhdGVyLWFjdGlvbi1wbGFuX2ZpbmFsX2Zvcm1hdHRlZC5wZGYmZGF0YT0wNSU3QzAxJTdDUGVhYm9keVZXJTQwc3RhdGUuZ292JTdDNTAxOWI1MWI0MGZlNDA4MGEwMGEwOGRhNDQzNGUxYjIlN0M2NmNmNTA3NDVhZmU0OGQxYTY5MWExMmIyMTIxZjQ0YiU3QzAlN0MwJTdDNjM3ODk3MjkxMTY3MzkzMTg0JTdDVW5rbm93biU3Q1RXRnBiR1pzYjNkOGV5SldJam9pTUM0d0xqQXdNREFpTENKUUlqb2lWMmx1TXpJaUxDSkJUaUk2SWsxaGFXd2lMQ0pYVkNJNk1uMCUzRCU3QzMwMDAlN0MlN0MlN0Mmc2RhdGE9ZE5SaEtmOHl5Tmh5NndVVEl5VG1JaE51TzEwJTJCR0s3dVBET1hCZVN2NUZrJTNEJnJlc2VydmVkPTAifQ.9IzUUZvrnw57g-WRMEObLKQ8npj0t25D-NDq5vFt13E%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F132284022753-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C6cc48c70d7bd4d0de9bf08da4498fd42%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C1%7C637897721122137965%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=Oc1hUGuZpb25K6%2B%2BLzDHIecUx7MLbNognP27fXhQbOk%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="0">White House Action Plan on Global Water Security</a>, a landmark whole-of-government effort to achieve a water-secure world.  The plan covers the full spectrum of global water issues and advances United States leadership on water security.</p>
<p>Secure and sustainable access to safe water is an essential element of national security, and the Department of State is working together with our partners and allies to facilitate water cooperation and engagement on water management across our development programming and diplomatic efforts.  Through the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs’ Office of Conservation and Water, we are coordinating with the U.S. Agency for International Development to update the U.S. Global Water Strategy, which outlines a whole-of-government approach to create a more water-secure world, where people and nations have the water they need to be healthy, prosperous, and resilient.</p>
<p>As the Vice President said, water scarcity is a global problem, and the State Department, together with our partners, will work to help achieve a global solution.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On the Occasion of Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II&#8217;s Platinum Jubilee and Official Birthday</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/on-the-occasion-of-her-majesty-queen-elizabeth-iis-platinum-jubilee-and-official-birthday/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 04:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=348917</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II and the people of the United Kingdom on the occasion of Her Majesty’s Platinum Jubilee and official birthday.</p>
<p>Her Majesty’s unprecedented 70 years of service to the United Kingdom are an inspiration to Americans, who deeply admire the Queen and are grateful for her decades of friendship with the United States.  Through our special relationship, common history, and shared values, we work together to uphold democracy, human rights, and the rule of law worldwide.  Our countries collaborate closely on virtually every significant challenge and opportunity the world over precisely because we have no closer partner.</p>
<p>The United States joins the British people in celebrating this historic and joyous occasion.  I send my heartfelt wishes for peace, prosperity, and good health to Her Majesty and all the people across the United Kingdom.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II and the people of the United Kingdom on the occasion of Her Majesty’s Platinum Jubilee and official birthday.</p>
<p>Her Majesty’s unprecedented 70 years of service to the United Kingdom are an inspiration to Americans, who deeply admire the Queen and are grateful for her decades of friendship with the United States.  Through our special relationship, common history, and shared values, we work together to uphold democracy, human rights, and the rule of law worldwide.  Our countries collaborate closely on virtually every significant challenge and opportunity the world over precisely because we have no closer partner.</p>
<p>The United States joins the British people in celebrating this historic and joyous occasion.  I send my heartfelt wishes for peace, prosperity, and good health to Her Majesty and all the people across the United Kingdom.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Anniversary of the Founding of the Italian Republic</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-anniversary-of-the-founding-of-the-italian-republic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 04:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=348892</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Italy on the 76th anniversary of the founding of the Italian Republic.</p>
<p>On this day, Italy and the United States celebrate our shared heritage and values including freedom, democracy, rule of law, and our flourishing cultural ties. Millions of Americans proudly claim Italian heritage and family, a testament to the enduring relationship between our two nations and the mutual commitments that we hold dear.</p>
<p>Italy and the United States are committed partners on a range of global issues – defense cooperation, energy security and the green transition, food security, and more. Italy continues to play a key role as we work together to counter Russia’s aggression, support the people of Ukraine, and hold Putin to account. We honor Italy’s role as a vital NATO Ally, committed to our common ideal of a free and prosperous Europe.</p>
<p>I extend my best wishes to the Italian people on this day of celebration.</p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Italy on the 76th anniversary of the founding of the Italian Republic.</p>
<p>On this day, Italy and the United States celebrate our shared heritage and values including freedom, democracy, rule of law, and our flourishing cultural ties. Millions of Americans proudly claim Italian heritage and family, a testament to the enduring relationship between our two nations and the mutual commitments that we hold dear.</p>
<p>Italy and the United States are committed partners on a range of global issues – defense cooperation, energy security and the green transition, food security, and more. Italy continues to play a key role as we work together to counter Russia’s aggression, support the people of Ukraine, and hold Putin to account. We honor Italy’s role as a vital NATO Ally, committed to our common ideal of a free and prosperous Europe.</p>
<p>I extend my best wishes to the Italian people on this day of celebration.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcoming the Resumption of Flights Between Sana’a, Yemen and Cairo, Egypt</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/welcoming-the-resumption-of-flights-between-sanaa-yemen-and-cairo-egypt/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 22:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=348890</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes today’s flight between Sana’a, Yemen, and Cairo, Egypt, which enables more Yemenis to seek medical care, pursue educational opportunities, and see loved ones from across Egypt’s diverse Yemeni diaspora community.  The United States appreciates the Government of Egypt’s efforts to facilitate these flights, along with the Governments of Yemen and Saudi Arabia.  The United States reiterates its strong support for the efforts of UN Special Envoy Hans Grundberg, and our collective work has resulted in the most significant progress toward peace in years.</p>
<p>While we are encouraged by the resumption of flights from Sana’a and expanded flow of fuel into northern Yemen, there is much more work needed to improve the freedom of movement of people and goods inside Yemen, particularly to the city of Taiz, where hundreds of thousands of Yemenis have suffered for far too long.</p>
<p>The truce has provided tangible relief to Yemenis, improving the lives of millions, demonstrating the benefits of peace, and giving hope that an end to this conflict is possible.  The United States urges all parties to seize this pivotal moment, listen to the demands of the people, maintain support for the truce, and build towards a comprehensive peace process.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes today’s flight between Sana’a, Yemen, and Cairo, Egypt, which enables more Yemenis to seek medical care, pursue educational opportunities, and see loved ones from across Egypt’s diverse Yemeni diaspora community.  The United States appreciates the Government of Egypt’s efforts to facilitate these flights, along with the Governments of Yemen and Saudi Arabia.  The United States reiterates its strong support for the efforts of UN Special Envoy Hans Grundberg, and our collective work has resulted in the most significant progress toward peace in years.</p>
<p>While we are encouraged by the resumption of flights from Sana’a and expanded flow of fuel into northern Yemen, there is much more work needed to improve the freedom of movement of people and goods inside Yemen, particularly to the city of Taiz, where hundreds of thousands of Yemenis have suffered for far too long.</p>
<p>The truce has provided tangible relief to Yemenis, improving the lives of millions, demonstrating the benefits of peace, and giving hope that an end to this conflict is possible.  The United States urges all parties to seize this pivotal moment, listen to the demands of the people, maintain support for the truce, and build towards a comprehensive peace process.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
