<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 03:46:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro Mayorkas Opening Remarks at the Ministerial Conference on Migration and Protection Reception</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-secretary-of-homeland-security-alejandro-mayorkas-opening-remarks-at-the-ministerial-conference-on-migration-and-protection-reception/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 03:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335608</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Panama City, Panama</p>
<p>Ministry of Foreign Affairs</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.  Good evening, everyone.  It is wonderful to be with so many colleagues in this extraordinary setting with this extraordinary history, as Erika was just describing it to us.  I very much want to thank President Cortizo, my friend the foreign minister, the people of Panama, for so generously hosting us for this week’s Ministerial Conference on Migration and Protection.  And a special note of gratitude to Panama, to you, Erika, for all the work that you’ve been doing to bring all of us together in what has to be a shared responsibility.</p>
<p>I am joined here by my friend and colleague, Ale Mayorkas, the Secretary of Homeland Security of the United States.  We’re both so eager to discuss with our fellow ministers the urgent migration challenges that we’re facing.  No two countries experience them in the same way.  All of us bring our own concerns to this discussion but also this sense of shared responsibility to meet the migration challenge throughout our region.  And we’re very much looking forward to hearing and sharing specific experiences and specific solutions.</p>
<p>This issue is a priority for the United States.  We have a strong interest in protecting the security of our borders in a safe, orderly, and humane way.  We care about the well-being of millions of people across the hemisphere who have made the desperate decision to leave their homes and communities in search of a better life.  The journeys are often dangerous.  Migrants are vulnerable to exploitation of all kinds.  Many are children, and their fates, their futures, are highly uncertain.  We have a responsibility, a shared responsibility, to look out for them.</p>
<p>Like you, we’re concerned about the rising tensions in communities across the region that have become home to huge numbers of migrants and are now pushed to the brink, unable to meet people’s needs, whether they’re migrants or their own citizens.  And we’re focused on the underlying issues that are pushing so many people to become migrants in the first place, including poverty, a lack of economic opportunity, corruption, political upheaval, insecurity – all of which has been made worse by the climate crisis and, of course, by COVID-19.</p>
<p>So I think what we have all come to understand, the common realization that I think is shared with everyone in this room, is that no one country can meet these challenges or solve them alone.  The United States is committed to working in partnership with all of you across every dimension of this issue from taking on migrant smuggling networks, to improving humane and effective border management, to countering misinformation, to developing legal pathways for immigrants and refugees seeking a safe place to call home.</p>
<p>In particular, we have to work together to help stabilize and strengthen communities that are hosting large populations of migrants.  We have to help them get the tools that they need to rebuild their lives, including access to jobs and education.  And we have to make sure that our support directly benefits the communities themselves with increased resources for public health and safety, social services, better infrastructure, opportunity for everyone.</p>
<p>So this has to be a job for all of us, for our governments, doing it together.  But it’s also a job for the international community writ large – NGOs, multilateral development and financial institutions, regional and global public health and climate agencies.  The United States will help bring together these different groups and leverage all of their contributions to this challenge.</p>
<p>I have to tell you I’m very glad to see here tonight and tomorrow as we meet representatives from key organizations, including the Inter-American Development Bank, the World Bank, the UN High Commissioner for Refugees, UNICEF.  Institutions like these were created to help us meet challenges too great for even our countries together to solve, which is exactly what we’re called on to do now on behalf of the region’s most vulnerable people.  And to those agencies and organizations that have already given and implemented assistance, thank you.</p>
<p>I know that we’ll do good work together here in Panama.  We have to.  And I hope that the additional momentum that we build here, complemented by what we did in Colombia – and my deep appreciation to our colleagues from Colombia for bringing us together some months ago – all of that needs to carry forward in concrete, practical ways.</p>
<p>In June, many of us will come together again in Los Angeles for the Summit of the Americas that President Biden will be hosting.  There we’ll have an opportunity to address the deeper concerns that drive irregular migration by strengthening our democracies, fighting corruption, building resilience in our health care systems, promoting more equitable economic growth, combating the climate crisis.  All of these things in their own ways have an impact on the challenge that we are coming together here tonight and tomorrow to deal with.</p>
<p>President Biden set a goal for the summit that our countries adopt a declaration on migration and protection that sets forth shared principles for a collaborative, coordinated response to migration and forced displacement.  So I hope our discussions here today and tomorrow in Panama will contribute to a strong declaration by our leaders when they gather in California in just a few weeks’ time.</p>
<p>So, simply put, to each and every one of you, thank you for your leadership at what is a critical moment.  Erika said it very well.  There is – we have a regional challenge, a hemispheric challenge, but it’s also a global challenge.  There are now around the world more people on the move, displaced from their homes, than at any time since the Second World War, some 95 million people.  By definition, this is a challenge that we have to stand together to meet, work together to meet, join together to meet.</p>
<p>With that, it is my pleasure to introduce my friend and colleague, the U.S. Secretary of Homeland Security, Alejandro Mayorkas.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b><strong>SECRETARY MAYORKAS:  </strong></b>Thank you and good evening.  My thanks to President Cortizo, Ministers Mouynes and Pino, for welcoming us to this beautiful country.  Earlier today I visited the Panama Canal, and it was a very uplifting visit.  I did so with my colleague and great friend, Tony Blinken.  And the canal represents the promise of economic prosperity and the hope for advancement, and not just today but in the days to come.</p>
<p>Yesterday I had a very different visit.  Minister Pino so generously gave of his time to show my colleagues and me the Darién region and to pass over the treacherous land that the most vulnerable people try to pass in the hope of a better future.  It is very difficult to see that land and to understand the depths and breadth of the treachery that vulnerable individuals seek to cross with the hope of a better life.</p>
<p>I remember a father of a friend of mine growing up who grew up in very difficult circumstances once said that one’s – when one’s back is up against the wall, the only direction one can move in is forward.  And it is our obligation collectively to close the divide between the promise of economic prosperity that the canal represents and the vulnerability that the Darién region represents for so many who seek a better life.  And I want to thank the ministers for bringing us all together to work on an effort that requires a collective response, because the movement of people in the Western Hemisphere, and frankly in other parts of the world, is not the challenge of one country or two; it is the challenge of the region and of the hemisphere of which we are a part.  And we must take a look at the individuals who are vulnerable as members of our community, and we must deliver a response of and by the community.</p>
<p>The most enduring way in which we can address this challenge which has been with us for far too many years is to deliver stabilization, to deliver for the people in their homes the promise that the canal represents, and allow them to understand and actually realize that they do not need to leave their homes to experience the promise that so many of us here represent and are obligated to deliver to others.</p>
<p>At the same time, as we work on that most enduring solution of addressing the cause for migration, we must also extend a hand, an outstretched hand, of humanitarian relief to those who are already outside of their homes to be able to provide them with the promise of that prosperity wherever they might be so that the dangers of the journey that they once anticipated ahead of them they need no longer take.  The promise of humanitarian relief and the stability of settlement and integration, as well as an understanding that the laws that guide our extension of humanitarian relief must be honored, and for those who do not qualify we must apply those laws equally.</p>
<p>These issues and the lines that draw – are drawn between the relief and the response that we must impose when that relief is not warranted are very, very difficult to draw.  They are very difficult decisions, but we as leaders in our respective countries, and together as leaders of a community throughout a region and a hemisphere, are obligated to make those difficult decisions, and that is what makes this convening so very important – bringing us together to make those difficult decisions in partnership and in friendship with one another so that we can deliver the promise of a better future to those who do not see it and so that we can accept this responsibility in a shared and, therefore, most effective way.</p>
<p>I thank you all so very much.  I look forward to our very important conversations tomorrow.  And again, my thanks to our wonderful hosts here in this beautiful country of Panama.  <em>Gracias</em>.  (Applause.)<input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Panama City, Panama</p>
<p>Ministry of Foreign Affairs</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.  Good evening, everyone.  It is wonderful to be with so many colleagues in this extraordinary setting with this extraordinary history, as Erika was just describing it to us.  I very much want to thank President Cortizo, my friend the foreign minister, the people of Panama, for so generously hosting us for this week’s Ministerial Conference on Migration and Protection.  And a special note of gratitude to Panama, to you, Erika, for all the work that you’ve been doing to bring all of us together in what has to be a shared responsibility.</p>
<p>I am joined here by my friend and colleague, Ale Mayorkas, the Secretary of Homeland Security of the United States.  We’re both so eager to discuss with our fellow ministers the urgent migration challenges that we’re facing.  No two countries experience them in the same way.  All of us bring our own concerns to this discussion but also this sense of shared responsibility to meet the migration challenge throughout our region.  And we’re very much looking forward to hearing and sharing specific experiences and specific solutions.</p>
<p>This issue is a priority for the United States.  We have a strong interest in protecting the security of our borders in a safe, orderly, and humane way.  We care about the well-being of millions of people across the hemisphere who have made the desperate decision to leave their homes and communities in search of a better life.  The journeys are often dangerous.  Migrants are vulnerable to exploitation of all kinds.  Many are children, and their fates, their futures, are highly uncertain.  We have a responsibility, a shared responsibility, to look out for them.</p>
<p>Like you, we’re concerned about the rising tensions in communities across the region that have become home to huge numbers of migrants and are now pushed to the brink, unable to meet people’s needs, whether they’re migrants or their own citizens.  And we’re focused on the underlying issues that are pushing so many people to become migrants in the first place, including poverty, a lack of economic opportunity, corruption, political upheaval, insecurity – all of which has been made worse by the climate crisis and, of course, by COVID-19.</p>
<p>So I think what we have all come to understand, the common realization that I think is shared with everyone in this room, is that no one country can meet these challenges or solve them alone.  The United States is committed to working in partnership with all of you across every dimension of this issue from taking on migrant smuggling networks, to improving humane and effective border management, to countering misinformation, to developing legal pathways for immigrants and refugees seeking a safe place to call home.</p>
<p>In particular, we have to work together to help stabilize and strengthen communities that are hosting large populations of migrants.  We have to help them get the tools that they need to rebuild their lives, including access to jobs and education.  And we have to make sure that our support directly benefits the communities themselves with increased resources for public health and safety, social services, better infrastructure, opportunity for everyone.</p>
<p>So this has to be a job for all of us, for our governments, doing it together.  But it’s also a job for the international community writ large – NGOs, multilateral development and financial institutions, regional and global public health and climate agencies.  The United States will help bring together these different groups and leverage all of their contributions to this challenge.</p>
<p>I have to tell you I’m very glad to see here tonight and tomorrow as we meet representatives from key organizations, including the Inter-American Development Bank, the World Bank, the UN High Commissioner for Refugees, UNICEF.  Institutions like these were created to help us meet challenges too great for even our countries together to solve, which is exactly what we’re called on to do now on behalf of the region’s most vulnerable people.  And to those agencies and organizations that have already given and implemented assistance, thank you.</p>
<p>I know that we’ll do good work together here in Panama.  We have to.  And I hope that the additional momentum that we build here, complemented by what we did in Colombia – and my deep appreciation to our colleagues from Colombia for bringing us together some months ago – all of that needs to carry forward in concrete, practical ways.</p>
<p>In June, many of us will come together again in Los Angeles for the Summit of the Americas that President Biden will be hosting.  There we’ll have an opportunity to address the deeper concerns that drive irregular migration by strengthening our democracies, fighting corruption, building resilience in our health care systems, promoting more equitable economic growth, combating the climate crisis.  All of these things in their own ways have an impact on the challenge that we are coming together here tonight and tomorrow to deal with.</p>
<p>President Biden set a goal for the summit that our countries adopt a declaration on migration and protection that sets forth shared principles for a collaborative, coordinated response to migration and forced displacement.  So I hope our discussions here today and tomorrow in Panama will contribute to a strong declaration by our leaders when they gather in California in just a few weeks’ time.</p>
<p>So, simply put, to each and every one of you, thank you for your leadership at what is a critical moment.  Erika said it very well.  There is – we have a regional challenge, a hemispheric challenge, but it’s also a global challenge.  There are now around the world more people on the move, displaced from their homes, than at any time since the Second World War, some 95 million people.  By definition, this is a challenge that we have to stand together to meet, work together to meet, join together to meet.</p>
<p>With that, it is my pleasure to introduce my friend and colleague, the U.S. Secretary of Homeland Security, Alejandro Mayorkas.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b><strong>SECRETARY MAYORKAS:  </strong></b>Thank you and good evening.  My thanks to President Cortizo, Ministers Mouynes and Pino, for welcoming us to this beautiful country.  Earlier today I visited the Panama Canal, and it was a very uplifting visit.  I did so with my colleague and great friend, Tony Blinken.  And the canal represents the promise of economic prosperity and the hope for advancement, and not just today but in the days to come.</p>
<p>Yesterday I had a very different visit.  Minister Pino so generously gave of his time to show my colleagues and me the Darién region and to pass over the treacherous land that the most vulnerable people try to pass in the hope of a better future.  It is very difficult to see that land and to understand the depths and breadth of the treachery that vulnerable individuals seek to cross with the hope of a better life.</p>
<p>I remember a father of a friend of mine growing up who grew up in very difficult circumstances once said that one’s – when one’s back is up against the wall, the only direction one can move in is forward.  And it is our obligation collectively to close the divide between the promise of economic prosperity that the canal represents and the vulnerability that the Darién region represents for so many who seek a better life.  And I want to thank the ministers for bringing us all together to work on an effort that requires a collective response, because the movement of people in the Western Hemisphere, and frankly in other parts of the world, is not the challenge of one country or two; it is the challenge of the region and of the hemisphere of which we are a part.  And we must take a look at the individuals who are vulnerable as members of our community, and we must deliver a response of and by the community.</p>
<p>The most enduring way in which we can address this challenge which has been with us for far too many years is to deliver stabilization, to deliver for the people in their homes the promise that the canal represents, and allow them to understand and actually realize that they do not need to leave their homes to experience the promise that so many of us here represent and are obligated to deliver to others.</p>
<p>At the same time, as we work on that most enduring solution of addressing the cause for migration, we must also extend a hand, an outstretched hand, of humanitarian relief to those who are already outside of their homes to be able to provide them with the promise of that prosperity wherever they might be so that the dangers of the journey that they once anticipated ahead of them they need no longer take.  The promise of humanitarian relief and the stability of settlement and integration, as well as an understanding that the laws that guide our extension of humanitarian relief must be honored, and for those who do not qualify we must apply those laws equally.</p>
<p>These issues and the lines that draw – are drawn between the relief and the response that we must impose when that relief is not warranted are very, very difficult to draw.  They are very difficult decisions, but we as leaders in our respective countries, and together as leaders of a community throughout a region and a hemisphere, are obligated to make those difficult decisions, and that is what makes this convening so very important – bringing us together to make those difficult decisions in partnership and in friendship with one another so that we can deliver the promise of a better future to those who do not see it and so that we can accept this responsibility in a shared and, therefore, most effective way.</p>
<p>I thank you all so very much.  I look forward to our very important conversations tomorrow.  And again, my thanks to our wonderful hosts here in this beautiful country of Panama.  <em>Gracias</em>.  (Applause.)<input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Transparency International Panama Chapter Executive Director Olga de Obaldía Opening Remarks at Meeting with Anticorruption and Transparency Advocates</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-transparency-international-panama-chapter-executive-director-olga-de-obaldia-opening-remarks-at-meeting-with-anticorruption-and-transparency-advocates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 02:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335604</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Panama City, Panama</p>
<p>American Trade Hotel</p>
<p><strong>MS OBALDIA:  </strong>Good afternoon, everybody.  My name is Olga de Obaldía.  I am the executive director of the Panama Chapter of Transparency International.  Our organization is called Foundation for the Development of Civil Liberties, or <em>Fundación para el Desarrollo de la Libertad Ciudadana</em>.  It is a pleasure for us, our organizations from the nongovernmental sector that are interested in democratic institutions, anticorruption, and transparency, to welcome today to Panama Mr. Secretary Antony Blinken, and I would like to welcome as well the government officials that are here, the embassy officials that are here, the champions of corruption from three countries – Venezuela, Guatemala, and Ecuador – and local activists that are our comrades-in-arm in this fight against corruption in Panama.</p>
<p>I’ve been asked to give you a brief introduction before I’ll let you hear from the star of the meeting, Mr. Blinken, and I’ll start by mentioning something about the American Trade Hotel where we are right now.  The American Trade Hotel and Plaza Herrera – Herrera – just in front of us here are symbols of the resilience of Panama in the – and we are in the Old Historic District of Panama.  This plaza dates from colonial times, and the building where we are right now – sorry – and the building where we are right now dates from the republican period.  It was built in 1917 and housed the American Trade Development Company, and in the hall next door was the first Citibank that helped finance the Panama Canal.</p>
<p>After falling through disrepair, it ended up housing dangerous gangs in the ‘60s, ‘70s, ‘80s, ‘90s, and the 2000s, and at some point the building was called the Grey Skull Castle, if you can imagine that.  And through community movement and local investors, the building was rescued and it’s right now one of the symbols of Panama’s resilience.  Panama has been through colonial times, republican times, to a dictatorship, to an invasion, and a new era of uninterrupted democracy since 1990.</p>
<p>However, our democracy right now is being threatened by corruption in multiple fronts.  I will just mention four of them, and I’m sure that most of the local press and the local officials are very well informed of what we are facing through regarding corruption and lack of transparency.</p>
<p>To start with, let me mention the critical impact of the impunity and the judiciary; second, the corrupt clientelist structure and practices in the national assembly that trickles down to communities and affects electoral fairness; third, a lack of fiscal accountability in the use of public resources; and fourth, a lack of a robust legal framework to fight and prevent corruption in the public and the private sector.</p>
<p>Our instruments to measure corruption are telling us that Panama is stagnant in the fight against corruption.  For the last 10 years, Panama has had an average rating of 36 over 100 in the Corruption Perceptions Index of Transparency International.  Moreover, the last transparency index of our parliament showed that Panama has the fourth most opaque parliament or congress in the whole of the Americas.  That has an impact, a terrible impact, on the population, and in the last few years, Panama’s population has been showing a lack of faith in democracy.  Sixty-five of Panamanian – 65 percent of Panamanian citizens, when asked, are not choosing democracy as their favorite form of government.</p>
<p>On top of that, we need to understand that the relationship between national security and corruption that was so well outlined in the June 3rd memo of the White House regarding the matter is the same thing in Panama.  Our national security right now is being threatened by the inclusion in politics and private financing of politics for monies that are known to be from organized crime.  And I think you all – most of you know about these facts, and I think this is enough for me.  I thank you for the opportunity of talking to you about these matters that are extremely important for us, and I give you Secretary Antony Blinken.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you so much.  Thank you.  And I appreciate very much the reference to being a featured attraction, but the truth of the matter is these are the stars of the evening – our colleagues who are on the front lines of fighting corruption in various parts of our hemisphere.</p>
<p>We’re here principally because our friends and colleagues in Panama are bringing together countries from around the hemisphere to help deal with the extraordinary phenomenon of irregular migration.  But one of the things we know very well is that one of the drivers of that irregular migration is corruption and the revulsion at corruption that people are feeling in many countries in our hemisphere and around the world.</p>
<p>If you look at, as well, the drivers of so many popular movements in every part of the world over the last couple of decades, you often find a revulsion at corruption as being one of if not the driver of these movements.  And there’s a good, good reason for that, as Olga said so well.  It is draining resources from countries that could be put to much better use supporting the people and supporting their needs.  It breeds incredible and understandable cynicism about government and about leadership.  It fuels all sorts of illicit enterprises.  And of course, it helps perpetuate nondemocratic rule in country after country.</p>
<p>So it is at the source of so many challenges, and we are incredibly gratified that we have champions who at great, often personal risk, as well as professional risk are leading the effort to uncover corruption, to create greater transparency in their societies, to prosecute those responsible – and again, in some cases at such risk that you’ve had to leave the countries that you’re from for your own safety and well-being.</p>
<p>The United States is working hard to support these efforts throughout our hemisphere and indeed around the world.  Part of it is by elevating the work of those who are combating corruption, and we are honored and proud to do it.  Part of it is by supporting civil society through the funding, assistance, training that we give.  Part of it is trying to make sure that we’re doing what we can to protect those who are on the front lines of this effort.</p>
<p>So I was really anxious to be here, not to talk to you but to hear from you, to listen to the work that you’re doing, the challenges you’re facing, and to learn a little bit about how we can do even better and do even more to help in this fight and to help you in your efforts.  So let me turn it over to you.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Panama City, Panama</p>
<p>American Trade Hotel</p>
<p><strong>MS OBALDIA:  </strong>Good afternoon, everybody.  My name is Olga de Obaldía.  I am the executive director of the Panama Chapter of Transparency International.  Our organization is called Foundation for the Development of Civil Liberties, or <em>Fundación para el Desarrollo de la Libertad Ciudadana</em>.  It is a pleasure for us, our organizations from the nongovernmental sector that are interested in democratic institutions, anticorruption, and transparency, to welcome today to Panama Mr. Secretary Antony Blinken, and I would like to welcome as well the government officials that are here, the embassy officials that are here, the champions of corruption from three countries – Venezuela, Guatemala, and Ecuador – and local activists that are our comrades-in-arm in this fight against corruption in Panama.</p>
<p>I’ve been asked to give you a brief introduction before I’ll let you hear from the star of the meeting, Mr. Blinken, and I’ll start by mentioning something about the American Trade Hotel where we are right now.  The American Trade Hotel and Plaza Herrera – Herrera – just in front of us here are symbols of the resilience of Panama in the – and we are in the Old Historic District of Panama.  This plaza dates from colonial times, and the building where we are right now – sorry – and the building where we are right now dates from the republican period.  It was built in 1917 and housed the American Trade Development Company, and in the hall next door was the first Citibank that helped finance the Panama Canal.</p>
<p>After falling through disrepair, it ended up housing dangerous gangs in the ‘60s, ‘70s, ‘80s, ‘90s, and the 2000s, and at some point the building was called the Grey Skull Castle, if you can imagine that.  And through community movement and local investors, the building was rescued and it’s right now one of the symbols of Panama’s resilience.  Panama has been through colonial times, republican times, to a dictatorship, to an invasion, and a new era of uninterrupted democracy since 1990.</p>
<p>However, our democracy right now is being threatened by corruption in multiple fronts.  I will just mention four of them, and I’m sure that most of the local press and the local officials are very well informed of what we are facing through regarding corruption and lack of transparency.</p>
<p>To start with, let me mention the critical impact of the impunity and the judiciary; second, the corrupt clientelist structure and practices in the national assembly that trickles down to communities and affects electoral fairness; third, a lack of fiscal accountability in the use of public resources; and fourth, a lack of a robust legal framework to fight and prevent corruption in the public and the private sector.</p>
<p>Our instruments to measure corruption are telling us that Panama is stagnant in the fight against corruption.  For the last 10 years, Panama has had an average rating of 36 over 100 in the Corruption Perceptions Index of Transparency International.  Moreover, the last transparency index of our parliament showed that Panama has the fourth most opaque parliament or congress in the whole of the Americas.  That has an impact, a terrible impact, on the population, and in the last few years, Panama’s population has been showing a lack of faith in democracy.  Sixty-five of Panamanian – 65 percent of Panamanian citizens, when asked, are not choosing democracy as their favorite form of government.</p>
<p>On top of that, we need to understand that the relationship between national security and corruption that was so well outlined in the June 3rd memo of the White House regarding the matter is the same thing in Panama.  Our national security right now is being threatened by the inclusion in politics and private financing of politics for monies that are known to be from organized crime.  And I think you all – most of you know about these facts, and I think this is enough for me.  I thank you for the opportunity of talking to you about these matters that are extremely important for us, and I give you Secretary Antony Blinken.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you so much.  Thank you.  And I appreciate very much the reference to being a featured attraction, but the truth of the matter is these are the stars of the evening – our colleagues who are on the front lines of fighting corruption in various parts of our hemisphere.</p>
<p>We’re here principally because our friends and colleagues in Panama are bringing together countries from around the hemisphere to help deal with the extraordinary phenomenon of irregular migration.  But one of the things we know very well is that one of the drivers of that irregular migration is corruption and the revulsion at corruption that people are feeling in many countries in our hemisphere and around the world.</p>
<p>If you look at, as well, the drivers of so many popular movements in every part of the world over the last couple of decades, you often find a revulsion at corruption as being one of if not the driver of these movements.  And there’s a good, good reason for that, as Olga said so well.  It is draining resources from countries that could be put to much better use supporting the people and supporting their needs.  It breeds incredible and understandable cynicism about government and about leadership.  It fuels all sorts of illicit enterprises.  And of course, it helps perpetuate nondemocratic rule in country after country.</p>
<p>So it is at the source of so many challenges, and we are incredibly gratified that we have champions who at great, often personal risk, as well as professional risk are leading the effort to uncover corruption, to create greater transparency in their societies, to prosecute those responsible – and again, in some cases at such risk that you’ve had to leave the countries that you’re from for your own safety and well-being.</p>
<p>The United States is working hard to support these efforts throughout our hemisphere and indeed around the world.  Part of it is by elevating the work of those who are combating corruption, and we are honored and proud to do it.  Part of it is by supporting civil society through the funding, assistance, training that we give.  Part of it is trying to make sure that we’re doing what we can to protect those who are on the front lines of this effort.</p>
<p>So I was really anxious to be here, not to talk to you but to hear from you, to listen to the work that you’re doing, the challenges you’re facing, and to learn a little bit about how we can do even better and do even more to help in this fight and to help you in your efforts.  So let me turn it over to you.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Acting Assistant Secretary Lempert’s Travel to Jordan, Israel, the West Bank and Egypt</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/acting-assistant-secretary-lemperts-travel-to-jordan-israel-the-west-bank-and-egypt/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 01:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335597</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Acting Assistant Secretary for Near Eastern Affairs Yael Lempert will travel to Jordan, Israel, the West Bank and Egypt from April 19 to April 26. She will engage with senior officials in the region to discuss reducing tensions and ending the cycle of violence in Israel, the West Bank and Gaza. Acting Assistant Secretary for Near Eastern Affairs Yael Lempert will be accompanied by Deputy Assistant Secretary for Israeli and Palestinian Affairs Hady Amr.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Acting Assistant Secretary for Near Eastern Affairs Yael Lempert will travel to Jordan, Israel, the West Bank and Egypt from April 19 to April 26. She will engage with senior officials in the region to discuss reducing tensions and ending the cycle of violence in Israel, the West Bank and Gaza. Acting Assistant Secretary for Near Eastern Affairs Yael Lempert will be accompanied by Deputy Assistant Secretary for Israeli and Palestinian Affairs Hady Amr.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States and Panama Advance Migration Cooperation</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-and-panama-advance-migration-cooperation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 01:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States and Panama have signed a Bilateral Arrangement on Migration and Protection detailing our collaborative commitments to improve migration management, expand stabilization efforts, and increase access to legal pathways and protection for those in the region.  Panama’s Minister of Security Juan Pino joined Embassy Panama City’s Chargé d’Affaires Stewart Tuttle in signing the Arrangement in Panama City on April 19.</p>
<p>This Arrangement on Migration and Protection adds to the expanding regional migration management framework that the United States is developing with counterparts across the Americas.  It also embodies the principles of that regional approach through humane border management, stabilization of displaced populations and host communities, and improved access to protection and legal pathways to provide an alternative to irregular migration.</p>
<p>Following the October 2021 Regional Migration Ministerial in Colombia, with this Arrangement both countries confirm their commitment to those principles for collaborative regional response to historic migration and refugee flows.  We look forward to working with Panama to advance the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection ahead of the Summit of the Americas, which the United States will host in June 2022.</p>
<p>The United States welcomes Panama’s leadership in building a more secure, prosperous, and democratic hemisphere.<input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States and Panama have signed a Bilateral Arrangement on Migration and Protection detailing our collaborative commitments to improve migration management, expand stabilization efforts, and increase access to legal pathways and protection for those in the region.  Panama’s Minister of Security Juan Pino joined Embassy Panama City’s Chargé d’Affaires Stewart Tuttle in signing the Arrangement in Panama City on April 19.</p>
<p>This Arrangement on Migration and Protection adds to the expanding regional migration management framework that the United States is developing with counterparts across the Americas.  It also embodies the principles of that regional approach through humane border management, stabilization of displaced populations and host communities, and improved access to protection and legal pathways to provide an alternative to irregular migration.</p>
<p>Following the October 2021 Regional Migration Ministerial in Colombia, with this Arrangement both countries confirm their commitment to those principles for collaborative regional response to historic migration and refugee flows.  We look forward to working with Panama to advance the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection ahead of the Summit of the Americas, which the United States will host in June 2022.</p>
<p>The United States welcomes Panama’s leadership in building a more secure, prosperous, and democratic hemisphere.<input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken At a Meet and Greet for Embassy Staff</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-meet-and-greet-for-embassy-staff/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[U.S. Department of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335582</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Panama City, Panama</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy Panama City</p>
<p><strong>MR TUTTLE:</strong>  Well, good afternoon, everybody.  What a fantastic turnout from Mission Panama.  Really delighted.  Give yourself some applause.  (Applause.)  Now, I know that ever since President Biden was inaugurated, there’s been a lot of buzz at this embassy about when the Secretary of State would be visiting, and it’s obviously with tremendous pleasure that I can – obviously I don’t need to surprise you.  He’s right here next to me, right?  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>So I mean – and I think what’s important to note – we all know what’s going on in the world today, right?  There’s a lot of crises, a lot of issues we’re dealing with, some of monumental importance.  The fact that Secretary Blinken has chosen to be here today in Panama with us – along with, not by coincidence, Secretary of Homeland Security Mayorkas as well – is an indication of not only the strength of our bilateral relationship with Panama but also the importance of the issues that they are here to address.</p>
<p>So Secretary Blinken became the 71st Secretary of State on January 26th of 2021, but he was obviously a familiar face to many of us in the department, having been the deputy secretary for a number of years during President Obama’s second term; prior to that, the deputy national security advisor; and in President Obama’s first term, the national security advisor to then-Vice President Joe Biden.  That was a relationship that had continued on from their time at the Senate, where the Secretary was the Democratic staff director at the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, a committee that then-Senator Biden served on for many years and which he chaired for quite a time while they were there together.</p>
<p>So, Mr. Secretary, I couldn’t help but notice that when I was looking at your bio, we both had our first experience in the State Department in the 1990s in the same year.  Now, I know what you’re all thinking – his career has progressed a little faster than mine.  (Laughter.)  But I’m a magnanimous guy, so no hard feelings, right?  In fact, Secretary Blinken has a soft spot in my heart, because in your very first virtual meeting with all the chiefs of mission of the Western Hemisphere, I made a comment that I was hoping would be taken as humorous, and the Secretary actually chuckled.  He did, right?  (Laughter.)  Now, just letting you know that you had me at a smirk, but thanks for going above and beyond the call.</p>
<p>So with that, hey, let me turn the microphone over to the man you’re here to see, Secretary of State Tony Blinken.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, thank you all very, very much.  It is great to be here with Mission Panama.  Wow, and greetings all the way up there.  (Laughter.)  So I hadn’t realized that we started at the same time, but look, in fairness, the office that I started in was on the sixth floor of the State Department, in the front office of what was then called the European and Canadian Affairs Bureau.  And if you go there now you can still see – I think they’ve changed it a little bit, but the previous occupant of that office, Stewart – the one right before me – was a large safe, which gives you some idea of what the office was like.  (Laughter.)  And as I say, basically over the course of about 30 years I managed to move up one flight of stairs and get some windows.  (Laughter.)  So I’ll take that.</p>
<p>But to Stewart’s point – and first let me start by thanking you so much for your leadership here at what really is a critical time.  And the fact that we’re here is evidence that not only is this partnership important, it’s increasingly vital.  We have – and we talked about this with the president today and the foreign minister.  We’re at a time of challenge, where democracies are being challenged, and having a strong beacon of democracy here in Panama makes a big difference at this time.</p>
<p>We’re, of course, facing an incredible challenge when it comes to irregular migration not just in our own hemisphere but quite literally around the world.  There are now more people on the move around the world, displaced from their homes, than at any time since World War II.  And we’re feeling that here in our hemisphere.  Panama has really stepped up in a big way to be a leader in making sure that we see this as a shared responsibility, which is really the focus of our trip here today.</p>
<p>But mostly I wanted to come by to say thank you to each and every one of you for the incredible service that you’re performing.  I have a couple things I want to say about that, but let me just give some thanks.  I caught the tail end of the dancers and percussionists.  Really remarkable; thank you so much for that.  And I am especially glad to see that we have obviously some first and second-tour members of the team here.  (Laughter.)  And I’m looking forward to talking to you guys when we get a chance.</p>
<p>But one of the things that’s really remarkable here is – we talk a lot about interagency collaboration back home.  This is the model of it.  By our count, there are 42 agencies represented here, everything from Ag to DOD to DOJ to Treasury, and so on down the line.  To each and every one of you, if you’re here from one of our partner agencies, thank you for the remarkable collaboration.  We can’t do what we do without that partnership, and this is really a model for the way that’s supposed to work.</p>
<p>You’ve been getting out and about despite the challenges of COVID.  I know there’s been an Embassy on the Road program, visiting provinces west of Panama City – should I – actually, here, I’ll hold it.  There we go, thank you.  Sorry about that.</p>
<p>Meeting community, business leaders; folks from all walks of life; visiting schools, touring farms, reaching diverse populations.  And that kind of outreach is vital, and I’m glad you’re doing it.</p>
<p>I’m also incredibly glad to know that the Peace Corps is on its way back, volunteers coming back in July after the COVID-19 pause.  So Peace Corps, welcome back to Panama.</p>
<p>And then, of course, we have a remarkable security partnership here with our partners.  Together you are doing, we are doing, search and rescue missions, stopping illegal fishing, fighting drug trafficking.  All of that happening out of this embassy.</p>
<p>But what I really wanted to focus on just for a minute is the culture of this mission and what each and every one of you is bringing to it.  We’ve all been through, and you’ve been through, an incredibly challenging time with COVID-19 over the last couple of years, and I know that’s had a profound effect on people’s professional lives, in many cases on your personal lives.  Some of you have lost family members, loved ones, gotten sick, and you’ve had to do your jobs in a different way, a much more difficult way, and yet you kept doing it.  And you’ve also kept the spirit alive, and that’s so important, making sure that you had each other’s backs as we worked through COVID.  And I know that everything from virtual cooking classes to virtual bingo – it sounds funny, but it really is a powerful way of keeping people connected when they were forced to part, so thank you for doing that.</p>
<p>And I’m grateful as well to all of you for engaging in service, service to this country and this community.  The Green Team with beach clean-ups, embassy volunteers working with local schools.  The last event, I am told, had some 200 volunteers.  That’s a powerful bit of diplomacy, too.  It really shows us connecting with our Panamanian friends and addressing issues that actually have an immediate impact on their lives as well.  So I’m thankful for it.</p>
<p>And then I was told that you had your own special version of the Winter Olympics.  (Laughter.)  So interesting events that I had not realized were normally part of the Winter Olympics.  Dodgeball.  (Laughter.)  Trivia – a lot of training has to go into that.  (Laughter.)  Musical chairs for section leaders.  (Laughter.)  And then my personal favorite, a sack race in the diplomatic pouch.  (Laughter.)  Now that is a very good use of the diplomatic pouch.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>But in all of these ways, and everything you’ve done, spring garden parties.  By the way, I heard that there was a lamb that made a repeated escape from this, showing that the lamb understands that one of our most sacred values is freedom.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>But in all these ways big and small, this is how you build, this is how you keep a community together, especially during challenging times.  And to you, Stewart, to the entire team here, to the acting DCM, everyone – thank you for coming together and for pulling together.</p>
<p>Finally, wherever I go there are two groups of people that I especially want to give a special shout-out to.  The first – and I saw some of our colleagues as we were coming in – are Marines.  Every embassy that you go to, no matter where it is in the world, the very first person you’re likely to see walking into an embassy is a Marine.  We can’t do our jobs without them doing their jobs.  This partnership is something that’s truly sacred to our institution.  And to our Marine brothers and sisters, we are grateful for you every single day.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>And second – and all of you who are Americans here know this so very well – the lifeblood of any embassy everywhere in the world is our locally engaged staff.  And I know that there are a number of you here.  I want to say thank you to you for what you do every single day to bring our countries closer together.  And there are a few people I just want to mention by name because this is really extraordinary.</p>
<p>Roberto Ortiz.  I don’t know if Roberto is here.  Forty years of service.  So Roberto, thank you.  (Cheers and applause.)</p>
<p>Mirtha Arhona.  I don’t know if Mirtha is here.  Right there.  Thank you.  (Cheers and applause.)  It can’t possibly be right.  It – this can’t be – it can’t be right.  It says 50 years of service.  Is that possible?  That can’t be right.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>And then I have here Mabel Camarena.  Mabel, are you here anywhere?  (Cheers and applause.) Back there.  So is this even possible – 52 years of service?  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>But whatever your contribution, whether you’re a direct hire, whether you are Foreign Service, Civil Service, a contractor, locally employed staff, whether you’re here from any of our fellow agencies and departments, thank you for all that you’re doing.  Thank you for all that you’re doing for your country.  Thank you for all that you’re doing for this partnership.  I am grateful for it every single day.  And I know that a lot of work goes into these visits, even one that’s relatively short.  So to anyone who took part, thank you for doing it, thank you for bringing us here, thank you for the incredible support, and have a great wheels-up party tomorrow.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Panama City, Panama</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy Panama City</p>
<p><strong>MR TUTTLE:</strong>  Well, good afternoon, everybody.  What a fantastic turnout from Mission Panama.  Really delighted.  Give yourself some applause.  (Applause.)  Now, I know that ever since President Biden was inaugurated, there’s been a lot of buzz at this embassy about when the Secretary of State would be visiting, and it’s obviously with tremendous pleasure that I can – obviously I don’t need to surprise you.  He’s right here next to me, right?  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>So I mean – and I think what’s important to note – we all know what’s going on in the world today, right?  There’s a lot of crises, a lot of issues we’re dealing with, some of monumental importance.  The fact that Secretary Blinken has chosen to be here today in Panama with us – along with, not by coincidence, Secretary of Homeland Security Mayorkas as well – is an indication of not only the strength of our bilateral relationship with Panama but also the importance of the issues that they are here to address.</p>
<p>So Secretary Blinken became the 71st Secretary of State on January 26th of 2021, but he was obviously a familiar face to many of us in the department, having been the deputy secretary for a number of years during President Obama’s second term; prior to that, the deputy national security advisor; and in President Obama’s first term, the national security advisor to then-Vice President Joe Biden.  That was a relationship that had continued on from their time at the Senate, where the Secretary was the Democratic staff director at the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, a committee that then-Senator Biden served on for many years and which he chaired for quite a time while they were there together.</p>
<p>So, Mr. Secretary, I couldn’t help but notice that when I was looking at your bio, we both had our first experience in the State Department in the 1990s in the same year.  Now, I know what you’re all thinking – his career has progressed a little faster than mine.  (Laughter.)  But I’m a magnanimous guy, so no hard feelings, right?  In fact, Secretary Blinken has a soft spot in my heart, because in your very first virtual meeting with all the chiefs of mission of the Western Hemisphere, I made a comment that I was hoping would be taken as humorous, and the Secretary actually chuckled.  He did, right?  (Laughter.)  Now, just letting you know that you had me at a smirk, but thanks for going above and beyond the call.</p>
<p>So with that, hey, let me turn the microphone over to the man you’re here to see, Secretary of State Tony Blinken.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, thank you all very, very much.  It is great to be here with Mission Panama.  Wow, and greetings all the way up there.  (Laughter.)  So I hadn’t realized that we started at the same time, but look, in fairness, the office that I started in was on the sixth floor of the State Department, in the front office of what was then called the European and Canadian Affairs Bureau.  And if you go there now you can still see – I think they’ve changed it a little bit, but the previous occupant of that office, Stewart – the one right before me – was a large safe, which gives you some idea of what the office was like.  (Laughter.)  And as I say, basically over the course of about 30 years I managed to move up one flight of stairs and get some windows.  (Laughter.)  So I’ll take that.</p>
<p>But to Stewart’s point – and first let me start by thanking you so much for your leadership here at what really is a critical time.  And the fact that we’re here is evidence that not only is this partnership important, it’s increasingly vital.  We have – and we talked about this with the president today and the foreign minister.  We’re at a time of challenge, where democracies are being challenged, and having a strong beacon of democracy here in Panama makes a big difference at this time.</p>
<p>We’re, of course, facing an incredible challenge when it comes to irregular migration not just in our own hemisphere but quite literally around the world.  There are now more people on the move around the world, displaced from their homes, than at any time since World War II.  And we’re feeling that here in our hemisphere.  Panama has really stepped up in a big way to be a leader in making sure that we see this as a shared responsibility, which is really the focus of our trip here today.</p>
<p>But mostly I wanted to come by to say thank you to each and every one of you for the incredible service that you’re performing.  I have a couple things I want to say about that, but let me just give some thanks.  I caught the tail end of the dancers and percussionists.  Really remarkable; thank you so much for that.  And I am especially glad to see that we have obviously some first and second-tour members of the team here.  (Laughter.)  And I’m looking forward to talking to you guys when we get a chance.</p>
<p>But one of the things that’s really remarkable here is – we talk a lot about interagency collaboration back home.  This is the model of it.  By our count, there are 42 agencies represented here, everything from Ag to DOD to DOJ to Treasury, and so on down the line.  To each and every one of you, if you’re here from one of our partner agencies, thank you for the remarkable collaboration.  We can’t do what we do without that partnership, and this is really a model for the way that’s supposed to work.</p>
<p>You’ve been getting out and about despite the challenges of COVID.  I know there’s been an Embassy on the Road program, visiting provinces west of Panama City – should I – actually, here, I’ll hold it.  There we go, thank you.  Sorry about that.</p>
<p>Meeting community, business leaders; folks from all walks of life; visiting schools, touring farms, reaching diverse populations.  And that kind of outreach is vital, and I’m glad you’re doing it.</p>
<p>I’m also incredibly glad to know that the Peace Corps is on its way back, volunteers coming back in July after the COVID-19 pause.  So Peace Corps, welcome back to Panama.</p>
<p>And then, of course, we have a remarkable security partnership here with our partners.  Together you are doing, we are doing, search and rescue missions, stopping illegal fishing, fighting drug trafficking.  All of that happening out of this embassy.</p>
<p>But what I really wanted to focus on just for a minute is the culture of this mission and what each and every one of you is bringing to it.  We’ve all been through, and you’ve been through, an incredibly challenging time with COVID-19 over the last couple of years, and I know that’s had a profound effect on people’s professional lives, in many cases on your personal lives.  Some of you have lost family members, loved ones, gotten sick, and you’ve had to do your jobs in a different way, a much more difficult way, and yet you kept doing it.  And you’ve also kept the spirit alive, and that’s so important, making sure that you had each other’s backs as we worked through COVID.  And I know that everything from virtual cooking classes to virtual bingo – it sounds funny, but it really is a powerful way of keeping people connected when they were forced to part, so thank you for doing that.</p>
<p>And I’m grateful as well to all of you for engaging in service, service to this country and this community.  The Green Team with beach clean-ups, embassy volunteers working with local schools.  The last event, I am told, had some 200 volunteers.  That’s a powerful bit of diplomacy, too.  It really shows us connecting with our Panamanian friends and addressing issues that actually have an immediate impact on their lives as well.  So I’m thankful for it.</p>
<p>And then I was told that you had your own special version of the Winter Olympics.  (Laughter.)  So interesting events that I had not realized were normally part of the Winter Olympics.  Dodgeball.  (Laughter.)  Trivia – a lot of training has to go into that.  (Laughter.)  Musical chairs for section leaders.  (Laughter.)  And then my personal favorite, a sack race in the diplomatic pouch.  (Laughter.)  Now that is a very good use of the diplomatic pouch.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>But in all of these ways, and everything you’ve done, spring garden parties.  By the way, I heard that there was a lamb that made a repeated escape from this, showing that the lamb understands that one of our most sacred values is freedom.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>But in all these ways big and small, this is how you build, this is how you keep a community together, especially during challenging times.  And to you, Stewart, to the entire team here, to the acting DCM, everyone – thank you for coming together and for pulling together.</p>
<p>Finally, wherever I go there are two groups of people that I especially want to give a special shout-out to.  The first – and I saw some of our colleagues as we were coming in – are Marines.  Every embassy that you go to, no matter where it is in the world, the very first person you’re likely to see walking into an embassy is a Marine.  We can’t do our jobs without them doing their jobs.  This partnership is something that’s truly sacred to our institution.  And to our Marine brothers and sisters, we are grateful for you every single day.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>And second – and all of you who are Americans here know this so very well – the lifeblood of any embassy everywhere in the world is our locally engaged staff.  And I know that there are a number of you here.  I want to say thank you to you for what you do every single day to bring our countries closer together.  And there are a few people I just want to mention by name because this is really extraordinary.</p>
<p>Roberto Ortiz.  I don’t know if Roberto is here.  Forty years of service.  So Roberto, thank you.  (Cheers and applause.)</p>
<p>Mirtha Arhona.  I don’t know if Mirtha is here.  Right there.  Thank you.  (Cheers and applause.)  It can’t possibly be right.  It – this can’t be – it can’t be right.  It says 50 years of service.  Is that possible?  That can’t be right.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>And then I have here Mabel Camarena.  Mabel, are you here anywhere?  (Cheers and applause.) Back there.  So is this even possible – 52 years of service?  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>But whatever your contribution, whether you’re a direct hire, whether you are Foreign Service, Civil Service, a contractor, locally employed staff, whether you’re here from any of our fellow agencies and departments, thank you for all that you’re doing.  Thank you for all that you’re doing for your country.  Thank you for all that you’re doing for this partnership.  I am grateful for it every single day.  And I know that a lot of work goes into these visits, even one that’s relatively short.  So to anyone who took part, thank you for doing it, thank you for bringing us here, thank you for the incredible support, and have a great wheels-up party tomorrow.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Panamanian President Cortizo and Foreign Minister Mouynes</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-panamanian-president-cortizo-and-foreign-minister-mouynes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 22:21:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Panamanian President Laurentino Cortizo Cohen and Foreign Minister Erika Mouynes in Panama City.  Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro N. Mayorkas also joined the meeting. Secretary Blinken, President Cortizo, Foreign Minister Mouynes, and Secretary Mayorkas discussed the importance of regional cooperation on irregular migration and forced displacement to promote safe, orderly, and humane migration throughout the region.  They also discussed strengthening our economic ties, preparations for using the June Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles to advance efforts to strengthen democracy and improve governance in the region, and the need to stand together against the Kremlin’s war in Ukraine.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Panamanian President Laurentino Cortizo Cohen and Foreign Minister Erika Mouynes in Panama City.  Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro N. Mayorkas also joined the meeting. Secretary Blinken, President Cortizo, Foreign Minister Mouynes, and Secretary Mayorkas discussed the importance of regional cooperation on irregular migration and forced displacement to promote safe, orderly, and humane migration throughout the region.  They also discussed strengthening our economic ties, preparations for using the June Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles to advance efforts to strengthen democracy and improve governance in the region, and the need to stand together against the Kremlin’s war in Ukraine.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Israeli Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Lapid</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-israeli-foreign-minister-and-alternate-prime-minister-lapid-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 22:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335507</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Israeli Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Yair Lapid regarding the importance of Israelis and Palestinians working to end the cycle of violence in Israel, the West Bank, and Gaza by exercising restraint and refraining from actions that escalate tensions, including at Jerusalem&#8217;s Haram al-Sharif/Temple Mount. They discussed the steps Israel has taken to do so. They also spoke of common efforts to confront global challenges, including those posed by Iran and its proxies. Secretary Blinken reiterated the Administration’s steadfast commitment to Israel’s security and condemned recent rocket attacks from Gaza. He emphasized U.S. support for a negotiated two-state solution and desire to deepen and expand Israel’s relations in the region following the successful Negev Summit.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Israeli Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Yair Lapid regarding the importance of Israelis and Palestinians working to end the cycle of violence in Israel, the West Bank, and Gaza by exercising restraint and refraining from actions that escalate tensions, including at Jerusalem&#8217;s Haram al-Sharif/Temple Mount. They discussed the steps Israel has taken to do so. They also spoke of common efforts to confront global challenges, including those posed by Iran and its proxies. Secretary Blinken reiterated the Administration’s steadfast commitment to Israel’s security and condemned recent rocket attacks from Gaza. He emphasized U.S. support for a negotiated two-state solution and desire to deepen and expand Israel’s relations in the region following the successful Negev Summit.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Palestinian President Abbas</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-palestinian-president-abbas-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 21:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335498</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Palestinian President Mahmoud Abbas regarding increased tensions and recent violence in Israel, the West Bank, and Gaza, including at Jerusalem&#8217;s Haram al-Sharif/Temple Mount. Secretary Blinken emphasized the importance of Palestinians and Israelis working to end the cycle of violence by refraining from actions and rhetoric that escalate tensions. He also reiterated the U.S. commitment to improving the quality of life of the Palestinian people in tangible ways and America&#8217;s support for a negotiated two-state solution</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Palestinian President Mahmoud Abbas regarding increased tensions and recent violence in Israel, the West Bank, and Gaza, including at Jerusalem&#8217;s Haram al-Sharif/Temple Mount. Secretary Blinken emphasized the importance of Palestinians and Israelis working to end the cycle of violence by refraining from actions and rhetoric that escalate tensions. He also reiterated the U.S. commitment to improving the quality of life of the Palestinian people in tangible ways and America&#8217;s support for a negotiated two-state solution</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Attacks on Education Institutions in Kabul</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/attacks-on-education-institutions-in-kabul/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 20:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335475</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States joins the international community in expressing outrage in response to today’s heinous attacks on the Mumtaz Education Center and the Abdul Rahim Shahid school in Kabul, Afghanistan.  We offer sincere condolences to the families and other loved ones of those killed in these cowardly acts. The perpetrators must be brought to justice.</p>
<p>All Afghan children deserve to pursue their studies safely and without fear of violence.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States joins the international community in expressing outrage in response to today’s heinous attacks on the Mumtaz Education Center and the Abdul Rahim Shahid school in Kabul, Afghanistan.  We offer sincere condolences to the families and other loved ones of those killed in these cowardly acts. The perpetrators must be brought to justice.</p>
<p>All Afghan children deserve to pursue their studies safely and without fear of violence.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States Pledges $600 Million to Combat Global Environmental Threats</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-pledges-600-million-to-combat-global-environmental-threats/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 17:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is being released jointly by the U.S. Department of State and the U.S. Department of the Treasury.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>On April 8, the United States pledged $600.8 million over the next four years to support the eighth replenishment of the Global Environment Facility (GEF-8).  This is the United States’ largest GEF pledge ever.  This pledge aligns with continuing U.S. priorities and supports the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to addressing climate change, conserving global carbon sinks and other critical ecosystems, and restoring the health of our ocean.  The United States joined 28 other donors in collectively pledging more than $5 billion to support GEF-8, a nearly 30 percent increase over GEF-7.</p>
<p>The U.S. pledge will help protect tropical rainforests and other critical carbon sinks; address ocean plastics pollution; combat wildlife trafficking and illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing; and reduce hazardous transboundary pollutants such as PCBs and mercury that can affect Americans’ health.  In its Fiscal Year 2023 Budget, the Administration has requested $150.2 million for the GEF, as the first of four planned installments for the U.S. contribution to GEF-8.</p>
<p>The GEF is one of the world’s largest dedicated funders of projects and programs to improve the global environment.  The United States supported the establishment of the GEF in 1991 and has contributed to all seven replenishments.  Since its launch in 1991, the GEF has provided nearly $22 billion in grants and mobilized another $119 billion in co-financing to safeguard the global environment.  The GEF is the world’s primary multilateral source of biodiversity finance and is the only multilateral environmental fund whose mandate is to achieve global environmental benefits across a diverse set of focal areas that also includes chemicals and waste, climate change mitigation, land degradation (including desertification and deforestation), and international waters.  The GEF Partnership spans 184 member governments, 18 implementing agencies, more than 500 civil society organizations, international bodies and funds, and businesses from every major sector.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is being released jointly by the U.S. Department of State and the U.S. Department of the Treasury.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>On April 8, the United States pledged $600.8 million over the next four years to support the eighth replenishment of the Global Environment Facility (GEF-8).  This is the United States’ largest GEF pledge ever.  This pledge aligns with continuing U.S. priorities and supports the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to addressing climate change, conserving global carbon sinks and other critical ecosystems, and restoring the health of our ocean.  The United States joined 28 other donors in collectively pledging more than $5 billion to support GEF-8, a nearly 30 percent increase over GEF-7.</p>
<p>The U.S. pledge will help protect tropical rainforests and other critical carbon sinks; address ocean plastics pollution; combat wildlife trafficking and illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing; and reduce hazardous transboundary pollutants such as PCBs and mercury that can affect Americans’ health.  In its Fiscal Year 2023 Budget, the Administration has requested $150.2 million for the GEF, as the first of four planned installments for the U.S. contribution to GEF-8.</p>
<p>The GEF is one of the world’s largest dedicated funders of projects and programs to improve the global environment.  The United States supported the establishment of the GEF in 1991 and has contributed to all seven replenishments.  Since its launch in 1991, the GEF has provided nearly $22 billion in grants and mobilized another $119 billion in co-financing to safeguard the global environment.  The GEF is the world’s primary multilateral source of biodiversity finance and is the only multilateral environmental fund whose mandate is to achieve global environmental benefits across a diverse set of focal areas that also includes chemicals and waste, climate change mitigation, land degradation (including desertification and deforestation), and international waters.  The GEF Partnership spans 184 member governments, 18 implementing agencies, more than 500 civil society organizations, international bodies and funds, and businesses from every major sector.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
