<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 11:42:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>G7 Foreign Ministers’ Statement on Russia’s War of Aggression Against Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/g7-foreign-ministers-statement-on-russias-war-of-aggression-against-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 11:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p align="left"><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p align="left">We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union, condemn in the strongest terms the atrocities committed by the Russian armed forces in Bucha and a number of other Ukrainian towns. Haunting images of civilian deaths, victims of torture, and apparent executions, as well as reports of sexual violence and destruction of civilian infrastructure show the true face of Russia’s brutal war of aggression against Ukraine and its people. The massacres in the town of Bucha and other Ukrainian towns will be inscribed in the list of atrocities and severe violations of international law, including international humanitarian law and human rights, committed by the aggressor on Ukrainian soil.</p>
<p align="left">In the presence of the Foreign Minister of Ukraine, Dmytro Kuleba, we expressed today our heart-felt solidarity with the Ukrainian people and our deepest condolences to the victims of this war and their families. We underline our unwavering support for Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders and express our readiness to assist further, including with military equipment and financial means, to allow Ukraine to defend itself against Russia’s aggression and to rebuild Ukraine.</p>
<p align="left">We underscore that those responsible for these heinous acts and atrocities, including any attacks targeting civilians and destruction of civilian infrastructure, will be held accountable and prosecuted. We welcome and support the ongoing work to investigate and gather evidence of these and other potential war crimes and crimes against humanity, including by the ICC Office of the Prosecutor, the Commission of Inquiry mandated by the UN Human Rights Council, the Human Rights Monitoring Mission Ukraine of the OHCHR, and the OSCE’s mission of experts mandated by OSCE Participating States. We will provide investigative support, technical experts and funding. We will continue to promote accountability for all those complicit in Moscow’s war of choice, including the Lukashenka regime in Belarus. We are convinced that now is the time to suspend Russian membership of the Human Rights Council.</p>
<p align="left">Russia must immediately comply with the legally binding order of the International Court of Justice (ICJ) to suspend the military operations that it commenced on 24 February 2022 in the territory of Ukraine. Further, we urge Russia to withdraw completely its military forces and equipment from the entire territory of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders.</p>
<p align="left">We warn against any threat or use of chemical, biological or nuclear weapons. We recall Russia’s obligations under international treaties of which it is a party, and which protect us all. Any use by Russia of such a weapon would be unacceptable and result in severe consequences. We condemn Russia’s unsubstantiated claims and false allegations against Ukraine, a respected member of the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention and the Chemical Weapons Convention that is in compliance with its legal obligations under those instruments. We express concern about other countries and actors that have amplified Russia’s disinformation campaign.</p>
<p align="left">We express our gravest concern with Russia forcefully seizing control of nuclear facilities, and other violent actions in connection with a number of nuclear facilities, nuclear and other radioactive material, which have caused and continue to pose serious and direct threats to the safety and security of these facilities and their civilian personnel, significantly raising the risk of a nuclear accident or incident, which endangers the population of Ukraine, neighboring States and the international community.</p>
<p align="left">We reiterate our demand that Russia upholds its obligations under international humanitarian law and desists from further blatant abuses. The Russian leadership must immediately provide for safe, rapid and unimpeded humanitarian access and make safe passages work, enabling humanitarian aid to be delivered to besieged cities and civilians to reach safety.</p>
<p align="left">We commit to supporting the Government of Ukraine’s humanitarian coordination structure and to disburse humanitarian support quickly. We ask others to join in this effort. A humanitarian push including more funding is urgently needed for Ukraine and beyond as Russia’s ruthless war and actions are having massive consequences on global commodity and food prices. The resulting rise in food insecurity is being felt disproportionately by the most vulnerable. We stand in solidarity with our partners across the world who have to bear the rising price of President Putin’s unilateral choice to wage war in Europe. We will make coherent use of all instruments and funding mechanisms to address food insecurity, keep markets open, and build resilience in the agriculture sector on all continents. We will actively counter Russia’s narrative that Western sanctions have caused the rise in global food prices and call it out for what it is: a blatant lie.</p>
<p align="left">In light of Russia’s ongoing aggression against Ukraine, carried out with Belarus’ complicity, we have already adopted unprecedented and coordinated economic and financial sanctions against Russia that impose a significant cost on its economy. We stress the necessity of further increasing the economic pressure inflicted on Russia and the Lukashenka regime in Belarus. Together with international partners, the G7 will sustain and increase pressure on Russia by imposing coordinated additional restrictive measures to effectively thwart Russian abilities to continue the aggression against Ukraine. We will work together to stop any attempts to circumvent sanctions or to aid Russia by other means. We are taking further steps to expedite plans to reduce our reliance on Russian energy, and will work together to this end.</p>
<p align="left">We commend those neighboring states to Ukraine that demonstrated great solidarity and humanity by welcoming Ukrainian refugees and third country nationals affected by the conflict. We confirm the need for increased international assistance and will continue to support these countries, including by receiving more refugees. President Putin’s war of aggression against Ukraine has already forced millions of civilians, especially women, children, and elderly, to flee their homes. Over 4.2 million crossed the border to other countries, almost all of them to the EU and the Republic of Moldova. We reiterate our concern about the risk to this vulnerable population, including the risk of human trafficking and our commitment to protect these refugees.</p>
<p align="left">Ministers paid special attention to the Republic of Moldova, which hosts the largest group of refugees from Ukraine per capita. The Ministers agreed to further coordinate their assistance for Moldova’s humanitarian response and long-term resilience following the Moldova Support Conference co-hosted by Germany, France and Romania on 5 April in Berlin and the establishment of the Moldova Support Platform.</p>
<p align="left"><i>End Text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p align="left"><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p align="left">We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union, condemn in the strongest terms the atrocities committed by the Russian armed forces in Bucha and a number of other Ukrainian towns. Haunting images of civilian deaths, victims of torture, and apparent executions, as well as reports of sexual violence and destruction of civilian infrastructure show the true face of Russia’s brutal war of aggression against Ukraine and its people. The massacres in the town of Bucha and other Ukrainian towns will be inscribed in the list of atrocities and severe violations of international law, including international humanitarian law and human rights, committed by the aggressor on Ukrainian soil.</p>
<p align="left">In the presence of the Foreign Minister of Ukraine, Dmytro Kuleba, we expressed today our heart-felt solidarity with the Ukrainian people and our deepest condolences to the victims of this war and their families. We underline our unwavering support for Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders and express our readiness to assist further, including with military equipment and financial means, to allow Ukraine to defend itself against Russia’s aggression and to rebuild Ukraine.</p>
<p align="left">We underscore that those responsible for these heinous acts and atrocities, including any attacks targeting civilians and destruction of civilian infrastructure, will be held accountable and prosecuted. We welcome and support the ongoing work to investigate and gather evidence of these and other potential war crimes and crimes against humanity, including by the ICC Office of the Prosecutor, the Commission of Inquiry mandated by the UN Human Rights Council, the Human Rights Monitoring Mission Ukraine of the OHCHR, and the OSCE’s mission of experts mandated by OSCE Participating States. We will provide investigative support, technical experts and funding. We will continue to promote accountability for all those complicit in Moscow’s war of choice, including the Lukashenka regime in Belarus. We are convinced that now is the time to suspend Russian membership of the Human Rights Council.</p>
<p align="left">Russia must immediately comply with the legally binding order of the International Court of Justice (ICJ) to suspend the military operations that it commenced on 24 February 2022 in the territory of Ukraine. Further, we urge Russia to withdraw completely its military forces and equipment from the entire territory of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders.</p>
<p align="left">We warn against any threat or use of chemical, biological or nuclear weapons. We recall Russia’s obligations under international treaties of which it is a party, and which protect us all. Any use by Russia of such a weapon would be unacceptable and result in severe consequences. We condemn Russia’s unsubstantiated claims and false allegations against Ukraine, a respected member of the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention and the Chemical Weapons Convention that is in compliance with its legal obligations under those instruments. We express concern about other countries and actors that have amplified Russia’s disinformation campaign.</p>
<p align="left">We express our gravest concern with Russia forcefully seizing control of nuclear facilities, and other violent actions in connection with a number of nuclear facilities, nuclear and other radioactive material, which have caused and continue to pose serious and direct threats to the safety and security of these facilities and their civilian personnel, significantly raising the risk of a nuclear accident or incident, which endangers the population of Ukraine, neighboring States and the international community.</p>
<p align="left">We reiterate our demand that Russia upholds its obligations under international humanitarian law and desists from further blatant abuses. The Russian leadership must immediately provide for safe, rapid and unimpeded humanitarian access and make safe passages work, enabling humanitarian aid to be delivered to besieged cities and civilians to reach safety.</p>
<p align="left">We commit to supporting the Government of Ukraine’s humanitarian coordination structure and to disburse humanitarian support quickly. We ask others to join in this effort. A humanitarian push including more funding is urgently needed for Ukraine and beyond as Russia’s ruthless war and actions are having massive consequences on global commodity and food prices. The resulting rise in food insecurity is being felt disproportionately by the most vulnerable. We stand in solidarity with our partners across the world who have to bear the rising price of President Putin’s unilateral choice to wage war in Europe. We will make coherent use of all instruments and funding mechanisms to address food insecurity, keep markets open, and build resilience in the agriculture sector on all continents. We will actively counter Russia’s narrative that Western sanctions have caused the rise in global food prices and call it out for what it is: a blatant lie.</p>
<p align="left">In light of Russia’s ongoing aggression against Ukraine, carried out with Belarus’ complicity, we have already adopted unprecedented and coordinated economic and financial sanctions against Russia that impose a significant cost on its economy. We stress the necessity of further increasing the economic pressure inflicted on Russia and the Lukashenka regime in Belarus. Together with international partners, the G7 will sustain and increase pressure on Russia by imposing coordinated additional restrictive measures to effectively thwart Russian abilities to continue the aggression against Ukraine. We will work together to stop any attempts to circumvent sanctions or to aid Russia by other means. We are taking further steps to expedite plans to reduce our reliance on Russian energy, and will work together to this end.</p>
<p align="left">We commend those neighboring states to Ukraine that demonstrated great solidarity and humanity by welcoming Ukrainian refugees and third country nationals affected by the conflict. We confirm the need for increased international assistance and will continue to support these countries, including by receiving more refugees. President Putin’s war of aggression against Ukraine has already forced millions of civilians, especially women, children, and elderly, to flee their homes. Over 4.2 million crossed the border to other countries, almost all of them to the EU and the Republic of Moldova. We reiterate our concern about the risk to this vulnerable population, including the risk of human trafficking and our commitment to protect these refugees.</p>
<p align="left">Ministers paid special attention to the Republic of Moldova, which hosts the largest group of refugees from Ukraine per capita. The Ministers agreed to further coordinate their assistance for Moldova’s humanitarian response and long-term resilience following the Moldova Support Conference co-hosted by Germany, France and Romania on 5 April in Berlin and the establishment of the Moldova Support Platform.</p>
<p align="left"><i>End Text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with UK National Security Adviser Lovegrove</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-uk-national-security-adviser-lovegrove/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 01:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332346</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with UK National Security Adviser Sir Stephen Lovegrove today in Washington.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and NSA Lovegrove continued their close coordination in responding to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine and atrocities the Russian Federation forces have committed.  The Deputy Secretary and NSA Lovegrove reaffirmed the strategic importance of the Indo-Pacific region and ensuring the AUKUS partnership delivers critical security and technology capabilities to address challenges in the Indo-Pacific and beyond.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with UK National Security Adviser Sir Stephen Lovegrove today in Washington.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and NSA Lovegrove continued their close coordination in responding to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine and atrocities the Russian Federation forces have committed.  The Deputy Secretary and NSA Lovegrove reaffirmed the strategic importance of the Indo-Pacific region and ensuring the AUKUS partnership delivers critical security and technology capabilities to address challenges in the Indo-Pacific and beyond.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-nato-secretary-general-stoltenberg-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 21:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg in Brussels.  The leaders discussed efforts to provide security and other forms of assistance to our Ukrainian partners in response to the Russian Federation’s unprovoked war against Ukraine. They also noted preparations for the June 29-30 NATO Summit in Madrid and reaffirmed support for NATO’s Asia-Pacific partners, Australia, Japan, the Republic of Korea, and New Zealand, attending the Ministerial for the first time. Secretary Blinken reiterated U.S. support for the development of a new NATO Strategic Concept that addresses current and future threats to the international rules-based order.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg in Brussels.  The leaders discussed efforts to provide security and other forms of assistance to our Ukrainian partners in response to the Russian Federation’s unprovoked war against Ukraine. They also noted preparations for the June 29-30 NATO Summit in Madrid and reaffirmed support for NATO’s Asia-Pacific partners, Australia, Japan, the Republic of Korea, and New Zealand, attending the Ministerial for the first time. Secretary Blinken reiterated U.S. support for the development of a new NATO Strategic Concept that addresses current and future threats to the international rules-based order.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary Medina’s Travel to Honolulu, Hawaii</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-medinas-travel-to-honolulu-hawaii/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 21:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica P. Medina will travel to Honolulu, Hawaii, April 7-9 to meet with officials from United States Indo-Pacific Command and the United States Coast Guard to discuss their work combating illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing.  In addition, she will visit the Hawai‘i Institute for Marine Biology to learn more about its research on climate change and marine wildlife conservation and meet with Hawaiian community leaders and nongovernmental organizations working to preserve unique island ecosystems.</p>
<p align="left">Following these activities, Assistant Secretary Medina will continue her travels to the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference,</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> which the United States will co-host with Palau in Koror, April 13-14.</p>
<p align="left">For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov.</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica P. Medina will travel to Honolulu, Hawaii, April 7-9 to meet with officials from United States Indo-Pacific Command and the United States Coast Guard to discuss their work combating illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing.  In addition, she will visit the Hawai‘i Institute for Marine Biology to learn more about its research on climate change and marine wildlife conservation and meet with Hawaiian community leaders and nongovernmental organizations working to preserve unique island ecosystems.</p>
<p align="left">Following these activities, Assistant Secretary Medina will continue her travels to the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference,</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> which the United States will co-host with Palau in Koror, April 13-14.</p>
<p align="left">For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov.</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with French, German, Italian, and UK Counterparts</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-french-german-italian-and-uk-counterparts-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 21:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332290</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian, German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock, Italian Foreign Minister Luigi Di Maio, and UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss today in Brussels, where they reiterated their commitment to supporting Ukraine in the face of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.  The Secretary again strongly condemned the reported atrocities by President Putin’s forces in Bucha and across Ukraine and called for accountability. He and his counterparts discussed how best to continue working to isolate the Russian Federation on the international stage for its flagrant violation of international law and principles, to increase pressure on the Kremlin, and to advance a swift end its devastating war against Ukraine.  They also discussed plans to provide additional humanitarian and security assistance to Ukraine.</p>
<p>Prior to this meeting, Secretary Blinken met with his E3 counterparts to discuss our common resolve to ensure that Iran never acquires a nuclear weapon. They agreed that a diplomatic solution entailing a mutual return to full implementation of the JCPOA is the best outcome, but noted that we are prepared for other scenarios if necessary.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian, German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock, Italian Foreign Minister Luigi Di Maio, and UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss today in Brussels, where they reiterated their commitment to supporting Ukraine in the face of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.  The Secretary again strongly condemned the reported atrocities by President Putin’s forces in Bucha and across Ukraine and called for accountability. He and his counterparts discussed how best to continue working to isolate the Russian Federation on the international stage for its flagrant violation of international law and principles, to increase pressure on the Kremlin, and to advance a swift end its devastating war against Ukraine.  They also discussed plans to provide additional humanitarian and security assistance to Ukraine.</p>
<p>Prior to this meeting, Secretary Blinken met with his E3 counterparts to discuss our common resolve to ensure that Iran never acquires a nuclear weapon. They agreed that a diplomatic solution entailing a mutual return to full implementation of the JCPOA is the best outcome, but noted that we are prepared for other scenarios if necessary.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Targeting Additional Russian Financial Institutions, Officials, and Other Individuals</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/targeting-additional-russian-financial-institutions-officials-and-other-individuals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 19:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332151</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is united with our allies and partners to ensure the Government of Russia pays a severe price for causing such death and destruction in Ukraine, and particularly for the horrors in Bucha and elsewhere.  In furtherance of this goal, today we are implementing full blocking sanctions on two key Russian financial institutions: Sberbank, Russia’s largest financial institution, and its subsidiaries and Alfa Bank, one of the largest private banks in Russia, and its subsidiaries. These entities continue to sustain President Putin’s aggression against Ukraine.  Accordingly, all U.S. persons are generally prohibited from engaging in transactions with Sberbank or Alfa Bank.</p>
<p>In addition, we are imposing sanctions on the adult children of President Vladimir Putin, Katerina Tikhonova and Maria Vorontsova, as well as Maria Lavrova, the wife of Russia’s Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov, and Ekaterina Lavrova, his adult child.</p>
<p>The United States is also designating 21 members of Russia’s National Security Council, including former President Dmitry Medvedev and Prime Minister Mikhail Mishustin, for their role and authority in crafting the Kremlin’s brutal policies and resulting abuses.</p>
<p>And finally, President Biden’s Executive Order today bans new investment in Russia – forcing Russia further down the road of financial and economic isolation.</p>
<p>This announcement of new economic sanctions follows our approval last night of $100 million in new security assistance to help Ukraine meet a continued need for additional anti-armor systems.  This is only the most recent of six drawdowns of arms, equipment, and supplies from Department of Defense inventories for Ukraine since August 2021, and brings U.S. military assistance to almost $2.5 billion since September, and $4.5 billion since 2014.  The United States commends the continued support of our allies and partners across the world in the face of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.  We stand with Ukraine and recognize the bravery and heroism of its people and they defend their country and their freedom against Russia’s brutal war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>United with our Allies and partners, the United States will continue to impose economic costs on Russia for their actions through economic sanctions and provide security assistance in support of Ukraine’s defense, as well as economic support and humanitarian aid for communities across Ukraine devastated by Russia’s ruthless brutality.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0705" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is united with our allies and partners to ensure the Government of Russia pays a severe price for causing such death and destruction in Ukraine, and particularly for the horrors in Bucha and elsewhere.  In furtherance of this goal, today we are implementing full blocking sanctions on two key Russian financial institutions: Sberbank, Russia’s largest financial institution, and its subsidiaries and Alfa Bank, one of the largest private banks in Russia, and its subsidiaries. These entities continue to sustain President Putin’s aggression against Ukraine.  Accordingly, all U.S. persons are generally prohibited from engaging in transactions with Sberbank or Alfa Bank.</p>
<p>In addition, we are imposing sanctions on the adult children of President Vladimir Putin, Katerina Tikhonova and Maria Vorontsova, as well as Maria Lavrova, the wife of Russia’s Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov, and Ekaterina Lavrova, his adult child.</p>
<p>The United States is also designating 21 members of Russia’s National Security Council, including former President Dmitry Medvedev and Prime Minister Mikhail Mishustin, for their role and authority in crafting the Kremlin’s brutal policies and resulting abuses.</p>
<p>And finally, President Biden’s Executive Order today bans new investment in Russia – forcing Russia further down the road of financial and economic isolation.</p>
<p>This announcement of new economic sanctions follows our approval last night of $100 million in new security assistance to help Ukraine meet a continued need for additional anti-armor systems.  This is only the most recent of six drawdowns of arms, equipment, and supplies from Department of Defense inventories for Ukraine since August 2021, and brings U.S. military assistance to almost $2.5 billion since September, and $4.5 billion since 2014.  The United States commends the continued support of our allies and partners across the world in the face of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.  We stand with Ukraine and recognize the bravery and heroism of its people and they defend their country and their freedom against Russia’s brutal war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>United with our Allies and partners, the United States will continue to impose economic costs on Russia for their actions through economic sanctions and provide security assistance in support of Ukraine’s defense, as well as economic support and humanitarian aid for communities across Ukraine devastated by Russia’s ruthless brutality.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0705" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department of State Offers Reward for Information to Bring Transnational Criminal to Justice</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/department-of-state-offers-reward-for-information-to-bring-transnational-criminal-to-justice/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 17:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332090</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department of State is offering a reward of up to $5 million for information leading to the arrest and/or conviction of Semion Mogilevich, a longtime transnational criminal currently living in Russia.  Mogilevich is wanted in the United States for his alleged participation between 1993 and 1998 in a multi-million dollar scheme to defraud thousands of investors related to a public company headquartered in Newtown, Pennsylvania.  The scheme collapsed in 1998 after thousands of investors lost more than $150 million.  Mogilevich was indicted in 2002 and again in 2003.</p>
<p>This reward is offered under the Department of State’s Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program (TOCRP), which the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs manages in close coordination with federal law enforcement partners and other U.S. government agencies.  More than 75 transnational criminals and major narcotics traffickers have been brought to justice under the TOCRP and the Narcotics Rewards Program (NRP) since the NRP’s inception in 1986, with the Department paying more than $135 million in rewards for information to-date.</p>
<p>Any information in response this reward offer should be directed to the FBI at +1-800-225-5324 (Voice), +1-215-839-6844 (WhatsApp), or online at <a class="external-link" href="https://tips.fbi.gov/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://tips.fbi.gov</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>For more information on the individuals listed above and the TOCRP, please see <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs/inl-rewards-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDYuNTYwMjY2NTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1LW9mLWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtbmFyY290aWNzLWFuZC1sYXctZW5mb3JjZW1lbnQtYWZmYWlycy9pbmwtcmV3YXJkcy1wcm9ncmFtLyJ9.vHtJLrWOE85p_foIC5JMihAc3jp6Ej2zlBJckG0Ua7Q/s/2171565732/br/129423737675-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649350926158000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1zFb-C9EQYSZOe9QiTX1IU">https://www.state.gov/bureau-<wbr />of-international-narcotics-<wbr />and-law-enforcement-affairs/<wbr />inl-rewards-program/</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department of State is offering a reward of up to $5 million for information leading to the arrest and/or conviction of Semion Mogilevich, a longtime transnational criminal currently living in Russia.  Mogilevich is wanted in the United States for his alleged participation between 1993 and 1998 in a multi-million dollar scheme to defraud thousands of investors related to a public company headquartered in Newtown, Pennsylvania.  The scheme collapsed in 1998 after thousands of investors lost more than $150 million.  Mogilevich was indicted in 2002 and again in 2003.</p>
<p>This reward is offered under the Department of State’s Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program (TOCRP), which the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs manages in close coordination with federal law enforcement partners and other U.S. government agencies.  More than 75 transnational criminals and major narcotics traffickers have been brought to justice under the TOCRP and the Narcotics Rewards Program (NRP) since the NRP’s inception in 1986, with the Department paying more than $135 million in rewards for information to-date.</p>
<p>Any information in response this reward offer should be directed to the FBI at +1-800-225-5324 (Voice), +1-215-839-6844 (WhatsApp), or online at <a class="external-link" href="https://tips.fbi.gov/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://tips.fbi.gov</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>For more information on the individuals listed above and the TOCRP, please see <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs/inl-rewards-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDYuNTYwMjY2NTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1LW9mLWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtbmFyY290aWNzLWFuZC1sYXctZW5mb3JjZW1lbnQtYWZmYWlycy9pbmwtcmV3YXJkcy1wcm9ncmFtLyJ9.vHtJLrWOE85p_foIC5JMihAc3jp6Ej2zlBJckG0Ua7Q/s/2171565732/br/129423737675-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649350926158000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1zFb-C9EQYSZOe9QiTX1IU">https://www.state.gov/bureau-<wbr />of-international-narcotics-<wbr />and-law-enforcement-affairs/<wbr />inl-rewards-program/</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Australian Foreign Minister Payne</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-australian-foreign-minister-payne-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 16:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332080</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Australian Foreign Minister Marise Payne in Brussels. The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed joint efforts to hold the Russian Federation accountable for its unprovoked and unjust war against Ukraine as well as mutual efforts to provide security assistance to Ukraine.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister reiterated their commitment to ensuring peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific region and noted the April 4 release of the AUKUS Leaders’ Statement, summarizing the progress AUKUS partners have made over the past six months.  They also shared concerns about recent regional developments and ways to support countries in making open and transparent decisions about their own security and economic interests.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Australian Foreign Minister Marise Payne in Brussels. The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed joint efforts to hold the Russian Federation accountable for its unprovoked and unjust war against Ukraine as well as mutual efforts to provide security assistance to Ukraine.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister reiterated their commitment to ensuring peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific region and noted the April 4 release of the AUKUS Leaders’ Statement, summarizing the progress AUKUS partners have made over the past six months.  They also shared concerns about recent regional developments and ways to support countries in making open and transparent decisions about their own security and economic interests.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>50th Anniversary of the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/50th-anniversary-of-the-biological-and-toxin-weapons-convention/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 15:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Fifty years ago, the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention (BTWC) was opened for signature and later became the first treaty to ban an entire category of weapons. Today, with over 180 States Parties, it is the cornerstone of international efforts to prevent biological weapons.</p>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic demonstrated the devastating impact that disease can have on the world. We must recognize that other biological risks are growing and take action to address them. We face not only an increased threat of naturally occurring diseases, but also the potential for laboratory accidents and the intentional misuse of life sciences and biotechnology. The weaponization of biological agents and toxins violates the BTWC and is unacceptable, and the use of biological weapons – in the words of the Convention – “would be repugnant to the conscience of mankind.”</p>
<p>We are determined to use the occasion of this important anniversary as a reminder of the need to strengthen and revitalize the BTWC. As we look to its Ninth Review Conference later this year, the United States urges States Parties to overcome differences and take urgent steps to guard against the development and use of biological weapons.</p>
<p>Specifically, we believe the Review Conference should take near-term, concrete action to strengthen the Convention and benefit States Parties in such areas as increasing resources for international assistance and cooperation and establishing a mechanism to review advances in science and technology. Additionally, we have proposed that the Conference establish a new expert group to study additional measures to strengthen implementation of the Convention, increase transparency, and enhance assurances of compliance. We also urge all states that have not yet become party to the BTWC to join it now, so they can play an active role in this year’s Review Conference.</p>
<p>The best way to commemorate this anniversary is for States Parties to work together to strengthen the BTWC and end the threat of biological weapons. Through our collective action to counter all biological threats – naturally occurring, accidental, and deliberate – we can make the world a safer place for all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Fifty years ago, the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention (BTWC) was opened for signature and later became the first treaty to ban an entire category of weapons. Today, with over 180 States Parties, it is the cornerstone of international efforts to prevent biological weapons.</p>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic demonstrated the devastating impact that disease can have on the world. We must recognize that other biological risks are growing and take action to address them. We face not only an increased threat of naturally occurring diseases, but also the potential for laboratory accidents and the intentional misuse of life sciences and biotechnology. The weaponization of biological agents and toxins violates the BTWC and is unacceptable, and the use of biological weapons – in the words of the Convention – “would be repugnant to the conscience of mankind.”</p>
<p>We are determined to use the occasion of this important anniversary as a reminder of the need to strengthen and revitalize the BTWC. As we look to its Ninth Review Conference later this year, the United States urges States Parties to overcome differences and take urgent steps to guard against the development and use of biological weapons.</p>
<p>Specifically, we believe the Review Conference should take near-term, concrete action to strengthen the Convention and benefit States Parties in such areas as increasing resources for international assistance and cooperation and establishing a mechanism to review advances in science and technology. Additionally, we have proposed that the Conference establish a new expert group to study additional measures to strengthen implementation of the Convention, increase transparency, and enhance assurances of compliance. We also urge all states that have not yet become party to the BTWC to join it now, so they can play an active role in this year’s Review Conference.</p>
<p>The best way to commemorate this anniversary is for States Parties to work together to strengthen the BTWC and end the threat of biological weapons. Through our collective action to counter all biological threats – naturally occurring, accidental, and deliberate – we can make the world a safer place for all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with Andrea Mitchell of NBC</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-andrea-mitchell-of-nbc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 15:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332032</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Mr. Secretary, thank you so much for being with us.  I wanted to ask you about what is going on right now.  The chairman of the Joint Chiefs had told Congress that this will likely last years, this war.  A protracted war is going to last years, according to the chairman of the Joint Chiefs.  Will today’s new commitment of Javelins, anti-tank weapons to Ukraine shorten that timeline?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Andrea, we want to see this come to an end as quickly as possible, and that’s exactly why we’re making sure that we’re doing everything we can to support Ukraine and to give them the assistance that they need to put pressure and to increase pressure on Russia, even as we’re strengthening our – the defenses of our NATO Alliance.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So what about the Javelins?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So the Javelins, we just did – the President authorized another $100 million in a drawdown that will provide more Javelins to our Ukrainian partners.  Put this in perspective:  Between the United States and other allies and partners, for every Russian tank in Ukraine, we have provided or will soon provide 10 anti-tank systems – 10 for every single Russian tank.  So in terms of what they need to act quickly and act effectively, to deal with the planes that are firing at them from the skies, the tanks that are trying to destroy their cities from the ground, they have the tools that they need, they’re going to keep getting them, and we’re going to keep sustaining that.</p>
<p>But to the chairman’s point, and the President said this as well, as much as we want to see this come to an end as soon as possible to stop the death and destruction that’s being wrought by Russia in Ukraine, there is also a very likely scenario by which this goes on for some time.  The Russians, even as they’re moving their forces, they’ve retreated from Kyiv, they’ve retreated from the north and the west, they’re consolidating forces in the east, in the Donbas.  They have a lot of force still left.  The Ukrainians have something else that’s ultimately stronger, and that is a fierce determination and will to defend their country with the support of many countries around the world.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Can they win?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So ultimately, yes, because what is success, what is victory?  It’s holding on to the sovereignty and independence of their country.  And there is no scenario by which over time that will not happen.  The problem is it may take time, and in the meantime, tremendous death and destruction.  But what is so powerful here is that the Ukrainians have made it very clear that they will not subjugate themselves to Vladimir Putin’s will.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But no matter how much we give them, how can Ukraine ever last against Russia for the long term unless the U.S. and other countries guarantee its borders, its safety, as President Zelenskyy wants?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, first things first.  The first thing is to see that this aggression by Russia comes to an end, that there is a ceasefire, that Russia withdraws its forces, that Ukraine asserts its sovereignty and its independence.  But then, yes, we have to do things to make sure that, to the best of our ability and Ukraine’s ability, this can’t happen again, that Russia is deterred, that Ukraine is defended.  We’re having constant conversations with &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will we guarantee that?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So we’re having &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will the U.S. get more involved?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We’re having constant conversations with our Ukrainian partners pretty much on a daily basis, including about what it is we and others could do in the event of a successful negotiation to defend them and help them defend themselves going forward.  All of this is the subject of conversations right now.  I’m not going to get ahead of that, but we’re going to do everything we can, others will do what they can to make sure that Ukraine can defend itself and deter aggression being repeated by Russia.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  President Putin has said he wants to recreate the Soviet Union, the glory of the Soviet Union.  With those ambitions, how can Ukraine ever be safe as long as Putin’s in power?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, two things:  First, in terms of what Russia set out to do, what Putin set out to do in Ukraine, this has already been a strategic setback, if not a failure.  Because keep in mind, Andrea, the goal that Putin set in his own words was to eliminate Ukraine’s sovereignty and independence.  He sees it as a state that doesn’t deserve to be independent, that needs to be subsumed back into some kind of greater Russia.  That is not happening, not just the retreat from Kyiv but the fact that no matter how you play this out the Ukrainians are not going to subject themselves to a Russian dictatorship.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  He’s more popular than ever at home.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So he may be for now more popular.  Of course, if you were getting fed a steady diet, morning, noon, and night of propaganda, which unfortunately the Russian people are, that speaks to what popularity he has.  At the same time, when people are responding to polls, they may be very much afraid of giving the truthful answer.  There’s now a 15-year criminal penalty for anyone who in any way opposes the so-called special military operation.  So you have to take that with a grain of salt.</p>
<p>Having said that, I think there is a real fundamental problem, which is the Russians don’t get the factual information that they need to make judgments for themselves, and that’s because of a system that Vladimir Putin has perfected in which that information is denied them.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  President Biden has called Putin a butcher, a war criminal.  You have said that the people responsible for the crimes in Bucha and those who ordered them will be held accountable.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  That’s right.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  How can that happen without Vladimir Putin standing trial?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  First, Andrea, the wheels of accountability can move slowly, but they move, and someday, someway, somewhere, those who committed these crimes and those who ordered the crimes will be held accountable.  But it takes time, and part of this is building the case, part of this is – which we’re doing and others are doing.  Part – there’s a Ukrainian special prosecutor who is working on this.  We’re supporting her efforts.  We set up at the United Nations at the Human Rights Council a Commission of Inquiry that’s looking into this as well.  We’re supporting those efforts, building the case, getting the evidence, documenting it.  The International Criminal Court is looking at this too.</p>
<p>But all of this will play out over time, and we have to build the case, we have to get the evidence, we have to document it – we’re doing all of that.  So is that next month, next year, in five years?  It could take time, but I think – I can guarantee you there will be a relentless effort to make sure that those responsible for what we’re seeing are held accountable.  And what we’re seeing, Andrea, is I think beyond what any of us even could fully anticipate.  We said before Russia committed this aggression that there would be atrocities, that it was a deliberate part of their campaign.  And even knowing that, when this Russian tide receded from Bucha and we saw the death and destruction left in its wake, and we saw what that looked like, including people who had been assassinated – and in fact, their hands tied – executed, their hands tied behind their backs – the abuse committed against women, against children, it’s horrific.  And there has to be accountability for it.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Did you see the video that President Zelenskyy provided to the United Nations, or other images from Bucha?  As you describe it, the atrocities, you have small children.  What do you tell your children?  What would you tell them?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, thankfully, they’re too small to actually see that, be able to digest it and to understand it.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But some day, they’ll – they will &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  But some day they will.  And I have to tell you, Andrea, I think – and I suspect most of us have the same reaction, especially those of who have children or even small children – you put yourself in the shoes of the father, the mother, the grandfather, the grandmother who’s in the middle of this, who is suffering this, whose kids’ lives are at stake or in jeopardy, or who have been lost.  And it hits you – I said the other day, seeing these images from Bucha was like a punch to the gut.  It takes the wind out of you.  You can know something intellectually, but then when you see these images and you translate that into your own life, when you ask yourself, “What if this was happening in my town, to my kids?  To my family?”  I think it only reinforces our determination to do everything we can to support the Ukrainians, to put pressure on Russia, to bring this to an end as quickly as possible.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Your UN ambassador, Linda Thomas-Greenfield, described these atrocities and compared it by extension to the Holocaust.  Talked about what the council in Mariupol had described, people forcibly – tens of thousands – taken from their homes, taken to Russia and put in camps.  Isn’t that the very definition of genocide?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, we have to get all of the information, all of the evidence.  We have to, as I said, document everything that’s happened, fully understand what’s happened.  It’s an interesting irony in a sense.  This is in some ways the most documented war in real time that we’ve experienced because of technology, because of smart phones, because of the incredible courage of reporters who remained in Ukraine.  But even so, the things that we’re not seeing in real time, including Bucha – and it’s only when that tide recedes that you see what’s actually happened.</p>
<p>So I think we’re going to learn a lot more in the days and weeks ahead.  I’m afraid that what we’re going to learn is even more horrifying.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Do we know anything about what’s happening in these Russian camps with Ukrainians, and do we have any hope of getting them back?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We don’t have good information on that, but certainly we’re doing everything we can.  Other countries are doing everything they can to make sure that anyone who is being detained is released.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  The U.S. has promised to take in 100,000 of these millions of refugees.  Europe has opened their doors, put them in their homes.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  They have.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  NBC has reported on at least two women, two Ukrainian women on the southern border, who were taken and for two weeks put behind barbed wire and at times shackled in an ICE camp.  How can we do that compared to the way Europe is welcoming them?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, I’m not aware of those reports.  It’s something I’ll certainly look into.  But here’s what’s going on.  First, Europeans have been extraordinary in their generosity, in opening their hearts, opening their arms, opening their homes to so many people.  Our friends in Poland, in the first instance, have had more than 2 million people come through Poland.  Many of the refugees – most of them, in fact – want to stay close to home because what you’re seeing, Andrea – and I know you’ve seen this firsthand – is virtually everyone is a woman and children.  Most of the men between 18 and 60 have stayed in Ukraine to fight.  They like to stay close at hand.  They want to go back, they want to be reunited with their husbands, with their brothers, with their sons.  And once they’re in Europe, they also have a lot of freedom of movement and the ability to reunite with other family members there.</p>
<p>Having said that, President Biden made clear that we will welcome 100,000 Ukrainians.  We’re ‑‑</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Is there a time frame?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So it’s over a period of time.  What we’re doing right now is looking at what are the legal pathways that we can do that because there’s the normal refugee program, but that, by definition, takes a long time.  It takes a couple years –</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Quick question before we lose time: sanctions.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Yeah.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  New sanctions, now Europe is putting on new sanctions.  China and India keep buying fuel from Russia and fueling this war, helping to fund Putin’s war.  Why aren’t we sanctioning China and India?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So in the first instance, Andrea, these sanctions are having a dramatic impact.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But there are big loopholes, and Europe still is buying natural gas and still will for another year.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  There are loopholes that, piece by piece, one by one, we’re trying to close.  Sometimes that takes time.  But let’s look at what’s already happened.  The sanctions cumulatively have put the Russian economy into a deep recession.  And what we’re seeing is a likely contraction of the Russian economy by about 15 percent.  That is dramatic.  We’ve seen something else.  We’ve seen an exodus from Russia of virtually every major company in the world.  And Putin, in the space of a matter of weeks, has basically shut down Russia to the world.  All of the opening, all of the opportunity that took place over the last 30 years is gone.  And the Russians will feel that, I’m afraid, in their daily lives.  They won’t be able to buy the things they’re used to buying, and they won’t be able to afford to buy what they’d like to buy.</p>
<p>And beyond that, the export controls that we put in place, denying Russia the technology that it needs to modernize critical industries like defense, like energy extraction – over time, those are going to have an even greater impact.</p>
<p>So we’re already seeing a dramatic impact to this.  And yes, there are places where different countries are doing different things.  We’re working every single day to close that down.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Quick question on Iran before I let you go.  You’re talking about Iran here in Brussels.  Is Iran’s Revolutionary Guard – which has attacked Americans and our allies – a terrorist organization?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So, they are.  And &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will they continue to be?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I’m not going to get into the details of where we are on the negotiations.  I would say simply that I’m not overly optimistic at the prospects of actually getting an agreement to conclusion, despite all the efforts we put into it and despite the fact that I believe we would be – our security would be better off.  We’re not there.  We’ll have to see if we can close &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Is time running out?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  And time is getting extremely short.  But this is something that we’ll be talking to our European partners about this afternoon and then over the course of the next day.  We’ve been working in very close coordination with the Europeans, with the European Union, with France, with Germany, with the UK.</p>
<p>So we’ll see where we get.  I continue to believe it would be in the best interests of our country if we can get back into compliance with the deal, if Iran will do the same.  We’re not there.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  Thanks for your patience.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks, Andrea.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Good to see you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  You as well.  Thanks.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Mr. Secretary, thank you so much for being with us.  I wanted to ask you about what is going on right now.  The chairman of the Joint Chiefs had told Congress that this will likely last years, this war.  A protracted war is going to last years, according to the chairman of the Joint Chiefs.  Will today’s new commitment of Javelins, anti-tank weapons to Ukraine shorten that timeline?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Andrea, we want to see this come to an end as quickly as possible, and that’s exactly why we’re making sure that we’re doing everything we can to support Ukraine and to give them the assistance that they need to put pressure and to increase pressure on Russia, even as we’re strengthening our – the defenses of our NATO Alliance.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So what about the Javelins?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So the Javelins, we just did – the President authorized another $100 million in a drawdown that will provide more Javelins to our Ukrainian partners.  Put this in perspective:  Between the United States and other allies and partners, for every Russian tank in Ukraine, we have provided or will soon provide 10 anti-tank systems – 10 for every single Russian tank.  So in terms of what they need to act quickly and act effectively, to deal with the planes that are firing at them from the skies, the tanks that are trying to destroy their cities from the ground, they have the tools that they need, they’re going to keep getting them, and we’re going to keep sustaining that.</p>
<p>But to the chairman’s point, and the President said this as well, as much as we want to see this come to an end as soon as possible to stop the death and destruction that’s being wrought by Russia in Ukraine, there is also a very likely scenario by which this goes on for some time.  The Russians, even as they’re moving their forces, they’ve retreated from Kyiv, they’ve retreated from the north and the west, they’re consolidating forces in the east, in the Donbas.  They have a lot of force still left.  The Ukrainians have something else that’s ultimately stronger, and that is a fierce determination and will to defend their country with the support of many countries around the world.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Can they win?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So ultimately, yes, because what is success, what is victory?  It’s holding on to the sovereignty and independence of their country.  And there is no scenario by which over time that will not happen.  The problem is it may take time, and in the meantime, tremendous death and destruction.  But what is so powerful here is that the Ukrainians have made it very clear that they will not subjugate themselves to Vladimir Putin’s will.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But no matter how much we give them, how can Ukraine ever last against Russia for the long term unless the U.S. and other countries guarantee its borders, its safety, as President Zelenskyy wants?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, first things first.  The first thing is to see that this aggression by Russia comes to an end, that there is a ceasefire, that Russia withdraws its forces, that Ukraine asserts its sovereignty and its independence.  But then, yes, we have to do things to make sure that, to the best of our ability and Ukraine’s ability, this can’t happen again, that Russia is deterred, that Ukraine is defended.  We’re having constant conversations with &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will we guarantee that?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So we’re having &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will the U.S. get more involved?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We’re having constant conversations with our Ukrainian partners pretty much on a daily basis, including about what it is we and others could do in the event of a successful negotiation to defend them and help them defend themselves going forward.  All of this is the subject of conversations right now.  I’m not going to get ahead of that, but we’re going to do everything we can, others will do what they can to make sure that Ukraine can defend itself and deter aggression being repeated by Russia.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  President Putin has said he wants to recreate the Soviet Union, the glory of the Soviet Union.  With those ambitions, how can Ukraine ever be safe as long as Putin’s in power?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, two things:  First, in terms of what Russia set out to do, what Putin set out to do in Ukraine, this has already been a strategic setback, if not a failure.  Because keep in mind, Andrea, the goal that Putin set in his own words was to eliminate Ukraine’s sovereignty and independence.  He sees it as a state that doesn’t deserve to be independent, that needs to be subsumed back into some kind of greater Russia.  That is not happening, not just the retreat from Kyiv but the fact that no matter how you play this out the Ukrainians are not going to subject themselves to a Russian dictatorship.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  He’s more popular than ever at home.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So he may be for now more popular.  Of course, if you were getting fed a steady diet, morning, noon, and night of propaganda, which unfortunately the Russian people are, that speaks to what popularity he has.  At the same time, when people are responding to polls, they may be very much afraid of giving the truthful answer.  There’s now a 15-year criminal penalty for anyone who in any way opposes the so-called special military operation.  So you have to take that with a grain of salt.</p>
<p>Having said that, I think there is a real fundamental problem, which is the Russians don’t get the factual information that they need to make judgments for themselves, and that’s because of a system that Vladimir Putin has perfected in which that information is denied them.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  President Biden has called Putin a butcher, a war criminal.  You have said that the people responsible for the crimes in Bucha and those who ordered them will be held accountable.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  That’s right.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  How can that happen without Vladimir Putin standing trial?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  First, Andrea, the wheels of accountability can move slowly, but they move, and someday, someway, somewhere, those who committed these crimes and those who ordered the crimes will be held accountable.  But it takes time, and part of this is building the case, part of this is – which we’re doing and others are doing.  Part – there’s a Ukrainian special prosecutor who is working on this.  We’re supporting her efforts.  We set up at the United Nations at the Human Rights Council a Commission of Inquiry that’s looking into this as well.  We’re supporting those efforts, building the case, getting the evidence, documenting it.  The International Criminal Court is looking at this too.</p>
<p>But all of this will play out over time, and we have to build the case, we have to get the evidence, we have to document it – we’re doing all of that.  So is that next month, next year, in five years?  It could take time, but I think – I can guarantee you there will be a relentless effort to make sure that those responsible for what we’re seeing are held accountable.  And what we’re seeing, Andrea, is I think beyond what any of us even could fully anticipate.  We said before Russia committed this aggression that there would be atrocities, that it was a deliberate part of their campaign.  And even knowing that, when this Russian tide receded from Bucha and we saw the death and destruction left in its wake, and we saw what that looked like, including people who had been assassinated – and in fact, their hands tied – executed, their hands tied behind their backs – the abuse committed against women, against children, it’s horrific.  And there has to be accountability for it.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Did you see the video that President Zelenskyy provided to the United Nations, or other images from Bucha?  As you describe it, the atrocities, you have small children.  What do you tell your children?  What would you tell them?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, thankfully, they’re too small to actually see that, be able to digest it and to understand it.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But some day, they’ll – they will &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  But some day they will.  And I have to tell you, Andrea, I think – and I suspect most of us have the same reaction, especially those of who have children or even small children – you put yourself in the shoes of the father, the mother, the grandfather, the grandmother who’s in the middle of this, who is suffering this, whose kids’ lives are at stake or in jeopardy, or who have been lost.  And it hits you – I said the other day, seeing these images from Bucha was like a punch to the gut.  It takes the wind out of you.  You can know something intellectually, but then when you see these images and you translate that into your own life, when you ask yourself, “What if this was happening in my town, to my kids?  To my family?”  I think it only reinforces our determination to do everything we can to support the Ukrainians, to put pressure on Russia, to bring this to an end as quickly as possible.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Your UN ambassador, Linda Thomas-Greenfield, described these atrocities and compared it by extension to the Holocaust.  Talked about what the council in Mariupol had described, people forcibly – tens of thousands – taken from their homes, taken to Russia and put in camps.  Isn’t that the very definition of genocide?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, we have to get all of the information, all of the evidence.  We have to, as I said, document everything that’s happened, fully understand what’s happened.  It’s an interesting irony in a sense.  This is in some ways the most documented war in real time that we’ve experienced because of technology, because of smart phones, because of the incredible courage of reporters who remained in Ukraine.  But even so, the things that we’re not seeing in real time, including Bucha – and it’s only when that tide recedes that you see what’s actually happened.</p>
<p>So I think we’re going to learn a lot more in the days and weeks ahead.  I’m afraid that what we’re going to learn is even more horrifying.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Do we know anything about what’s happening in these Russian camps with Ukrainians, and do we have any hope of getting them back?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We don’t have good information on that, but certainly we’re doing everything we can.  Other countries are doing everything they can to make sure that anyone who is being detained is released.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  The U.S. has promised to take in 100,000 of these millions of refugees.  Europe has opened their doors, put them in their homes.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  They have.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  NBC has reported on at least two women, two Ukrainian women on the southern border, who were taken and for two weeks put behind barbed wire and at times shackled in an ICE camp.  How can we do that compared to the way Europe is welcoming them?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, I’m not aware of those reports.  It’s something I’ll certainly look into.  But here’s what’s going on.  First, Europeans have been extraordinary in their generosity, in opening their hearts, opening their arms, opening their homes to so many people.  Our friends in Poland, in the first instance, have had more than 2 million people come through Poland.  Many of the refugees – most of them, in fact – want to stay close to home because what you’re seeing, Andrea – and I know you’ve seen this firsthand – is virtually everyone is a woman and children.  Most of the men between 18 and 60 have stayed in Ukraine to fight.  They like to stay close at hand.  They want to go back, they want to be reunited with their husbands, with their brothers, with their sons.  And once they’re in Europe, they also have a lot of freedom of movement and the ability to reunite with other family members there.</p>
<p>Having said that, President Biden made clear that we will welcome 100,000 Ukrainians.  We’re ‑‑</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Is there a time frame?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So it’s over a period of time.  What we’re doing right now is looking at what are the legal pathways that we can do that because there’s the normal refugee program, but that, by definition, takes a long time.  It takes a couple years –</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Quick question before we lose time: sanctions.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Yeah.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  New sanctions, now Europe is putting on new sanctions.  China and India keep buying fuel from Russia and fueling this war, helping to fund Putin’s war.  Why aren’t we sanctioning China and India?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So in the first instance, Andrea, these sanctions are having a dramatic impact.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But there are big loopholes, and Europe still is buying natural gas and still will for another year.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  There are loopholes that, piece by piece, one by one, we’re trying to close.  Sometimes that takes time.  But let’s look at what’s already happened.  The sanctions cumulatively have put the Russian economy into a deep recession.  And what we’re seeing is a likely contraction of the Russian economy by about 15 percent.  That is dramatic.  We’ve seen something else.  We’ve seen an exodus from Russia of virtually every major company in the world.  And Putin, in the space of a matter of weeks, has basically shut down Russia to the world.  All of the opening, all of the opportunity that took place over the last 30 years is gone.  And the Russians will feel that, I’m afraid, in their daily lives.  They won’t be able to buy the things they’re used to buying, and they won’t be able to afford to buy what they’d like to buy.</p>
<p>And beyond that, the export controls that we put in place, denying Russia the technology that it needs to modernize critical industries like defense, like energy extraction – over time, those are going to have an even greater impact.</p>
<p>So we’re already seeing a dramatic impact to this.  And yes, there are places where different countries are doing different things.  We’re working every single day to close that down.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Quick question on Iran before I let you go.  You’re talking about Iran here in Brussels.  Is Iran’s Revolutionary Guard – which has attacked Americans and our allies – a terrorist organization?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So, they are.  And &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will they continue to be?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I’m not going to get into the details of where we are on the negotiations.  I would say simply that I’m not overly optimistic at the prospects of actually getting an agreement to conclusion, despite all the efforts we put into it and despite the fact that I believe we would be – our security would be better off.  We’re not there.  We’ll have to see if we can close &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Is time running out?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  And time is getting extremely short.  But this is something that we’ll be talking to our European partners about this afternoon and then over the course of the next day.  We’ve been working in very close coordination with the Europeans, with the European Union, with France, with Germany, with the UK.</p>
<p>So we’ll see where we get.  I continue to believe it would be in the best interests of our country if we can get back into compliance with the deal, if Iran will do the same.  We’re not there.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  Thanks for your patience.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks, Andrea.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Good to see you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  You as well.  Thanks.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
