<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 14:44:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Anzac Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/anzac-day-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 14:44:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336248</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I am honored to commemorate Anzac Day this April 25, 2022, together with all Australians and New Zealanders.</p>
<p>Today we honor the memory of the heroes of Gallipoli and pay tribute to all those who served, and currently serve, in the defense forces of Australia and New Zealand.  These brave men and women fought courageously to defend freedom and democracy, and we are forever grateful.</p>
<p>We, too, will remember them.</p>
<p>More than a century after that fateful battle, the United States remains a proud partner of Australia and New Zealand.  Together, our democracies will continue to advance prosperity, security, and liberty in the Indo-Pacific in the century to come.</p>
<p>I send the highest regards and appreciation for our abiding and deep friendship to all Australians and New Zealanders on this historic day.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I am honored to commemorate Anzac Day this April 25, 2022, together with all Australians and New Zealanders.</p>
<p>Today we honor the memory of the heroes of Gallipoli and pay tribute to all those who served, and currently serve, in the defense forces of Australia and New Zealand.  These brave men and women fought courageously to defend freedom and democracy, and we are forever grateful.</p>
<p>We, too, will remember them.</p>
<p>More than a century after that fateful battle, the United States remains a proud partner of Australia and New Zealand.  Together, our democracies will continue to advance prosperity, security, and liberty in the Indo-Pacific in the century to come.</p>
<p>I send the highest regards and appreciation for our abiding and deep friendship to all Australians and New Zealanders on this historic day.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Greek Prime Minister Mitsotakis</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-greek-prime-minister-mitsotakis-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 14:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336240</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Greek Prime Minister Mitsotakis.  The Secretary thanked Greece for its steadfast support to Ukraine, including Greece’s strong sanctions enforcement and its extensive humanitarian and defensive assistance.  The two discussed additional ways to assist Ukraine as it defends itself against Russia’s unprovoked and brutal war.  The Secretary and Prime Minister also discussed an upcoming meeting of the 3+1 mechanism to strengthen energy and economic cooperation between Greece, the Republic of Cyprus, and Israel, plus the United States and advance our goals, bolstered by shared democratic ideals, for regional stability and prosperity.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Greek Prime Minister Mitsotakis.  The Secretary thanked Greece for its steadfast support to Ukraine, including Greece’s strong sanctions enforcement and its extensive humanitarian and defensive assistance.  The two discussed additional ways to assist Ukraine as it defends itself against Russia’s unprovoked and brutal war.  The Secretary and Prime Minister also discussed an upcoming meeting of the 3+1 mechanism to strengthen energy and economic cooperation between Greece, the Republic of Cyprus, and Israel, plus the United States and advance our goals, bolstered by shared democratic ideals, for regional stability and prosperity.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>$800 Million in Additional U.S. Security Assistance for Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/800-million-in-additional-u-s-security-assistance-for-ukraine-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 14:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336232</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Since Russian President Vladimir Putin launched his premeditated, unprovoked, unjustified, and brutal war on Ukraine, the ceaseless bombardment of Ukraine’s cities and critical infrastructure by Russia’s forces has created one of the fastest-growing humanitarian crises in decades.  This is a tragic and catastrophic war of choice entirely of Russia’s making, and the United States, its Allies, and partners will stand in solidarity with the people of Ukraine in their just cause  ̶  the defense of their country and their democracy. Together, we continue to support Ukraine’s defense of its sovereignty and territorial integrity and to strengthen Ukraine’s position on the battlefield and at the negotiating table.</p>
<p>Today, as Russia begins its renewed offensive in Ukraine’s east, I have authorized, pursuant to a delegation from the President, a drawdown to provide further immediate military assistance to Ukraine, valued at up to $800 million worth of arms and equipment from U.S. Department of Defense inventories.  This authorization, building on last week’s $800 million package, is the eighth drawdown of arms, equipment, and supplies from Department of Defense inventories for Ukraine since August 2021.</p>
<p>We will continue to provide Ukraine the arms its forces are effectively using on the ground to defend themselves.  These efforts, combined with direct U.S. humanitarian and financial support to Ukraine, support documenting evidence of Russia’s war crimes against Ukraine’s civilians, and continued efforts to ratchet up pressure on Putin’s crumbling economy together will help weaken the Russian Government’s position and further isolate them from the world until Russia ends its unprovoked and unjustified war on Ukraine.</p>
<p>For almost eight weeks, Russia has waged its savage assault against Ukraine, its sovereignty, its independence, its freedom, and its people.  From Bucha to Kramatorsk, from Kharkiv to Mariupol, we have seen Russia’s brutalities and its atrocities laid bare for the world to see.  And yet Ukrainian Winter has turned to Ukrainian Spring.  The people of Ukraine will prevail.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Since Russian President Vladimir Putin launched his premeditated, unprovoked, unjustified, and brutal war on Ukraine, the ceaseless bombardment of Ukraine’s cities and critical infrastructure by Russia’s forces has created one of the fastest-growing humanitarian crises in decades.  This is a tragic and catastrophic war of choice entirely of Russia’s making, and the United States, its Allies, and partners will stand in solidarity with the people of Ukraine in their just cause  ̶  the defense of their country and their democracy. Together, we continue to support Ukraine’s defense of its sovereignty and territorial integrity and to strengthen Ukraine’s position on the battlefield and at the negotiating table.</p>
<p>Today, as Russia begins its renewed offensive in Ukraine’s east, I have authorized, pursuant to a delegation from the President, a drawdown to provide further immediate military assistance to Ukraine, valued at up to $800 million worth of arms and equipment from U.S. Department of Defense inventories.  This authorization, building on last week’s $800 million package, is the eighth drawdown of arms, equipment, and supplies from Department of Defense inventories for Ukraine since August 2021.</p>
<p>We will continue to provide Ukraine the arms its forces are effectively using on the ground to defend themselves.  These efforts, combined with direct U.S. humanitarian and financial support to Ukraine, support documenting evidence of Russia’s war crimes against Ukraine’s civilians, and continued efforts to ratchet up pressure on Putin’s crumbling economy together will help weaken the Russian Government’s position and further isolate them from the world until Russia ends its unprovoked and unjustified war on Ukraine.</p>
<p>For almost eight weeks, Russia has waged its savage assault against Ukraine, its sovereignty, its independence, its freedom, and its people.  From Bucha to Kramatorsk, from Kharkiv to Mariupol, we have seen Russia’s brutalities and its atrocities laid bare for the world to see.  And yet Ukrainian Winter has turned to Ukrainian Spring.  The people of Ukraine will prevail.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with European External Action Service Secretary General Sannino</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-european-external-action-service-secretary-general-sannino-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 14:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336216</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Wendy Sherman met today in Brussels with European External Action Service Secretary General Stefano Sannino prior to their participation in the third High-Level Meeting of the U.S.-EU Dialogue on China.  Deputy Secretary Sherman welcomed the EU’s efforts to provide significant economic, military, and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  They agreed to continue close U.S.-EU coordination to support Ukraine and hold the Russian Federation accountable for Putin’s unprovoked war and abhorrent attacks on civilians in Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Wendy Sherman met today in Brussels with European External Action Service Secretary General Stefano Sannino prior to their participation in the third High-Level Meeting of the U.S.-EU Dialogue on China.  Deputy Secretary Sherman welcomed the EU’s efforts to provide significant economic, military, and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  They agreed to continue close U.S.-EU coordination to support Ukraine and hold the Russian Federation accountable for Putin’s unprovoked war and abhorrent attacks on civilians in Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Head of Cabinet of the European Commission President Seibert</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-head-of-cabinet-of-the-european-commission-president-seibert/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 14:06:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336213</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today in Brussels with Bjoern Seibert, Head of Cabinet of the European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen. They agreed to continue the close and coordinated transatlantic efforts to support the Ukrainian people and impose severe costs on the Russian Federation for Putin’s war of choice and the abhorrent attacks on civilians in Ukraine.  Both sides underscored a continuing commitment to urge the People’s Republic of China not to circumvent or undermine sanctions against Russia, and not to provide any form of support for Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.  Deputy Secretary Sherman reaffirmed the United States’ support for the formal opening of EU accession negotiations with North Macedonia and Albania as soon as possible.  Both sides highlighted the importance of the Trans-Atlantic Data Privacy Framework to our economies and societies, and committed to its swift implementation.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today in Brussels with Bjoern Seibert, Head of Cabinet of the European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen. They agreed to continue the close and coordinated transatlantic efforts to support the Ukrainian people and impose severe costs on the Russian Federation for Putin’s war of choice and the abhorrent attacks on civilians in Ukraine.  Both sides underscored a continuing commitment to urge the People’s Republic of China not to circumvent or undermine sanctions against Russia, and not to provide any form of support for Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.  Deputy Secretary Sherman reaffirmed the United States’ support for the formal opening of EU accession negotiations with North Macedonia and Albania as soon as possible.  Both sides highlighted the importance of the Trans-Atlantic Data Privacy Framework to our economies and societies, and committed to its swift implementation.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Homeland Security Secretary Alejandro Mayorkas, Panamanian Foreign Minister Erika Mouynes, and Panamanian Public Security Minister Juan Manuel Pino Forero at a Joint Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-homeland-security-secretary-alejandro-mayorkas-panamanian-foreign-minister-erika-mouynes-and-panamanian-public-security-minister-juan-manuel-pino-forero-at-a-joint-pr/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 20:14:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336078</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Panama City, Panama</p>
<p>Westin Playa Bonita Panama</p>
<p><strong>MR VASQUEZ:</strong>  (Via interpreter) A very good morning to you all, and welcome to the press conference called by Erika Mouynes, Minister of Foreign Affairs, after the ministerial on migration where the national government talks about joint actions to deal with the growing phenomenon of irregular migration at the highest level.  It is my honor to leave you with Minister Erika Mouynes, Minister of Foreign Affairs.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MOUYNES:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Good morning, everyone.  Thank you very much for your interest.  Before getting to the questions, I would like to establish what I think is a vital agreement or vital achievement of the ministerial meeting held in Panama, the great welcome at which this has been received at the highest level – ministers of foreign affairs, defense, development banks, international organizations – 31 delegations were here.  Their very presence is a show of support, and the involvement of the United States, the declared destination of most migrants who cross through our country, has been fundamental.</p>
<p>Over a year ago, when we made a call to attention about the unprecedented increase regarding migrants crossing our borders, we were facing a regional migration crisis.  The cooperation between countries of origin, of transit, and destination countries for transcontinental migration was shown to be an efficient alternative to combat this unstoppable phenomenon, but we cannot relax.  Reality is what it is, and we need a regional strategy that is ongoing when facing these issues.  We must continue with the work that we have started.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>MR VASQUEZ:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  We will now hear from His Excellency Secretary Blinken, Secretary of State from the United States of America.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.  It is a pleasure to be in Panama, the bridge of the world and the heart of the universe, with Foreign<strong> </strong>Minister Mouynes, Minister of Security Pino, and my friend and colleague Secretary Mayorkas.  I also want to start by thanking our outstanding embassy team here in Panama City, including our chargé d&#8217;affaires, Stewart Tuttle, for their great work in sustaining and strengthening our friendship with Panama.   So we have just concluded a set of ministerial meetings to discuss a challenge that affects all 22 countries represented here: managing migration in our hemisphere.  Precisely because it affects all of us, this is a challenge that we have to solve together, and that was at the heart of our discussions today.</p>
<p>Here in Panama we talked about some of the most urgent aspects of this issue, including helping stabilize and strengthen communities that are hosting migrants and refugees; creating more legal pathways to reinforce safe, orderly, and humane migration; dealing with the root causes of irregular migration by growing economic opportunity, fighting corruption, increasing citizen security, combating the climate crisis, improving democratic governance that’s responsive to people’s needs.</p>
<p>Yesterday Panama and the United States signed an arrangement to increase our bilateral cooperation across all of these issues.  This is the second one we’ve made.  The first was with Costa Rica.  We hope to announce more in the coming weeks and months.  This is how we deepen our coordination and this is how we make more progress in helping vulnerable people, support communities, and protect the security of our borders.  Our work together is going to continue at the Summit of the Americas in June, where we hope that leaders from across the region will be able to lay out shared principles for a shared response to regional migration and forced displacement.</p>
<p>I also want to mention the international organizations that joined us here in Panama.  They are critical partners in everything that we’re working to do – the International Organization for Migration, the International Committee of the Red Cross, the Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights, the UN High Commissioner for Refugees, UNICEF, the World Bank – and also equally important partners, multilateral development banks, they joined us here as well, including the Andean Development Corporation, the Central American Bank for Economic Integration, the Inter-American Development Bank, and the International Monetary Fund.  This is the kind of cross-cutting coordination that the challenges of irregular migration demand.  We’re grateful for everyone’s participation and everyone’s contributions.</p>
<p>I want to thank the Government of Panama for being a leader, a partner on this issue, and for bringing all of us together for two days of what were productive talks, productive planning, and action.  As President Cortizo and I discussed yesterday, the partnership between Panama and the United States is one of the strongest that we have in the Americas.  Our countries work together every single day on the issues that matter most to our people.  Our economic relationship is strong, with more than $13 billion in bilateral trade between us that’s supporting thousands of jobs in both our countries, and 72 percent of all goods that travel through the Panama Canal are either going to or coming from the United States.</p>
<p>We’re proud to be the largest humanitarian donor to international organizations in Panama, and their work complements Panama’s own assistance to migrants and refugees.  We’re working closely on counterterrorism and counternarcotics through our security cooperation and combating organized crime and money laundering through law enforcement cooperation.</p>
<p>We’re also fighting COVID-19 together.  More than 70 percent of Panama’s population is fully vaccinated, a remarkable achievement that that the United States was proud to support with a donation of more than 500,000 Pfizer vaccine doses.</p>
<p>We applaud Panama’s leadership on climate, including the work that you’ve done on reforestation and decreasing energy emissions.</p>
<p>And our countries stand together to support shared values here at home and around the world.  We value Panama’s strong voice in the region on democracy.  We stand with Panama’s voice to strengthen its own democratic governance, fighting corruption.  And we appreciate how Panama stood firmly against Russia’s unprovoked war of aggression against Ukraine and affirmed the principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity that lie at the heart of the United Nations Charter.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Secretary Mayorkas and I visited the Panama Canal, something that I’ve – like so many millions of people – read about, studied.  But when you see it, as I did for the first time, it really gives you a – gives you pause at the extraordinary feat of human engineering, human ingenuity, but also the powerful symbol of the historical partnership between our countries, a reminder that Panama is at the center of so much global economic activity and connection – a gateway between the continents and oceans, a leader in the region and beyond, a true friend and partner to the United States.  And for that, we’re very thankful.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR VASQUEZ:</strong>  (Via interpreter) His Excellency Pino, Minister of Public Safety.</p>
<p><strong>SECURITY MINISTER PINO:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Good morning, everyone.  First of all, I would like to thank you for this time that we have spent together while working out in the field and working bilateral meetings and in multilateral meetings as well.  We have tackled this issue from many angles.  I thank Secretary Mayorkas for going with us to (inaudible), which is (inaudible) as has been said, because it is a way of understanding what happens to migrants as they travel through Panama.</p>
<p>First of all, Panama, in order to strengthen the willingness to work on this issue of global concern, migration, signed a letter of intent where it reaffirms its willingness to continue to deal with this issue on the – at the bilateral level with the United States, where we&#8217;d have an historic relationship in the area of security, which must be supported increasingly every day because these issues must be dealt with in a timely manner quickly, because these are issues that affect the future.  Migration is here due to changes that are happening at the global level, so I appreciate this visit.  And Panama here reaffirms its willingness to continue to work on this via the signing of the letter of intent.</p>
<p>Finally, I led issue number two, the working group for security, with ministers and vice ministers of security as well as delegations of (inaudible) countries who are with us here.  It is clearly reflected – we saw the good intentions – and for the first time, I was able to see how at the multilateral level we tackle this scourge.  We saw examples of how different countries deal with the issue.  And now we must bring our efforts together and act quickly because migratory flows will continue and will increase.</p>
<p>We saw the need to promote stabilization, control measures, awareness campaigns, and preventing irregular migration.  And the risks that are linked to this phenomenon – transit routes must be safer.  We must harmonize migratory policies.  We must preserve the environment.  We need to look at new schemes and more work-related migration schemes – traceability – we need technology and tools; we need to exchange information in a timely fashion.  And we must improve our cooperation in order to improve security in the region.</p>
<p>During my time as minister of security and during my career in security agencies, I’ve never seen a meeting that was as aligned around one single issue – a common issue – where countries have come to an agreement.  We have set forth a route, but this route and the destination – we must travel this route quickly.  And I can say and affirm that there is a great deal of willingness on behalf of the countries who participated, and I appreciate that.  I appreciate that call that was made through the Panamanian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, because this is a golden opportunity, and we must continue to build on this issue for a better future for our countries.  Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><strong>MR VASQUEZ:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Words now from Secretary of DHS Alejandro Mayorkas from the U.S.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY MAYORKAS:  </strong>Good morning.  Our gratitude to President Cortizo, Ministers Mouynes and Pino for convening, hosting, and welcoming us here in beautiful Panama.  By bringing us together from across this region, we are demonstrating the commitment shared by each one of us and our nations to resolve, to address our joint hemispheric challenge of irregular migration, its impacts, its complexities, and the factors causing it.</p>
<p>These issues have tested our governments and our citizens in the United States, Panama, and throughout the Americas.  And this task has been made more difficult and more urgent in the face of an ongoing pandemic, natural disasters worsened by climate change, threats to public safety and economic security, and much more.</p>
<p>None of these matters exists in isolation.  Each requires creative and unified solutions.  All of them demand our cooperation and our partnership.  The presence of leaders from so many countries at this ministerial demonstrates the urgency of this issue for our entire hemisphere and reinforces our shared determination to engage in this kind of collaboration.</p>
<p>For the Department of Homeland Security that I am proud to represent, our immediate goals are crystal-clear: think regionally about stemming migration flows through enhanced prevention and enforcement; create viable legal pathways in the spirit of regional responsibility-sharing; address root causes by investing in the stabilization of communities that need it most; foster and grow legitimate trade and travel between our countries that will help our communities prosper; and attack the shared dangers of transnational crime.</p>
<p>To meet these objectives throughout this week’s meetings, ongoing consultations, and building on bilateral and regional arrangements and agreements, we will do what we can to strengthen access to stronger protections and legal pathways for refugees and vulnerable migrants.  We will focus on ways to help prevent these individuals and families from experiencing the desperation that drives people to embark on these dangerous journeys in the first place.</p>
<p>We will seize the opportunity presented by this ministerial to identify the support and resources that will help stabilize communities affected by migration and strengthen humane border management across the region. We will build on the growing momentum in our hemisphere and toward a regional responsibility-sharing and a recognition that each country must do its part to address irregular migration in our region, which involves so much human suffering.  This is one step in a larger effort.</p>
<p>One of our next opportunities, as my friend and colleague Secretary Blinken stated, will come at the Summit of the Americas in my hometown of Los Angeles, California, where we will focus on the theme of building a resilient, sustainable, and equitable future in our hemisphere.  But before then, now, we will act.  We will tackle the shared challenges, seize the opportunities, and begin to realize our shared goals and underlying values.</p>
<p>Thank you once again for your welcome and partnership.</p>
<p><strong>MR VASQUEZ: </strong> (Via interpreter) Thank you.  Now (inaudible) we will open our Q&amp;A session for different media outlets.  First, we will (inaudible) Isaías Cedeño from TVN.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong> (Via interpreter) Hello, good morning.  I would like to know specifically what the promises are that will be undertaken by the U.S. (inaudible) in order to talk on migration as countries of origin where this problem originates (inaudible).  We haven’t had – Venezuela, Cuba, and Haiti, for example, have not been present at this meeting.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY MAYORKAS: </strong> So our plans have a number of different components to them.  One critical first step is reflected in the ministerial that we have convened today that has brought together so many different nations.  And that is to address the root causes of why individuals flee their homes, leave their countries of origin for lands that are unfamiliar to them – the process of stabilization.</p>
<p>Secondly, to build legal, orderly, and humane pathways so individuals do not need to place their lives, their well-beings, the well-beings of their loved ones, in the hands of smugglers and traffickers who only seek to exploit them for profit.</p>
<p>Third is to develop humanitarian programs for individuals already resident in the countries other than those of their origin so that we can settle them in a stable and prosperous manner, address their needs, present them with the opportunities of a stable life in their new homes.</p>
<p>Lastly, of course, in the United States, we have significant humanitarian programs, the asylum program.  But we also take pride in being not only a nation of immigrants but a nation of laws.  Those who qualify for relief under our nation’s laws will be provided a home in the United States and an ability to resettle in the States.  Those who do not qualify will be repatriated to their countries of origin, and so to give integrity to our system and to stand as a nation of laws as well as a nation of relief.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  And I really have very little to add because Secretary Mayorkas covered it so well.  I would only emphasize one point because it’s really what brought us together here today, and that is this sense of shared responsibility.  What is very powerful in the meeting today, in work that was done in the lead-up to this meeting including by Panama and Foreign Minister Mouynes, is building on that shared – sense of shared responsibility.</p>
<p>We know that virtually every aspect of this problem demands coordination, cooperation, consultation, and not only among governments but among international organizations, international financial institutions, civil society, and so on.  That’s very much the spirit of what took place today.  It’s the spirit that will animate the Summit of the Americas and its own focus on migration.</p>
<p>And it is, I think, the difference-maker because to underscore Secretary Mayorkas’s points, we have two challenges.  One is dealing with this effectively in a sustainable way, and that involves going at the root causes.  What is it that is driving people to make the decision to leave their homes, to leave their families, to leave their countries, to leave everything they know to make an incredibly hazardous journey with all the dangers that go along with that?  What is it that drives them to do that?  How do we address those challenges so that people feel the confidence that their future can be in the country that they come from?</p>
<p>But we know that that takes time.  It takes sustained effort.  It’s not like flipping a light switch.  But in the meantime, we have to be able to address the problem as it presents to us right now, and that goes with some of the practical cooperation that we’re taking, including through the work that we did today, including through the bilateral work that we’ve done with Panama on a new arrangement that we have for enhancing our coordination and cooperation on dealing with migration.</p>
<p>So we have to be able to deal with the short-term challenge even as we address the long-term drivers, which is the only sustainable way to get at this.  And all of that comes together in enhanced coordination, cooperation, shared responsibility.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Our first question goes to Alfonso Fernandez Sanchez of EFE.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello, Secretary Blinken.  The U.S. Government has underscored the need to tackle the root causes of migration in the Northern Triangle.  Do you think these countries are making enough efforts?  And particularly, are you worried about the decisions against freedom of speech and press in El Salvador by President Bukele?  Do you think he’s going down the authoritarian slope?</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) (Inaudible) and do you think that the U.S. is complying with all that they are supposed to comply with these migratory things?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Right.  First, what we are experiencing in our own hemisphere is multifaceted, and of course, there are challenges that are clear in the so-called Northern Triangle countries, in El Salvador, Honduras, and Guatemala, but also Nicaragua, Venezuela, Haiti, Cuba, and then people now coming into our hemisphere from beyond who are also on a migratory path, including coming to the United States.  So we’re looking at this comprehensively and looking at what we can do together to meet the challenge, wherever it comes from.</p>
<p>With regard to the Northern Triangle countries, we’re working with each of them in different ways to address both short-term challenges but also these long-term drivers.  I would note that Vice President Harris, among other things, led a very significant call to action from the private sector to make new investments in the Northern Triangle countries.  And since that call to action, I think we’ve seen something like $1.2 billion in additional investment that, over time, as it takes root, will create new opportunities for people and help take away some of what’s driving them to leave, which is the lack of economic opportunity.  But it has to be comprehensive.  Economic opportunity, governance, combating corruption, dealing with insecurity – all of these things are vital.</p>
<p>But I think it’s also fair to say that none of the countries in question, of course, can do this alone.  The demands are extraordinary, so this is where all of us come into play, but it’s also where the international financial institutions, as well as international organizations, come into play.  And bringing all of that together with the goodwill and intentions of the governments in question, I think we can make a real difference.</p>
<p>When it comes to El Salvador more exclusively, look, we have a strong partnership with the people of El Salvador.  El Salvador has experienced setbacks in democratic governance, in the separation of powers, the rule of law.  And we look to President Bukele to make progress in addressing some of those setbacks.</p>
<p>We also urge El Salvador to implement the state of emergency in a manner that is consistent with human rights.  We can tackle violence and crime while also protecting civil rights and fundamental freedoms.  These two things are not in opposition to each other.  I would note, for our part, that the United States has provided tens of millions of dollars recently in funding to deal with the problem posed by gangs.  We continue to cooperate and coordinate closely, including also with a number of pending extradition requests of gang leaders, to help address the problems posed by criminality and gangs.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MOUYNES:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  Regarding the participation of the U.S., I believe first of all I would say that their participation, as I said before, because the U.S. is the destination of most of the migrants, their participation here is fundamental, but also not only from the work that we have been doing – I started working and talking about this about a year ago when I called an alarm because of the increase of migrants that we were seeing, and the ally that has helped us all the way has been the U.S.  And what we are doing now is to show the result of that working together with all the countries in the region, but the U.S. is a leader in this.</p>
<p>I think that the fact that we are here together, we have security, foreign policy on both sides of the country, because these are the priorities.  For us, migration and – are issues for us and for the U.S., and it’s also a priority for the security issue for Panama and for the U.S.</p>
<p><strong>MR VASQUEZ:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  Adames from SerTV.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  Good afternoon.  We are here live, and this is for the foreign minister.  This is the third meeting held in this country to deal with irregular migration.  However, how does financing work together with multilateral support in the area of migration?  And what is the agreement that will be arrived at as a result of this meeting?</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MOUYNES:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  (In progress) meeting, because when you were talking specifically about the root causes and how to settle populations, infrastructure – infrastructure creates prosperity.  It’s – it creates development, and that is what we need to strive for.  And in order to do that, we need to get them involved, to get their commitment so they hear reality, so they hear what is going on in each country to have specific proposals drafted, to involve the private sector.</p>
<p>So they need to be a part of this exercise.  We have three of the most important banks represented here, as well as international organizations.  This is the way to work together and to create regional projects little by little to create the development that we need.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Priscilla Alvarez of CNN.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Secretary Mayorkas, in light of the increase of Cubans at the U.S.-Mexico border, what does the U.S. hope to accomplish in migration talks with Cuba this week?  And is there consideration within the administration to delay the end of Title 42?</p>
<p>And for Secretary Blinken, on Ukraine.  Russia and Ukraine say a humanitarian corridor has been established for Ukrainians who are women, children, and elderly to leave Mariupol.  Does the U.S. urge Ukrainians to depart the city that way?  Is there reason to believe it is a safe exit and is the U.S. helping in those efforts?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY MAYORKAS:</strong>  Thank you very much.  I don’t want to get ahead of the dialogue between the United States and Cuba, but as everyone knows, we have had migration accords with the country of Cuba for many, many years.  Those were discontinued, and we will explore the possibility of resuming that.  And that is a reflection of our commitment to legal, orderly, and humane pathways so individuals, including Cubans, do not take, for example, to the seas, which is an extraordinarily perilous journey.</p>
<p>Title 42 – the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention announced a while ago now that the use of Title 42, which is a public health authority and not an immigration policy, will discontinue as of May 23rd, and we are in the Department of Homeland Security and throughout the government planning accordingly.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  With regard to Ukraine and the situation in Mariupol and humanitarian corridors, a few things.  First, what the world witnessed just a couple of weeks ago when the receding Russian tide from Bucha revealed what was left in its wake in terms of death, destruction, atrocities – we can only anticipate that when this tide also, at some point, recedes from Mariupol we’re going to see far worse, if that’s possible to imagine.</p>
<p>So the conditions there, the situation there as a result of this Russian aggression are truly horrific.  And of course, we want to see people who are in harm’s way, if they’re able to, leave it safely and securely.  The judgment on whether the humanitarian corridor established to do that from Mariupol is safe and secure is one ultimately that the Ukrainian Government is going to make.  We will – we’re certainly assisting in that process, giving our own evaluations and assessments.  And ultimately the decision to leave is going to be a burden on the people themselves to make that very difficult decision.</p>
<p>What gives pause is the fact that there have been agreements on humanitarian corridors established before that have fallen apart very, very quickly, if not immediately, principally because the security has been violated by Russian forces.  And so people leaving, believing that they can do so safely and securely, were fired upon.</p>
<p>So this is a very, very difficult decision to make, to evaluate not only whether what’s been agreed to, if something’s been agreed to, is safe and secure, but whether Russia will actually live up to whatever obligations it’s undertaken to make sure that people can leave safely and securely.  Again, this is for the Government of Ukraine to decide.  We’ll do anything we can to try to inform that decision.</p>
<p><strong>MR VASQUEZ:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Colleagues, with that question, then, we bring to a close today’s press conference after the ministerial conference on migration.  Once again, we would like to thank you very much, thank you for your professional coverage of this event.  I wish you all a great day.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Panama City, Panama</p>
<p>Westin Playa Bonita Panama</p>
<p><strong>MR VASQUEZ:</strong>  (Via interpreter) A very good morning to you all, and welcome to the press conference called by Erika Mouynes, Minister of Foreign Affairs, after the ministerial on migration where the national government talks about joint actions to deal with the growing phenomenon of irregular migration at the highest level.  It is my honor to leave you with Minister Erika Mouynes, Minister of Foreign Affairs.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MOUYNES:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Good morning, everyone.  Thank you very much for your interest.  Before getting to the questions, I would like to establish what I think is a vital agreement or vital achievement of the ministerial meeting held in Panama, the great welcome at which this has been received at the highest level – ministers of foreign affairs, defense, development banks, international organizations – 31 delegations were here.  Their very presence is a show of support, and the involvement of the United States, the declared destination of most migrants who cross through our country, has been fundamental.</p>
<p>Over a year ago, when we made a call to attention about the unprecedented increase regarding migrants crossing our borders, we were facing a regional migration crisis.  The cooperation between countries of origin, of transit, and destination countries for transcontinental migration was shown to be an efficient alternative to combat this unstoppable phenomenon, but we cannot relax.  Reality is what it is, and we need a regional strategy that is ongoing when facing these issues.  We must continue with the work that we have started.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>MR VASQUEZ:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  We will now hear from His Excellency Secretary Blinken, Secretary of State from the United States of America.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.  It is a pleasure to be in Panama, the bridge of the world and the heart of the universe, with Foreign<strong> </strong>Minister Mouynes, Minister of Security Pino, and my friend and colleague Secretary Mayorkas.  I also want to start by thanking our outstanding embassy team here in Panama City, including our chargé d&#8217;affaires, Stewart Tuttle, for their great work in sustaining and strengthening our friendship with Panama.   So we have just concluded a set of ministerial meetings to discuss a challenge that affects all 22 countries represented here: managing migration in our hemisphere.  Precisely because it affects all of us, this is a challenge that we have to solve together, and that was at the heart of our discussions today.</p>
<p>Here in Panama we talked about some of the most urgent aspects of this issue, including helping stabilize and strengthen communities that are hosting migrants and refugees; creating more legal pathways to reinforce safe, orderly, and humane migration; dealing with the root causes of irregular migration by growing economic opportunity, fighting corruption, increasing citizen security, combating the climate crisis, improving democratic governance that’s responsive to people’s needs.</p>
<p>Yesterday Panama and the United States signed an arrangement to increase our bilateral cooperation across all of these issues.  This is the second one we’ve made.  The first was with Costa Rica.  We hope to announce more in the coming weeks and months.  This is how we deepen our coordination and this is how we make more progress in helping vulnerable people, support communities, and protect the security of our borders.  Our work together is going to continue at the Summit of the Americas in June, where we hope that leaders from across the region will be able to lay out shared principles for a shared response to regional migration and forced displacement.</p>
<p>I also want to mention the international organizations that joined us here in Panama.  They are critical partners in everything that we’re working to do – the International Organization for Migration, the International Committee of the Red Cross, the Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights, the UN High Commissioner for Refugees, UNICEF, the World Bank – and also equally important partners, multilateral development banks, they joined us here as well, including the Andean Development Corporation, the Central American Bank for Economic Integration, the Inter-American Development Bank, and the International Monetary Fund.  This is the kind of cross-cutting coordination that the challenges of irregular migration demand.  We’re grateful for everyone’s participation and everyone’s contributions.</p>
<p>I want to thank the Government of Panama for being a leader, a partner on this issue, and for bringing all of us together for two days of what were productive talks, productive planning, and action.  As President Cortizo and I discussed yesterday, the partnership between Panama and the United States is one of the strongest that we have in the Americas.  Our countries work together every single day on the issues that matter most to our people.  Our economic relationship is strong, with more than $13 billion in bilateral trade between us that’s supporting thousands of jobs in both our countries, and 72 percent of all goods that travel through the Panama Canal are either going to or coming from the United States.</p>
<p>We’re proud to be the largest humanitarian donor to international organizations in Panama, and their work complements Panama’s own assistance to migrants and refugees.  We’re working closely on counterterrorism and counternarcotics through our security cooperation and combating organized crime and money laundering through law enforcement cooperation.</p>
<p>We’re also fighting COVID-19 together.  More than 70 percent of Panama’s population is fully vaccinated, a remarkable achievement that that the United States was proud to support with a donation of more than 500,000 Pfizer vaccine doses.</p>
<p>We applaud Panama’s leadership on climate, including the work that you’ve done on reforestation and decreasing energy emissions.</p>
<p>And our countries stand together to support shared values here at home and around the world.  We value Panama’s strong voice in the region on democracy.  We stand with Panama’s voice to strengthen its own democratic governance, fighting corruption.  And we appreciate how Panama stood firmly against Russia’s unprovoked war of aggression against Ukraine and affirmed the principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity that lie at the heart of the United Nations Charter.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Secretary Mayorkas and I visited the Panama Canal, something that I’ve – like so many millions of people – read about, studied.  But when you see it, as I did for the first time, it really gives you a – gives you pause at the extraordinary feat of human engineering, human ingenuity, but also the powerful symbol of the historical partnership between our countries, a reminder that Panama is at the center of so much global economic activity and connection – a gateway between the continents and oceans, a leader in the region and beyond, a true friend and partner to the United States.  And for that, we’re very thankful.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR VASQUEZ:</strong>  (Via interpreter) His Excellency Pino, Minister of Public Safety.</p>
<p><strong>SECURITY MINISTER PINO:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Good morning, everyone.  First of all, I would like to thank you for this time that we have spent together while working out in the field and working bilateral meetings and in multilateral meetings as well.  We have tackled this issue from many angles.  I thank Secretary Mayorkas for going with us to (inaudible), which is (inaudible) as has been said, because it is a way of understanding what happens to migrants as they travel through Panama.</p>
<p>First of all, Panama, in order to strengthen the willingness to work on this issue of global concern, migration, signed a letter of intent where it reaffirms its willingness to continue to deal with this issue on the – at the bilateral level with the United States, where we&#8217;d have an historic relationship in the area of security, which must be supported increasingly every day because these issues must be dealt with in a timely manner quickly, because these are issues that affect the future.  Migration is here due to changes that are happening at the global level, so I appreciate this visit.  And Panama here reaffirms its willingness to continue to work on this via the signing of the letter of intent.</p>
<p>Finally, I led issue number two, the working group for security, with ministers and vice ministers of security as well as delegations of (inaudible) countries who are with us here.  It is clearly reflected – we saw the good intentions – and for the first time, I was able to see how at the multilateral level we tackle this scourge.  We saw examples of how different countries deal with the issue.  And now we must bring our efforts together and act quickly because migratory flows will continue and will increase.</p>
<p>We saw the need to promote stabilization, control measures, awareness campaigns, and preventing irregular migration.  And the risks that are linked to this phenomenon – transit routes must be safer.  We must harmonize migratory policies.  We must preserve the environment.  We need to look at new schemes and more work-related migration schemes – traceability – we need technology and tools; we need to exchange information in a timely fashion.  And we must improve our cooperation in order to improve security in the region.</p>
<p>During my time as minister of security and during my career in security agencies, I’ve never seen a meeting that was as aligned around one single issue – a common issue – where countries have come to an agreement.  We have set forth a route, but this route and the destination – we must travel this route quickly.  And I can say and affirm that there is a great deal of willingness on behalf of the countries who participated, and I appreciate that.  I appreciate that call that was made through the Panamanian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, because this is a golden opportunity, and we must continue to build on this issue for a better future for our countries.  Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><strong>MR VASQUEZ:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Words now from Secretary of DHS Alejandro Mayorkas from the U.S.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY MAYORKAS:  </strong>Good morning.  Our gratitude to President Cortizo, Ministers Mouynes and Pino for convening, hosting, and welcoming us here in beautiful Panama.  By bringing us together from across this region, we are demonstrating the commitment shared by each one of us and our nations to resolve, to address our joint hemispheric challenge of irregular migration, its impacts, its complexities, and the factors causing it.</p>
<p>These issues have tested our governments and our citizens in the United States, Panama, and throughout the Americas.  And this task has been made more difficult and more urgent in the face of an ongoing pandemic, natural disasters worsened by climate change, threats to public safety and economic security, and much more.</p>
<p>None of these matters exists in isolation.  Each requires creative and unified solutions.  All of them demand our cooperation and our partnership.  The presence of leaders from so many countries at this ministerial demonstrates the urgency of this issue for our entire hemisphere and reinforces our shared determination to engage in this kind of collaboration.</p>
<p>For the Department of Homeland Security that I am proud to represent, our immediate goals are crystal-clear: think regionally about stemming migration flows through enhanced prevention and enforcement; create viable legal pathways in the spirit of regional responsibility-sharing; address root causes by investing in the stabilization of communities that need it most; foster and grow legitimate trade and travel between our countries that will help our communities prosper; and attack the shared dangers of transnational crime.</p>
<p>To meet these objectives throughout this week’s meetings, ongoing consultations, and building on bilateral and regional arrangements and agreements, we will do what we can to strengthen access to stronger protections and legal pathways for refugees and vulnerable migrants.  We will focus on ways to help prevent these individuals and families from experiencing the desperation that drives people to embark on these dangerous journeys in the first place.</p>
<p>We will seize the opportunity presented by this ministerial to identify the support and resources that will help stabilize communities affected by migration and strengthen humane border management across the region. We will build on the growing momentum in our hemisphere and toward a regional responsibility-sharing and a recognition that each country must do its part to address irregular migration in our region, which involves so much human suffering.  This is one step in a larger effort.</p>
<p>One of our next opportunities, as my friend and colleague Secretary Blinken stated, will come at the Summit of the Americas in my hometown of Los Angeles, California, where we will focus on the theme of building a resilient, sustainable, and equitable future in our hemisphere.  But before then, now, we will act.  We will tackle the shared challenges, seize the opportunities, and begin to realize our shared goals and underlying values.</p>
<p>Thank you once again for your welcome and partnership.</p>
<p><strong>MR VASQUEZ: </strong> (Via interpreter) Thank you.  Now (inaudible) we will open our Q&amp;A session for different media outlets.  First, we will (inaudible) Isaías Cedeño from TVN.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong> (Via interpreter) Hello, good morning.  I would like to know specifically what the promises are that will be undertaken by the U.S. (inaudible) in order to talk on migration as countries of origin where this problem originates (inaudible).  We haven’t had – Venezuela, Cuba, and Haiti, for example, have not been present at this meeting.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY MAYORKAS: </strong> So our plans have a number of different components to them.  One critical first step is reflected in the ministerial that we have convened today that has brought together so many different nations.  And that is to address the root causes of why individuals flee their homes, leave their countries of origin for lands that are unfamiliar to them – the process of stabilization.</p>
<p>Secondly, to build legal, orderly, and humane pathways so individuals do not need to place their lives, their well-beings, the well-beings of their loved ones, in the hands of smugglers and traffickers who only seek to exploit them for profit.</p>
<p>Third is to develop humanitarian programs for individuals already resident in the countries other than those of their origin so that we can settle them in a stable and prosperous manner, address their needs, present them with the opportunities of a stable life in their new homes.</p>
<p>Lastly, of course, in the United States, we have significant humanitarian programs, the asylum program.  But we also take pride in being not only a nation of immigrants but a nation of laws.  Those who qualify for relief under our nation’s laws will be provided a home in the United States and an ability to resettle in the States.  Those who do not qualify will be repatriated to their countries of origin, and so to give integrity to our system and to stand as a nation of laws as well as a nation of relief.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  And I really have very little to add because Secretary Mayorkas covered it so well.  I would only emphasize one point because it’s really what brought us together here today, and that is this sense of shared responsibility.  What is very powerful in the meeting today, in work that was done in the lead-up to this meeting including by Panama and Foreign Minister Mouynes, is building on that shared – sense of shared responsibility.</p>
<p>We know that virtually every aspect of this problem demands coordination, cooperation, consultation, and not only among governments but among international organizations, international financial institutions, civil society, and so on.  That’s very much the spirit of what took place today.  It’s the spirit that will animate the Summit of the Americas and its own focus on migration.</p>
<p>And it is, I think, the difference-maker because to underscore Secretary Mayorkas’s points, we have two challenges.  One is dealing with this effectively in a sustainable way, and that involves going at the root causes.  What is it that is driving people to make the decision to leave their homes, to leave their families, to leave their countries, to leave everything they know to make an incredibly hazardous journey with all the dangers that go along with that?  What is it that drives them to do that?  How do we address those challenges so that people feel the confidence that their future can be in the country that they come from?</p>
<p>But we know that that takes time.  It takes sustained effort.  It’s not like flipping a light switch.  But in the meantime, we have to be able to address the problem as it presents to us right now, and that goes with some of the practical cooperation that we’re taking, including through the work that we did today, including through the bilateral work that we’ve done with Panama on a new arrangement that we have for enhancing our coordination and cooperation on dealing with migration.</p>
<p>So we have to be able to deal with the short-term challenge even as we address the long-term drivers, which is the only sustainable way to get at this.  And all of that comes together in enhanced coordination, cooperation, shared responsibility.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Our first question goes to Alfonso Fernandez Sanchez of EFE.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello, Secretary Blinken.  The U.S. Government has underscored the need to tackle the root causes of migration in the Northern Triangle.  Do you think these countries are making enough efforts?  And particularly, are you worried about the decisions against freedom of speech and press in El Salvador by President Bukele?  Do you think he’s going down the authoritarian slope?</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) (Inaudible) and do you think that the U.S. is complying with all that they are supposed to comply with these migratory things?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Right.  First, what we are experiencing in our own hemisphere is multifaceted, and of course, there are challenges that are clear in the so-called Northern Triangle countries, in El Salvador, Honduras, and Guatemala, but also Nicaragua, Venezuela, Haiti, Cuba, and then people now coming into our hemisphere from beyond who are also on a migratory path, including coming to the United States.  So we’re looking at this comprehensively and looking at what we can do together to meet the challenge, wherever it comes from.</p>
<p>With regard to the Northern Triangle countries, we’re working with each of them in different ways to address both short-term challenges but also these long-term drivers.  I would note that Vice President Harris, among other things, led a very significant call to action from the private sector to make new investments in the Northern Triangle countries.  And since that call to action, I think we’ve seen something like $1.2 billion in additional investment that, over time, as it takes root, will create new opportunities for people and help take away some of what’s driving them to leave, which is the lack of economic opportunity.  But it has to be comprehensive.  Economic opportunity, governance, combating corruption, dealing with insecurity – all of these things are vital.</p>
<p>But I think it’s also fair to say that none of the countries in question, of course, can do this alone.  The demands are extraordinary, so this is where all of us come into play, but it’s also where the international financial institutions, as well as international organizations, come into play.  And bringing all of that together with the goodwill and intentions of the governments in question, I think we can make a real difference.</p>
<p>When it comes to El Salvador more exclusively, look, we have a strong partnership with the people of El Salvador.  El Salvador has experienced setbacks in democratic governance, in the separation of powers, the rule of law.  And we look to President Bukele to make progress in addressing some of those setbacks.</p>
<p>We also urge El Salvador to implement the state of emergency in a manner that is consistent with human rights.  We can tackle violence and crime while also protecting civil rights and fundamental freedoms.  These two things are not in opposition to each other.  I would note, for our part, that the United States has provided tens of millions of dollars recently in funding to deal with the problem posed by gangs.  We continue to cooperate and coordinate closely, including also with a number of pending extradition requests of gang leaders, to help address the problems posed by criminality and gangs.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MOUYNES:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  Regarding the participation of the U.S., I believe first of all I would say that their participation, as I said before, because the U.S. is the destination of most of the migrants, their participation here is fundamental, but also not only from the work that we have been doing – I started working and talking about this about a year ago when I called an alarm because of the increase of migrants that we were seeing, and the ally that has helped us all the way has been the U.S.  And what we are doing now is to show the result of that working together with all the countries in the region, but the U.S. is a leader in this.</p>
<p>I think that the fact that we are here together, we have security, foreign policy on both sides of the country, because these are the priorities.  For us, migration and – are issues for us and for the U.S., and it’s also a priority for the security issue for Panama and for the U.S.</p>
<p><strong>MR VASQUEZ:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  Adames from SerTV.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  Good afternoon.  We are here live, and this is for the foreign minister.  This is the third meeting held in this country to deal with irregular migration.  However, how does financing work together with multilateral support in the area of migration?  And what is the agreement that will be arrived at as a result of this meeting?</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MOUYNES:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  (In progress) meeting, because when you were talking specifically about the root causes and how to settle populations, infrastructure – infrastructure creates prosperity.  It’s – it creates development, and that is what we need to strive for.  And in order to do that, we need to get them involved, to get their commitment so they hear reality, so they hear what is going on in each country to have specific proposals drafted, to involve the private sector.</p>
<p>So they need to be a part of this exercise.  We have three of the most important banks represented here, as well as international organizations.  This is the way to work together and to create regional projects little by little to create the development that we need.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Priscilla Alvarez of CNN.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Secretary Mayorkas, in light of the increase of Cubans at the U.S.-Mexico border, what does the U.S. hope to accomplish in migration talks with Cuba this week?  And is there consideration within the administration to delay the end of Title 42?</p>
<p>And for Secretary Blinken, on Ukraine.  Russia and Ukraine say a humanitarian corridor has been established for Ukrainians who are women, children, and elderly to leave Mariupol.  Does the U.S. urge Ukrainians to depart the city that way?  Is there reason to believe it is a safe exit and is the U.S. helping in those efforts?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY MAYORKAS:</strong>  Thank you very much.  I don’t want to get ahead of the dialogue between the United States and Cuba, but as everyone knows, we have had migration accords with the country of Cuba for many, many years.  Those were discontinued, and we will explore the possibility of resuming that.  And that is a reflection of our commitment to legal, orderly, and humane pathways so individuals, including Cubans, do not take, for example, to the seas, which is an extraordinarily perilous journey.</p>
<p>Title 42 – the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention announced a while ago now that the use of Title 42, which is a public health authority and not an immigration policy, will discontinue as of May 23rd, and we are in the Department of Homeland Security and throughout the government planning accordingly.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  With regard to Ukraine and the situation in Mariupol and humanitarian corridors, a few things.  First, what the world witnessed just a couple of weeks ago when the receding Russian tide from Bucha revealed what was left in its wake in terms of death, destruction, atrocities – we can only anticipate that when this tide also, at some point, recedes from Mariupol we’re going to see far worse, if that’s possible to imagine.</p>
<p>So the conditions there, the situation there as a result of this Russian aggression are truly horrific.  And of course, we want to see people who are in harm’s way, if they’re able to, leave it safely and securely.  The judgment on whether the humanitarian corridor established to do that from Mariupol is safe and secure is one ultimately that the Ukrainian Government is going to make.  We will – we’re certainly assisting in that process, giving our own evaluations and assessments.  And ultimately the decision to leave is going to be a burden on the people themselves to make that very difficult decision.</p>
<p>What gives pause is the fact that there have been agreements on humanitarian corridors established before that have fallen apart very, very quickly, if not immediately, principally because the security has been violated by Russian forces.  And so people leaving, believing that they can do so safely and securely, were fired upon.</p>
<p>So this is a very, very difficult decision to make, to evaluate not only whether what’s been agreed to, if something’s been agreed to, is safe and secure, but whether Russia will actually live up to whatever obligations it’s undertaken to make sure that people can leave safely and securely.  Again, this is for the Government of Ukraine to decide.  We’ll do anything we can to try to inform that decision.</p>
<p><strong>MR VASQUEZ:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Colleagues, with that question, then, we bring to a close today’s press conference after the ministerial conference on migration.  Once again, we would like to thank you very much, thank you for your professional coverage of this event.  I wish you all a great day.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Promoting Accountability for Human Rights Abuses in Russia and Belarus and Taking Action Against Sanctions Evaders</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/promoting-accountability-for-human-rights-abuses-in-russia-and-belarus-and-taking-action-against-sanctions-evaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 18:57:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335927</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p align="left">President Putin’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine, conducted with the complicity of the Lukashenka regime, continues to cause needless suffering and thousands of civilian casualties.  The world has witnessed the horrors of this war in the images from the Ukrainian towns of Bucha, Irpin, and Hostomel, and in Ukrainian towns and cities still occupied or under siege, such as Mariupol.</p>
<p align="left">As a result, the United States is taking further actions to promote accountability for human rights abuses and violations, to include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Action to impose visa restrictions on 587 Russian individuals pursuant to a new policy under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, which was announced March 15.  The policy applies to Russian government officials involved in suppressing dissent in Russia and abroad.  Today’s action includes Duma members who have been involved in repressing independent media.  Family members of those who fall under the policy will also be ineligible for visas.</li>
<li>Designation of three Russian officials, Khusein Merlovich <wbr />Khutaev, Nurid Denilbekovich Salamov, and Dzhabrail Alkhazurovich <wbr />Akhmatov, pursuant to Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2022.  Khutaev, Salamov, and Akhmatov were publicly designated for their involvement in a gross violation of human rights perpetrated against human rights defender Oyub Titiev.</li>
<li>Action to impose visa restrictions on 48 individuals pursuant to a policy under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act that applies to those who are believed to have taken, supported, or been actively complicit in actions that threaten or violate the sovereignty, territorial integrity, or political independence of Ukraine.  Today’s action includes ten purported “authorities” of the so-called Donetsk People’s Republic and Luhansk People’s Republic who are further reported to have been involved in human rights abuses at prison facilities and places of unofficial detention in Russia-controlled areas of the Donbas since 2014.</li>
<li>Action to impose visa restrictions on 17 individuals responsible for undermining democracy in Belarus pursuant to Presidential Proclamation 8015, including Belarusian nationals involved in the intimidation, harassment, and repression of strikers supporting the pro-democracy movement and the expulsion of students for participating in peaceful pro-democracy protests.  Specific individuals include officials from state-owned factories and universities.</li>
</ul>
<p>The United States is committed to a world in which human rights are respected, their defenders are free from repression, and those who commit human rights abuses are held accountable.  We will use every tool to promote accountability for human rights abuses and violations of international humanitarian law in Ukraine.  The actions today hold to account individuals participating in Putin and Lukashenka’s repression, and those who seek to enable it.</p>
<p>Additionally, the U.S. Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) is designating entities and individuals involved in attempting to evade sanctions imposed by the United States and its international partners on Russia.  OFAC is designating Russian commercial bank Transkapitalbank and a global network of more than 40 individuals and entities led by U.S.-designated Russian oligarch Konstantin Malofeyev, including organizations whose primary mission is to facilitate sanctions evasion for Russian entities. OFAC also designated companies operating in Russia’s virtual currency mining industry, reportedly the third-largest in the world.  For more information on OFAC actions, see the Treasury’s press release: <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0731" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0731</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p>Pursuant to Executive Order 14024 section 1(a)(iii)(C), the Department of State is designating 16 Bank Otkritie Board Members:  Kseniya Valentinovna Yudayeva, Mikhail Yurevich Alekseev, Anatoly Mikhailovich Karachinskiy, Vladimir Vladimirovich Kolychev, Alexey Yurevich Simanovskiy, Andrey Fedorovich Golikov, Elena Borisovna Titova, Mikhail Mikhaylovich Zadornov, Dmitriy Olegovich Levin, Svetlana Petrovna Emelyanova, Tatyana Gennadevna Nesterenko, Irina Vladimirovna Kremleva, Viktor Andreevich Nikolaev, Sergey Georgievich Rusanov, Nadia Narimanovna Cherkasova, and Paul Andrew Goldfinch for being or having been a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors, or members of an entity whose property and interests in property are blocked.</p>
<p>We will continue to target those who take part in or facilitate sanctions evasion for sanctioned Russian entities, as they are complicit in President Putin’s brutal war.  We will ensure that the sanctions we have imposed in close coordination with our international partners degrade the Kremlin’s ability to project power and fund its war of aggression.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p align="left">President Putin’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine, conducted with the complicity of the Lukashenka regime, continues to cause needless suffering and thousands of civilian casualties.  The world has witnessed the horrors of this war in the images from the Ukrainian towns of Bucha, Irpin, and Hostomel, and in Ukrainian towns and cities still occupied or under siege, such as Mariupol.</p>
<p align="left">As a result, the United States is taking further actions to promote accountability for human rights abuses and violations, to include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Action to impose visa restrictions on 587 Russian individuals pursuant to a new policy under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, which was announced March 15.  The policy applies to Russian government officials involved in suppressing dissent in Russia and abroad.  Today’s action includes Duma members who have been involved in repressing independent media.  Family members of those who fall under the policy will also be ineligible for visas.</li>
<li>Designation of three Russian officials, Khusein Merlovich <wbr />Khutaev, Nurid Denilbekovich Salamov, and Dzhabrail Alkhazurovich <wbr />Akhmatov, pursuant to Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2022.  Khutaev, Salamov, and Akhmatov were publicly designated for their involvement in a gross violation of human rights perpetrated against human rights defender Oyub Titiev.</li>
<li>Action to impose visa restrictions on 48 individuals pursuant to a policy under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act that applies to those who are believed to have taken, supported, or been actively complicit in actions that threaten or violate the sovereignty, territorial integrity, or political independence of Ukraine.  Today’s action includes ten purported “authorities” of the so-called Donetsk People’s Republic and Luhansk People’s Republic who are further reported to have been involved in human rights abuses at prison facilities and places of unofficial detention in Russia-controlled areas of the Donbas since 2014.</li>
<li>Action to impose visa restrictions on 17 individuals responsible for undermining democracy in Belarus pursuant to Presidential Proclamation 8015, including Belarusian nationals involved in the intimidation, harassment, and repression of strikers supporting the pro-democracy movement and the expulsion of students for participating in peaceful pro-democracy protests.  Specific individuals include officials from state-owned factories and universities.</li>
</ul>
<p>The United States is committed to a world in which human rights are respected, their defenders are free from repression, and those who commit human rights abuses are held accountable.  We will use every tool to promote accountability for human rights abuses and violations of international humanitarian law in Ukraine.  The actions today hold to account individuals participating in Putin and Lukashenka’s repression, and those who seek to enable it.</p>
<p>Additionally, the U.S. Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) is designating entities and individuals involved in attempting to evade sanctions imposed by the United States and its international partners on Russia.  OFAC is designating Russian commercial bank Transkapitalbank and a global network of more than 40 individuals and entities led by U.S.-designated Russian oligarch Konstantin Malofeyev, including organizations whose primary mission is to facilitate sanctions evasion for Russian entities. OFAC also designated companies operating in Russia’s virtual currency mining industry, reportedly the third-largest in the world.  For more information on OFAC actions, see the Treasury’s press release: <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0731" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0731</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p>Pursuant to Executive Order 14024 section 1(a)(iii)(C), the Department of State is designating 16 Bank Otkritie Board Members:  Kseniya Valentinovna Yudayeva, Mikhail Yurevich Alekseev, Anatoly Mikhailovich Karachinskiy, Vladimir Vladimirovich Kolychev, Alexey Yurevich Simanovskiy, Andrey Fedorovich Golikov, Elena Borisovna Titova, Mikhail Mikhaylovich Zadornov, Dmitriy Olegovich Levin, Svetlana Petrovna Emelyanova, Tatyana Gennadevna Nesterenko, Irina Vladimirovna Kremleva, Viktor Andreevich Nikolaev, Sergey Georgievich Rusanov, Nadia Narimanovna Cherkasova, and Paul Andrew Goldfinch for being or having been a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors, or members of an entity whose property and interests in property are blocked.</p>
<p>We will continue to target those who take part in or facilitate sanctions evasion for sanctioned Russian entities, as they are complicit in President Putin’s brutal war.  We will ensure that the sanctions we have imposed in close coordination with our international partners degrade the Kremlin’s ability to project power and fund its war of aggression.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary Noyes Travel to Mexico</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-noyes-travel-to-mexico/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 18:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336045</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Assistant Secretary of State for Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM) Julieta Valls Noyes will travel to Mexico April 20-23.</p>
<p align="left">Assistant Secretary Noyes will meet with international organization partners and with Mexican government representatives, including from the Mexican Commission for Refugee Assistance (COMAR), to discuss collaborative efforts and shared priorities for addressing forced displacement in the region.  She will also visit providers of critical humanitarian assistance for vulnerable populations, including refugees and migrants.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Assistant Secretary of State for Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM) Julieta Valls Noyes will travel to Mexico April 20-23.</p>
<p align="left">Assistant Secretary Noyes will meet with international organization partners and with Mexican government representatives, including from the Mexican Commission for Refugee Assistance (COMAR), to discuss collaborative efforts and shared priorities for addressing forced displacement in the region.  She will also visit providers of critical humanitarian assistance for vulnerable populations, including refugees and migrants.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with Panamanian President Laurentino Cortizo Cohen and Panamanian Foreign Minister Erika Mouynes at the Ministerial Conference on Migration and Protection Session on Stabilization of Communities and Post-COVID Recovery</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-panamanian-president-laurentino-cortizo-cohen-and-panamanian-foreign-minister-erika-mouynes-at-the-ministerial-conference-on-migration-and-protection-session-on-stabil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 16:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335934</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Panama City, Panama</p>
<p>Westin Playa Bonita Panama</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT COHEN:</strong>  (Via interpreter) (In progress) irregular migration.  We have been creating tourism and increasing (inaudible) irregular migration going through the borders  (inaudible).  Given these conditions, we have – there are victims of criminal organizations.  They’re exposed to multiple risks that attempt against human rights.</p>
<p>Facing this reality, we cannot be indifferent.  Our countries also work in a coordinated manner to find solutions in the short, medium, and long range.  We have an international humanitarian approach with shared responsibility among the countries of origin, transit, and final destination of these irregular migrants.  That is why we have to strengthen the policies of the region to be able to drive the economic growth in our countries to generate human growth opportunities and to create better living conditions for our peoples.</p>
<p>It is fundamental, achieving joint agreements and articulated agreements to tackle this migration phenomenon (inaudible) humanitarian organizations.  It is opportune to highlight what I mentioned already in the General Assembly of the United Nations back in September.  Irregular migration is possibly the (inaudible).  It demands a joint effort of coordinated strategies and enough resources to anticipate the humanitarian crisis in the region of great preparations.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, Panama is a (inaudible) standing in the flood of this irregular migration.  We have created a lot of efforts to tackle proactively and positively and with a humanitarian approach.  And we have coordinated (inaudible) states acting immediately and facing this challenge with (inaudible) because we understand that we cannot just stay talking, facing a problem like this.</p>
<p>Today I reaffirm Panama’s commitment to work jointly with friendly countries as strategic partners in the search of joint solutions with cross-sectional policies and concrete actions that will promote regular migrations, orderly and safe, respecting human rights.  I do appreciate all of you here present for your participation, your will, and determination to work in a regional integration to tackle the irregular migration phenomenon within the context of international migration.  Thank you so much.</p>
<p><strong>MR VASQUEZ: </strong> (Via interpreter) Ladies and gentlemen, having heard the opening remarks of His Excellency the President of Panama, Mr. Laurentino Cortizo Cohen, we open the floor to Erika Mouynes, Foreign Relations Minister, who will open the ministerial regional meeting on migration.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MOUYNES: </strong> (Via interpreter)  Good morning, everyone.  I would like to thank one more time your attendance, for just by being here is a clear support to the initiative to tackle the impact on irregular migration in a continental manner.  We all care, we have made this a priority, and we need to work together.  Migration is a current phenomenon and it is a complex one.  It is a world phenomenon.  And this phenomenon in particular responds to particular joint circumstances that magnify the COVID pandemic, climate change, war, conflict, and economic issues.  By working together with our neighboring countries and the United States, we are trying to approach this phenomenon in a responsible, effective, and humanitarian-focused way for which we have advocated since the very beginning, like our president said.</p>
<p>Figures are clear.  In August of 2021, influx through the Darién border came to a peak of 2,800 migrants in a day.  Today, it doesn’t go over 100 daily.  So we have motives to be optimistic, but we cannot falter because, one more time, the figures are still increasing.  Reality is harsh, and these events of – which are unexpected create migration waves and compels us to be prepared not only to be able to offer assistance but also not to have a negative impact.  There will be always cataclysms, new conflicts, but we can create effective and long-lasting control with a regional and continental strategy, but it has to be a permanent role.</p>
<p>Today we are providing continuity to something that we already began.  So today before we begin we should have three set objectives: one, coming to agreement in a working framework that will facilitate the standardization of migration policies in the region; number two, broaden the efforts of collaboration to fight trans-country organized crime; and number three, to concrete the cooperation dynamics among states, international organizations, and development banking in the region to have the structural basis to stop the structural basis that prompt migration.</p>
<p>Friends, your presence here is important, and it conveys the will to work together, sharing this responsibility to approach this challenge that is going to define the 21st century.  It will be collaboration, commitment, and consensus that always works.  Today we have an opportunity to speak with one voice, being certain that our meeting will mark a milestone in the history of our continent.  Thank you so much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good morning, everyone, and Erika, thank you so much for bringing us all together.  We are all living what is truly a historic challenge, and that is the fact that more people on our planet are on the move, forcibly displaced from their homes, than at any time since the Second World War.  That is the magnitude of the challenge, and we feel it strongly in our own hemisphere.  We’re focusing on different aspects of the problem today.</p>
<p>This morning in this first session, I know we want to focus on one particularly urgent aspect of the challenge:  How can we more effectively work together to help stabilize and strengthen communities across the region that are generously hosting large numbers of migrants and refugees?  The millions of people who have made the difficult and often dangerous decision to leave their homes we know do so for a variety of reasons – poverty, a lack of economic opportunity, repressive governance, corruption, political upheaval, conflict and insecurity.  All of these challenges already there are exacerbated by COVID-19 and by the climate crisis.</p>
<p>Ultimately, we all know this: the only lasting, sustainable response to irregular migration is to tackle its root causes.  But that takes time.  And in the meantime, many cities and towns simply don’t have the resources they need to provide for their own citizens, much less meeting the needs of migrants who are with them.</p>
<p>As Erika said, we know that no country, no community can solve a challenge as complicated as irregular migration alone.  We have to work together to support the front-line communities hosting migrants and refugees with increased resources for public health and safety, for stronger social services, for more resilient infrastructure, for opportunity for all – for migrants and host communities alike.</p>
<p>We’re making some progress.  Just to cite a few examples.  Colombia has registered more than 1.9 million Venezuelans for temporary protected status, and more than 600,000 have officially received that status.  That gives them documentation and legal protections that are critical for integrating into their local community.</p>
<p>It also means that more migrants can be vaccinated against COVID-19, which is critical to ending the pandemic and boosting economic recovery.</p>
<p>In that same spirit, the United States is expediting family-based petitions at our embassies throughout Central America so that migrants with family members in the United States are able to go there sponsored by the family members, and they can move much more quickly through the process as a result.</p>
<p>We’re also expanding visas for eligible groups – for example, 20,000 additional H2B temporary agricultural worker visas that Secretary Mayorkas recently announced.  And a critical piece of this is the role that multilateral finance and development institutions have been doing to provide more resources to front-line communities.  We have to work together to bring these efforts to scale throughout the hemisphere.</p>
<p>Again, with some examples.  The Inter-American Development Bank is boosting public health education and social protection in migrant host cities in Ecuador.  In Belize, the bank is running programs to increase educational opportunity for girls both from migrant families and from local communities.  And again, this is such a critical piece.  The support that we need to give to migrants we have to find ways also to make sure that local communities are getting support, getting help – are benefitting.  Otherwise, we know that none of this will be sustainable – politically, economically, socially.</p>
<p>In five Colombian cities, the bank is facilitating housing and helping local governments build institutional capacity to assist migrants, both of which are critical for them to integrate more seamlessly into our communities.  The World Bank’s Global Concessional Financing Facility has been instrumental in providing development assistance to countries worldwide that are affected by the refugee crisis, including economic and social support to Colombian communities hosting Venezuelan refugees.</p>
<p>So programs like these help point the way forward.  We need that kind of cross-cutting coordination – local and national governments, multilateral institutions, businesses, civil society – all working toward safe, orderly, and humane migration throughout the region and supporting the communities so that they can do right by these vulnerable populations.</p>
<p>Of course, even as we’re doing this, as I said at the outset, we have to remain resolutely focused on addressing root causes, in particular some of the economic drivers of migration, and there, again, we’re making some progress.  To name just one example, Vice President Harris’ call to action to the private sector just several months ago has rallied $1.2 billion in investments to support long-term social and economic progress in northern Central America.</p>
<p>Finally, many of us will meet again in Los Angeles for the Summit of the Americas in just a few weeks’ time in June.  There, we’ll have an opportunity to address the deeper issues driving irregular migration like improving public health, strengthening our democracies.  By adopting a Los Angeles declaration on migration and protection that sets forth our shared principles for a collaborative, coordinated response to migration and forced displacement as President Biden has proposed, our countries can take our partnership on this issue to the next level of effectiveness, and we can make a profound difference in the lives of our most vulnerable fellow citizens and in the future of our shared region.</p>
<p>So I hope we can use our time together as well today to lay the groundwork for a strong declaration by our leaders when they gather in California in June.  But to each and every one of you, we’ve been working together over many months now at the United Nations, Colombia, here in Panama.  Thank you.  Thank you for your commitment.  Thank you for your leadership.  Thank you for your partnership as we work together to promote safe, orderly, and humane migration across the Americas.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Panama City, Panama</p>
<p>Westin Playa Bonita Panama</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT COHEN:</strong>  (Via interpreter) (In progress) irregular migration.  We have been creating tourism and increasing (inaudible) irregular migration going through the borders  (inaudible).  Given these conditions, we have – there are victims of criminal organizations.  They’re exposed to multiple risks that attempt against human rights.</p>
<p>Facing this reality, we cannot be indifferent.  Our countries also work in a coordinated manner to find solutions in the short, medium, and long range.  We have an international humanitarian approach with shared responsibility among the countries of origin, transit, and final destination of these irregular migrants.  That is why we have to strengthen the policies of the region to be able to drive the economic growth in our countries to generate human growth opportunities and to create better living conditions for our peoples.</p>
<p>It is fundamental, achieving joint agreements and articulated agreements to tackle this migration phenomenon (inaudible) humanitarian organizations.  It is opportune to highlight what I mentioned already in the General Assembly of the United Nations back in September.  Irregular migration is possibly the (inaudible).  It demands a joint effort of coordinated strategies and enough resources to anticipate the humanitarian crisis in the region of great preparations.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, Panama is a (inaudible) standing in the flood of this irregular migration.  We have created a lot of efforts to tackle proactively and positively and with a humanitarian approach.  And we have coordinated (inaudible) states acting immediately and facing this challenge with (inaudible) because we understand that we cannot just stay talking, facing a problem like this.</p>
<p>Today I reaffirm Panama’s commitment to work jointly with friendly countries as strategic partners in the search of joint solutions with cross-sectional policies and concrete actions that will promote regular migrations, orderly and safe, respecting human rights.  I do appreciate all of you here present for your participation, your will, and determination to work in a regional integration to tackle the irregular migration phenomenon within the context of international migration.  Thank you so much.</p>
<p><strong>MR VASQUEZ: </strong> (Via interpreter) Ladies and gentlemen, having heard the opening remarks of His Excellency the President of Panama, Mr. Laurentino Cortizo Cohen, we open the floor to Erika Mouynes, Foreign Relations Minister, who will open the ministerial regional meeting on migration.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MOUYNES: </strong> (Via interpreter)  Good morning, everyone.  I would like to thank one more time your attendance, for just by being here is a clear support to the initiative to tackle the impact on irregular migration in a continental manner.  We all care, we have made this a priority, and we need to work together.  Migration is a current phenomenon and it is a complex one.  It is a world phenomenon.  And this phenomenon in particular responds to particular joint circumstances that magnify the COVID pandemic, climate change, war, conflict, and economic issues.  By working together with our neighboring countries and the United States, we are trying to approach this phenomenon in a responsible, effective, and humanitarian-focused way for which we have advocated since the very beginning, like our president said.</p>
<p>Figures are clear.  In August of 2021, influx through the Darién border came to a peak of 2,800 migrants in a day.  Today, it doesn’t go over 100 daily.  So we have motives to be optimistic, but we cannot falter because, one more time, the figures are still increasing.  Reality is harsh, and these events of – which are unexpected create migration waves and compels us to be prepared not only to be able to offer assistance but also not to have a negative impact.  There will be always cataclysms, new conflicts, but we can create effective and long-lasting control with a regional and continental strategy, but it has to be a permanent role.</p>
<p>Today we are providing continuity to something that we already began.  So today before we begin we should have three set objectives: one, coming to agreement in a working framework that will facilitate the standardization of migration policies in the region; number two, broaden the efforts of collaboration to fight trans-country organized crime; and number three, to concrete the cooperation dynamics among states, international organizations, and development banking in the region to have the structural basis to stop the structural basis that prompt migration.</p>
<p>Friends, your presence here is important, and it conveys the will to work together, sharing this responsibility to approach this challenge that is going to define the 21st century.  It will be collaboration, commitment, and consensus that always works.  Today we have an opportunity to speak with one voice, being certain that our meeting will mark a milestone in the history of our continent.  Thank you so much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good morning, everyone, and Erika, thank you so much for bringing us all together.  We are all living what is truly a historic challenge, and that is the fact that more people on our planet are on the move, forcibly displaced from their homes, than at any time since the Second World War.  That is the magnitude of the challenge, and we feel it strongly in our own hemisphere.  We’re focusing on different aspects of the problem today.</p>
<p>This morning in this first session, I know we want to focus on one particularly urgent aspect of the challenge:  How can we more effectively work together to help stabilize and strengthen communities across the region that are generously hosting large numbers of migrants and refugees?  The millions of people who have made the difficult and often dangerous decision to leave their homes we know do so for a variety of reasons – poverty, a lack of economic opportunity, repressive governance, corruption, political upheaval, conflict and insecurity.  All of these challenges already there are exacerbated by COVID-19 and by the climate crisis.</p>
<p>Ultimately, we all know this: the only lasting, sustainable response to irregular migration is to tackle its root causes.  But that takes time.  And in the meantime, many cities and towns simply don’t have the resources they need to provide for their own citizens, much less meeting the needs of migrants who are with them.</p>
<p>As Erika said, we know that no country, no community can solve a challenge as complicated as irregular migration alone.  We have to work together to support the front-line communities hosting migrants and refugees with increased resources for public health and safety, for stronger social services, for more resilient infrastructure, for opportunity for all – for migrants and host communities alike.</p>
<p>We’re making some progress.  Just to cite a few examples.  Colombia has registered more than 1.9 million Venezuelans for temporary protected status, and more than 600,000 have officially received that status.  That gives them documentation and legal protections that are critical for integrating into their local community.</p>
<p>It also means that more migrants can be vaccinated against COVID-19, which is critical to ending the pandemic and boosting economic recovery.</p>
<p>In that same spirit, the United States is expediting family-based petitions at our embassies throughout Central America so that migrants with family members in the United States are able to go there sponsored by the family members, and they can move much more quickly through the process as a result.</p>
<p>We’re also expanding visas for eligible groups – for example, 20,000 additional H2B temporary agricultural worker visas that Secretary Mayorkas recently announced.  And a critical piece of this is the role that multilateral finance and development institutions have been doing to provide more resources to front-line communities.  We have to work together to bring these efforts to scale throughout the hemisphere.</p>
<p>Again, with some examples.  The Inter-American Development Bank is boosting public health education and social protection in migrant host cities in Ecuador.  In Belize, the bank is running programs to increase educational opportunity for girls both from migrant families and from local communities.  And again, this is such a critical piece.  The support that we need to give to migrants we have to find ways also to make sure that local communities are getting support, getting help – are benefitting.  Otherwise, we know that none of this will be sustainable – politically, economically, socially.</p>
<p>In five Colombian cities, the bank is facilitating housing and helping local governments build institutional capacity to assist migrants, both of which are critical for them to integrate more seamlessly into our communities.  The World Bank’s Global Concessional Financing Facility has been instrumental in providing development assistance to countries worldwide that are affected by the refugee crisis, including economic and social support to Colombian communities hosting Venezuelan refugees.</p>
<p>So programs like these help point the way forward.  We need that kind of cross-cutting coordination – local and national governments, multilateral institutions, businesses, civil society – all working toward safe, orderly, and humane migration throughout the region and supporting the communities so that they can do right by these vulnerable populations.</p>
<p>Of course, even as we’re doing this, as I said at the outset, we have to remain resolutely focused on addressing root causes, in particular some of the economic drivers of migration, and there, again, we’re making some progress.  To name just one example, Vice President Harris’ call to action to the private sector just several months ago has rallied $1.2 billion in investments to support long-term social and economic progress in northern Central America.</p>
<p>Finally, many of us will meet again in Los Angeles for the Summit of the Americas in just a few weeks’ time in June.  There, we’ll have an opportunity to address the deeper issues driving irregular migration like improving public health, strengthening our democracies.  By adopting a Los Angeles declaration on migration and protection that sets forth our shared principles for a collaborative, coordinated response to migration and forced displacement as President Biden has proposed, our countries can take our partnership on this issue to the next level of effectiveness, and we can make a profound difference in the lives of our most vulnerable fellow citizens and in the future of our shared region.</p>
<p>So I hope we can use our time together as well today to lay the groundwork for a strong declaration by our leaders when they gather in California in June.  But to each and every one of you, we’ve been working together over many months now at the United Nations, Colombia, here in Panama.  Thank you.  Thank you for your commitment.  Thank you for your leadership.  Thank you for your partnership as we work together to promote safe, orderly, and humane migration across the Americas.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with NATO Permanent Representatives</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-nato-permanent-representatives/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 16:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335908</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today in Brussels with NATO Deputy Secretary General Mircea Geoană and NATO Permanent Representatives.  Deputy Secretary Sherman discussed continued strong coordination at NATO to ensure robust deterrence and defense, and shared U.S. priorities for NATO’s next Strategic Concept, which will make clear that NATO is stronger and more united than ever.  She noted U.S. concerns about the PRC’s support for Russia’s aggression, including through its amplification of Russian disinformation about NATO and Russia’s war in Ukraine, and called for continued strong Transatlantic coordination to defend the rules-based international order.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today in Brussels with NATO Deputy Secretary General Mircea Geoană and NATO Permanent Representatives.  Deputy Secretary Sherman discussed continued strong coordination at NATO to ensure robust deterrence and defense, and shared U.S. priorities for NATO’s next Strategic Concept, which will make clear that NATO is stronger and more united than ever.  She noted U.S. concerns about the PRC’s support for Russia’s aggression, including through its amplification of Russian disinformation about NATO and Russia’s war in Ukraine, and called for continued strong Transatlantic coordination to defend the rules-based international order.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
