<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 18:53:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-nato-secretary-general-stoltenberg-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 18:53:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344384</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today by phone with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg regarding the NATO Foreign Ministerial taking place in Berlin May 14-15. They deplored President Putin’s ruinous war in Ukraine, reiterated their support for the Ukrainian people and Ukraine’s territorial integrity, and discussed the importance of NATO maintaining strong deterrence and defense. They conferred about preparations for the upcoming June 28-30 NATO Summit in Madrid, including the new NATO Strategic Concept document that will guide NATO for the next decade.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today by phone with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg regarding the NATO Foreign Ministerial taking place in Berlin May 14-15. They deplored President Putin’s ruinous war in Ukraine, reiterated their support for the Ukrainian people and Ukraine’s territorial integrity, and discussed the importance of NATO maintaining strong deterrence and defense. They conferred about preparations for the upcoming June 28-30 NATO Summit in Madrid, including the new NATO Strategic Concept document that will guide NATO for the next decade.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Vietnamese Prime Minister Chinh</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-vietnamese-prime-minister-chinh/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 16:18:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344369</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met yesterday with Vietnamese Prime Minister Pham Minh Chinh in Washington, D.C. on the margins of the U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit.  Secretary Blinken highlighted the strong U.S. relationship with ASEAN, as evidenced by the U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit.  He reaffirmed the thriving U.S.-Vietnam Comprehensive Partnership and U.S. support for ASEAN centrality; the Mekong-U.S. Partnership; and a strong, prosperous, and independent Vietnam.  The Secretary and the Prime Minister discussed ways to broaden and deepen security cooperation, trade and economic ties, climate change cooperation, and people-to-people exchanges.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met yesterday with Vietnamese Prime Minister Pham Minh Chinh in Washington, D.C. on the margins of the U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit.  Secretary Blinken highlighted the strong U.S. relationship with ASEAN, as evidenced by the U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit.  He reaffirmed the thriving U.S.-Vietnam Comprehensive Partnership and U.S. support for ASEAN centrality; the Mekong-U.S. Partnership; and a strong, prosperous, and independent Vietnam.  The Secretary and the Prime Minister discussed ways to broaden and deepen security cooperation, trade and economic ties, climate change cooperation, and people-to-people exchanges.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Cambodian Deputy Prime Minister/Foreign Minister Sokhonn</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-cambodian-deputy-prime-minister-foreign-minister-sokhonn/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 16:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344366</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met yesterday with Cambodian Deputy Prime Minister/Foreign Minister Prak Sokhonn on the sidelines of the U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit in Washington, D.C.  The Secretary emphasized the United States’ continued support for Cambodia’s year as ASEAN Chair and thanked Deputy Prime Minister Sokhonn and the Royal Government of Cambodia for their support in making the summit a success.  The Secretary urged Deputy Prime Minister Sokhonn, in his role as ASEAN Special Envoy on Burma, to continue to push for the full implementation of the ASEAN Five-Point Consensus, including an immediate cessation of violence and dialogue with all parties concerned.  The Secretary also expressed concerns about the restrictions on human rights and fundamental freedoms in Cambodia.  He urged Cambodia to drop politically-motivated charges and allow opposition politicians to participate freely in upcoming elections.  The Secretary further reiterated U.S. concerns about how the People’s Republic of China’s construction of military facilities at Ream Naval Base could negatively affect regional security.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met yesterday with Cambodian Deputy Prime Minister/Foreign Minister Prak Sokhonn on the sidelines of the U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit in Washington, D.C.  The Secretary emphasized the United States’ continued support for Cambodia’s year as ASEAN Chair and thanked Deputy Prime Minister Sokhonn and the Royal Government of Cambodia for their support in making the summit a success.  The Secretary urged Deputy Prime Minister Sokhonn, in his role as ASEAN Special Envoy on Burma, to continue to push for the full implementation of the ASEAN Five-Point Consensus, including an immediate cessation of violence and dialogue with all parties concerned.  The Secretary also expressed concerns about the restrictions on human rights and fundamental freedoms in Cambodia.  He urged Cambodia to drop politically-motivated charges and allow opposition politicians to participate freely in upcoming elections.  The Secretary further reiterated U.S. concerns about how the People’s Republic of China’s construction of military facilities at Ream Naval Base could negatively affect regional security.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>G7 Foreign Ministers’ Statement on Russia’s War Against Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/g7-foreign-ministers-statement-on-russias-war-against-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 15:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344358</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><i>The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</i></p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<ol>
<li>We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union, are steadfast in our solidarity with and our support for Ukraine as it defends itself against Russia’s unjustifiable, unprovoked and illegal war of aggression, a war in which Belarus is complicit. We are committed to helping Ukraine, a democracy and a UN member, uphold its sovereignty and territorial integrity, to defend itself and resist future attacks or coercion, choose its own future and prosper.</li>
<li>In the presence of the Foreign Ministers of Ukraine and Moldova, we underscore Ukraine’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, independence and right for self-defence under the UN Charter. This war of aggression has reaffirmed our determination to reject outright attempts to redraw borders by force in violation of sovereignty and territorial integrity.</li>
<li>We are providing significant humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and its neighbours to meet urgent protection and other lifesaving needs. We continue to make substantial financial and economic support available to Ukraine to strengthen the resilience of its economy. We reaffirm our commitment to support Ukraine, including in the reconstruction of the country, and call on all partners to join our efforts to ensure support for Ukraine in meeting its immediate humanitarian and financial needs and for Ukraine to rebuild its future. We will pursue our ongoing military and defense assistance to Ukraine as long as necessary.</li>
<li>We reiterate our demand that Russia put an end to the war it started unprovoked and to end the tragic suffering and loss of life it continues to cause. We also continue to call on Belarus to stop enabling Russia’s aggression and to abide by its international obligations. We urge full compliance with international humanitarian law, allowing and facilitating rapid, safe and unimpeded humanitarian access as well as the humanitarian evacuation of civilians safeguarding evacuees’ freedom to choose their destination. We call on Russia to immediately comply with the legally binding order of the International Court of Justice of 16 March 2022 and to abide by the relevant resolutions of the UN General Assembly and stop its military aggression – to cease fire, and immediately and unconditionally withdraw its troops from the entire territory of Ukraine within its internationally recognised borders.</li>
<li>Russia has violated the UN Charter, undermined the fundamental principles of the European security architecture as enshrined in the Helsinki Final Act and the Charter of Paris and will have to face consequences for its actions. We reject any notion of spheres of influence and any use of force that is not in compliance with international law. We will never recognize borders Russia has attempted to change by military aggression, and will uphold our engagement in the support of the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine, including Crimea, and all states. We condemn as irresponsible threats of use of chemical, biological or nuclear weapons or related materials by Russia and reiterate that any use of such weapons would be met with severe consequences.</li>
<li>Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine as well as its unilateral actions restraining Ukrainian agricultural exports, are leading to steep price rises in commodity markets and the threats we are now seeing to global food security. As global markets suffer from Russia’s war of choice by rising food and commodity prices, thus affecting the lives of people around the world and exacerbating existing humanitarian and protection needs, we are determined to contribute additional resources to and support all relevant efforts that aim to ensure availability and accessibility of food, energy and financial resources as well as basic commodities for all. We call on Russia to cease immediately its attacks on key transport infrastructure in Ukraine, including ports, so that they can be used for exporting Ukrainian agricultural products. We will address the causes and consequences of the global food crisis through a Global Alliance for Food Security, that is to be launched officially at the G7 Development Ministers meeting, and other efforts in close cooperation with international partners and organisations beyond the G7. We will closely cooperate with international parters and organisations beyond the G7, and, with the aim of transforming political commitments into concrete actions as planned by various international initiatives such as the Food and Agricultural Resilience Mission (FARM) and key regional outreach initiatives, including towards African and Mediterranean countries.</li>
<li>We underscore that our sanctions and export controls against Russia do not and will not target essential exports of food and agricultural inputs to developing countries and to this end include measures to avoid any negative consequences for the production and distribution of food. We reaffirm our commitment to protect the most vulnerable countries and people suffering from Russia’s war against Ukraine and its global repercussions.</li>
<li>We condemn and will systematically expose Russia&#8217;s policy of information manipulation and interference, including disinformation which it employs to justify and support its war of aggression against Ukraine and which deliberately aims at manipulating public opinions domestically and worldwide with a view to covering its responsibilities in the ongoing war. We will continue to work together to address this manipulative behavior, in particular within the G7 Rapid Response Mechanism, and promote the exercise of freedom of opinion and expression and access to reliable information from free, pluralistic and independent media, notably on the war and its consequences for the world.</li>
<li>We stand united against Russia’s violation of the UN Charter and other fundamental principles of international law. We condemn in the strongest terms the ongoing attacks killing and wounding civilians and non-combatants, the systematic targeting of critical infrastructure and the extensive harm to healthcare personnel and facilities, as well as conflict-related sexual and gender-based violence in Ukraine. We will continue to support the ongoing investigations into violations of international law, including violations of international humanitarian law, and human rights violations and potential war crimes and crimes against humanity committed in Ukraine. We support investigations by the Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court, the Prosecutor-General of Ukraine, and other national prosecutors who are able to establish jurisdiction under national law. Further, we fully support the Commission of Inquiry mandated by the UN Human Rights Council, the UN Human Rights Monitoring Mission in Ukraine and efforts of civil society organizations to investigate violations and document potential war crimes. We commit to providing investigative support, technical expertise, funding and other assistance to work towards ensuring the accountability of those who are responsible for the atrocities and crimes committed.</li>
<li>A number of countries have shown solidarity and provided safe haven for those who have fled from Russia’s war of aggression. We particularly commend Moldova’s remarkable efforts in hosting so many refugees, both in relative and absolute terms. Through the Moldova Support Platform launched in Berlin on 5 April and other formats, we will support Moldova to meet short-term needs and its longer-term development and reform programme. We express our concern regarding the recent attempts to destabilise the Transnistrian region and emphasize our support to Moldova’s stability, sovereignty and territorial integrity.</li>
<li>We reaffirm our determination to further increase economic and political pressure on Russia, continuing to act in unity. We will do so, as underlined by G7 Leaders on 8 May, by imposing coordinated further restrictive measures on Russia‘s economy and financial system; by further targeting Russian elites including economic actors, the central government institutions and the military, that enable President Putin to lead his war of choice; and by isolating Russia from our economies, the international financial system, and within global institutions. We will broaden our sanctions measures to include sectors on which Russia has a particular dependence.</li>
<li>We commend partners that have aligned with us, and encourage others to adopt measures to increase the cost of the war for Russia by isolating it, and Belarus for its support, from the global economy, and to prevent sanctions evasion, circumvention and backfilling. We will listen to and work with partners around the world through increased outreach to mitigate any impacts to their own economies caused by Putin’s war, and pledge our support in mitigating the costs.</li>
<li>We will expedite our efforts to reduce and end reliance on Russian energy supplies as quickly as possible, building on G7 commitments to phase out or ban imports of Russian coal and oil. We will accelerate the energy transition and enhance energy efficiency in the context of the accelerated phasing out of our dependency on Russian energy, in accordance with our climate objectives and energy security imperatives, thereby steadily reducing foreign currency flows into Russia and restricting the financial means available to fund Russia’s war machinery. We will ensure that we do so in a timely and orderly fashion, and in ways that provide time for the world to secure alternative supplies.</li>
<li>We deplore the domestic repressions in Russia and Belarus against independent media, civil society, the opposition and citizens who peacefully express their disapproval of Russia’s war against Ukraine. The Russians and Belarusians deserve better: They should be able to make full use of fundamental human rights, most basically the right to decide their own fate and the fate of their countries. We, the G7, are not at war with Russia or the Russian people. The Russian decision to attack Ukraine was taken by leaders who reject democratic responsibility. We lend our support to those who have fallen victim to repression. We reaffirm the right of Russians and Belarusians to seek, receive and impart fact-based information from free, pluralistic and independent media and condemn the Russian government’s and Belarusian regime’s recourse to censorship and other methods of hampering Russians’ and Belarusians’ access to independent media, including through restrictions on access to the internet and social media platforms.</li>
<li>We condemn actions perpetrated by Russia, which compromise the safety and security of nuclear material and facilities in Ukraine and consequently pose serious risks to human life and the environment. We underline our full support for the efforts of the IAEA and its Director-General to ensure the nuclear safety and security of, and the application of safeguards to, nuclear material and facilities in Ukraine. We call on Russia to immediately withdraw its forces from Ukraine’s nuclear facilities and to return full control to legitimate Ukrainian authorities. We reiterate that the IAEA must be able to access all nuclear facilities in Ukraine safely and without any impediments.</li>
</ol>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><i>The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</i></p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<ol>
<li>We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union, are steadfast in our solidarity with and our support for Ukraine as it defends itself against Russia’s unjustifiable, unprovoked and illegal war of aggression, a war in which Belarus is complicit. We are committed to helping Ukraine, a democracy and a UN member, uphold its sovereignty and territorial integrity, to defend itself and resist future attacks or coercion, choose its own future and prosper.</li>
<li>In the presence of the Foreign Ministers of Ukraine and Moldova, we underscore Ukraine’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, independence and right for self-defence under the UN Charter. This war of aggression has reaffirmed our determination to reject outright attempts to redraw borders by force in violation of sovereignty and territorial integrity.</li>
<li>We are providing significant humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and its neighbours to meet urgent protection and other lifesaving needs. We continue to make substantial financial and economic support available to Ukraine to strengthen the resilience of its economy. We reaffirm our commitment to support Ukraine, including in the reconstruction of the country, and call on all partners to join our efforts to ensure support for Ukraine in meeting its immediate humanitarian and financial needs and for Ukraine to rebuild its future. We will pursue our ongoing military and defense assistance to Ukraine as long as necessary.</li>
<li>We reiterate our demand that Russia put an end to the war it started unprovoked and to end the tragic suffering and loss of life it continues to cause. We also continue to call on Belarus to stop enabling Russia’s aggression and to abide by its international obligations. We urge full compliance with international humanitarian law, allowing and facilitating rapid, safe and unimpeded humanitarian access as well as the humanitarian evacuation of civilians safeguarding evacuees’ freedom to choose their destination. We call on Russia to immediately comply with the legally binding order of the International Court of Justice of 16 March 2022 and to abide by the relevant resolutions of the UN General Assembly and stop its military aggression – to cease fire, and immediately and unconditionally withdraw its troops from the entire territory of Ukraine within its internationally recognised borders.</li>
<li>Russia has violated the UN Charter, undermined the fundamental principles of the European security architecture as enshrined in the Helsinki Final Act and the Charter of Paris and will have to face consequences for its actions. We reject any notion of spheres of influence and any use of force that is not in compliance with international law. We will never recognize borders Russia has attempted to change by military aggression, and will uphold our engagement in the support of the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine, including Crimea, and all states. We condemn as irresponsible threats of use of chemical, biological or nuclear weapons or related materials by Russia and reiterate that any use of such weapons would be met with severe consequences.</li>
<li>Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine as well as its unilateral actions restraining Ukrainian agricultural exports, are leading to steep price rises in commodity markets and the threats we are now seeing to global food security. As global markets suffer from Russia’s war of choice by rising food and commodity prices, thus affecting the lives of people around the world and exacerbating existing humanitarian and protection needs, we are determined to contribute additional resources to and support all relevant efforts that aim to ensure availability and accessibility of food, energy and financial resources as well as basic commodities for all. We call on Russia to cease immediately its attacks on key transport infrastructure in Ukraine, including ports, so that they can be used for exporting Ukrainian agricultural products. We will address the causes and consequences of the global food crisis through a Global Alliance for Food Security, that is to be launched officially at the G7 Development Ministers meeting, and other efforts in close cooperation with international partners and organisations beyond the G7. We will closely cooperate with international parters and organisations beyond the G7, and, with the aim of transforming political commitments into concrete actions as planned by various international initiatives such as the Food and Agricultural Resilience Mission (FARM) and key regional outreach initiatives, including towards African and Mediterranean countries.</li>
<li>We underscore that our sanctions and export controls against Russia do not and will not target essential exports of food and agricultural inputs to developing countries and to this end include measures to avoid any negative consequences for the production and distribution of food. We reaffirm our commitment to protect the most vulnerable countries and people suffering from Russia’s war against Ukraine and its global repercussions.</li>
<li>We condemn and will systematically expose Russia&#8217;s policy of information manipulation and interference, including disinformation which it employs to justify and support its war of aggression against Ukraine and which deliberately aims at manipulating public opinions domestically and worldwide with a view to covering its responsibilities in the ongoing war. We will continue to work together to address this manipulative behavior, in particular within the G7 Rapid Response Mechanism, and promote the exercise of freedom of opinion and expression and access to reliable information from free, pluralistic and independent media, notably on the war and its consequences for the world.</li>
<li>We stand united against Russia’s violation of the UN Charter and other fundamental principles of international law. We condemn in the strongest terms the ongoing attacks killing and wounding civilians and non-combatants, the systematic targeting of critical infrastructure and the extensive harm to healthcare personnel and facilities, as well as conflict-related sexual and gender-based violence in Ukraine. We will continue to support the ongoing investigations into violations of international law, including violations of international humanitarian law, and human rights violations and potential war crimes and crimes against humanity committed in Ukraine. We support investigations by the Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court, the Prosecutor-General of Ukraine, and other national prosecutors who are able to establish jurisdiction under national law. Further, we fully support the Commission of Inquiry mandated by the UN Human Rights Council, the UN Human Rights Monitoring Mission in Ukraine and efforts of civil society organizations to investigate violations and document potential war crimes. We commit to providing investigative support, technical expertise, funding and other assistance to work towards ensuring the accountability of those who are responsible for the atrocities and crimes committed.</li>
<li>A number of countries have shown solidarity and provided safe haven for those who have fled from Russia’s war of aggression. We particularly commend Moldova’s remarkable efforts in hosting so many refugees, both in relative and absolute terms. Through the Moldova Support Platform launched in Berlin on 5 April and other formats, we will support Moldova to meet short-term needs and its longer-term development and reform programme. We express our concern regarding the recent attempts to destabilise the Transnistrian region and emphasize our support to Moldova’s stability, sovereignty and territorial integrity.</li>
<li>We reaffirm our determination to further increase economic and political pressure on Russia, continuing to act in unity. We will do so, as underlined by G7 Leaders on 8 May, by imposing coordinated further restrictive measures on Russia‘s economy and financial system; by further targeting Russian elites including economic actors, the central government institutions and the military, that enable President Putin to lead his war of choice; and by isolating Russia from our economies, the international financial system, and within global institutions. We will broaden our sanctions measures to include sectors on which Russia has a particular dependence.</li>
<li>We commend partners that have aligned with us, and encourage others to adopt measures to increase the cost of the war for Russia by isolating it, and Belarus for its support, from the global economy, and to prevent sanctions evasion, circumvention and backfilling. We will listen to and work with partners around the world through increased outreach to mitigate any impacts to their own economies caused by Putin’s war, and pledge our support in mitigating the costs.</li>
<li>We will expedite our efforts to reduce and end reliance on Russian energy supplies as quickly as possible, building on G7 commitments to phase out or ban imports of Russian coal and oil. We will accelerate the energy transition and enhance energy efficiency in the context of the accelerated phasing out of our dependency on Russian energy, in accordance with our climate objectives and energy security imperatives, thereby steadily reducing foreign currency flows into Russia and restricting the financial means available to fund Russia’s war machinery. We will ensure that we do so in a timely and orderly fashion, and in ways that provide time for the world to secure alternative supplies.</li>
<li>We deplore the domestic repressions in Russia and Belarus against independent media, civil society, the opposition and citizens who peacefully express their disapproval of Russia’s war against Ukraine. The Russians and Belarusians deserve better: They should be able to make full use of fundamental human rights, most basically the right to decide their own fate and the fate of their countries. We, the G7, are not at war with Russia or the Russian people. The Russian decision to attack Ukraine was taken by leaders who reject democratic responsibility. We lend our support to those who have fallen victim to repression. We reaffirm the right of Russians and Belarusians to seek, receive and impart fact-based information from free, pluralistic and independent media and condemn the Russian government’s and Belarusian regime’s recourse to censorship and other methods of hampering Russians’ and Belarusians’ access to independent media, including through restrictions on access to the internet and social media platforms.</li>
<li>We condemn actions perpetrated by Russia, which compromise the safety and security of nuclear material and facilities in Ukraine and consequently pose serious risks to human life and the environment. We underline our full support for the efforts of the IAEA and its Director-General to ensure the nuclear safety and security of, and the application of safeguards to, nuclear material and facilities in Ukraine. We call on Russia to immediately withdraw its forces from Ukraine’s nuclear facilities and to return full control to legitimate Ukrainian authorities. We reiterate that the IAEA must be able to access all nuclear facilities in Ukraine safely and without any impediments.</li>
</ol>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paraguay Independence Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/paraguay-independence-day-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 13:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the people of the United States, I congratulate the people of Paraguay as you celebrate the 211th anniversary of your independence.</p>
<p>We reaffirm our strong partnership with Paraguay as we work together to recover from the COVID-19 pandemic.  We will continue to work together to advance our many shared interests, such as promoting transparency, combating corruption, fighting transnational crime, and supporting economic inclusivity for our two nations.  We look forward to engaging with Paraguay on these and other important issues at the Ninth Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles, California.</p>
<p>As we unite in celebration of Paraguay’s democratic achievements on this great occasion, the United States renews our partnership to promote peace, prosperity, and security in the Americas.  We look forward to deepening our enduring friendship, based on shared values and commitments, in the coming years.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the people of the United States, I congratulate the people of Paraguay as you celebrate the 211th anniversary of your independence.</p>
<p>We reaffirm our strong partnership with Paraguay as we work together to recover from the COVID-19 pandemic.  We will continue to work together to advance our many shared interests, such as promoting transparency, combating corruption, fighting transnational crime, and supporting economic inclusivity for our two nations.  We look forward to engaging with Paraguay on these and other important issues at the Ninth Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles, California.</p>
<p>As we unite in celebration of Paraguay’s democratic achievements on this great occasion, the United States renews our partnership to promote peace, prosperity, and security in the Americas.  We look forward to deepening our enduring friendship, based on shared values and commitments, in the coming years.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Thai Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-thai-deputy-prime-minister-and-foreign-minister-don-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;"><span>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met yesterday with Thai Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don Pramudwinai in Washington, D.C.  Secretary Blinken emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Thailand alliance and partnership to the security and prosperity of the region and discussed potential cooperation under<i> </i>the new Indo-Pacific Economic Framework<b><i>.</i></b></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;"><span>Highlighting closely aligned aspirations for the respective Thai and U.S. 2022 and 2023 APEC host years, the Secretary highlighted the need to tackle the climate crisis and bolster climate-friendly economic growth. He also underscored the importance of upholding shared values across the Mekong region, including by providing humanitarian assistance to the people of Burma and working through ASEAN to restore Burma’s path to democracy.  </span></span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;"><span>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met yesterday with Thai Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don Pramudwinai in Washington, D.C.  Secretary Blinken emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Thailand alliance and partnership to the security and prosperity of the region and discussed potential cooperation under<i> </i>the new Indo-Pacific Economic Framework<b><i>.</i></b></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;"><span>Highlighting closely aligned aspirations for the respective Thai and U.S. 2022 and 2023 APEC host years, the Secretary highlighted the need to tackle the climate crisis and bolster climate-friendly economic growth. He also underscored the importance of upholding shared values across the Mekong region, including by providing humanitarian assistance to the people of Burma and working through ASEAN to restore Burma’s path to democracy.  </span></span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Escalations in Jerusalem at the Funeral of Shireen Abu Akleh</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/escalations-in-jerusalem-at-the-funeral-of-shireen-abu-akleh/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 21:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States again extends our deepest condolences to the family and loved ones of Shireen Abu Akleh, a renowned Palestinian American journalist. We were deeply troubled to see the images of Israeli police intruding into her funeral procession today. Every family deserves to be able to lay their loved ones to rest in a dignified and unimpeded manner. We remain in close contact with our Israeli and Palestinian counterparts and call on all to maintain calm and avoid any actions that could further escalate tensions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States again extends our deepest condolences to the family and loved ones of Shireen Abu Akleh, a renowned Palestinian American journalist. We were deeply troubled to see the images of Israeli police intruding into her funeral procession today. Every family deserves to be able to lay their loved ones to rest in a dignified and unimpeded manner. We remain in close contact with our Israeli and Palestinian counterparts and call on all to maintain calm and avoid any actions that could further escalate tensions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Cambodian Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Prak Sokhonn</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-cambodian-deputy-prime-minister-and-foreign-minister-prak-sokhonn/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Prak Sokhonn, Cambodian Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 20:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Prak Sokhonn, Cambodian Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a pleasure to be here with the deputy prime minister of Cambodia.  I really want to thank you, Deputy Prime Minister, and Cambodia for your leadership of ASEAN and for everything you’ve done to make this such a successful special summit between the United States and ASEAN.</p>
<p>We’ve had an opportunity to deepen the work that we’re doing together, and to put out – I think, a very important vision statement for the future, and Cambodia’s work to bring us to this point is greatly appreciated.  We’re working very closely together as partners to try to advance a shared vision for the region, including regional security.  And of course, we welcome the leadership role that you’re playing in ASEAN on a number of issues, including hopefully working to restore the democratic path in Myanmar.</p>
<p>So, it’s very good to have you here.  Welcome again to the State Department.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY PRIME MINISTER PRAK SOKHONN:</strong>  Thank you very much, Secretary Blinken.  It’s a real honor, pleasure to be here to have this meeting with you.  It’s an opportunity for us to exchange views, especially to strengthen our bilateral cooperation.  And it’s a wonderful for Cambodia as a chair to have been able to organize – co-organize this summit between ASEAN leaders and the U.S.</p>
<p>I am ready to have a good discussion with Secretary Blinken, in order to strengthen our bilateral relationship and to push forward for solution in a number of regional issues.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you, everyone.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Prak Sokhonn, Cambodian Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a pleasure to be here with the deputy prime minister of Cambodia.  I really want to thank you, Deputy Prime Minister, and Cambodia for your leadership of ASEAN and for everything you’ve done to make this such a successful special summit between the United States and ASEAN.</p>
<p>We’ve had an opportunity to deepen the work that we’re doing together, and to put out – I think, a very important vision statement for the future, and Cambodia’s work to bring us to this point is greatly appreciated.  We’re working very closely together as partners to try to advance a shared vision for the region, including regional security.  And of course, we welcome the leadership role that you’re playing in ASEAN on a number of issues, including hopefully working to restore the democratic path in Myanmar.</p>
<p>So, it’s very good to have you here.  Welcome again to the State Department.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY PRIME MINISTER PRAK SOKHONN:</strong>  Thank you very much, Secretary Blinken.  It’s a real honor, pleasure to be here to have this meeting with you.  It’s an opportunity for us to exchange views, especially to strengthen our bilateral cooperation.  And it’s a wonderful for Cambodia as a chair to have been able to organize – co-organize this summit between ASEAN leaders and the U.S.</p>
<p>I am ready to have a good discussion with Secretary Blinken, in order to strengthen our bilateral relationship and to push forward for solution in a number of regional issues.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you, everyone.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Launch Event for the Establishment of the Counterterrorism Law Enforcement Forum</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/launch-event-for-the-establishment-of-the-counterterrorism-law-enforcement-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 19:33:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344137</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On May 11-12 in Berlin, the Departments of State and Justice launched the Counterterrorism Law Enforcement Forum (CTLEF), co-hosted by the Government of Germany. The CTLEF, which focuses on countering racially or ethnically motivated violent extremism (REMVE) globally, brought together law enforcement, prosecutors, and other criminal justice practitioners from Europe, North and South America, and the Indo-Pacific, alongside specialists from INTERPOL, Europol, the International Institute for Justice and the Rule of Law, the UN Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC), and other multilateral organizations.</p>
<p>The inaugural CTLEF meeting increased awareness and information sharing among law enforcement and criminal justice partners about global REMVE activity, including the transnational linkages between and among REMVE actors. Participants also learned about recent law enforcement actions undertaken by governments to disrupt REMVE actors’ global activity.</p>
<p>Officials from the U.S. Departments of State, Justice, and the Treasury, as well as the Federal Bureau of Investigation, participated. The CTLEF will convene again in the spring of 2023.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On May 11-12 in Berlin, the Departments of State and Justice launched the Counterterrorism Law Enforcement Forum (CTLEF), co-hosted by the Government of Germany. The CTLEF, which focuses on countering racially or ethnically motivated violent extremism (REMVE) globally, brought together law enforcement, prosecutors, and other criminal justice practitioners from Europe, North and South America, and the Indo-Pacific, alongside specialists from INTERPOL, Europol, the International Institute for Justice and the Rule of Law, the UN Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC), and other multilateral organizations.</p>
<p>The inaugural CTLEF meeting increased awareness and information sharing among law enforcement and criminal justice partners about global REMVE activity, including the transnational linkages between and among REMVE actors. Participants also learned about recent law enforcement actions undertaken by governments to disrupt REMVE actors’ global activity.</p>
<p>Officials from the U.S. Departments of State, Justice, and the Treasury, as well as the Federal Bureau of Investigation, participated. The CTLEF will convene again in the spring of 2023.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Indonesian Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-indonesian-foreign-minister-retno-marsudi-before-their-meeting-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 15:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344029</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good morning, everyone.  It’s a real pleasure to be here with my friend and colleague, the foreign minister of Indonesia.  Retno, thank you for being here, but thank you more broadly for Indonesia’s remarkable leadership.  We just had – we’re still having what is truly a historic summit between the United States and ASEAN.  And the success of this effort is in no small measure due to Indonesia’s leadership as our country coordinator, but also as the leader of ASEAN.  I know from speaking to President Biden that the meetings have been already a significant success.  And it just puts an emphasis on the great importance that we attach, the United States attaches to ASEAN, our relationship, ASEAN centrality.  But so much of this is due to Indonesia’s leadership.</p>
<p>We are working together across the board to advance a shared vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific region.  We’re working to strengthen economic ties among countries in the region.  We’re working together to deal with global challenges, like COVID-19.  Just yesterday at the summit that the President was also convening, I had the opportunity to do a session with your health minister about how we can strengthen the global health security system for the future.  So here, again, Indonesia is playing a leadership role.</p>
<p>We have a lot to talk about, including the situation in Myanmar and other occupations, but I think most important is that what I’ve seen over the last year and a half is a increasingly strong relationship, partnership between our countries, for which the United States is truly appreciative.  So welcome.  It’s great to have you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MARSUDI:</strong>  Well, thank you very much, Secretary Blinken.  Thank you very much, Tony.  It’s very – I feel so glad to be back to D.C. again, and this time is for the ASEAN-U.S. Summit.  And I’m also very glad that we are able to have separately a bilateral meeting to discuss various issues of bilateral relation as well as regional and global issue.</p>
<p>U.S. and Indonesia are strategic partner.  With this strategic partnership, I am very glad to see intensified communication and cooperation between our two countries.  And we should use this strategic partnership also to contribute to the peace, stability, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>So, I also hope to see synergy between the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework with implementation of cooperation under the ASEAN Outlook on the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>On the global issue, I would like to reiterate the very consistent of the principle of Indonesia on the importance of respecting territorial integrity and sovereignty of a country to another country.  So, this principle is upheld by Indonesia very consistently.</p>
<p>Our hope is to see the war in Ukraine stop as soon as possible, and we give the peaceful resolution of a conflict a chance to succeed.  Because we know that if the war continues, all of us will suffer.</p>
<p>And finally, looking forward to welcoming you on the foreign ministers meeting of the G20 in July 2022 in Bali.</p>
<p>So once again, thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MARSUDI:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Come on in.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good morning, everyone.  It’s a real pleasure to be here with my friend and colleague, the foreign minister of Indonesia.  Retno, thank you for being here, but thank you more broadly for Indonesia’s remarkable leadership.  We just had – we’re still having what is truly a historic summit between the United States and ASEAN.  And the success of this effort is in no small measure due to Indonesia’s leadership as our country coordinator, but also as the leader of ASEAN.  I know from speaking to President Biden that the meetings have been already a significant success.  And it just puts an emphasis on the great importance that we attach, the United States attaches to ASEAN, our relationship, ASEAN centrality.  But so much of this is due to Indonesia’s leadership.</p>
<p>We are working together across the board to advance a shared vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific region.  We’re working to strengthen economic ties among countries in the region.  We’re working together to deal with global challenges, like COVID-19.  Just yesterday at the summit that the President was also convening, I had the opportunity to do a session with your health minister about how we can strengthen the global health security system for the future.  So here, again, Indonesia is playing a leadership role.</p>
<p>We have a lot to talk about, including the situation in Myanmar and other occupations, but I think most important is that what I’ve seen over the last year and a half is a increasingly strong relationship, partnership between our countries, for which the United States is truly appreciative.  So welcome.  It’s great to have you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MARSUDI:</strong>  Well, thank you very much, Secretary Blinken.  Thank you very much, Tony.  It’s very – I feel so glad to be back to D.C. again, and this time is for the ASEAN-U.S. Summit.  And I’m also very glad that we are able to have separately a bilateral meeting to discuss various issues of bilateral relation as well as regional and global issue.</p>
<p>U.S. and Indonesia are strategic partner.  With this strategic partnership, I am very glad to see intensified communication and cooperation between our two countries.  And we should use this strategic partnership also to contribute to the peace, stability, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>So, I also hope to see synergy between the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework with implementation of cooperation under the ASEAN Outlook on the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>On the global issue, I would like to reiterate the very consistent of the principle of Indonesia on the importance of respecting territorial integrity and sovereignty of a country to another country.  So, this principle is upheld by Indonesia very consistently.</p>
<p>Our hope is to see the war in Ukraine stop as soon as possible, and we give the peaceful resolution of a conflict a chance to succeed.  Because we know that if the war continues, all of us will suffer.</p>
<p>And finally, looking forward to welcoming you on the foreign ministers meeting of the G20 in July 2022 in Bali.</p>
<p>So once again, thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MARSUDI:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Come on in.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
