<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 22:29:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Estonian Foreign Minister Eva-Maria Liimets Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-estonian-foreign-minister-eva-maria-liimets-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 21:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=315007</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone.  Eva-Maria, it’s a pleasure to welcome you here to the State Department, to Washington.  We have a – marked a year that I think is significant because this year actually marks 100 years of diplomatic relations between Estonia and the United States.  But we are very much focused not only on that but on the present and the work that we’re doing together with Estonia, a very strong partner in NATO, and working together, of course, to support Ukraine, to try to deter Russian aggression, and to continue to strengthen NATO faced with the challenges of the moment.</p>
<p>But beyond that, I look very much forward to talking with the foreign minister about many other aspects of our relationship, and of course we always look to Estonia for insight on technology and the future because Estonia is a remarkably future-oriented country, and we’re just grateful for the partnership that we have.  We have a lot to talk about within the moment that we are all living and the challenges to your security that unfortunately come from Russia’s aggressive posture, but we’ll cover that and much more.</p>
<p>But meanwhile, welcome.  It’s so good to have you here in Washington.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER LIIMETS:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you very much, Secretary Blinken.  (Inaudible) if I may.  Thank you very much for the warm welcome today in Washington, D.C.  I very much look forward to our discussion, of course, about the bilateral relations, our good friendship, but also, of course, the security concerns that we face today in Europe and also what we could do more together to promote democracy, human rights, fundamental values around the globe, but particularly in the Eastern Partnership countries close to Estonia, close to our neighborhood.</p>
<p>Estonia of course is forever thankful to the United States for its nonrecognition policy when Estonia was occupied, and it’s really very unfortunate we see that 30 years after we regained our independence, we face such a severe security crisis in Europe.  And we have been very thankful for your leadership in coping with this current security crisis and truly hope that diplomacy is successful and we can have a peaceful future instead of having more and more (inaudible).</p>
<p>And of course, as we celebrate 100 years of diplomatic relations, I think that it’s been a full century behind us and I hope that our close and steadfast friendship continues (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  (Inaudible.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone.  Eva-Maria, it’s a pleasure to welcome you here to the State Department, to Washington.  We have a – marked a year that I think is significant because this year actually marks 100 years of diplomatic relations between Estonia and the United States.  But we are very much focused not only on that but on the present and the work that we’re doing together with Estonia, a very strong partner in NATO, and working together, of course, to support Ukraine, to try to deter Russian aggression, and to continue to strengthen NATO faced with the challenges of the moment.</p>
<p>But beyond that, I look very much forward to talking with the foreign minister about many other aspects of our relationship, and of course we always look to Estonia for insight on technology and the future because Estonia is a remarkably future-oriented country, and we’re just grateful for the partnership that we have.  We have a lot to talk about within the moment that we are all living and the challenges to your security that unfortunately come from Russia’s aggressive posture, but we’ll cover that and much more.</p>
<p>But meanwhile, welcome.  It’s so good to have you here in Washington.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER LIIMETS:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you very much, Secretary Blinken.  (Inaudible) if I may.  Thank you very much for the warm welcome today in Washington, D.C.  I very much look forward to our discussion, of course, about the bilateral relations, our good friendship, but also, of course, the security concerns that we face today in Europe and also what we could do more together to promote democracy, human rights, fundamental values around the globe, but particularly in the Eastern Partnership countries close to Estonia, close to our neighborhood.</p>
<p>Estonia of course is forever thankful to the United States for its nonrecognition policy when Estonia was occupied, and it’s really very unfortunate we see that 30 years after we regained our independence, we face such a severe security crisis in Europe.  And we have been very thankful for your leadership in coping with this current security crisis and truly hope that diplomacy is successful and we can have a peaceful future instead of having more and more (inaudible).</p>
<p>And of course, as we celebrate 100 years of diplomatic relations, I think that it’s been a full century behind us and I hope that our close and steadfast friendship continues (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  (Inaudible.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Danish Acting Permanent Secretary Moller Sorensen</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-danish-acting-permanent-secretary-moller-sorensen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 20:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=315001</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Danish Acting Permanent Secretary Jesper Moller Sorensen today in Washington, D.C. The Deputy Secretary and Acting Permanent Secretary emphasized the enduring partnership between the United States and Denmark. They discussed our shared commitment to urging Russia to de-escalate and choose diplomacy and reaffirmed that any further Russian aggression would result in massive consequences and severe costs to the Russian Federation. The two also discussed the Arctic, joint efforts to protect democracy, and other issues of mutual interest. The Deputy Secretary welcomed Denmark’s February 10 announcement to begin negotiating a new Defense Cooperation Agreement between the United States and Denmark.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Danish Acting Permanent Secretary Jesper Moller Sorensen today in Washington, D.C. The Deputy Secretary and Acting Permanent Secretary emphasized the enduring partnership between the United States and Denmark. They discussed our shared commitment to urging Russia to de-escalate and choose diplomacy and reaffirmed that any further Russian aggression would result in massive consequences and severe costs to the Russian Federation. The two also discussed the Arctic, joint efforts to protect democracy, and other issues of mutual interest. The Deputy Secretary welcomed Denmark’s February 10 announcement to begin negotiating a new Defense Cooperation Agreement between the United States and Denmark.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Travel to Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 19:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=314977</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Munich, Germany, February 17 to 20, 2022 to attend the Munich Security Conference. On the sidelines of the Conference, the Secretary will have the opportunity to discuss with Allies and partners our coordinated, ongoing efforts to urge Russia to deescalate and choose the path of diplomacy as well as our readiness to impose severe costs should Russia further invade Ukraine. The Secretary will also reaffirm our support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. He will have bilateral meetings with his counterparts to address our commitment to transatlantic coordination to strengthen European security and other ongoing global challenges.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Munich, Germany, February 17 to 20, 2022 to attend the Munich Security Conference. On the sidelines of the Conference, the Secretary will have the opportunity to discuss with Allies and partners our coordinated, ongoing efforts to urge Russia to deescalate and choose the path of diplomacy as well as our readiness to impose severe costs should Russia further invade Ukraine. The Secretary will also reaffirm our support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. He will have bilateral meetings with his counterparts to address our commitment to transatlantic coordination to strengthen European security and other ongoing global challenges.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at Virtual Summit for Democracy Civil Society Roundtable</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-virtual-summit-for-democracy-civil-society-roundtable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 17:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=314952</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>UNDER SECRETARY ZEYA:</b>  Good morning and welcome, everyone.  It’s great to see you all again, and I hope your 2022 is off to a healthy and strong start.  For my part, I want to start with a thank you.</p>
<p>As some of our most valued thinkers and doers, we greatly appreciate your time and commitment and the ideas and feedback that we used from you to strengthen the summit agenda.  We incorporated many of your recommendations, and we hope you saw those reflected in our December event.  Some of what the Secretary will lay out today for the Year of Action may also sound familiar; the concept of establishing democracy cohorts, for example, comes directly from all of you.</p>
<p>I’m excited to use this call today to pick up our conversation from last year.  As we move into the Year of Action, we look forward to regular consultations with civil society.  This isn’t a one-way conversation, either.  We plan to both listen and share, and work in partnership with civil society to achieve our shared summit goals this year.  The main goal in the Year of Action is to sustain the summit’s momentum and land concrete results that shore up democracies around the world, including our own; push back against the raw deal of authoritarianism; defend and promote respect for human rights; and combat corruption.  And at a time when all indicators flag continued democratic backsliding, we cannot achieve our summit goals without a meaningful partnership with civil society.  So, I thank you all for your leadership.</p>
<p>Today we’re honored to be joined by Secretary Blinken, and thank you for being with us today.  I’m also delighted to welcome Erin Barclay, our coordinator for global democratic renewal, who will moderate today’s Q&amp;A.  And as the Secretary, given the pace of world events, has been called away to a meeting at the White House, his time with us is a bit compressed.  I want to hand the floor to him, and thank you, sir, for your leadership.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Uzra, thank you so much.  Erin, thank you as well.  And it’s great to see everyone on the screen.</p>
<p>Yes.  I was looking forward to actually spending a bit of time this morning.  Unfortunately, a larger force, as in the President, has called me over to a meeting, so I want to at least spend the top of this meeting with you.  And I’m going to make sure that I hear from both Uzra and Erin exactly what was said during the meeting so that I can factor that in.  But let me just say a few words, if I can, at the outset and see if we have any time for questions before I get pulled over down the street.</p>
<p>First and foremost, thank you for being here today.  But thank you even more for being partners in this effort, the Democracy Summit, everything that is following from it in this Year of Action, and of course for, irrespective of that, the vital work that each and every one of you is doing every single day to advance democracy and human rights.  We really did want to spend some time, again, hearing from you as we continue to inform our own efforts, we continue to carry forward what was started with the Democracy Summit.  You know that the basic aim of the summit was to start to rally countries to try to make concrete commitments to strengthen their own democracies and to help other democracies deliver for the people that they’re supposed to serve.  And then, having made those commitments, we are now in what we’ve been calling a Year of Action, where we try to turn commitments into real change.  And that’s what this year is all about.</p>
<p>And the “we” includes all of us with a stake in advancing democracy and human rights, not only governments but the private sector, individual citizens, and, of course, civil society organizations.  Earlier this week we posted online the voluntary commitments that countries made at the summit.  For example, Paraguay will create an interagency task force to fight money laundering; Micronesia will put forward an access to information law; Luxembourg will create a senior-level post for advancing racial equity and diversity, to name just a few of the pledges.  Putting the commitments out there for all to see is a key part of holding governments, including our own, accountable.  And I have no doubt that you will all help do that.</p>
<p>Many countries are starting to follow through on commitments.  As we meet here today, Ghana and Norway are co-chairing the Global Disability Summit.  Just last week the Estonians convened the Global Conference on Media Freedom.  Both were pledges made at the Summit for Democracy.</p>
<p>Meetings like these are not only valuable for sharing our individual efforts, they offer a chance to team up across borders and across sectors.  In Tallinn, for example, the U.S. delegation that Uzra led encouraged others to join us in launching a new journalism protection platform to help reporters in hostile press environments.  We’ve got tools like legal aid, training on digital and physical security, very practical things that we hope will actually advance the safety and security of journalists, and protect them when they’re under threat.</p>
<p>This assistance is obviously more important than ever.  We’ve seen repressive laws multiply, threats and attacks on journalists increase across the globe.  And we all are joined by the shared conviction that a free media is indispensable to keeping people informed, to holding governments accountable, to shining a spotlight on issues that otherwise wouldn’t get a lot of public attention.  These are all core elements of a healthy democracy.  That’s why we’ve made supporting independent, free public media one of our priorities for this year.</p>
<p>Next week we’re also going to release the U.S. Government’s plan of action for making meaningful progress on our commitments and helping other governments meet theirs.  These goals are mutually reinforcing because if we’re going to address many of the challenges that democracies face, from inequity to corruption to efforts by authoritarian governments to sow distrust in free and open societies, we’ve got to have strong democratic partners by our side.  We are absolutely convinced, as we approach virtually everything we’re doing around the world, that we’re stronger and more effective when we’re partnering with others than when we’re doing things alone.</p>
<p>We need civil society engaged in every part of the action plan.  It’s as simple as that.  But if I could, let me just highlight three parts of the plan where I think your leadership is especially important.</p>
<p>First, on your recommendation and as Uzra mentioned, we will create a series of groups that we’re calling democracy cohorts which will bring together representatives of government, civil society, philanthropy, and the private sector around priority themes.  The cohorts will work to implement and expand on key commitments related to their theme as well as monitor progress, which is so critical.  They’ll forge new connections among those working on the issue.  The aim is for each cohort to be co-led by summit partners in government and civil society, and we really hope your institutions will consider playing a leading role.</p>
<p>To give just one example, given the President’s strong commitment to fighting corruption, which was one of the key pillars of the summit, the United States will co-lead a cohort focused on curbing the flow of illicit money.  The group will focus on issues like improving information gathering and sharing, strengthening prevention measures like enhancing transparency in real estate transactions, and broadening tools for recovering stolen assets.</p>
<p>Second, we will also restart our regular consultations with civil society on a range of key summit topics.  These consultations will complement the work of the cohorts by allowing us to hear from a broader cross-section of nongovernmental organizations on a wide range of issues, and what we learn will in turn help inform the broader process to shape summit number two.</p>
<p>Third, I’ve instructed our embassies in every one of the countries that participated in the summit to make it a part of their job to help drive progress on the commitments that were made.  What that means is that our posts will regularly engage with civil society organizations in country to get their take on where governments are moving forward, where they’re falling back or falling short, as well as what the United States can do to help.  And it means that our diplomats at every level, on every relevant issue, will regularly raise summit pledges with their counterparts and encourage them to work with partners outside of government to deliver on those commitments.</p>
<p>So all three of these efforts are intended to be responsive to something that we heard from you, which is that more regular, inclusive consultation with civil society is essential.  So I want you to know that we’re listening and we’re acting on what we’re hearing.</p>
<p>In closing, let me again simply say thank you.  We talk a lot about what makes democracy unique, why it’s worth fighting for, and a big part of that is that democracy is the only system that actually empowers people to improve on what we have, to fix our flaws, to make things better, a little bit more just, a little bit more equitable.  The organizations and institutions that you’re leading, you are the primary drivers of that enduring process of self-government.  So, on behalf of all of us, everyone involved in this effort, thank you, thank you, thank you for your hard work.  Thank you for your service.  Thank you for being champions of democracy at a time when democracy really needs those champions.</p>
<p>Let me stop there and see if we have any time for starting questions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>UNDER SECRETARY ZEYA:</b>  Good morning and welcome, everyone.  It’s great to see you all again, and I hope your 2022 is off to a healthy and strong start.  For my part, I want to start with a thank you.</p>
<p>As some of our most valued thinkers and doers, we greatly appreciate your time and commitment and the ideas and feedback that we used from you to strengthen the summit agenda.  We incorporated many of your recommendations, and we hope you saw those reflected in our December event.  Some of what the Secretary will lay out today for the Year of Action may also sound familiar; the concept of establishing democracy cohorts, for example, comes directly from all of you.</p>
<p>I’m excited to use this call today to pick up our conversation from last year.  As we move into the Year of Action, we look forward to regular consultations with civil society.  This isn’t a one-way conversation, either.  We plan to both listen and share, and work in partnership with civil society to achieve our shared summit goals this year.  The main goal in the Year of Action is to sustain the summit’s momentum and land concrete results that shore up democracies around the world, including our own; push back against the raw deal of authoritarianism; defend and promote respect for human rights; and combat corruption.  And at a time when all indicators flag continued democratic backsliding, we cannot achieve our summit goals without a meaningful partnership with civil society.  So, I thank you all for your leadership.</p>
<p>Today we’re honored to be joined by Secretary Blinken, and thank you for being with us today.  I’m also delighted to welcome Erin Barclay, our coordinator for global democratic renewal, who will moderate today’s Q&amp;A.  And as the Secretary, given the pace of world events, has been called away to a meeting at the White House, his time with us is a bit compressed.  I want to hand the floor to him, and thank you, sir, for your leadership.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Uzra, thank you so much.  Erin, thank you as well.  And it’s great to see everyone on the screen.</p>
<p>Yes.  I was looking forward to actually spending a bit of time this morning.  Unfortunately, a larger force, as in the President, has called me over to a meeting, so I want to at least spend the top of this meeting with you.  And I’m going to make sure that I hear from both Uzra and Erin exactly what was said during the meeting so that I can factor that in.  But let me just say a few words, if I can, at the outset and see if we have any time for questions before I get pulled over down the street.</p>
<p>First and foremost, thank you for being here today.  But thank you even more for being partners in this effort, the Democracy Summit, everything that is following from it in this Year of Action, and of course for, irrespective of that, the vital work that each and every one of you is doing every single day to advance democracy and human rights.  We really did want to spend some time, again, hearing from you as we continue to inform our own efforts, we continue to carry forward what was started with the Democracy Summit.  You know that the basic aim of the summit was to start to rally countries to try to make concrete commitments to strengthen their own democracies and to help other democracies deliver for the people that they’re supposed to serve.  And then, having made those commitments, we are now in what we’ve been calling a Year of Action, where we try to turn commitments into real change.  And that’s what this year is all about.</p>
<p>And the “we” includes all of us with a stake in advancing democracy and human rights, not only governments but the private sector, individual citizens, and, of course, civil society organizations.  Earlier this week we posted online the voluntary commitments that countries made at the summit.  For example, Paraguay will create an interagency task force to fight money laundering; Micronesia will put forward an access to information law; Luxembourg will create a senior-level post for advancing racial equity and diversity, to name just a few of the pledges.  Putting the commitments out there for all to see is a key part of holding governments, including our own, accountable.  And I have no doubt that you will all help do that.</p>
<p>Many countries are starting to follow through on commitments.  As we meet here today, Ghana and Norway are co-chairing the Global Disability Summit.  Just last week the Estonians convened the Global Conference on Media Freedom.  Both were pledges made at the Summit for Democracy.</p>
<p>Meetings like these are not only valuable for sharing our individual efforts, they offer a chance to team up across borders and across sectors.  In Tallinn, for example, the U.S. delegation that Uzra led encouraged others to join us in launching a new journalism protection platform to help reporters in hostile press environments.  We’ve got tools like legal aid, training on digital and physical security, very practical things that we hope will actually advance the safety and security of journalists, and protect them when they’re under threat.</p>
<p>This assistance is obviously more important than ever.  We’ve seen repressive laws multiply, threats and attacks on journalists increase across the globe.  And we all are joined by the shared conviction that a free media is indispensable to keeping people informed, to holding governments accountable, to shining a spotlight on issues that otherwise wouldn’t get a lot of public attention.  These are all core elements of a healthy democracy.  That’s why we’ve made supporting independent, free public media one of our priorities for this year.</p>
<p>Next week we’re also going to release the U.S. Government’s plan of action for making meaningful progress on our commitments and helping other governments meet theirs.  These goals are mutually reinforcing because if we’re going to address many of the challenges that democracies face, from inequity to corruption to efforts by authoritarian governments to sow distrust in free and open societies, we’ve got to have strong democratic partners by our side.  We are absolutely convinced, as we approach virtually everything we’re doing around the world, that we’re stronger and more effective when we’re partnering with others than when we’re doing things alone.</p>
<p>We need civil society engaged in every part of the action plan.  It’s as simple as that.  But if I could, let me just highlight three parts of the plan where I think your leadership is especially important.</p>
<p>First, on your recommendation and as Uzra mentioned, we will create a series of groups that we’re calling democracy cohorts which will bring together representatives of government, civil society, philanthropy, and the private sector around priority themes.  The cohorts will work to implement and expand on key commitments related to their theme as well as monitor progress, which is so critical.  They’ll forge new connections among those working on the issue.  The aim is for each cohort to be co-led by summit partners in government and civil society, and we really hope your institutions will consider playing a leading role.</p>
<p>To give just one example, given the President’s strong commitment to fighting corruption, which was one of the key pillars of the summit, the United States will co-lead a cohort focused on curbing the flow of illicit money.  The group will focus on issues like improving information gathering and sharing, strengthening prevention measures like enhancing transparency in real estate transactions, and broadening tools for recovering stolen assets.</p>
<p>Second, we will also restart our regular consultations with civil society on a range of key summit topics.  These consultations will complement the work of the cohorts by allowing us to hear from a broader cross-section of nongovernmental organizations on a wide range of issues, and what we learn will in turn help inform the broader process to shape summit number two.</p>
<p>Third, I’ve instructed our embassies in every one of the countries that participated in the summit to make it a part of their job to help drive progress on the commitments that were made.  What that means is that our posts will regularly engage with civil society organizations in country to get their take on where governments are moving forward, where they’re falling back or falling short, as well as what the United States can do to help.  And it means that our diplomats at every level, on every relevant issue, will regularly raise summit pledges with their counterparts and encourage them to work with partners outside of government to deliver on those commitments.</p>
<p>So all three of these efforts are intended to be responsive to something that we heard from you, which is that more regular, inclusive consultation with civil society is essential.  So I want you to know that we’re listening and we’re acting on what we’re hearing.</p>
<p>In closing, let me again simply say thank you.  We talk a lot about what makes democracy unique, why it’s worth fighting for, and a big part of that is that democracy is the only system that actually empowers people to improve on what we have, to fix our flaws, to make things better, a little bit more just, a little bit more equitable.  The organizations and institutions that you’re leading, you are the primary drivers of that enduring process of self-government.  So, on behalf of all of us, everyone involved in this effort, thank you, thank you, thank you for your hard work.  Thank you for your service.  Thank you for being champions of democracy at a time when democracy really needs those champions.</p>
<p>Let me stop there and see if we have any time for starting questions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with Joe Scarborough, Mika Brzezinski, and Willie Geist of Morning Joe, MSNBC</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-joe-scarborough-mika-brzezinski-and-willie-geist-of-morning-joe-msnbc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 16:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=314921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Joining us now, U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken.  Mr. Secretary, thank you for being on with us this morning.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good morning, Mika.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Russia suggested yesterday it was pulling back its forces.  What does U.S. intel say about this?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, there’s what Russia says and then there’s what Russia does, and we haven’t seen any pullback of its forces.  They remain massed in a very threatening way along Ukraine’s borders.  It would be good if they followed through on what they said, but so far, we haven’t seen it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Jonathan Lemire.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary of State, good to see you.  In fact, on that, the NATO secretary general, as you may know, just in a short time ago, said he – NATO has seen no evidence of any sort of pullback, and in fact, has seen further escalation, more troop buildup in the region.  What more can you tell us about that, and what would you need to see from Moscow to have any suggestion there that Vladimir Putin is actually going to de-escalate?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, Jonathan, that’s exactly right.  I saw what NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg said, and we continue to see not only these forces mass – we continue to see critical units moving toward the border, not away from the border.  So what we need to see is exactly the opposite.  We need to see these forces moving away.  We’ve heard what the Kremlin said about this.  As President Biden said yesterday, we’d welcome that, but we haven’t seen it on the ground.</p>
<p>And the bottom line is this:  We’re prepared either way.  We’re prepared to engage in diplomacy with Russia if it’s serious about it.  We’re also prepared for renewed Russian aggression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mike Barnicle.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, back to basics here.  What would be the upside for Putin by invading the Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Mike, that’s a great question because what we’ve seen from President Putin is basically to precipitate everything he says he wants to prevent.  He says he wants NATO further away from Russia.  NATO has only gotten more united, more solidified as a result of the threat of Russian aggression, and of course, for defensive reasons, is moving more forces closer to Russia.  And so we’ve seen that.</p>
<p>We’ve seen Russia’s actions alienate more and more of the Ukrainian people from Russia.  That’s exactly what Putin says he doesn’t want.  So it’s an excellent question, one best asked of him, because what he’s doing and what he’s threatening actually counters and undermines Russia’s stated interests.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, we’ve been talking about how actually this crisis has brought NATO Allies closer together than they’ve been for quite some time.  Can you highlight some of the things that our NATO Allies have done?  Because we actually have a constructive relationship with them and some – where some troops, where some weapons have been sent to counter this threat?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, Joe, it’s – it really goes back to something that President Biden has been doing from day one, and that is working to revitalize, re-energize our alliances and partnerships, because we know virtually every problem we have to confront, we’re going to be stronger and more effective if we’re doing it in unison with other countries than if we’re doing it alone.</p>
<p>So we invested a lot in that over the last year and it’s paying off now, just in this case alone with Ukraine and Russia’s threats.  There have been more than 200 engagements, meetings, phone calls, video conferences with NATO, with the European Union, with the OSCE, with allies and partners throughout Europe, even beyond.  And as a result, they’re all stepping up.  We have allies who are ready to join in imposing massive consequences on Russia if it renews its aggression.  Various partners have helped bolster Ukraine’s defenses.  Other partners have stood up for Ukraine’s economy and bolstered that.</p>
<p>And so we’re seeing countries step up in different ways, but all to the end of supporting Ukraine, standing up for the principles that are at stake here as a result of Russia’s threats, and doing it in unison, in coordination with us.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Well, we saw the Germans foot – dragging their feet a little bit at the beginning of this crisis, but yesterday the German chancellor in Russia seemed to be delivering a unified message, again, with the rest of NATO.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  That’s right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And a unified NATO is certainly a frightening specter for Vladimir Putin because he’s been used to being able to work one member off the other.  I’m curious what your assessment is of the Germans.  Are they doing everything that they can do right now to be good NATO partners?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Joe, keep this in mind:  Other than us, Germany is the number-one supporter of Ukraine economically.  They’ve provided more assistance to Ukraine than any other country in Europe.  That’s very meaningful.  At a time when all of these tensions are sort of talking down Ukraine’s economy, Germany’s assistance makes a big difference.</p>
<p>So different countries are doing different things in different ways, but all toward the same end: supporting Ukraine, supporting the principles that are being threatened by Russia, supporting us in trying to engage in diplomacy, but also being ready if Russia chooses aggression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Now we had Richard Haass on earlier this morning talking about the fact, even if there’s not an invasion, we may have cyber attacks, may have other sort of attacks.  I’m curious, are we ready, are we ready to go?  Are we prepared for those attacks and countering those attacks, and have we let the Russians know that those attacks too will lead to a dead end for them?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yes.  I was with President Biden in Geneva some months ago when he met with President Putin, and that was the time, you’ll remember, when there were these ransomware attacks directed against us, the Colonial Pipeline and other things.  And they were talking about that and President Biden said to President Putin, you understand how important this is to us, and I can only imagine sitting where you are with all of that energy infrastructure if someone engaged in a ransomware or a cyber attack against you; you wouldn’t like it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, we were – Mr. Secretary, we were saying earlier, it was like, nice gas field you have there; shame if anything would happen to it.</p>
<p>I wanted to ask you about the other actor in this scenario, though, and that’s President Zelenskyy in Ukraine.  And there’s some mixed messaging from him at this point.  We know he’s trying to – he’s been trying to downplay the threat to the Ukrainian people, which has been a marked difference from what we’re hearing from you and the West.  Give us the state of that relationship.  How often are you talking to him?  What is he saying to you about the threat he sees?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’re in constant contact with our Ukrainian counterparts, including President Zelenskyy, including my counterpart, the Foreign Minister Kuleba, and others.  And look, of course, President Zelenskyy understandably doesn’t want his people to panic.  He’s trying to keep things calm.  I understand that.  But they’re taking this dead seriously and so are we.  We’ve provided to Ukraine over the last year more security assistance than in any previous year.  Just the other day, we provided a billion-dollar sovereign loan guarantee that helped bolster their economy.  So we’re doing this in lockstep with them and we want to make sure that we’re there for them, others are there for them in this hour of need.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, I downloaded some of your songs in the past.  I must say when I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  When I’m driving in my car and Apple would just pop up – a song would just pop up as a suggestion, and for some reason you come up more than the Beatles or the Rolling Stones or anybody else.  And I was thinking about this the other day.  When you put out a playlist and there were some people on the – let’s just say the Trump right, they were so outraged as if you couldn’t, like, listen to music, have a life, and manage the State Department.  You seem to be doing so very effectively.  But thank you for putting out the playlist.  We’re getting good music selections and somehow we’re managing to survive as a republic at the same time.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Joe, right back at you.  I’ve got a lot of your songs downloaded over the years.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Of course he does.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  There it is.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  There you go.  Blinken listens.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I love the intros and outros for every segment, listen carefully every morning to figure out what you’re going to play.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  And yeah, you’ve got to have a little music in your life.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Got to have a little music in life.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I love that.  U.S. Secretary of State &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You know why he plays my music?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Why?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  In case &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Because it’s good.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  It’s like he &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I love your music.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  It makes you mentally tough.  If you can get through that, you can get through any crisis staring you in the face.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Okay.  Antony Blinken, thank you very much.  (Inaudible) following this.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary, (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  We appreciate it.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Joining us now, U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken.  Mr. Secretary, thank you for being on with us this morning.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good morning, Mika.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Russia suggested yesterday it was pulling back its forces.  What does U.S. intel say about this?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, there’s what Russia says and then there’s what Russia does, and we haven’t seen any pullback of its forces.  They remain massed in a very threatening way along Ukraine’s borders.  It would be good if they followed through on what they said, but so far, we haven’t seen it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Jonathan Lemire.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary of State, good to see you.  In fact, on that, the NATO secretary general, as you may know, just in a short time ago, said he – NATO has seen no evidence of any sort of pullback, and in fact, has seen further escalation, more troop buildup in the region.  What more can you tell us about that, and what would you need to see from Moscow to have any suggestion there that Vladimir Putin is actually going to de-escalate?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, Jonathan, that’s exactly right.  I saw what NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg said, and we continue to see not only these forces mass – we continue to see critical units moving toward the border, not away from the border.  So what we need to see is exactly the opposite.  We need to see these forces moving away.  We’ve heard what the Kremlin said about this.  As President Biden said yesterday, we’d welcome that, but we haven’t seen it on the ground.</p>
<p>And the bottom line is this:  We’re prepared either way.  We’re prepared to engage in diplomacy with Russia if it’s serious about it.  We’re also prepared for renewed Russian aggression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mike Barnicle.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, back to basics here.  What would be the upside for Putin by invading the Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Mike, that’s a great question because what we’ve seen from President Putin is basically to precipitate everything he says he wants to prevent.  He says he wants NATO further away from Russia.  NATO has only gotten more united, more solidified as a result of the threat of Russian aggression, and of course, for defensive reasons, is moving more forces closer to Russia.  And so we’ve seen that.</p>
<p>We’ve seen Russia’s actions alienate more and more of the Ukrainian people from Russia.  That’s exactly what Putin says he doesn’t want.  So it’s an excellent question, one best asked of him, because what he’s doing and what he’s threatening actually counters and undermines Russia’s stated interests.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, we’ve been talking about how actually this crisis has brought NATO Allies closer together than they’ve been for quite some time.  Can you highlight some of the things that our NATO Allies have done?  Because we actually have a constructive relationship with them and some – where some troops, where some weapons have been sent to counter this threat?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, Joe, it’s – it really goes back to something that President Biden has been doing from day one, and that is working to revitalize, re-energize our alliances and partnerships, because we know virtually every problem we have to confront, we’re going to be stronger and more effective if we’re doing it in unison with other countries than if we’re doing it alone.</p>
<p>So we invested a lot in that over the last year and it’s paying off now, just in this case alone with Ukraine and Russia’s threats.  There have been more than 200 engagements, meetings, phone calls, video conferences with NATO, with the European Union, with the OSCE, with allies and partners throughout Europe, even beyond.  And as a result, they’re all stepping up.  We have allies who are ready to join in imposing massive consequences on Russia if it renews its aggression.  Various partners have helped bolster Ukraine’s defenses.  Other partners have stood up for Ukraine’s economy and bolstered that.</p>
<p>And so we’re seeing countries step up in different ways, but all to the end of supporting Ukraine, standing up for the principles that are at stake here as a result of Russia’s threats, and doing it in unison, in coordination with us.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Well, we saw the Germans foot – dragging their feet a little bit at the beginning of this crisis, but yesterday the German chancellor in Russia seemed to be delivering a unified message, again, with the rest of NATO.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  That’s right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And a unified NATO is certainly a frightening specter for Vladimir Putin because he’s been used to being able to work one member off the other.  I’m curious what your assessment is of the Germans.  Are they doing everything that they can do right now to be good NATO partners?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Joe, keep this in mind:  Other than us, Germany is the number-one supporter of Ukraine economically.  They’ve provided more assistance to Ukraine than any other country in Europe.  That’s very meaningful.  At a time when all of these tensions are sort of talking down Ukraine’s economy, Germany’s assistance makes a big difference.</p>
<p>So different countries are doing different things in different ways, but all toward the same end: supporting Ukraine, supporting the principles that are being threatened by Russia, supporting us in trying to engage in diplomacy, but also being ready if Russia chooses aggression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Now we had Richard Haass on earlier this morning talking about the fact, even if there’s not an invasion, we may have cyber attacks, may have other sort of attacks.  I’m curious, are we ready, are we ready to go?  Are we prepared for those attacks and countering those attacks, and have we let the Russians know that those attacks too will lead to a dead end for them?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yes.  I was with President Biden in Geneva some months ago when he met with President Putin, and that was the time, you’ll remember, when there were these ransomware attacks directed against us, the Colonial Pipeline and other things.  And they were talking about that and President Biden said to President Putin, you understand how important this is to us, and I can only imagine sitting where you are with all of that energy infrastructure if someone engaged in a ransomware or a cyber attack against you; you wouldn’t like it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, we were – Mr. Secretary, we were saying earlier, it was like, nice gas field you have there; shame if anything would happen to it.</p>
<p>I wanted to ask you about the other actor in this scenario, though, and that’s President Zelenskyy in Ukraine.  And there’s some mixed messaging from him at this point.  We know he’s trying to – he’s been trying to downplay the threat to the Ukrainian people, which has been a marked difference from what we’re hearing from you and the West.  Give us the state of that relationship.  How often are you talking to him?  What is he saying to you about the threat he sees?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’re in constant contact with our Ukrainian counterparts, including President Zelenskyy, including my counterpart, the Foreign Minister Kuleba, and others.  And look, of course, President Zelenskyy understandably doesn’t want his people to panic.  He’s trying to keep things calm.  I understand that.  But they’re taking this dead seriously and so are we.  We’ve provided to Ukraine over the last year more security assistance than in any previous year.  Just the other day, we provided a billion-dollar sovereign loan guarantee that helped bolster their economy.  So we’re doing this in lockstep with them and we want to make sure that we’re there for them, others are there for them in this hour of need.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, I downloaded some of your songs in the past.  I must say when I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  When I’m driving in my car and Apple would just pop up – a song would just pop up as a suggestion, and for some reason you come up more than the Beatles or the Rolling Stones or anybody else.  And I was thinking about this the other day.  When you put out a playlist and there were some people on the – let’s just say the Trump right, they were so outraged as if you couldn’t, like, listen to music, have a life, and manage the State Department.  You seem to be doing so very effectively.  But thank you for putting out the playlist.  We’re getting good music selections and somehow we’re managing to survive as a republic at the same time.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Joe, right back at you.  I’ve got a lot of your songs downloaded over the years.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Of course he does.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  There it is.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  There you go.  Blinken listens.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I love the intros and outros for every segment, listen carefully every morning to figure out what you’re going to play.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  And yeah, you’ve got to have a little music in your life.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Got to have a little music in life.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I love that.  U.S. Secretary of State &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You know why he plays my music?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Why?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  In case &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Because it’s good.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  It’s like he &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I love your music.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  It makes you mentally tough.  If you can get through that, you can get through any crisis staring you in the face.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Okay.  Antony Blinken, thank you very much.  (Inaudible) following this.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary, (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  We appreciate it.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with George Stephanopoulos of ABC’s Good Morning America</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-george-stephanopoulos-of-abcs-good-morning-america-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 15:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=314894</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>And we are joined now by Secretary of State Antony Blinken for the latest on the crisis with Russia over Ukraine.  Mr. Secretary, thank you for joining us again this morning.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Good morning, George.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>The Russians said again this morning that they’re continuing to pull back troops from the border.  Yesterday the President said he was skeptical about that.  Are you seeing any evidence that this is being done in a real and significant way?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>We’re not, and unfortunately there’s a difference between what Russia says and what it does, and what we’re seeing is no meaningful pullback.  On the contrary, we continue to see forces, especially forces that would be in the vanguard of any renewed aggression against Ukraine, continuing to be at the border, to mass at the border.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>We’re also – heard from the Kremlin spokesman this morning, Dmitry Peskov, saying that there still is a possibility that diplomacy can work, but that Russia is getting pretty tired of these threats and warnings from the President.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, the threats are coming in the other direction.  They’re coming from Russia – unprovoked, massing forces on Ukraine’s borders – but there always has to be an opening for diplomacy.  And in fact, that’s my job.  So we’ll pursue that.  And as the President said yesterday, we’re prepared either way.  We’re prepared if Russia is ready to actually engage in meaningful diplomacy that would strengthen everyone’s security in Europe.  We’re also prepared if they choose to renew aggression against Ukraine.  The choice is really President Putin’s.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Your intelligence has suggested that the invasion could actually come today. Does that still feel possible?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>We said that we were in a window of time at which the invasion could come at any time.  President Putin’s put in place the capacity to act on very short notice.  He can pull the trigger.  He could pull it today, he could pull it tomorrow, he could pull it next week.  The forces are there if he wants to renew aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>What’s the basis for a diplomatic solution right now?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Look, George, we shared ideas with Russia several weeks ago about ways on a reciprocal basis, with each side taking steps, we could actually improve security throughout Europe.  We did that in close coordination with our European partners and allies.  We’re waiting for a response from Russia.  I spoke to Foreign Minister Lavrov yesterday.  He said a response is forthcoming in the next few days.  I hope it comes.  We’ll take a hard look at it and then we’ll see where we go from there.  But we remain committed to seeing if we can find a diplomatic resolution.  It’s the right thing to do.  It’s the responsible thing to do.  It would avert a war.  But again, it really is President Putin’s choice to make, and what we’re seeing on the border remains deeply, deeply concerning.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>It appears from some of the comments from American officials over the last several days that you’re concerned that President Zelenskyy of the Ukraine is not taking this threat seriously enough.  Is that true?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Oh no, I think President Zelenskyy’s taking it very seriously.  He’s trying to maintain calm.  He doesn’t want his people to panic.  That’s the right thing to do.  But I think the Ukrainians are taking it very seriously.  And of course, if there is renewed aggression by Russia, the consequences would be terrible, and first and foremost terrible for the Ukrainian people.  So he recognizes that.  We have been supporting Ukraine.  We’ve provided more defensive assistance to Ukraine last year than we did in any previous year. Just the other day we put out a $1 billion loan guarantee to help bolster their economy.  Other countries are doing the same.  We’re there to support Ukraine.  We’re there to help it defend itself if there’s Russian aggression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>But the President ruled out American troops.  Can the Ukrainians handle the Russians on their own?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>The Ukrainians have real capacity aided by many countries, including the United States.  I think they’d make life very difficult for the Russians if they went in, but again, the – by far the more responsible course is to avoid conflict in the first place, which is why we’re continuing to do everything we can to see if there’s a diplomatic resolution, at the same time making it very clear to Russia that it will face massive consequences for renewed aggression, not only in terms of continued support for Ukraine’s defense, not only in terms of bolstering NATO itself – which is exactly what President Putin says he wants to prevent – but also in terms of very serious economic and financial sanctions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>But the president of Ukraine also said that perhaps this idea of joining NATO is something – he called it a dream, I think was the word that he used.  Maybe that’s the likely outcome of this, that it’s something for the far, far, far distant future.  Is that accurate?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, the main point is that that should be up to the people of Ukraine and its elected government.  If they want to seek to join NATO, again, NATO has an “Open Door” policy.  It’s in its founding documents.  That principle is sacrosanct.  And so it really is up to them, and of course, it’s up to the Alliance itself in terms of admitting new members if they meet the requirements.  I think President Biden and others have said that’s not happening tomorrow, but the principle that if Ukraine seeks admission to NATO, it needs to be considered and the Alliance will make that decision – that remains front and center, and it’s not a principle we’re going back on.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Final quick question:  Is the threat today greater than it was yesterday?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>You know, from day to day, George, you can’t say it’s higher or lower.  It’s there.  It’s there; it’s real.  We haven’t seen a pullback.  We’d like to see one.  If we see one we would welcome it.  We’re prepared for diplomacy.  We’re prepared for aggression.  We’re prepared either way.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Mr. Secretary, thanks as always for your time and your information.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thanks, George.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>And we are joined now by Secretary of State Antony Blinken for the latest on the crisis with Russia over Ukraine.  Mr. Secretary, thank you for joining us again this morning.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Good morning, George.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>The Russians said again this morning that they’re continuing to pull back troops from the border.  Yesterday the President said he was skeptical about that.  Are you seeing any evidence that this is being done in a real and significant way?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>We’re not, and unfortunately there’s a difference between what Russia says and what it does, and what we’re seeing is no meaningful pullback.  On the contrary, we continue to see forces, especially forces that would be in the vanguard of any renewed aggression against Ukraine, continuing to be at the border, to mass at the border.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>We’re also – heard from the Kremlin spokesman this morning, Dmitry Peskov, saying that there still is a possibility that diplomacy can work, but that Russia is getting pretty tired of these threats and warnings from the President.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, the threats are coming in the other direction.  They’re coming from Russia – unprovoked, massing forces on Ukraine’s borders – but there always has to be an opening for diplomacy.  And in fact, that’s my job.  So we’ll pursue that.  And as the President said yesterday, we’re prepared either way.  We’re prepared if Russia is ready to actually engage in meaningful diplomacy that would strengthen everyone’s security in Europe.  We’re also prepared if they choose to renew aggression against Ukraine.  The choice is really President Putin’s.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Your intelligence has suggested that the invasion could actually come today. Does that still feel possible?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>We said that we were in a window of time at which the invasion could come at any time.  President Putin’s put in place the capacity to act on very short notice.  He can pull the trigger.  He could pull it today, he could pull it tomorrow, he could pull it next week.  The forces are there if he wants to renew aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>What’s the basis for a diplomatic solution right now?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Look, George, we shared ideas with Russia several weeks ago about ways on a reciprocal basis, with each side taking steps, we could actually improve security throughout Europe.  We did that in close coordination with our European partners and allies.  We’re waiting for a response from Russia.  I spoke to Foreign Minister Lavrov yesterday.  He said a response is forthcoming in the next few days.  I hope it comes.  We’ll take a hard look at it and then we’ll see where we go from there.  But we remain committed to seeing if we can find a diplomatic resolution.  It’s the right thing to do.  It’s the responsible thing to do.  It would avert a war.  But again, it really is President Putin’s choice to make, and what we’re seeing on the border remains deeply, deeply concerning.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>It appears from some of the comments from American officials over the last several days that you’re concerned that President Zelenskyy of the Ukraine is not taking this threat seriously enough.  Is that true?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Oh no, I think President Zelenskyy’s taking it very seriously.  He’s trying to maintain calm.  He doesn’t want his people to panic.  That’s the right thing to do.  But I think the Ukrainians are taking it very seriously.  And of course, if there is renewed aggression by Russia, the consequences would be terrible, and first and foremost terrible for the Ukrainian people.  So he recognizes that.  We have been supporting Ukraine.  We’ve provided more defensive assistance to Ukraine last year than we did in any previous year. Just the other day we put out a $1 billion loan guarantee to help bolster their economy.  Other countries are doing the same.  We’re there to support Ukraine.  We’re there to help it defend itself if there’s Russian aggression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>But the President ruled out American troops.  Can the Ukrainians handle the Russians on their own?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>The Ukrainians have real capacity aided by many countries, including the United States.  I think they’d make life very difficult for the Russians if they went in, but again, the – by far the more responsible course is to avoid conflict in the first place, which is why we’re continuing to do everything we can to see if there’s a diplomatic resolution, at the same time making it very clear to Russia that it will face massive consequences for renewed aggression, not only in terms of continued support for Ukraine’s defense, not only in terms of bolstering NATO itself – which is exactly what President Putin says he wants to prevent – but also in terms of very serious economic and financial sanctions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>But the president of Ukraine also said that perhaps this idea of joining NATO is something – he called it a dream, I think was the word that he used.  Maybe that’s the likely outcome of this, that it’s something for the far, far, far distant future.  Is that accurate?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, the main point is that that should be up to the people of Ukraine and its elected government.  If they want to seek to join NATO, again, NATO has an “Open Door” policy.  It’s in its founding documents.  That principle is sacrosanct.  And so it really is up to them, and of course, it’s up to the Alliance itself in terms of admitting new members if they meet the requirements.  I think President Biden and others have said that’s not happening tomorrow, but the principle that if Ukraine seeks admission to NATO, it needs to be considered and the Alliance will make that decision – that remains front and center, and it’s not a principle we’re going back on.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Final quick question:  Is the threat today greater than it was yesterday?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>You know, from day to day, George, you can’t say it’s higher or lower.  It’s there.  It’s there; it’s real.  We haven’t seen a pullback.  We’d like to see one.  If we see one we would welcome it.  We’re prepared for diplomacy.  We’re prepared for aggression.  We’re prepared either way.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Mr. Secretary, thanks as always for your time and your information.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thanks, George.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with Natalya Lutsenko of ICTV</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-natalya-lutsenko-of-ictv/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 13:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=314851</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  All reports in the American media that intelligence is public in – the exact date of the attack, which is convinced that Russia will attack Ukraine day by day.  Can we consider that as some specific actions as not giving Putin any room for a maneuver – for a maneuver?  Or is just – is it just a coincidence?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’ve done everything we can to share whatever information we receive, get access to, share it with – of course, with our Ukrainian partners as well as with other allies and partners, just to make sure that everyone is on notice about what could happen.  We have not seen a definitive decision by President Putin, but we do know that he’s put in place the capacity to act on very, very short notice.  And so as we’ve said, if he chooses the path of renewed aggression against Ukraine, it could happen at any time and it’s important that people understand that even as we work overtime through diplomacy to try to prevent Russia from renewing its aggression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  It just feels like with this revealing the information, you’re always leaving Putin behind because when you’re saying that the actions will be on the 15th of February, it feels like it’s not going to be like that because everybody knows that already.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, it’s important to, I think, again, put Russia on notice that we see what it’s planning and we see what it might do, and to share that information with our partners and to share it, as necessary, with the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  So today Russian Duma ask Putin to recognize Ukrainian occupied region or bloc as independent.  So Putin should – could decide, but he didn’t say anything directly, particularly.  Can he use this decision – his decision as a blackmail, perhaps?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, this effort is totally inconsistent with the Minsk Agreements.  It’s in contradiction of the Minsk Agreements.  And so if Russia is serious about implementing Minsk, it has to reject this effort, and it’s certainly something that we don’t recognize and don’t accept.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Is there any cautious optimism that Russia said again it’s ready for dialogue?  Today I’ve heard that thought in – from Stoltenberg.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  It’s not a question, for me at least, of being optimistic or pessimistic.  It’s a question of focusing on the facts, on what we see, and on what Russia is doing.  Yes, it said some more positive things about diplomacy in recent days, but I think your foreign minister, Foreign Minister Kuleba, had it exactly right when he said we should be less focused on what Russia says and more focused on what it does.  We have yet to see any removal of forces surrounding Ukraine, any pullback, any end to the so-called exercises that Russia has claimed it’s engaged in.  That’s what we’re focused on.  And if we see that, that would be positive, and I think that would create a better environment, a better atmosphere for pursuing diplomacy.</p>
<p>But we’re prepared either way.  If Russia chooses the path of diplomacy, we’re fully prepared to engage.  At the same time, if they choose the path of aggression, we’re prepared to respond to that too.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Am I correct the United States intelligence don’t see any withdrawal from Ukrainian border?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  That’s correct.  We have yet to see any pullback, any withdrawal of Russian forces from around Ukraine’s borders.  We’re watching that very carefully, and again, it’s very important to look at what Russia actually does, not what it says it’s doing.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>And the last question that I couldn’t ask you that – could not now ask you about the American embassy in Ukraine.  Don’t you think there is a chance that by abandoning the embassy it might send a signal that Russia can now start their attack?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’ve been very clear that if Russia engages in renewed aggression against Ukraine, there will be massive consequences, and that’s come from not just us, but from virtually all of our partners in the – in Europe, NATO, the European Union, the G7, the world’s largest democratic economies.  So that’s been very clear.  I think President Putin knows that if he makes the terrible mistake of renewing aggression, that’s what he’ll face.  And at the same time, we are – we continue to work to support Ukraine’s defenses.  We’ve provided over the last year well more than $600 million in 2021, more than at any previous year.  But we also want to make sure that we’re supporting your economy.  Just yesterday we announced a sovereign loan guarantee of a billion dollars in support of the economy.</p>
<p>When it comes to the embassy, look, I have a unique responsibility as Secretary of State, which is to look out for the safety and well-being of the people who work for me, and that’s really unique to me.  So we did make the decision to temporarily relocate our diplomatic functions from Kyiv to Lviv out of an abundance of precaution.  It’s the prudent thing to do because, again, my personal responsibility is to the safety and security of our people.  But they continue to work directly with their counterparts in the Ukrainian Government.  They continue to support the very – the different programs we have in support of Ukraine.  And of course, I’m on the phone almost every day with Dmytro Kuleba; others are on the phone with President Zelenskyy and other senior officials.</p>
<p>And so our support, our engagement, our work with the Ukrainian Government remains very, very strong.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Is there any expiry date for that removal – removing the embassy?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’ll be focused on the facts.  We’ll be focused on what we see.  And again, unfortunately, we haven’t seen any pullback of Russian forces, but if it’s clear that Russia is truly engaged on a diplomatic path and the military threat goes away, of course, that changes the situation.  But that’s what we’re focused on.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you very much for your time.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Good to be with you.  Nice to see you again.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Nice to see you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Bye-bye.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  All reports in the American media that intelligence is public in – the exact date of the attack, which is convinced that Russia will attack Ukraine day by day.  Can we consider that as some specific actions as not giving Putin any room for a maneuver – for a maneuver?  Or is just – is it just a coincidence?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’ve done everything we can to share whatever information we receive, get access to, share it with – of course, with our Ukrainian partners as well as with other allies and partners, just to make sure that everyone is on notice about what could happen.  We have not seen a definitive decision by President Putin, but we do know that he’s put in place the capacity to act on very, very short notice.  And so as we’ve said, if he chooses the path of renewed aggression against Ukraine, it could happen at any time and it’s important that people understand that even as we work overtime through diplomacy to try to prevent Russia from renewing its aggression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  It just feels like with this revealing the information, you’re always leaving Putin behind because when you’re saying that the actions will be on the 15th of February, it feels like it’s not going to be like that because everybody knows that already.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, it’s important to, I think, again, put Russia on notice that we see what it’s planning and we see what it might do, and to share that information with our partners and to share it, as necessary, with the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  So today Russian Duma ask Putin to recognize Ukrainian occupied region or bloc as independent.  So Putin should – could decide, but he didn’t say anything directly, particularly.  Can he use this decision – his decision as a blackmail, perhaps?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, this effort is totally inconsistent with the Minsk Agreements.  It’s in contradiction of the Minsk Agreements.  And so if Russia is serious about implementing Minsk, it has to reject this effort, and it’s certainly something that we don’t recognize and don’t accept.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Is there any cautious optimism that Russia said again it’s ready for dialogue?  Today I’ve heard that thought in – from Stoltenberg.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  It’s not a question, for me at least, of being optimistic or pessimistic.  It’s a question of focusing on the facts, on what we see, and on what Russia is doing.  Yes, it said some more positive things about diplomacy in recent days, but I think your foreign minister, Foreign Minister Kuleba, had it exactly right when he said we should be less focused on what Russia says and more focused on what it does.  We have yet to see any removal of forces surrounding Ukraine, any pullback, any end to the so-called exercises that Russia has claimed it’s engaged in.  That’s what we’re focused on.  And if we see that, that would be positive, and I think that would create a better environment, a better atmosphere for pursuing diplomacy.</p>
<p>But we’re prepared either way.  If Russia chooses the path of diplomacy, we’re fully prepared to engage.  At the same time, if they choose the path of aggression, we’re prepared to respond to that too.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Am I correct the United States intelligence don’t see any withdrawal from Ukrainian border?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  That’s correct.  We have yet to see any pullback, any withdrawal of Russian forces from around Ukraine’s borders.  We’re watching that very carefully, and again, it’s very important to look at what Russia actually does, not what it says it’s doing.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>And the last question that I couldn’t ask you that – could not now ask you about the American embassy in Ukraine.  Don’t you think there is a chance that by abandoning the embassy it might send a signal that Russia can now start their attack?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’ve been very clear that if Russia engages in renewed aggression against Ukraine, there will be massive consequences, and that’s come from not just us, but from virtually all of our partners in the – in Europe, NATO, the European Union, the G7, the world’s largest democratic economies.  So that’s been very clear.  I think President Putin knows that if he makes the terrible mistake of renewing aggression, that’s what he’ll face.  And at the same time, we are – we continue to work to support Ukraine’s defenses.  We’ve provided over the last year well more than $600 million in 2021, more than at any previous year.  But we also want to make sure that we’re supporting your economy.  Just yesterday we announced a sovereign loan guarantee of a billion dollars in support of the economy.</p>
<p>When it comes to the embassy, look, I have a unique responsibility as Secretary of State, which is to look out for the safety and well-being of the people who work for me, and that’s really unique to me.  So we did make the decision to temporarily relocate our diplomatic functions from Kyiv to Lviv out of an abundance of precaution.  It’s the prudent thing to do because, again, my personal responsibility is to the safety and security of our people.  But they continue to work directly with their counterparts in the Ukrainian Government.  They continue to support the very – the different programs we have in support of Ukraine.  And of course, I’m on the phone almost every day with Dmytro Kuleba; others are on the phone with President Zelenskyy and other senior officials.</p>
<p>And so our support, our engagement, our work with the Ukrainian Government remains very, very strong.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Is there any expiry date for that removal – removing the embassy?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’ll be focused on the facts.  We’ll be focused on what we see.  And again, unfortunately, we haven’t seen any pullback of Russian forces, but if it’s clear that Russia is truly engaged on a diplomatic path and the military threat goes away, of course, that changes the situation.  But that’s what we’re focused on.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you very much for your time.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Good to be with you.  Nice to see you again.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Nice to see you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Bye-bye.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lithuania National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/lithuania-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 05:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=314630</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Lithuania as you celebrate your independence.</p>
<p>In the face of today’s global challenges, the United States stands firm in our close relationship with Lithuania, a strong NATO Ally and EU partner.  Together, we deter and defend against threats to our sovereignty and security, continue our robust cooperation in advancing human rights globally, and act resolutely in response to actions by those who seek to repress fundamental freedoms, undermine democracy, and engage in economic coercion.  We also stand together in defending our values and economies against attempts to undermine the international rules-based order.</p>
<p>In 2022, the United States proudly commemorates 100 years of uninterrupted diplomatic relations with Lithuania, a milestone that underscores our enduring friendship and vibrant people-to-people ties.  As we expand our partnership during the next century of our relationship, we look forward to deepening our collaboration to strengthen the Transatlantic ties that benefit our peoples.</p>
<p>I join you in celebrating this anniversary and send best wishes for health and prosperity to all Lithuanians.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Lithuania as you celebrate your independence.</p>
<p>In the face of today’s global challenges, the United States stands firm in our close relationship with Lithuania, a strong NATO Ally and EU partner.  Together, we deter and defend against threats to our sovereignty and security, continue our robust cooperation in advancing human rights globally, and act resolutely in response to actions by those who seek to repress fundamental freedoms, undermine democracy, and engage in economic coercion.  We also stand together in defending our values and economies against attempts to undermine the international rules-based order.</p>
<p>In 2022, the United States proudly commemorates 100 years of uninterrupted diplomatic relations with Lithuania, a milestone that underscores our enduring friendship and vibrant people-to-people ties.  As we expand our partnership during the next century of our relationship, we look forward to deepening our collaboration to strengthen the Transatlantic ties that benefit our peoples.</p>
<p>I join you in celebrating this anniversary and send best wishes for health and prosperity to all Lithuanians.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with Japanese Vice Foreign Minister Mori</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-japanese-vice-foreign-minister-mori/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[U.S. Department of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 02:54:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=314740</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Japanese Vice Foreign Minister Mori Takeo.  Deputy Secretary Sherman reiterated unwavering support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and discussed efforts, including the February 14 G7 Finance Ministers’ statement on readiness to move swiftly and decisively to support the Ukrainian economy, to deter Russia from further military action or other aggressive acts, while remaining committed to diplomacy.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Vice Foreign Minister Mori emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Japan Alliance to the security and prosperity of the Indo-Pacific region and the world.  The Deputy Secretary and Vice Foreign Minister discussed U.S.-Japan economic cooperation, including the new Economic Policy Consultative Committee announced by President Biden and Prime Minister Kishida on January 21.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Vice Foreign Minister Mori affirmed the importance of global cooperation to end the COVID-19 pandemic worldwide.  The two officials reaffirmed the importance of continued U.S.-Japan cooperation in making progress toward the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  The Deputy Secretary and Vice Foreign Minister discussed the destabilizing nature of the DPRK’s recent ballistic missile launches.  Deputy Secretary Sherman highlighted U.S. preparedness to meet the DPRK without preconditions and called for the DPRK to engage in serious and sustained diplomacy.  She also emphasized the importance of trilateral U.S.-Japan-ROK cooperation on the DPRK, as well as in addressing many shared priorities in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Japanese Vice Foreign Minister Mori Takeo.  Deputy Secretary Sherman reiterated unwavering support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and discussed efforts, including the February 14 G7 Finance Ministers’ statement on readiness to move swiftly and decisively to support the Ukrainian economy, to deter Russia from further military action or other aggressive acts, while remaining committed to diplomacy.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Vice Foreign Minister Mori emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Japan Alliance to the security and prosperity of the Indo-Pacific region and the world.  The Deputy Secretary and Vice Foreign Minister discussed U.S.-Japan economic cooperation, including the new Economic Policy Consultative Committee announced by President Biden and Prime Minister Kishida on January 21.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Vice Foreign Minister Mori affirmed the importance of global cooperation to end the COVID-19 pandemic worldwide.  The two officials reaffirmed the importance of continued U.S.-Japan cooperation in making progress toward the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  The Deputy Secretary and Vice Foreign Minister discussed the destabilizing nature of the DPRK’s recent ballistic missile launches.  Deputy Secretary Sherman highlighted U.S. preparedness to meet the DPRK without preconditions and called for the DPRK to engage in serious and sustained diplomacy.  She also emphasized the importance of trilateral U.S.-Japan-ROK cooperation on the DPRK, as well as in addressing many shared priorities in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with Canadian Deputy Foreign Minister Morgan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-canadian-deputy-foreign-minister-morgan-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 01:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=314704</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Canadian Deputy Foreign Minister Marta Morgan to follow up on previous conversations on Russia’s escalating aggression against Ukraine.  The Deputy Secretary and Deputy Foreign Minister discussed efforts to urge Russia to de-escalate and choose diplomacy.  They reiterated that further Russian escalation would be met with massive, coordinated consequences and severe costs for the Russian Federation.  Both expressed the United States’ and Canada’s resolute support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and commitment to strong transatlantic coordination.  The Deputy Secretary also thanked DFM Morgan for Canada’s actions over the weekend to resolve the situation at the Ambassador Bridge.  They discussed the importance of a quick and peaceful resolution to ensure the free flow of goods and legitimate travel across the border.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Canadian Deputy Foreign Minister Marta Morgan to follow up on previous conversations on Russia’s escalating aggression against Ukraine.  The Deputy Secretary and Deputy Foreign Minister discussed efforts to urge Russia to de-escalate and choose diplomacy.  They reiterated that further Russian escalation would be met with massive, coordinated consequences and severe costs for the Russian Federation.  Both expressed the United States’ and Canada’s resolute support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and commitment to strong transatlantic coordination.  The Deputy Secretary also thanked DFM Morgan for Canada’s actions over the weekend to resolve the situation at the Ambassador Bridge.  They discussed the importance of a quick and peaceful resolution to ensure the free flow of goods and legitimate travel across the border.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
