<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 21:47:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-nato-secretary-general-stoltenberg-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 21:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg in Brussels.  The leaders discussed efforts to provide security and other forms of assistance to our Ukrainian partners in response to the Russian Federation’s unprovoked war against Ukraine. They also noted preparations for the June 29-30 NATO Summit in Madrid and reaffirmed support for NATO’s Asia-Pacific partners, Australia, Japan, the Republic of Korea, and New Zealand, attending the Ministerial for the first time. Secretary Blinken reiterated U.S. support for the development of a new NATO Strategic Concept that addresses current and future threats to the international rules-based order.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg in Brussels.  The leaders discussed efforts to provide security and other forms of assistance to our Ukrainian partners in response to the Russian Federation’s unprovoked war against Ukraine. They also noted preparations for the June 29-30 NATO Summit in Madrid and reaffirmed support for NATO’s Asia-Pacific partners, Australia, Japan, the Republic of Korea, and New Zealand, attending the Ministerial for the first time. Secretary Blinken reiterated U.S. support for the development of a new NATO Strategic Concept that addresses current and future threats to the international rules-based order.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary Medina’s Travel to Honolulu, Hawaii</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-medinas-travel-to-honolulu-hawaii/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 21:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica P. Medina will travel to Honolulu, Hawaii, April 7-9 to meet with officials from United States Indo-Pacific Command and the United States Coast Guard to discuss their work combating illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing.  In addition, she will visit the Hawai‘i Institute for Marine Biology to learn more about its research on climate change and marine wildlife conservation and meet with Hawaiian community leaders and nongovernmental organizations working to preserve unique island ecosystems.</p>
<p align="left">Following these activities, Assistant Secretary Medina will continue her travels to the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference,</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> which the United States will co-host with Palau in Koror, April 13-14.</p>
<p align="left">For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov.</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica P. Medina will travel to Honolulu, Hawaii, April 7-9 to meet with officials from United States Indo-Pacific Command and the United States Coast Guard to discuss their work combating illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing.  In addition, she will visit the Hawai‘i Institute for Marine Biology to learn more about its research on climate change and marine wildlife conservation and meet with Hawaiian community leaders and nongovernmental organizations working to preserve unique island ecosystems.</p>
<p align="left">Following these activities, Assistant Secretary Medina will continue her travels to the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference,</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> which the United States will co-host with Palau in Koror, April 13-14.</p>
<p align="left">For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov.</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with French, German, Italian, and UK Counterparts</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-french-german-italian-and-uk-counterparts-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 21:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332290</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian, German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock, Italian Foreign Minister Luigi Di Maio, and UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss today in Brussels, where they reiterated their commitment to supporting Ukraine in the face of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.  The Secretary again strongly condemned the reported atrocities by President Putin’s forces in Bucha and across Ukraine and called for accountability. He and his counterparts discussed how best to continue working to isolate the Russian Federation on the international stage for its flagrant violation of international law and principles, to increase pressure on the Kremlin, and to advance a swift end its devastating war against Ukraine.  They also discussed plans to provide additional humanitarian and security assistance to Ukraine.</p>
<p>Prior to this meeting, Secretary Blinken met with his E3 counterparts to discuss our common resolve to ensure that Iran never acquires a nuclear weapon. They agreed that a diplomatic solution entailing a mutual return to full implementation of the JCPOA is the best outcome, but noted that we are prepared for other scenarios if necessary.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian, German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock, Italian Foreign Minister Luigi Di Maio, and UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss today in Brussels, where they reiterated their commitment to supporting Ukraine in the face of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.  The Secretary again strongly condemned the reported atrocities by President Putin’s forces in Bucha and across Ukraine and called for accountability. He and his counterparts discussed how best to continue working to isolate the Russian Federation on the international stage for its flagrant violation of international law and principles, to increase pressure on the Kremlin, and to advance a swift end its devastating war against Ukraine.  They also discussed plans to provide additional humanitarian and security assistance to Ukraine.</p>
<p>Prior to this meeting, Secretary Blinken met with his E3 counterparts to discuss our common resolve to ensure that Iran never acquires a nuclear weapon. They agreed that a diplomatic solution entailing a mutual return to full implementation of the JCPOA is the best outcome, but noted that we are prepared for other scenarios if necessary.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Targeting Additional Russian Financial Institutions, Officials, and Other Individuals</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/targeting-additional-russian-financial-institutions-officials-and-other-individuals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 19:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332151</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is united with our allies and partners to ensure the Government of Russia pays a severe price for causing such death and destruction in Ukraine, and particularly for the horrors in Bucha and elsewhere.  In furtherance of this goal, today we are implementing full blocking sanctions on two key Russian financial institutions: Sberbank, Russia’s largest financial institution, and its subsidiaries and Alfa Bank, one of the largest private banks in Russia, and its subsidiaries. These entities continue to sustain President Putin’s aggression against Ukraine.  Accordingly, all U.S. persons are generally prohibited from engaging in transactions with Sberbank or Alfa Bank.</p>
<p>In addition, we are imposing sanctions on the adult children of President Vladimir Putin, Katerina Tikhonova and Maria Vorontsova, as well as Maria Lavrova, the wife of Russia’s Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov, and Ekaterina Lavrova, his adult child.</p>
<p>The United States is also designating 21 members of Russia’s National Security Council, including former President Dmitry Medvedev and Prime Minister Mikhail Mishustin, for their role and authority in crafting the Kremlin’s brutal policies and resulting abuses.</p>
<p>And finally, President Biden’s Executive Order today bans new investment in Russia – forcing Russia further down the road of financial and economic isolation.</p>
<p>This announcement of new economic sanctions follows our approval last night of $100 million in new security assistance to help Ukraine meet a continued need for additional anti-armor systems.  This is only the most recent of six drawdowns of arms, equipment, and supplies from Department of Defense inventories for Ukraine since August 2021, and brings U.S. military assistance to almost $2.5 billion since September, and $4.5 billion since 2014.  The United States commends the continued support of our allies and partners across the world in the face of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.  We stand with Ukraine and recognize the bravery and heroism of its people and they defend their country and their freedom against Russia’s brutal war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>United with our Allies and partners, the United States will continue to impose economic costs on Russia for their actions through economic sanctions and provide security assistance in support of Ukraine’s defense, as well as economic support and humanitarian aid for communities across Ukraine devastated by Russia’s ruthless brutality.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0705" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is united with our allies and partners to ensure the Government of Russia pays a severe price for causing such death and destruction in Ukraine, and particularly for the horrors in Bucha and elsewhere.  In furtherance of this goal, today we are implementing full blocking sanctions on two key Russian financial institutions: Sberbank, Russia’s largest financial institution, and its subsidiaries and Alfa Bank, one of the largest private banks in Russia, and its subsidiaries. These entities continue to sustain President Putin’s aggression against Ukraine.  Accordingly, all U.S. persons are generally prohibited from engaging in transactions with Sberbank or Alfa Bank.</p>
<p>In addition, we are imposing sanctions on the adult children of President Vladimir Putin, Katerina Tikhonova and Maria Vorontsova, as well as Maria Lavrova, the wife of Russia’s Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov, and Ekaterina Lavrova, his adult child.</p>
<p>The United States is also designating 21 members of Russia’s National Security Council, including former President Dmitry Medvedev and Prime Minister Mikhail Mishustin, for their role and authority in crafting the Kremlin’s brutal policies and resulting abuses.</p>
<p>And finally, President Biden’s Executive Order today bans new investment in Russia – forcing Russia further down the road of financial and economic isolation.</p>
<p>This announcement of new economic sanctions follows our approval last night of $100 million in new security assistance to help Ukraine meet a continued need for additional anti-armor systems.  This is only the most recent of six drawdowns of arms, equipment, and supplies from Department of Defense inventories for Ukraine since August 2021, and brings U.S. military assistance to almost $2.5 billion since September, and $4.5 billion since 2014.  The United States commends the continued support of our allies and partners across the world in the face of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.  We stand with Ukraine and recognize the bravery and heroism of its people and they defend their country and their freedom against Russia’s brutal war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>United with our Allies and partners, the United States will continue to impose economic costs on Russia for their actions through economic sanctions and provide security assistance in support of Ukraine’s defense, as well as economic support and humanitarian aid for communities across Ukraine devastated by Russia’s ruthless brutality.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0705" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Briefing with Special Representative for the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea Sung Kim on Recent Developments in the DPRK and U.S. Efforts to Advance Denuclearization on the Korean Peninsula</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-with-special-representative-for-the-democratic-peoples-republic-of-korea-sung-kim-on-recent-developments-in-the-dprk-and-u-s-efforts-to-advance-denuclearization-on-the-korean-penins/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sung Kim, Acting Assistant Secretary  Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 18:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332131</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Sung Kim, Acting Assistant Secretary  Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:  </b>Good morning, everyone, and thank you so much for joining today’s press call. Special Representative for the DPRK Ambassador Sung Kim is visiting Washington this week for a series of engagements and is here to discuss U.S. policy toward the DPRK.  We’re very glad to have the special representative with us on the line today to tell you a little bit more about his visit.  Ambassador Kim will start with some opening remarks and then proceed with taking your questions.  I’d like to also take this opportunity to remind everyone that while this call is on the record, the contents of this briefing are embargoed until the end of the call.  And with that, I’ll hand it over to Special Representative Kim.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:  </b>Great, thank you very much, Jalina.  And thank – many thanks to all of you for joining us this morning.  Let me start by saying a few words on where we are and where we are heading in our work on the DPRK, and then I’d be happy to take your questions.</p>
<p>Since taking office, the Biden-Harris administration has made clear its priority to reduce the threat posed by the DPRK.  We are determined to protect the security of the United States, along with that of our allies and partners in the region and beyond.  We are of course closely following developments in the DPRK, and we maintain the ultimate goal of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>We know there are challenges, and these will not be easily resolved, but we remain fully committed to working closely with our allies and partners in a global effort to make progress toward this end goal.  Our efforts involve both diplomatic outreach and threat reduction.  And while it is clear the DPRK leadership is determined to advance its illegal weapons programs, we know that our efforts are constraining their progress.  At the same time, we have not closed the door on diplomacy.  We are committed to pursuing serious and sustained dialogue.  As we have said many times, we are prepared to meet the DPRK without preconditions.  But Pyongyang must make the choice to halt its destabilizing actions and instead choose engagement.</p>
<p>The U.S. Government at all levels has engaged vigorously on the DPRK with our allies and partners around the world.  The Secretary, Deputy Secretary Sherman, and I have consulted regularly with our counterparts in the ROK and Japan bilaterally as well as trilaterally.  We have repeatedly offered to meet the DPRK to discuss any and all issues, and yet the DPRK has declined our invitation to dialogue.  Instead, they have initiated a series of missile tests that recently culminated in at least three ICBM launches.  These actions pose a serious threat to regional stability.</p>
<p>The U.S. strongly condemns these tests, each of which was a blatant violation of multiple Security Council resolutions.  These launches demonstrate the DPRK continues to prioritize its weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs at the expense of regional and international security.  This prioritization is also at the expense of the North Korean people.  The government has chosen to deploy its limited resources to fund illegal weapons programs even as the humanitarian situation in the country has grown increasingly dire.</p>
<p>The potential range of these ICBMs should also remind us that the DPRK’s actions are a global security concern.  It is not merely about the United States and the DPRK.</p>
<p>In response to DPRK’s recent escalatory actions and as part of our effort to impede the DPRK’s ability to advance its missile program, we have taken a series of diplomatic, economic, and military measures.  As of March 25, we have raised the DPRK’s ballistic missile launches at the UN Security Council six times this year.  Russia and the PRC have consistently blocked our efforts to produce a UN public statement.  And in spite of this, we’ve worked with a growing group of like-minded countries to draw attention to the DPRK’s irresponsible behavior.</p>
<p>On March 7th, the U.S. Indo-Pacific Command, INDOPACOM, ordered intensified intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance collection activities in the Yellow Sea.  USINDOPACOM also enhanced readiness among our ballistic missile defense forces in the region to help ensure the security of our allies.</p>
<p>A week later, on March 15th, USINDOPACOM announced it had conducted a carrier-based air demonstration in the Yellow Sea as a demonstration of resolve and commitment to our regional allies.  The U.S. Department of Treasury and the Department of State have also announced several new actions to help prevent the DPRK from accessing foreign items and technology that enable it to advance its prohibited weapons programs.  We have placed sanctions on a number of individuals and entities as well.</p>
<p>We will also continue to work closely with our allies and partners to address the critical issue of the DPRK’s cyber program, which poses a sophisticated and agile espionage, cyber crime, and attack threat.  The illicit revenues from the DPRK’s malicious cyber activities directly fund its unlawful WMD and ballistic missile programs.</p>
<p>Our actions are intended to make clear to the DPRK that its escalatory behavior has consequences and that the international community will not accept the DPRK’s ongoing weapons development as normal.  Most importantly, we want to make clear to the DPRK that its only viable path forward is through diplomacy.  We harbor no hostile intent towards the DPRK.  This administration is willing to listen to the DPRK’s full range of concerns and address difficult topics, but this can only happen through dialogue.</p>
<p>The DPRK finds itself isolated in unprecedented ways and has shut itself off during the COVID pandemic.  Only the resumption of diplomacy can break this isolation, and only then can we pick up the important work that has been done before, building on the Singapore Joint Statement.</p>
<p>But even as we take steps to further deter the DPRK and reduce its threat, the threat that it poses to the region and beyond, we will continue to reach out with a sincere commitment to diplomacy.  I sincerely hope this message will make its way to Pyongyang and that they will respond positively.</p>
<p>Be happy to take your questions now.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b> Let’s take our first question from Courtney McBride.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Just what is the U.S. interpretation of or reaction to the recent statements from Kim Yo-jong which appeared designed to threaten South Korea?</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you.  Her statement in response to some comments that the ROK defense minister made – I obviously was concerned by Kim Yo-jong’s statements.  They were provocative.  We obviously hope that instead of making such provocative statements, that they would focus instead on some serious engagement that will address our common goal of denuclearization – and may promote stability on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b> Let’s take our next question from Janne Pak, please.  Janne Pak, USA Journal Korea.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR: </b> One moment.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b> Hi.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello, can you – hi, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b> Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  All right.  Thank you.  Hi, Jalina.  Nice to hear from you.  And hi, Ambassador Kim.  I have two questions on North Korea.  Recently, North Korea has declared long-term confrontation rather than dialogue.  If North Korea does not come to the table of negotiation, how will the United States diplomatic solution proceed?</p>
<p>And the second question:  You said that you will not close the U.S. diplomacy.  In the meantime, North Korea has continued to develop nuclear missile in the background while having dialogue with the United States.  Do you believe that North Korea will give its nuclear weapons through dialogue?  If so, what is the reason?  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you very much, Ms. Pak.  So we remain committed to the path of dialogue, and we believe, along with our allies and partners, that the only viable path forward is through diplomacy, and we hope that the North Koreans will accept our invitation to engage in a serious and sustained dialogue to advance our shared goals on the peninsula, starting with, of course, the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  But as I indicated in my opening remarks, we are willing and prepared to address any serious concerns that they may have about their situation on the peninsula.</p>
<p>With your question of – the second question about if they don’t give up through diplomacy, well, I mean, we – we and our allies and partners are determined to continue to seek the path of diplomacy.  We believe that that is the only viable path forward to achieve denuclearization on the peninsula and to maintain peace and prosperity on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s please go to the line of Ryohei Takagi.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Yes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Oh, thank you for briefing, Ambassador Kim.  We support you are trying to persuade China to join the new UN Security Council resolution against North Korea.  So what was your Chinese counterpart’s reaction to possible sanction resolution?</p>
<p>And secondly, I’m just wondering whether you had any good suggestions from Chinese counterparts to encourage the DPRK to engage in meaningful negotiations?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you very much, Takagi-san.  So I had a very long and detailed discussion with Special Representative Liu Xiaoming yesterday.  We covered a number of issues, including our work in the UN Security Council to achieve a new UN Security Council resolution.  We believe that the unprecedented number of DPRK ballistic missile launches this year and the instability they belong to the Korean Peninsula are obviously in nobody’s interest, and we call on the PRC as well as Russia to work with us to send a very clear message to the Security Council that North Korea’s actions are unacceptable.</p>
<p>The U.S. and China have a very important shared interest in maintaining stability on the Korean Peninsula, and through my many years of involvement in this issue, I’m convinced that Beijing shares our goal of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  So I look forward to working with Special Representative Liu and his colleagues in Beijing to make progress towards that goal.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s now go to the line of Doug Byun.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi.  Hello, Ambassador.  Thank you for doing this.  I was wondering if the – I mean, you kind of mentioned this, but I was wondering if North Korea has responded in any way, negative or positive, to U.S. overtures, and also if the United States is sending any private messages instead of just messaging over public messaging.</p>
<p>And I have one more question regarding the – Secretary Blinken’s meeting with his South Korean and Japanese counterparts last month in Hawaii.  At the time, the sides said they had discussed new ideas to bring North Korea back to the dialogue table.  I was wondering if you could share some of what some of those new ideas were and if there has been any progress in your discussions on those ideas.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thanks very much, Doug.  We have not received any response from Pyongyang, which is very disappointing because we have sent several messages, both public and private, inviting them to a dialogue without any conditions.  We made very clear that we’re willing to address their concerns, but also chart a path forward on how we can achieve progress on the denuclearization goal.</p>
<p>I still hope that they will respond positively to our many outreaches, but thus far they have not.</p>
<p>The Secretary, as you mentioned, had very productive meetings with his South Korean and Japanese counterparts in Hawaii a couple of months ago.  In fact, I think that is another example of the close coordination and communication that we have enjoyed with our allies on this very difficult issue.  I don’t want to go into the details of those discussions, but I can assure you that all three of us are committed to exploring all possible avenues to jumpstart a serious diplomatic process.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s go to the line of Edward Wong, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello.  I was wondering, with the change in administration in Seoul, what is your assessment of the direction that Seoul would now like to take their policy on the DPRK?  And how much of it is a departure from the policy of the Moon administration?</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Yeah, thanks, Edward.  It’s tempting, but I don’t think it’s my place to predict the incoming South Korean government’s policies on this issue.  What I can say is that we have enjoyed very close cooperation and coordination with the ROK, and I fully expect that with the incoming administration that close coordination will continue on this very important issue.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s please go to the line of Sangmin Lee.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  (Inaudible) to several measure to North Korea to hold DPRK accountable for their provocative action, shooting ICBM.  So the resumption of large-scale field-based U.S.-Korean military exercises is – can be another measure you’re thinking about?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Hi, if you’re still on the line, can you please repeat your question for us?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  We can hear you now.  If you’re able to repeat your question, that would be wonderful.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Okay, okay.  So the – Ambassador, you mentioned about several measure to hold DPRK accountable for their provocations.  So do you think that the resumption of large-scale field-based U.S.-ROK joint military exercises can be another measure you’re thinking about?</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you very much, Sangmin.  So the U.S.-ROK joint military exercises, as you know, are defensive and they’re done to make sure that we have the combined deterring capability necessary to deal with any contingency on the peninsula.  So these are extremely important exercises, and I know that both militaries are committed to continuing those efforts going forward.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s go to the line of Michelle Nichols, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi, thanks so much for the call.  I’m the Reuters correspondent up here at the UN, so I just wanted to follow up on the earlier question about the resolution.  Is China and Russia engaging on the draft resolution?  What exactly are you proposing?  Are you seeing any spillover from the Ukraine conflict?</p>
<p>And this call – you mentioned earlier that you’re hoping this – Pyongyang will get a message that the U.S. wants to talk.  Is that why you’re doing this call, to sort of publicly get a message to them because they’re not responding?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thanks very much.  As I mentioned earlier, I think the escalatory and provocative actions by the North Koreans require us to have a decisive response in the Security Council, and this is why we have, in cooperation with our partners, proposed a new UN Security Council resolution.  We have had discussions with the PRC and Russia.  Unfortunately, I cannot report that we have had productive discussions with them thus far, but I would defer to my very capable colleagues in New York to continue that effort.  I know that there is overwhelming consensus that the Security Council needs to respond to these blatant violations of multiple Security Council resolutions, and we hope that Russia and China will agree that it’s in their interest to work with us on this new Security Council resolution.</p>
<p>The purpose of doing this call, I think, is to try to address any questions and comments that the press corps may have about the status of our North Korea-related efforts.  It’s not necessarily to send a public message to the North Koreans, because I think we have made ourselves very clear through both public statements and private messages to the DPRK that we are ready to engage them in a serious and meaningful dialogue.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s please go to the line of Sho Watanabe, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello, do you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Okay, thank you for doing that.  I have two questions.  One, that North Korea’s anniversary on April 15th is now approaching, and there are also the concerns about further provocations.  So in your meeting with your Chinese counterparts, did you ask China to urge North Korea not to conduct any tests or even nuclear tests, and you persuaded China to use their own leverage to North Korea?</p>
<p>And my second question is:  Do you think there are any concrete steps that can be taken further by the three countries – Japan, U.S., and the South Korea – to increase our deterrence towards North Korea?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you very much, Mr. Watanabe.  So we are worried that, in connection with the upcoming April 15th anniversary, that the DPRK may be tempted to take another provocative action.  We obviously hope not, but we will be prepared.</p>
<p>Part of their preparation is related to your second question about the importance of trilateral cooperation among the U.S., the ROK, and Japan.  As I mentioned earlier, we have had closest possible communication and coordination with both governments, Tokyo and Seoul, and that will continue, especially as we anticipate that there may be further provocative actions by the DPRK.  And I think those possible measures include a number of different areas and I know that our colleagues in the military are also considering what we can be doing together bilaterally as well as trilaterally – more strengthen our deterrent capability.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s please go to the line of Jinmyung Kim, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  This is Jinmyung Kim from South Korea’s <i>Chosunilbo</i>, and thank you for doing this.  Ambassador Kim, I have a question about the UN Security Council resolution you are seeking with South Korea’s Special Representative Noh Kyu-duk.  And so what is the nature of this resolution?  Do you seek to impose new, substantial sanctions on North Korea?  Or do you simply aim to have a kind of declaratory statement that condemns North Korea’s action?</p>
<p>And my second question is:  So everybody knows that it is probably unachievable right now because of the lack of cooperation – Russia’s cooperation.  So why do you still pursue this resolution while you know that it may not go through?  And my second question is:  In your dialogue with Chinese special representative, have you seen any positive signs that China has already engaged in direct communication with DPRK to help bring back them to the negotiating table?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thanks very much, Ms. Kim.  So the new UN Security Council resolution is intended to address a number of things, especially their continued missile activities, ballistic missile activities, because this resolution is in response to the escalatory, provocative actions that they have taken through a series of missile launches this year.  They’re up to 13 launches just this year, deeply concerning, and at least three of those have been ICBM launches.  I think it’s important for the Security Council to respond to such behavior that are clearly a violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions.</p>
<p>You may be right that the PRC and Russia will not cooperate despite our earnest efforts, but I think it’s still important for us to do what is responsible.  This actually affects more than the DPRK issue.  This is about the credibility of the United Nations.  When a country violates multiple Security Council resolutions in addition to their own commitments under the Six-Party Talks as well as the Singapore joint declaration, I think we need to hold them accountable.  And this is why we’re pushing the resolution despite the fact that so far, we have received very little cooperation from Beijing and Moscow.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  We have time for a final question, and let’s go to the line of Conor Finnegan.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hey, Ambassador.  Just first brief follow-ups to some of my colleagues’ questions.  When you said that you were worried about provocative action perhaps next week on the anniversary, is that concern specifically of a nuclear test?  When you talk about no response from North Korea, I’m just wondering why you think that they haven’t responded.</p>
<p>And then finally, you referenced the Singapore declaration in your opening remarks.  Do you think that that declaration should form the basis for future negotiations despite what some people see as its flaws and its vague language?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thanks, Conor.  So in terms of the upcoming anniversary and the provocation – provocative actions the DPRK may take, I don’t want to speculate too much, but I think it could be another missile launch, it could be a nuclear test.  The important thing is that we, in cooperation and coordination with our allies and partners, are prepared to deal with whatever they may undertake.  And I want to emphasize that we obviously hope that they will refrain from further provocation.  They’ve already done quite a bit this year – 13 launches.  So hopefully the anniversary can pass without any further escalation.</p>
<p>And I – it’s always hard for me to speculate on why Pyongyang does what it does or what it doesn’t do.  I mean, we have indicated very sincerely our interest in a diplomatic effort with them, and hope that they will respond.  I mean, I would just speculate that given that the country has been a – complete shutdown for the past two years due to the COVID pandemic, perhaps that’s a factor in the fact that they have not responded.  But I will limit my speculation to that.</p>
<p>On the Singapore declaration, I mean, you’re right about there’s been criticism that the document was too vague, not detailed enough.  But we believe that it would form a useful basis to build on, because that is one document in which the dear leader Kim Jong-un has personally made a commitment towards denuclearization.  So I think it would appropriately form a basis for a further effort to develop a viable diplomatic path and roadmap towards the complete denuclearization goal.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Thank you, everyone.  That concludes today’s briefing.  The embargo is now lifted.  Special Representative Kim, thank you so much for your time, and I hope you all have a great day ahead.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sung Kim, Acting Assistant Secretary  Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:  </b>Good morning, everyone, and thank you so much for joining today’s press call. Special Representative for the DPRK Ambassador Sung Kim is visiting Washington this week for a series of engagements and is here to discuss U.S. policy toward the DPRK.  We’re very glad to have the special representative with us on the line today to tell you a little bit more about his visit.  Ambassador Kim will start with some opening remarks and then proceed with taking your questions.  I’d like to also take this opportunity to remind everyone that while this call is on the record, the contents of this briefing are embargoed until the end of the call.  And with that, I’ll hand it over to Special Representative Kim.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:  </b>Great, thank you very much, Jalina.  And thank – many thanks to all of you for joining us this morning.  Let me start by saying a few words on where we are and where we are heading in our work on the DPRK, and then I’d be happy to take your questions.</p>
<p>Since taking office, the Biden-Harris administration has made clear its priority to reduce the threat posed by the DPRK.  We are determined to protect the security of the United States, along with that of our allies and partners in the region and beyond.  We are of course closely following developments in the DPRK, and we maintain the ultimate goal of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>We know there are challenges, and these will not be easily resolved, but we remain fully committed to working closely with our allies and partners in a global effort to make progress toward this end goal.  Our efforts involve both diplomatic outreach and threat reduction.  And while it is clear the DPRK leadership is determined to advance its illegal weapons programs, we know that our efforts are constraining their progress.  At the same time, we have not closed the door on diplomacy.  We are committed to pursuing serious and sustained dialogue.  As we have said many times, we are prepared to meet the DPRK without preconditions.  But Pyongyang must make the choice to halt its destabilizing actions and instead choose engagement.</p>
<p>The U.S. Government at all levels has engaged vigorously on the DPRK with our allies and partners around the world.  The Secretary, Deputy Secretary Sherman, and I have consulted regularly with our counterparts in the ROK and Japan bilaterally as well as trilaterally.  We have repeatedly offered to meet the DPRK to discuss any and all issues, and yet the DPRK has declined our invitation to dialogue.  Instead, they have initiated a series of missile tests that recently culminated in at least three ICBM launches.  These actions pose a serious threat to regional stability.</p>
<p>The U.S. strongly condemns these tests, each of which was a blatant violation of multiple Security Council resolutions.  These launches demonstrate the DPRK continues to prioritize its weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs at the expense of regional and international security.  This prioritization is also at the expense of the North Korean people.  The government has chosen to deploy its limited resources to fund illegal weapons programs even as the humanitarian situation in the country has grown increasingly dire.</p>
<p>The potential range of these ICBMs should also remind us that the DPRK’s actions are a global security concern.  It is not merely about the United States and the DPRK.</p>
<p>In response to DPRK’s recent escalatory actions and as part of our effort to impede the DPRK’s ability to advance its missile program, we have taken a series of diplomatic, economic, and military measures.  As of March 25, we have raised the DPRK’s ballistic missile launches at the UN Security Council six times this year.  Russia and the PRC have consistently blocked our efforts to produce a UN public statement.  And in spite of this, we’ve worked with a growing group of like-minded countries to draw attention to the DPRK’s irresponsible behavior.</p>
<p>On March 7th, the U.S. Indo-Pacific Command, INDOPACOM, ordered intensified intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance collection activities in the Yellow Sea.  USINDOPACOM also enhanced readiness among our ballistic missile defense forces in the region to help ensure the security of our allies.</p>
<p>A week later, on March 15th, USINDOPACOM announced it had conducted a carrier-based air demonstration in the Yellow Sea as a demonstration of resolve and commitment to our regional allies.  The U.S. Department of Treasury and the Department of State have also announced several new actions to help prevent the DPRK from accessing foreign items and technology that enable it to advance its prohibited weapons programs.  We have placed sanctions on a number of individuals and entities as well.</p>
<p>We will also continue to work closely with our allies and partners to address the critical issue of the DPRK’s cyber program, which poses a sophisticated and agile espionage, cyber crime, and attack threat.  The illicit revenues from the DPRK’s malicious cyber activities directly fund its unlawful WMD and ballistic missile programs.</p>
<p>Our actions are intended to make clear to the DPRK that its escalatory behavior has consequences and that the international community will not accept the DPRK’s ongoing weapons development as normal.  Most importantly, we want to make clear to the DPRK that its only viable path forward is through diplomacy.  We harbor no hostile intent towards the DPRK.  This administration is willing to listen to the DPRK’s full range of concerns and address difficult topics, but this can only happen through dialogue.</p>
<p>The DPRK finds itself isolated in unprecedented ways and has shut itself off during the COVID pandemic.  Only the resumption of diplomacy can break this isolation, and only then can we pick up the important work that has been done before, building on the Singapore Joint Statement.</p>
<p>But even as we take steps to further deter the DPRK and reduce its threat, the threat that it poses to the region and beyond, we will continue to reach out with a sincere commitment to diplomacy.  I sincerely hope this message will make its way to Pyongyang and that they will respond positively.</p>
<p>Be happy to take your questions now.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b> Let’s take our first question from Courtney McBride.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Just what is the U.S. interpretation of or reaction to the recent statements from Kim Yo-jong which appeared designed to threaten South Korea?</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you.  Her statement in response to some comments that the ROK defense minister made – I obviously was concerned by Kim Yo-jong’s statements.  They were provocative.  We obviously hope that instead of making such provocative statements, that they would focus instead on some serious engagement that will address our common goal of denuclearization – and may promote stability on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b> Let’s take our next question from Janne Pak, please.  Janne Pak, USA Journal Korea.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR: </b> One moment.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b> Hi.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello, can you – hi, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER: </b> Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  All right.  Thank you.  Hi, Jalina.  Nice to hear from you.  And hi, Ambassador Kim.  I have two questions on North Korea.  Recently, North Korea has declared long-term confrontation rather than dialogue.  If North Korea does not come to the table of negotiation, how will the United States diplomatic solution proceed?</p>
<p>And the second question:  You said that you will not close the U.S. diplomacy.  In the meantime, North Korea has continued to develop nuclear missile in the background while having dialogue with the United States.  Do you believe that North Korea will give its nuclear weapons through dialogue?  If so, what is the reason?  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you very much, Ms. Pak.  So we remain committed to the path of dialogue, and we believe, along with our allies and partners, that the only viable path forward is through diplomacy, and we hope that the North Koreans will accept our invitation to engage in a serious and sustained dialogue to advance our shared goals on the peninsula, starting with, of course, the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  But as I indicated in my opening remarks, we are willing and prepared to address any serious concerns that they may have about their situation on the peninsula.</p>
<p>With your question of – the second question about if they don’t give up through diplomacy, well, I mean, we – we and our allies and partners are determined to continue to seek the path of diplomacy.  We believe that that is the only viable path forward to achieve denuclearization on the peninsula and to maintain peace and prosperity on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s please go to the line of Ryohei Takagi.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Yes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Oh, thank you for briefing, Ambassador Kim.  We support you are trying to persuade China to join the new UN Security Council resolution against North Korea.  So what was your Chinese counterpart’s reaction to possible sanction resolution?</p>
<p>And secondly, I’m just wondering whether you had any good suggestions from Chinese counterparts to encourage the DPRK to engage in meaningful negotiations?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you very much, Takagi-san.  So I had a very long and detailed discussion with Special Representative Liu Xiaoming yesterday.  We covered a number of issues, including our work in the UN Security Council to achieve a new UN Security Council resolution.  We believe that the unprecedented number of DPRK ballistic missile launches this year and the instability they belong to the Korean Peninsula are obviously in nobody’s interest, and we call on the PRC as well as Russia to work with us to send a very clear message to the Security Council that North Korea’s actions are unacceptable.</p>
<p>The U.S. and China have a very important shared interest in maintaining stability on the Korean Peninsula, and through my many years of involvement in this issue, I’m convinced that Beijing shares our goal of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  So I look forward to working with Special Representative Liu and his colleagues in Beijing to make progress towards that goal.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s now go to the line of Doug Byun.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi.  Hello, Ambassador.  Thank you for doing this.  I was wondering if the – I mean, you kind of mentioned this, but I was wondering if North Korea has responded in any way, negative or positive, to U.S. overtures, and also if the United States is sending any private messages instead of just messaging over public messaging.</p>
<p>And I have one more question regarding the – Secretary Blinken’s meeting with his South Korean and Japanese counterparts last month in Hawaii.  At the time, the sides said they had discussed new ideas to bring North Korea back to the dialogue table.  I was wondering if you could share some of what some of those new ideas were and if there has been any progress in your discussions on those ideas.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thanks very much, Doug.  We have not received any response from Pyongyang, which is very disappointing because we have sent several messages, both public and private, inviting them to a dialogue without any conditions.  We made very clear that we’re willing to address their concerns, but also chart a path forward on how we can achieve progress on the denuclearization goal.</p>
<p>I still hope that they will respond positively to our many outreaches, but thus far they have not.</p>
<p>The Secretary, as you mentioned, had very productive meetings with his South Korean and Japanese counterparts in Hawaii a couple of months ago.  In fact, I think that is another example of the close coordination and communication that we have enjoyed with our allies on this very difficult issue.  I don’t want to go into the details of those discussions, but I can assure you that all three of us are committed to exploring all possible avenues to jumpstart a serious diplomatic process.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s go to the line of Edward Wong, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello.  I was wondering, with the change in administration in Seoul, what is your assessment of the direction that Seoul would now like to take their policy on the DPRK?  And how much of it is a departure from the policy of the Moon administration?</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Yeah, thanks, Edward.  It’s tempting, but I don’t think it’s my place to predict the incoming South Korean government’s policies on this issue.  What I can say is that we have enjoyed very close cooperation and coordination with the ROK, and I fully expect that with the incoming administration that close coordination will continue on this very important issue.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s please go to the line of Sangmin Lee.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  (Inaudible) to several measure to North Korea to hold DPRK accountable for their provocative action, shooting ICBM.  So the resumption of large-scale field-based U.S.-Korean military exercises is – can be another measure you’re thinking about?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Hi, if you’re still on the line, can you please repeat your question for us?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  We can hear you now.  If you’re able to repeat your question, that would be wonderful.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Okay, okay.  So the – Ambassador, you mentioned about several measure to hold DPRK accountable for their provocations.  So do you think that the resumption of large-scale field-based U.S.-ROK joint military exercises can be another measure you’re thinking about?</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you very much, Sangmin.  So the U.S.-ROK joint military exercises, as you know, are defensive and they’re done to make sure that we have the combined deterring capability necessary to deal with any contingency on the peninsula.  So these are extremely important exercises, and I know that both militaries are committed to continuing those efforts going forward.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s go to the line of Michelle Nichols, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi, thanks so much for the call.  I’m the Reuters correspondent up here at the UN, so I just wanted to follow up on the earlier question about the resolution.  Is China and Russia engaging on the draft resolution?  What exactly are you proposing?  Are you seeing any spillover from the Ukraine conflict?</p>
<p>And this call – you mentioned earlier that you’re hoping this – Pyongyang will get a message that the U.S. wants to talk.  Is that why you’re doing this call, to sort of publicly get a message to them because they’re not responding?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thanks very much.  As I mentioned earlier, I think the escalatory and provocative actions by the North Koreans require us to have a decisive response in the Security Council, and this is why we have, in cooperation with our partners, proposed a new UN Security Council resolution.  We have had discussions with the PRC and Russia.  Unfortunately, I cannot report that we have had productive discussions with them thus far, but I would defer to my very capable colleagues in New York to continue that effort.  I know that there is overwhelming consensus that the Security Council needs to respond to these blatant violations of multiple Security Council resolutions, and we hope that Russia and China will agree that it’s in their interest to work with us on this new Security Council resolution.</p>
<p>The purpose of doing this call, I think, is to try to address any questions and comments that the press corps may have about the status of our North Korea-related efforts.  It’s not necessarily to send a public message to the North Koreans, because I think we have made ourselves very clear through both public statements and private messages to the DPRK that we are ready to engage them in a serious and meaningful dialogue.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s please go to the line of Sho Watanabe, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello, do you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Okay, thank you for doing that.  I have two questions.  One, that North Korea’s anniversary on April 15th is now approaching, and there are also the concerns about further provocations.  So in your meeting with your Chinese counterparts, did you ask China to urge North Korea not to conduct any tests or even nuclear tests, and you persuaded China to use their own leverage to North Korea?</p>
<p>And my second question is:  Do you think there are any concrete steps that can be taken further by the three countries – Japan, U.S., and the South Korea – to increase our deterrence towards North Korea?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you very much, Mr. Watanabe.  So we are worried that, in connection with the upcoming April 15th anniversary, that the DPRK may be tempted to take another provocative action.  We obviously hope not, but we will be prepared.</p>
<p>Part of their preparation is related to your second question about the importance of trilateral cooperation among the U.S., the ROK, and Japan.  As I mentioned earlier, we have had closest possible communication and coordination with both governments, Tokyo and Seoul, and that will continue, especially as we anticipate that there may be further provocative actions by the DPRK.  And I think those possible measures include a number of different areas and I know that our colleagues in the military are also considering what we can be doing together bilaterally as well as trilaterally – more strengthen our deterrent capability.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Let’s please go to the line of Jinmyung Kim, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  This is Jinmyung Kim from South Korea’s <i>Chosunilbo</i>, and thank you for doing this.  Ambassador Kim, I have a question about the UN Security Council resolution you are seeking with South Korea’s Special Representative Noh Kyu-duk.  And so what is the nature of this resolution?  Do you seek to impose new, substantial sanctions on North Korea?  Or do you simply aim to have a kind of declaratory statement that condemns North Korea’s action?</p>
<p>And my second question is:  So everybody knows that it is probably unachievable right now because of the lack of cooperation – Russia’s cooperation.  So why do you still pursue this resolution while you know that it may not go through?  And my second question is:  In your dialogue with Chinese special representative, have you seen any positive signs that China has already engaged in direct communication with DPRK to help bring back them to the negotiating table?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thanks very much, Ms. Kim.  So the new UN Security Council resolution is intended to address a number of things, especially their continued missile activities, ballistic missile activities, because this resolution is in response to the escalatory, provocative actions that they have taken through a series of missile launches this year.  They’re up to 13 launches just this year, deeply concerning, and at least three of those have been ICBM launches.  I think it’s important for the Security Council to respond to such behavior that are clearly a violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions.</p>
<p>You may be right that the PRC and Russia will not cooperate despite our earnest efforts, but I think it’s still important for us to do what is responsible.  This actually affects more than the DPRK issue.  This is about the credibility of the United Nations.  When a country violates multiple Security Council resolutions in addition to their own commitments under the Six-Party Talks as well as the Singapore joint declaration, I think we need to hold them accountable.  And this is why we’re pushing the resolution despite the fact that so far, we have received very little cooperation from Beijing and Moscow.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  We have time for a final question, and let’s go to the line of Conor Finnegan.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hey, Ambassador.  Just first brief follow-ups to some of my colleagues’ questions.  When you said that you were worried about provocative action perhaps next week on the anniversary, is that concern specifically of a nuclear test?  When you talk about no response from North Korea, I’m just wondering why you think that they haven’t responded.</p>
<p>And then finally, you referenced the Singapore declaration in your opening remarks.  Do you think that that declaration should form the basis for future negotiations despite what some people see as its flaws and its vague language?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thanks, Conor.  So in terms of the upcoming anniversary and the provocation – provocative actions the DPRK may take, I don’t want to speculate too much, but I think it could be another missile launch, it could be a nuclear test.  The important thing is that we, in cooperation and coordination with our allies and partners, are prepared to deal with whatever they may undertake.  And I want to emphasize that we obviously hope that they will refrain from further provocation.  They’ve already done quite a bit this year – 13 launches.  So hopefully the anniversary can pass without any further escalation.</p>
<p>And I – it’s always hard for me to speculate on why Pyongyang does what it does or what it doesn’t do.  I mean, we have indicated very sincerely our interest in a diplomatic effort with them, and hope that they will respond.  I mean, I would just speculate that given that the country has been a – complete shutdown for the past two years due to the COVID pandemic, perhaps that’s a factor in the fact that they have not responded.  But I will limit my speculation to that.</p>
<p>On the Singapore declaration, I mean, you’re right about there’s been criticism that the document was too vague, not detailed enough.  But we believe that it would form a useful basis to build on, because that is one document in which the dear leader Kim Jong-un has personally made a commitment towards denuclearization.  So I think it would appropriately form a basis for a further effort to develop a viable diplomatic path and roadmap towards the complete denuclearization goal.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS PORTER:</b>  Thank you, everyone.  That concludes today’s briefing.  The embargo is now lifted.  Special Representative Kim, thank you so much for your time, and I hope you all have a great day ahead.</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR KIM:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department of State Offers Reward for Information to Bring Transnational Criminal to Justice</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/department-of-state-offers-reward-for-information-to-bring-transnational-criminal-to-justice/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 17:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332090</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department of State is offering a reward of up to $5 million for information leading to the arrest and/or conviction of Semion Mogilevich, a longtime transnational criminal currently living in Russia.  Mogilevich is wanted in the United States for his alleged participation between 1993 and 1998 in a multi-million dollar scheme to defraud thousands of investors related to a public company headquartered in Newtown, Pennsylvania.  The scheme collapsed in 1998 after thousands of investors lost more than $150 million.  Mogilevich was indicted in 2002 and again in 2003.</p>
<p>This reward is offered under the Department of State’s Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program (TOCRP), which the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs manages in close coordination with federal law enforcement partners and other U.S. government agencies.  More than 75 transnational criminals and major narcotics traffickers have been brought to justice under the TOCRP and the Narcotics Rewards Program (NRP) since the NRP’s inception in 1986, with the Department paying more than $135 million in rewards for information to-date.</p>
<p>Any information in response this reward offer should be directed to the FBI at +1-800-225-5324 (Voice), +1-215-839-6844 (WhatsApp), or online at <a class="external-link" href="https://tips.fbi.gov/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://tips.fbi.gov</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>For more information on the individuals listed above and the TOCRP, please see <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs/inl-rewards-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDYuNTYwMjY2NTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1LW9mLWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtbmFyY290aWNzLWFuZC1sYXctZW5mb3JjZW1lbnQtYWZmYWlycy9pbmwtcmV3YXJkcy1wcm9ncmFtLyJ9.vHtJLrWOE85p_foIC5JMihAc3jp6Ej2zlBJckG0Ua7Q/s/2171565732/br/129423737675-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649350926158000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1zFb-C9EQYSZOe9QiTX1IU">https://www.state.gov/bureau-<wbr />of-international-narcotics-<wbr />and-law-enforcement-affairs/<wbr />inl-rewards-program/</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department of State is offering a reward of up to $5 million for information leading to the arrest and/or conviction of Semion Mogilevich, a longtime transnational criminal currently living in Russia.  Mogilevich is wanted in the United States for his alleged participation between 1993 and 1998 in a multi-million dollar scheme to defraud thousands of investors related to a public company headquartered in Newtown, Pennsylvania.  The scheme collapsed in 1998 after thousands of investors lost more than $150 million.  Mogilevich was indicted in 2002 and again in 2003.</p>
<p>This reward is offered under the Department of State’s Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program (TOCRP), which the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs manages in close coordination with federal law enforcement partners and other U.S. government agencies.  More than 75 transnational criminals and major narcotics traffickers have been brought to justice under the TOCRP and the Narcotics Rewards Program (NRP) since the NRP’s inception in 1986, with the Department paying more than $135 million in rewards for information to-date.</p>
<p>Any information in response this reward offer should be directed to the FBI at +1-800-225-5324 (Voice), +1-215-839-6844 (WhatsApp), or online at <a class="external-link" href="https://tips.fbi.gov/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://tips.fbi.gov</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>For more information on the individuals listed above and the TOCRP, please see <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs/inl-rewards-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDYuNTYwMjY2NTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1LW9mLWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtbmFyY290aWNzLWFuZC1sYXctZW5mb3JjZW1lbnQtYWZmYWlycy9pbmwtcmV3YXJkcy1wcm9ncmFtLyJ9.vHtJLrWOE85p_foIC5JMihAc3jp6Ej2zlBJckG0Ua7Q/s/2171565732/br/129423737675-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649350926158000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1zFb-C9EQYSZOe9QiTX1IU">https://www.state.gov/bureau-<wbr />of-international-narcotics-<wbr />and-law-enforcement-affairs/<wbr />inl-rewards-program/</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Australian Foreign Minister Payne</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-australian-foreign-minister-payne-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 16:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332080</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Australian Foreign Minister Marise Payne in Brussels. The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed joint efforts to hold the Russian Federation accountable for its unprovoked and unjust war against Ukraine as well as mutual efforts to provide security assistance to Ukraine.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister reiterated their commitment to ensuring peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific region and noted the April 4 release of the AUKUS Leaders’ Statement, summarizing the progress AUKUS partners have made over the past six months.  They also shared concerns about recent regional developments and ways to support countries in making open and transparent decisions about their own security and economic interests.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Australian Foreign Minister Marise Payne in Brussels. The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed joint efforts to hold the Russian Federation accountable for its unprovoked and unjust war against Ukraine as well as mutual efforts to provide security assistance to Ukraine.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister reiterated their commitment to ensuring peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific region and noted the April 4 release of the AUKUS Leaders’ Statement, summarizing the progress AUKUS partners have made over the past six months.  They also shared concerns about recent regional developments and ways to support countries in making open and transparent decisions about their own security and economic interests.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>50th Anniversary of the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/50th-anniversary-of-the-biological-and-toxin-weapons-convention/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 15:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Fifty years ago, the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention (BTWC) was opened for signature and later became the first treaty to ban an entire category of weapons. Today, with over 180 States Parties, it is the cornerstone of international efforts to prevent biological weapons.</p>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic demonstrated the devastating impact that disease can have on the world. We must recognize that other biological risks are growing and take action to address them. We face not only an increased threat of naturally occurring diseases, but also the potential for laboratory accidents and the intentional misuse of life sciences and biotechnology. The weaponization of biological agents and toxins violates the BTWC and is unacceptable, and the use of biological weapons – in the words of the Convention – “would be repugnant to the conscience of mankind.”</p>
<p>We are determined to use the occasion of this important anniversary as a reminder of the need to strengthen and revitalize the BTWC. As we look to its Ninth Review Conference later this year, the United States urges States Parties to overcome differences and take urgent steps to guard against the development and use of biological weapons.</p>
<p>Specifically, we believe the Review Conference should take near-term, concrete action to strengthen the Convention and benefit States Parties in such areas as increasing resources for international assistance and cooperation and establishing a mechanism to review advances in science and technology. Additionally, we have proposed that the Conference establish a new expert group to study additional measures to strengthen implementation of the Convention, increase transparency, and enhance assurances of compliance. We also urge all states that have not yet become party to the BTWC to join it now, so they can play an active role in this year’s Review Conference.</p>
<p>The best way to commemorate this anniversary is for States Parties to work together to strengthen the BTWC and end the threat of biological weapons. Through our collective action to counter all biological threats – naturally occurring, accidental, and deliberate – we can make the world a safer place for all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Fifty years ago, the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention (BTWC) was opened for signature and later became the first treaty to ban an entire category of weapons. Today, with over 180 States Parties, it is the cornerstone of international efforts to prevent biological weapons.</p>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic demonstrated the devastating impact that disease can have on the world. We must recognize that other biological risks are growing and take action to address them. We face not only an increased threat of naturally occurring diseases, but also the potential for laboratory accidents and the intentional misuse of life sciences and biotechnology. The weaponization of biological agents and toxins violates the BTWC and is unacceptable, and the use of biological weapons – in the words of the Convention – “would be repugnant to the conscience of mankind.”</p>
<p>We are determined to use the occasion of this important anniversary as a reminder of the need to strengthen and revitalize the BTWC. As we look to its Ninth Review Conference later this year, the United States urges States Parties to overcome differences and take urgent steps to guard against the development and use of biological weapons.</p>
<p>Specifically, we believe the Review Conference should take near-term, concrete action to strengthen the Convention and benefit States Parties in such areas as increasing resources for international assistance and cooperation and establishing a mechanism to review advances in science and technology. Additionally, we have proposed that the Conference establish a new expert group to study additional measures to strengthen implementation of the Convention, increase transparency, and enhance assurances of compliance. We also urge all states that have not yet become party to the BTWC to join it now, so they can play an active role in this year’s Review Conference.</p>
<p>The best way to commemorate this anniversary is for States Parties to work together to strengthen the BTWC and end the threat of biological weapons. Through our collective action to counter all biological threats – naturally occurring, accidental, and deliberate – we can make the world a safer place for all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with Andrea Mitchell of NBC</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-andrea-mitchell-of-nbc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 15:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332032</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Mr. Secretary, thank you so much for being with us.  I wanted to ask you about what is going on right now.  The chairman of the Joint Chiefs had told Congress that this will likely last years, this war.  A protracted war is going to last years, according to the chairman of the Joint Chiefs.  Will today’s new commitment of Javelins, anti-tank weapons to Ukraine shorten that timeline?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Andrea, we want to see this come to an end as quickly as possible, and that’s exactly why we’re making sure that we’re doing everything we can to support Ukraine and to give them the assistance that they need to put pressure and to increase pressure on Russia, even as we’re strengthening our – the defenses of our NATO Alliance.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So what about the Javelins?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So the Javelins, we just did – the President authorized another $100 million in a drawdown that will provide more Javelins to our Ukrainian partners.  Put this in perspective:  Between the United States and other allies and partners, for every Russian tank in Ukraine, we have provided or will soon provide 10 anti-tank systems – 10 for every single Russian tank.  So in terms of what they need to act quickly and act effectively, to deal with the planes that are firing at them from the skies, the tanks that are trying to destroy their cities from the ground, they have the tools that they need, they’re going to keep getting them, and we’re going to keep sustaining that.</p>
<p>But to the chairman’s point, and the President said this as well, as much as we want to see this come to an end as soon as possible to stop the death and destruction that’s being wrought by Russia in Ukraine, there is also a very likely scenario by which this goes on for some time.  The Russians, even as they’re moving their forces, they’ve retreated from Kyiv, they’ve retreated from the north and the west, they’re consolidating forces in the east, in the Donbas.  They have a lot of force still left.  The Ukrainians have something else that’s ultimately stronger, and that is a fierce determination and will to defend their country with the support of many countries around the world.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Can they win?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So ultimately, yes, because what is success, what is victory?  It’s holding on to the sovereignty and independence of their country.  And there is no scenario by which over time that will not happen.  The problem is it may take time, and in the meantime, tremendous death and destruction.  But what is so powerful here is that the Ukrainians have made it very clear that they will not subjugate themselves to Vladimir Putin’s will.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But no matter how much we give them, how can Ukraine ever last against Russia for the long term unless the U.S. and other countries guarantee its borders, its safety, as President Zelenskyy wants?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, first things first.  The first thing is to see that this aggression by Russia comes to an end, that there is a ceasefire, that Russia withdraws its forces, that Ukraine asserts its sovereignty and its independence.  But then, yes, we have to do things to make sure that, to the best of our ability and Ukraine’s ability, this can’t happen again, that Russia is deterred, that Ukraine is defended.  We’re having constant conversations with &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will we guarantee that?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So we’re having &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will the U.S. get more involved?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We’re having constant conversations with our Ukrainian partners pretty much on a daily basis, including about what it is we and others could do in the event of a successful negotiation to defend them and help them defend themselves going forward.  All of this is the subject of conversations right now.  I’m not going to get ahead of that, but we’re going to do everything we can, others will do what they can to make sure that Ukraine can defend itself and deter aggression being repeated by Russia.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  President Putin has said he wants to recreate the Soviet Union, the glory of the Soviet Union.  With those ambitions, how can Ukraine ever be safe as long as Putin’s in power?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, two things:  First, in terms of what Russia set out to do, what Putin set out to do in Ukraine, this has already been a strategic setback, if not a failure.  Because keep in mind, Andrea, the goal that Putin set in his own words was to eliminate Ukraine’s sovereignty and independence.  He sees it as a state that doesn’t deserve to be independent, that needs to be subsumed back into some kind of greater Russia.  That is not happening, not just the retreat from Kyiv but the fact that no matter how you play this out the Ukrainians are not going to subject themselves to a Russian dictatorship.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  He’s more popular than ever at home.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So he may be for now more popular.  Of course, if you were getting fed a steady diet, morning, noon, and night of propaganda, which unfortunately the Russian people are, that speaks to what popularity he has.  At the same time, when people are responding to polls, they may be very much afraid of giving the truthful answer.  There’s now a 15-year criminal penalty for anyone who in any way opposes the so-called special military operation.  So you have to take that with a grain of salt.</p>
<p>Having said that, I think there is a real fundamental problem, which is the Russians don’t get the factual information that they need to make judgments for themselves, and that’s because of a system that Vladimir Putin has perfected in which that information is denied them.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  President Biden has called Putin a butcher, a war criminal.  You have said that the people responsible for the crimes in Bucha and those who ordered them will be held accountable.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  That’s right.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  How can that happen without Vladimir Putin standing trial?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  First, Andrea, the wheels of accountability can move slowly, but they move, and someday, someway, somewhere, those who committed these crimes and those who ordered the crimes will be held accountable.  But it takes time, and part of this is building the case, part of this is – which we’re doing and others are doing.  Part – there’s a Ukrainian special prosecutor who is working on this.  We’re supporting her efforts.  We set up at the United Nations at the Human Rights Council a Commission of Inquiry that’s looking into this as well.  We’re supporting those efforts, building the case, getting the evidence, documenting it.  The International Criminal Court is looking at this too.</p>
<p>But all of this will play out over time, and we have to build the case, we have to get the evidence, we have to document it – we’re doing all of that.  So is that next month, next year, in five years?  It could take time, but I think – I can guarantee you there will be a relentless effort to make sure that those responsible for what we’re seeing are held accountable.  And what we’re seeing, Andrea, is I think beyond what any of us even could fully anticipate.  We said before Russia committed this aggression that there would be atrocities, that it was a deliberate part of their campaign.  And even knowing that, when this Russian tide receded from Bucha and we saw the death and destruction left in its wake, and we saw what that looked like, including people who had been assassinated – and in fact, their hands tied – executed, their hands tied behind their backs – the abuse committed against women, against children, it’s horrific.  And there has to be accountability for it.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Did you see the video that President Zelenskyy provided to the United Nations, or other images from Bucha?  As you describe it, the atrocities, you have small children.  What do you tell your children?  What would you tell them?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, thankfully, they’re too small to actually see that, be able to digest it and to understand it.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But some day, they’ll – they will &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  But some day they will.  And I have to tell you, Andrea, I think – and I suspect most of us have the same reaction, especially those of who have children or even small children – you put yourself in the shoes of the father, the mother, the grandfather, the grandmother who’s in the middle of this, who is suffering this, whose kids’ lives are at stake or in jeopardy, or who have been lost.  And it hits you – I said the other day, seeing these images from Bucha was like a punch to the gut.  It takes the wind out of you.  You can know something intellectually, but then when you see these images and you translate that into your own life, when you ask yourself, “What if this was happening in my town, to my kids?  To my family?”  I think it only reinforces our determination to do everything we can to support the Ukrainians, to put pressure on Russia, to bring this to an end as quickly as possible.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Your UN ambassador, Linda Thomas-Greenfield, described these atrocities and compared it by extension to the Holocaust.  Talked about what the council in Mariupol had described, people forcibly – tens of thousands – taken from their homes, taken to Russia and put in camps.  Isn’t that the very definition of genocide?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, we have to get all of the information, all of the evidence.  We have to, as I said, document everything that’s happened, fully understand what’s happened.  It’s an interesting irony in a sense.  This is in some ways the most documented war in real time that we’ve experienced because of technology, because of smart phones, because of the incredible courage of reporters who remained in Ukraine.  But even so, the things that we’re not seeing in real time, including Bucha – and it’s only when that tide recedes that you see what’s actually happened.</p>
<p>So I think we’re going to learn a lot more in the days and weeks ahead.  I’m afraid that what we’re going to learn is even more horrifying.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Do we know anything about what’s happening in these Russian camps with Ukrainians, and do we have any hope of getting them back?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We don’t have good information on that, but certainly we’re doing everything we can.  Other countries are doing everything they can to make sure that anyone who is being detained is released.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  The U.S. has promised to take in 100,000 of these millions of refugees.  Europe has opened their doors, put them in their homes.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  They have.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  NBC has reported on at least two women, two Ukrainian women on the southern border, who were taken and for two weeks put behind barbed wire and at times shackled in an ICE camp.  How can we do that compared to the way Europe is welcoming them?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, I’m not aware of those reports.  It’s something I’ll certainly look into.  But here’s what’s going on.  First, Europeans have been extraordinary in their generosity, in opening their hearts, opening their arms, opening their homes to so many people.  Our friends in Poland, in the first instance, have had more than 2 million people come through Poland.  Many of the refugees – most of them, in fact – want to stay close to home because what you’re seeing, Andrea – and I know you’ve seen this firsthand – is virtually everyone is a woman and children.  Most of the men between 18 and 60 have stayed in Ukraine to fight.  They like to stay close at hand.  They want to go back, they want to be reunited with their husbands, with their brothers, with their sons.  And once they’re in Europe, they also have a lot of freedom of movement and the ability to reunite with other family members there.</p>
<p>Having said that, President Biden made clear that we will welcome 100,000 Ukrainians.  We’re ‑‑</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Is there a time frame?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So it’s over a period of time.  What we’re doing right now is looking at what are the legal pathways that we can do that because there’s the normal refugee program, but that, by definition, takes a long time.  It takes a couple years –</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Quick question before we lose time: sanctions.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Yeah.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  New sanctions, now Europe is putting on new sanctions.  China and India keep buying fuel from Russia and fueling this war, helping to fund Putin’s war.  Why aren’t we sanctioning China and India?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So in the first instance, Andrea, these sanctions are having a dramatic impact.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But there are big loopholes, and Europe still is buying natural gas and still will for another year.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  There are loopholes that, piece by piece, one by one, we’re trying to close.  Sometimes that takes time.  But let’s look at what’s already happened.  The sanctions cumulatively have put the Russian economy into a deep recession.  And what we’re seeing is a likely contraction of the Russian economy by about 15 percent.  That is dramatic.  We’ve seen something else.  We’ve seen an exodus from Russia of virtually every major company in the world.  And Putin, in the space of a matter of weeks, has basically shut down Russia to the world.  All of the opening, all of the opportunity that took place over the last 30 years is gone.  And the Russians will feel that, I’m afraid, in their daily lives.  They won’t be able to buy the things they’re used to buying, and they won’t be able to afford to buy what they’d like to buy.</p>
<p>And beyond that, the export controls that we put in place, denying Russia the technology that it needs to modernize critical industries like defense, like energy extraction – over time, those are going to have an even greater impact.</p>
<p>So we’re already seeing a dramatic impact to this.  And yes, there are places where different countries are doing different things.  We’re working every single day to close that down.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Quick question on Iran before I let you go.  You’re talking about Iran here in Brussels.  Is Iran’s Revolutionary Guard – which has attacked Americans and our allies – a terrorist organization?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So, they are.  And &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will they continue to be?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I’m not going to get into the details of where we are on the negotiations.  I would say simply that I’m not overly optimistic at the prospects of actually getting an agreement to conclusion, despite all the efforts we put into it and despite the fact that I believe we would be – our security would be better off.  We’re not there.  We’ll have to see if we can close &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Is time running out?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  And time is getting extremely short.  But this is something that we’ll be talking to our European partners about this afternoon and then over the course of the next day.  We’ve been working in very close coordination with the Europeans, with the European Union, with France, with Germany, with the UK.</p>
<p>So we’ll see where we get.  I continue to believe it would be in the best interests of our country if we can get back into compliance with the deal, if Iran will do the same.  We’re not there.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  Thanks for your patience.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks, Andrea.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Good to see you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  You as well.  Thanks.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Mr. Secretary, thank you so much for being with us.  I wanted to ask you about what is going on right now.  The chairman of the Joint Chiefs had told Congress that this will likely last years, this war.  A protracted war is going to last years, according to the chairman of the Joint Chiefs.  Will today’s new commitment of Javelins, anti-tank weapons to Ukraine shorten that timeline?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Andrea, we want to see this come to an end as quickly as possible, and that’s exactly why we’re making sure that we’re doing everything we can to support Ukraine and to give them the assistance that they need to put pressure and to increase pressure on Russia, even as we’re strengthening our – the defenses of our NATO Alliance.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So what about the Javelins?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So the Javelins, we just did – the President authorized another $100 million in a drawdown that will provide more Javelins to our Ukrainian partners.  Put this in perspective:  Between the United States and other allies and partners, for every Russian tank in Ukraine, we have provided or will soon provide 10 anti-tank systems – 10 for every single Russian tank.  So in terms of what they need to act quickly and act effectively, to deal with the planes that are firing at them from the skies, the tanks that are trying to destroy their cities from the ground, they have the tools that they need, they’re going to keep getting them, and we’re going to keep sustaining that.</p>
<p>But to the chairman’s point, and the President said this as well, as much as we want to see this come to an end as soon as possible to stop the death and destruction that’s being wrought by Russia in Ukraine, there is also a very likely scenario by which this goes on for some time.  The Russians, even as they’re moving their forces, they’ve retreated from Kyiv, they’ve retreated from the north and the west, they’re consolidating forces in the east, in the Donbas.  They have a lot of force still left.  The Ukrainians have something else that’s ultimately stronger, and that is a fierce determination and will to defend their country with the support of many countries around the world.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Can they win?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So ultimately, yes, because what is success, what is victory?  It’s holding on to the sovereignty and independence of their country.  And there is no scenario by which over time that will not happen.  The problem is it may take time, and in the meantime, tremendous death and destruction.  But what is so powerful here is that the Ukrainians have made it very clear that they will not subjugate themselves to Vladimir Putin’s will.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But no matter how much we give them, how can Ukraine ever last against Russia for the long term unless the U.S. and other countries guarantee its borders, its safety, as President Zelenskyy wants?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, first things first.  The first thing is to see that this aggression by Russia comes to an end, that there is a ceasefire, that Russia withdraws its forces, that Ukraine asserts its sovereignty and its independence.  But then, yes, we have to do things to make sure that, to the best of our ability and Ukraine’s ability, this can’t happen again, that Russia is deterred, that Ukraine is defended.  We’re having constant conversations with &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will we guarantee that?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So we’re having &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will the U.S. get more involved?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We’re having constant conversations with our Ukrainian partners pretty much on a daily basis, including about what it is we and others could do in the event of a successful negotiation to defend them and help them defend themselves going forward.  All of this is the subject of conversations right now.  I’m not going to get ahead of that, but we’re going to do everything we can, others will do what they can to make sure that Ukraine can defend itself and deter aggression being repeated by Russia.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  President Putin has said he wants to recreate the Soviet Union, the glory of the Soviet Union.  With those ambitions, how can Ukraine ever be safe as long as Putin’s in power?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, two things:  First, in terms of what Russia set out to do, what Putin set out to do in Ukraine, this has already been a strategic setback, if not a failure.  Because keep in mind, Andrea, the goal that Putin set in his own words was to eliminate Ukraine’s sovereignty and independence.  He sees it as a state that doesn’t deserve to be independent, that needs to be subsumed back into some kind of greater Russia.  That is not happening, not just the retreat from Kyiv but the fact that no matter how you play this out the Ukrainians are not going to subject themselves to a Russian dictatorship.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  He’s more popular than ever at home.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So he may be for now more popular.  Of course, if you were getting fed a steady diet, morning, noon, and night of propaganda, which unfortunately the Russian people are, that speaks to what popularity he has.  At the same time, when people are responding to polls, they may be very much afraid of giving the truthful answer.  There’s now a 15-year criminal penalty for anyone who in any way opposes the so-called special military operation.  So you have to take that with a grain of salt.</p>
<p>Having said that, I think there is a real fundamental problem, which is the Russians don’t get the factual information that they need to make judgments for themselves, and that’s because of a system that Vladimir Putin has perfected in which that information is denied them.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  President Biden has called Putin a butcher, a war criminal.  You have said that the people responsible for the crimes in Bucha and those who ordered them will be held accountable.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  That’s right.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  How can that happen without Vladimir Putin standing trial?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  First, Andrea, the wheels of accountability can move slowly, but they move, and someday, someway, somewhere, those who committed these crimes and those who ordered the crimes will be held accountable.  But it takes time, and part of this is building the case, part of this is – which we’re doing and others are doing.  Part – there’s a Ukrainian special prosecutor who is working on this.  We’re supporting her efforts.  We set up at the United Nations at the Human Rights Council a Commission of Inquiry that’s looking into this as well.  We’re supporting those efforts, building the case, getting the evidence, documenting it.  The International Criminal Court is looking at this too.</p>
<p>But all of this will play out over time, and we have to build the case, we have to get the evidence, we have to document it – we’re doing all of that.  So is that next month, next year, in five years?  It could take time, but I think – I can guarantee you there will be a relentless effort to make sure that those responsible for what we’re seeing are held accountable.  And what we’re seeing, Andrea, is I think beyond what any of us even could fully anticipate.  We said before Russia committed this aggression that there would be atrocities, that it was a deliberate part of their campaign.  And even knowing that, when this Russian tide receded from Bucha and we saw the death and destruction left in its wake, and we saw what that looked like, including people who had been assassinated – and in fact, their hands tied – executed, their hands tied behind their backs – the abuse committed against women, against children, it’s horrific.  And there has to be accountability for it.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Did you see the video that President Zelenskyy provided to the United Nations, or other images from Bucha?  As you describe it, the atrocities, you have small children.  What do you tell your children?  What would you tell them?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, thankfully, they’re too small to actually see that, be able to digest it and to understand it.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But some day, they’ll – they will &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  But some day they will.  And I have to tell you, Andrea, I think – and I suspect most of us have the same reaction, especially those of who have children or even small children – you put yourself in the shoes of the father, the mother, the grandfather, the grandmother who’s in the middle of this, who is suffering this, whose kids’ lives are at stake or in jeopardy, or who have been lost.  And it hits you – I said the other day, seeing these images from Bucha was like a punch to the gut.  It takes the wind out of you.  You can know something intellectually, but then when you see these images and you translate that into your own life, when you ask yourself, “What if this was happening in my town, to my kids?  To my family?”  I think it only reinforces our determination to do everything we can to support the Ukrainians, to put pressure on Russia, to bring this to an end as quickly as possible.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Your UN ambassador, Linda Thomas-Greenfield, described these atrocities and compared it by extension to the Holocaust.  Talked about what the council in Mariupol had described, people forcibly – tens of thousands – taken from their homes, taken to Russia and put in camps.  Isn’t that the very definition of genocide?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, we have to get all of the information, all of the evidence.  We have to, as I said, document everything that’s happened, fully understand what’s happened.  It’s an interesting irony in a sense.  This is in some ways the most documented war in real time that we’ve experienced because of technology, because of smart phones, because of the incredible courage of reporters who remained in Ukraine.  But even so, the things that we’re not seeing in real time, including Bucha – and it’s only when that tide recedes that you see what’s actually happened.</p>
<p>So I think we’re going to learn a lot more in the days and weeks ahead.  I’m afraid that what we’re going to learn is even more horrifying.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Do we know anything about what’s happening in these Russian camps with Ukrainians, and do we have any hope of getting them back?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We don’t have good information on that, but certainly we’re doing everything we can.  Other countries are doing everything they can to make sure that anyone who is being detained is released.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  The U.S. has promised to take in 100,000 of these millions of refugees.  Europe has opened their doors, put them in their homes.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  They have.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  NBC has reported on at least two women, two Ukrainian women on the southern border, who were taken and for two weeks put behind barbed wire and at times shackled in an ICE camp.  How can we do that compared to the way Europe is welcoming them?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, I’m not aware of those reports.  It’s something I’ll certainly look into.  But here’s what’s going on.  First, Europeans have been extraordinary in their generosity, in opening their hearts, opening their arms, opening their homes to so many people.  Our friends in Poland, in the first instance, have had more than 2 million people come through Poland.  Many of the refugees – most of them, in fact – want to stay close to home because what you’re seeing, Andrea – and I know you’ve seen this firsthand – is virtually everyone is a woman and children.  Most of the men between 18 and 60 have stayed in Ukraine to fight.  They like to stay close at hand.  They want to go back, they want to be reunited with their husbands, with their brothers, with their sons.  And once they’re in Europe, they also have a lot of freedom of movement and the ability to reunite with other family members there.</p>
<p>Having said that, President Biden made clear that we will welcome 100,000 Ukrainians.  We’re ‑‑</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Is there a time frame?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So it’s over a period of time.  What we’re doing right now is looking at what are the legal pathways that we can do that because there’s the normal refugee program, but that, by definition, takes a long time.  It takes a couple years –</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Quick question before we lose time: sanctions.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Yeah.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  New sanctions, now Europe is putting on new sanctions.  China and India keep buying fuel from Russia and fueling this war, helping to fund Putin’s war.  Why aren’t we sanctioning China and India?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So in the first instance, Andrea, these sanctions are having a dramatic impact.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But there are big loopholes, and Europe still is buying natural gas and still will for another year.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  There are loopholes that, piece by piece, one by one, we’re trying to close.  Sometimes that takes time.  But let’s look at what’s already happened.  The sanctions cumulatively have put the Russian economy into a deep recession.  And what we’re seeing is a likely contraction of the Russian economy by about 15 percent.  That is dramatic.  We’ve seen something else.  We’ve seen an exodus from Russia of virtually every major company in the world.  And Putin, in the space of a matter of weeks, has basically shut down Russia to the world.  All of the opening, all of the opportunity that took place over the last 30 years is gone.  And the Russians will feel that, I’m afraid, in their daily lives.  They won’t be able to buy the things they’re used to buying, and they won’t be able to afford to buy what they’d like to buy.</p>
<p>And beyond that, the export controls that we put in place, denying Russia the technology that it needs to modernize critical industries like defense, like energy extraction – over time, those are going to have an even greater impact.</p>
<p>So we’re already seeing a dramatic impact to this.  And yes, there are places where different countries are doing different things.  We’re working every single day to close that down.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Quick question on Iran before I let you go.  You’re talking about Iran here in Brussels.  Is Iran’s Revolutionary Guard – which has attacked Americans and our allies – a terrorist organization?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So, they are.  And &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will they continue to be?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I’m not going to get into the details of where we are on the negotiations.  I would say simply that I’m not overly optimistic at the prospects of actually getting an agreement to conclusion, despite all the efforts we put into it and despite the fact that I believe we would be – our security would be better off.  We’re not there.  We’ll have to see if we can close &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Is time running out?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  And time is getting extremely short.  But this is something that we’ll be talking to our European partners about this afternoon and then over the course of the next day.  We’ve been working in very close coordination with the Europeans, with the European Union, with France, with Germany, with the UK.</p>
<p>So we’ll see where we get.  I continue to believe it would be in the best interests of our country if we can get back into compliance with the deal, if Iran will do the same.  We’re not there.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  Thanks for your patience.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks, Andrea.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Good to see you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  You as well.  Thanks.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Australian Foreign Minister Marise Payne Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-australian-foreign-minister-marise-payne-before-their-meeting-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 15:02:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=331987</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p>The Hotel</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  I’ll just say very quickly what a pleasure it is to see my friend and colleague Marise Payne.  We’ve spent a fair bit of time together in various parts of the world &#8212;</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER PAYNE:</b>  We’re here.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  &#8212; but it’s very good to see you here in Brussels.  We’re excited at the prospect of bringing some of our partners from the Asia Pacific together with NATO – that’s certainly part of what we’re doing here together – but also a lot of work that we’re following up on that we’ve been doing together in the region through AUKUS, and many other initiatives that we’re engaged in, and of course, the situation resulting from Russia’s aggression in Ukraine.</p>
<p>So, lots to catch up on.  Great to see you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER PAYNE:  </b>Indeed.  Great to be here too, Tony, with our team.  We’ve just arrived, as you noted, but importantly, at this critical time, a critical time for partners like Australia and the United States to be closely joined in response to the actions of authoritarian states that are untenable, unacceptable, complete illegal violations, wholesale violations of international law and the UN Charter.  So coming here this week is extremely important for Australia to join with the United States and our partners in that response to make sure that we are working in as coordinated and comprehensive a way as possible.</p>
<p>So I’m looking forward to those discussions, and also to reinforcing the importance that no matter where in the world they behave like this, authoritarian states cannot be allowed to trample on the rights of democratic countries and on the people who have chosen to live and work in those democracies.  So it is a very important engagement.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p>The Hotel</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  I’ll just say very quickly what a pleasure it is to see my friend and colleague Marise Payne.  We’ve spent a fair bit of time together in various parts of the world &#8212;</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER PAYNE:</b>  We’re here.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  &#8212; but it’s very good to see you here in Brussels.  We’re excited at the prospect of bringing some of our partners from the Asia Pacific together with NATO – that’s certainly part of what we’re doing here together – but also a lot of work that we’re following up on that we’ve been doing together in the region through AUKUS, and many other initiatives that we’re engaged in, and of course, the situation resulting from Russia’s aggression in Ukraine.</p>
<p>So, lots to catch up on.  Great to see you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER PAYNE:  </b>Indeed.  Great to be here too, Tony, with our team.  We’ve just arrived, as you noted, but importantly, at this critical time, a critical time for partners like Australia and the United States to be closely joined in response to the actions of authoritarian states that are untenable, unacceptable, complete illegal violations, wholesale violations of international law and the UN Charter.  So coming here this week is extremely important for Australia to join with the United States and our partners in that response to make sure that we are working in as coordinated and comprehensive a way as possible.</p>
<p>So I’m looking forward to those discussions, and also to reinforcing the importance that no matter where in the world they behave like this, authoritarian states cannot be allowed to trample on the rights of democratic countries and on the people who have chosen to live and work in those democracies.  So it is a very important engagement.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
