<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 15:55:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meetings with South African Minister Pandor and Deputy Minister Botes</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meetings-with-south-african-minister-pandor-and-deputy-minister-botes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 15:55:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=340895</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman had warm and productive meetings with South African Minister of International Relations and Cooperation Naledi Pandor and Deputy Minister of International Relations and Cooperation Alvin Botes today in Pretoria.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Minister Pandor discussed the importance of the U.S.-South Africa partnership and shared priorities including health, climate, and regional and global peace and security.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Deputy Minister Botes, who was joined by Economic Advisor to President Ramaphosa Trudi Makhaya, discussed the growing partnership on mutual areas of interest, including trade, investment, and infrastructure.  Deputy Secretary Sherman also expressed condolences on the loss of life and destruction as a result of the weather disaster in KwaZulu-Natal in April.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman had warm and productive meetings with South African Minister of International Relations and Cooperation Naledi Pandor and Deputy Minister of International Relations and Cooperation Alvin Botes today in Pretoria.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Minister Pandor discussed the importance of the U.S.-South Africa partnership and shared priorities including health, climate, and regional and global peace and security.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Deputy Minister Botes, who was joined by Economic Advisor to President Ramaphosa Trudi Makhaya, discussed the growing partnership on mutual areas of interest, including trade, investment, and infrastructure.  Deputy Secretary Sherman also expressed condolences on the loss of life and destruction as a result of the weather disaster in KwaZulu-Natal in April.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with UK Foreign Secretary Truss</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-uk-foreign-secretary-truss-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 01:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=340758</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss.  The Secretary reaffirmed support for Ukraine, where the brave Ukrainian people continue to defend against the brutal attacks of Putin’s war of aggression.  The two discussed additional security and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and continued transatlantic unity.  They also discussed economic consequences for those who continue to provide financial or material support that aids the Kremlin’s war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Additionally, the Secretary raised the need to continue our collective support for combatting the COVID-19 pandemic globally and providing sustainable health security financing, including through a robust, commitments-driven summit on May 12.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss.  The Secretary reaffirmed support for Ukraine, where the brave Ukrainian people continue to defend against the brutal attacks of Putin’s war of aggression.  The two discussed additional security and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and continued transatlantic unity.  They also discussed economic consequences for those who continue to provide financial or material support that aids the Kremlin’s war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Additionally, the Secretary raised the need to continue our collective support for combatting the COVID-19 pandemic globally and providing sustainable health security financing, including through a robust, commitments-driven summit on May 12.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Mexican Foreign Secretary Ebrard</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-mexican-foreign-secretary-ebrard-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 23:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=340733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Mexican Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard in Washington, D.C. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Ebrard discussed preparations for the Summit of the Americas, U.S.-Mexico collaboration to address the root causes of irregular migration, and the importance of ensuring a strong, stable, and competitive North America.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken highlighted how the Summit of the Americas will build on the strong collaboration between the United States and Mexico, especially when it comes to the Summit themes of democracy, clean energy, climate change, technology, and pandemic resilience.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Mexican Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard in Washington, D.C. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Ebrard discussed preparations for the Summit of the Americas, U.S.-Mexico collaboration to address the root causes of irregular migration, and the importance of ensuring a strong, stable, and competitive North America.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken highlighted how the Summit of the Americas will build on the strong collaboration between the United States and Mexico, especially when it comes to the Summit themes of democracy, clean energy, climate change, technology, and pandemic resilience.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2022 U.S.-Armenia Strategic Dialogue Joint Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/2022-u-s-armenia-strategic-dialogue-joint-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 23:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=340728</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and the Republic of Armenia on the occasion of the U.S.-Armenia Strategic Dialogue.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken hosted Armenian Foreign Minister Ararat Mirzoyan in Washington, D.C., to launch the U.S.-Armenia Strategic Dialogue (USASD) on May 2, 2022. During the Dialogue, the United States and Armenia reiterated their commitment to strengthening bilateral ties across the breadth of the bilateral relationship.</p>
<p>This round of USASD discussions coincided with the 30th anniversary of the establishment of U.S.-Armenian diplomatic relations. The delegations positively assessed the status of bilateral ties and reviewed the potential for expanding our partnership. The Armenian delegation included Deputy Minister of Justice Grigor Minasyan, Deputy Central Bank Governor Nerses Yeritsyan, and Ministry of Defense officials. Assistant Secretary of State for European and Eurasian Affairs Dr. Karen Donfried and several leaders from throughout the Departments of State and Defense also participated in the USASD session. U.S. Ambassador to Armenia Lynne Tracy was in Washington as well, joined by Armenian Ambassador to the United States Lilit Makunts.</p>
<p><strong>Further Democratic Reforms and Promote Mutual Prosperity</strong></p>
<p>Assistant Secretary Donfried reaffirmed the United States would continue its robust assistance and cooperation to the Armenian government in building responsive democratic and economic institutions that both reflect our common values and deliver better governance and prosperity. The delegations had a robust dialogue on U.S. assistance to support Armenia’s positive democratic trajectory. This includes programs to support human rights, media literacy, social protection, justice sector reforms, and the new Patrol Police Service. The delegations also discussed advancing judicial impartiality and strengthening freedom of expression. Mechanisms to promote mutual prosperity in the economic sphere were also a key topic of discussion, including energy cooperation and workforce development to promote and deepen bilateral trade and investment.</p>
<p><strong>Towards Security, Peace, and Regional Conflict Resolution</strong></p>
<p>The two delegations discussed issues related to border security, and partnership in the defense and security sector through disaster management, defense reform, medical support, and peacekeeping. The delegations exchanged views on security matters and noted the United States’ role as a Co-Chair of the OSCE Minsk Group, which has a mandate to facilitate a peaceful resolution of the Nagorno-Karabakh conflict.</p>
<p><strong>Looking To Tangible Results</strong></p>
<p>Minister Mirzoyan and the Armenian delegation also had constructive meetings with USAID Administrator Samantha Power, Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland, and many others. During their time in Washington, delegation members signed a number of documents, including a Nuclear Cooperation Memorandum of Understanding that will serve as a mechanism through which our governments can develop stronger ties between our nuclear experts, industries, and researchers. The United States and Armenia also signed two joint action plans on anti-corruption and law enforcement reforms.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and the Republic of Armenia on the occasion of the U.S.-Armenia Strategic Dialogue.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken hosted Armenian Foreign Minister Ararat Mirzoyan in Washington, D.C., to launch the U.S.-Armenia Strategic Dialogue (USASD) on May 2, 2022. During the Dialogue, the United States and Armenia reiterated their commitment to strengthening bilateral ties across the breadth of the bilateral relationship.</p>
<p>This round of USASD discussions coincided with the 30th anniversary of the establishment of U.S.-Armenian diplomatic relations. The delegations positively assessed the status of bilateral ties and reviewed the potential for expanding our partnership. The Armenian delegation included Deputy Minister of Justice Grigor Minasyan, Deputy Central Bank Governor Nerses Yeritsyan, and Ministry of Defense officials. Assistant Secretary of State for European and Eurasian Affairs Dr. Karen Donfried and several leaders from throughout the Departments of State and Defense also participated in the USASD session. U.S. Ambassador to Armenia Lynne Tracy was in Washington as well, joined by Armenian Ambassador to the United States Lilit Makunts.</p>
<p><strong>Further Democratic Reforms and Promote Mutual Prosperity</strong></p>
<p>Assistant Secretary Donfried reaffirmed the United States would continue its robust assistance and cooperation to the Armenian government in building responsive democratic and economic institutions that both reflect our common values and deliver better governance and prosperity. The delegations had a robust dialogue on U.S. assistance to support Armenia’s positive democratic trajectory. This includes programs to support human rights, media literacy, social protection, justice sector reforms, and the new Patrol Police Service. The delegations also discussed advancing judicial impartiality and strengthening freedom of expression. Mechanisms to promote mutual prosperity in the economic sphere were also a key topic of discussion, including energy cooperation and workforce development to promote and deepen bilateral trade and investment.</p>
<p><strong>Towards Security, Peace, and Regional Conflict Resolution</strong></p>
<p>The two delegations discussed issues related to border security, and partnership in the defense and security sector through disaster management, defense reform, medical support, and peacekeeping. The delegations exchanged views on security matters and noted the United States’ role as a Co-Chair of the OSCE Minsk Group, which has a mandate to facilitate a peaceful resolution of the Nagorno-Karabakh conflict.</p>
<p><strong>Looking To Tangible Results</strong></p>
<p>Minister Mirzoyan and the Armenian delegation also had constructive meetings with USAID Administrator Samantha Power, Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland, and many others. During their time in Washington, delegation members signed a number of documents, including a Nuclear Cooperation Memorandum of Understanding that will serve as a mechanism through which our governments can develop stronger ties between our nuclear experts, industries, and researchers. The United States and Armenia also signed two joint action plans on anti-corruption and law enforcement reforms.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement Through the Global Partnership for Action on Gender-Based Online Harassment and Abuse on World Press Freedom Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-through-the-global-partnership-for-action-on-gender-based-online-harassment-and-abuse-on-world-press-freedom-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 23:31:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=340718</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America, Australia, Denmark, Republic of Korea, Sweden, and the United Kingdom.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>Today, on World Press Freedom Day 2022, the undersigned foreign ministers for country members of the Global Partnership for Action on Gender-Based Online Harassment and Abuse call attention to the pressing need for enhanced safety of women journalists and media workers.</p>
<p>Women in journalism are disproportionately impacted by threats and attacks, which are more often gendered and sexualized than threats against their male counterparts and increasingly take place online. Many women journalists face multiple and intersecting forms of discrimination and sexual and gender-based violence, including on the basis of other characteristics, including race, religion, ethnicity, disability, sexual orientation, or gender identity. The latest study from 2020 (UNESCO) shows that almost 75 percent of women journalists worldwide have experienced online violence.</p>
<p>Social media is a critical avenue for journalists and media organizations to engage their audiences, but it is also a vector of online harms.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the escalation of technology-facilitated gender-based violence is of urgent concern and forms a serious threat to an inclusive and diverse media landscape. It is a risk to media pluralism and democracy. Online threats to women journalists and media workers can lead to self-censorship and disengagement from the digital public square, undermining their ability to exercise their human rights and enjoy freedom of expression, compounding the forms of violence they face offline. All people – including women – should be able to speak out without fear of harassment, discrimination, or violence. There is also in many places a culture of impunity surrounding online attacks on women journalists and media workers, which perpetuates the cycle of gender-based violence.</p>
<p>Today, we call upon all states, media companies, workplaces, technology platforms and civil society groups to speak out against technology-facilitated gender-based violence, to prevent and address all forms of violence against women journalists and media workers, both online and offline, and defend their ability to practice journalism freely and safely.</p>
<p>Co-signatories:</p>
<ul>
<li>Australia Minister for Foreign Affairs and Minister for Women, Senator the Hon Marise Payne;</li>
<li>Danish Minister of Foreign Affairs, Mr. Jeppe Kofod;</li>
<li>Republic of Korea Minister of Foreign Affairs Mr. Chung Eui-yong;</li>
<li>Sweden Minister for Foreign Affairs, Ms. Ann Linde;</li>
<li>United Kingdom’s Secretary of State for Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Affairs and Minister for Women and Equalities, Rt Hon Liz Truss;</li>
<li>United States Secretary of State, Antony J. Blinken.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America, Australia, Denmark, Republic of Korea, Sweden, and the United Kingdom.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>Today, on World Press Freedom Day 2022, the undersigned foreign ministers for country members of the Global Partnership for Action on Gender-Based Online Harassment and Abuse call attention to the pressing need for enhanced safety of women journalists and media workers.</p>
<p>Women in journalism are disproportionately impacted by threats and attacks, which are more often gendered and sexualized than threats against their male counterparts and increasingly take place online. Many women journalists face multiple and intersecting forms of discrimination and sexual and gender-based violence, including on the basis of other characteristics, including race, religion, ethnicity, disability, sexual orientation, or gender identity. The latest study from 2020 (UNESCO) shows that almost 75 percent of women journalists worldwide have experienced online violence.</p>
<p>Social media is a critical avenue for journalists and media organizations to engage their audiences, but it is also a vector of online harms.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the escalation of technology-facilitated gender-based violence is of urgent concern and forms a serious threat to an inclusive and diverse media landscape. It is a risk to media pluralism and democracy. Online threats to women journalists and media workers can lead to self-censorship and disengagement from the digital public square, undermining their ability to exercise their human rights and enjoy freedom of expression, compounding the forms of violence they face offline. All people – including women – should be able to speak out without fear of harassment, discrimination, or violence. There is also in many places a culture of impunity surrounding online attacks on women journalists and media workers, which perpetuates the cycle of gender-based violence.</p>
<p>Today, we call upon all states, media companies, workplaces, technology platforms and civil society groups to speak out against technology-facilitated gender-based violence, to prevent and address all forms of violence against women journalists and media workers, both online and offline, and defend their ability to practice journalism freely and safely.</p>
<p>Co-signatories:</p>
<ul>
<li>Australia Minister for Foreign Affairs and Minister for Women, Senator the Hon Marise Payne;</li>
<li>Danish Minister of Foreign Affairs, Mr. Jeppe Kofod;</li>
<li>Republic of Korea Minister of Foreign Affairs Mr. Chung Eui-yong;</li>
<li>Sweden Minister for Foreign Affairs, Ms. Ann Linde;</li>
<li>United Kingdom’s Secretary of State for Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Affairs and Minister for Women and Equalities, Rt Hon Liz Truss;</li>
<li>United States Secretary of State, Antony J. Blinken.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Keynote Remarks at the 52nd Annual Conference on the Americas Luncheon</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-keynote-remarks-at-the-52nd-annual-conference-on-the-americas-luncheon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 23:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=340715</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room</p>
<p><strong>MR GLUSKI:</strong>  Well, Mr. Secretary, this is the second time I’ve had the pleasure of introducing you at the Washington conference.  But a year ago, we were all online, and most of us were still stuck at home, so I’m going to venture that this will be an even better experience for all of us.</p>
<p>In the year that you’ve – since you’ve last joined us, a lot has happened, to say the least.  It seems almost like another era.  But what hasn’t changed is your commitment to building bridges with our hemisphere, and I know that mandate comes straight from President Biden.</p>
<p>Perhaps even more significant for our region than what has gone before is what’s coming up next.  Next month, you will join President Biden as he hosts the ninth Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles.  As this is the first time the U.S. is hosting the Summit of the Americas since 1994, it would already be consequential.  But with the health and economic consequences of a pandemic, Russia’s brutal and unprovoked attack on Ukraine, and the growing threat to free and democratic societies from China and other authoritarian governments, there has never been a more important time for the United States to lead our hemisphere in reinforcing our shared principles of democracy, rule of law, and free and fair trade.</p>
<p>Beyond the opportunity to defend these core principles, the summit will also offer the opportunity to expand our partnership with leaders in the Americas, to take full advantage of the digital future, to protect the environment and address climate change, and to ensure growth that is equitable and sustainable.</p>
<p>We at the Council of the Americas have been steadfast partners of the State Department since our founding, almost 60 years ago.  And we look forward to partnering with you and President Biden at this historic event.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, we all know that you have a great deal on your plate these days.  We take your presence here today as a strong confirmation of the importance that you personally place on the U.S. partnership in the hemisphere.  We look forward to hearing your vision for the U.S. relations with the Americas.</p>
<p>My fellow council members and guests, please join me in welcoming the United States Secretary of State Antony Blinken.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Andres, thank you so much for the introduction, for your good words today, and for your leadership every day on something that we both care about deeply.  And to you, President Segal, Eric Farnsworth – an old colleague and friend – it’s wonderful to be here today with all of you.  To the supporters of the council’s critically important work, thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>
<p>We have – everyone is quite literally a distinguished guest around these tables, so at the risk of causing offense to everyone else, I do want to just mention a couple of other people who I see here before me and want to acknowledge.  First of all, our extraordinary ambassador to Mexico, Ken Salazar, it’s great to be with you today.  (Applause.)  And to a friend of many years, who’s been a leader of this institution, who knows this room and these halls so well, John Negroponte.  John.  (Applause.)  And I’m looking around to see – I think Bill Hagerty is here.  Bill, are you here, in fact?  He was here before, so I wanted to acknowledge him, and a great colleague in the Senate and a great leader in our own hemisphere as well as in the Asia Pacific as well.</p>
<p>It’s also wonderful to be here with each of you today because we’re getting back to something approximating normal, including using this room, which is my favorite room in the department, the Ben Franklin Room.  And John spent many an hour here as well.  And it’s very apt, in some ways, that we’re here in this room.  Ben Franklin, of course, was our nation’s first diplomat.  He charted the Gulf Stream.  He pioneered electricity.  He authored America’s very first treaty.  He helped forge a new ethos of self-government.  And he did virtually none of this sober. (Laughter.)  So I’m not sure what the lesson to be drawn from that is, but there’s something there.  I also suspect he couldn’t get confirmed for a job, but that’s another matter.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>I also am very pleased to see an old friend and colleague, the Secretary General Almagro.  It’s wonderful to be with you.  Congratulations on your very well-deserved leadership award.  (Applause.)  Thank you.</p>
<p>And then I want to extend a very special welcome to the ambassadors from the region who are here today.  You’re at home here in the State Department.  Welcome, welcome, welcome.</p>
<p>And indeed, it’s welcome to – wonderful to welcome this council back to the State Department for the annual conference, again something we’ve not been able to do for the last couple of years.  But we are now back; you are now back.  And I’m grateful for that.</p>
<p>So as Andres said, in a little over a month, the United States will host a Summit of the Americas for the first time since that inaugural summit in 1994.  And I have to tell you, it’s a little bit of a personal bookend for me, because at the time of the Miami summit in 1994, I was a speechwriter for President Bill Clinton and got to work on the summit.  Some of the things he said at the summit actually may have reflected some of the things I put into the speeches, and it’s a very strong and early memory of my time working for President Clinton.</p>
<p>My memory is – and we fact-checked this in the archives – the early drafts that we produced for President Clinton received a fairly healthy amount of editing from the president and others, but clearly to the benefit of the speeches and clearly to the benefit of the summit.  But this is very much a homecoming, and I am so glad that we have the summit back in the United States.</p>
<p>As with so many who took part in that first summit in ’94, Miami left a lasting impression on me – capturing the enthusiasm of the moment, the promise of the democratic aspirations of the region that we share, promise that we still very much see.  And today what I’d like to do is just to set out a little bit how the Biden administration will use the forthcoming Summit of the Americas to continue building on that promise.</p>
<p>Now, it’s no secret to anyone in this room that the summit comes at a challenging time for the region.  COVID-19 has taken the lives of 2.7 million men, women, and children in our hemisphere.  That accounts for more than 40 percent of global reported deaths.  It’s the highest per capita loss of any region in the world.  The pandemic has also inflicted massive economic harm throughout the region – job losses, declining income, rising poverty.  And it has had massive social implications: we have seen fewer kids in school, more youth out of work, and a ravaging of the public health sector.</p>
<p>Now, with the Russian Government’s brutal war of aggression on Ukraine, many of these preexisting problems, these preexisting conditions, have been made worse, raising the price of essential commodities throughout the Americas, from fertilizer to wheat to petroleum, cutting off key export markets for many industries in the Americas, and forcing households across the region to make very wrenching choices as the cost of living skyrockets.  So all of this is very much felt and is very much present.</p>
<p>These are just some of the short-term headwinds that we have to deal with.  They come atop longstanding challenges.  We know in many parts of the hemisphere that we share there remains a lack of economic opportunity and inequity.  An accelerating climate crisis, widespread violence and insecurity, endemic corruption, declining trust in government – all problems that are leading people across the Americas to leave home in search of places where they have a better shot of providing for their loved ones, even if the journey comes with the most profound risks.</p>
<p>One of my colleagues at one of the meetings we were having some months ago talked about this phenomenon, the extraordinary migration that we’re dealing with not only in our own hemisphere but around the world.  And she talked about the need to try to establish what she called a right to remain.  And creating for the conditions for that right to remain are something that I think all of us need to be thinking about and working on together.</p>
<p>Now, in the face of what are incredibly serious challenges, it’s easy to lose sight of the fact that for the vast majority of countries in our hemisphere, there is still a strong agreement on the best way to address these challenges, and that’s through democracy.  That’s not because democracy has a perfect track record, of course.  It doesn’t.  It’s because citizens across the region still believe that they should be the ones to chart the path of their nations.</p>
<p>Yet, as every government participating in the summit knows, we can’t take the democratic character of this region for granted.  It’s not inevitable.  It depends fundamentally on people’s continued belief that they can improve the system from within – as we say here in the United States, that we can work together to form a more perfect union.  And to keep that faith, we have to show people that democracies can do better, that they can deliver what people want and what people need.</p>
<p>I think that requires learning from our experience in the nearly three decades since that first Summit of the Americas in 1994.  So what I’d like to do quickly is to just share a few thoughts about some of the important lessons that might inform our actions going into next month’s summit, lessons that we might take from the experience of the last few decades.</p>
<p>First, we should avoid falling into blocks of left and right, liberal and conservative, and instead focus on what actually brings us together as democracies.  That means recognizing our shared interest in strengthening the pillars of our fellow free and open societies like the rule of law, like respect for human rights, like free and fair elections, a vibrant, independent press, which is front and center in my mind today.  This is actually World Press Freedom Day, which we started out by going over to the Foreign Press Center and talking to reporters from around the world, many of whom are quite literally putting their lives in danger to try to bring the facts, to try to bring information, to try and bring the truth to people around the world.</p>
<p>This approach that’s resisting labels of left and right, liberal and conservative, but instead is focusing on the common fundamental principles that bring us together, that’s the approach that we’ve been taking, including at the recent Summit for Democracy that President Biden convened late last year.  Twenty-six countries from the Americas took part in the summit.  That accounts for more than a quarter of all the participants in the Summit for Democracy.  Every one of those countries showed up with concrete commitments to make their democracies stronger – Trinidad and Tobago to increase transparency in public spending, Costa Rica pledging to expand an effective community-based violence prevention program.  The list goes on.  But in each of these ways, we’re making an effort to demonstrate that democracies can effectively produce more and better results for people across a wide spectrum of activities.</p>
<p>Second, there was tremendous enthusiasm in 1994 for the ability of open markets and free trade to create broad-based opportunity and improve conditions of workers across the hemisphere.  And this past decade has seen remarkable growth across the region, millions more people lifted out of poverty and into the possibility of being part of the global middle class.  But I suspect everyone in this room knows very well that growth also brought some downsides, notably immense inequality, including right here in the United States.  Instead, a lot of the disillusionment citizens in the Americas feel with democracy is a result of this gap between what democracies promised and what they’ve delivered, notably in the concrete standard of living that people have been experiencing.  The gap, as President Clinton framed it in 1994, between <em>deechos</em> and <em>hechos</em>, words and deeds.  And this is a gap we always, always have to mind if we want to make sure that we have sustained support for what we’re doing.</p>
<p>The answer, of course, is not to give up on free markets and trade, but to set the terms of trade and investment in ways that benefit all citizens, not just those on the very top:  eliminating the barriers that keep small business from joining the formal economy; combating the corruption that robs the resources and energy of innovators and communities alike; broadening access to emerging technologies that are increasingly crucial to actually doing business – something that we’ll drive at at the upcoming summit with the first-ever regional agenda for digital transformation.</p>
<p>In my judgment, we also have to do more to reinforce social safety nets, because even the most effective economic policies are not going to benefit all communities at the same time.  We have to be there for those who are left behind.</p>
<p>Delivering growth with equity also demands tapping into one of the most powerful engines for opportunity in the Americas: the private sector.  And I would start by saying the U.S. private sector.  The United States is already the top trading partner for more than two-thirds of the hemisphere’s countries.  In 2019, U.S. foreign direct investment in the Americas totaled $1.3 trillion dollars.  U.S. trade with countries in the region totals $1.5 trillion every year – more, by far, than any other country in the world.</p>
<p>And it’s not just the volume that’s so significant.  It’s how the United States invests that matters:  openly, transparently, with respect for labor and human rights; in a way that’s sustainable for the environment and without piling debt upon countries that they can’t afford to get out from under.</p>
<p>At the same time, our diplomats are working to raise the standards of investment in countries around the hemisphere – so that this approach becomes the rule, not the exception.</p>
<p>Consider the Call to Action for an investment in Central America that Vice President Harris launched in December, and that’s already raised more than $1.2 billion in commitments from the U.S. private sector.</p>
<p>As part of this call, Parkdale Mills, one of the world’s major providers of cotton consumer products, committed $150 million to building a new facility in Honduras.  This investment is going to help shift production of a million pounds of yarn per week from Asia to the Americas, increasing regional supply, increasing resilience of supply, while also supporting approximately a thousand new, good-paying jobs between Honduras and the United States.  And that’s just one example of what is possible.</p>
<p>We also have to close another gap in our economic development approach – and that “we” when I say “we have to close that gap,” that includes the United States and leading multilateral institutions active in the region.  That is, we have to do more to meet the region’s and reach the region’s middle-income economies.</p>
<p>There is something of another kind of middle-income trap that I know many of our closest neighbors experience: countries that are not quite developed enough to qualify for membership in groups like the G20 or the OECD, and yet too developed to qualify for aid from institutions like the Inter-American Development Bank and the World Bank.  Even modest increases in public investment in these countries will go a long way toward stimulating more private investment in their economies.  And we’re looking at other ways to deal with this trap.  This is something that I’ve heard again and again from colleagues throughout the hemisphere.  And countries that have been on the front line of being ravaged by COVID or climate – we need to find more effective ways to make sure that they have the resources necessary to deal with these challenges.</p>
<p>The same is true, I’d say, for the investments that we make within countries, so that we can support growth not only from the bottom up, but also from the middle out.  That means doing more to stimulate investment in the region’s working class – the entrepreneurs, women- and minority-led small enterprises, and others who are ready to grow their businesses but lack the capital or access to the formal economy to do so.  This has been a major focus of the U.S.  Development Finance Corporation.  It’s invested more than $10 billion in Latin America and the Caribbean, including a hundred million to help women-owned small businesses in Mexico weather the pandemic.</p>
<p>Third, we need to build greater regional resilience to make our hemisphere less vulnerable to global disruptions in the supplies that we need most and that, for many of us, we have taken for granted over many years, and now we suddenly realize the fragility in the system that we built.  This is one of the most hard-earned lessons of the pandemic.  It’s also a hard-earned lesson of Putin’s war on Ukraine.  Building this kind of resilience demands pooling our individual strengths to make our democracies stronger as a whole.</p>
<p>Now, I think we’ve made a start on that – from the supply chain working group that the United States has created with Mexico, which includes a special focus on semiconductors and information communications technology; to the work of the newly formed Alliance for Development in Democracy formed by Costa Rica, the Dominican Republic, Panama, the United States – to strengthen supply chains in the areas of health, food security, and technology.</p>
<p>Fourth, even as we stay focused on strengthening democracies from within, we need a shared approach to autocracies in the region.  And this includes continuing to support the individuals and groups in closed countries who are fighting so bravely to advance human rights and democracy, as we’ve done for decades.  We have a responsibility also to speak up and speak out collectively when we see governments weakening democracy at home, clamping down on the free press, threatening political opponents, undermining the independence of the courts.  This is another one of democracies’ inherent strengths: we believe in holding one another to account.  And that includes the United States.  And I can tell you that there is always more force and power in this and effect in this when we’re actually able to do it collectively.  And this points to, among other things, the vital role that the OAS plays and continues to play.</p>
<p>It also means taking the argument to closed countries, and to citizens across the hemisphere, about which system is actually better in delivering for its people.  In Cuba, Venezuela, more recently Nicaragua, repressive governments offer a false choice between respecting people’s rights and improving their welfare.  But the decades since that first Summit of the Americas have demonstrated that non-democratic governments in the Americas have delivered neither – and instead produced rising corruption and declining standards of living.  The debate about which system does better by the people it’s supposed to serve is one that we should welcome.  We can at once be humble about where democracy has fallen short, and confident about its stronger track record than autocracy.</p>
<p>Finally, we have to remember that there’s not a single challenge that we face in the Americas that our democracies are better off facing alone individually.  That was true in 1994.  It’s true today, maybe even more true today.  The way forward on virtually every challenge that’s affecting the lives of citizens in all of our countries is through closer collaboration, closer coordination, coming together, working together – especially when it comes to the most intractable problems, like the migration challenge, the root cause drivers of which, as we’ve seen, simply can’t be addressed by short-term fixes, and where the incentives often favor passing onto others the problems that we’re all better off tackling together as a region.</p>
<p>That’s why we’ve joined Colombia and Panama in convening a pair of ministerial meetings to foster a more candid, concrete discussion about how we can work together to support communities that are hosting large populations of migrants; creating legal, humane pathways to migration; improving border security; combating transnational criminal organizations that prey on migrants; and addressing, as we were talking about earlier, the root causes that are leaving so many people to leave their homes.  As a result of this effort, I am confident that we will get to a regional declaration on migration and protection at the upcoming summit – something that can benefit all of our countries, and especially benefit people across the region.</p>
<p>Together is the only way forward on addressing the accelerating climate crisis, which communities across the hemisphere are feeling more and more acutely.  We see the region coming together on this, too.  More countries in the Americas signed onto the Global Methane Pledge than any other region in the world – 24 and counting.  That commits them and each of us to cut global methane emissions by 30 percent by the year 2030.  If – if – the world’s major methane producers join us in meeting this pledge, this would be the equivalent of taking every plane out of the skies and every ship off the seas in terms of the emissions they produce, a dramatic step forward in trying to meet the test of dealing with climate change.</p>
<p>Together is the way forward on health security, too.  We’ve seen how weaknesses in any one country in preventing, detecting, responding to outbreaks can put people in every country at risk.  That’s why we have donated more than 67 million doses of safe, effective vaccines to countries across the Americas – free of charge, no political strings attached.  And it’s why the budget that we put forward to Congress just last week aims to double down on our investments in public health and pandemic preparedness in our hemisphere, while also seeking significant funding to continue leading the global response to COVID-19.</p>
<p>Perhaps most important, together means enlisting partners beyond our governments.  And it’s here that I’d like to conclude.</p>
<p>Of all the forces driving democratic progress in the Americas since 1994, none – in my judgment – has been more critical than the region’s vibrant, diverse, and growing civil society.  Whether those are journalists shining a light on corruption, human rights defenders documenting gross abuses, indigenous rights organizations giving voice to underserved communities – the work of these citizens has given people hope that we can still improve democracy from within, that the gap between <em>deechos</em> and <em>hechos</em> can still be closed.</p>
<p>That’s why the United States has planned the most inclusive Summit of the Americas in history, ensuring that civil society groups, leaders from the private sector will not just be included in the meetings in Los Angeles; they’ll be able to engage directly with the governments.</p>
<p>I’m confident that if we embrace this and other lessons learned since the first Summit of the Americas – focusing on what unites us as democracies rather than what divides us; ensuring not only growth, but greater equity; deepening regional resiliency in the face of shared challenges; and standing together in addressing autocracy and democratic backsliding alike – we will not only strengthen our individual democracies; we will do better at what is our number-one responsibility, and that is delivering on the fundamental needs and the fundamental hopes of all the peoples in this hemisphere that we share.</p>
<p>Thank you very much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room</p>
<p><strong>MR GLUSKI:</strong>  Well, Mr. Secretary, this is the second time I’ve had the pleasure of introducing you at the Washington conference.  But a year ago, we were all online, and most of us were still stuck at home, so I’m going to venture that this will be an even better experience for all of us.</p>
<p>In the year that you’ve – since you’ve last joined us, a lot has happened, to say the least.  It seems almost like another era.  But what hasn’t changed is your commitment to building bridges with our hemisphere, and I know that mandate comes straight from President Biden.</p>
<p>Perhaps even more significant for our region than what has gone before is what’s coming up next.  Next month, you will join President Biden as he hosts the ninth Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles.  As this is the first time the U.S. is hosting the Summit of the Americas since 1994, it would already be consequential.  But with the health and economic consequences of a pandemic, Russia’s brutal and unprovoked attack on Ukraine, and the growing threat to free and democratic societies from China and other authoritarian governments, there has never been a more important time for the United States to lead our hemisphere in reinforcing our shared principles of democracy, rule of law, and free and fair trade.</p>
<p>Beyond the opportunity to defend these core principles, the summit will also offer the opportunity to expand our partnership with leaders in the Americas, to take full advantage of the digital future, to protect the environment and address climate change, and to ensure growth that is equitable and sustainable.</p>
<p>We at the Council of the Americas have been steadfast partners of the State Department since our founding, almost 60 years ago.  And we look forward to partnering with you and President Biden at this historic event.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, we all know that you have a great deal on your plate these days.  We take your presence here today as a strong confirmation of the importance that you personally place on the U.S. partnership in the hemisphere.  We look forward to hearing your vision for the U.S. relations with the Americas.</p>
<p>My fellow council members and guests, please join me in welcoming the United States Secretary of State Antony Blinken.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Andres, thank you so much for the introduction, for your good words today, and for your leadership every day on something that we both care about deeply.  And to you, President Segal, Eric Farnsworth – an old colleague and friend – it’s wonderful to be here today with all of you.  To the supporters of the council’s critically important work, thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>
<p>We have – everyone is quite literally a distinguished guest around these tables, so at the risk of causing offense to everyone else, I do want to just mention a couple of other people who I see here before me and want to acknowledge.  First of all, our extraordinary ambassador to Mexico, Ken Salazar, it’s great to be with you today.  (Applause.)  And to a friend of many years, who’s been a leader of this institution, who knows this room and these halls so well, John Negroponte.  John.  (Applause.)  And I’m looking around to see – I think Bill Hagerty is here.  Bill, are you here, in fact?  He was here before, so I wanted to acknowledge him, and a great colleague in the Senate and a great leader in our own hemisphere as well as in the Asia Pacific as well.</p>
<p>It’s also wonderful to be here with each of you today because we’re getting back to something approximating normal, including using this room, which is my favorite room in the department, the Ben Franklin Room.  And John spent many an hour here as well.  And it’s very apt, in some ways, that we’re here in this room.  Ben Franklin, of course, was our nation’s first diplomat.  He charted the Gulf Stream.  He pioneered electricity.  He authored America’s very first treaty.  He helped forge a new ethos of self-government.  And he did virtually none of this sober. (Laughter.)  So I’m not sure what the lesson to be drawn from that is, but there’s something there.  I also suspect he couldn’t get confirmed for a job, but that’s another matter.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>I also am very pleased to see an old friend and colleague, the Secretary General Almagro.  It’s wonderful to be with you.  Congratulations on your very well-deserved leadership award.  (Applause.)  Thank you.</p>
<p>And then I want to extend a very special welcome to the ambassadors from the region who are here today.  You’re at home here in the State Department.  Welcome, welcome, welcome.</p>
<p>And indeed, it’s welcome to – wonderful to welcome this council back to the State Department for the annual conference, again something we’ve not been able to do for the last couple of years.  But we are now back; you are now back.  And I’m grateful for that.</p>
<p>So as Andres said, in a little over a month, the United States will host a Summit of the Americas for the first time since that inaugural summit in 1994.  And I have to tell you, it’s a little bit of a personal bookend for me, because at the time of the Miami summit in 1994, I was a speechwriter for President Bill Clinton and got to work on the summit.  Some of the things he said at the summit actually may have reflected some of the things I put into the speeches, and it’s a very strong and early memory of my time working for President Clinton.</p>
<p>My memory is – and we fact-checked this in the archives – the early drafts that we produced for President Clinton received a fairly healthy amount of editing from the president and others, but clearly to the benefit of the speeches and clearly to the benefit of the summit.  But this is very much a homecoming, and I am so glad that we have the summit back in the United States.</p>
<p>As with so many who took part in that first summit in ’94, Miami left a lasting impression on me – capturing the enthusiasm of the moment, the promise of the democratic aspirations of the region that we share, promise that we still very much see.  And today what I’d like to do is just to set out a little bit how the Biden administration will use the forthcoming Summit of the Americas to continue building on that promise.</p>
<p>Now, it’s no secret to anyone in this room that the summit comes at a challenging time for the region.  COVID-19 has taken the lives of 2.7 million men, women, and children in our hemisphere.  That accounts for more than 40 percent of global reported deaths.  It’s the highest per capita loss of any region in the world.  The pandemic has also inflicted massive economic harm throughout the region – job losses, declining income, rising poverty.  And it has had massive social implications: we have seen fewer kids in school, more youth out of work, and a ravaging of the public health sector.</p>
<p>Now, with the Russian Government’s brutal war of aggression on Ukraine, many of these preexisting problems, these preexisting conditions, have been made worse, raising the price of essential commodities throughout the Americas, from fertilizer to wheat to petroleum, cutting off key export markets for many industries in the Americas, and forcing households across the region to make very wrenching choices as the cost of living skyrockets.  So all of this is very much felt and is very much present.</p>
<p>These are just some of the short-term headwinds that we have to deal with.  They come atop longstanding challenges.  We know in many parts of the hemisphere that we share there remains a lack of economic opportunity and inequity.  An accelerating climate crisis, widespread violence and insecurity, endemic corruption, declining trust in government – all problems that are leading people across the Americas to leave home in search of places where they have a better shot of providing for their loved ones, even if the journey comes with the most profound risks.</p>
<p>One of my colleagues at one of the meetings we were having some months ago talked about this phenomenon, the extraordinary migration that we’re dealing with not only in our own hemisphere but around the world.  And she talked about the need to try to establish what she called a right to remain.  And creating for the conditions for that right to remain are something that I think all of us need to be thinking about and working on together.</p>
<p>Now, in the face of what are incredibly serious challenges, it’s easy to lose sight of the fact that for the vast majority of countries in our hemisphere, there is still a strong agreement on the best way to address these challenges, and that’s through democracy.  That’s not because democracy has a perfect track record, of course.  It doesn’t.  It’s because citizens across the region still believe that they should be the ones to chart the path of their nations.</p>
<p>Yet, as every government participating in the summit knows, we can’t take the democratic character of this region for granted.  It’s not inevitable.  It depends fundamentally on people’s continued belief that they can improve the system from within – as we say here in the United States, that we can work together to form a more perfect union.  And to keep that faith, we have to show people that democracies can do better, that they can deliver what people want and what people need.</p>
<p>I think that requires learning from our experience in the nearly three decades since that first Summit of the Americas in 1994.  So what I’d like to do quickly is to just share a few thoughts about some of the important lessons that might inform our actions going into next month’s summit, lessons that we might take from the experience of the last few decades.</p>
<p>First, we should avoid falling into blocks of left and right, liberal and conservative, and instead focus on what actually brings us together as democracies.  That means recognizing our shared interest in strengthening the pillars of our fellow free and open societies like the rule of law, like respect for human rights, like free and fair elections, a vibrant, independent press, which is front and center in my mind today.  This is actually World Press Freedom Day, which we started out by going over to the Foreign Press Center and talking to reporters from around the world, many of whom are quite literally putting their lives in danger to try to bring the facts, to try to bring information, to try and bring the truth to people around the world.</p>
<p>This approach that’s resisting labels of left and right, liberal and conservative, but instead is focusing on the common fundamental principles that bring us together, that’s the approach that we’ve been taking, including at the recent Summit for Democracy that President Biden convened late last year.  Twenty-six countries from the Americas took part in the summit.  That accounts for more than a quarter of all the participants in the Summit for Democracy.  Every one of those countries showed up with concrete commitments to make their democracies stronger – Trinidad and Tobago to increase transparency in public spending, Costa Rica pledging to expand an effective community-based violence prevention program.  The list goes on.  But in each of these ways, we’re making an effort to demonstrate that democracies can effectively produce more and better results for people across a wide spectrum of activities.</p>
<p>Second, there was tremendous enthusiasm in 1994 for the ability of open markets and free trade to create broad-based opportunity and improve conditions of workers across the hemisphere.  And this past decade has seen remarkable growth across the region, millions more people lifted out of poverty and into the possibility of being part of the global middle class.  But I suspect everyone in this room knows very well that growth also brought some downsides, notably immense inequality, including right here in the United States.  Instead, a lot of the disillusionment citizens in the Americas feel with democracy is a result of this gap between what democracies promised and what they’ve delivered, notably in the concrete standard of living that people have been experiencing.  The gap, as President Clinton framed it in 1994, between <em>deechos</em> and <em>hechos</em>, words and deeds.  And this is a gap we always, always have to mind if we want to make sure that we have sustained support for what we’re doing.</p>
<p>The answer, of course, is not to give up on free markets and trade, but to set the terms of trade and investment in ways that benefit all citizens, not just those on the very top:  eliminating the barriers that keep small business from joining the formal economy; combating the corruption that robs the resources and energy of innovators and communities alike; broadening access to emerging technologies that are increasingly crucial to actually doing business – something that we’ll drive at at the upcoming summit with the first-ever regional agenda for digital transformation.</p>
<p>In my judgment, we also have to do more to reinforce social safety nets, because even the most effective economic policies are not going to benefit all communities at the same time.  We have to be there for those who are left behind.</p>
<p>Delivering growth with equity also demands tapping into one of the most powerful engines for opportunity in the Americas: the private sector.  And I would start by saying the U.S. private sector.  The United States is already the top trading partner for more than two-thirds of the hemisphere’s countries.  In 2019, U.S. foreign direct investment in the Americas totaled $1.3 trillion dollars.  U.S. trade with countries in the region totals $1.5 trillion every year – more, by far, than any other country in the world.</p>
<p>And it’s not just the volume that’s so significant.  It’s how the United States invests that matters:  openly, transparently, with respect for labor and human rights; in a way that’s sustainable for the environment and without piling debt upon countries that they can’t afford to get out from under.</p>
<p>At the same time, our diplomats are working to raise the standards of investment in countries around the hemisphere – so that this approach becomes the rule, not the exception.</p>
<p>Consider the Call to Action for an investment in Central America that Vice President Harris launched in December, and that’s already raised more than $1.2 billion in commitments from the U.S. private sector.</p>
<p>As part of this call, Parkdale Mills, one of the world’s major providers of cotton consumer products, committed $150 million to building a new facility in Honduras.  This investment is going to help shift production of a million pounds of yarn per week from Asia to the Americas, increasing regional supply, increasing resilience of supply, while also supporting approximately a thousand new, good-paying jobs between Honduras and the United States.  And that’s just one example of what is possible.</p>
<p>We also have to close another gap in our economic development approach – and that “we” when I say “we have to close that gap,” that includes the United States and leading multilateral institutions active in the region.  That is, we have to do more to meet the region’s and reach the region’s middle-income economies.</p>
<p>There is something of another kind of middle-income trap that I know many of our closest neighbors experience: countries that are not quite developed enough to qualify for membership in groups like the G20 or the OECD, and yet too developed to qualify for aid from institutions like the Inter-American Development Bank and the World Bank.  Even modest increases in public investment in these countries will go a long way toward stimulating more private investment in their economies.  And we’re looking at other ways to deal with this trap.  This is something that I’ve heard again and again from colleagues throughout the hemisphere.  And countries that have been on the front line of being ravaged by COVID or climate – we need to find more effective ways to make sure that they have the resources necessary to deal with these challenges.</p>
<p>The same is true, I’d say, for the investments that we make within countries, so that we can support growth not only from the bottom up, but also from the middle out.  That means doing more to stimulate investment in the region’s working class – the entrepreneurs, women- and minority-led small enterprises, and others who are ready to grow their businesses but lack the capital or access to the formal economy to do so.  This has been a major focus of the U.S.  Development Finance Corporation.  It’s invested more than $10 billion in Latin America and the Caribbean, including a hundred million to help women-owned small businesses in Mexico weather the pandemic.</p>
<p>Third, we need to build greater regional resilience to make our hemisphere less vulnerable to global disruptions in the supplies that we need most and that, for many of us, we have taken for granted over many years, and now we suddenly realize the fragility in the system that we built.  This is one of the most hard-earned lessons of the pandemic.  It’s also a hard-earned lesson of Putin’s war on Ukraine.  Building this kind of resilience demands pooling our individual strengths to make our democracies stronger as a whole.</p>
<p>Now, I think we’ve made a start on that – from the supply chain working group that the United States has created with Mexico, which includes a special focus on semiconductors and information communications technology; to the work of the newly formed Alliance for Development in Democracy formed by Costa Rica, the Dominican Republic, Panama, the United States – to strengthen supply chains in the areas of health, food security, and technology.</p>
<p>Fourth, even as we stay focused on strengthening democracies from within, we need a shared approach to autocracies in the region.  And this includes continuing to support the individuals and groups in closed countries who are fighting so bravely to advance human rights and democracy, as we’ve done for decades.  We have a responsibility also to speak up and speak out collectively when we see governments weakening democracy at home, clamping down on the free press, threatening political opponents, undermining the independence of the courts.  This is another one of democracies’ inherent strengths: we believe in holding one another to account.  And that includes the United States.  And I can tell you that there is always more force and power in this and effect in this when we’re actually able to do it collectively.  And this points to, among other things, the vital role that the OAS plays and continues to play.</p>
<p>It also means taking the argument to closed countries, and to citizens across the hemisphere, about which system is actually better in delivering for its people.  In Cuba, Venezuela, more recently Nicaragua, repressive governments offer a false choice between respecting people’s rights and improving their welfare.  But the decades since that first Summit of the Americas have demonstrated that non-democratic governments in the Americas have delivered neither – and instead produced rising corruption and declining standards of living.  The debate about which system does better by the people it’s supposed to serve is one that we should welcome.  We can at once be humble about where democracy has fallen short, and confident about its stronger track record than autocracy.</p>
<p>Finally, we have to remember that there’s not a single challenge that we face in the Americas that our democracies are better off facing alone individually.  That was true in 1994.  It’s true today, maybe even more true today.  The way forward on virtually every challenge that’s affecting the lives of citizens in all of our countries is through closer collaboration, closer coordination, coming together, working together – especially when it comes to the most intractable problems, like the migration challenge, the root cause drivers of which, as we’ve seen, simply can’t be addressed by short-term fixes, and where the incentives often favor passing onto others the problems that we’re all better off tackling together as a region.</p>
<p>That’s why we’ve joined Colombia and Panama in convening a pair of ministerial meetings to foster a more candid, concrete discussion about how we can work together to support communities that are hosting large populations of migrants; creating legal, humane pathways to migration; improving border security; combating transnational criminal organizations that prey on migrants; and addressing, as we were talking about earlier, the root causes that are leaving so many people to leave their homes.  As a result of this effort, I am confident that we will get to a regional declaration on migration and protection at the upcoming summit – something that can benefit all of our countries, and especially benefit people across the region.</p>
<p>Together is the only way forward on addressing the accelerating climate crisis, which communities across the hemisphere are feeling more and more acutely.  We see the region coming together on this, too.  More countries in the Americas signed onto the Global Methane Pledge than any other region in the world – 24 and counting.  That commits them and each of us to cut global methane emissions by 30 percent by the year 2030.  If – if – the world’s major methane producers join us in meeting this pledge, this would be the equivalent of taking every plane out of the skies and every ship off the seas in terms of the emissions they produce, a dramatic step forward in trying to meet the test of dealing with climate change.</p>
<p>Together is the way forward on health security, too.  We’ve seen how weaknesses in any one country in preventing, detecting, responding to outbreaks can put people in every country at risk.  That’s why we have donated more than 67 million doses of safe, effective vaccines to countries across the Americas – free of charge, no political strings attached.  And it’s why the budget that we put forward to Congress just last week aims to double down on our investments in public health and pandemic preparedness in our hemisphere, while also seeking significant funding to continue leading the global response to COVID-19.</p>
<p>Perhaps most important, together means enlisting partners beyond our governments.  And it’s here that I’d like to conclude.</p>
<p>Of all the forces driving democratic progress in the Americas since 1994, none – in my judgment – has been more critical than the region’s vibrant, diverse, and growing civil society.  Whether those are journalists shining a light on corruption, human rights defenders documenting gross abuses, indigenous rights organizations giving voice to underserved communities – the work of these citizens has given people hope that we can still improve democracy from within, that the gap between <em>deechos</em> and <em>hechos</em> can still be closed.</p>
<p>That’s why the United States has planned the most inclusive Summit of the Americas in history, ensuring that civil society groups, leaders from the private sector will not just be included in the meetings in Los Angeles; they’ll be able to engage directly with the governments.</p>
<p>I’m confident that if we embrace this and other lessons learned since the first Summit of the Americas – focusing on what unites us as democracies rather than what divides us; ensuring not only growth, but greater equity; deepening regional resiliency in the face of shared challenges; and standing together in addressing autocracy and democratic backsliding alike – we will not only strengthen our individual democracies; we will do better at what is our number-one responsibility, and that is delivering on the fundamental needs and the fundamental hopes of all the peoples in this hemisphere that we share.</p>
<p>Thank you very much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Mexican Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-mexican-foreign-secretary-marcelo-ebrard-before-their-meeting-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Marcelo Ebrard, Mexican Foreign Secretary]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 20:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=340657</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Marcelo Ebrard, Mexican Foreign Secretary</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a great pleasure to be here with my colleague, my friend, Marcelo Ebrard, the foreign minister of Mexico.  We have been working together very closely since almost day one of our administration, and it’s no surprise our countries – the United States and Mexico – have a partnership that dates back many, many years.  We’re about to celebrate our – soon our 200th anniversary of diplomatic relations.  But beyond that, we are drawn together by the profound connections between our countries, and a shared agenda in our own hemisphere and around the world.</p>
<p>Of course, we’re working together closely to deal with what is an unprecedented migration challenge throughout our hemisphere, and for that matter around the world, and the collaboration with Mexico is absolutely vital.  Also vital to building, helping to build a better future and better opportunity for people throughout the Americas, which ultimately will have the greatest impact on migration in the longer run.</p>
<p>We come together to build strong North American economic competitiveness, including by building more resilient supply chains and dealing with other issues that are going to actually enhance the livelihoods of Mexicans and Americans alike.  And from energy security to climate to so many other things, we’re working hand in hand every day.</p>
<p>Finally, one of the tasks but also opportunities that we have before us – and this is the focus of conversations today – is preparing for the Summit of the Americas coming up very soon in Los Angeles, the first Summit of the Americas since 1994 – which I actually was at the very first one – hosted in the United States.  The United States and Mexico together will be working on shaping and sharing with all of our partners a strong agenda that ultimately has the goal of demonstrating that our democracies can deliver effectively for our people.</p>
<p>So I think this is a very timely moment to compare notes and to keep getting down to work.</p>
<p>Marcelo.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN SECRETARY EBRARD:</b>  Thank you.  Thank you, Antony.  How are you?  Good afternoon.</p>
<p>Thank you very much for having us this afternoon to have a meeting following the conversation past Friday between President Biden and President López Obrador.  As mentioned, we have a very close ties.  We have design about the future we share.  It’s about democracy, prosperity in the Americas.  We see the next summit as a very positive location to share those views about the future, and to start to work together not only North America, which already we have a very close ties, and we are working together; but with the rest of America, with everyone in the Americas.</p>
<p>And we are going to share in this location those views.  Also competitiveness and prosperity between Mexico and the United States and the rest of Americas, and also about the global geopolitical and economic new situations, and geopolitical risks that we should pay attention that and share views how to solve the conflicts all over the world, and strengthen stability of the multilateral  and United Nations strength in order to find peace solutions and prosperity for everyone.</p>
<p>So thank you very much, Antony.  We are going to have a meeting, and we are going to follow the conversation between President Biden and President López Obrador in the next days.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Down to work.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Marcelo Ebrard, Mexican Foreign Secretary</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a great pleasure to be here with my colleague, my friend, Marcelo Ebrard, the foreign minister of Mexico.  We have been working together very closely since almost day one of our administration, and it’s no surprise our countries – the United States and Mexico – have a partnership that dates back many, many years.  We’re about to celebrate our – soon our 200th anniversary of diplomatic relations.  But beyond that, we are drawn together by the profound connections between our countries, and a shared agenda in our own hemisphere and around the world.</p>
<p>Of course, we’re working together closely to deal with what is an unprecedented migration challenge throughout our hemisphere, and for that matter around the world, and the collaboration with Mexico is absolutely vital.  Also vital to building, helping to build a better future and better opportunity for people throughout the Americas, which ultimately will have the greatest impact on migration in the longer run.</p>
<p>We come together to build strong North American economic competitiveness, including by building more resilient supply chains and dealing with other issues that are going to actually enhance the livelihoods of Mexicans and Americans alike.  And from energy security to climate to so many other things, we’re working hand in hand every day.</p>
<p>Finally, one of the tasks but also opportunities that we have before us – and this is the focus of conversations today – is preparing for the Summit of the Americas coming up very soon in Los Angeles, the first Summit of the Americas since 1994 – which I actually was at the very first one – hosted in the United States.  The United States and Mexico together will be working on shaping and sharing with all of our partners a strong agenda that ultimately has the goal of demonstrating that our democracies can deliver effectively for our people.</p>
<p>So I think this is a very timely moment to compare notes and to keep getting down to work.</p>
<p>Marcelo.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN SECRETARY EBRARD:</b>  Thank you.  Thank you, Antony.  How are you?  Good afternoon.</p>
<p>Thank you very much for having us this afternoon to have a meeting following the conversation past Friday between President Biden and President López Obrador.  As mentioned, we have a very close ties.  We have design about the future we share.  It’s about democracy, prosperity in the Americas.  We see the next summit as a very positive location to share those views about the future, and to start to work together not only North America, which already we have a very close ties, and we are working together; but with the rest of America, with everyone in the Americas.</p>
<p>And we are going to share in this location those views.  Also competitiveness and prosperity between Mexico and the United States and the rest of Americas, and also about the global geopolitical and economic new situations, and geopolitical risks that we should pay attention that and share views how to solve the conflicts all over the world, and strengthen stability of the multilateral  and United Nations strength in order to find peace solutions and prosperity for everyone.</p>
<p>So thank you very much, Antony.  We are going to have a meeting, and we are going to follow the conversation between President Biden and President López Obrador in the next days.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Down to work.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>World Press Freedom Day 2022: State of World Press Freedom</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings-foreign-press-centers/world-press-freedom-day-2022-state-of-world-press-freedom</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 19:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=340593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington D.C. </p>
<p>Tuesday, May 3, 2022, at 11:00 am </p>
<p><strong>THE WASHINGTON FOREIGN PRESS CENTER, WASHINGTON, D.C.</strong></p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Good morning.  Welcome to the Department of State’s Washington Foreign Press Center.  My name is Ned Price; I’m the spokesperson here at the Department of State.  And I’m especially pleased to be with you here today in person, the first time we’ve been able to hold an in-person press briefing at the Foreign Press Center in over two years, since the start of COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>And it’s especially notable that we are able to do that today on World Press Freedom Day.  And it’s my distinct honor to have with us Secretary of State Blinken, who will be able to offer some remarks on World Press Freedom Day and to take your questions.  We have journalists here in person.  We also have journalists with us online.  We’ll be able to hear from both of them.</p>
<p>Before I hand the podium over to Secretary Blinken, just some quick announcements at the top.  After his opening remarks, I’ll open the floor to questions.  We’ll first take a few questions from here in the room.  Please do wait until you’re handed a microphone before you start asking your questions.  We would also ask that you keep your question brief so that we can take as many questions as we are able to.  We will then move to Zoom.  Please do raise your digital hand on the Zoom, and we will call on you from there.  We ask that you please click “raise hand” to notify that you have a question.  Please do unmute yourself before speaking, and we’ll take your question.</p>
<p>This, of course, is live-streamed.  There will be a transcript available after the fact.  And now, as I said before, it’s my distinct pleasure to introduce Secretary Blinken.  Secretary Blinken, the podium is yours.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Morning, everyone.  Ned, thank you very, very much.  And it is particularly good to be here, and I wanted to start by saying welcome, everyone, to the Foreign Press Center.  It’s been too long since those words have actually been said.  This is the first in-person event, as Ned said, that we’ve been able to have in over two years as a result of the pandemic.  And I can’t imagine a more fitting occasion than to do it on World Press Freedom Day.  So welcome back, everyone.</p>
<p>The United States has a vital stake in promoting the right to freedom of expression, including a free press, at home and also around the world.  The free flow of information, ideas, opinions, including dissenting ones, is essential to inclusive and tolerant societies.</p>
<p>A vibrant independent press is a cornerstone for any healthy democracy.  At its core is the idea that information is a public good, crucial to everything we do, to every decision that we make.  And often we trust the press with providing that information.  It’s what helps citizens understand the events, the forces that are shaping their lives.  It allows people to engage meaningfully in the political and civic spheres of their communities, their nations, and the world.</p>
<p>A free press is one of the most effective tools that we have for advancing human rights.  Whether it’s documenting unjust working conditions, corrupt or failing public services, discrimination against women and marginalized groups, abuse of security forces, accurate reporting shines a bright light on the parts of our societies that need fixing, that need to be illuminated.  That brings pressure to change, to form, as we say in the United States, a more perfect union.</p>
<p>Having said that, we meet a time when the exercise of freedom of expression, including freedom of the press, faces profound threats.  Some of these are old; some are new.  Threats that we, the United States Government, Department of State, all of us as citizens have an abiding interest in confronting, and doing so head on.</p>
<p>Just last Thursday, April 28th, journalist Vira Hyrych was killed when the apartment that she was living in was struck by the Russian military in Kyiv.  Vira is one of 11 journalists killed in Ukraine this year according to the Committee to Protect Journalists.  Many more have been wounded in conflict.  One is Fox News correspondent Ben Hall, who was seriously wounded when the car that he and his team were traveling in was struck by incoming fire on March 14th.  His cameraman, Pierre Zakrzewski, and his producer, Oleksandra Kuvshynova,  killed in this attack.</p>
<p>I know Ben well.  He’s traveled with me on many occasions since I’ve been in this job.  Thinking of him, his loved ones, the loved ones of Pierre and Oleksandra, and those of all who were killed in Ukraine.  For my part, I look very much forward to welcoming Ben back to the press corps.</p>
<p>And as this group knows in particular, the Kremlin’s war of aggression on Ukraine is just one of many conflicts around the globe where journalists are putting their lives on the line right now as we speak, as we gather, in order to report the news.</p>
<p>In Burma this past January, journalist Pu Tuidim’s body was discovered two days after he was abducted alongside nine other people in Chin State.  In November, Yemeni journalist Rasha Abdullah al-Harazi and Mahmud al-Utmi, husband and wife, were driving together in Aden when a bomb attached to their car blew up.  Rasha, who was pregnant, was killed.  Mahmud survived and later told the UN Human Rights Council that he’d been threatened shortly before the attack by Houthis.</p>
<p>Of course, we also know that journalists face grave risks beyond areas of conflict.  Around the world, governments – as well as non-state actors like terrorist groups and criminal organizations – threaten, harass, imprison, and attack journalists every week.</p>
<p>Two hundred and ninety-three journalists were behind bars at the end of 2021.  That’s a new annual record, and this is according to the Committee to Protect Journalists.  The PRC continues to hold the highest number, imprisoning some 50 journalists, including eight from Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Other governments use the threat of imprisonment and lawsuits to intimidate journalists.  In Afghanistan, the Taliban have systematically repressed the Afghan independent press, particularly women journalists and those working in rural areas.  According to a survey conducted at the end of 2021, 40 percent of independent media outlets in Afghanistan have closed since the Taliban takeover.</p>
<p>When individual journalists are threatened, when they’re attacked, when they’re imprisoned, the chilling effects reach far beyond their targets.  Some in the media start to self-censor.  Others flee.  Some stop reporting altogether.  And when repressive governments come after journalists, human rights defenders, labor leaders, others in civil society are usually not far behind.</p>
<p>That was the message sent on April 7th, when an assailant attacked Russian editor and Nobel Prize winner Dmitry Muratov with red paint and acetone as he rode on a train outside of Moscow.  Just some months before, I had the privilege of being on a panel with Dmitry during the Summit for Democracy.  This attack, which U.S. intelligence assessed was the work of Russian intelligence, left Dmitry with chemical burns in his eyes, and sent a clear message to others considering criticizing the Kremlin’s war of aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Governments are supplementing traditional forms of repression with new tactics aimed at undermining press freedom.</p>
<p>More governments are taking steps to control access to information – and news in particular – on the internet, whether through shutdowns, slowdowns, or outright censorship.  These restrictions make it harder for reporting from inside closed areas to get out, and news from the outside getting in.</p>
<p>Technology is being used not only to block journalists, but to watch them.  From 2020 to 2021, more than 30 reporters, editors, other media employees in El Salvador were hacked with the spyware Pegasus, according to an independent investigation – one of several countries where journalists, human rights defenders, and others in civil society have been targeted with this spyware.  Last year, the Biden Administration placed the foreign company that produces Pegasus – the NSO Group – on the Entity List, forbidding it from receiving U.S. exports, including technologies, and seriously affecting its operations.</p>
<p>Whether these attacks on journalists are made using old methods or new ones, the overwhelming majority of crimes against journalists worldwide are carried out with impunity.  This sends a clear message to perpetrators that they can keep targeting the press without consequences.</p>
<p>The U.S. Government is taking a wide range of action to push back against this repression and to strengthen press freedom. I’d like to highlight three aspects of what we’re doing in the time that we have today.</p>
<p>First, we are taking urgent steps to help protect journalists in conflict areas.  In Ukraine, for example, we’re equipping journalists with flak jackets, first aid kits, satellite phones.  We set up a press center in Lviv to help local and national Ukrainian media outlets continue their operations.  We’re also offering emergency aid and psychosocial support to journalists who bear the invisible wounds of reporting from war zones.  This work goes hand-in-hand with the Journalism Protection Platform that we announced at the Summit for Democracy a few months ago, which will provide at-risk journalists with training in digital and physical security, psychosocial care, and other forms of support.</p>
<p>Second, we continue to raise the profile of cases of journalists who are being targeted for their work – using every platform and diplomatic engagement that we have.  Today and every day we think of American journalist Austin Tice, who has been held captive in Syria for nearly 10 years, a quarter of his life.  We will continue to pursue every avenue to secure his release.</p>
<p>We’re rallying broader coalitions of countries to these efforts, such as the Media Freedom Coalition.  This is a group of more than 50 countries that share our commitment to press freedom as well as to the safety of journalists.  So, for example, when we call out Beijing for cracking down on independent media in Hong Kong, we’re doing it together with countries from every part of the world.  And we’re using targeted sanctions to impose costs on the perpetrators of such attacks, including new authorities we created like the Khashoggi Ban.</p>
<p>Third, the United States is helping independent media in financial peril.  We’re providing direct financial assistance to at-risk outlets.  We’re working with business groups and the private sector to help them become more financially sustainable.  At the same time, we’re providing financial support to reporters and news organizations unfairly targeted with litigation for their critical reporting.</p>
<p>So let me close with two words:  Thank you.  Thank you for all that you do.  For all the challenges the press faces today, the work endures because of brave reporters like you.</p>
<p>Journalists like Adela Navarro, who I believe is joining us virtually today from Tijuana, Mexico, and whose publication, Zeta, continues to conduct essential reporting on tough issues like organized crime, corruption, even after several of her colleagues have been murdered with impunity.</p>
<p>Journalists like Ko Swe Win, also I believe joining us, who leads one of Burma’s last remaining independent news sites, Myanmar Now, which continues to cover the widespread atrocities being committed against the Burmese people by the military – work Ko continues in spite of having previously spent seven years in prison for opposing military rule, three of them in solitary confinement.</p>
<p>And journalists like Sevgil Musaeyava, joining us today from Ukraine, where she leads one of the country’s most widely read news sites, Ukrainska Pravda – work she continues even after her brother-in-law, documentarian and U.S. citizen Brent Renaud, was killed by Russian forces while reporting from Irpin on March 1st.  Sevgil recently said in an interview – and I quote – “We are trying to make sure that the people  are not just statistics.”</p>
<p>In that, and so much more, you’re succeeding.</p>
<p>So to all the journalists here today, to all of you joining us online, to members of the media doing this work around the globe:</p>
<p>We’re humbled by your courage.</p>
<p>We’re in awe of your commitment to providing the public with the truth.</p>
<p>We’re honored to be your partners in advancing the essential cause of press freedom – today and every day.</p>
<p>And with that, I’m happy to take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll start with Stacy Hsu from the Central News Agency of Taiwan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you, Secretary, for doing this.  The State Department’s Human Rights Report has for many years expressed a concern that Beijing is trying to influence sort of media outlets in Taiwan by either pressuring their parent company’s business interests in Beijing or pressuring companies with operations in China to avoid advertising with outlets that publish articles critical of Beijing.  And I’m sure that’s happened not only in Taiwan but elsewhere as well.  So based on the U.S. assessment, how serious is this problem, and how can we avoid, like, erosion of Taiwan’s press freedom?</p>
<p>And secondly, if I may, there have been concerns that with Elon Musk’s business ties to China, his acquisition of Twitter may allow Beijing to influence or censor critics on the social media platform.  Do you agree with this concern?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.  So to the first part of the question first, Taiwan is quite literally on the frontlines of the PRC’s hybrid warfare, including disinformation, including cyber attacks.  And these are designed to basically distort the information environment and democratic processes.  So we’ve partnered with Taiwanese authorities on this, civil society organizations, to support independent, fact-based journalism, to try to build societal resilience to disinformation and other forms of foreign interference.  But it’s something that we look at very closely and that we continue to work on.</p>
<p>The second part of your question, on Twitter.  So let me say first it’s a private company.  I’m not going to comment on what is hypothetical at this stage.</p>
<p>Let me say more broadly, though, in response to the question, as we’ve just discussed, free speech – including free media, including platforms of one kind or another – are incredibly important to the Biden Administration.  We’ve made that clear at home; we’ve made that clear around the world.</p>
<p>And I would say again – and this goes to the first part of your question as well as the second – we’ve been deeply concerned about what we’re seeing from the PRC in terms of its misuse of its technology to try to do things like increase surveillance, harassment, intimidation, censorship of PRC citizens, of journalists, of activists and others.  And that includes abroad.</p>
<p>At the same time, we have a total imbalance because these very same leaders in Beijing are using the free and open media – that we ensure that are protected in democratic systems – to spread propaganda, to spread disinformation.  And ultimately, that’s an unsustainable proposition.</p>
<p>Now, it also appears that they are further using these systems to stalk, harass, to threaten critics who are outside the PRC’s territory.  We’ve condemned and we’ve taken action against these efforts, and we’ll continue to defend the principles of a free press, an open, secure, reliable, and interoperable internet and the benefits that flow from it.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Alexander Panov, Novaya Gazeta.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, thank you for this event.  I represent Novaya Gazeta, Russia.  Of course, I want to ask you about Mr. Muratov, but you already mentioned this brutal attack on our editor and Nobel Peace Prize winner.  Actually, could we expect any new statements regarding this situation?</p>
<p>And if I may, I want to tell about second case.  This is Mr. Vladimir Kara-Murza, a political activist but he is former journalist.  He was my colleague.  We worked together 10 years.  And actually, he was poisoned twice in Russia.  Now he was arrested and he could get up to 15 years of prison.  He is Washington Post columnist still, and he – his wife and his three kids live here in the northern Virginia.</p>
<p>And for those who are familiar with situation knew that it’s a kind of revenge.  It’s not discreditation of Russian army in his speech of House of Representative of State of Arizona, but his – it’s revenge for Magnitsky Act, which Vladimir Kara-Murza and late Boris Nemtsov lobbied in U.S. continent, successfully lobbied.</p>
<p>Actually, could we wait for some statement from U.S. Government regarding this situation with this gentleman and regarding Mr. Muratov, and regarding generally the situation in Russia when lots of young Russian journalists had to leave country to work abroad because it’s like – it’s not just censorship, it’s military censorship in Russia.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  No, thank you very much for the question.  A few things in response.</p>
<p>First, as I mentioned, I was with Dmitry Muratov on a panel during our Summit for Democracy just a few months ago.  At that time, the news outlet that he was leading was able to operate, as were many others.  And of course, that space – already incredibly restricted – has been virtually shut down.</p>
<p>I’d say generically governments, regimes that engage in these practices do not evidence a great deal of confidence in themselves.  What are they afraid of?  I think we know the answer: it’s the truth.</p>
<p>I had the opportunity some years ago to actually meet with your colleague, Mr. Kara-Murza, in Washington when he was here.  This, I think, was back in 2016, 2015.  I remember the conversation very vividly.  And like you, we are deeply, deeply disturbed by his treatment.  It’s a case that we’re following very, very closely.</p>
<p>As you know better than I do, he’s suffered arrests, he’s suffered near-fatal poisonings in connection with his peaceful political activities.  And of course, these tactics have long been part of the Kremlin’s playbook.</p>
<p>So we urge Russia to cease the abuse of repressive laws to target nonviolent organizations and individuals as well as journalists.  The Russian people, like people everywhere, have a right to speak freely, they have the right to form peaceful associations to common ends, they have the right to exercise freedom of expression and to have their voices heard through free and fair elections.</p>
<p>And of course, right now the mere fact of calling what is happening in Ukraine by its name – a brutal, unprovoked aggression, as opposed to the Orwellian special military operation – that risks getting anyone who does that 15 years in jail, as you’ve noted.  Again, among many other things, not evidence of a government or leadership that actually has confidence in itself.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Jahanzaib Ali, ARY Pakistan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So thank you so much.  Sir, Pakistan remains among those countries in the world considered most dangerous place for the journalists.  Last year, many Pakistani journalists were killed, kidnapped, and tortured for exposing crime and corruption and criticizing some of the government policies.  Sir, has State Department ever take up this issue in bilateral talks with the Pakistani authorities?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  The short answer is yes, we take this up in our engagements with Pakistani counterparts.  Of course, this is also a feature of the annual Human Rights Reports that we put out, and, of course, we’re aware of significant restrictions on media outlets and civil society more broadly in Pakistan.  Here again a vibrant free press, an informed citizenry are key for any nation and its future, including Pakistan, and I think these practices that we see undermine freedom of expression.  They undermine peaceful assembly.  They undermine Pakistan’s image as well as its ability to progress.  So it is something that comes up both in our direct engagements and in the work that we’re doing every day.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll take a couple questions online.  As a reminder, please do raise your digital hand and unmute yourself if you’re called upon.  We’ll start with Sevgil Musaeyava of Ukrainska Pravda.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Okay.  Good morning, Secretary of State.  First of all, thank you for your support of our country, continued support of our country, which is now fighting for democratic values not only in post-Soviet countries but all over the world.  Thank you for mentioning my dear friend Brent Renaud, who was brutally killed in Ukraine on March.</p>
<p>For me personally, it’s not a war between democratic world and authoritarian regime; it’s also war between truth and propaganda.  For the last eight – 20 years, actually, Russia destroyed all independent medias in their country and they supported state propaganda, and this propaganda now is disrupting not only information field of Ukraine but all over the world, in your country too.  Few days ago, for example, CNN published an investigation about how Russian troll army worked in Ghana and how they spread information about Black Lives Matter’s campaign.</p>
<p>But I have one very personal question, very concrete case.  Everybody knows about tragedy of Mariupol city, which is now occupied by Russia, but still a lot of our civilians and soldiers are blocked in Azovstal plant.  Some of them were evacuated and we met them in control – Ukrainian-controlled territory, but a lot of people still are blocked in this plant.  And Russian propaganda for the last eight years pictured those people – I mean soldiers, first of all – like Nazis.  And for Putin now it’s justified and propaganda justified his cruelty against those people.</p>
<p>And so I have two questions.  How we can save the lives of these people?  And do you have a special plan how to fight against propaganda and how to minimize impact of Russian propaganda in your own country?  Thank you so much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.  And thank you for, again, the incredible courage that you and your colleagues are showing every single day in Ukraine.  By the way, the contrast between media in Ukraine and media in Russia in and of itself speaks volumes.  And in Ukraine, whether before the aggression or now during the aggression, its vibrant – incredibly vibrant – free press putting a light on everything that’s happening is invaluable.  And again, we really applaud the courage that you’re showing every day.</p>
<p>So it’s a very significant challenge when it comes to dealing with the information environment in Russia that has been created and im- bolstered over many, many years.  And a space that was already incredibly restricted is being shut down to virtually nothing just in the last six months.  That’s not something that gets reversed overnight.  But more people are speaking out, speaking up for more journalists who are doing their jobs to the extent possible in Russia but even outside of Russia.  Over time and by different ways, information will find a crack and will get through.  And over time, even in the most closed-down society in terms of its information space, I think it’s going to be very difficult to fully hide the truth.</p>
<p>And the truth is what in the world has Russia’s aggression in Ukraine done to benefit the Russian people?  Absolutely nothing, and to the contrary, they are also bearing the consequences of the horrific decisions made by their leadership.  How has this aggression advanced in any way desire for someone in Russia, like anywhere else, to have a good job, to educate their kids, to find opportunity, to live a life that promises an even better life for their children?  How does that have anything to do with the basic aspirations that people have?</p>
<p>And on the contrary, of course, along  many other things, Putin’s actions have turned Russia into a pariah.  The fact that virtually every leading company on Earth has exited from Russia speaks volumes to that.  And that too is something that, over time, Russian people will feel in their daily lives and that will begin to penetrate the information space, and people increasingly, I believe, will ask themselves the question, “Why, to what end?”</p>
<p>But again, it takes a lot of time because this is a system that’s been built up over many, many years, many decades, but the most important thing is for people, wherever they are, to continue doing their jobs, continue to shine a light on what’s happening in Ukraine, continue to get the information out there, and it will ultimately find its way to its destination.</p>
<p>We’ve been across the board, of course, deeply concerned about those in various parts of Ukraine who are trapped by the Russian onslaught.  Mariupol is front and center in the news for so many people, continues to be contested, and simply put, people need to be allowed out and humanitarian assistance needs to be allowed in.  We’ve seen efforts over the last couple of months to have humanitarian corridors to allow people to exit.  In virtually every instance, those corridors have not held up because Russia has not abided by the commitments that it made.</p>
<p>Now, we just had one successful exit from Mariupol of about a hundred people just yesterday, but then again, the corridors was shut down, and it’s – my understanding is that the shelling and targeting and rocketing of people who are trapped in this factory area has resumed.</p>
<p>Here again, I think it’s incredibly important for the work that all of you are doing to just keep shining a light on it, to make sure that the world knows, to the best of our ability, what’s actually going on; to see, to know, to understand the brutality of it, the inhumanity of it.  And that too, over time, I think, has a way of putting pressure on those who are engaging in these actions to change course.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to Swe Win, Voice of Burma.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Good morning, Mr. Secretary.  This is Swe Win from Burma.  Let me ask you a question regarding the U.S. policy to Burma.  In response to the latest military coup there last year, the United States froze $1 billion of – Burma had at the U.S. Federal Reserve Bank in New York.  There are some rumors out there that the U.S. Government is considering to release those funds to opposition groups in Burma.</p>
<p>Is there any element of truth in that?  Does the U.S. have any plan to actively support a nationwide and resistant movement in Burma against the military junta, such as by weapons as you are now doing for Ukraine?  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.  Let me say first, generally, we have, we are, we will continue to support the aspirations of the Burmese people to return to the path of democracy.  We’re doing that in a variety of ways, and this is the focus of our actions.  Since the coup, we have sanctioned over 27 entities, 70 individuals.  This includes military leaders, it includes officers, it includes cronies who support the regime.</p>
<p>Having said that, we, the international community, believe that more needs to be done.  For example – and this is, I think, an important focus – ending the sale and the transfer of arms, materiel, of dual-use equipment, technical assistance to the military regime, which it is then in turn using to abuse the Burmese people.  We continue to press and we will continue to look for different ways to be effective in pressing for it.  We continue to press the regime to release all those who’ve been unjustly detained, to allow unhindered humanitarian access, to advance the peaceful resolution of the crisis, to restore the path to democracy.</p>
<p>So as we’re doing this, we will continue to look at what tools we believe we have, others may have, to do it more effectively.  And that’s an ongoing proposition but something that we take very, very seriously.</p>
<p>It’s one of the more deeply disturbing tragedies that we have – we’ve experienced and that the Burmese people especially have experienced, in no small measure because of the extraordinary hope and expectations that have been created by this move to democracy – the fact that it’s been derailed, and not only derailed but derailed in such a violent, repressive way.</p>
<p>It’s something that should continue and needs to continue: to galvanize the attention, the focus, the determination of the world to help Burma get back on the democratic track that was interrupted.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  That unfortunately has exhausted our time for today, but I would be remiss on World Press Freedom Day if I didn’t remind everyone here in person to please attend our daily press briefings at the Department if you’re able.  For those of you who are based around the world, please do feel free to dial into our phone briefings, which we also do regularly.</p>
<p>Thank you, Mr. Secretary.  If I could ask everyone to please remain seated, and we hope to see you soon.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, folks.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" /></p>
<p><input type="hidden" /></p>
<p><input type="hidden" /></p>
<p><input type="hidden" /></p>
<p><input type="hidden" /></p>
<p><input type="hidden" /></p>
<p><input type="hidden" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington D.C. </p>
<p>Tuesday, May 3, 2022, at 11:00 am </p>
<p><strong>THE WASHINGTON FOREIGN PRESS CENTER, WASHINGTON, D.C.</strong></p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Good morning.  Welcome to the Department of State’s Washington Foreign Press Center.  My name is Ned Price; I’m the spokesperson here at the Department of State.  And I’m especially pleased to be with you here today in person, the first time we’ve been able to hold an in-person press briefing at the Foreign Press Center in over two years, since the start of COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>And it’s especially notable that we are able to do that today on World Press Freedom Day.  And it’s my distinct honor to have with us Secretary of State Blinken, who will be able to offer some remarks on World Press Freedom Day and to take your questions.  We have journalists here in person.  We also have journalists with us online.  We’ll be able to hear from both of them.</p>
<p>Before I hand the podium over to Secretary Blinken, just some quick announcements at the top.  After his opening remarks, I’ll open the floor to questions.  We’ll first take a few questions from here in the room.  Please do wait until you’re handed a microphone before you start asking your questions.  We would also ask that you keep your question brief so that we can take as many questions as we are able to.  We will then move to Zoom.  Please do raise your digital hand on the Zoom, and we will call on you from there.  We ask that you please click “raise hand” to notify that you have a question.  Please do unmute yourself before speaking, and we’ll take your question.</p>
<p>This, of course, is live-streamed.  There will be a transcript available after the fact.  And now, as I said before, it’s my distinct pleasure to introduce Secretary Blinken.  Secretary Blinken, the podium is yours.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Morning, everyone.  Ned, thank you very, very much.  And it is particularly good to be here, and I wanted to start by saying welcome, everyone, to the Foreign Press Center.  It’s been too long since those words have actually been said.  This is the first in-person event, as Ned said, that we’ve been able to have in over two years as a result of the pandemic.  And I can’t imagine a more fitting occasion than to do it on World Press Freedom Day.  So welcome back, everyone.</p>
<p>The United States has a vital stake in promoting the right to freedom of expression, including a free press, at home and also around the world.  The free flow of information, ideas, opinions, including dissenting ones, is essential to inclusive and tolerant societies.</p>
<p>A vibrant independent press is a cornerstone for any healthy democracy.  At its core is the idea that information is a public good, crucial to everything we do, to every decision that we make.  And often we trust the press with providing that information.  It’s what helps citizens understand the events, the forces that are shaping their lives.  It allows people to engage meaningfully in the political and civic spheres of their communities, their nations, and the world.</p>
<p>A free press is one of the most effective tools that we have for advancing human rights.  Whether it’s documenting unjust working conditions, corrupt or failing public services, discrimination against women and marginalized groups, abuse of security forces, accurate reporting shines a bright light on the parts of our societies that need fixing, that need to be illuminated.  That brings pressure to change, to form, as we say in the United States, a more perfect union.</p>
<p>Having said that, we meet a time when the exercise of freedom of expression, including freedom of the press, faces profound threats.  Some of these are old; some are new.  Threats that we, the United States Government, Department of State, all of us as citizens have an abiding interest in confronting, and doing so head on.</p>
<p>Just last Thursday, April 28th, journalist Vira Hyrych was killed when the apartment that she was living in was struck by the Russian military in Kyiv.  Vira is one of 11 journalists killed in Ukraine this year according to the Committee to Protect Journalists.  Many more have been wounded in conflict.  One is Fox News correspondent Ben Hall, who was seriously wounded when the car that he and his team were traveling in was struck by incoming fire on March 14th.  His cameraman, Pierre Zakrzewski, and his producer, Oleksandra Kuvshynova,  killed in this attack.</p>
<p>I know Ben well.  He’s traveled with me on many occasions since I’ve been in this job.  Thinking of him, his loved ones, the loved ones of Pierre and Oleksandra, and those of all who were killed in Ukraine.  For my part, I look very much forward to welcoming Ben back to the press corps.</p>
<p>And as this group knows in particular, the Kremlin’s war of aggression on Ukraine is just one of many conflicts around the globe where journalists are putting their lives on the line right now as we speak, as we gather, in order to report the news.</p>
<p>In Burma this past January, journalist Pu Tuidim’s body was discovered two days after he was abducted alongside nine other people in Chin State.  In November, Yemeni journalist Rasha Abdullah al-Harazi and Mahmud al-Utmi, husband and wife, were driving together in Aden when a bomb attached to their car blew up.  Rasha, who was pregnant, was killed.  Mahmud survived and later told the UN Human Rights Council that he’d been threatened shortly before the attack by Houthis.</p>
<p>Of course, we also know that journalists face grave risks beyond areas of conflict.  Around the world, governments – as well as non-state actors like terrorist groups and criminal organizations – threaten, harass, imprison, and attack journalists every week.</p>
<p>Two hundred and ninety-three journalists were behind bars at the end of 2021.  That’s a new annual record, and this is according to the Committee to Protect Journalists.  The PRC continues to hold the highest number, imprisoning some 50 journalists, including eight from Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Other governments use the threat of imprisonment and lawsuits to intimidate journalists.  In Afghanistan, the Taliban have systematically repressed the Afghan independent press, particularly women journalists and those working in rural areas.  According to a survey conducted at the end of 2021, 40 percent of independent media outlets in Afghanistan have closed since the Taliban takeover.</p>
<p>When individual journalists are threatened, when they’re attacked, when they’re imprisoned, the chilling effects reach far beyond their targets.  Some in the media start to self-censor.  Others flee.  Some stop reporting altogether.  And when repressive governments come after journalists, human rights defenders, labor leaders, others in civil society are usually not far behind.</p>
<p>That was the message sent on April 7th, when an assailant attacked Russian editor and Nobel Prize winner Dmitry Muratov with red paint and acetone as he rode on a train outside of Moscow.  Just some months before, I had the privilege of being on a panel with Dmitry during the Summit for Democracy.  This attack, which U.S. intelligence assessed was the work of Russian intelligence, left Dmitry with chemical burns in his eyes, and sent a clear message to others considering criticizing the Kremlin’s war of aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Governments are supplementing traditional forms of repression with new tactics aimed at undermining press freedom.</p>
<p>More governments are taking steps to control access to information – and news in particular – on the internet, whether through shutdowns, slowdowns, or outright censorship.  These restrictions make it harder for reporting from inside closed areas to get out, and news from the outside getting in.</p>
<p>Technology is being used not only to block journalists, but to watch them.  From 2020 to 2021, more than 30 reporters, editors, other media employees in El Salvador were hacked with the spyware Pegasus, according to an independent investigation – one of several countries where journalists, human rights defenders, and others in civil society have been targeted with this spyware.  Last year, the Biden Administration placed the foreign company that produces Pegasus – the NSO Group – on the Entity List, forbidding it from receiving U.S. exports, including technologies, and seriously affecting its operations.</p>
<p>Whether these attacks on journalists are made using old methods or new ones, the overwhelming majority of crimes against journalists worldwide are carried out with impunity.  This sends a clear message to perpetrators that they can keep targeting the press without consequences.</p>
<p>The U.S. Government is taking a wide range of action to push back against this repression and to strengthen press freedom. I’d like to highlight three aspects of what we’re doing in the time that we have today.</p>
<p>First, we are taking urgent steps to help protect journalists in conflict areas.  In Ukraine, for example, we’re equipping journalists with flak jackets, first aid kits, satellite phones.  We set up a press center in Lviv to help local and national Ukrainian media outlets continue their operations.  We’re also offering emergency aid and psychosocial support to journalists who bear the invisible wounds of reporting from war zones.  This work goes hand-in-hand with the Journalism Protection Platform that we announced at the Summit for Democracy a few months ago, which will provide at-risk journalists with training in digital and physical security, psychosocial care, and other forms of support.</p>
<p>Second, we continue to raise the profile of cases of journalists who are being targeted for their work – using every platform and diplomatic engagement that we have.  Today and every day we think of American journalist Austin Tice, who has been held captive in Syria for nearly 10 years, a quarter of his life.  We will continue to pursue every avenue to secure his release.</p>
<p>We’re rallying broader coalitions of countries to these efforts, such as the Media Freedom Coalition.  This is a group of more than 50 countries that share our commitment to press freedom as well as to the safety of journalists.  So, for example, when we call out Beijing for cracking down on independent media in Hong Kong, we’re doing it together with countries from every part of the world.  And we’re using targeted sanctions to impose costs on the perpetrators of such attacks, including new authorities we created like the Khashoggi Ban.</p>
<p>Third, the United States is helping independent media in financial peril.  We’re providing direct financial assistance to at-risk outlets.  We’re working with business groups and the private sector to help them become more financially sustainable.  At the same time, we’re providing financial support to reporters and news organizations unfairly targeted with litigation for their critical reporting.</p>
<p>So let me close with two words:  Thank you.  Thank you for all that you do.  For all the challenges the press faces today, the work endures because of brave reporters like you.</p>
<p>Journalists like Adela Navarro, who I believe is joining us virtually today from Tijuana, Mexico, and whose publication, Zeta, continues to conduct essential reporting on tough issues like organized crime, corruption, even after several of her colleagues have been murdered with impunity.</p>
<p>Journalists like Ko Swe Win, also I believe joining us, who leads one of Burma’s last remaining independent news sites, Myanmar Now, which continues to cover the widespread atrocities being committed against the Burmese people by the military – work Ko continues in spite of having previously spent seven years in prison for opposing military rule, three of them in solitary confinement.</p>
<p>And journalists like Sevgil Musaeyava, joining us today from Ukraine, where she leads one of the country’s most widely read news sites, Ukrainska Pravda – work she continues even after her brother-in-law, documentarian and U.S. citizen Brent Renaud, was killed by Russian forces while reporting from Irpin on March 1st.  Sevgil recently said in an interview – and I quote – “We are trying to make sure that the people  are not just statistics.”</p>
<p>In that, and so much more, you’re succeeding.</p>
<p>So to all the journalists here today, to all of you joining us online, to members of the media doing this work around the globe:</p>
<p>We’re humbled by your courage.</p>
<p>We’re in awe of your commitment to providing the public with the truth.</p>
<p>We’re honored to be your partners in advancing the essential cause of press freedom – today and every day.</p>
<p>And with that, I’m happy to take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll start with Stacy Hsu from the Central News Agency of Taiwan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you, Secretary, for doing this.  The State Department’s Human Rights Report has for many years expressed a concern that Beijing is trying to influence sort of media outlets in Taiwan by either pressuring their parent company’s business interests in Beijing or pressuring companies with operations in China to avoid advertising with outlets that publish articles critical of Beijing.  And I’m sure that’s happened not only in Taiwan but elsewhere as well.  So based on the U.S. assessment, how serious is this problem, and how can we avoid, like, erosion of Taiwan’s press freedom?</p>
<p>And secondly, if I may, there have been concerns that with Elon Musk’s business ties to China, his acquisition of Twitter may allow Beijing to influence or censor critics on the social media platform.  Do you agree with this concern?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.  So to the first part of the question first, Taiwan is quite literally on the frontlines of the PRC’s hybrid warfare, including disinformation, including cyber attacks.  And these are designed to basically distort the information environment and democratic processes.  So we’ve partnered with Taiwanese authorities on this, civil society organizations, to support independent, fact-based journalism, to try to build societal resilience to disinformation and other forms of foreign interference.  But it’s something that we look at very closely and that we continue to work on.</p>
<p>The second part of your question, on Twitter.  So let me say first it’s a private company.  I’m not going to comment on what is hypothetical at this stage.</p>
<p>Let me say more broadly, though, in response to the question, as we’ve just discussed, free speech – including free media, including platforms of one kind or another – are incredibly important to the Biden Administration.  We’ve made that clear at home; we’ve made that clear around the world.</p>
<p>And I would say again – and this goes to the first part of your question as well as the second – we’ve been deeply concerned about what we’re seeing from the PRC in terms of its misuse of its technology to try to do things like increase surveillance, harassment, intimidation, censorship of PRC citizens, of journalists, of activists and others.  And that includes abroad.</p>
<p>At the same time, we have a total imbalance because these very same leaders in Beijing are using the free and open media – that we ensure that are protected in democratic systems – to spread propaganda, to spread disinformation.  And ultimately, that’s an unsustainable proposition.</p>
<p>Now, it also appears that they are further using these systems to stalk, harass, to threaten critics who are outside the PRC’s territory.  We’ve condemned and we’ve taken action against these efforts, and we’ll continue to defend the principles of a free press, an open, secure, reliable, and interoperable internet and the benefits that flow from it.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Alexander Panov, Novaya Gazeta.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, thank you for this event.  I represent Novaya Gazeta, Russia.  Of course, I want to ask you about Mr. Muratov, but you already mentioned this brutal attack on our editor and Nobel Peace Prize winner.  Actually, could we expect any new statements regarding this situation?</p>
<p>And if I may, I want to tell about second case.  This is Mr. Vladimir Kara-Murza, a political activist but he is former journalist.  He was my colleague.  We worked together 10 years.  And actually, he was poisoned twice in Russia.  Now he was arrested and he could get up to 15 years of prison.  He is Washington Post columnist still, and he – his wife and his three kids live here in the northern Virginia.</p>
<p>And for those who are familiar with situation knew that it’s a kind of revenge.  It’s not discreditation of Russian army in his speech of House of Representative of State of Arizona, but his – it’s revenge for Magnitsky Act, which Vladimir Kara-Murza and late Boris Nemtsov lobbied in U.S. continent, successfully lobbied.</p>
<p>Actually, could we wait for some statement from U.S. Government regarding this situation with this gentleman and regarding Mr. Muratov, and regarding generally the situation in Russia when lots of young Russian journalists had to leave country to work abroad because it’s like – it’s not just censorship, it’s military censorship in Russia.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  No, thank you very much for the question.  A few things in response.</p>
<p>First, as I mentioned, I was with Dmitry Muratov on a panel during our Summit for Democracy just a few months ago.  At that time, the news outlet that he was leading was able to operate, as were many others.  And of course, that space – already incredibly restricted – has been virtually shut down.</p>
<p>I’d say generically governments, regimes that engage in these practices do not evidence a great deal of confidence in themselves.  What are they afraid of?  I think we know the answer: it’s the truth.</p>
<p>I had the opportunity some years ago to actually meet with your colleague, Mr. Kara-Murza, in Washington when he was here.  This, I think, was back in 2016, 2015.  I remember the conversation very vividly.  And like you, we are deeply, deeply disturbed by his treatment.  It’s a case that we’re following very, very closely.</p>
<p>As you know better than I do, he’s suffered arrests, he’s suffered near-fatal poisonings in connection with his peaceful political activities.  And of course, these tactics have long been part of the Kremlin’s playbook.</p>
<p>So we urge Russia to cease the abuse of repressive laws to target nonviolent organizations and individuals as well as journalists.  The Russian people, like people everywhere, have a right to speak freely, they have the right to form peaceful associations to common ends, they have the right to exercise freedom of expression and to have their voices heard through free and fair elections.</p>
<p>And of course, right now the mere fact of calling what is happening in Ukraine by its name – a brutal, unprovoked aggression, as opposed to the Orwellian special military operation – that risks getting anyone who does that 15 years in jail, as you’ve noted.  Again, among many other things, not evidence of a government or leadership that actually has confidence in itself.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Jahanzaib Ali, ARY Pakistan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So thank you so much.  Sir, Pakistan remains among those countries in the world considered most dangerous place for the journalists.  Last year, many Pakistani journalists were killed, kidnapped, and tortured for exposing crime and corruption and criticizing some of the government policies.  Sir, has State Department ever take up this issue in bilateral talks with the Pakistani authorities?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  The short answer is yes, we take this up in our engagements with Pakistani counterparts.  Of course, this is also a feature of the annual Human Rights Reports that we put out, and, of course, we’re aware of significant restrictions on media outlets and civil society more broadly in Pakistan.  Here again a vibrant free press, an informed citizenry are key for any nation and its future, including Pakistan, and I think these practices that we see undermine freedom of expression.  They undermine peaceful assembly.  They undermine Pakistan’s image as well as its ability to progress.  So it is something that comes up both in our direct engagements and in the work that we’re doing every day.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll take a couple questions online.  As a reminder, please do raise your digital hand and unmute yourself if you’re called upon.  We’ll start with Sevgil Musaeyava of Ukrainska Pravda.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Okay.  Good morning, Secretary of State.  First of all, thank you for your support of our country, continued support of our country, which is now fighting for democratic values not only in post-Soviet countries but all over the world.  Thank you for mentioning my dear friend Brent Renaud, who was brutally killed in Ukraine on March.</p>
<p>For me personally, it’s not a war between democratic world and authoritarian regime; it’s also war between truth and propaganda.  For the last eight – 20 years, actually, Russia destroyed all independent medias in their country and they supported state propaganda, and this propaganda now is disrupting not only information field of Ukraine but all over the world, in your country too.  Few days ago, for example, CNN published an investigation about how Russian troll army worked in Ghana and how they spread information about Black Lives Matter’s campaign.</p>
<p>But I have one very personal question, very concrete case.  Everybody knows about tragedy of Mariupol city, which is now occupied by Russia, but still a lot of our civilians and soldiers are blocked in Azovstal plant.  Some of them were evacuated and we met them in control – Ukrainian-controlled territory, but a lot of people still are blocked in this plant.  And Russian propaganda for the last eight years pictured those people – I mean soldiers, first of all – like Nazis.  And for Putin now it’s justified and propaganda justified his cruelty against those people.</p>
<p>And so I have two questions.  How we can save the lives of these people?  And do you have a special plan how to fight against propaganda and how to minimize impact of Russian propaganda in your own country?  Thank you so much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.  And thank you for, again, the incredible courage that you and your colleagues are showing every single day in Ukraine.  By the way, the contrast between media in Ukraine and media in Russia in and of itself speaks volumes.  And in Ukraine, whether before the aggression or now during the aggression, its vibrant – incredibly vibrant – free press putting a light on everything that’s happening is invaluable.  And again, we really applaud the courage that you’re showing every day.</p>
<p>So it’s a very significant challenge when it comes to dealing with the information environment in Russia that has been created and im- bolstered over many, many years.  And a space that was already incredibly restricted is being shut down to virtually nothing just in the last six months.  That’s not something that gets reversed overnight.  But more people are speaking out, speaking up for more journalists who are doing their jobs to the extent possible in Russia but even outside of Russia.  Over time and by different ways, information will find a crack and will get through.  And over time, even in the most closed-down society in terms of its information space, I think it’s going to be very difficult to fully hide the truth.</p>
<p>And the truth is what in the world has Russia’s aggression in Ukraine done to benefit the Russian people?  Absolutely nothing, and to the contrary, they are also bearing the consequences of the horrific decisions made by their leadership.  How has this aggression advanced in any way desire for someone in Russia, like anywhere else, to have a good job, to educate their kids, to find opportunity, to live a life that promises an even better life for their children?  How does that have anything to do with the basic aspirations that people have?</p>
<p>And on the contrary, of course, along  many other things, Putin’s actions have turned Russia into a pariah.  The fact that virtually every leading company on Earth has exited from Russia speaks volumes to that.  And that too is something that, over time, Russian people will feel in their daily lives and that will begin to penetrate the information space, and people increasingly, I believe, will ask themselves the question, “Why, to what end?”</p>
<p>But again, it takes a lot of time because this is a system that’s been built up over many, many years, many decades, but the most important thing is for people, wherever they are, to continue doing their jobs, continue to shine a light on what’s happening in Ukraine, continue to get the information out there, and it will ultimately find its way to its destination.</p>
<p>We’ve been across the board, of course, deeply concerned about those in various parts of Ukraine who are trapped by the Russian onslaught.  Mariupol is front and center in the news for so many people, continues to be contested, and simply put, people need to be allowed out and humanitarian assistance needs to be allowed in.  We’ve seen efforts over the last couple of months to have humanitarian corridors to allow people to exit.  In virtually every instance, those corridors have not held up because Russia has not abided by the commitments that it made.</p>
<p>Now, we just had one successful exit from Mariupol of about a hundred people just yesterday, but then again, the corridors was shut down, and it’s – my understanding is that the shelling and targeting and rocketing of people who are trapped in this factory area has resumed.</p>
<p>Here again, I think it’s incredibly important for the work that all of you are doing to just keep shining a light on it, to make sure that the world knows, to the best of our ability, what’s actually going on; to see, to know, to understand the brutality of it, the inhumanity of it.  And that too, over time, I think, has a way of putting pressure on those who are engaging in these actions to change course.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to Swe Win, Voice of Burma.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Good morning, Mr. Secretary.  This is Swe Win from Burma.  Let me ask you a question regarding the U.S. policy to Burma.  In response to the latest military coup there last year, the United States froze $1 billion of – Burma had at the U.S. Federal Reserve Bank in New York.  There are some rumors out there that the U.S. Government is considering to release those funds to opposition groups in Burma.</p>
<p>Is there any element of truth in that?  Does the U.S. have any plan to actively support a nationwide and resistant movement in Burma against the military junta, such as by weapons as you are now doing for Ukraine?  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.  Let me say first, generally, we have, we are, we will continue to support the aspirations of the Burmese people to return to the path of democracy.  We’re doing that in a variety of ways, and this is the focus of our actions.  Since the coup, we have sanctioned over 27 entities, 70 individuals.  This includes military leaders, it includes officers, it includes cronies who support the regime.</p>
<p>Having said that, we, the international community, believe that more needs to be done.  For example – and this is, I think, an important focus – ending the sale and the transfer of arms, materiel, of dual-use equipment, technical assistance to the military regime, which it is then in turn using to abuse the Burmese people.  We continue to press and we will continue to look for different ways to be effective in pressing for it.  We continue to press the regime to release all those who’ve been unjustly detained, to allow unhindered humanitarian access, to advance the peaceful resolution of the crisis, to restore the path to democracy.</p>
<p>So as we’re doing this, we will continue to look at what tools we believe we have, others may have, to do it more effectively.  And that’s an ongoing proposition but something that we take very, very seriously.</p>
<p>It’s one of the more deeply disturbing tragedies that we have – we’ve experienced and that the Burmese people especially have experienced, in no small measure because of the extraordinary hope and expectations that have been created by this move to democracy – the fact that it’s been derailed, and not only derailed but derailed in such a violent, repressive way.</p>
<p>It’s something that should continue and needs to continue: to galvanize the attention, the focus, the determination of the world to help Burma get back on the democratic track that was interrupted.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  That unfortunately has exhausted our time for today, but I would be remiss on World Press Freedom Day if I didn’t remind everyone here in person to please attend our daily press briefings at the Department if you’re able.  For those of you who are based around the world, please do feel free to dial into our phone briefings, which we also do regularly.</p>
<p>Thank you, Mr. Secretary.  If I could ask everyone to please remain seated, and we hope to see you soon.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, folks.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" /></p>
<p><input type="hidden" /></p>
<p><input type="hidden" /></p>
<p><input type="hidden" /></p>
<p><input type="hidden" /></p>
<p><input type="hidden" /></p>
<p><input type="hidden" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Swiss President Cassis</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-swiss-president-cassis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 15:52:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=340455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Swiss President Ignazio Cassis.  Secretary Blinken and President Cassis discussed economic efforts to address the humanitarian situation in Afghanistan and our shared commitment to the people of Ukraine as they defend themselves against Putin’s unprovoked war of aggression.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Swiss President Ignazio Cassis.  Secretary Blinken and President Cassis discussed economic efforts to address the humanitarian situation in Afghanistan and our shared commitment to the people of Ukraine as they defend themselves against Putin’s unprovoked war of aggression.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Chilean Foreign Minister Urrejola</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-chilean-foreign-minister-urrejola/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 12:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=340370</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke yesterday with Chilean Foreign Minister Antonia Urrejola to congratulate her on her new role as Foreign Minister.  The Secretary conveyed that he looked forward to Chile’s participation in the Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles in early June. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Urrejola also discussed our critical partnership in promoting human rights, democracy, and a collective response to address irregular migration throughout the region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke yesterday with Chilean Foreign Minister Antonia Urrejola to congratulate her on her new role as Foreign Minister.  The Secretary conveyed that he looked forward to Chile’s participation in the Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles in early June. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Urrejola also discussed our critical partnership in promoting human rights, democracy, and a collective response to address irregular migration throughout the region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
