<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 20:54:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with Indian Minister of External Affairs Dr. Subrahmanyam Jaishankar Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-indian-minister-of-external-affairs-dr-subrahmanyam-jaishankar-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Dr. Subrahmanyam Jaishankar, Indian Minister of External Affairs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 19:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Dr. Subrahmanyam Jaishankar, Indian Minister of External Affairs</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a special pleasure to be here with my friend and colleague, Foreign Minister Jaishankar.  It’s wonderful to have him at the State Department, and very important as well because the United States and India are working together on so many of the most important challenges of our time and ones that are having a profound impact on the lives of our citizens.  And we are united in confronting COVID-19 together, we’re united in dealing with the challenge posed by climate change, and we are partnered together directly through the Quad and other institutions at the United Nations in dealing with many of the challenges that we face in the region and around the world.</p>
<p>The partnership between the United States and India is vital, it’s strong, and I think it’s increasingly productive.  So I’m very pleased to have the foreign minister here today and we have, as usual, a lot to talk about.</p>
<p><b>EXTERNAL AFFAIRS MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</b>  Thank you.  Thank you, Tony.  Well, let me echo the Secretary’s remarks.  It’s first of all a great pleasure to be back.  This is the first cabinet-level visit from India to the new administration, and I’m of course delighted that I see someone as a counterpart with whom I’ve worked for many years.  We have a lot of issues to discuss.  I think our relations have grown stronger over the years, and I’m very confident they’ll continue to do so.  But I also want to take the opportunity to express to the Secretary and through him to the administration, to the United States, for the strong support and solidarity at a moment of great difficulty for us.  So as he said, we have many things to talk about, but I thought that’s something I should express.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.  We were – we know.  We remember in the earlier days of COVID, India was there for the United States, something we’ll never forget, and now we want to make sure that we’re there for and with India.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><b>EXTERNAL AFFAIRS MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</b>  Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Dr. Subrahmanyam Jaishankar, Indian Minister of External Affairs</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a special pleasure to be here with my friend and colleague, Foreign Minister Jaishankar.  It’s wonderful to have him at the State Department, and very important as well because the United States and India are working together on so many of the most important challenges of our time and ones that are having a profound impact on the lives of our citizens.  And we are united in confronting COVID-19 together, we’re united in dealing with the challenge posed by climate change, and we are partnered together directly through the Quad and other institutions at the United Nations in dealing with many of the challenges that we face in the region and around the world.</p>
<p>The partnership between the United States and India is vital, it’s strong, and I think it’s increasingly productive.  So I’m very pleased to have the foreign minister here today and we have, as usual, a lot to talk about.</p>
<p><b>EXTERNAL AFFAIRS MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</b>  Thank you.  Thank you, Tony.  Well, let me echo the Secretary’s remarks.  It’s first of all a great pleasure to be back.  This is the first cabinet-level visit from India to the new administration, and I’m of course delighted that I see someone as a counterpart with whom I’ve worked for many years.  We have a lot of issues to discuss.  I think our relations have grown stronger over the years, and I’m very confident they’ll continue to do so.  But I also want to take the opportunity to express to the Secretary and through him to the administration, to the United States, for the strong support and solidarity at a moment of great difficulty for us.  So as he said, we have many things to talk about, but I thought that’s something I should express.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.  We were – we know.  We remember in the earlier days of COVID, India was there for the United States, something we’ll never forget, and now we want to make sure that we’re there for and with India.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><b>EXTERNAL AFFAIRS MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</b>  Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Colombian Vice President Ramírez</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-colombian-vice-president-ramirez/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 19:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Colombian Vice President and Foreign Minister-Designate Marta Lucía Ramírez today at the Department of State. The Secretary reaffirmed the enduring partnership our two countries have maintained for decades, based on a commitment to democracy, the security of our people, and mutual prosperity. He expressed his concern and condolences for the loss of life during recent protests in Colombia and reiterated the unquestionable right of citizens to protest peacefully. He welcomed the national dialogue President Duque has convened as an opportunity for the Colombian people to work together to construct a peaceful, prosperous future. The Secretary reiterated his appreciation for the U.S.-Colombia partnership, and pledged to continue our close cooperation to support lasting peace in Colombia, coordinate an effective health response to the pandemic, and facilitate inclusive economic growth as our hemisphere recovers.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Colombian Vice President and Foreign Minister-Designate Marta Lucía Ramírez today at the Department of State. The Secretary reaffirmed the enduring partnership our two countries have maintained for decades, based on a commitment to democracy, the security of our people, and mutual prosperity. He expressed his concern and condolences for the loss of life during recent protests in Colombia and reiterated the unquestionable right of citizens to protest peacefully. He welcomed the national dialogue President Duque has convened as an opportunity for the Colombian people to work together to construct a peaceful, prosperous future. The Secretary reiterated his appreciation for the U.S.-Colombia partnership, and pledged to continue our close cooperation to support lasting peace in Colombia, coordinate an effective health response to the pandemic, and facilitate inclusive economic growth as our hemisphere recovers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>State Department and U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) FY 2022 Budget Request</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/state-department-and-u-s-agency-for-international-development-usaid-fy-2022-budget-request/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247226</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The President’s FY 2022 Budget requests $58.5 billion for the State Department and USAID. The funding request invests in the core foundations of our country’s strength and delivers for the American people, including by working with allies and partners to address the COVID-19 pandemic and the climate crisis, promote and defend our democratic values, and engage China in the Indo-Pacific and globally from a position of collective strength. This budget will enable the Department of State and USAID to help achieve the President’s vision of restoring U.S. leadership and delivering security and prosperity for all Americans.</p>
<p>The Department of State and USAID use diplomatic and development tools to advance U.S. interests and deliver for all Americans. After four years of neglect, the State and USAID Budget request significantly increases funding for climate initiatives, makes needed investments in global health security, enhances our support for the promotion and protection of democracy, human rights, labor rights, and rule of law, reasserts U.S. global humanitarian leadership, including rebuilding U.S. refugee resettlement, increases economic and security assistance to Central America to address the root causes of irregular migration, reinvigorates the diplomatic and development workforce, and meets our international obligations, all while supporting efforts to advance racial equity and inclusion in foreign assistance and within foreign affairs agencies.</p>
<p>The President’s FY 2022 budget request includes $58.5 billion for the Department of State and USAID, an increase of $5.5 billion or 10 percent over the FY 2021 enacted level. It:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ensures the United States is Better Prepared to Prevent, Detect, and Respond to Future Biological Threats and Pandemics. </strong>The budget request expands American leadership in global health security in order to address long-term impacts of COVID-19 and to prevent, prepare for, and respond to future infectious disease outbreaks, whether naturally occurring, accidental, or deliberate. The budget request includes $10.1 billion for global health programs of which nearly $1 billion would fund global health security programs and support to end the COVID-19 pandemic, an increase of over $800 million above the FY 2021 enacted level. This nearly $1 billion would expand Global Health Security Agenda capacity-building programs to additional countries and increase investments in crosscutting research and viral discovery programs to detect and stamp out future infectious disease outbreaks before they become pandemics. These funds also support global pandemic preparedness efforts, including a health security financing mechanism developed alongside U.S. partners and allies to catalyze increased investment in pandemic prevention and preparedness for future outbreaks. Funding would also support the global Access to COVID-19 Tools (ACT) Accelerator platform to deploy tests, treatments, and vaccines around the world. Global health activities supported in the FY 2022 budget request build upon existing global health security infrastructure developed through decades of U.S. investment as well as emergency supplemental funding over the past year and the $10.8 billion provided in the American Rescue Plan Act for the Department and USAID to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic.</li>
<li><strong>Responds to the Climate Crisis. </strong>The budget request tackles the climate emergency head-on, providing more than $2.5 billion across all government agencies for international climate programs, more than four times the 2021 enacted level, to rally the world against this urgent threat that cannot be defeated by a single nation alone. The budget request includes $1.25 billion for the Green Climate Fund, with funding split between the Department and Treasury. The request also includes over $700 million in State and USAID bilateral, regional, and global climate-related assistance. The United States would provide $485 million to support other multilateral climate initiatives, including $100 million for international climate adaptation programs. The budget request also proposes funding for staffing increases to develop new centers of climate expertise at the Department of State and the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation. By reestablishing U.S. leadership on climate change, these increased climate investments would revitalize America’s coalitions with its allies and help mobilize the rest of the international community to increase its contributions.</li>
<li><strong>Revitalizes Collaborative U.S. Leadership in Central America. </strong>It is critical to revitalize U.S. leadership in Central America and to address the root causes of irregular migration from Central America to the United States. To that end, the budget request invests $861 million in the region as a first step toward a four-year commitment of $4 billion. These resources would allow the United States to work with partners in the region to strengthen host government accountability in curtailing endemic corruption, expanding economic opportunity, improving governance, and reducing violence and insecurity.</li>
<li><strong>Restores America’s Standing in International Organizations. </strong>To ensure we are in a position to uphold and defend the principles and values of the international order we helped build, we must meet U.S. commitments to international peacekeeping and pay our assessed dues to international organizations on time and in full, reversing the chronic underfunding of these critical programs by the previous administration. The budget request provides approximately $500 million more than last year, for a total of nearly $2 billion, for UN peacekeeping missions, including $300 million to begin reducing cap-related arrears accumulated over the past four years, with the intention of fully paying these arrears within two years. The budget request also makes investments to restore America’s standing in the world by providing funding, including for the payment of arrears where applicable, to support international organizations and related programs, including the World Health Organization, the UN Population Fund, and the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights, while continuing to press for needed reforms. These investments position us to lead in international organizations with our like-minded partners.</li>
<li><strong>Advances U.S. Humanitarian Leadership, Rebuilds U.S. Refugee Resettlement. </strong>Humanitarian needs are at historic levels as COVID-19 has exacerbated existing challenges from ongoing and new complex emergencies. The budget request provides the resources necessary to rebuild the badly damaged U.S. refugee admissions program and support up to 125,000 admissions in 2022. It provides over $10 billion in humanitarian assistance to support vulnerable people abroad, including refugees, conflict victims, and other displaced persons.</li>
<li><strong>Promotes and Defends our Democratic Values and Counters Rising Authoritarianism. </strong>This budget will enable the United States to lead efforts with our democratic allies and partners to support open and free societies, strengthen democratic institutions, combat growing authoritarianism and corruption, increase respect for human rights, support marginalized populations, and strengthen partner capacity to protect democratic systems against malign influence from China, Russia, and other authoritarian states. This programming would complement international efforts stemming from the Administration’s Summit for Democracy to strengthen democratic institutions, honestly confront nations that are backsliding, and forge a common agenda.</li>
<li><strong>Supports U.S. Partners in the Middle East and Advances Peace in the Region. </strong>The budget request fully funds U.S. commitments to key allies in the Middle East, including Israel and Jordan. The budget request funds assistance programs and humanitarian aid for Palestinians, including support for the UN Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA). The United States will maintain steadfast support for Israel as the Administration renews relations with Palestinian leadership, restores economic and humanitarian assistance for Palestinians, and works to advance freedom, prosperity, and security for the Israeli and Palestinian people alike.</li>
<li><strong>Revitalizes the Foreign Policy Workforce to Deliver for All Americans</strong>through increases in funding for the Department’s and USAID’s greatest asset, our people. The FY 2022 request proposes funding for the largest State staffing increase in a decade, building a diplomatic and development corps that fully represents America in all its talent and   By empowering our workforce and deepening our expertise, we will be able to successfully address 21st century challenges on global health, climate, and technology. State’s new Chief Diversity and Inclusion Officer will lead the charge to implement our Diversity and Inclusion Strategic Plan across the Department.</li>
<li><strong>Invests in Information Technology (IT) Modernization and Stronger Cybersecurity</strong>across State and USAID, providing more secure and mobile communication tools enabling our workforce to succeed in the modern information environment, with greater agility, collaboration, and access to data. An increase of more than $100 million for State’s cybersecurity is crucial to mitigating the evolving cybersecurity threat landscape. The Department and the Agency remain prime targets of malicious state- and non-state actors, as evidenced by the recent attacks.</li>
<li><strong>Supports Consular Services to Assist Americans, Promote Prosperity, and Advance U.S. Interests.</strong>The request includes a direct appropriation of $320 million to provide a stable source of support for consular services provided to American citizens and foreign visa applicants who come to visit, study, and invest in our communities in light of reduced fee revenue due to the pandemic, as well as continuing authorities allowing fees collected to support a wider array of consular activity through FY 2022.</li>
<li><strong>Sustains Security for our Worldwide Presence at $6.1 billion,</strong>protecting our personnel, embassies, and cybersecurity around the globe. These include initiatives to expand real-time threat monitoring, accelerate security vetting, and the construction or renovation of embassies and consulates in Vietnam, Democratic Republic of Congo, Bosnia, South Africa, and France.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, please visit <a href="https://www.state.gov/fy-2022-international-affairs-budget/">www.state.gov/cj</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The President’s FY 2022 Budget requests $58.5 billion for the State Department and USAID. The funding request invests in the core foundations of our country’s strength and delivers for the American people, including by working with allies and partners to address the COVID-19 pandemic and the climate crisis, promote and defend our democratic values, and engage China in the Indo-Pacific and globally from a position of collective strength. This budget will enable the Department of State and USAID to help achieve the President’s vision of restoring U.S. leadership and delivering security and prosperity for all Americans.</p>
<p>The Department of State and USAID use diplomatic and development tools to advance U.S. interests and deliver for all Americans. After four years of neglect, the State and USAID Budget request significantly increases funding for climate initiatives, makes needed investments in global health security, enhances our support for the promotion and protection of democracy, human rights, labor rights, and rule of law, reasserts U.S. global humanitarian leadership, including rebuilding U.S. refugee resettlement, increases economic and security assistance to Central America to address the root causes of irregular migration, reinvigorates the diplomatic and development workforce, and meets our international obligations, all while supporting efforts to advance racial equity and inclusion in foreign assistance and within foreign affairs agencies.</p>
<p>The President’s FY 2022 budget request includes $58.5 billion for the Department of State and USAID, an increase of $5.5 billion or 10 percent over the FY 2021 enacted level. It:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ensures the United States is Better Prepared to Prevent, Detect, and Respond to Future Biological Threats and Pandemics. </strong>The budget request expands American leadership in global health security in order to address long-term impacts of COVID-19 and to prevent, prepare for, and respond to future infectious disease outbreaks, whether naturally occurring, accidental, or deliberate. The budget request includes $10.1 billion for global health programs of which nearly $1 billion would fund global health security programs and support to end the COVID-19 pandemic, an increase of over $800 million above the FY 2021 enacted level. This nearly $1 billion would expand Global Health Security Agenda capacity-building programs to additional countries and increase investments in crosscutting research and viral discovery programs to detect and stamp out future infectious disease outbreaks before they become pandemics. These funds also support global pandemic preparedness efforts, including a health security financing mechanism developed alongside U.S. partners and allies to catalyze increased investment in pandemic prevention and preparedness for future outbreaks. Funding would also support the global Access to COVID-19 Tools (ACT) Accelerator platform to deploy tests, treatments, and vaccines around the world. Global health activities supported in the FY 2022 budget request build upon existing global health security infrastructure developed through decades of U.S. investment as well as emergency supplemental funding over the past year and the $10.8 billion provided in the American Rescue Plan Act for the Department and USAID to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic.</li>
<li><strong>Responds to the Climate Crisis. </strong>The budget request tackles the climate emergency head-on, providing more than $2.5 billion across all government agencies for international climate programs, more than four times the 2021 enacted level, to rally the world against this urgent threat that cannot be defeated by a single nation alone. The budget request includes $1.25 billion for the Green Climate Fund, with funding split between the Department and Treasury. The request also includes over $700 million in State and USAID bilateral, regional, and global climate-related assistance. The United States would provide $485 million to support other multilateral climate initiatives, including $100 million for international climate adaptation programs. The budget request also proposes funding for staffing increases to develop new centers of climate expertise at the Department of State and the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation. By reestablishing U.S. leadership on climate change, these increased climate investments would revitalize America’s coalitions with its allies and help mobilize the rest of the international community to increase its contributions.</li>
<li><strong>Revitalizes Collaborative U.S. Leadership in Central America. </strong>It is critical to revitalize U.S. leadership in Central America and to address the root causes of irregular migration from Central America to the United States. To that end, the budget request invests $861 million in the region as a first step toward a four-year commitment of $4 billion. These resources would allow the United States to work with partners in the region to strengthen host government accountability in curtailing endemic corruption, expanding economic opportunity, improving governance, and reducing violence and insecurity.</li>
<li><strong>Restores America’s Standing in International Organizations. </strong>To ensure we are in a position to uphold and defend the principles and values of the international order we helped build, we must meet U.S. commitments to international peacekeeping and pay our assessed dues to international organizations on time and in full, reversing the chronic underfunding of these critical programs by the previous administration. The budget request provides approximately $500 million more than last year, for a total of nearly $2 billion, for UN peacekeeping missions, including $300 million to begin reducing cap-related arrears accumulated over the past four years, with the intention of fully paying these arrears within two years. The budget request also makes investments to restore America’s standing in the world by providing funding, including for the payment of arrears where applicable, to support international organizations and related programs, including the World Health Organization, the UN Population Fund, and the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights, while continuing to press for needed reforms. These investments position us to lead in international organizations with our like-minded partners.</li>
<li><strong>Advances U.S. Humanitarian Leadership, Rebuilds U.S. Refugee Resettlement. </strong>Humanitarian needs are at historic levels as COVID-19 has exacerbated existing challenges from ongoing and new complex emergencies. The budget request provides the resources necessary to rebuild the badly damaged U.S. refugee admissions program and support up to 125,000 admissions in 2022. It provides over $10 billion in humanitarian assistance to support vulnerable people abroad, including refugees, conflict victims, and other displaced persons.</li>
<li><strong>Promotes and Defends our Democratic Values and Counters Rising Authoritarianism. </strong>This budget will enable the United States to lead efforts with our democratic allies and partners to support open and free societies, strengthen democratic institutions, combat growing authoritarianism and corruption, increase respect for human rights, support marginalized populations, and strengthen partner capacity to protect democratic systems against malign influence from China, Russia, and other authoritarian states. This programming would complement international efforts stemming from the Administration’s Summit for Democracy to strengthen democratic institutions, honestly confront nations that are backsliding, and forge a common agenda.</li>
<li><strong>Supports U.S. Partners in the Middle East and Advances Peace in the Region. </strong>The budget request fully funds U.S. commitments to key allies in the Middle East, including Israel and Jordan. The budget request funds assistance programs and humanitarian aid for Palestinians, including support for the UN Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA). The United States will maintain steadfast support for Israel as the Administration renews relations with Palestinian leadership, restores economic and humanitarian assistance for Palestinians, and works to advance freedom, prosperity, and security for the Israeli and Palestinian people alike.</li>
<li><strong>Revitalizes the Foreign Policy Workforce to Deliver for All Americans</strong>through increases in funding for the Department’s and USAID’s greatest asset, our people. The FY 2022 request proposes funding for the largest State staffing increase in a decade, building a diplomatic and development corps that fully represents America in all its talent and   By empowering our workforce and deepening our expertise, we will be able to successfully address 21st century challenges on global health, climate, and technology. State’s new Chief Diversity and Inclusion Officer will lead the charge to implement our Diversity and Inclusion Strategic Plan across the Department.</li>
<li><strong>Invests in Information Technology (IT) Modernization and Stronger Cybersecurity</strong>across State and USAID, providing more secure and mobile communication tools enabling our workforce to succeed in the modern information environment, with greater agility, collaboration, and access to data. An increase of more than $100 million for State’s cybersecurity is crucial to mitigating the evolving cybersecurity threat landscape. The Department and the Agency remain prime targets of malicious state- and non-state actors, as evidenced by the recent attacks.</li>
<li><strong>Supports Consular Services to Assist Americans, Promote Prosperity, and Advance U.S. Interests.</strong>The request includes a direct appropriation of $320 million to provide a stable source of support for consular services provided to American citizens and foreign visa applicants who come to visit, study, and invest in our communities in light of reduced fee revenue due to the pandemic, as well as continuing authorities allowing fees collected to support a wider array of consular activity through FY 2022.</li>
<li><strong>Sustains Security for our Worldwide Presence at $6.1 billion,</strong>protecting our personnel, embassies, and cybersecurity around the globe. These include initiatives to expand real-time threat monitoring, accelerate security vetting, and the construction or renovation of embassies and consulates in Vietnam, Democratic Republic of Congo, Bosnia, South Africa, and France.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, please visit <a href="https://www.state.gov/fy-2022-international-affairs-budget/">www.state.gov/cj</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The President’s Fiscal Year 2022 Budget</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-presidents-fiscal-year-2022-budget/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 18:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247220</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The Administration has submitted to Congress the President’s Budget for Fiscal Year 2022. As we continue to make progress defeating the pandemic and getting our economy back on track, this budget makes historic investments that will help us build back better, leaving us stronger at home and on the world stage.</p>
<p>The President’s Budget for FY 2022 requests $58.5 billion for the Department of State and USAID, a 10 percent increase over FY 2021 as enacted. These resources will position us to advance the Administration’s foreign policy agenda on behalf of the American people. It also reflects the importance the Administration places on U.S. global leadership and the fact that diplomacy and development are vital tools for advancing U.S. interests.</p>
<p>These increased diplomatic and foreign assistance resources will enable us to deliver for the American people by bolstering global health security, addressing the climate crisis, helping tackle the root causes of irregular migration from Central America, reasserting American leadership to promote democracy and counter rising authoritarianism, providing international humanitarian leadership, and meeting competition head on from nations that do not share our values of freedom, democracy, and respect for human rights.</p>
<p>This budget supports the Department’s consular activities that protect Americans. It also invests in our foreign policy and development workforce to ensure that it fully represents America in all its talent and diversity and that it has the necessary 21st century tools and technology at its disposal to deliver results for American taxpayers.</p>
<p>More generally, the budget includes the two historic plans the President has already put forward — the American Jobs Plan and the American Families Plan – and reinvests in education, research, public health, and other foundations of our country’s strength.  Enacting this budget this year will strengthen our Nation’s economy and lay the foundation for shared prosperity, while also improving our Nation’s long-term fiscal health.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The Administration has submitted to Congress the President’s Budget for Fiscal Year 2022. As we continue to make progress defeating the pandemic and getting our economy back on track, this budget makes historic investments that will help us build back better, leaving us stronger at home and on the world stage.</p>
<p>The President’s Budget for FY 2022 requests $58.5 billion for the Department of State and USAID, a 10 percent increase over FY 2021 as enacted. These resources will position us to advance the Administration’s foreign policy agenda on behalf of the American people. It also reflects the importance the Administration places on U.S. global leadership and the fact that diplomacy and development are vital tools for advancing U.S. interests.</p>
<p>These increased diplomatic and foreign assistance resources will enable us to deliver for the American people by bolstering global health security, addressing the climate crisis, helping tackle the root causes of irregular migration from Central America, reasserting American leadership to promote democracy and counter rising authoritarianism, providing international humanitarian leadership, and meeting competition head on from nations that do not share our values of freedom, democracy, and respect for human rights.</p>
<p>This budget supports the Department’s consular activities that protect Americans. It also invests in our foreign policy and development workforce to ensure that it fully represents America in all its talent and diversity and that it has the necessary 21st century tools and technology at its disposal to deliver results for American taxpayers.</p>
<p>More generally, the budget includes the two historic plans the President has already put forward — the American Jobs Plan and the American Families Plan – and reinvests in education, research, public health, and other foundations of our country’s strength.  Enacting this budget this year will strengthen our Nation’s economy and lay the foundation for shared prosperity, while also improving our Nation’s long-term fiscal health.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Withhold and Release Orders (WROs) for Seafood Products Imported from the Dalian Ocean Fishing Company</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/on-withhold-and-release-orders-wros-for-seafood-products-imported-from-the-dalian-ocean-fishing-company/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 17:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247199</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, an agency of the Department of Homeland Security, issued <a class="external-link" href="https://www.cbp.gov/newsroom/national-media-release/cbp-issues-withhold-release-order-chinese-fishing-fleet" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Withhold Release Orders (WROs)</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> for seafood products imported from the Dalian Ocean Fishing Company, a firm in the People’s Republic of China (PRC) for which there is credible evidence of the use of forced labor to harvest its seafood, primarily tuna.  As a result, the United States is prohibiting the import of seafood products from this company.</p>
<p>U.S. law forbids the importation of products made with forced labor.  Today’s action helps stop human rights abusers from profiting from forced labor.  It is also another example of the United States taking measures to address harmful fishing practices.  In 2020, the Department revoked more than a dozen visas for individuals complicit in illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing with links to human trafficking.</p>
<p>Reports of the use of forced labor by PRC fishing vessels were described in the Department’s <a href="https://www.state.gov/reports/2020-country-reports-on-human-rights-practices/china/">2020 Human Rights Report.</a>  The report noted other PRC firms that abuse migrant workers subjected to forced labor.  These workers are forced to work 18 to 22 hours a day, often in illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing.  They are prevented from leaving their ships while facing hunger, restricted communication, inadequate medical care, degrading living and working conditions, physical abuse, and debt-based coercion.  The Department of Labor similarly has reported on widespread use of forced labor in the PRC’s distant-water fishing fleet.</p>
<p>The United States will promote accountability for those who use forced labor to exploit individuals for profit, and we will work with our international partners to ensure that the voiceless are heard and protected.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, an agency of the Department of Homeland Security, issued <a class="external-link" href="https://www.cbp.gov/newsroom/national-media-release/cbp-issues-withhold-release-order-chinese-fishing-fleet" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Withhold Release Orders (WROs)</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> for seafood products imported from the Dalian Ocean Fishing Company, a firm in the People’s Republic of China (PRC) for which there is credible evidence of the use of forced labor to harvest its seafood, primarily tuna.  As a result, the United States is prohibiting the import of seafood products from this company.</p>
<p>U.S. law forbids the importation of products made with forced labor.  Today’s action helps stop human rights abusers from profiting from forced labor.  It is also another example of the United States taking measures to address harmful fishing practices.  In 2020, the Department revoked more than a dozen visas for individuals complicit in illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing with links to human trafficking.</p>
<p>Reports of the use of forced labor by PRC fishing vessels were described in the Department’s <a href="https://www.state.gov/reports/2020-country-reports-on-human-rights-practices/china/">2020 Human Rights Report.</a>  The report noted other PRC firms that abuse migrant workers subjected to forced labor.  These workers are forced to work 18 to 22 hours a day, often in illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing.  They are prevented from leaving their ships while facing hunger, restricted communication, inadequate medical care, degrading living and working conditions, physical abuse, and debt-based coercion.  The Department of Labor similarly has reported on widespread use of forced labor in the PRC’s distant-water fishing fleet.</p>
<p>The United States will promote accountability for those who use forced labor to exploit individuals for profit, and we will work with our international partners to ensure that the voiceless are heard and protected.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Colombian Vice President and Foreign Minister Marta Lucia Ramirez Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-colombian-vice-president-and-foreign-minister-marta-lucia-ramirez-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 15:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247142</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington D.C. </p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Good morning, everyone.  I am delighted to have the vice president and foreign minister here with us today.  The partnership between the United States and Colombia is absolutely vital.  We work together on so many different issues and in so many different ways, and it’s a particular pleasure this morning to have an opportunity for us to continue that work, to deepen the partnership on many challenges, I think some opportunities as well, and I very much look forward to the conversation.  Welcome. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">VICE PRESIDENT RAMIREZ:  Thank you very much, and Secretary Blinken, as you said, this is a long history that we have together, working together for values that we share – democracy, development, the creation of jobs.  We have a lot of common challenges, and for Colombia, it has been the most important relation.  We have to maintain this commitment to increase opportunities for our people, not only Colombia but also in the United States.  And for us, this is a relation that we really want to have in the first point always.  So thank you very much for giving us this opportunity.  And thank you because I know that you are arriving from a long trip, so this is the importance of our relation.  Thank you.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Thank you, Vice President.  Thank you all.  Have a good morning.  </span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington D.C. </p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Good morning, everyone.  I am delighted to have the vice president and foreign minister here with us today.  The partnership between the United States and Colombia is absolutely vital.  We work together on so many different issues and in so many different ways, and it’s a particular pleasure this morning to have an opportunity for us to continue that work, to deepen the partnership on many challenges, I think some opportunities as well, and I very much look forward to the conversation.  Welcome. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">VICE PRESIDENT RAMIREZ:  Thank you very much, and Secretary Blinken, as you said, this is a long history that we have together, working together for values that we share – democracy, development, the creation of jobs.  We have a lot of common challenges, and for Colombia, it has been the most important relation.  We have to maintain this commitment to increase opportunities for our people, not only Colombia but also in the United States.  And for us, this is a relation that we really want to have in the first point always.  So thank you very much for giving us this opportunity.  And thank you because I know that you are arriving from a long trip, so this is the importance of our relation.  Thank you.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Thank you, Vice President.  Thank you all.  Have a good morning.  </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>International Day of United Nations Peacekeepers</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/international-day-of-united-nations-peacekeepers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 13:38:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247035</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On May 29, the International Day of UN Peacekeepers, the United States reaffirms its unwavering commitment to UN peacekeeping.  We join the international community in honoring those who have served in UN peacekeeping operations since 1948, the more than 4,000 peacekeepers who have died in the line of duty, those who have been injured, and those who continue to risk their lives every day upholding peace.  We are heartened to see an increase of women peacekeepers every year; they inspire and support women and girls to be leaders in their communities and agents of change.</p>
<p>At its core, peacekeeping is about helping people whose lives have been ravaged by conflict and creating space for durable peace to take root.  We are focused on promoting the protection of civilians, sustainable political solutions, human rights, and gender equality as priority aspects of peacekeeping missions – these efforts help build the conditions for enduring peace.</p>
<p>We are also advancing improvements and reforms in several key areas: providing missions with achievable and realistic mandates; building the capacity of troop- and police-contributing countries and providing them the necessary resources to effectively and safely implement those mandates; enhancing peacekeeper performance, accountability, safety, and security; and preventing sexual exploitation and abuse by peacekeepers and holding perpetrators accountable.</p>
<p>While the United States is the largest financial contributor to UN peacekeeping, we also contribute key, scarce capabilities to UN peacekeeping and invest heavily in long-term bilateral capacity-building partnerships through the Global Peace Operations Initiative and the International Police Peacekeeping Operations Support program.</p>
<p>UN peacekeeping continues to be one of the most effective mechanisms for promoting international peace and security and protecting the world’s most vulnerable populations.  The United States is committed to strengthening and reforming UN peacekeeping to help make it as effective and efficient as possible in delivering on its vital global mission.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On May 29, the International Day of UN Peacekeepers, the United States reaffirms its unwavering commitment to UN peacekeeping.  We join the international community in honoring those who have served in UN peacekeeping operations since 1948, the more than 4,000 peacekeepers who have died in the line of duty, those who have been injured, and those who continue to risk their lives every day upholding peace.  We are heartened to see an increase of women peacekeepers every year; they inspire and support women and girls to be leaders in their communities and agents of change.</p>
<p>At its core, peacekeeping is about helping people whose lives have been ravaged by conflict and creating space for durable peace to take root.  We are focused on promoting the protection of civilians, sustainable political solutions, human rights, and gender equality as priority aspects of peacekeeping missions – these efforts help build the conditions for enduring peace.</p>
<p>We are also advancing improvements and reforms in several key areas: providing missions with achievable and realistic mandates; building the capacity of troop- and police-contributing countries and providing them the necessary resources to effectively and safely implement those mandates; enhancing peacekeeper performance, accountability, safety, and security; and preventing sexual exploitation and abuse by peacekeepers and holding perpetrators accountable.</p>
<p>While the United States is the largest financial contributor to UN peacekeeping, we also contribute key, scarce capabilities to UN peacekeeping and invest heavily in long-term bilateral capacity-building partnerships through the Global Peace Operations Initiative and the International Police Peacekeeping Operations Support program.</p>
<p>UN peacekeeping continues to be one of the most effective mechanisms for promoting international peace and security and protecting the world’s most vulnerable populations.  The United States is committed to strengthening and reforming UN peacekeeping to help make it as effective and efficient as possible in delivering on its vital global mission.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Samoa Independence Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/samoa-independence-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 13:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247053</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I offer my congratulations to the people of Samoa on the occasion of the fifty-ninth anniversary of your independence on June 1, 2021.</p>
<p>The United States and Samoa have enjoyed a close friendship that began with your independence in 1962.  Most recently, we have worked together to combat COVID-19 and other health threats.  The United States is committed to collaborating with you and our partners in the region to help ensure Samoa and neighboring Pacific Island countries recover quickly from the impacts of the pandemic.  We also look forward to working with Samoa and other Pacific Island countries to combat climate change.</p>
<p>This year, in the aftermath of the general election in Samoa, the United States calls on Samoa’s leaders to respect democratic processes and uphold the rule of law.  These values, and our shared love of freedom and human rights, are the foundation of our democratic societies.</p>
<p>Happy Independence Day to all Samoans.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I offer my congratulations to the people of Samoa on the occasion of the fifty-ninth anniversary of your independence on June 1, 2021.</p>
<p>The United States and Samoa have enjoyed a close friendship that began with your independence in 1962.  Most recently, we have worked together to combat COVID-19 and other health threats.  The United States is committed to collaborating with you and our partners in the region to help ensure Samoa and neighboring Pacific Island countries recover quickly from the impacts of the pandemic.  We also look forward to working with Samoa and other Pacific Island countries to combat climate change.</p>
<p>This year, in the aftermath of the general election in Samoa, the United States calls on Samoa’s leaders to respect democratic processes and uphold the rule of law.  These values, and our shared love of freedom and human rights, are the foundation of our democratic societies.</p>
<p>Happy Independence Day to all Samoans.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Azerbaijan Republic Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/azerbaijan-republic-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 04:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246970</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Azerbaijan as you celebrate Republic Day and mark the 1918 establishment of the first democratic government in the Muslim world.</p>
<p>The United States values the thirty years of partnership with Azerbaijan on economic, energy, and security cooperation, and our ongoing dialogue on improving Azerbaijan’s respect for human rights and the rule of law.  We recognize Azerbaijan’s significant contributions to European energy diversification through the Southern Gas Corridor.  Strong institutions and processes that respect human rights and fundamental freedoms, rule of law, transparency, and accountability, are vital to us achieving our shared goals and building stronger and deeper ties.</p>
<p>The United States also values the connections fostered between thousands of Azerbaijani and American citizens through people-to-people exchanges, as well as through our Embassies’ public outreach.</p>
<p>As a co-chair of the OSCE Minsk Group, the United States remains committed to helping the sides negotiate a long-term political settlement of the Nagorno-Karabakh conflict and address the humanitarian impact of the fighting, including the release of all detainees, accounting for those missing, and the full and expeditious exchange of remains.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Azerbaijan as you celebrate Republic Day and mark the 1918 establishment of the first democratic government in the Muslim world.</p>
<p>The United States values the thirty years of partnership with Azerbaijan on economic, energy, and security cooperation, and our ongoing dialogue on improving Azerbaijan’s respect for human rights and the rule of law.  We recognize Azerbaijan’s significant contributions to European energy diversification through the Southern Gas Corridor.  Strong institutions and processes that respect human rights and fundamental freedoms, rule of law, transparency, and accountability, are vital to us achieving our shared goals and building stronger and deeper ties.</p>
<p>The United States also values the connections fostered between thousands of Azerbaijani and American citizens through people-to-people exchanges, as well as through our Embassies’ public outreach.</p>
<p>As a co-chair of the OSCE Minsk Group, the United States remains committed to helping the sides negotiate a long-term political settlement of the Nagorno-Karabakh conflict and address the humanitarian impact of the fighting, including the release of all detainees, accounting for those missing, and the full and expeditious exchange of remains.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Vietnamese Foreign Minister Son</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-vietnamese-foreign-minister-son/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 01:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246975</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Vietnamese Foreign Minister Bui Thanh Son.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Son celebrated the strength of the U.S.-Vietnam Comprehensive Partnership and reaffirmed our shared commitment to protecting and preserving the rules-based order in the South China Sea.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister also discussed ongoing concerns regarding the military coup in Burma and commitments to addressing climate change and tackling COVID-19.  Secretary Blinken emphasized U.S. commitment to ASEAN centrality, the <a href="https://mekonguspartnership.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mekong-U.S. Partnership</a>, and support of a strong, prosperous, and independent Vietnam that respects human rights and the rule of law.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Vietnamese Foreign Minister Bui Thanh Son.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Son celebrated the strength of the U.S.-Vietnam Comprehensive Partnership and reaffirmed our shared commitment to protecting and preserving the rules-based order in the South China Sea.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister also discussed ongoing concerns regarding the military coup in Burma and commitments to addressing climate change and tackling COVID-19.  Secretary Blinken emphasized U.S. commitment to ASEAN centrality, the <a href="https://mekonguspartnership.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mekong-U.S. Partnership</a>, and support of a strong, prosperous, and independent Vietnam that respects human rights and the rule of law.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
