<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 12:30:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Israeli Foreign Minister Gabi Ashkenazi Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-israeli-foreign-minister-gabi-ashkenazi-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 12:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246026</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Jerusalem</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER ASHKENAZI:  </strong>Very briefly.  It’s an honor and pleasure to have my friend the Secretary of State for his first official visit in Israel and welcoming him on behalf of the government and the people of Israel.  The United States is our closest ally.  I’m committed, as I’m sure the Secretary, for expanding the relationship.  It’s an excellent opportunity to thank their President of the United States and the Secretary of State and his team for their unwavering support of the State of Israel.  It was no surprise to me from the day one that we discussed.  Thank you for the dedicated move and the close relation and involvement during the last event.  I wish you a fruitful visit in Israel.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you very, very much.  It&#8217;s wonderful to be here.  It&#8217;s particularly wonderful to get a chance to spend some time with Gabi, with the foreign minister.  We know each other very well because we&#8217;ve spent a lot of time on the phone together over these past months now, and certainly over the last few weeks.  But I&#8217;m particularly pleased to be here and get a chance to spend some time in person.</p>
<p>I think Gabi said it very, very well.  I&#8217;m here, as I said earlier, to reaffirm the strong commitment of United States to Israel&#8217;s security, to the partnership between us, to move forward now on dealing with the humanitarian situation in Gaza and also starting to rebuild, to re-engage with the Palestinian community and Palestinian Authority.  And I hope to start to move things in a positive direction where we can make material progress in the lives of Israelis and Palestinians alike.  We have a lot of work to do, but we&#8217;re grateful to have close parties.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER ASHKENAZI:  </strong>The Secretary has an impossible schedule, so thank you, we have to move.  Thank you very much.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Jerusalem</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER ASHKENAZI:  </strong>Very briefly.  It’s an honor and pleasure to have my friend the Secretary of State for his first official visit in Israel and welcoming him on behalf of the government and the people of Israel.  The United States is our closest ally.  I’m committed, as I’m sure the Secretary, for expanding the relationship.  It’s an excellent opportunity to thank their President of the United States and the Secretary of State and his team for their unwavering support of the State of Israel.  It was no surprise to me from the day one that we discussed.  Thank you for the dedicated move and the close relation and involvement during the last event.  I wish you a fruitful visit in Israel.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you very, very much.  It&#8217;s wonderful to be here.  It&#8217;s particularly wonderful to get a chance to spend some time with Gabi, with the foreign minister.  We know each other very well because we&#8217;ve spent a lot of time on the phone together over these past months now, and certainly over the last few weeks.  But I&#8217;m particularly pleased to be here and get a chance to spend some time in person.</p>
<p>I think Gabi said it very, very well.  I&#8217;m here, as I said earlier, to reaffirm the strong commitment of United States to Israel&#8217;s security, to the partnership between us, to move forward now on dealing with the humanitarian situation in Gaza and also starting to rebuild, to re-engage with the Palestinian community and Palestinian Authority.  And I hope to start to move things in a positive direction where we can make material progress in the lives of Israelis and Palestinians alike.  We have a lot of work to do, but we&#8217;re grateful to have close parties.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER ASHKENAZI:  </strong>The Secretary has an impossible schedule, so thank you, we have to move.  Thank you very much.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu Statements to the Press</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-israeli-prime-minister-benjamin-netanyahu-statements-to-the-press/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 11:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Jerusalem</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MININSTER NETANYAHU:</strong>  Secretary Blinken, Tony, welcome to Jerusalem, your first visit as the Secretary of State.  I have – since we’re running – we had a long discussion, and we’re running late, so I want to be very brief and speak about three points.</p>
<p>The first point is a vote of thanks to President Biden and you for firmly supporting Israel’s right of self-defense.  I have to say that Secretary Blinken, in a previous capacity in 2014, when we had another round of engagement against Hamas aggression, supported us by having Iron Dome replenishments, a quarter of a billion dollars, that you personally shepherded through the system very quickly.  And we remember it and we’re very grateful to you.  And you are giving meaning to this now again with replenishments of Iron Dome interceptors that saved civilian lives on both sides, and we’re grateful for that too.  We too will give meaning to our commitment to our self-defense.  If Hamas breaks the calm and attacks Israel, our response will be very powerful.  And we have discussed ways of how to work together to prevent Hamas rearmament with weapons and means of aggression.</p>
<p>The second point is – naturally, is Iran.  We discussed many regional issues, but none is greater than Iran.  And I can tell you that I hope that the United States will not go back to the old JCPOA because we believe that that deal paves the way for Iran to have an arsenal of nuclear weapons with international legitimacy.  We also reiterated that whatever happens, Israel will always reserve the right to defend itself against a regime committed to our destruction, committed to getting the weapons of mass destruction for that end.</p>
<p>The third point is peace.  We need to work together to expand normalization between Israel and the Arab and the Muslim world, and deepen the peace treaties that we already have.  We discussed also how to improve the lives and the conditions of the Palestinians, the humanitarian conditions in Gaza, including the question of the return of our MIAs and two civilians who are there, as well as building economic growth for Judea and Samaria, the West Bank, with international cooperation and participation, and for peace itself with the Palestinians, a formal peace.  I think President Biden was absolutely correct when he said you’re not going to get peace until Israel is recognized as an independent Jewish state.  And that is the key.  I couldn’t agree more with President Biden.</p>
<p>And I couldn’t be happier than welcoming you here and your delegation in Jerusalem.  We have a lot to work for.  We have common goals of peace, security, and prosperity, and I look forward to working with you on those in this visit and more, so welcome.  Welcome.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Prime Minister, thank you.  Thank you very, very much.  Thank you for hosting us today.  Thank you for the very good and lengthy conversation.  I’m looking forward also to spending some more time with some of our colleagues, with Foreign Minister Ashkenazi, Defense Minister Gantz, as well later with President Abbas and other Palestinian leaders.</p>
<p>President Biden asked me to come here today, really, for four reasons:  First, to demonstrate the commitment of the United States to Israel’s security, to start to work toward greater stability and reduce tensions in the West Bank and Jerusalem, to support urgent humanitarian and reconstruction assistance for Gaza, to benefit the Palestinian people, and to continue to rebuild our relationship with the Palestinian people and the Palestinian Authority.  Intense behind-the-scenes diplomacy led by President Biden, working very closely with the prime minister, helped produce last week’s ceasefire.  Now, we believe we must build on it.</p>
<p>That starts with the recognition that losses on both sides were profound. Casualties are often reduced to numbers but behind every number is an individual human being – a daughter, a son, a father, a mother, a grandparent, a best friend.  And as the Talmud teaches, to lose a life is to lose the whole world, whether that life is Palestinian or Israeli.  I underscored to the prime minister something that President Biden made crystal-clear throughout the violence:  The United States fully supports Israel’s right to defend itself against attacks such as the thousands of rockets fired by Hamas indiscriminately against Israeli civilians.</p>
<p>For the President, I think as many of you know, this commitment is personal.  It runs deep.  He has been one of Israel’s most steadfast supporters for the last 50 years, having worked closely with every prime minister starting with Golda Meir and now with Prime Minister Netanyahu.</p>
<p>As the prime minister mentioned, we had a detailed discussion about Israel’s security needs, including replenishing Iron Dome.  We’ll continue to strengthen all aspects of our longstanding partnership.  And that includes consulting closely with Israel, as we did today, on the ongoing negotiations in Vienna around a potential return to the Iran nuclear agreement, at the same time as we continue to work together to counter Iran’s destabilizing actions in the region.</p>
<p>We know that to prevent a return to violence, we have to use the space created to address a larger set of underlying issues and challenges, and that begins with tackling the grave humanitarian situation in Gaza and starting to rebuild.  The United States will work to rally international support around that effort while also making our own significant contributions, including some that I’ll announce later today.  We’ll work with our partners, closely with all to ensure that Hamas does not benefit from the reconstruction assistance.</p>
<p>At the same time, we need to work to expand opportunity for Palestinians in Gaza and in the West Bank, including by strengthening the private sector, expanding trade and investment, and other means.  Assistance and investment like these will help foster a more stable environment that benefits Palestinians and also benefits Israelis.</p>
<p>Prime Minister and I had a chance to discuss other steps that need to be taken by leaders on both sides to set a better course for their shared future.  As President Biden has said, we believe that Palestinians and Israelis equally deserve to live safely and securely; to enjoy equal measures of freedom, opportunity, and democracy; to be treated with dignity.  We also discussed some of the intercommunal violence that erupted in Israel during the conflict, and healing these wounds will take leadership at every level of society, from elected officials to community leaders to neighbors.  And we very much welcome the statements the prime minister made and members of his government made condemning the attacks regardless of whom they targeted.</p>
<p>In our own country, in the United States, we’ve witnessed a shocking eruption of anti-Semitic attacks.  As President Biden said just yesterday, they are despicable and they must stop.  There’s a lot of hard work ahead to restore hope, respect, and some trust across communities.  But we’ve seen the alternative, and I think that should cause all of us to redouble our efforts to preserve the peace and improve the lives of Israelis and Palestinians alike.</p>
<p>But Prime Minister, again, thank you so much for all the time, thank you for the very, very good conversation, and we look forward to doing a lot of work together.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER NETANYAHU:</strong>  And thank you and the President for your strong statements against anti-Semitism masquerading as anti-Zionism, but it’s anti-Semitism, and you took a bold position, clear position, and we appreciate it.  I think all decent people, decent people everywhere appreciate that stance.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Jerusalem</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MININSTER NETANYAHU:</strong>  Secretary Blinken, Tony, welcome to Jerusalem, your first visit as the Secretary of State.  I have – since we’re running – we had a long discussion, and we’re running late, so I want to be very brief and speak about three points.</p>
<p>The first point is a vote of thanks to President Biden and you for firmly supporting Israel’s right of self-defense.  I have to say that Secretary Blinken, in a previous capacity in 2014, when we had another round of engagement against Hamas aggression, supported us by having Iron Dome replenishments, a quarter of a billion dollars, that you personally shepherded through the system very quickly.  And we remember it and we’re very grateful to you.  And you are giving meaning to this now again with replenishments of Iron Dome interceptors that saved civilian lives on both sides, and we’re grateful for that too.  We too will give meaning to our commitment to our self-defense.  If Hamas breaks the calm and attacks Israel, our response will be very powerful.  And we have discussed ways of how to work together to prevent Hamas rearmament with weapons and means of aggression.</p>
<p>The second point is – naturally, is Iran.  We discussed many regional issues, but none is greater than Iran.  And I can tell you that I hope that the United States will not go back to the old JCPOA because we believe that that deal paves the way for Iran to have an arsenal of nuclear weapons with international legitimacy.  We also reiterated that whatever happens, Israel will always reserve the right to defend itself against a regime committed to our destruction, committed to getting the weapons of mass destruction for that end.</p>
<p>The third point is peace.  We need to work together to expand normalization between Israel and the Arab and the Muslim world, and deepen the peace treaties that we already have.  We discussed also how to improve the lives and the conditions of the Palestinians, the humanitarian conditions in Gaza, including the question of the return of our MIAs and two civilians who are there, as well as building economic growth for Judea and Samaria, the West Bank, with international cooperation and participation, and for peace itself with the Palestinians, a formal peace.  I think President Biden was absolutely correct when he said you’re not going to get peace until Israel is recognized as an independent Jewish state.  And that is the key.  I couldn’t agree more with President Biden.</p>
<p>And I couldn’t be happier than welcoming you here and your delegation in Jerusalem.  We have a lot to work for.  We have common goals of peace, security, and prosperity, and I look forward to working with you on those in this visit and more, so welcome.  Welcome.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Prime Minister, thank you.  Thank you very, very much.  Thank you for hosting us today.  Thank you for the very good and lengthy conversation.  I’m looking forward also to spending some more time with some of our colleagues, with Foreign Minister Ashkenazi, Defense Minister Gantz, as well later with President Abbas and other Palestinian leaders.</p>
<p>President Biden asked me to come here today, really, for four reasons:  First, to demonstrate the commitment of the United States to Israel’s security, to start to work toward greater stability and reduce tensions in the West Bank and Jerusalem, to support urgent humanitarian and reconstruction assistance for Gaza, to benefit the Palestinian people, and to continue to rebuild our relationship with the Palestinian people and the Palestinian Authority.  Intense behind-the-scenes diplomacy led by President Biden, working very closely with the prime minister, helped produce last week’s ceasefire.  Now, we believe we must build on it.</p>
<p>That starts with the recognition that losses on both sides were profound. Casualties are often reduced to numbers but behind every number is an individual human being – a daughter, a son, a father, a mother, a grandparent, a best friend.  And as the Talmud teaches, to lose a life is to lose the whole world, whether that life is Palestinian or Israeli.  I underscored to the prime minister something that President Biden made crystal-clear throughout the violence:  The United States fully supports Israel’s right to defend itself against attacks such as the thousands of rockets fired by Hamas indiscriminately against Israeli civilians.</p>
<p>For the President, I think as many of you know, this commitment is personal.  It runs deep.  He has been one of Israel’s most steadfast supporters for the last 50 years, having worked closely with every prime minister starting with Golda Meir and now with Prime Minister Netanyahu.</p>
<p>As the prime minister mentioned, we had a detailed discussion about Israel’s security needs, including replenishing Iron Dome.  We’ll continue to strengthen all aspects of our longstanding partnership.  And that includes consulting closely with Israel, as we did today, on the ongoing negotiations in Vienna around a potential return to the Iran nuclear agreement, at the same time as we continue to work together to counter Iran’s destabilizing actions in the region.</p>
<p>We know that to prevent a return to violence, we have to use the space created to address a larger set of underlying issues and challenges, and that begins with tackling the grave humanitarian situation in Gaza and starting to rebuild.  The United States will work to rally international support around that effort while also making our own significant contributions, including some that I’ll announce later today.  We’ll work with our partners, closely with all to ensure that Hamas does not benefit from the reconstruction assistance.</p>
<p>At the same time, we need to work to expand opportunity for Palestinians in Gaza and in the West Bank, including by strengthening the private sector, expanding trade and investment, and other means.  Assistance and investment like these will help foster a more stable environment that benefits Palestinians and also benefits Israelis.</p>
<p>Prime Minister and I had a chance to discuss other steps that need to be taken by leaders on both sides to set a better course for their shared future.  As President Biden has said, we believe that Palestinians and Israelis equally deserve to live safely and securely; to enjoy equal measures of freedom, opportunity, and democracy; to be treated with dignity.  We also discussed some of the intercommunal violence that erupted in Israel during the conflict, and healing these wounds will take leadership at every level of society, from elected officials to community leaders to neighbors.  And we very much welcome the statements the prime minister made and members of his government made condemning the attacks regardless of whom they targeted.</p>
<p>In our own country, in the United States, we’ve witnessed a shocking eruption of anti-Semitic attacks.  As President Biden said just yesterday, they are despicable and they must stop.  There’s a lot of hard work ahead to restore hope, respect, and some trust across communities.  But we’ve seen the alternative, and I think that should cause all of us to redouble our efforts to preserve the peace and improve the lives of Israelis and Palestinians alike.</p>
<p>But Prime Minister, again, thank you so much for all the time, thank you for the very, very good conversation, and we look forward to doing a lot of work together.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER NETANYAHU:</strong>  And thank you and the President for your strong statements against anti-Semitism masquerading as anti-Zionism, but it’s anti-Semitism, and you took a bold position, clear position, and we appreciate it.  I think all decent people, decent people everywhere appreciate that stance.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Irish Minister for Foreign Affairs and Defense Minister Coveney</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-irish-minister-for-foreign-affairs-and-defense-minister-coveney/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245949</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Irish Minister for Foreign Affairs and Defense Simon Coveney.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Coveney reaffirmed the strong bilateral relationship between the United States and Ireland and Ireland’s role as an enduring Transatlantic partner.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister condemned the outrageous diversion of Ryanair Flight 4978 in Belarus, and they discussed the status of JCPOA negotiations, Ireland’s role on the UN Security Council as a non-permanent member, and other shared foreign policy priorities.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Irish Minister for Foreign Affairs and Defense Simon Coveney.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Coveney reaffirmed the strong bilateral relationship between the United States and Ireland and Ireland’s role as an enduring Transatlantic partner.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister condemned the outrageous diversion of Ryanair Flight 4978 in Belarus, and they discussed the status of JCPOA negotiations, Ireland’s role on the UN Security Council as a non-permanent member, and other shared foreign policy priorities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Return Travel on Recently Expired U.S. Passports</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/return-travel-on-recently-expired-u-s-passports/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245945</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The welfare and safety of U.S. citizens abroad is the highest priority of the Department of State. To alleviate travel difficulties and unprecedented appointment backlogs created by the global COVID-19 pandemic, the State Department and the Department of Homeland Security are working together to facilitate U.S. citizens’ return to the United States.</p>
<p>U.S. citizens currently overseas whose passports expired on or after January 1, 2020, may be able to use their expired U.S. passport for direct return travel to the United States until December 31, 2021. Certain criteria apply, and we encourage U.S. citizens to confirm their eligibility for traveling on an expired passport at <a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/traveladvisories/ea/covid-19-information.html">https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/traveladvisories/ea/covid-19-information.html</a> prior to finalizing travel arrangements.</p>
<p>U.S. Customs and Border Protection (DHS CBP) officers will accept for admission certain expired U.S. passports, thereby assisting U.S. citizens who have been affected by appointment backlogs at embassies and consulates overseas caused by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>Recently expired passports cannot be used to travel from the United States to an international destination or to travel to a foreign country for any length of stay longer than an airport connection en route to the United States or to a United States territory.</p>
<p>The State Department continues to strongly recommend U.S. citizens reconsider travel abroad and postpone their trips if possible. We also remind U.S. citizens who wish to return to the United States that proof of a negative COVID-19 test result, taken within 72 hours of their flight’s departure, is required for air travel to the United States. For those wishing to renew their passport upon their return to the United States, current processing times can be found at <a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/passports.html">https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/passports.html</a>.</p>
<p>For more information, please see our website at <a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel.html">travel.state.gov</a>.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:CAPRESSREQUESTS@state.gov">CAPRESSREQUESTS@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The welfare and safety of U.S. citizens abroad is the highest priority of the Department of State. To alleviate travel difficulties and unprecedented appointment backlogs created by the global COVID-19 pandemic, the State Department and the Department of Homeland Security are working together to facilitate U.S. citizens’ return to the United States.</p>
<p>U.S. citizens currently overseas whose passports expired on or after January 1, 2020, may be able to use their expired U.S. passport for direct return travel to the United States until December 31, 2021. Certain criteria apply, and we encourage U.S. citizens to confirm their eligibility for traveling on an expired passport at <a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/traveladvisories/ea/covid-19-information.html">https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/traveladvisories/ea/covid-19-information.html</a> prior to finalizing travel arrangements.</p>
<p>U.S. Customs and Border Protection (DHS CBP) officers will accept for admission certain expired U.S. passports, thereby assisting U.S. citizens who have been affected by appointment backlogs at embassies and consulates overseas caused by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>Recently expired passports cannot be used to travel from the United States to an international destination or to travel to a foreign country for any length of stay longer than an airport connection en route to the United States or to a United States territory.</p>
<p>The State Department continues to strongly recommend U.S. citizens reconsider travel abroad and postpone their trips if possible. We also remind U.S. citizens who wish to return to the United States that proof of a negative COVID-19 test result, taken within 72 hours of their flight’s departure, is required for air travel to the United States. For those wishing to renew their passport upon their return to the United States, current processing times can be found at <a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/passports.html">https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/passports.html</a>.</p>
<p>For more information, please see our website at <a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel.html">travel.state.gov</a>.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:CAPRESSREQUESTS@state.gov">CAPRESSREQUESTS@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with German Foreign Minister Maas</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-german-foreign-minister-maas-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245942</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with German Foreign Minister Heiko Maas. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Maas discussed coordination on next steps to respond to events in Belarus and relief efforts in Gaza, as well as the importance of revitalizing the NATO Alliance through an ambitious NATO 2030 process. The Secretary also reiterated U.S. concerns about the Nord Stream 2 pipeline.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with German Foreign Minister Heiko Maas. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Maas discussed coordination on next steps to respond to events in Belarus and relief efforts in Gaza, as well as the importance of revitalizing the NATO Alliance through an ambitious NATO 2030 process. The Secretary also reiterated U.S. concerns about the Nord Stream 2 pipeline.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with UAE Foreign Minister Sheikh bin Zayed</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-uae-foreign-minister-sheikh-bin-zayed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245939</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with UAE Foreign Minister Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed. The Secretary and Foreign Minister expressed their support for the ceasefire between Israel, Hamas, and other parties in Gaza. Secretary Blinken thanked the Foreign Minister for the UAE’s efforts to de-escalate the conflict and discussed the need to explore new paths to achieve peace. The Secretary also raised the importance of reconstruction efforts in Gaza.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with UAE Foreign Minister Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed. The Secretary and Foreign Minister expressed their support for the ceasefire between Israel, Hamas, and other parties in Gaza. Secretary Blinken thanked the Foreign Minister for the UAE’s efforts to de-escalate the conflict and discussed the need to explore new paths to achieve peace. The Secretary also raised the importance of reconstruction efforts in Gaza.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Briefing with Senior State Department Official on the Secretary’s Upcoming Travel to Jerusalem, Ramallah, Cairo, and Amman</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-with-senior-state-department-official-on-the-secretarys-upcoming-travel-to-jerusalem-ramallah-cairo-and-amman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 15:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Good morning, everyone.  Thanks for joining this call, and especially thanks for joining it on short notice.</p>
<p>As you saw from the department as well as from the White House this morning, Secretary Blinken will be traveling to Jerusalem, Ramallah, Cairo, and Amman at the request of President Biden and will be departing later today.  We wanted to give you an opportunity to hear a little bit more about this travel and to ask questions.</p>
<p>We have with us this morning a senior State Department official to offer a bit more context and to take your questions.  This call is embargoed until the end of the call.  It is also on background.  You can attribute what you hear to a senior State Department official.  Just for the knowledge of those on this call, you’ll be hearing today from , who will be speaking and answering your questions, but again, he will be referred to as a senior State Department official, and this is embargoed until the end of the call.</p>
<p>So with that, I will turn it over to our speaker.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Thank you, and good morning, everyone.  Thank you for joining.  I want to speak to you on the Secretary’s upcoming trip to Israel, the West Bank, Egypt, and Jordan, as well as take your questions after this bit, but first I want to recognize the important development of last week, the ceasefire led by Egypt.</p>
<p>This ceasefire was agreed to after 11 days of violence which tragically claimed the lives of innocent Palestinians and Israelis, including children, and it’s just really heartbreaking.  The United States wants to convey our deepest condolences to the families who have lost loved ones in the conflict, and our thoughts go out to those who are wounded.</p>
<p>We’re relieved the violence has come to an end, and I just really want to share that the U.S. worked tirelessly with all our partners in the region, including Israelis and Palestinians in public, but much, much more importantly, behind the scenes to help the ceasefire come about.  We really appreciate the important role played by Egypt, which was critical in the effort to mediate an end to the violence, and also really appreciate the roles of Jordan and Qatar and other partners who played a role here.</p>
<p>Look, in the wake of the ceasefire, Secretary Blinken will be traveling to Israel and the West Bank today and tomorrow, where he’ll meet with Israeli and Palestinian leaders.  He’ll then move on to Egypt and Jordan, where he’ll meet with leaders there to discuss recovery efforts and a means of working together to build better futures for people here on the ground and in the region.</p>
<p>Again, we’re incredibly relieved at the terrible violence which tore apart the lives of so many innocents has ended, and we’re committed to supporting all efforts to a lasting peace.  The Secretary looks forward to meeting regional leaders and discussing how the U.S. can support Israelis and Palestinians to rebuild and address the underlying causes that led to this crisis, and by advancing equal measures of freedom, security, and prosperity for Israelis and Palestinians alike in tangible ways.</p>
<p>With that, I’d love to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Great, thanks very much.  We will start with the line of Nick Wadhams, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hey, I’m here.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Yes.  Go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks.  , thank you.  It’s a short trip.  Can you give us a little more detail on what the Secretary hopes to achieve from this?  The ceasefire has already been signed.  Is it the hope that he will set them on the course toward actually trying to jumpstart broader peace talks, a lasting settlement?  Or is he more just hoping to provide impetus so that this ceasefire sticks?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Thank you.  In the first instance, the most important thing is that the ceasefire does hold.  It’s an – extremely important that it does.  We just – we don’t want to see a return to the bloodshed that was heartbreaking during the 11-day conflict.  And we’re certainly going to look for ways to improve Israeli and Palestinian lives, and as we’ve said over and over again, advance freedom, security, and prosperity for Israelis and Palestinians alike, hopefully in tangible ways in the immediate term.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Let’s go to the line of Humeyra Pamuk.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello?</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Yes, we have you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Okay.  Thanks for this.  Just a quick follow-up on Nick and something else as well.  The Secretary and others have said the focus at the moment is to keep the ceasefire intact, and he just said that, and rebuild as well.  But just to push you a little bit on that because I really didn’t hear an answer, could this be an opportunity to lay the – at least the groundwork for future peace talks?  And if yes, what exactly will you be doing towards that?</p>
<p>And the second one is:  How can the U.S. guarantee aid to Gaza won’t be diverted toward replenishing the Hamas arsenal?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  So on the second question, we’re going to be working in partnership with the United Nations and the Palestinian Authority to kind of channel aid there in a manner that does its best to go to the people of Gaza.  I’m also sure that the Government of Egypt will have some role in that.  As we’ve seen in life, as we all know in life, there are no guarantees, but we’re going to do everything that we can to ensure that this assistance reaches the people who need it the most.</p>
<p>Again, regarding your question, we’re really focused primarily on ensuring that the ceasefire sticks and taking the steps to – taking tangible steps to advance the quality of people’s lives: advance their freedom, advance their security, and advance their prosperity.  We believe that in the immediate term, that’s what’s feasible and that’s what’s important.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll go to Barak Ravid.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Inaudible) questions.  First, is the Secretary going to meet also Minister of Defense Gantz and head of opposition, Lapid?  It wasn’t mentioned in the statement that was released.</p>
<p>And second, there seems to be quite a lot of donor fatigue around the world, and many countries are saying that they’re not going to give again money to reconstruct Gaza without the broader context of a two-state solution.  How are you going to deal with this position?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  , do you want to comment anything on the schedule?</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Barak, the – we’ll have more details on the schedule as we get closer to the ground, and we’ll update as we can.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Thanks, .  So look, on donor fatigue, we acknowledge that, we understand that, and it’s understandable.  There has been a cycle of violence between Israel and Hamas that’s gone on for years and it’s even over a decade old, so we understand that.  But we also understand that the international community does want to help the people of Gaza.  And so we’re just going to be focused on providing assistance – seeing that assistance is provided in a manner that’s consistent with our goals, and that’s what it’s about right now.  It’s just about improving lives today.  Over.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>We’ll go to Lara Jakes.  Do we have Lara?</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>One moment, please.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Oh, hi.  Thanks.  I’m sorry if this got asked in the first question.  My phone got dropped weirdly.  But I was just curious as to how you all envision helping rebuild Gaza by working with the PA given that Hamas and the PA can’t stand each other and Hamas controls Gaza.  How is that going to work?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>That’s a great question.  And we’ve been meeting regularly and intensively with the United Nations, which is going to – we expect to lead the reconstruction efforts there.  We’ve also been meeting with the PA and together with the United Nations to look for a formula to kind of create a partnership between the United Nations and the Palestinian Authority to channel through the reconstruction assistance.  And I think we don’t talk to Hamas, obviously, but we would – we expect that they understand that if assistance is going to come in, that’s the manner it’s going to do so.  But you’re right; it presents significant challenges.  But we believe that by doing so it will get us on the pathway, we hope eventually, to a reintegration to some extent of the Palestinian Authority in Gaza, which we hope in turn can help create the conditions to move us forward to a more stable situation.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>We’ll go to Nadia Bilbassy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>(Inaudible) hear me?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Yes.  Go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Okay, great.  Thank you for doing this.  Thank you,  – thank you, .  Sorry.  So two of my questions have been asked, but let me rephrase – so basically, can you say it’s premature to think that this trip will really ignite the peace process, and the focus mainly really is on reconstruction and on maintaining the ceasefire?  Number one.  And number two, since there is – one of my colleagues mentioned the donor fatigue, can – did you ask the Gulf states to help since they have been talking about helping Gaza, despite of Hamas being in control?  And will the money again be channeled through the PA, or the UN, or one of the states who have some influence on Hamas, which is primarily Qatar? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>Thank you, Nadia, for the question.  They’re good questions.  Look, so in terms of the funding, we’re in close communication with our partners in the Gulf about how to move forward.  Things are still pretty early.  The United Nations hasn’t even completed its back-of-the-envelope assessment yet in terms of the needs, and they’ll be going into Gaza and continue to go in to conduct these assessments in the days ahead. But we’re in touch with the Gulf, and again, we are – and other donors – and we’re trying to structure things, again, in a way that diminishes Hamas’s abilities, strengthens the people of Gaza, begins a process of hopefully reintroducing and reintegrating the Palestinian Authority into Gaza, and is in partnership with the United Nations.  We are – as I said, we are primarily focused on making sure that the ceasefire holds, on making sure that the people of Gaza get the relief that they desperately need, and that we create the conditions to hopefully advance forward.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>We’ll go to Nike Ching.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>(Inaudible) call.  I would like to ask about the Palestinian elections.  Does the United States have a position on Palestinian elections?  Do you see the elections as a necessary step towards reviving Palestinian democratic institutions?  And is there something on the agenda when Secretary Blinken met with Abbas?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>So look, the administration has been consistent that the exercise of democratic elections are a matter for the Palestinian people and government to determine, not the United States Government.  So that’s – we believe that democracy is up to them and it’s up to the Palestinian people in government on how to proceed. So I’ll just leave it there.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>We’ll go to Mouhamed Elahmed.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi.  Thank you for doing this.  I have three questions.  First, should we expect an extension of the Secretary trip to the Middle East that would include a possible visit to the Gulf region as well?  Also, would the U.S. consider inviting the parties to Washington, D.C. – that is, the Palestinians and the Israelis – as well as regional players and leaders to Washington, D.C., for example, to revive the peace talks?  And last question:  What is the U.S. vision to the solution to the Palestinian-Israeli conflict at the drop of what happened recently?  Thank you so much.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>Thank you so much for those questions.  So the United States remains committed to the two-state solution.  That remains the vision of the United States, and we are not wavering from that in any way.  It’s probably premature at this time to invite the parties to Washington or anywhere else.  We are – so this will be the Secretary’s first trip to the region.  He’ll be engaging with the parties and listening to them and – again, with a focus on a cease – ensuring that the ceasefire holds and keeping – ensuring that the ceasefire holds.  I’ll just leave it there.  In terms of the expansion of the trip, , I’ll leave all those questions to you.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Sure.  Thanks for that.  At this point, we expect the Secretary will be visiting Jerusalem, Ramallah, Cairo, and Amman.  As always, if there are updates to that schedule, we will let you know.</p>
<p>We’ll go to the line of Andrea Mitchell.  Do we have Andrea?</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  I do not see Andrea’s &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  It look – it may be spelled “An Mitchell” in the system.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Oh, yes.  Thank you, one moment.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello?</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Go ahead, Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, can you hear me?  Given the perception that Hamas has been considerably strengthened politically by this with the people of Gaza showing their muscle against Israel, do they effectively have veto power over how the aid, if it materializes, is going to be distributed despite the efforts to run it through the UN and the Palestinian Authority?  Just following up on what Lara asked, how do you circumvent the PA in this instance?</p>
<p>And secondly, how important is it to get some kind of commitment – if not elections, but some other kind of commitment from the Palestinian Authority given the problems that they have had in the past in terms of proper administration of aid?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Right, so thank you for those questions.  We certainly don’t see Hamas as having a veto power.  We’re going to be working with the United Nations, and the United Nations has a significant and meaningful presence on the ground there.  And we are confident that working in partnership with them and also with the involvement of the Palestinian Authority in the process, we will get the job done.</p>
<p>In terms of the Palestinian Authority, look, again, the aid is going to be primarily going through the United Nations with the participation of the Palestinian Authority.  And that’s going to be our – that’s going to be our focus.  So we’re not – so that’s really going to be our focus.  I’ll leave it there.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll take a final question or two here.  Let’s go to the line of Karen DeYoung.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yes, hi, thank you.  Given that the Israelis said that their goal during this operation was to prevent a recurrence – in other words, to completely destroy the Hamas infrastructure and armaments that let this happen – are you confident at this point that Israel has either achieved that goal, or has agreed, if not, that it – that this is over, that it will be abide by the ceasefire?  And also, does Secretary Blinken plan on addressing with the Israeli Government some of the concerns that have been expressed here, particularly in Congress, about Israeli actions and how that might influence the relationship and assistance relationship in the future?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  So what I would say is first of all, I’m not going to get into the content of the conversations that we expect to happen, but there’s no question there will be forthright and important conversations on the Secretary’s first trip out here.</p>
<p>In terms of the destruction of Hamas’s capabilities, my sense is – our sense is that, of course, that’s not complete.  They’re still there on the ground, they’re still a presence, and that’s why we’re restructuring the way we engage on this file in a manner that seeks to diminish and contain their efforts.  But look, we take the commitments we received from all the parties seriously, and we have every hope and expectation that the ceasefire will continue to hold, at least in the immediate term, and we’re going to do everything we can to work with our partners to ensure that it does continue to hold.</p>
<p>So yeah, I’ll just – I’ll leave it there.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  And we’ll take a final question from Michele Kelemen.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Okay.  So I’m just – I’m wondering, just broadly, do you see any prospects of reviving diplomacy between Israelis and Palestinians?  And how is the street violence within Israeli cities complicating any of this?  Have you had any message to Israel about that?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  So again, our primary focus is on maintaining the ceasefire, getting the assistance to the people who need it.  In the first instance, we’ve restarted, as you’ve seen, our relationship with the Palestinian people and leadership that was missing in action for a number of years now and did nothing to restart diplomacy, so in and of itself, that is an important first step.  This is going to be an important trip for the Secretary to meet with Israeli leaders and three Arab leaders in Ramallah, Cairo, and Amman, Jordan, along with their associates.  So we are kind of reopening the chapter of engagement and working that way.</p>
<p>Look, in terms of the inter-communal violence and tensions in Israel, obviously, I think the world has seen that.  That is a significant concern.  And look, the United States has just gone through a period where we have kind of confronted or been forced to confront our own challenges at home.  And so we understand that other countries are also going through similar challenges.  So that will be – so I’m sure – let me just say while the focus is primarily on making sure the ceasefire holds in Gaza and bilateral relations with the governments with which we’ll be meeting, obviously, other issues like that I’m sure will come up.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Well, thanks very much to our speaker.  Thanks very much for everyone who was able to call in.  As a reminder, this call is on background to a senior State Department official.  And with that, the embargo is lifted.  Thank you all very much.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Good morning, everyone.  Thanks for joining this call, and especially thanks for joining it on short notice.</p>
<p>As you saw from the department as well as from the White House this morning, Secretary Blinken will be traveling to Jerusalem, Ramallah, Cairo, and Amman at the request of President Biden and will be departing later today.  We wanted to give you an opportunity to hear a little bit more about this travel and to ask questions.</p>
<p>We have with us this morning a senior State Department official to offer a bit more context and to take your questions.  This call is embargoed until the end of the call.  It is also on background.  You can attribute what you hear to a senior State Department official.  Just for the knowledge of those on this call, you’ll be hearing today from , who will be speaking and answering your questions, but again, he will be referred to as a senior State Department official, and this is embargoed until the end of the call.</p>
<p>So with that, I will turn it over to our speaker.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Thank you, and good morning, everyone.  Thank you for joining.  I want to speak to you on the Secretary’s upcoming trip to Israel, the West Bank, Egypt, and Jordan, as well as take your questions after this bit, but first I want to recognize the important development of last week, the ceasefire led by Egypt.</p>
<p>This ceasefire was agreed to after 11 days of violence which tragically claimed the lives of innocent Palestinians and Israelis, including children, and it’s just really heartbreaking.  The United States wants to convey our deepest condolences to the families who have lost loved ones in the conflict, and our thoughts go out to those who are wounded.</p>
<p>We’re relieved the violence has come to an end, and I just really want to share that the U.S. worked tirelessly with all our partners in the region, including Israelis and Palestinians in public, but much, much more importantly, behind the scenes to help the ceasefire come about.  We really appreciate the important role played by Egypt, which was critical in the effort to mediate an end to the violence, and also really appreciate the roles of Jordan and Qatar and other partners who played a role here.</p>
<p>Look, in the wake of the ceasefire, Secretary Blinken will be traveling to Israel and the West Bank today and tomorrow, where he’ll meet with Israeli and Palestinian leaders.  He’ll then move on to Egypt and Jordan, where he’ll meet with leaders there to discuss recovery efforts and a means of working together to build better futures for people here on the ground and in the region.</p>
<p>Again, we’re incredibly relieved at the terrible violence which tore apart the lives of so many innocents has ended, and we’re committed to supporting all efforts to a lasting peace.  The Secretary looks forward to meeting regional leaders and discussing how the U.S. can support Israelis and Palestinians to rebuild and address the underlying causes that led to this crisis, and by advancing equal measures of freedom, security, and prosperity for Israelis and Palestinians alike in tangible ways.</p>
<p>With that, I’d love to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Great, thanks very much.  We will start with the line of Nick Wadhams, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hey, I’m here.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Yes.  Go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks.  , thank you.  It’s a short trip.  Can you give us a little more detail on what the Secretary hopes to achieve from this?  The ceasefire has already been signed.  Is it the hope that he will set them on the course toward actually trying to jumpstart broader peace talks, a lasting settlement?  Or is he more just hoping to provide impetus so that this ceasefire sticks?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Thank you.  In the first instance, the most important thing is that the ceasefire does hold.  It’s an – extremely important that it does.  We just – we don’t want to see a return to the bloodshed that was heartbreaking during the 11-day conflict.  And we’re certainly going to look for ways to improve Israeli and Palestinian lives, and as we’ve said over and over again, advance freedom, security, and prosperity for Israelis and Palestinians alike, hopefully in tangible ways in the immediate term.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Let’s go to the line of Humeyra Pamuk.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello?</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Yes, we have you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Okay.  Thanks for this.  Just a quick follow-up on Nick and something else as well.  The Secretary and others have said the focus at the moment is to keep the ceasefire intact, and he just said that, and rebuild as well.  But just to push you a little bit on that because I really didn’t hear an answer, could this be an opportunity to lay the – at least the groundwork for future peace talks?  And if yes, what exactly will you be doing towards that?</p>
<p>And the second one is:  How can the U.S. guarantee aid to Gaza won’t be diverted toward replenishing the Hamas arsenal?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  So on the second question, we’re going to be working in partnership with the United Nations and the Palestinian Authority to kind of channel aid there in a manner that does its best to go to the people of Gaza.  I’m also sure that the Government of Egypt will have some role in that.  As we’ve seen in life, as we all know in life, there are no guarantees, but we’re going to do everything that we can to ensure that this assistance reaches the people who need it the most.</p>
<p>Again, regarding your question, we’re really focused primarily on ensuring that the ceasefire sticks and taking the steps to – taking tangible steps to advance the quality of people’s lives: advance their freedom, advance their security, and advance their prosperity.  We believe that in the immediate term, that’s what’s feasible and that’s what’s important.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll go to Barak Ravid.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Inaudible) questions.  First, is the Secretary going to meet also Minister of Defense Gantz and head of opposition, Lapid?  It wasn’t mentioned in the statement that was released.</p>
<p>And second, there seems to be quite a lot of donor fatigue around the world, and many countries are saying that they’re not going to give again money to reconstruct Gaza without the broader context of a two-state solution.  How are you going to deal with this position?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  , do you want to comment anything on the schedule?</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Barak, the – we’ll have more details on the schedule as we get closer to the ground, and we’ll update as we can.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Thanks, .  So look, on donor fatigue, we acknowledge that, we understand that, and it’s understandable.  There has been a cycle of violence between Israel and Hamas that’s gone on for years and it’s even over a decade old, so we understand that.  But we also understand that the international community does want to help the people of Gaza.  And so we’re just going to be focused on providing assistance – seeing that assistance is provided in a manner that’s consistent with our goals, and that’s what it’s about right now.  It’s just about improving lives today.  Over.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>We’ll go to Lara Jakes.  Do we have Lara?</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>One moment, please.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Oh, hi.  Thanks.  I’m sorry if this got asked in the first question.  My phone got dropped weirdly.  But I was just curious as to how you all envision helping rebuild Gaza by working with the PA given that Hamas and the PA can’t stand each other and Hamas controls Gaza.  How is that going to work?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>That’s a great question.  And we’ve been meeting regularly and intensively with the United Nations, which is going to – we expect to lead the reconstruction efforts there.  We’ve also been meeting with the PA and together with the United Nations to look for a formula to kind of create a partnership between the United Nations and the Palestinian Authority to channel through the reconstruction assistance.  And I think we don’t talk to Hamas, obviously, but we would – we expect that they understand that if assistance is going to come in, that’s the manner it’s going to do so.  But you’re right; it presents significant challenges.  But we believe that by doing so it will get us on the pathway, we hope eventually, to a reintegration to some extent of the Palestinian Authority in Gaza, which we hope in turn can help create the conditions to move us forward to a more stable situation.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>We’ll go to Nadia Bilbassy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>(Inaudible) hear me?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Yes.  Go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Okay, great.  Thank you for doing this.  Thank you,  – thank you, .  Sorry.  So two of my questions have been asked, but let me rephrase – so basically, can you say it’s premature to think that this trip will really ignite the peace process, and the focus mainly really is on reconstruction and on maintaining the ceasefire?  Number one.  And number two, since there is – one of my colleagues mentioned the donor fatigue, can – did you ask the Gulf states to help since they have been talking about helping Gaza, despite of Hamas being in control?  And will the money again be channeled through the PA, or the UN, or one of the states who have some influence on Hamas, which is primarily Qatar? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>Thank you, Nadia, for the question.  They’re good questions.  Look, so in terms of the funding, we’re in close communication with our partners in the Gulf about how to move forward.  Things are still pretty early.  The United Nations hasn’t even completed its back-of-the-envelope assessment yet in terms of the needs, and they’ll be going into Gaza and continue to go in to conduct these assessments in the days ahead. But we’re in touch with the Gulf, and again, we are – and other donors – and we’re trying to structure things, again, in a way that diminishes Hamas’s abilities, strengthens the people of Gaza, begins a process of hopefully reintroducing and reintegrating the Palestinian Authority into Gaza, and is in partnership with the United Nations.  We are – as I said, we are primarily focused on making sure that the ceasefire holds, on making sure that the people of Gaza get the relief that they desperately need, and that we create the conditions to hopefully advance forward.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>We’ll go to Nike Ching.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>(Inaudible) call.  I would like to ask about the Palestinian elections.  Does the United States have a position on Palestinian elections?  Do you see the elections as a necessary step towards reviving Palestinian democratic institutions?  And is there something on the agenda when Secretary Blinken met with Abbas?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>So look, the administration has been consistent that the exercise of democratic elections are a matter for the Palestinian people and government to determine, not the United States Government.  So that’s – we believe that democracy is up to them and it’s up to the Palestinian people in government on how to proceed. So I’ll just leave it there.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>We’ll go to Mouhamed Elahmed.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi.  Thank you for doing this.  I have three questions.  First, should we expect an extension of the Secretary trip to the Middle East that would include a possible visit to the Gulf region as well?  Also, would the U.S. consider inviting the parties to Washington, D.C. – that is, the Palestinians and the Israelis – as well as regional players and leaders to Washington, D.C., for example, to revive the peace talks?  And last question:  What is the U.S. vision to the solution to the Palestinian-Israeli conflict at the drop of what happened recently?  Thank you so much.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>Thank you so much for those questions.  So the United States remains committed to the two-state solution.  That remains the vision of the United States, and we are not wavering from that in any way.  It’s probably premature at this time to invite the parties to Washington or anywhere else.  We are – so this will be the Secretary’s first trip to the region.  He’ll be engaging with the parties and listening to them and – again, with a focus on a cease – ensuring that the ceasefire holds and keeping – ensuring that the ceasefire holds.  I’ll just leave it there.  In terms of the expansion of the trip, , I’ll leave all those questions to you.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Sure.  Thanks for that.  At this point, we expect the Secretary will be visiting Jerusalem, Ramallah, Cairo, and Amman.  As always, if there are updates to that schedule, we will let you know.</p>
<p>We’ll go to the line of Andrea Mitchell.  Do we have Andrea?</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  I do not see Andrea’s &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  It look – it may be spelled “An Mitchell” in the system.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Oh, yes.  Thank you, one moment.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello?</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Go ahead, Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, can you hear me?  Given the perception that Hamas has been considerably strengthened politically by this with the people of Gaza showing their muscle against Israel, do they effectively have veto power over how the aid, if it materializes, is going to be distributed despite the efforts to run it through the UN and the Palestinian Authority?  Just following up on what Lara asked, how do you circumvent the PA in this instance?</p>
<p>And secondly, how important is it to get some kind of commitment – if not elections, but some other kind of commitment from the Palestinian Authority given the problems that they have had in the past in terms of proper administration of aid?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Right, so thank you for those questions.  We certainly don’t see Hamas as having a veto power.  We’re going to be working with the United Nations, and the United Nations has a significant and meaningful presence on the ground there.  And we are confident that working in partnership with them and also with the involvement of the Palestinian Authority in the process, we will get the job done.</p>
<p>In terms of the Palestinian Authority, look, again, the aid is going to be primarily going through the United Nations with the participation of the Palestinian Authority.  And that’s going to be our – that’s going to be our focus.  So we’re not – so that’s really going to be our focus.  I’ll leave it there.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll take a final question or two here.  Let’s go to the line of Karen DeYoung.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yes, hi, thank you.  Given that the Israelis said that their goal during this operation was to prevent a recurrence – in other words, to completely destroy the Hamas infrastructure and armaments that let this happen – are you confident at this point that Israel has either achieved that goal, or has agreed, if not, that it – that this is over, that it will be abide by the ceasefire?  And also, does Secretary Blinken plan on addressing with the Israeli Government some of the concerns that have been expressed here, particularly in Congress, about Israeli actions and how that might influence the relationship and assistance relationship in the future?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  So what I would say is first of all, I’m not going to get into the content of the conversations that we expect to happen, but there’s no question there will be forthright and important conversations on the Secretary’s first trip out here.</p>
<p>In terms of the destruction of Hamas’s capabilities, my sense is – our sense is that, of course, that’s not complete.  They’re still there on the ground, they’re still a presence, and that’s why we’re restructuring the way we engage on this file in a manner that seeks to diminish and contain their efforts.  But look, we take the commitments we received from all the parties seriously, and we have every hope and expectation that the ceasefire will continue to hold, at least in the immediate term, and we’re going to do everything we can to work with our partners to ensure that it does continue to hold.</p>
<p>So yeah, I’ll just – I’ll leave it there.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  And we’ll take a final question from Michele Kelemen.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Okay.  So I’m just – I’m wondering, just broadly, do you see any prospects of reviving diplomacy between Israelis and Palestinians?  And how is the street violence within Israeli cities complicating any of this?  Have you had any message to Israel about that?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  So again, our primary focus is on maintaining the ceasefire, getting the assistance to the people who need it.  In the first instance, we’ve restarted, as you’ve seen, our relationship with the Palestinian people and leadership that was missing in action for a number of years now and did nothing to restart diplomacy, so in and of itself, that is an important first step.  This is going to be an important trip for the Secretary to meet with Israeli leaders and three Arab leaders in Ramallah, Cairo, and Amman, Jordan, along with their associates.  So we are kind of reopening the chapter of engagement and working that way.</p>
<p>Look, in terms of the inter-communal violence and tensions in Israel, obviously, I think the world has seen that.  That is a significant concern.  And look, the United States has just gone through a period where we have kind of confronted or been forced to confront our own challenges at home.  And so we understand that other countries are also going through similar challenges.  So that will be – so I’m sure – let me just say while the focus is primarily on making sure the ceasefire holds in Gaza and bilateral relations with the governments with which we’ll be meeting, obviously, other issues like that I’m sure will come up.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Well, thanks very much to our speaker.  Thanks very much for everyone who was able to call in.  As a reminder, this call is on background to a senior State Department official.  And with that, the embargo is lifted.  Thank you all very much.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Travel to Jerusalem, Ramallah, Cairo, and Amman</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-jerusalem-ramallah-cairo-and-amman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 11:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Jerusalem, Ramallah, Cairo, and Amman May 24-27, 2021.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken is undertaking this trip at the request of President Biden. He will first travel to Jerusalem, where he will meet with Israeli President Reuven Rivlin, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, Foreign Minister Gabi Ashkenazi, and other senior Israeli officials. In Ramallah, he will meet with Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas, Prime Minister Mohammad Shtayyeh, and other senior officials from the Palestinian Authority. Secretary Blinken will then travel to Cairo to meet with President Abdel Fattah Al Sisi and Foreign Minister Sameh Shoukry. The Secretary will conclude his trip with a stop in Amman to meet with His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan and Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Ayman Safadi.</p>
<p>The United States has engaged in intensive diplomacy to bring an end to the hostilities in Gaza. Secretary Blinken is traveling to the region to discuss essential follow-up efforts to consolidate the ceasefire and reduce risks of further conflict over the coming months.</p>
<p>For any questions, please email <a href="mailto:NEA-Press@state.gov">NEA-Press@state.gov</a> and follow us on Twitter @StateDept_NEA.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Jerusalem, Ramallah, Cairo, and Amman May 24-27, 2021.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken is undertaking this trip at the request of President Biden. He will first travel to Jerusalem, where he will meet with Israeli President Reuven Rivlin, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, Foreign Minister Gabi Ashkenazi, and other senior Israeli officials. In Ramallah, he will meet with Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas, Prime Minister Mohammad Shtayyeh, and other senior officials from the Palestinian Authority. Secretary Blinken will then travel to Cairo to meet with President Abdel Fattah Al Sisi and Foreign Minister Sameh Shoukry. The Secretary will conclude his trip with a stop in Amman to meet with His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan and Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Ayman Safadi.</p>
<p>The United States has engaged in intensive diplomacy to bring an end to the hostilities in Gaza. Secretary Blinken is traveling to the region to discuss essential follow-up efforts to consolidate the ceasefire and reduce risks of further conflict over the coming months.</p>
<p>For any questions, please email <a href="mailto:NEA-Press@state.gov">NEA-Press@state.gov</a> and follow us on Twitter @StateDept_NEA.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States’ Actions To Press for the Resolution of the Crisis in the Tigray Region of Ethiopia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-actions-to-press-for-the-resolution-of-the-crisis-in-the-tigray-region-of-ethiopia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 23:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245722</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States has deepening concerns about the ongoing crisis in Ethiopia’s Tigray region as well as other threats to the sovereignty, national unity, and territorial integrity of Ethiopia. People in Tigray continue to suffer human rights violations, abuses, and atrocities, and urgently needed humanitarian relief is being blocked by the Ethiopian and Eritrean militaries as well as other armed actors. Despite significant diplomatic engagement, the parties to the conflict in Tigray have taken no meaningful steps to end hostilities or pursue a peaceful resolution of the political crisis. The United States condemns in the strongest terms the killings, forced removals, systemic sexual violence, and other human rights violations and abuses. We are equally appalled by the destruction of civilian property including water sources, hospitals, and medical facilities, taking place in Tigray. We call on the Ethiopian government to meet public commitments to hold accountable all those responsible for human rights violations and abuses, to protect civilians, and to ensure unhindered humanitarian access. We call for the Eritrean government to live up to its public commitment and immediately return its troops to internationally recognized Eritrean territory. Without an immediate cessation of hostilities and a rapid expansion of humanitarian access, current and significant food insecurity could lead to famine.</p>
<p>The time for action from the international community is now. Today, I am announcing a visa restriction policy under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act on the issuance of visas for any current or former Ethiopian or Eritrean government officials, members of the security forces, or other individuals—to include Amhara regional and irregular forces and members of the Tigray People’s Liberation Front (TPLF)—responsible for, or complicit in, undermining resolution of the crisis in Tigray. This includes those who have conducted wrongful violence or other abuses against people in the Tigray region of Ethiopia, as well as those who have hindered access of humanitarian assistance to those in the region. Immediate family members of such persons may also be subject to these restrictions. Should those responsible for undermining a resolution of the crisis in Tigray fail to reverse course, they should anticipate further actions from the United States and the international community. We call on other governments to join us in taking these actions.</p>
<p>Additionally, we have imposed wide-ranging restrictions on economic and security assistance to Ethiopia and will bring our defense trade control policy in line with them. We will continue humanitarian assistance and certain other critical aid to Ethiopia in areas such as health, food security, basic education, support for women and girls, human rights and democracy, good governance, and conflict mitigation, consistent with available authorities. The United States will continue its existing broad restrictions on assistance to Eritrea.</p>
<p>The United States reiterates its calls for a durable, political solution to the crisis. We are committed to supporting efforts to resolve the crisis in Tigray and help Ethiopians advance reconciliation and dialogue to overcome current divisions.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States has deepening concerns about the ongoing crisis in Ethiopia’s Tigray region as well as other threats to the sovereignty, national unity, and territorial integrity of Ethiopia. People in Tigray continue to suffer human rights violations, abuses, and atrocities, and urgently needed humanitarian relief is being blocked by the Ethiopian and Eritrean militaries as well as other armed actors. Despite significant diplomatic engagement, the parties to the conflict in Tigray have taken no meaningful steps to end hostilities or pursue a peaceful resolution of the political crisis. The United States condemns in the strongest terms the killings, forced removals, systemic sexual violence, and other human rights violations and abuses. We are equally appalled by the destruction of civilian property including water sources, hospitals, and medical facilities, taking place in Tigray. We call on the Ethiopian government to meet public commitments to hold accountable all those responsible for human rights violations and abuses, to protect civilians, and to ensure unhindered humanitarian access. We call for the Eritrean government to live up to its public commitment and immediately return its troops to internationally recognized Eritrean territory. Without an immediate cessation of hostilities and a rapid expansion of humanitarian access, current and significant food insecurity could lead to famine.</p>
<p>The time for action from the international community is now. Today, I am announcing a visa restriction policy under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act on the issuance of visas for any current or former Ethiopian or Eritrean government officials, members of the security forces, or other individuals—to include Amhara regional and irregular forces and members of the Tigray People’s Liberation Front (TPLF)—responsible for, or complicit in, undermining resolution of the crisis in Tigray. This includes those who have conducted wrongful violence or other abuses against people in the Tigray region of Ethiopia, as well as those who have hindered access of humanitarian assistance to those in the region. Immediate family members of such persons may also be subject to these restrictions. Should those responsible for undermining a resolution of the crisis in Tigray fail to reverse course, they should anticipate further actions from the United States and the international community. We call on other governments to join us in taking these actions.</p>
<p>Additionally, we have imposed wide-ranging restrictions on economic and security assistance to Ethiopia and will bring our defense trade control policy in line with them. We will continue humanitarian assistance and certain other critical aid to Ethiopia in areas such as health, food security, basic education, support for women and girls, human rights and democracy, good governance, and conflict mitigation, consistent with available authorities. The United States will continue its existing broad restrictions on assistance to Eritrea.</p>
<p>The United States reiterates its calls for a durable, political solution to the crisis. We are committed to supporting efforts to resolve the crisis in Tigray and help Ethiopians advance reconciliation and dialogue to overcome current divisions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Diversion of Ryanair Flight to Belarus and Arrest of Journalist</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/diversion-of-ryanair-flight-to-belarus-and-arrest-of-journalist/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 22:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245718</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States strongly condemns the forced diversion of a flight between two EU member states and the subsequent removal and arrest of journalist Raman Pratasevich in Minsk. We demand his immediate release. This shocking act perpetrated by the Lukashenka regime endangered the lives of more than 120 passengers, including U.S. citizens. Initial reports suggesting the involvement of the Belarusian security services and the use of Belarusian military aircraft to escort the plane are deeply concerning and require full investigation.</p>
<p>We are closely coordinating our response with our partners, including the EU and Lithuanian and Greek officials. Given indications the forced landing was based on false pretenses, we support the earliest possible meeting of the Council of the International Civil Aviation Organization to review these events.</p>
<p>Independent media are an essential pillar supporting the rule of law and a vital component of a democratic society. The United States once again condemns the Lukashenka regime’s ongoing harassment and arbitrary detention of journalists. We stand with the Belarusian people in their aspirations for a free, democratic, and prosperous future and support their call for the regime to respect human rights and fundamental freedoms.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States strongly condemns the forced diversion of a flight between two EU member states and the subsequent removal and arrest of journalist Raman Pratasevich in Minsk. We demand his immediate release. This shocking act perpetrated by the Lukashenka regime endangered the lives of more than 120 passengers, including U.S. citizens. Initial reports suggesting the involvement of the Belarusian security services and the use of Belarusian military aircraft to escort the plane are deeply concerning and require full investigation.</p>
<p>We are closely coordinating our response with our partners, including the EU and Lithuanian and Greek officials. Given indications the forced landing was based on false pretenses, we support the earliest possible meeting of the Council of the International Civil Aviation Organization to review these events.</p>
<p>Independent media are an essential pillar supporting the rule of law and a vital component of a democratic society. The United States once again condemns the Lukashenka regime’s ongoing harassment and arbitrary detention of journalists. We stand with the Belarusian people in their aspirations for a free, democratic, and prosperous future and support their call for the regime to respect human rights and fundamental freedoms.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
