<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 01:38:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Azerbaijan Republic Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/azerbaijan-republic-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 04:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246970</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Azerbaijan as you celebrate Republic Day and mark the 1918 establishment of the first democratic government in the Muslim world.</p>
<p>The United States values the thirty years of partnership with Azerbaijan on economic, energy, and security cooperation, and our ongoing dialogue on improving Azerbaijan’s respect for human rights and the rule of law.  We recognize Azerbaijan’s significant contributions to European energy diversification through the Southern Gas Corridor.  Strong institutions and processes that respect human rights and fundamental freedoms, rule of law, transparency, and accountability, are vital to us achieving our shared goals and building stronger and deeper ties.</p>
<p>The United States also values the connections fostered between thousands of Azerbaijani and American citizens through people-to-people exchanges, as well as through our Embassies’ public outreach.</p>
<p>As a co-chair of the OSCE Minsk Group, the United States remains committed to helping the sides negotiate a long-term political settlement of the Nagorno-Karabakh conflict and address the humanitarian impact of the fighting, including the release of all detainees, accounting for those missing, and the full and expeditious exchange of remains.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Azerbaijan as you celebrate Republic Day and mark the 1918 establishment of the first democratic government in the Muslim world.</p>
<p>The United States values the thirty years of partnership with Azerbaijan on economic, energy, and security cooperation, and our ongoing dialogue on improving Azerbaijan’s respect for human rights and the rule of law.  We recognize Azerbaijan’s significant contributions to European energy diversification through the Southern Gas Corridor.  Strong institutions and processes that respect human rights and fundamental freedoms, rule of law, transparency, and accountability, are vital to us achieving our shared goals and building stronger and deeper ties.</p>
<p>The United States also values the connections fostered between thousands of Azerbaijani and American citizens through people-to-people exchanges, as well as through our Embassies’ public outreach.</p>
<p>As a co-chair of the OSCE Minsk Group, the United States remains committed to helping the sides negotiate a long-term political settlement of the Nagorno-Karabakh conflict and address the humanitarian impact of the fighting, including the release of all detainees, accounting for those missing, and the full and expeditious exchange of remains.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Vietnamese Foreign Minister Son</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-vietnamese-foreign-minister-son/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 01:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246975</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Vietnamese Foreign Minister Bui Thanh Son.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Son celebrated the strength of the U.S.-Vietnam Comprehensive Partnership and reaffirmed our shared commitment to protecting and preserving the rules-based order in the South China Sea.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister also discussed ongoing concerns regarding the military coup in Burma and commitments to addressing climate change and tackling COVID-19.  Secretary Blinken emphasized U.S. commitment to ASEAN centrality, the Mekong-U.S. Partnership, and support of a strong, prosperous, and independent Vietnam that respects human rights and the rule of law.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Vietnamese Foreign Minister Bui Thanh Son.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Son celebrated the strength of the U.S.-Vietnam Comprehensive Partnership and reaffirmed our shared commitment to protecting and preserving the rules-based order in the South China Sea.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister also discussed ongoing concerns regarding the military coup in Burma and commitments to addressing climate change and tackling COVID-19.  Secretary Blinken emphasized U.S. commitment to ASEAN centrality, the Mekong-U.S. Partnership, and support of a strong, prosperous, and independent Vietnam that respects human rights and the rule of law.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Somalia’s Electoral Agreement</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/somalias-electoral-agreement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 22:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246962</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the May 27 agreement between Somalia’s national and Federal Member State leaders to proceed with parliamentary and presidential elections on the basis of the September 17, 2020, framework.  We commend Prime Minister Roble’s efforts and call on Somalia’s leaders to maintain the spirit of cooperation and compromise demonstrated during this week’s negotiations.  We encourage them to move swiftly to implement the agreement, as concluding a peaceful, inclusive, and transparent electoral process as soon as possible is vital for Somalia to continue on its path to peace and prosperity.  We look forward to continuing our support for that process.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the May 27 agreement between Somalia’s national and Federal Member State leaders to proceed with parliamentary and presidential elections on the basis of the September 17, 2020, framework.  We commend Prime Minister Roble’s efforts and call on Somalia’s leaders to maintain the spirit of cooperation and compromise demonstrated during this week’s negotiations.  We encourage them to move swiftly to implement the agreement, as concluding a peaceful, inclusive, and transparent electoral process as soon as possible is vital for Somalia to continue on its path to peace and prosperity.  We look forward to continuing our support for that process.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rule of Law in Iraq</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/rule-of-law-in-iraq/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 22:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246959</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is outraged that peaceful demonstrators who took to the streets to urge reform were met with threats and brutal violence.  Moreover, the violation of Iraqi sovereignty and rule of law by armed militias harms all Iraqis and their country. We welcome every effort by the government to hold accountable the militias, thugs, and vigilante groups for their attacks against Iraqis exercising their right to freedom of expression and peaceful assembly as well as for their assault on the rule of law.</p>
<p>We reaffirm the U.S. government’s enduring commitment to the Iraqi people and a strong, sovereign, and prosperous Iraq.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is outraged that peaceful demonstrators who took to the streets to urge reform were met with threats and brutal violence.  Moreover, the violation of Iraqi sovereignty and rule of law by armed militias harms all Iraqis and their country. We welcome every effort by the government to hold accountable the militias, thugs, and vigilante groups for their attacks against Iraqis exercising their right to freedom of expression and peaceful assembly as well as for their assault on the rule of law.</p>
<p>We reaffirm the U.S. government’s enduring commitment to the Iraqi people and a strong, sovereign, and prosperous Iraq.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Briefing with Acting Assistant Secretary for Western Hemisphere Affairs Julie Chung On the Secretary’s Upcoming Travel to San Jose, Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-with-acting-assistant-secretary-for-western-hemisphere-affairs-julie-chung-on-the-secretarys-upcoming-travel-to-san-jose-costa-rica/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie J. Chung, Acting Assistant SecretaryBureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 22:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246956</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Julie J. Chung, Acting Assistant SecretaryBureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Thank you. Good afternoon, everyone, and welcome to our briefing this afternoon. It is our pleasure to have you with us. It is also our pleasure to have as your briefer today Acting Assistant Secretary Julie Chung from the State Department’s Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs. She will talk with you about Secretary Blinken’s upcoming travel to Costa Rica, which we announced officially just this morning. Acting Assistant Secretary Chung will start off with some brief remarks and then she’ll be happy to take your questions.</p>
<p>Just a quick reminder, this call is on the record, but the contents are embargoed until the end of the call, okay? And with that, I’ll go ahead and turn it over to Assistant Secretary Julie Chung.</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG:</b> Thanks very much. Good afternoon, everybody.</p>
<p>Next week, Secretary of State Blinken will embark on his first in-person trip to the Western Hemisphere when he travels to San Jose, Costa Rica. While there, he will meet with Costa Rican President Alvarado, senior Costa Rican officials, and Americans and Costa Ricans building better futures for our countries. On June 1st, the Secretary will attend a regional meeting of the Central American foreign ministers, held under the aegis of the Central American Integration System, or SICA.</p>
<p>The leaders will use this multilateral forum to confront a broad array of issues, deepening our collaborative approach to migration challenges; combating corruption and impunity and reinforcing democratic institutions and rule of law; improving security and inclusive economic growth for the people of the region; combating the COVID-19 pandemic and addressing social and economic recovery; and improving environmental stewardship. All these challenges transcend borders and demand coordinated responses that enlist regional and global partners, including Mexico. We also know that the nations of Central America will benefit from deeper economic integration.</p>
<p>While the details regarding attendance are still taking form, I understand that all SICA countries and Mexico are invited to send their foreign ministers to the meeting, and this includes all seven Central American countries, as well as the Dominican Republic. Secretary Blinken will also raise issues specific to our bilateral relationship with some of his counterparts as the opportunity arises.</p>
<p>We are particularly appreciative of Costa Rica’s role as host of this meeting. And Secretary Blinken will also meet with Costa Rican President Carlos Alvarado Quesada and Minister of Foreign Affairs Rodolfo Solano Quiros to discuss our very robust and multifaceted relationship and celebrate their status as the newest member of the OECD.</p>
<p>With that, I would be happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Okay. Thank you, Assistant Secretary Chung. Everyone, just as a reminder, if you’d like to get into the question queue, go ahead and dial 1, 0.</p>
<p>Okay. I think we’ll start off with Karen DeYoung.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you, hi. I wondered if you could – two things, actually. One, what you expect in terms of bilateral meetings. I know you said details are still being formulated. Obviously, there are a couple of governments there with which the United States does not have the best of relationships, and I wonder if all of the seven members have been invited for bilateral meetings with the Secretary.</p>
<p>And secondarily, in a more general sense, I wonder if you could talk about the $4 billion program that President Biden has said he was going to use for the Northern Triangle states and give us some sense of where that stands right now. Have any programs been announced? Has any of the money been distributed? Is there any legislation for it? Where is it right now?</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG:</b> Yeah, thank you. In terms of the meeting, we really think this is a great opportunity to see regional solutions and have this regional discussion with the SICA grouping of government leadership. So we’ll be doing that. Of course, the bilateral meeting we have confirmed is with the president and foreign minister of Costa Rica, as they are the hosts. So we’ll be looking forward to a really robust discussion with Costa Rica.</p>
<p>I can’t speak to the other bilateral meetings which have not been confirmed yet, but again, this is a great opportunity for us to engage all these ministers and representatives on a range of issues that affect the region.</p>
<p>On the President’s $4 billion and commitment to the region, those are still being worked out. There are many phases of budget planning and programming that are being discussed in the interagency. But the commitment is very clear that the President has been making from the beginning, and the Vice President and the Secretary, about the U.S. commitment to the region, addressing the root causes, and making sure we work in partnership with not only the governments in the region but the private sector, civil society, and other stakeholders as well.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Let’s go to the line of Matt Spetalnick at Reuters.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Yes, thank you very much, appreciate it. You mentioned – can you hear me okay?</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG:</b> Yes.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Yes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Okay, great, great. So you mentioned corruption, that that will be taken up – that issue will be taken up with the leaders. Can you speak specifically to what the Secretary will have to say to the Northern Triangle countries where this has been flagged as one of the root causes of increased migration, the failure to address corruption and governance issues?</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG:</b> Well, the administration has been clear from the beginning about the importance of addressing corruption and making sure anticorruption, democracy, human rights – those are at the core of our foreign policy. So whether it’s discussions with the SICA counterparts or within Central America, El Salvador, Honduras, El Salvador – any of the countries in the region – we have pledged to work with the governments that also work in concert with us to address these kinds of issues on corruption. I think this is what the people in the region also look for their governments to do, so that when you address the migration – irregular migration – the corruption and governance and rule of law, those are all interconnected. So we are looking to really discuss and hear from the governments on what the challenges are and how we can address these challenges together.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Now let’s go to the line of Carla Angola at EVTV, Miami.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you so much for this opportunity. Secretary, we understand that on this trip, as you said, to Costa Rica, you are going to meet with senior officials from Mexico. Due to the massive arrival of Venezuelans at the border, we imagine that this will be an important issue to discover how, for example, human traffickers that take advantage of this circumstance. But I also want to know if you will talk about the negotiations between Juan Guaido and the Maduro regime, since it has been commented that the place of the first meeting in the spring work of those talks will be precisely Mexico. Could you confirm that information? Thank you so much.</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG:</b> Well, SICA and these regional discussions will focus on regional challenges and regional migration management. Of course, the horrific humanitarian disaster caused by the Maduro regime and the exodus of millions of Venezuelans to the region has had a deep impact, and United States has been the largest donor in terms of providing for those migrants and assistance to the countries. We understand there are 30,000 Venezuelans in Costa Rica and we have provided funding to support those migrants, including $6 million for Venezuelans in Costa Rica.</p>
<p>So this is a shared commitment. We want to look at the Venezuelan humanitarian crisis, its impact on the region, of course, the migration flows, and then, as you referred to, the abuse of traffickers and coyotes and the ability for us to use all tools, including law enforcement and other ways, to stop this flow of the dangerous movement that’s been happening throughout the region. So this will be an important topic, part of the migration discussion that all the countries in the region are addressing.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Okay. Let’s go to the line, please, of Beatriz Pascual.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi. Thank you. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG:</b> Yes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Great. Thank you so much. My question is about Nicaragua. Is the Secretary planning on meeting with the foreign minister of Nicaragua, Moncada? And what is the U.S. doing in regards to the targeting that Ortega is doing to the opposition figures as elections are approaching? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG:</b> We understand Nicaragua is a member of SICA, so Costa Rica as the host is inviting Nicaragua to attend the meeting. We don’t know – we haven’t confirmed who will attend for that government, but the United States has been very concerned about the situation in Nicaragua, the oppression of people, of freedom of press, of civil society and human rights defenders. That’s something we’ve spoken out frequently about, and we are working very closely in a multilateral fashion through the OAS. And I must say, Costa Rica has been a strong partner within that framework of the OAS to call for democracy and human rights in Nicaragua. So we will continue to work in that multilateral format, but I think there are very big concerns about elections being planned for later this year and whether the right conditions are there for those free and fair elections.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Okay. Let’s go to the line, please, of Pearl Matibe.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you very much for your availability. I wonder, as part of the discussions and with the growing transit of illegal drugs and – either through or from African countries, will any of that be part of the discussions, if you’re noticing any increase in trends in that that also cross over into counterterrorism areas in Africa? And as part of the regional migration issue in and around South America, will any part of the increase, perhaps, in Africans transiting through that area, that region into the United States be part of that discussion? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG:</b> Thank you. Well, Costa Rica is one of the major transit countries we know for drugs in Latin America, so it’s an area that we work very closely with Costa Rica on, on this rising challenge. We have worked to support Costa Rican security services so that they’ve seized over I think 71 metric tons of drugs in the past year, and no matter where the origin of that is. I think that transit – and then what brings along with the transit of drugs comes trafficking of persons and money laundering and all those things that transnational organizations – organized crime – all are involved with. So I think we will be addressing, again, the – some of the key pillars of SICA is to address democratic security, but also economic integration and regional coordinated solutions to these kind of challenges. So I look forward to those discussions when we arrive in Costa Rica.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Let’s go to the line of Cindy Regidor.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Hi, thank you. Yes, I wanted to ask again about the – how will you plan to include the Nicaraguan ongoing crisis in the agenda? Are you planning something special with the SICA members to have a big impact on the upcoming elections in November?</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG: </b>Well, this is an opportunity to discuss a range of issues of regional importance with SICA members. Again, the SICA was created in 1991, I believe, to really address migration management, climate change, social integration, economic integration. So we are an observer member of SICA, and we are welcomed by Costa Rica as the host to this meeting. So it’s a good opportunity for us to hear from regional leaders about their concerns and how to address these challenges together. Again, Costa Rica and the United States and many other countries have expressed our concerns, our joint concerns about Nicaragua and the state of democracy there through the OAS bilaterally, and also through our own individual public statements. And we will continue with that, and including our advocacy by our U.S. embassy in Nicaragua and our embassy in Costa Rica, who has often met with Nicaraguans in the country as well.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Let’s go to the line of Roman Gressier.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Hi, thanks for taking my question. One of the points of the agenda is going to be democratic governance, and it’s where, of course, we’re looking for regional leadership from Costa Rica to do that. In El Salvador, there were – there was, of course, the removals of the supreme court magistrates and the attorney general. And the government refused to reverse those moves after Special Envoy Zuniga’s visit.</p>
<p>So – excuse me – my question would be: Given that the department just named Jean Manes to return to El Salvador to – which is kind of a – it’s an exception, it’s a bit of a rarity that you would send a diplomat back to an embassy where they were formerly posted – I was wondering what – how should we read that in this current context?</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG: </b>Well, first<b> </b>of all, Ambassador Jean Manes is a well-respected career diplomat and ambassador, and we appreciate all her experience and insights and – through her experience as formerly, as you indicated, ambassador to El Salvador. So we are happy to center with the full confidence of the Secretary of State to engage with the government as we relay these concerns very publicly about the need for rule of law and our concern for the separation of powers.</p>
<p>I think this is an issue not just for El Salvador, but the entire region. These are some of the issues that are the drivers of why people leave their homes in the first place. They don’t have confidence in their governments and rule of law and governance and corruption issues that they themselves must address. So we want to talk about how these conditions can be changed and how we can help and partner with not only the governments, but working with civil society and others. So this will be a very frank and honest exchange of views, and again, we look forward to having those exchange of views in the SICA meeting.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Okay. And I think we have time for maybe one more question. Let’s go the line Matthew Russell Lee.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Sure. Thanks a lot and thanks for taking the question. I had wanted to ask specifically about Honduras. There have been a series of cases in the Southern District of New York where the brother of the president, Juan Orlando Hernandez, his brother Tony was convicted of drug trafficking. And in the most recent trial, his name came up repeatedly as “CC-4,” seemingly involved in the trafficking.</p>
<p>So I’m wondering – I know there’s a general concern with corruption and countries being sort of involuntarily subject to drug trafficking, but what’s the State Department’s thought of how to ensure that that aid to Honduras isn’t used by the current government? Or what’s your thinking on this? Thanks a lot.</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG: </b>Yes, well, we take any allegations of criminal activity very seriously. I won’t speak to the specifics of the DOJ case, but combating corruption and impunity, those are really at the center of the President’s priorities in the region and how to address the root causes of irregular migration. So we have said very clearly that any leader unwilling to tackle corruption will not be considered a close U.S. partner, and we take that very seriously. And so we want to have these conversations ongoing with, again, not just the governments but all stakeholders in the region. And we also want to use this opportunity in this multilateral format to see how countries can look for these regional challenges and come up with regional solutions together as well.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Okay, everyone. Once again, let me thank you for your participation today in our briefing. I’d also like to thank Acting Assistant Secretary Julie Chung for her participation. With that, our briefing is ended and the embargo is lifted. Have a nice day and a nice weekend.</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG: </b>Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Julie J. Chung, Acting Assistant SecretaryBureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Thank you. Good afternoon, everyone, and welcome to our briefing this afternoon. It is our pleasure to have you with us. It is also our pleasure to have as your briefer today Acting Assistant Secretary Julie Chung from the State Department’s Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs. She will talk with you about Secretary Blinken’s upcoming travel to Costa Rica, which we announced officially just this morning. Acting Assistant Secretary Chung will start off with some brief remarks and then she’ll be happy to take your questions.</p>
<p>Just a quick reminder, this call is on the record, but the contents are embargoed until the end of the call, okay? And with that, I’ll go ahead and turn it over to Assistant Secretary Julie Chung.</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG:</b> Thanks very much. Good afternoon, everybody.</p>
<p>Next week, Secretary of State Blinken will embark on his first in-person trip to the Western Hemisphere when he travels to San Jose, Costa Rica. While there, he will meet with Costa Rican President Alvarado, senior Costa Rican officials, and Americans and Costa Ricans building better futures for our countries. On June 1st, the Secretary will attend a regional meeting of the Central American foreign ministers, held under the aegis of the Central American Integration System, or SICA.</p>
<p>The leaders will use this multilateral forum to confront a broad array of issues, deepening our collaborative approach to migration challenges; combating corruption and impunity and reinforcing democratic institutions and rule of law; improving security and inclusive economic growth for the people of the region; combating the COVID-19 pandemic and addressing social and economic recovery; and improving environmental stewardship. All these challenges transcend borders and demand coordinated responses that enlist regional and global partners, including Mexico. We also know that the nations of Central America will benefit from deeper economic integration.</p>
<p>While the details regarding attendance are still taking form, I understand that all SICA countries and Mexico are invited to send their foreign ministers to the meeting, and this includes all seven Central American countries, as well as the Dominican Republic. Secretary Blinken will also raise issues specific to our bilateral relationship with some of his counterparts as the opportunity arises.</p>
<p>We are particularly appreciative of Costa Rica’s role as host of this meeting. And Secretary Blinken will also meet with Costa Rican President Carlos Alvarado Quesada and Minister of Foreign Affairs Rodolfo Solano Quiros to discuss our very robust and multifaceted relationship and celebrate their status as the newest member of the OECD.</p>
<p>With that, I would be happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Okay. Thank you, Assistant Secretary Chung. Everyone, just as a reminder, if you’d like to get into the question queue, go ahead and dial 1, 0.</p>
<p>Okay. I think we’ll start off with Karen DeYoung.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you, hi. I wondered if you could – two things, actually. One, what you expect in terms of bilateral meetings. I know you said details are still being formulated. Obviously, there are a couple of governments there with which the United States does not have the best of relationships, and I wonder if all of the seven members have been invited for bilateral meetings with the Secretary.</p>
<p>And secondarily, in a more general sense, I wonder if you could talk about the $4 billion program that President Biden has said he was going to use for the Northern Triangle states and give us some sense of where that stands right now. Have any programs been announced? Has any of the money been distributed? Is there any legislation for it? Where is it right now?</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG:</b> Yeah, thank you. In terms of the meeting, we really think this is a great opportunity to see regional solutions and have this regional discussion with the SICA grouping of government leadership. So we’ll be doing that. Of course, the bilateral meeting we have confirmed is with the president and foreign minister of Costa Rica, as they are the hosts. So we’ll be looking forward to a really robust discussion with Costa Rica.</p>
<p>I can’t speak to the other bilateral meetings which have not been confirmed yet, but again, this is a great opportunity for us to engage all these ministers and representatives on a range of issues that affect the region.</p>
<p>On the President’s $4 billion and commitment to the region, those are still being worked out. There are many phases of budget planning and programming that are being discussed in the interagency. But the commitment is very clear that the President has been making from the beginning, and the Vice President and the Secretary, about the U.S. commitment to the region, addressing the root causes, and making sure we work in partnership with not only the governments in the region but the private sector, civil society, and other stakeholders as well.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Let’s go to the line of Matt Spetalnick at Reuters.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Yes, thank you very much, appreciate it. You mentioned – can you hear me okay?</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG:</b> Yes.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Yes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Okay, great, great. So you mentioned corruption, that that will be taken up – that issue will be taken up with the leaders. Can you speak specifically to what the Secretary will have to say to the Northern Triangle countries where this has been flagged as one of the root causes of increased migration, the failure to address corruption and governance issues?</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG:</b> Well, the administration has been clear from the beginning about the importance of addressing corruption and making sure anticorruption, democracy, human rights – those are at the core of our foreign policy. So whether it’s discussions with the SICA counterparts or within Central America, El Salvador, Honduras, El Salvador – any of the countries in the region – we have pledged to work with the governments that also work in concert with us to address these kinds of issues on corruption. I think this is what the people in the region also look for their governments to do, so that when you address the migration – irregular migration – the corruption and governance and rule of law, those are all interconnected. So we are looking to really discuss and hear from the governments on what the challenges are and how we can address these challenges together.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Now let’s go to the line of Carla Angola at EVTV, Miami.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you so much for this opportunity. Secretary, we understand that on this trip, as you said, to Costa Rica, you are going to meet with senior officials from Mexico. Due to the massive arrival of Venezuelans at the border, we imagine that this will be an important issue to discover how, for example, human traffickers that take advantage of this circumstance. But I also want to know if you will talk about the negotiations between Juan Guaido and the Maduro regime, since it has been commented that the place of the first meeting in the spring work of those talks will be precisely Mexico. Could you confirm that information? Thank you so much.</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG:</b> Well, SICA and these regional discussions will focus on regional challenges and regional migration management. Of course, the horrific humanitarian disaster caused by the Maduro regime and the exodus of millions of Venezuelans to the region has had a deep impact, and United States has been the largest donor in terms of providing for those migrants and assistance to the countries. We understand there are 30,000 Venezuelans in Costa Rica and we have provided funding to support those migrants, including $6 million for Venezuelans in Costa Rica.</p>
<p>So this is a shared commitment. We want to look at the Venezuelan humanitarian crisis, its impact on the region, of course, the migration flows, and then, as you referred to, the abuse of traffickers and coyotes and the ability for us to use all tools, including law enforcement and other ways, to stop this flow of the dangerous movement that’s been happening throughout the region. So this will be an important topic, part of the migration discussion that all the countries in the region are addressing.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Okay. Let’s go to the line, please, of Beatriz Pascual.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Hi. Thank you. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG:</b> Yes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Great. Thank you so much. My question is about Nicaragua. Is the Secretary planning on meeting with the foreign minister of Nicaragua, Moncada? And what is the U.S. doing in regards to the targeting that Ortega is doing to the opposition figures as elections are approaching? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG:</b> We understand Nicaragua is a member of SICA, so Costa Rica as the host is inviting Nicaragua to attend the meeting. We don’t know – we haven’t confirmed who will attend for that government, but the United States has been very concerned about the situation in Nicaragua, the oppression of people, of freedom of press, of civil society and human rights defenders. That’s something we’ve spoken out frequently about, and we are working very closely in a multilateral fashion through the OAS. And I must say, Costa Rica has been a strong partner within that framework of the OAS to call for democracy and human rights in Nicaragua. So we will continue to work in that multilateral format, but I think there are very big concerns about elections being planned for later this year and whether the right conditions are there for those free and fair elections.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b> Okay. Let’s go to the line, please, of Pearl Matibe.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Thank you very much for your availability. I wonder, as part of the discussions and with the growing transit of illegal drugs and – either through or from African countries, will any of that be part of the discussions, if you’re noticing any increase in trends in that that also cross over into counterterrorism areas in Africa? And as part of the regional migration issue in and around South America, will any part of the increase, perhaps, in Africans transiting through that area, that region into the United States be part of that discussion? Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG:</b> Thank you. Well, Costa Rica is one of the major transit countries we know for drugs in Latin America, so it’s an area that we work very closely with Costa Rica on, on this rising challenge. We have worked to support Costa Rican security services so that they’ve seized over I think 71 metric tons of drugs in the past year, and no matter where the origin of that is. I think that transit – and then what brings along with the transit of drugs comes trafficking of persons and money laundering and all those things that transnational organizations – organized crime – all are involved with. So I think we will be addressing, again, the – some of the key pillars of SICA is to address democratic security, but also economic integration and regional coordinated solutions to these kind of challenges. So I look forward to those discussions when we arrive in Costa Rica.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Let’s go to the line of Cindy Regidor.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Hi, thank you. Yes, I wanted to ask again about the – how will you plan to include the Nicaraguan ongoing crisis in the agenda? Are you planning something special with the SICA members to have a big impact on the upcoming elections in November?</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG: </b>Well, this is an opportunity to discuss a range of issues of regional importance with SICA members. Again, the SICA was created in 1991, I believe, to really address migration management, climate change, social integration, economic integration. So we are an observer member of SICA, and we are welcomed by Costa Rica as the host to this meeting. So it’s a good opportunity for us to hear from regional leaders about their concerns and how to address these challenges together. Again, Costa Rica and the United States and many other countries have expressed our concerns, our joint concerns about Nicaragua and the state of democracy there through the OAS bilaterally, and also through our own individual public statements. And we will continue with that, and including our advocacy by our U.S. embassy in Nicaragua and our embassy in Costa Rica, who has often met with Nicaraguans in the country as well.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Let’s go to the line of Roman Gressier.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Hi, thanks for taking my question. One of the points of the agenda is going to be democratic governance, and it’s where, of course, we’re looking for regional leadership from Costa Rica to do that. In El Salvador, there were – there was, of course, the removals of the supreme court magistrates and the attorney general. And the government refused to reverse those moves after Special Envoy Zuniga’s visit.</p>
<p>So – excuse me – my question would be: Given that the department just named Jean Manes to return to El Salvador to – which is kind of a – it’s an exception, it’s a bit of a rarity that you would send a diplomat back to an embassy where they were formerly posted – I was wondering what – how should we read that in this current context?</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG: </b>Well, first<b> </b>of all, Ambassador Jean Manes is a well-respected career diplomat and ambassador, and we appreciate all her experience and insights and – through her experience as formerly, as you indicated, ambassador to El Salvador. So we are happy to center with the full confidence of the Secretary of State to engage with the government as we relay these concerns very publicly about the need for rule of law and our concern for the separation of powers.</p>
<p>I think this is an issue not just for El Salvador, but the entire region. These are some of the issues that are the drivers of why people leave their homes in the first place. They don’t have confidence in their governments and rule of law and governance and corruption issues that they themselves must address. So we want to talk about how these conditions can be changed and how we can help and partner with not only the governments, but working with civil society and others. So this will be a very frank and honest exchange of views, and again, we look forward to having those exchange of views in the SICA meeting.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Okay. And I think we have time for maybe one more question. Let’s go the line Matthew Russell Lee.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Sure. Thanks a lot and thanks for taking the question. I had wanted to ask specifically about Honduras. There have been a series of cases in the Southern District of New York where the brother of the president, Juan Orlando Hernandez, his brother Tony was convicted of drug trafficking. And in the most recent trial, his name came up repeatedly as “CC-4,” seemingly involved in the trafficking.</p>
<p>So I’m wondering – I know there’s a general concern with corruption and countries being sort of involuntarily subject to drug trafficking, but what’s the State Department’s thought of how to ensure that that aid to Honduras isn’t used by the current government? Or what’s your thinking on this? Thanks a lot.</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG: </b>Yes, well, we take any allegations of criminal activity very seriously. I won’t speak to the specifics of the DOJ case, but combating corruption and impunity, those are really at the center of the President’s priorities in the region and how to address the root causes of irregular migration. So we have said very clearly that any leader unwilling to tackle corruption will not be considered a close U.S. partner, and we take that very seriously. And so we want to have these conversations ongoing with, again, not just the governments but all stakeholders in the region. And we also want to use this opportunity in this multilateral format to see how countries can look for these regional challenges and come up with regional solutions together as well.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE: </b>Okay, everyone. Once again, let me thank you for your participation today in our briefing. I’d also like to thank Acting Assistant Secretary Julie Chung for her participation. With that, our briefing is ended and the embargo is lifted. Have a nice day and a nice weekend.</p>
<p><b>MS CHUNG: </b>Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dedication of the Davis Conference Room at the Foreign Service Institute</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/dedication-of-the-davis-conference-room-at-the-foreign-service-institute/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 20:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246937</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">In honor of Ambassador (ret.) Ruth A. Davis’s 40-year distinguished career and commitment to diplomatic excellence, the Department of State’s Foreign Service Institute (FSI) is renaming its Director’s Conference Room as the Davis Conference Room. Dedicating this high visibility space on FSI’s campus to Ambassador Davis symbolizes the Department of State’s commitment to honoring her legacy as a groundbreaking and inspirational leader.</p>
<p align="left">FSI will host the dedication ceremony on Friday, May 28, at 11:00 a.m. Acting Director of the Foreign Service Institute Julieta Valls Noyes, Deputy Secretary for Management and Resources Brian McKeon, and Acting Under Secretary for Management Carol Perez will deliver remarks.   Ambassador Davis will accept the dedication in front of a limited and socially distanced guest list. Additional guests will join via live stream.</p>
<p align="left">This event is open to the press via pre-registered live stream.  To register and receive a link to the event live stream please visit <a class="external-link" href="https://iipstate.secure.force.com/Events?objType=CRM&amp;id=a0Ut000000ElDSe" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">here</span></a>. For additional information, please contact FSI Public Affairs at <a href="mailto:FSIPublicAffairs@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FSIPublicAffairs@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">In honor of Ambassador (ret.) Ruth A. Davis’s 40-year distinguished career and commitment to diplomatic excellence, the Department of State’s Foreign Service Institute (FSI) is renaming its Director’s Conference Room as the Davis Conference Room. Dedicating this high visibility space on FSI’s campus to Ambassador Davis symbolizes the Department of State’s commitment to honoring her legacy as a groundbreaking and inspirational leader.</p>
<p align="left">FSI will host the dedication ceremony on Friday, May 28, at 11:00 a.m. Acting Director of the Foreign Service Institute Julieta Valls Noyes, Deputy Secretary for Management and Resources Brian McKeon, and Acting Under Secretary for Management Carol Perez will deliver remarks.   Ambassador Davis will accept the dedication in front of a limited and socially distanced guest list. Additional guests will join via live stream.</p>
<p align="left">This event is open to the press via pre-registered live stream.  To register and receive a link to the event live stream please visit <a class="external-link" href="https://iipstate.secure.force.com/Events?objType=CRM&amp;id=a0Ut000000ElDSe" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">here</span></a>. For additional information, please contact FSI Public Affairs at <a href="mailto:FSIPublicAffairs@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FSIPublicAffairs@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Detention of Armenian Soldiers</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/detention-of-armenian-soldiers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 18:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246892</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is concerned by recent developments along the international border between Armenia and Azerbaijan, including the detention of several Armenian soldiers by Azerbaijani forces. We call on both sides to urgently and peacefully resolve this incident. We also continue to call on Azerbaijan to release immediately all prisoners of war and other detainees, and we remind Azerbaijan of its obligations under international humanitarian law to treat all detainees humanely.</p>
<p>The United States considers any movements along the non-demarcated areas of the international border between Armenia and Azerbaijan to be provocative and unnecessary.  We reject the use of force to demarcate the border and call on both sides to return to their previous positions and to cease military fortification of the non-demarcated border and the emplacement of landmines. Specifically, we call on Azerbaijan to relocate its forces to the positions they held on May 11.  We also call on Armenia to relocate its forces to the positions they held on May 11, and welcome statements of intent to this effect. These actions will de-escalate tensions and create space for a peaceful negotiation process to demarcate the border on an urgent basis.  The United States is prepared to assist these efforts.</p>
<p>The United States urges the sides to return as soon as possible to substantive negotiations under the auspices of the​ OSCE Minsk Group Co-Chairs to achieve a long-term political settlement to the Nagorno-Karabakh conflict.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is concerned by recent developments along the international border between Armenia and Azerbaijan, including the detention of several Armenian soldiers by Azerbaijani forces. We call on both sides to urgently and peacefully resolve this incident. We also continue to call on Azerbaijan to release immediately all prisoners of war and other detainees, and we remind Azerbaijan of its obligations under international humanitarian law to treat all detainees humanely.</p>
<p>The United States considers any movements along the non-demarcated areas of the international border between Armenia and Azerbaijan to be provocative and unnecessary.  We reject the use of force to demarcate the border and call on both sides to return to their previous positions and to cease military fortification of the non-demarcated border and the emplacement of landmines. Specifically, we call on Azerbaijan to relocate its forces to the positions they held on May 11.  We also call on Armenia to relocate its forces to the positions they held on May 11, and welcome statements of intent to this effect. These actions will de-escalate tensions and create space for a peaceful negotiation process to demarcate the border on an urgent basis.  The United States is prepared to assist these efforts.</p>
<p>The United States urges the sides to return as soon as possible to substantive negotiations under the auspices of the​ OSCE Minsk Group Co-Chairs to achieve a long-term political settlement to the Nagorno-Karabakh conflict.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-nato-secretary-general-stoltenberg-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 17:10:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246861</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg.  Secretary Blinken and Secretary General Stoltenberg discussed next month’s NATO Summit as well as NATO’s importance to the security and prosperity of the Transatlantic community and the world.  The Secretary and the Secretary General stressed that adapting and modernizing NATO to meet the challenges of the 21st century, including by advancing the NATO 2030 initiative, is essential to ensure Transatlantic security.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg.  Secretary Blinken and Secretary General Stoltenberg discussed next month’s NATO Summit as well as NATO’s importance to the security and prosperity of the Transatlantic community and the world.  The Secretary and the Secretary General stressed that adapting and modernizing NATO to meet the challenges of the 21st century, including by advancing the NATO 2030 initiative, is essential to ensure Transatlantic security.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with UN Special Coordinator Wennesland</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-un-special-coordinator-wennesland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 15:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246820</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with UN Special Coordinator for Middle East Peace Tor Wennesland. Secretary Blinken and Special Coordinator Wennesland discussed the critical humanitarian needs of the Palestinian people and underscored the need for rapid and unimpeded movement of relief and recovery supplies that also ensures assistance goes to the Palestinian people and not Hamas.  The Secretary and Special Coordinator also discussed the need to prevent the cycle of violence from recurring.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with UN Special Coordinator for Middle East Peace Tor Wennesland. Secretary Blinken and Special Coordinator Wennesland discussed the critical humanitarian needs of the Palestinian people and underscored the need for rapid and unimpeded movement of relief and recovery supplies that also ensures assistance goes to the Palestinian people and not Hamas.  The Secretary and Special Coordinator also discussed the need to prevent the cycle of violence from recurring.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Denial of Democracy in Hong Kong</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/denial-of-democracy-in-hong-kong/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 14:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246787</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The Chinese government continues to undermine the democratic institutions of Hong Kong, denying Hong Kong residents the rights that the People’s Republic of China (PRC) itself has guaranteed.  The Hong Kong Legislative Council (LegCo) passage on May 27 of new measures that alter the composition of the LegCo and Election Commission severely constrains people in Hong Kong from meaningfully participating in their own governance and having their voices heard.</p>
<p>Decreasing Hong Kong residents’ electoral representation will not foster long-term political and social stability for Hong Kong.  This legislation defies the Basic Law’s clear acknowledgment that the ultimate objective is the election of all members of the LegCo by universal suffrage.  We once again call on the PRC and the Hong Kong authorities to allow the voices of all Hong Kongers to be heard.  We also call on these authorities to release and drop charges against all individuals charged under the National Security Law and other laws merely for standing for election or for expressing dissenting views.  The United States stands united with our allies and partners in speaking out for the human rights and fundamental freedoms guaranteed to the people in Hong Kong by the Sino-British Joint Declaration and the Basic Law.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The Chinese government continues to undermine the democratic institutions of Hong Kong, denying Hong Kong residents the rights that the People’s Republic of China (PRC) itself has guaranteed.  The Hong Kong Legislative Council (LegCo) passage on May 27 of new measures that alter the composition of the LegCo and Election Commission severely constrains people in Hong Kong from meaningfully participating in their own governance and having their voices heard.</p>
<p>Decreasing Hong Kong residents’ electoral representation will not foster long-term political and social stability for Hong Kong.  This legislation defies the Basic Law’s clear acknowledgment that the ultimate objective is the election of all members of the LegCo by universal suffrage.  We once again call on the PRC and the Hong Kong authorities to allow the voices of all Hong Kongers to be heard.  We also call on these authorities to release and drop charges against all individuals charged under the National Security Law and other laws merely for standing for election or for expressing dissenting views.  The United States stands united with our allies and partners in speaking out for the human rights and fundamental freedoms guaranteed to the people in Hong Kong by the Sino-British Joint Declaration and the Basic Law.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
