<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 20:45:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>On the Occasion of Vesak Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/on-the-occasion-of-vesak-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 20:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246601</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Today we join Buddhists at home and around the world in their celebration of Vesak, a day honoring the legacy, tradition, and teachings of the Buddha.</p>
<p>On this occasion, we celebrate the invaluable contributions of Buddhist communities the world over.  We join these communities in recommitting ourselves to upholding the universal principles of compassion, peace, and respect for human dignity.</p>
<p>May this day inspire us all to reflect on our shared values and to collectively work to build a better world for Buddhists and people of all belief traditions.</p>
<p>Happy Buddha Purnima.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Today we join Buddhists at home and around the world in their celebration of Vesak, a day honoring the legacy, tradition, and teachings of the Buddha.</p>
<p>On this occasion, we celebrate the invaluable contributions of Buddhist communities the world over.  We join these communities in recommitting ourselves to upholding the universal principles of compassion, peace, and respect for human dignity.</p>
<p>May this day inspire us all to reflect on our shared values and to collectively work to build a better world for Buddhists and people of all belief traditions.</p>
<p>Happy Buddha Purnima.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at a Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-press-availability-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 19:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246602</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Amman, Jordan</p>
<p>St. Regis Hotel</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Let me start with a few words before taking some questions.  And let me start, first of all, by congratulating the people of Jordan on the 75th anniversary of the kingdom’s independence this week.  I’d very much like to thank His Majesty King Abdullah for a very warm welcome today and a very good conversation.  Our time in Jordan has been brief, but we had very broad-ranging and very substantive discussions at the palace today.</p>
<p>Jordan’s recent contributions to help bring an end to the conflict in Israel demonstrate the kingdom’s enduring role as a force for peace in the region, which is one of the reasons our relationship is so strong and so vital.  His Majesty King Abdullah’s leadership has been crucial on this run, as it has been in so many other areas where Jordan and the United States work together, including efforts to promote stability, economic opportunity, and justice across the region.</p>
<p>Jordan is more than a strategic partner to America.  It’s a friend.  And friends stand by one another in challenging times, and I know this past period has been difficult on Jordan, as it has been on many of us.  Both of our nations are now grappling with how we can grow our economies so that they can deliver real opportunities for our people.  The fact that Jordan is doing this while continuing to show considerable generosity to people who came here fleeing violence and persecution is a reflection of the country’s character and the big hearts of the Jordanian people.</p>
<p>As you know, President Biden asked me to make this trip, and I’ve kept him updated on our progress throughout.  Securing the ceasefire was important, particularly because of the devastating toll violence took on families on both sides.  But we see the ceasefire not as an end, but as a beginning, something to build on.  Earlier today, I discussed how we can do this with President al-Sisi and Foreign Minister Shoukry in Cairo.  Egypt played a crucial role in brokering the ceasefire.  It’s already committed $500 million to the reconstruction effort in Gaza.  We talked about that.</p>
<p>We also discussed Egypt’s water needs and the importance of finding a diplomatic solution to issues around the Grand Ethiopian Renaissance Dam that meet the legitimate needs of Egypt, Sudan, and Ethiopia.  I commended Egypt for its leadership in urging Libya’s legislature to keep elections on track for December, and we agreed on the need for all foreign forces to leave Libya.  I also underscored the importance that President Biden places on human rights, and we agreed to engage in a constructive dialogue on these issues in Egypt.</p>
<p>Here today in Amman, my conversation with His Majesty touched on, again, a range of topics, including the urgent work we need to do together to meet humanitarian and reconstruction needs in Gaza while ensuring that the Palestinian people, not Hamas, benefit from this assistance.  We discussed Jordan’s essential role as a custodian of Muslim holy places and the importance of preserving the historic status quo at Jerusalem’s holy sites.  Jordan also plays a vital role in the West Bank.  As the U.S. re-engages with the Palestinian people and reopens our consulate in Jerusalem, we’ll have a lot of work to do together as well.</p>
<p>Our meetings today in Cairo and Amman, indeed this whole trip, reflect a fundamental reality.  If we want to avoid a return to the harrowing violence of recent weeks, the countries of this region need to help and support one another.  In the coming days, I’ll be consulting broadly with Gulf countries and other partners to ensure we all contribute to recovery, stability, and the reduction of tensions.</p>
<p>We covered a fair bit of ground in a short trip, but I think one thing is very clear from the many conversations that I’ve had:  The aspirations of people in every place we visit – Palestinians, Israelis, Egyptians, Jordanians – are remarkably similar.  They want security for themselves and their loved ones.  They want opportunity.  They want greater equity.  They want their leaders to deliver on their most fundamental needs.  They want their rights to be respected.  They want to live with dignity.  These are the aspirations we all have, including Americans; indeed, they’re universal.  As people in this region make hard choices and do hard work to meet these goals, the United States will stand with them.</p>
<p>And with that, I’m happy to take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll turn to Nike Ching.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Good evening, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good evening.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  How are you?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  We understand you had a very busy schedule today, so thank you for talking to the press.  On the human rights issue with regard to your meeting with – earlier today with President Sisi, are Americans or other detainees being released by Egypt soon?  How did the discussion come about, or was there a discussion to prompt the release?  And if I may, why not include a meeting with human rights defenders in Egypt in the original schedule?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.  We had a lengthy discussion and exchange on human rights today in the meeting with President al-Sisi, which followed on President Biden’s conversation with President al-Sisi some days ago.  And a couple of things.  First, with regard to Americans who are detained, first let me say that we remain deeply saddened by the needless death in custody of Mustafa Kassem.  We’ve seen, I think, just in the last hours the Freedom Initiative and the good-faith work that it’s doing to put a light on this important issue.  I certainly raised this in my meeting today, and we’ll continue to do so until Americans are reunited with their families.</p>
<p>More broadly, I think you know that President Biden takes the issue of human rights and our commitment to human rights very seriously.  Indeed, he’s asked us to put it at the heart of our foreign policy, and that’s exactly what we’re doing, and that was reflected in the conversations that we had today.</p>
<p>Oh, and I’m sorry, as to – with regard to meetings, look, we had unfortunately in Egypt, and also here in Amman, a very compressed time to work with.  And I had an opportunity, as you know, when I was in Ramallah, to meet with civil society leaders, including some remarkable people who are working on human rights.  I expect that in the future and on future trips, I’ll have an opportunity to do more of that.  We just had, unfortunately, in Cairo, a very, very tight time and only were able to do meetings with the government.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Saleh Khawaldeh from Petra News Agency.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Your Excellency, what’s the next U.S. step for dealing with the conflict after the ceasefire, especially after the – President Biden’s statement that the two-state solution is the only solution?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.  The most urgent thing is humanitarian assistance for the people in Gaza, and particularly water, sanitation, electricity.  We all have to come together to answer those immediate needs.  Beyond that, reconstruction, rebuilding.  And we had very good conversations over the course of the last couple of days with the Palestinian Authority, with Israel, with Egypt, and we were also in conversation with the United Nations about that effort, and we’ve already contributed significant sums.  The Egyptians have contributed a very significant sum to the rebuilding process.  So we will start to engage in that as well.</p>
<p>But more broadly than that, what we want to see and what we’re working on is steps that all sides can take to reduce tensions and to build both some more trust and more hope going forward.  And as that takes shape and as that hopefully moves forward, then I think we’re – we can see the possibility of conditions developing in which it will be more possible to actually advance on the prospect of two states.  But most urgently, again, is dealing with the immediate needs of people and then taking the necessary steps that I think can create better conditions in which we can try to move forward on two states.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Tracy Wilkinson, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yes, hi, thank you.  You had very long meetings today with both President Sisi and King Abdullah.  So I just wondered if you could give a little more detail about the kinds of steps you talked about them taking – Egypt, for example – beyond just reconstruction, but maintaining the ceasefire, keeping it in check.  You mentioned the money that Egypt is going to contribute to reconstruction, but what other concrete steps are they prepared to take?  For example, we’ve seen Israel has already relaxed some of the fishing restrictions on Gaza.  What in that kind of vein might Egypt take?  Jordan – King Abdullah for a long time has been very upset about restrictions that Israel is putting on access to al-Aqsa.  Have you been able to reassure him or convey any reassurances from Israel that that will be less of an issue in the future?</p>
<p>And then finally, a human rights question to follow up on the human rights issue with President Sisi.  This administration came in saying that human rights would be the core value of your foreign policy.  Do you feel at all like President Sisi thinks that maybe now that you need him for Gaza, he is somehow inoculated against your demands for improving the human rights situations in Egypt?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Great, thank you.  There are a number of things that everyone involved is looking at, and I think will be doing to address the – some of the needs that I’ve described.  And in particular when it comes to Gaza, there has to be – and we’re working on this – a process to, in a very deliberate way, evaluate exactly what is required, what needs to be rebuilt, and then how do we most effectively go about doing that.  And that is going to involve the United Nations, that’s going to involve Israel, Egypt, the Palestinian Authority.</p>
<p>And so we’re working to put together the right process, the right mechanism to do that.  And it really does start with assessing exactly what’s needed and then how to address the need.  And again, just to make the clear distinction, we have – and this is already moving – urgent humanitarian requirements, as I’ve said, particularly water, electricity, sanitation.  That’s already moving forward with different things moving into Gaza as we speak.</p>
<p>With regard to some of the flashpoints that contributed to the events of the last couple of weeks, we discussed those in some detail, to include the al-Aqsa Mosque and the Temple Mount, to include the evictions of Palestinians who’ve been living in homes for decades, even generations, to include a number of other issues of incitement to violence, payments to prisoners who – or their families, who are engaged or been engaged in acts of terrorism.  We cover all of those and more and shared our strongly held view that it’s really incumbent on all sides to, again, avoid taking steps that could potentially reignite this cycle of violence, and longer-term would make the efforts to pursue a two-state solution even more challenging than they already are.  So we certainly shared that.</p>
<p>And again, to come back to human rights, I think the fact that, as I said, we had a lengthy exchange on that with President al-Sisi as a reflection of the fact that it remains very much on the agenda with Egypt.  And my own exchange followed one that President Biden had with President al-Sisi when they spoke on the phone.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Final question from Priyanka Navani from Roya TV.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good evening.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Good evening.  Thank you so much for being here, and welcome to Jordan.  Yesterday during a press conference with Netanyahu, you reaffirmed President Biden’s support for the idea that Palestinians and Israelis should both be able to leave – live, sorry – securely and safely.  And actually you just underscored that very point, that Palestinians should be able to live safely, in your speech.  But yesterday in your press conference, you said that the U.S. would be contributing more money to the Iron Dome, and then you said also that Palestinians – you would be expanding trade and investment in Palestine.  So I’m just wondering:  Why not commit to building infrastructure in Palestine that would keep Palestinians safe?  Maslow’s hierarchy would indicate that safety would be more of a priority than trade and investment.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.  A few things there.  As we announced yesterday, the United States is in the process of providing more than $360 million of assistance to the Palestinian people.  That includes nearly $40 million in new assistance and that’s directed primarily to support the humanitarian efforts in the West Bank and Gaza.  The new assistance includes nearly 33 million for UNRWA in support of the West Bank and Gaza operations, an additional five and a half million, again, for humanitarian partners.</p>
<p>And all of this will support humanitarian organizations in the first instance to provide what’s needed immediately, and that’s the emergency shelter, food, relief items, health care, mental health, et cetera.  But beyond that, working with Congress, the State Department, USAID intend to provide about 75 million in additional development and economic assistance over the next year that can support relief, recovery, and indeed, infrastructure in the West Bank as well as in Gaza.  It will help advance private sector growth, which is really critical to bringing jobs to people who need them, as well as access to basic needs, services, like health care, like food.  And there are additional programs as well.  This is on top of about $250 million in economic, development, and security and humanitarian assistance that we announced before recent events, back in March and April.</p>
<p>And that’s where you get to a total of about $360 million for the Palestinian people.  All of this does go to building things – some concrete things, some programmatic things, all of which are designed to bring more hope, but also, concretely, more prospects, more opportunity for Palestinians.  And some of that need will include infrastructure.  This is critical because so much of this is, in the first instance, doing everything we can to improve in material ways the lives that people are living.  That’s where I think it starts.  That’s where you try to build hope as well as opportunity.  And that, both in a literal sense when it comes to infrastructure and in a broader sense, is the foundation, I believe, upon which maybe we can build something even better.</p>
<p>So there’s a lot that’s already in the works.  It’s going to take some time to see the effect, to see the impact, but it is moving forward.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thank you very much.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Amman, Jordan</p>
<p>St. Regis Hotel</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Let me start with a few words before taking some questions.  And let me start, first of all, by congratulating the people of Jordan on the 75th anniversary of the kingdom’s independence this week.  I’d very much like to thank His Majesty King Abdullah for a very warm welcome today and a very good conversation.  Our time in Jordan has been brief, but we had very broad-ranging and very substantive discussions at the palace today.</p>
<p>Jordan’s recent contributions to help bring an end to the conflict in Israel demonstrate the kingdom’s enduring role as a force for peace in the region, which is one of the reasons our relationship is so strong and so vital.  His Majesty King Abdullah’s leadership has been crucial on this run, as it has been in so many other areas where Jordan and the United States work together, including efforts to promote stability, economic opportunity, and justice across the region.</p>
<p>Jordan is more than a strategic partner to America.  It’s a friend.  And friends stand by one another in challenging times, and I know this past period has been difficult on Jordan, as it has been on many of us.  Both of our nations are now grappling with how we can grow our economies so that they can deliver real opportunities for our people.  The fact that Jordan is doing this while continuing to show considerable generosity to people who came here fleeing violence and persecution is a reflection of the country’s character and the big hearts of the Jordanian people.</p>
<p>As you know, President Biden asked me to make this trip, and I’ve kept him updated on our progress throughout.  Securing the ceasefire was important, particularly because of the devastating toll violence took on families on both sides.  But we see the ceasefire not as an end, but as a beginning, something to build on.  Earlier today, I discussed how we can do this with President al-Sisi and Foreign Minister Shoukry in Cairo.  Egypt played a crucial role in brokering the ceasefire.  It’s already committed $500 million to the reconstruction effort in Gaza.  We talked about that.</p>
<p>We also discussed Egypt’s water needs and the importance of finding a diplomatic solution to issues around the Grand Ethiopian Renaissance Dam that meet the legitimate needs of Egypt, Sudan, and Ethiopia.  I commended Egypt for its leadership in urging Libya’s legislature to keep elections on track for December, and we agreed on the need for all foreign forces to leave Libya.  I also underscored the importance that President Biden places on human rights, and we agreed to engage in a constructive dialogue on these issues in Egypt.</p>
<p>Here today in Amman, my conversation with His Majesty touched on, again, a range of topics, including the urgent work we need to do together to meet humanitarian and reconstruction needs in Gaza while ensuring that the Palestinian people, not Hamas, benefit from this assistance.  We discussed Jordan’s essential role as a custodian of Muslim holy places and the importance of preserving the historic status quo at Jerusalem’s holy sites.  Jordan also plays a vital role in the West Bank.  As the U.S. re-engages with the Palestinian people and reopens our consulate in Jerusalem, we’ll have a lot of work to do together as well.</p>
<p>Our meetings today in Cairo and Amman, indeed this whole trip, reflect a fundamental reality.  If we want to avoid a return to the harrowing violence of recent weeks, the countries of this region need to help and support one another.  In the coming days, I’ll be consulting broadly with Gulf countries and other partners to ensure we all contribute to recovery, stability, and the reduction of tensions.</p>
<p>We covered a fair bit of ground in a short trip, but I think one thing is very clear from the many conversations that I’ve had:  The aspirations of people in every place we visit – Palestinians, Israelis, Egyptians, Jordanians – are remarkably similar.  They want security for themselves and their loved ones.  They want opportunity.  They want greater equity.  They want their leaders to deliver on their most fundamental needs.  They want their rights to be respected.  They want to live with dignity.  These are the aspirations we all have, including Americans; indeed, they’re universal.  As people in this region make hard choices and do hard work to meet these goals, the United States will stand with them.</p>
<p>And with that, I’m happy to take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll turn to Nike Ching.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Good evening, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good evening.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  How are you?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  We understand you had a very busy schedule today, so thank you for talking to the press.  On the human rights issue with regard to your meeting with – earlier today with President Sisi, are Americans or other detainees being released by Egypt soon?  How did the discussion come about, or was there a discussion to prompt the release?  And if I may, why not include a meeting with human rights defenders in Egypt in the original schedule?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.  We had a lengthy discussion and exchange on human rights today in the meeting with President al-Sisi, which followed on President Biden’s conversation with President al-Sisi some days ago.  And a couple of things.  First, with regard to Americans who are detained, first let me say that we remain deeply saddened by the needless death in custody of Mustafa Kassem.  We’ve seen, I think, just in the last hours the Freedom Initiative and the good-faith work that it’s doing to put a light on this important issue.  I certainly raised this in my meeting today, and we’ll continue to do so until Americans are reunited with their families.</p>
<p>More broadly, I think you know that President Biden takes the issue of human rights and our commitment to human rights very seriously.  Indeed, he’s asked us to put it at the heart of our foreign policy, and that’s exactly what we’re doing, and that was reflected in the conversations that we had today.</p>
<p>Oh, and I’m sorry, as to – with regard to meetings, look, we had unfortunately in Egypt, and also here in Amman, a very compressed time to work with.  And I had an opportunity, as you know, when I was in Ramallah, to meet with civil society leaders, including some remarkable people who are working on human rights.  I expect that in the future and on future trips, I’ll have an opportunity to do more of that.  We just had, unfortunately, in Cairo, a very, very tight time and only were able to do meetings with the government.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Saleh Khawaldeh from Petra News Agency.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Your Excellency, what’s the next U.S. step for dealing with the conflict after the ceasefire, especially after the – President Biden’s statement that the two-state solution is the only solution?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.  The most urgent thing is humanitarian assistance for the people in Gaza, and particularly water, sanitation, electricity.  We all have to come together to answer those immediate needs.  Beyond that, reconstruction, rebuilding.  And we had very good conversations over the course of the last couple of days with the Palestinian Authority, with Israel, with Egypt, and we were also in conversation with the United Nations about that effort, and we’ve already contributed significant sums.  The Egyptians have contributed a very significant sum to the rebuilding process.  So we will start to engage in that as well.</p>
<p>But more broadly than that, what we want to see and what we’re working on is steps that all sides can take to reduce tensions and to build both some more trust and more hope going forward.  And as that takes shape and as that hopefully moves forward, then I think we’re – we can see the possibility of conditions developing in which it will be more possible to actually advance on the prospect of two states.  But most urgently, again, is dealing with the immediate needs of people and then taking the necessary steps that I think can create better conditions in which we can try to move forward on two states.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Tracy Wilkinson, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yes, hi, thank you.  You had very long meetings today with both President Sisi and King Abdullah.  So I just wondered if you could give a little more detail about the kinds of steps you talked about them taking – Egypt, for example – beyond just reconstruction, but maintaining the ceasefire, keeping it in check.  You mentioned the money that Egypt is going to contribute to reconstruction, but what other concrete steps are they prepared to take?  For example, we’ve seen Israel has already relaxed some of the fishing restrictions on Gaza.  What in that kind of vein might Egypt take?  Jordan – King Abdullah for a long time has been very upset about restrictions that Israel is putting on access to al-Aqsa.  Have you been able to reassure him or convey any reassurances from Israel that that will be less of an issue in the future?</p>
<p>And then finally, a human rights question to follow up on the human rights issue with President Sisi.  This administration came in saying that human rights would be the core value of your foreign policy.  Do you feel at all like President Sisi thinks that maybe now that you need him for Gaza, he is somehow inoculated against your demands for improving the human rights situations in Egypt?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Great, thank you.  There are a number of things that everyone involved is looking at, and I think will be doing to address the – some of the needs that I’ve described.  And in particular when it comes to Gaza, there has to be – and we’re working on this – a process to, in a very deliberate way, evaluate exactly what is required, what needs to be rebuilt, and then how do we most effectively go about doing that.  And that is going to involve the United Nations, that’s going to involve Israel, Egypt, the Palestinian Authority.</p>
<p>And so we’re working to put together the right process, the right mechanism to do that.  And it really does start with assessing exactly what’s needed and then how to address the need.  And again, just to make the clear distinction, we have – and this is already moving – urgent humanitarian requirements, as I’ve said, particularly water, electricity, sanitation.  That’s already moving forward with different things moving into Gaza as we speak.</p>
<p>With regard to some of the flashpoints that contributed to the events of the last couple of weeks, we discussed those in some detail, to include the al-Aqsa Mosque and the Temple Mount, to include the evictions of Palestinians who’ve been living in homes for decades, even generations, to include a number of other issues of incitement to violence, payments to prisoners who – or their families, who are engaged or been engaged in acts of terrorism.  We cover all of those and more and shared our strongly held view that it’s really incumbent on all sides to, again, avoid taking steps that could potentially reignite this cycle of violence, and longer-term would make the efforts to pursue a two-state solution even more challenging than they already are.  So we certainly shared that.</p>
<p>And again, to come back to human rights, I think the fact that, as I said, we had a lengthy exchange on that with President al-Sisi as a reflection of the fact that it remains very much on the agenda with Egypt.  And my own exchange followed one that President Biden had with President al-Sisi when they spoke on the phone.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Final question from Priyanka Navani from Roya TV.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good evening.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Good evening.  Thank you so much for being here, and welcome to Jordan.  Yesterday during a press conference with Netanyahu, you reaffirmed President Biden’s support for the idea that Palestinians and Israelis should both be able to leave – live, sorry – securely and safely.  And actually you just underscored that very point, that Palestinians should be able to live safely, in your speech.  But yesterday in your press conference, you said that the U.S. would be contributing more money to the Iron Dome, and then you said also that Palestinians – you would be expanding trade and investment in Palestine.  So I’m just wondering:  Why not commit to building infrastructure in Palestine that would keep Palestinians safe?  Maslow’s hierarchy would indicate that safety would be more of a priority than trade and investment.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.  A few things there.  As we announced yesterday, the United States is in the process of providing more than $360 million of assistance to the Palestinian people.  That includes nearly $40 million in new assistance and that’s directed primarily to support the humanitarian efforts in the West Bank and Gaza.  The new assistance includes nearly 33 million for UNRWA in support of the West Bank and Gaza operations, an additional five and a half million, again, for humanitarian partners.</p>
<p>And all of this will support humanitarian organizations in the first instance to provide what’s needed immediately, and that’s the emergency shelter, food, relief items, health care, mental health, et cetera.  But beyond that, working with Congress, the State Department, USAID intend to provide about 75 million in additional development and economic assistance over the next year that can support relief, recovery, and indeed, infrastructure in the West Bank as well as in Gaza.  It will help advance private sector growth, which is really critical to bringing jobs to people who need them, as well as access to basic needs, services, like health care, like food.  And there are additional programs as well.  This is on top of about $250 million in economic, development, and security and humanitarian assistance that we announced before recent events, back in March and April.</p>
<p>And that’s where you get to a total of about $360 million for the Palestinian people.  All of this does go to building things – some concrete things, some programmatic things, all of which are designed to bring more hope, but also, concretely, more prospects, more opportunity for Palestinians.  And some of that need will include infrastructure.  This is critical because so much of this is, in the first instance, doing everything we can to improve in material ways the lives that people are living.  That’s where I think it starts.  That’s where you try to build hope as well as opportunity.  And that, both in a literal sense when it comes to infrastructure and in a broader sense, is the foundation, I believe, upon which maybe we can build something even better.</p>
<p>So there’s a lot that’s already in the works.  It’s going to take some time to see the effect, to see the impact, but it is moving forward.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thank you very much.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with Yonit Levy of Channel 12</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-yonit-levy-of-channel-12/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 18:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246524</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Jerusalem</p>
<p>David Citadel Hotel</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Secretary of State Antony Blinken, welcome.  Thank you very much for talking to us today.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Hi.  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  This isn’t – you’re of course not a stranger to the region.  This is far from being your first time here, but it’s the first time as Secretary of State.  And I wanted to begin by asking you about the ceasefire.  I mean, you seem to be in this cycle of every couple of years having a short but devastating war between Israel and Hamas, and of course, the U.S. played a constructive role in bringing about a ceasefire.</p>
<p>(Interruption.)</p>
<p>I’m going to ask just part of that again.  The U.S. played a constructive role in bringing about a ceasefire, but many Israelis believe that this is just a countdown to the next conflict.  What can be done?  What is the way out?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I think we do have to try to break the cycle of violence, because if we don’t it will repeat itself.  And maybe it’s next month, maybe it’s next year, maybe it’s in five years, but I don’t think that’s in anyone’s interests.  It’s not in the interests of Israelis.  It’s not in the interests of Palestinians.  It’s not in the interests of the broader region.</p>
<p>So I think we have to all try to work on a few things.  First, of course, we need to deal with the urgent situation in Gaza itself – humanitarian assistance, water, electricity, sanitation – to respond to the immediate needs.  We need to work together to try and rebuild and create some prospects for a better life for people who live in Gaza.  But then I think it’s really incumbent on both sides to try to do something to take away some of the things that can spark the cycle of violence.  And ultimately, what that really comes down to is, at least in our judgment, doing everything possible to make sure that Israelis and Palestinians alike have in their lives equal measures of security, of opportunity, of dignity.  And that manifests itself in many different ways, but I think at heart, that’s what needs to happen.  And so we spent some time today talking to our allies here in Israel about how that might go forward and did the same with the Palestinians.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Regarding the U.S.’s military assistance to Israel, during this operation in Gaza we heard mounting opposition from progressive lawmakers to the arms deal with Israel and trying to block it.  Is there any chance that the administration will reconsider the deal to supply Israel with precision-guided weapons?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  President Biden has been absolutely clear, and he’s been clear on more than one occasion:  We are committed to Israel’s security, period.  We will make sure that Israel has the means to defend itself.  And particularly when we have something like what the Israelis experienced in the last couple of weeks, attacks from a terrorist group indiscriminately targeting civilians, we want to make sure that Israel has the means to deal with that.</p>
<p>At the same time, as a democracy, I think Israel has an extra burden, and we owe the same thing to make sure that when it is defending itself, defending its citizens, it is doing everything it possibly can to avoid civilian casualties, to minimize the harm that is done to those who can get caught in the crossfire.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Do you believe that Israel did in this case?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I think Israel took very significant steps to do that, but we also know that on both sides men, women, and especially children were lost, and I think that’s deeply painful, and it’s a reminder that we throw around numbers, statistics, but these statistics, these numbers can’t hide the fact that we’re talking about real human beings.  And that’s important because I think it just reminds us about the need to make sure that we’re doing everything we can to avoid a repetition.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Taking the opportunity to talk about the bigger picture, the relationship between Israel and Palestinians, will there be an attempt to reignite the Israel-Palestinian peace process?  You spoke in your confirmation hearings saying that a Palestinian state is realistically – it’s hard to see near-term prospects for moving forward.  Do you still think that?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, two things.  I think a lot of work needs to be redone to try to rebuild some confidence, to try to rebuild some trust, to try to build some conditions and an environment in which it might be possible to re-engage in a meaningful way on two states.  But equally important, we continue to believe very strongly that a two-state solution is not just the best way, but probably the only way to really assure that going forward, Israel has a future as a secure Jewish and democratic state, and the Palestinians have a state to which they’re entitled.</p>
<p>So I think we want to get to that.  But right now, the focus is on dealing with the aftermath, the recent violence, trying to build on the ceasefire, address the immediate needs and concerns, and then see if over time the conditions are such that there’s a better environment for trying to pursue a two-state solution.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I want to move on to Iran.  Iranian President Hassan Rouhani said last Thursday that his country’s close to reaching a deal.  He said we have taken a big step and an agreement in principle has been achieved.  Is that true?  How close is the deal?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, I think that would be news to us, because we’re now, I think, in the fifth rounds of talks in Vienna.  These are – as I think you know – indirect talks.  We haven’t been talking directly to the Iranians.  It’s been through the European Union and our other partners.  I think we’ve clarified increasingly what each side would need to do to come back into compliance with the JCPOA, but it remains an unanswered question whether Iran is actually prepared to do what it needs to do to come back into compliance.  The jury is still out on that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Israeli prime minister has been quite clear in his opposition to the Iran deal.  Today during your joint statement, he said, “I hope the U.S.  not  to the old JCPOA.”  So let me ask you, Mr. Secretary, are the plans indeed to return to the same terms as the JCPOA or additional safeguards, for example to ensure that Iran – Iran’s compliance?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  The United States and Israel are absolutely united in the proposition that Iran can never acquire a nuclear weapon.  We are joined in that goal and in that commitment.  It’s also no secret that over time we’ve had differences over the best way to get there, to make sure that Iran does not get a weapon.  From our perspective, the JCPOA did exactly what it set out to accomplish, which was to cut off all of the pathways that Iran had to producing fissile material for a nuclear weapon on short order.  And our experts verified that it was working, international experts verified that it was working, and it had the most intrusive inspections regime of any arms control agreement ever achieved.  And the result was that when the agreement was in force, Iran, had it decided to try to produce fissile material for a nuclear weapon, would have required at least a year to do so, which would have been plenty of time to see it and, if necessary, to do something about it.</p>
<p>But here’s what happened since.  Now that we’re out of the deal, Iran has started to ignore the constrains that the deal imposed.  And it is closer and closer and closer to being able to produce fissile material for a nuclear weapon on very short order.  And so far from getting less dangerous without the deal, it’s gotten more dangerous.  And I think there’s a certain amount of urgency to try to put Iran back into the nuclear box that the deal constructed.</p>
<p>So having said that, if – what we’ve said along is if we succeed in doing that, if Iran returns to compliance with the deal, we would do the same.  We would also seek to make it, as we say, longer and stronger.  And we’d also work hard to engage the other issues where Iran is a very dangerous and problematic actor for us and for Israel – destabilizing activities in the region, proliferation of weapons, support for terrorist groups, et cetera.  All of those things &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So when you say “longer” does that mean the sunset clause is extended, for example?  It won’t end in 2031?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yeah, I think this is important.  Of course, with the passage of time the different timelines have gotten shorter.  Having said that, the two most important timelines – the level at which Iran can enrich, 3.67 percent, the limits on the stockpile of enriched uranium to 300 kilograms – those don’t expire until 2030.  So if Iran were to come back into compliance, we would also have some time to seek to extend those deadlines and others.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Sir, I think you spoke in your acceptance speech – you spoke about your stepfather Samuel being a Holocaust survivor.  I think that resonated with many Israelis.  And I wanted to ask you:  When we see this rise in anti-Semitic incidents in the U.S., could you tell us what that makes you feel not only on the national level as the Secretary of State, but on a personal level?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>It&#8217;s profoundly, profoundly disturbing.  And we have seen, not just in the last week although we&#8217;ve seen – well, actually, we have seen a very disturbing eruption of anti-Semitic incidents.  But the truth of the matter is anti-Semitism’s been on the rise in the United States and around the world for the last several years.  And we know this from history.  It’s the canary in the coal mine because it’s almost inevitable that when you see anti-Semitism erupt and emerge, hatred directed at other groups almost is sure to follow.  And we’re seeing that in the United States now with hatred directed, for example, at Asian Americans.</p>
<p>And so when I see that I feel it both on a very personal level, but I also see it as a warning sign, a signal that there are – things are happening that we have to address.  Because if it’s allowed to fester, if it’s allowed to grow, if it’s allowed to go even further with impunity, you wind up having a conflagration that affects a lot of people.  So we&#8217;re taking this very, very seriously.  I think you heard President Biden’s speech just yesterday – the most recent incidents we’ve seen in the United States, he called them despicable.  And we’re determined to deal with that and put it to an end.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>The Israeli-Palestinian conflict obviously has been stoking anti-Semitic violence in Europe for years.  When we see, for example, known figures on the far left in the United States referring to Israel as an apartheid state, are you worried that this rhetoric could lead to more anti-Semitic incidents, instead of calming things down?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>One of the – one of the great things about my job right now as Secretary of State is I don&#8217;t do politics, I just focus on policy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>So I’m not going to ask you anything about Israeli politics either.  Don’t worry about it.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>No, no – no Israeli politics, no American politics.  But look, I think we all have to be attentive.  And whether – when we see anti-Semitism emerge anywhere, whether it’s in the United States, whether it’s in this part of the world, whether it’s anywhere in the world, we have to take it seriously, we have to address it, we have to deal with it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Mr. Secretary, my final question:  President Biden, of course, has been here many times.  His famous story about as a young senator meeting Golda Meir, he’s been here as a senator and as a vice president.  Can you let us in on when his first visit as President will be to Israel?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>I don’t have the time, I don’t have the date, but I can tell you I know that he very much looks forward to coming back.  And you’re right, he’s been engaged here for – ever since Golda Meir.  And as he’s often said, he’s worked with every Israeli prime minister since Golda Meir.  This is something that he feels deeply: the relationship with Israel, the commitment to Israel’s security.  That’s something that’s very deeply rooted in him.  And of course, as a true friend of Israel’s, he’s also fully prepared to say when he might disagree with something.</p>
<p>But that’s exactly the nature of our relationship, of our alliance, of our partnership.  We speak very directly, very frankly to each other, and ultimately we try to reason through problems together, right?  That was the nature of the conversations that I had today with the prime minister, with the foreign minister, with the defense minister, and so many others.  And I suspect that when the President does come here, he’ll pursue a long, longstanding conversation that he’s had going back a few years.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Well, you still have a long schedule in front of you, so thank you so much, Mr. Secretary, for talking to us today.  We really appreciate it.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Great to be with you.  Thanks for having me.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Jerusalem</p>
<p>David Citadel Hotel</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Secretary of State Antony Blinken, welcome.  Thank you very much for talking to us today.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Hi.  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  This isn’t – you’re of course not a stranger to the region.  This is far from being your first time here, but it’s the first time as Secretary of State.  And I wanted to begin by asking you about the ceasefire.  I mean, you seem to be in this cycle of every couple of years having a short but devastating war between Israel and Hamas, and of course, the U.S. played a constructive role in bringing about a ceasefire.</p>
<p>(Interruption.)</p>
<p>I’m going to ask just part of that again.  The U.S. played a constructive role in bringing about a ceasefire, but many Israelis believe that this is just a countdown to the next conflict.  What can be done?  What is the way out?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I think we do have to try to break the cycle of violence, because if we don’t it will repeat itself.  And maybe it’s next month, maybe it’s next year, maybe it’s in five years, but I don’t think that’s in anyone’s interests.  It’s not in the interests of Israelis.  It’s not in the interests of Palestinians.  It’s not in the interests of the broader region.</p>
<p>So I think we have to all try to work on a few things.  First, of course, we need to deal with the urgent situation in Gaza itself – humanitarian assistance, water, electricity, sanitation – to respond to the immediate needs.  We need to work together to try and rebuild and create some prospects for a better life for people who live in Gaza.  But then I think it’s really incumbent on both sides to try to do something to take away some of the things that can spark the cycle of violence.  And ultimately, what that really comes down to is, at least in our judgment, doing everything possible to make sure that Israelis and Palestinians alike have in their lives equal measures of security, of opportunity, of dignity.  And that manifests itself in many different ways, but I think at heart, that’s what needs to happen.  And so we spent some time today talking to our allies here in Israel about how that might go forward and did the same with the Palestinians.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Regarding the U.S.’s military assistance to Israel, during this operation in Gaza we heard mounting opposition from progressive lawmakers to the arms deal with Israel and trying to block it.  Is there any chance that the administration will reconsider the deal to supply Israel with precision-guided weapons?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  President Biden has been absolutely clear, and he’s been clear on more than one occasion:  We are committed to Israel’s security, period.  We will make sure that Israel has the means to defend itself.  And particularly when we have something like what the Israelis experienced in the last couple of weeks, attacks from a terrorist group indiscriminately targeting civilians, we want to make sure that Israel has the means to deal with that.</p>
<p>At the same time, as a democracy, I think Israel has an extra burden, and we owe the same thing to make sure that when it is defending itself, defending its citizens, it is doing everything it possibly can to avoid civilian casualties, to minimize the harm that is done to those who can get caught in the crossfire.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Do you believe that Israel did in this case?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I think Israel took very significant steps to do that, but we also know that on both sides men, women, and especially children were lost, and I think that’s deeply painful, and it’s a reminder that we throw around numbers, statistics, but these statistics, these numbers can’t hide the fact that we’re talking about real human beings.  And that’s important because I think it just reminds us about the need to make sure that we’re doing everything we can to avoid a repetition.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Taking the opportunity to talk about the bigger picture, the relationship between Israel and Palestinians, will there be an attempt to reignite the Israel-Palestinian peace process?  You spoke in your confirmation hearings saying that a Palestinian state is realistically – it’s hard to see near-term prospects for moving forward.  Do you still think that?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, two things.  I think a lot of work needs to be redone to try to rebuild some confidence, to try to rebuild some trust, to try to build some conditions and an environment in which it might be possible to re-engage in a meaningful way on two states.  But equally important, we continue to believe very strongly that a two-state solution is not just the best way, but probably the only way to really assure that going forward, Israel has a future as a secure Jewish and democratic state, and the Palestinians have a state to which they’re entitled.</p>
<p>So I think we want to get to that.  But right now, the focus is on dealing with the aftermath, the recent violence, trying to build on the ceasefire, address the immediate needs and concerns, and then see if over time the conditions are such that there’s a better environment for trying to pursue a two-state solution.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I want to move on to Iran.  Iranian President Hassan Rouhani said last Thursday that his country’s close to reaching a deal.  He said we have taken a big step and an agreement in principle has been achieved.  Is that true?  How close is the deal?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, I think that would be news to us, because we’re now, I think, in the fifth rounds of talks in Vienna.  These are – as I think you know – indirect talks.  We haven’t been talking directly to the Iranians.  It’s been through the European Union and our other partners.  I think we’ve clarified increasingly what each side would need to do to come back into compliance with the JCPOA, but it remains an unanswered question whether Iran is actually prepared to do what it needs to do to come back into compliance.  The jury is still out on that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Israeli prime minister has been quite clear in his opposition to the Iran deal.  Today during your joint statement, he said, “I hope the U.S.  not  to the old JCPOA.”  So let me ask you, Mr. Secretary, are the plans indeed to return to the same terms as the JCPOA or additional safeguards, for example to ensure that Iran – Iran’s compliance?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  The United States and Israel are absolutely united in the proposition that Iran can never acquire a nuclear weapon.  We are joined in that goal and in that commitment.  It’s also no secret that over time we’ve had differences over the best way to get there, to make sure that Iran does not get a weapon.  From our perspective, the JCPOA did exactly what it set out to accomplish, which was to cut off all of the pathways that Iran had to producing fissile material for a nuclear weapon on short order.  And our experts verified that it was working, international experts verified that it was working, and it had the most intrusive inspections regime of any arms control agreement ever achieved.  And the result was that when the agreement was in force, Iran, had it decided to try to produce fissile material for a nuclear weapon, would have required at least a year to do so, which would have been plenty of time to see it and, if necessary, to do something about it.</p>
<p>But here’s what happened since.  Now that we’re out of the deal, Iran has started to ignore the constrains that the deal imposed.  And it is closer and closer and closer to being able to produce fissile material for a nuclear weapon on very short order.  And so far from getting less dangerous without the deal, it’s gotten more dangerous.  And I think there’s a certain amount of urgency to try to put Iran back into the nuclear box that the deal constructed.</p>
<p>So having said that, if – what we’ve said along is if we succeed in doing that, if Iran returns to compliance with the deal, we would do the same.  We would also seek to make it, as we say, longer and stronger.  And we’d also work hard to engage the other issues where Iran is a very dangerous and problematic actor for us and for Israel – destabilizing activities in the region, proliferation of weapons, support for terrorist groups, et cetera.  All of those things &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So when you say “longer” does that mean the sunset clause is extended, for example?  It won’t end in 2031?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yeah, I think this is important.  Of course, with the passage of time the different timelines have gotten shorter.  Having said that, the two most important timelines – the level at which Iran can enrich, 3.67 percent, the limits on the stockpile of enriched uranium to 300 kilograms – those don’t expire until 2030.  So if Iran were to come back into compliance, we would also have some time to seek to extend those deadlines and others.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Sir, I think you spoke in your acceptance speech – you spoke about your stepfather Samuel being a Holocaust survivor.  I think that resonated with many Israelis.  And I wanted to ask you:  When we see this rise in anti-Semitic incidents in the U.S., could you tell us what that makes you feel not only on the national level as the Secretary of State, but on a personal level?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>It&#8217;s profoundly, profoundly disturbing.  And we have seen, not just in the last week although we&#8217;ve seen – well, actually, we have seen a very disturbing eruption of anti-Semitic incidents.  But the truth of the matter is anti-Semitism’s been on the rise in the United States and around the world for the last several years.  And we know this from history.  It’s the canary in the coal mine because it’s almost inevitable that when you see anti-Semitism erupt and emerge, hatred directed at other groups almost is sure to follow.  And we’re seeing that in the United States now with hatred directed, for example, at Asian Americans.</p>
<p>And so when I see that I feel it both on a very personal level, but I also see it as a warning sign, a signal that there are – things are happening that we have to address.  Because if it’s allowed to fester, if it’s allowed to grow, if it’s allowed to go even further with impunity, you wind up having a conflagration that affects a lot of people.  So we&#8217;re taking this very, very seriously.  I think you heard President Biden’s speech just yesterday – the most recent incidents we’ve seen in the United States, he called them despicable.  And we’re determined to deal with that and put it to an end.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>The Israeli-Palestinian conflict obviously has been stoking anti-Semitic violence in Europe for years.  When we see, for example, known figures on the far left in the United States referring to Israel as an apartheid state, are you worried that this rhetoric could lead to more anti-Semitic incidents, instead of calming things down?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>One of the – one of the great things about my job right now as Secretary of State is I don&#8217;t do politics, I just focus on policy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>So I’m not going to ask you anything about Israeli politics either.  Don’t worry about it.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>No, no – no Israeli politics, no American politics.  But look, I think we all have to be attentive.  And whether – when we see anti-Semitism emerge anywhere, whether it’s in the United States, whether it’s in this part of the world, whether it’s anywhere in the world, we have to take it seriously, we have to address it, we have to deal with it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Mr. Secretary, my final question:  President Biden, of course, has been here many times.  His famous story about as a young senator meeting Golda Meir, he’s been here as a senator and as a vice president.  Can you let us in on when his first visit as President will be to Israel?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>I don’t have the time, I don’t have the date, but I can tell you I know that he very much looks forward to coming back.  And you’re right, he’s been engaged here for – ever since Golda Meir.  And as he’s often said, he’s worked with every Israeli prime minister since Golda Meir.  This is something that he feels deeply: the relationship with Israel, the commitment to Israel’s security.  That’s something that’s very deeply rooted in him.  And of course, as a true friend of Israel’s, he’s also fully prepared to say when he might disagree with something.</p>
<p>But that’s exactly the nature of our relationship, of our alliance, of our partnership.  We speak very directly, very frankly to each other, and ultimately we try to reason through problems together, right?  That was the nature of the conversations that I had today with the prime minister, with the foreign minister, with the defense minister, and so many others.  And I suspect that when the President does come here, he’ll pursue a long, longstanding conversation that he’s had going back a few years.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Well, you still have a long schedule in front of you, so thank you so much, Mr. Secretary, for talking to us today.  We really appreciate it.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Great to be with you.  Thanks for having me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-EU:  Joint Press Release by the EEAS and Department of State on Consultations Between Deputy Secretary Wendy Sherman and Secretary General Stefano Sannino</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-eu-joint-press-release-by-the-eeas-and-department-of-state-on-consultations-between-deputy-secretary-wendy-sherman-and-secretary-general-stefano-sannino/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 14:46:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246505</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is the text of a joint press release by the U.S. Department of State and the European External Action Service.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>On May 26, Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman and European External Action Service Secretary General Stefano Sannino met in Brussels to reaffirm the strength of the U.S.-EU partnership on key foreign policy and security issues.  They welcomed the upcoming EU-U.S. Summit taking place on 15 June as an important step in the revitalized transatlantic partnership. The two sides underscored the shared U.S.-EU interest in strengthening the rules-based international order and pledged further close cooperation in support of democratic values, global and regional stability, and universal human rights.  They discussed a range of foreign policy issues of mutual concern, such as Russia, Ukraine, and Belarus, and the recent violence in Israel and the West Bank and Gaza. They exchanged views on the Eastern Mediterranean, Western Balkans, Afghanistan, Syria, Myanmar, the Indo-Pacific, Ethiopia, and Venezuela. They also underscored a shared interest in improving connectivity by supporting partners in setting up regulatory environments that are conducive to sustainable connectivity, as well as through quality infrastructure development and projects consistent with the highest transparency, digital, and green standards as part of their respective approaches to the Indo-Pacific region. They agreed to continue close consultations in view of possible joint approaches and actions by the EU and the U.S. that can bring about positive change.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Secretary General Sannino held the first high-level meeting of the U.S.-EU dialogue on China.  The two sides reiterated that the United States’ and EU’s relations with China are multifaceted and comprise elements of cooperation, competition, and systemic rivalry.  They highlighted issues of shared concern, including ongoing human rights violations in Xinjiang and Tibet, the erosion of autonomy and democratic processes in Hong Kong, economic coercion, disinformation campaigns, and regional security issues, in particular the situation in the South China Sea.  They discussed the importance of Taiwan’s meaningful participation in the work of international organizations, including World Health Organization forums and the World Health Assembly.  They also discussed pursuing constructive engagement with China on issues such as climate change and non-proliferation, and on certain regional issues.</p>
<p>The two sides decided to continue meetings in this dialogue at senior official and expert levels to discuss reciprocity, including economic issues; resilience; human rights; security; multilateralism; and engagement.  The next high-level meeting will take place in winter 2021/2022.</p>
<p><em>End Text.</em></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is the text of a joint press release by the U.S. Department of State and the European External Action Service.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>On May 26, Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman and European External Action Service Secretary General Stefano Sannino met in Brussels to reaffirm the strength of the U.S.-EU partnership on key foreign policy and security issues.  They welcomed the upcoming EU-U.S. Summit taking place on 15 June as an important step in the revitalized transatlantic partnership. The two sides underscored the shared U.S.-EU interest in strengthening the rules-based international order and pledged further close cooperation in support of democratic values, global and regional stability, and universal human rights.  They discussed a range of foreign policy issues of mutual concern, such as Russia, Ukraine, and Belarus, and the recent violence in Israel and the West Bank and Gaza. They exchanged views on the Eastern Mediterranean, Western Balkans, Afghanistan, Syria, Myanmar, the Indo-Pacific, Ethiopia, and Venezuela. They also underscored a shared interest in improving connectivity by supporting partners in setting up regulatory environments that are conducive to sustainable connectivity, as well as through quality infrastructure development and projects consistent with the highest transparency, digital, and green standards as part of their respective approaches to the Indo-Pacific region. They agreed to continue close consultations in view of possible joint approaches and actions by the EU and the U.S. that can bring about positive change.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Secretary General Sannino held the first high-level meeting of the U.S.-EU dialogue on China.  The two sides reiterated that the United States’ and EU’s relations with China are multifaceted and comprise elements of cooperation, competition, and systemic rivalry.  They highlighted issues of shared concern, including ongoing human rights violations in Xinjiang and Tibet, the erosion of autonomy and democratic processes in Hong Kong, economic coercion, disinformation campaigns, and regional security issues, in particular the situation in the South China Sea.  They discussed the importance of Taiwan’s meaningful participation in the work of international organizations, including World Health Organization forums and the World Health Assembly.  They also discussed pursuing constructive engagement with China on issues such as climate change and non-proliferation, and on certain regional issues.</p>
<p>The two sides decided to continue meetings in this dialogue at senior official and expert levels to discuss reciprocity, including economic issues; resilience; human rights; security; multilateralism; and engagement.  The next high-level meeting will take place in winter 2021/2022.</p>
<p><em>End Text.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guyana National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/guyana-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 14:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246474</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States, I congratulate the people of Guyana on your 55<sup>th</sup> anniversary of independence.</p>
<p>The partnership between the United States and Guyana is rooted in our shared principles.  We value our continued collaboration to strengthen Guyana&#8217;s democratic institutions and processes.  Guyana&#8217;s hosting of the annual Tradewinds joint exercises next month is a testament to our strong security partnership.  Our joint efforts to combat narcotics and illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing will continue to contribute to regional stability and cooperation.  We value our shared commitment to addressing climate change, and hope that we can work together to increase investments in renewable energy.</p>
<p>As you celebrate this joyous occasion with family and friends, we join you in recognizing this Independence Day celebration.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States, I congratulate the people of Guyana on your 55<sup>th</sup> anniversary of independence.</p>
<p>The partnership between the United States and Guyana is rooted in our shared principles.  We value our continued collaboration to strengthen Guyana&#8217;s democratic institutions and processes.  Guyana&#8217;s hosting of the annual Tradewinds joint exercises next month is a testament to our strong security partnership.  Our joint efforts to combat narcotics and illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing will continue to contribute to regional stability and cooperation.  We value our shared commitment to addressing climate change, and hope that we can work together to increase investments in renewable energy.</p>
<p>As you celebrate this joyous occasion with family and friends, we join you in recognizing this Independence Day celebration.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Assistance for the Palestinian People</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-assistance-for-the-palestinian-people/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 12:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>As I announced yesterday, the United States is in the process of providing more than $360 million in assistance to the Palestinian people. This includes $38 million in new assistance to support humanitarian efforts in the West Bank and Gaza.  This new assistance includes nearly $33 million for the UN Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA) in support of its West Bank and Gaza operations, and an additional $5.5 million to humanitarian partners.  This critical assistance will support humanitarian organizations to provide emergency shelter, food, relief items, and health care, as well as mental health and psychosocial support for those who experienced trauma.</p>
<p>Additionally, working with Congress, the State Department and USAID intend to provide $75 million in additional development and economic assistance over the next year that will support relief and recovery in the West Bank and Gaza. This funding will advance private sector growth and access to basic needs and services, such as providing health care and addressing food insecurity. Pending completion of congressional notification, another $10 million will support programs that support reconciliation work to reduce tension and violence over the long term.</p>
<p>This assistance is in addition to the more than $250 million in economic, development, security, and humanitarian assistance for the Palestinian people announced in March and April, bringing planned U.S. assistance to more than $360 million.  All of these funds will be administered in a way that benefit the Palestinian people &#8212; not Hamas, which has only brought misery and despair to Gaza. The U.S. government is also firmly committed to ensuring all its assistance is provided consistent with applicable U.S. law, including the Taylor Force Act.</p>
<p>U.S. foreign assistance for the Palestinian people serves important U.S. interests and values. It provides critical relief to those in great need, fosters economic development, and supports Israeli-Palestinian understanding, security coordination, and stability.  It also aligns with the values and interests of our allies and partners.</p>
<p>The United States will continue to encourage other donors to support humanitarian and recovery efforts in the West Bank and Gaza, and programs and activities that work toward a common goal of stability and progress for Israelis and Palestinians alike.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>As I announced yesterday, the United States is in the process of providing more than $360 million in assistance to the Palestinian people. This includes $38 million in new assistance to support humanitarian efforts in the West Bank and Gaza.  This new assistance includes nearly $33 million for the UN Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA) in support of its West Bank and Gaza operations, and an additional $5.5 million to humanitarian partners.  This critical assistance will support humanitarian organizations to provide emergency shelter, food, relief items, and health care, as well as mental health and psychosocial support for those who experienced trauma.</p>
<p>Additionally, working with Congress, the State Department and USAID intend to provide $75 million in additional development and economic assistance over the next year that will support relief and recovery in the West Bank and Gaza. This funding will advance private sector growth and access to basic needs and services, such as providing health care and addressing food insecurity. Pending completion of congressional notification, another $10 million will support programs that support reconciliation work to reduce tension and violence over the long term.</p>
<p>This assistance is in addition to the more than $250 million in economic, development, security, and humanitarian assistance for the Palestinian people announced in March and April, bringing planned U.S. assistance to more than $360 million.  All of these funds will be administered in a way that benefit the Palestinian people &#8212; not Hamas, which has only brought misery and despair to Gaza. The U.S. government is also firmly committed to ensuring all its assistance is provided consistent with applicable U.S. law, including the Taylor Force Act.</p>
<p>U.S. foreign assistance for the Palestinian people serves important U.S. interests and values. It provides critical relief to those in great need, fosters economic development, and supports Israeli-Palestinian understanding, security coordination, and stability.  It also aligns with the values and interests of our allies and partners.</p>
<p>The United States will continue to encourage other donors to support humanitarian and recovery efforts in the West Bank and Gaza, and programs and activities that work toward a common goal of stability and progress for Israelis and Palestinians alike.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Georgia’s National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/georgias-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 04:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246165</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Georgia as you celebrate your Independence Day.</p>
<p>The United States and Georgia enjoy a strategic partnership that is based on shared values.  In the year ahead, we look forward to supporting Georgia as it works to strengthen democratic processes, create a more independent judiciary, and foster a fully engaged parliament. We will continue to support the Georgian people’s Euro-Atlantic aspirations, as well as their efforts to advance democratic and economic development as they rebound from the COVID-19 pandemic.  In the spirit of our ongoing cooperation, we wish you a Happy Independence Day!</p>
<p>We are proud to support Georgia’s efforts to strengthen its defense capabilities, and we appreciate its contributions to NATO’s mission in Afghanistan.  We honor the Georgians who have sacrificed in pursuit of global peace and security.  The United States firmly supports Georgia’s sovereignty and territorial integrity within its internationally recognized borders and condemns Russia’s occupation of Georgia’s Abkhazia and South Ossetia regions.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Georgia as you celebrate your Independence Day.</p>
<p>The United States and Georgia enjoy a strategic partnership that is based on shared values.  In the year ahead, we look forward to supporting Georgia as it works to strengthen democratic processes, create a more independent judiciary, and foster a fully engaged parliament. We will continue to support the Georgian people’s Euro-Atlantic aspirations, as well as their efforts to advance democratic and economic development as they rebound from the COVID-19 pandemic.  In the spirit of our ongoing cooperation, we wish you a Happy Independence Day!</p>
<p>We are proud to support Georgia’s efforts to strengthen its defense capabilities, and we appreciate its contributions to NATO’s mission in Afghanistan.  We honor the Georgians who have sacrificed in pursuit of global peace and security.  The United States firmly supports Georgia’s sovereignty and territorial integrity within its internationally recognized borders and condemns Russia’s occupation of Georgia’s Abkhazia and South Ossetia regions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken  at a Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-press-availability-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 20:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246281</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Jerusalem</p>
<p>David Citadel Hotel</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good evening, everyone.  Ah, must be a slow night.  (Laughter.)  Good to see you all.</p>
<p>We had, as those of you who’ve been along with us all day know, a fairly busy and certainly very productive day in Jerusalem and Ramallah since arriving this morning.  I traveled here at the request of President Biden, who asked me to come to pursue four basic objectives.  First, to demonstrate the commitment of the United States to Israel’s security.  Second, to start to work toward greater stability and reduce tensions in the West Bank and Jerusalem.  Third, to support urgent humanitarian and reconstruction assistance for Gaza to benefit the Palestinian people.  And fourth, to continue to rebuild our relationship with the Palestinian people and the Palestinian Authority.</p>
<p>Those objectives shaped all of the meetings that I held today with elected leaders on both sides, including Prime Minister Netanyahu, Foreign Minister Ashkenazi, Defense Minister Gantz here in Jerusalem, and President Abbas and Prime Minister Shtayyeh in the West Bank.  They’ll drive my discussions this evening with Knesset opposition leader Lapid and tomorrow morning with President Rivlin.</p>
<p>Across the meetings that I’ve had so far, I’ve heard a shared recognition from all sides that steps need to be taken, work needs to be done, to address the underlying conditions that helped fuel this latest conflict.  The ceasefire creates space to begin to take those steps.  Attending to the urgent humanitarian needs of Palestinians in Gaza and helping rebuild is a key starting point.  The United States is committed to rallying international support to that effort and doing our part.  That’s why we announced additional assistance for the Palestinian people today.</p>
<p>But we all know that is not enough.  As President Biden has said, we believe that Palestinians and Israelis equally deserve to live safely and securely; to enjoy equal measures of freedom, opportunity, and democracy; to be treated with dignity.  Earlier today, I had a chance to meet with two of the State Department’s locally employed staff: an Israeli whose family lives near the Gaza separation wall and a Palestinian who lives in Gaza.  Both of them recounted how the violence in recent weeks repeatedly forced them and their families to take cover.  Both feared they would be killed.  For too many innocent Israelis and Palestinians, lives lost in the conflict and loved ones suffering immeasurably as a result.</p>
<p>But the stories of those staff members remind us that the survivors on both sides also walk away scarred, none as much as children.  That’s another reason we have to break the cycle of violence.  Leaders on both sides will need to chart a better course, starting by making real improvements in the lives of people in Israel, Gaza, and the West Bank.  I’m convinced that if they do, they will find willing partners in both Israeli and Palestinian civil society.  That’s one of the messages I took away from a meeting earlier today with Palestinian civil society leaders.</p>
<p>Tomorrow, I’ve got a chance to travel to Egypt and also to Jordan.  As you know, Egypt played a critical role in helping to broker the ceasefire, and Jordan has long been a voice for peace and stability in the region.  We’re grateful for their continued engagement, and I look forward to the meetings there tomorrow.</p>
<p>But with that, I’m happy to take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll start with Lara Jakes, <em>New York Times.</em></p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Good evening, Secretary Blinken.  Hello.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Where are you, Lara?  Oh, there you are.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I think some of my colleagues will ask you some of the nitty-gritty questions of the day.  I wanted to kind of take a step back, if I could.  Reasserting America’s role in the world has been one of the themes of your foreign policy.  Can you describe how that took shape over the last three weeks in this part of the Middle East, where the United States had a very active role in promoting Israeli interests during the Trump administration but had shut down relations with Palestinian officials?  And so what struck you in what you heard today from both sides?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, a few things.  First, I think that the violence that we’ve seen in recent weeks is a reminder of the need to try to make genuine progress toward peacefully resolving the conflict that continues to divide Israelis and Palestinians.</p>
<p>In terms of U.S. reengagement, U.S. leadership, I think what you saw was President Biden leading, very determined, very intensive, but also behind-the-scenes diplomacy to do the first thing that needed to be done, which was to end the violence, to get the ceasefire.  And with a lot of hard work, with the efforts of others, including the Egyptians, we were able to do that.  But that was just the starting point for something that I just described.</p>
<p>It’s now I think incumbent on us to work with our partners here and work with others, as I said, to address the urgent needs in Gaza itself and the people in Gaza, to then try to build something more positive on that, and also to address some of the underlying causes that could, if not addressed, spark another cycle of violence.</p>
<p>So I think we found in working on this intensely, quietly but resolutely, that America’s words matter, America’s actions matter, and America’s engagement matters.  I’m glad that we were able to make – help make a difference in getting to the ceasefire.  And I hope and expect that we can continue to make a difference in moving beyond it in trying to build something more positive.  So that’s what I take away from at least the last couple of weeks.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to Gili Cohen from KAN.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, thank you for that.  Prime Minister Netanyahu has been pretty vocal in his objection to the JCPOA.  Did those remarks encourage or deter the U.S. from returning to the JCPOA?  And speaking of the Iran deal, is it a matter of weeks before the U.S. will return to the agreement?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Let’s start with this.  The fact is the United States and Israel are absolutely united in the proposition that Iran must never be allowed to acquire a nuclear weapon.  We share exactly the same goal.  It’s no secret that we sometimes have our differences with regard to the best way to achieve that goal, and that’s what allies and partners do.  We work together, try to find the best way to achieve a common objective.  What we have done very, very resolutely, as we’ve tried to see whether a return to mutual compliance with the JCPOA is possible, is that we have regularly before, during, and after all of our engagements – indirect engagements with the Iranians in Vienna – kept our partners here in Israel informed, as well as others who are concerned.  And that’s not going to stop.</p>
<p>Let me add this:  The JCPOA I think accomplished something very important, and that is it cut off all of Iran’s pathways to produce fissile material for a nuclear weapon on short order.  And it pushed the so-called breakout time, the amount of time it would take Iran to develop that material for a nuclear weapon, to beyond a year.  It was the most heavily monitored and verified agreement in the history of arms control.  Our experts said that Iran was abiding by its commitments under the agreement.  So did international experts.  And as a result, the challenge that both the United States and Israel were focused on, the prospect of Iran getting to the point where it could have a – fissile material for a nuclear weapon or produce it on very short order, we took that off of the – off the field.  And I think that was an important development.</p>
<p>What have we seen since we pulled out of the agreement?  Well, Iran has stopped abiding by some of the critical constraints in the agreement, and as a result, it is far closer today to the ability to produce fissile material for a nuclear weapon on short order than it was even before the deal was reached, and certainly during the pendency of the deal itself.  And so I think that only underscores the importance and, indeed, urgency in seeing if we can get Iran back into compliance with the agreement, to put Iran back in the nuclear box that the deal constructed.  The alternative is an Iran that is getting closer and closer – if it continues to do what it’s doing, in spinning more and more sophisticated centrifuges and building up stockpiles of enriched uranium – getting closer and closer to having a very, very short breakout time, which is in – not in our interest, not in Israel’s interest, not in anyone’s interest.</p>
<p>So that’s why we’re working to see if we can get back into mutual compliance.  We’ve said all along that that would be a first step, that we also would seek to try to make the agreement longer and stronger, and also to deal with other issues and other challenges posed by Iran, to include its support for terrorism, its support for destabilizing proxy groups in countries throughout the region, its proliferation.  All of these things we’re determined to engage, but the first thing we’re trying to achieve is to, as I said, put the nuclear problem back into the box that we constructed and that was strong, solid, and doing what we needed to do.</p>
<p>Now, we’re engaged or about to engage in I think the fifth round of discussions in Vienna, and we still don’t know the answer to the most important question, which is whether Iran is actually willing and able to make the decisions it needs to make to come back into full compliance.  The jury is still out, and we will see whether or not Iran makes that decision.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks.  Mr. Secretary, a few of those nitty-gritty questions for you:  Did President Abbas say anything to you about reopening a Palestinian Authority representative office in the U.S.?  Can you give us a timeframe on when you would reopen the consulate and bring Michael Ratney here?</p>
<p>And then if I could just press you a little bit on the Iran issue, understanding everything you’ve laid out to us, did you offer any assurances to Prime Minister Netanyahu?  His comments to us essentially showed that he disagreed with everything you just said.  He thinks that the deal essentially legitimizes Iran getting a nuclear weapon.  So was there anything you asked of him or offered him on the JCPOA to try to reassure him?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  So on the question of an office in Washington, that did not come up today.  With regard to our consulate, we’re just beginning the process.  I can’t give you a timeline on how long that will take.  But I can tell you that it’s, I think, important to have that platform to be able to more effectively engage not just the Palestinian Authority, but Palestinians from different walks of life, the NGO community, the business community, and others.  And so we look forward to doing that, but I can’t put a timeline on it.</p>
<p>And coming back to Iran, no, I think the most important thing when it comes to this is what we committed to do from day one of this administration.  We said all along that if there was an opportunity, we would seek to return to mutual compliance with the JCPOA, but we also said that from day one, we would be keeping our closest allies and closest partners fully and contemporaneously informed of what we were doing and where we were going.  And that’s what we’ve done and that’s what we’ll continue to do.  That is how you keep faith with your partners and allies on something that, of course, is of great consequence to Israel.  We understand that.</p>
<p>And again, we have the same objective, and let’s see where things go in the next few weeks.  But I can again tell you that we are fully, fully engaged with our partners here in at least making sure that they’re fully informed of what we’re doing.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll turn to Hikmet Yosef from PalSawa.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (In Arabic.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Good afternoon.</p>
<p>(In Arabic.)</p>
<p><strong>INTERPRETER:</strong>  Okay.  So his question was:  “The U.S. administration said that it’s going to do the reconstruction of Gaza through the United Nations.  Is this considered an implicit, direct, or indirect recognition of Hamas that is taking over – that is the taken-over authority in Gaza?  And – or is there a plan for Washington to deal with Hamas directly or indirectly?”</p>
<p>And he’s asking also:  “Is the negotiation – will be resumed between the PA and Israel after the ceasefire?”  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much for your question.  Look, if we do this right, reconstruction and then – and relief for the people of Gaza, far from empowering Hamas, I think has the potential to undermine it.  I say that because Hamas thrives, unfortunately, on despair, on misery, on desperation, on a lack of opportunity.  In fact, it’s a movement that has thrived on a vacuum of opportunity.  And what reconstruction and relief need to do is not just answer the immediate needs – and those needs are significant and they’re urgent, whether it’s water, whether it’s sanitation, whether it’s electricity – but they need to offer a genuine prospect for opportunity, for progress, for material improvement in people’s lives.  And our goal is to give the Palestinian people, including those in Gaza, a renewed sense of confidence, of optimism, of real opportunity.</p>
<p>And if we succeed – and by the way, it’s not just us, it’s not just the UN.  It’s the Palestinian Authority that needs to be fully engaged, Israel needs to fully engage, other partners need to fully engage.  But in my judgment, at least, if we’re able to do that all together, then Hamas’s foothold in Gaza will slip, and we know that and I think that Hamas knows that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll take one final question from Andrea Mitchell.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  Did you get any commitments from Prime Minister Netanyahu to not evict Palestinians from East Jerusalem neighborhoods and to work with the Palestinian Authority and other Palestinians in order to avoid any spark that could break the ceasefire?  And did you get any assurances from the Palestinian Authority today that they could have any influence over Gaza?  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, Andrea.  So first, as – let me take a step back for a minute, because we’re focused right now on responding to, as I said, the urgent needs that exist in Gaza on a humanitarian basis, the urgent needs for rebuilding and reconstruction, and then looking to see actions on the part of both Israelis and Palestinians that will take down tension, and try to remove or minimize some of the potential catalysts for a renewed cycle of violence, and, building on that, try to – in very practical and material ways, start to improve people’s lives and add a real sense of dignity and hope.</p>
<p>If that happens – and that will take some time – that may, I think, produce a better environment in which ultimately there’s a possibility of resuming the effort to achieve a two-state solution, which we continue to believe is the only way to truly assure Israel’s future as a Jewish and democratic state, and of course, to give the Palestinians the state that they’re entitled to.</p>
<p>I say all that because any steps that either side takes that either risk sparking violence or – over time – and ultimately undermine the prospect for returning to the pursuit of two states, we oppose.  And that includes settlement activity, it includes demolitions, it includes evictions, it includes incitement to violence, it includes payment to terrorists.  All of those things would, I think, on the one hand potentially be catalysts for renewed tension and potentially violence, and certainly undermine the prospects of achieving two states.  And that’s something that we’ve been very clear about in our conversations with Israelis and Palestinians alike.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But did you get any commitment today?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I’ll let the – I’ll let our partners speak for themselves.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you very much, everybody.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Jerusalem</p>
<p>David Citadel Hotel</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good evening, everyone.  Ah, must be a slow night.  (Laughter.)  Good to see you all.</p>
<p>We had, as those of you who’ve been along with us all day know, a fairly busy and certainly very productive day in Jerusalem and Ramallah since arriving this morning.  I traveled here at the request of President Biden, who asked me to come to pursue four basic objectives.  First, to demonstrate the commitment of the United States to Israel’s security.  Second, to start to work toward greater stability and reduce tensions in the West Bank and Jerusalem.  Third, to support urgent humanitarian and reconstruction assistance for Gaza to benefit the Palestinian people.  And fourth, to continue to rebuild our relationship with the Palestinian people and the Palestinian Authority.</p>
<p>Those objectives shaped all of the meetings that I held today with elected leaders on both sides, including Prime Minister Netanyahu, Foreign Minister Ashkenazi, Defense Minister Gantz here in Jerusalem, and President Abbas and Prime Minister Shtayyeh in the West Bank.  They’ll drive my discussions this evening with Knesset opposition leader Lapid and tomorrow morning with President Rivlin.</p>
<p>Across the meetings that I’ve had so far, I’ve heard a shared recognition from all sides that steps need to be taken, work needs to be done, to address the underlying conditions that helped fuel this latest conflict.  The ceasefire creates space to begin to take those steps.  Attending to the urgent humanitarian needs of Palestinians in Gaza and helping rebuild is a key starting point.  The United States is committed to rallying international support to that effort and doing our part.  That’s why we announced additional assistance for the Palestinian people today.</p>
<p>But we all know that is not enough.  As President Biden has said, we believe that Palestinians and Israelis equally deserve to live safely and securely; to enjoy equal measures of freedom, opportunity, and democracy; to be treated with dignity.  Earlier today, I had a chance to meet with two of the State Department’s locally employed staff: an Israeli whose family lives near the Gaza separation wall and a Palestinian who lives in Gaza.  Both of them recounted how the violence in recent weeks repeatedly forced them and their families to take cover.  Both feared they would be killed.  For too many innocent Israelis and Palestinians, lives lost in the conflict and loved ones suffering immeasurably as a result.</p>
<p>But the stories of those staff members remind us that the survivors on both sides also walk away scarred, none as much as children.  That’s another reason we have to break the cycle of violence.  Leaders on both sides will need to chart a better course, starting by making real improvements in the lives of people in Israel, Gaza, and the West Bank.  I’m convinced that if they do, they will find willing partners in both Israeli and Palestinian civil society.  That’s one of the messages I took away from a meeting earlier today with Palestinian civil society leaders.</p>
<p>Tomorrow, I’ve got a chance to travel to Egypt and also to Jordan.  As you know, Egypt played a critical role in helping to broker the ceasefire, and Jordan has long been a voice for peace and stability in the region.  We’re grateful for their continued engagement, and I look forward to the meetings there tomorrow.</p>
<p>But with that, I’m happy to take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll start with Lara Jakes, <em>New York Times.</em></p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Good evening, Secretary Blinken.  Hello.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Where are you, Lara?  Oh, there you are.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I think some of my colleagues will ask you some of the nitty-gritty questions of the day.  I wanted to kind of take a step back, if I could.  Reasserting America’s role in the world has been one of the themes of your foreign policy.  Can you describe how that took shape over the last three weeks in this part of the Middle East, where the United States had a very active role in promoting Israeli interests during the Trump administration but had shut down relations with Palestinian officials?  And so what struck you in what you heard today from both sides?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, a few things.  First, I think that the violence that we’ve seen in recent weeks is a reminder of the need to try to make genuine progress toward peacefully resolving the conflict that continues to divide Israelis and Palestinians.</p>
<p>In terms of U.S. reengagement, U.S. leadership, I think what you saw was President Biden leading, very determined, very intensive, but also behind-the-scenes diplomacy to do the first thing that needed to be done, which was to end the violence, to get the ceasefire.  And with a lot of hard work, with the efforts of others, including the Egyptians, we were able to do that.  But that was just the starting point for something that I just described.</p>
<p>It’s now I think incumbent on us to work with our partners here and work with others, as I said, to address the urgent needs in Gaza itself and the people in Gaza, to then try to build something more positive on that, and also to address some of the underlying causes that could, if not addressed, spark another cycle of violence.</p>
<p>So I think we found in working on this intensely, quietly but resolutely, that America’s words matter, America’s actions matter, and America’s engagement matters.  I’m glad that we were able to make – help make a difference in getting to the ceasefire.  And I hope and expect that we can continue to make a difference in moving beyond it in trying to build something more positive.  So that’s what I take away from at least the last couple of weeks.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to Gili Cohen from KAN.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, thank you for that.  Prime Minister Netanyahu has been pretty vocal in his objection to the JCPOA.  Did those remarks encourage or deter the U.S. from returning to the JCPOA?  And speaking of the Iran deal, is it a matter of weeks before the U.S. will return to the agreement?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Let’s start with this.  The fact is the United States and Israel are absolutely united in the proposition that Iran must never be allowed to acquire a nuclear weapon.  We share exactly the same goal.  It’s no secret that we sometimes have our differences with regard to the best way to achieve that goal, and that’s what allies and partners do.  We work together, try to find the best way to achieve a common objective.  What we have done very, very resolutely, as we’ve tried to see whether a return to mutual compliance with the JCPOA is possible, is that we have regularly before, during, and after all of our engagements – indirect engagements with the Iranians in Vienna – kept our partners here in Israel informed, as well as others who are concerned.  And that’s not going to stop.</p>
<p>Let me add this:  The JCPOA I think accomplished something very important, and that is it cut off all of Iran’s pathways to produce fissile material for a nuclear weapon on short order.  And it pushed the so-called breakout time, the amount of time it would take Iran to develop that material for a nuclear weapon, to beyond a year.  It was the most heavily monitored and verified agreement in the history of arms control.  Our experts said that Iran was abiding by its commitments under the agreement.  So did international experts.  And as a result, the challenge that both the United States and Israel were focused on, the prospect of Iran getting to the point where it could have a – fissile material for a nuclear weapon or produce it on very short order, we took that off of the – off the field.  And I think that was an important development.</p>
<p>What have we seen since we pulled out of the agreement?  Well, Iran has stopped abiding by some of the critical constraints in the agreement, and as a result, it is far closer today to the ability to produce fissile material for a nuclear weapon on short order than it was even before the deal was reached, and certainly during the pendency of the deal itself.  And so I think that only underscores the importance and, indeed, urgency in seeing if we can get Iran back into compliance with the agreement, to put Iran back in the nuclear box that the deal constructed.  The alternative is an Iran that is getting closer and closer – if it continues to do what it’s doing, in spinning more and more sophisticated centrifuges and building up stockpiles of enriched uranium – getting closer and closer to having a very, very short breakout time, which is in – not in our interest, not in Israel’s interest, not in anyone’s interest.</p>
<p>So that’s why we’re working to see if we can get back into mutual compliance.  We’ve said all along that that would be a first step, that we also would seek to try to make the agreement longer and stronger, and also to deal with other issues and other challenges posed by Iran, to include its support for terrorism, its support for destabilizing proxy groups in countries throughout the region, its proliferation.  All of these things we’re determined to engage, but the first thing we’re trying to achieve is to, as I said, put the nuclear problem back into the box that we constructed and that was strong, solid, and doing what we needed to do.</p>
<p>Now, we’re engaged or about to engage in I think the fifth round of discussions in Vienna, and we still don’t know the answer to the most important question, which is whether Iran is actually willing and able to make the decisions it needs to make to come back into full compliance.  The jury is still out, and we will see whether or not Iran makes that decision.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks.  Mr. Secretary, a few of those nitty-gritty questions for you:  Did President Abbas say anything to you about reopening a Palestinian Authority representative office in the U.S.?  Can you give us a timeframe on when you would reopen the consulate and bring Michael Ratney here?</p>
<p>And then if I could just press you a little bit on the Iran issue, understanding everything you’ve laid out to us, did you offer any assurances to Prime Minister Netanyahu?  His comments to us essentially showed that he disagreed with everything you just said.  He thinks that the deal essentially legitimizes Iran getting a nuclear weapon.  So was there anything you asked of him or offered him on the JCPOA to try to reassure him?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  So on the question of an office in Washington, that did not come up today.  With regard to our consulate, we’re just beginning the process.  I can’t give you a timeline on how long that will take.  But I can tell you that it’s, I think, important to have that platform to be able to more effectively engage not just the Palestinian Authority, but Palestinians from different walks of life, the NGO community, the business community, and others.  And so we look forward to doing that, but I can’t put a timeline on it.</p>
<p>And coming back to Iran, no, I think the most important thing when it comes to this is what we committed to do from day one of this administration.  We said all along that if there was an opportunity, we would seek to return to mutual compliance with the JCPOA, but we also said that from day one, we would be keeping our closest allies and closest partners fully and contemporaneously informed of what we were doing and where we were going.  And that’s what we’ve done and that’s what we’ll continue to do.  That is how you keep faith with your partners and allies on something that, of course, is of great consequence to Israel.  We understand that.</p>
<p>And again, we have the same objective, and let’s see where things go in the next few weeks.  But I can again tell you that we are fully, fully engaged with our partners here in at least making sure that they’re fully informed of what we’re doing.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll turn to Hikmet Yosef from PalSawa.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (In Arabic.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Good afternoon.</p>
<p>(In Arabic.)</p>
<p><strong>INTERPRETER:</strong>  Okay.  So his question was:  “The U.S. administration said that it’s going to do the reconstruction of Gaza through the United Nations.  Is this considered an implicit, direct, or indirect recognition of Hamas that is taking over – that is the taken-over authority in Gaza?  And – or is there a plan for Washington to deal with Hamas directly or indirectly?”</p>
<p>And he’s asking also:  “Is the negotiation – will be resumed between the PA and Israel after the ceasefire?”  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much for your question.  Look, if we do this right, reconstruction and then – and relief for the people of Gaza, far from empowering Hamas, I think has the potential to undermine it.  I say that because Hamas thrives, unfortunately, on despair, on misery, on desperation, on a lack of opportunity.  In fact, it’s a movement that has thrived on a vacuum of opportunity.  And what reconstruction and relief need to do is not just answer the immediate needs – and those needs are significant and they’re urgent, whether it’s water, whether it’s sanitation, whether it’s electricity – but they need to offer a genuine prospect for opportunity, for progress, for material improvement in people’s lives.  And our goal is to give the Palestinian people, including those in Gaza, a renewed sense of confidence, of optimism, of real opportunity.</p>
<p>And if we succeed – and by the way, it’s not just us, it’s not just the UN.  It’s the Palestinian Authority that needs to be fully engaged, Israel needs to fully engage, other partners need to fully engage.  But in my judgment, at least, if we’re able to do that all together, then Hamas’s foothold in Gaza will slip, and we know that and I think that Hamas knows that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll take one final question from Andrea Mitchell.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  Did you get any commitments from Prime Minister Netanyahu to not evict Palestinians from East Jerusalem neighborhoods and to work with the Palestinian Authority and other Palestinians in order to avoid any spark that could break the ceasefire?  And did you get any assurances from the Palestinian Authority today that they could have any influence over Gaza?  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, Andrea.  So first, as – let me take a step back for a minute, because we’re focused right now on responding to, as I said, the urgent needs that exist in Gaza on a humanitarian basis, the urgent needs for rebuilding and reconstruction, and then looking to see actions on the part of both Israelis and Palestinians that will take down tension, and try to remove or minimize some of the potential catalysts for a renewed cycle of violence, and, building on that, try to – in very practical and material ways, start to improve people’s lives and add a real sense of dignity and hope.</p>
<p>If that happens – and that will take some time – that may, I think, produce a better environment in which ultimately there’s a possibility of resuming the effort to achieve a two-state solution, which we continue to believe is the only way to truly assure Israel’s future as a Jewish and democratic state, and of course, to give the Palestinians the state that they’re entitled to.</p>
<p>I say all that because any steps that either side takes that either risk sparking violence or – over time – and ultimately undermine the prospect for returning to the pursuit of two states, we oppose.  And that includes settlement activity, it includes demolitions, it includes evictions, it includes incitement to violence, it includes payment to terrorists.  All of those things would, I think, on the one hand potentially be catalysts for renewed tension and potentially violence, and certainly undermine the prospects of achieving two states.  And that’s something that we’ve been very clear about in our conversations with Israelis and Palestinians alike.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But did you get any commitment today?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I’ll let the – I’ll let our partners speak for themselves.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you very much, everybody.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement by the Secretary of State of the United States of America, the Foreign Secretary of the United Kingdom, and the Foreign Ministers of France, Germany, and Italy</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-by-the-secretary-of-state-of-the-united-states-of-america-the-foreign-secretary-of-the-united-kingdom-and-the-foreign-ministers-of-france-germany-and-italy-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 19:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following statement was released by United States Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken, French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian, German Foreign Minister Heiko Maas, Italian Foreign Minister Luigi Di Maio, and UK Foreign Secretary Dominic Raab on Syria’s presidential election.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>We, the Foreign Ministers of France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom and the United States of America wish to make clear that Syria’s May 26 presidential election will neither be free nor fair. We denounce the Assad regime’s decision to hold an election outside of the framework described in UN Security Council Resolution 2254 and we support the voices of all Syrians, including civil society organisations and the Syrian opposition, who have condemned the electoral process as illegitimate.</p>
<p>As outlined in the Resolution, free and fair elections should be convened under UN supervision to the highest international standards of transparency and accountability. For an election to be credible, all Syrians should be allowed to participate, including internally displaced Syrians, refugees, and members of the diaspora, in a safe and neutral environment.</p>
<p>Without these elements, this fraudulent election does not represent any progress towards a political settlement. We urge the international community to unequivocally reject this attempt by the Assad regime to regain legitimacy without ending its grave human rights violations and meaningfully participating in the UN-facilitated political process to end the conflict.</p>
<p>We reiterate our firm support for the UN Special Envoy for Syria’s efforts to promote a political settlement, based on all aspects of UNSCR 2254, which protects the future prosperity and the rights of all Syrians, including the right to vote in free and fair elections.</p>
<p><em>End text. </em></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following statement was released by United States Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken, French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian, German Foreign Minister Heiko Maas, Italian Foreign Minister Luigi Di Maio, and UK Foreign Secretary Dominic Raab on Syria’s presidential election.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>We, the Foreign Ministers of France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom and the United States of America wish to make clear that Syria’s May 26 presidential election will neither be free nor fair. We denounce the Assad regime’s decision to hold an election outside of the framework described in UN Security Council Resolution 2254 and we support the voices of all Syrians, including civil society organisations and the Syrian opposition, who have condemned the electoral process as illegitimate.</p>
<p>As outlined in the Resolution, free and fair elections should be convened under UN supervision to the highest international standards of transparency and accountability. For an election to be credible, all Syrians should be allowed to participate, including internally displaced Syrians, refugees, and members of the diaspora, in a safe and neutral environment.</p>
<p>Without these elements, this fraudulent election does not represent any progress towards a political settlement. We urge the international community to unequivocally reject this attempt by the Assad regime to regain legitimacy without ending its grave human rights violations and meaningfully participating in the UN-facilitated political process to end the conflict.</p>
<p>We reiterate our firm support for the UN Special Envoy for Syria’s efforts to promote a political settlement, based on all aspects of UNSCR 2254, which protects the future prosperity and the rights of all Syrians, including the right to vote in free and fair elections.</p>
<p><em>End text. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas Statements to the Press</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-palestinian-authority-president-mahmoud-abbas-statements-to-the-press/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 17:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246201</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Ramallah, West Bank</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ABBAS:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  In the name of God, the merciful and the compassionate, we would like to welcome Secretary Clinton, who visits us these – in these days &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>STAFF:</strong>  Blinken.</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ABBAS:</strong>  (Via interpreter) – sorry – Blinken, who visits us in these days &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  It’s an improvement.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ABBAS:</strong>  (Via interpreter) – under very difficult conditions.  And we also would like to thank President Biden and the U.S. administration for their efforts to achieve a ceasefire between the Gaza Strip and Israel, and the efforts that they continue to exert in order to reach a comprehensive ceasefire that will hold.</p>
<p>We would also like to thank the U.S. administration for its support to the state of Palestine and for the resumption of its assistance to us and to the UNRWA.  This is something that we highly value, and we hope that the future will be rife with diplomatic and political effort headed by the U.S. and the Quartet so that we can reach a lasting and comprehensive peace in the region according to international legitimacy resolutions, and so that these actions on the part of a few – of a hurtful few would come to an end.</p>
<p>We also thank the U.S. administration for its commitment to a two-state solution, and the maintenance of the status quo in Jerusalem, and to keep the residents of Jerusalem and Sheikh Jarrah in their homes.  And also we thank the U.S. administration for its position vis-a-vis the expansion of settlements, and the actions taken by settlers.</p>
<p>We have also affirmed that we are committed to peaceful popular resistance and that we renounce violence and terrorism, and we only want to achieve a political solution through peaceful means between us and Israel.</p>
<p>We have also affirmed that our government stands ready to work directly in order for the reconstruction of Gaza and also to establish a national unity government for that end that would be all-inclusive.  And in the event that such agreement materializes, our first condition would be that Hamas and all parties have to abide by international legitimacy resolutions that are known for everyone.</p>
<p>And we also informed the Secretary that we have postponed the elections, because Israel has refused to include Jerusalem in these elections, and the minute that it does we will hold them immediately and without any delay, because ultimately what we’re interested in is to establish democracy throughout Palestine.</p>
<p>Once again, I thank the U.S. administration and President Biden and Secretary Tony Blinken for the efforts that he’s in engaging in now in order to achieve that end.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, Mr. President, thank you very, very much.  It’s very good to be in Ramallah, or maybe I should say back in Ramallah, to see you, to see the prime minister and your team.</p>
<p>And let me start by conveying the deep condolences of the United States to the families who’ve lost loved ones in the recent violence – the children, the women, the men whose lives were lost.  I say this as a father.  No child, whether Israeli, Palestinian, or American, is a statistic.  We know the human consequences when violence takes the upper hand, and we are determined that that not be the case.  I think the loss of any child is a universe of loss, and in some ways incomprehensible except to those who’ve suffered the loss.  And that’s true irrespective of whether you’re Israeli, Palestinian, American; if you’re a human being, that’s what matters.</p>
<p>We know that the last round of violence is symptomatic of a larger set of issues that we have to address if we’re going to prevent its recurrence, and that’s what we talked about today.  We welcome the ceasefire that continues to hold, but that’s not enough.  We have to build on the ceasefire and try to move things in a genuinely positive direction.  As I told the president, I am here to underscore the commitment of the United States to rebuilding a relationship with the Palestinian Authority and with the Palestinian people, a relationship built on mutual respect and also a shared conviction that Palestinians and Israelis alike deserve equal measures of freedom, security, opportunity, and dignity.</p>
<p>As I told Prime Minister Netanyahu and President Abbas, the United States will be moving forward with the process to reopen our consulate in Jerusalem.  That’s an important way for our country to engage with and provide support to the Palestinian people.  We’re also working in partnership with the United Nations, the international community, the Palestinian Authority, the Palestinian people, the Government of Israel to assist in the relief and recovery efforts in Gaza.  The – this relief is urgent.  We have to respond to the profound need to help people in this moment.</p>
<p>To that end, I informed President Abbas and, earlier, Prime Minister Netanyahu that the United States will notify Congress of our intention to provide $75 million in additional development and economic assistance for the Palestinians in 2021.  We’ll also provide $5.5 million in immediate disaster assistance for Gaza and a little over $32 million for UNRWA’s emergency humanitarian appeal.  This new assistance comes on top of significant support the United States has recently committed and resumed to the Palestinian Authority, the Palestinians, to different agencies and groups.</p>
<p>In total, we are in the process of providing more than $360 million of urgent support for the Palestinian people, and across these efforts, we will work with partners to ensure that Hamas does not benefit from these reconstruction efforts.  Asking the international community, asking all of us to help rebuild Gaza only makes sense if there is confidence that what is rebuilt is not lost again because Hamas decides to launch more rocket attacks in the future.  So this is vitally important.</p>
<p>We also talked a little bit about a challenge that all of us have faced together in the past year, and that is COVID-19.  And we will work in the United States to rally the international community to provide 1.5 million doses of safe, effective COVID-19 vaccines to the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>Beyond the immediate reconstruction and (inaudible), we’re also committed to working with the Palestinian Authority and the international community to promote economic stability and progress in the West Bank and Gaza, more opportunity, to strengthen the private sector, expand trade and investment, all of which are essential to growing opportunity across the board.  We’ll also work with the Palestinian Authority to ensure freedom of expression for all Palestinians and the promotion and protection of civil society.  I very much look forward in a short while to meeting with leaders from Palestinian civil society a little later today.</p>
<p>We will, as the president noted, continue to firmly oppose any unilateral provocative actions that risk sparking more violence and that undermine prospects for a just, durable resolution of the conflict between Palestinians and Israelis, which ultimately requires two states.  And whether that is settlement activity, whether that is home demolitions, annexation of territory, incitement to violence, compensation for individuals imprisoned for acts of terrorism, any unilateral action that undermines the prospects for genuine progress and genuine peace is something we will continue to oppose.</p>
<p>We remain committed to the historic status quo on the Haram al-Sharif.  Palestinians and Muslims from around the world must be able to pray in peace on the Noble Sanctuary, now and eternally.  In Jerusalem and across Israel, Christian and Muslim Palestinian families deserve the same right to worship, build, and thrive as their Jewish cohabitants.</p>
<p>The aspirations of the Palestinian people are like those of people everywhere: to live in freedom; to have their basic rights respected, including the right to choose their own leaders; to live in security; to have equal access to opportunity for themselves, for their children; to be treated with dignity.  And my message today is that the United States is committed, Mr. President, to working with you, to working with the Palestinian people, to realize these aspirations.</p>
<p>Thank you for having us here today.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Ramallah, West Bank</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ABBAS:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  In the name of God, the merciful and the compassionate, we would like to welcome Secretary Clinton, who visits us these – in these days &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>STAFF:</strong>  Blinken.</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ABBAS:</strong>  (Via interpreter) – sorry – Blinken, who visits us in these days &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  It’s an improvement.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ABBAS:</strong>  (Via interpreter) – under very difficult conditions.  And we also would like to thank President Biden and the U.S. administration for their efforts to achieve a ceasefire between the Gaza Strip and Israel, and the efforts that they continue to exert in order to reach a comprehensive ceasefire that will hold.</p>
<p>We would also like to thank the U.S. administration for its support to the state of Palestine and for the resumption of its assistance to us and to the UNRWA.  This is something that we highly value, and we hope that the future will be rife with diplomatic and political effort headed by the U.S. and the Quartet so that we can reach a lasting and comprehensive peace in the region according to international legitimacy resolutions, and so that these actions on the part of a few – of a hurtful few would come to an end.</p>
<p>We also thank the U.S. administration for its commitment to a two-state solution, and the maintenance of the status quo in Jerusalem, and to keep the residents of Jerusalem and Sheikh Jarrah in their homes.  And also we thank the U.S. administration for its position vis-a-vis the expansion of settlements, and the actions taken by settlers.</p>
<p>We have also affirmed that we are committed to peaceful popular resistance and that we renounce violence and terrorism, and we only want to achieve a political solution through peaceful means between us and Israel.</p>
<p>We have also affirmed that our government stands ready to work directly in order for the reconstruction of Gaza and also to establish a national unity government for that end that would be all-inclusive.  And in the event that such agreement materializes, our first condition would be that Hamas and all parties have to abide by international legitimacy resolutions that are known for everyone.</p>
<p>And we also informed the Secretary that we have postponed the elections, because Israel has refused to include Jerusalem in these elections, and the minute that it does we will hold them immediately and without any delay, because ultimately what we’re interested in is to establish democracy throughout Palestine.</p>
<p>Once again, I thank the U.S. administration and President Biden and Secretary Tony Blinken for the efforts that he’s in engaging in now in order to achieve that end.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, Mr. President, thank you very, very much.  It’s very good to be in Ramallah, or maybe I should say back in Ramallah, to see you, to see the prime minister and your team.</p>
<p>And let me start by conveying the deep condolences of the United States to the families who’ve lost loved ones in the recent violence – the children, the women, the men whose lives were lost.  I say this as a father.  No child, whether Israeli, Palestinian, or American, is a statistic.  We know the human consequences when violence takes the upper hand, and we are determined that that not be the case.  I think the loss of any child is a universe of loss, and in some ways incomprehensible except to those who’ve suffered the loss.  And that’s true irrespective of whether you’re Israeli, Palestinian, American; if you’re a human being, that’s what matters.</p>
<p>We know that the last round of violence is symptomatic of a larger set of issues that we have to address if we’re going to prevent its recurrence, and that’s what we talked about today.  We welcome the ceasefire that continues to hold, but that’s not enough.  We have to build on the ceasefire and try to move things in a genuinely positive direction.  As I told the president, I am here to underscore the commitment of the United States to rebuilding a relationship with the Palestinian Authority and with the Palestinian people, a relationship built on mutual respect and also a shared conviction that Palestinians and Israelis alike deserve equal measures of freedom, security, opportunity, and dignity.</p>
<p>As I told Prime Minister Netanyahu and President Abbas, the United States will be moving forward with the process to reopen our consulate in Jerusalem.  That’s an important way for our country to engage with and provide support to the Palestinian people.  We’re also working in partnership with the United Nations, the international community, the Palestinian Authority, the Palestinian people, the Government of Israel to assist in the relief and recovery efforts in Gaza.  The – this relief is urgent.  We have to respond to the profound need to help people in this moment.</p>
<p>To that end, I informed President Abbas and, earlier, Prime Minister Netanyahu that the United States will notify Congress of our intention to provide $75 million in additional development and economic assistance for the Palestinians in 2021.  We’ll also provide $5.5 million in immediate disaster assistance for Gaza and a little over $32 million for UNRWA’s emergency humanitarian appeal.  This new assistance comes on top of significant support the United States has recently committed and resumed to the Palestinian Authority, the Palestinians, to different agencies and groups.</p>
<p>In total, we are in the process of providing more than $360 million of urgent support for the Palestinian people, and across these efforts, we will work with partners to ensure that Hamas does not benefit from these reconstruction efforts.  Asking the international community, asking all of us to help rebuild Gaza only makes sense if there is confidence that what is rebuilt is not lost again because Hamas decides to launch more rocket attacks in the future.  So this is vitally important.</p>
<p>We also talked a little bit about a challenge that all of us have faced together in the past year, and that is COVID-19.  And we will work in the United States to rally the international community to provide 1.5 million doses of safe, effective COVID-19 vaccines to the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>Beyond the immediate reconstruction and (inaudible), we’re also committed to working with the Palestinian Authority and the international community to promote economic stability and progress in the West Bank and Gaza, more opportunity, to strengthen the private sector, expand trade and investment, all of which are essential to growing opportunity across the board.  We’ll also work with the Palestinian Authority to ensure freedom of expression for all Palestinians and the promotion and protection of civil society.  I very much look forward in a short while to meeting with leaders from Palestinian civil society a little later today.</p>
<p>We will, as the president noted, continue to firmly oppose any unilateral provocative actions that risk sparking more violence and that undermine prospects for a just, durable resolution of the conflict between Palestinians and Israelis, which ultimately requires two states.  And whether that is settlement activity, whether that is home demolitions, annexation of territory, incitement to violence, compensation for individuals imprisoned for acts of terrorism, any unilateral action that undermines the prospects for genuine progress and genuine peace is something we will continue to oppose.</p>
<p>We remain committed to the historic status quo on the Haram al-Sharif.  Palestinians and Muslims from around the world must be able to pray in peace on the Noble Sanctuary, now and eternally.  In Jerusalem and across Israel, Christian and Muslim Palestinian families deserve the same right to worship, build, and thrive as their Jewish cohabitants.</p>
<p>The aspirations of the Palestinian people are like those of people everywhere: to live in freedom; to have their basic rights respected, including the right to choose their own leaders; to live in security; to have equal access to opportunity for themselves, for their children; to be treated with dignity.  And my message today is that the United States is committed, Mr. President, to working with you, to working with the Palestinian people, to realize these aspirations.</p>
<p>Thank you for having us here today.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
