<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 19:35:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and European Union High Representative for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy and Vice President of the European Commission Josep Borrell at a Joint Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-european-union-high-representative-for-foreign-affairs-and-security-policy-and-vice-president-of-the-european-commission-josep-borrell-at-a-joint-press-availabilit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Josep Borrell, European Union High Representative for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy and Vice President of the European Commission]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 19:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312036</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Josep Borrell, European Union High Representative for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy and Vice President of the European Commission</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Dean Acheson Auditorium</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>I was just checking to make sure I can say good afternoon.  It is good afternoon.  Good afternoon, everyone.  And let me first start by thanking the High Representative Josep Borrell, Josep my friend, for traveling to Washington today for a meeting of the U.S.-EU Energy Council.  The timing could not be more important; this is a pivotal moment.</p>
<p>As President Biden and European Commission President von der Leyen described in their joint statement just a couple of weeks ago, we’re working together right now to protect Europe’s energy supply against supply shocks including those that could result from further Russian aggression against Ukraine.  Energy security is tied directly to national security, regional security, global security.  Europe needs reliable and affordable energy, especially in the winter months.</p>
<p>When Russia halted gas supplies to Europe over a dispute with Ukraine in 2009, people died from the cold.  And when energy supplies fail, economies falter.  We’re determined to prevent that from happening and to mitigate the impact on energy supplies and prices should Russia choose to cut natural gas supplies to Europe more than it already has.  For example, we’re talking with governments and major producers around the world about surging their production and distribution capacity; we’re coordinating with our allies and partners, with energy sector stakeholders, including about how best to share energy reserves in the event that Russia turns off the spigot or initiates a conflict that disrupts the flow of gas through Ukraine.</p>
<p>This is part of broader coordination between Europe and the United States during this crisis and, indeed, beyond this crisis.  We and our allies and partners are united across the board.  We’ve listened to Russia’s concerns and shared concerns of our own about the steps that they’re taking to undermine security.  The United States, the European Union, our NATO Allies, our OSCE partners throughout Europe have put forward ideas about how we and Russia can find common agreement that will strengthen collective security for everyone.  I reiterated this in my conversation with Russian Foreign Minister Lavrov a few days ago; others have reinforced these same concerns directly with Moscow.  We and our allies and partners have done so collectively at NATO, at the OSCE.</p>
<p>We’re all driving the same message:  We’re willing to continue a substantive conversation with Russia on mutual security concerns.  The diplomatic path is clear.  At the same time, we and our allies are resolved that there will be real and profound consequences should Russia choose to continue aggression.  We’ve developed a high-impact, quick action response that would inflict massive costs on the Russian economy and financial system, including sanctions and significant export controls that would have a long-term effect in denying Russia the technology that it needs in key sectors.  And we’re working closely with the EU as they prepare complementary actions.</p>
<p>At the same time, we continue to work closely with Congress and with allies and partners to significantly increase assistance to Ukraine to help it prepare to defend itself.  We’ve provided Ukraine with $650 million in security assistance last year, more than in any previous year; we authorized allies to provide U.S. origin equipment; we’ve deployed forces and put more on a heightened state of readiness to shore up NATO’s eastern flank; and we’re working with partners to support the Ukrainian economy.</p>
<p>We’ve done all of this through constant coordination, some 200 engagements to date by phone, screen, in-person.  What happens next will depend on whether President Putin will choose to engage in a meaningful path forward on diplomacy for enhanced collective security or if he will choose the path of further conflict with Ukraine.  Either way – either way, the United States and our allies and partners are prepared.</p>
<p>As we’ve done many times before, we’re acting in unity to defend the principles that have been at the core of security, stability, and prosperity for decades in Europe and beyond.  We can see that across our cooperation with the European Union, including our work together to support resilient infrastructure and developing economies through Build Back Better World and the EU’s Global Gateway, to boost the supply of vaccines and treatments to end the COVID-19 pandemic, and through the U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council we’re shaping emerging technologies so that they enhance our democracies, not undermine them.  Today’s meeting of the U.S.-EU Energy Council has continued vital work that we’re doing together both to build energy security and also to advance the critical work of responding to the climate crisis and pursuing new technologies, renewable energy, and doing that together.</p>
<p>When the EU and the United States are working together, we have a tremendous capacity to lead the world.  Together our economies represent about 45 percent of world GDP.  When we’re acting in concert we can move others, motivate others, and actually deal effectively with the challenges that are before our people and people around the world.  So I was particularly pleased to have this opportunity to focus today on energy, but almost quite literally every day in the work that we’re doing together.  Thank you.</p>
<p>Josep.</p>
<p><strong>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you very much, Secretary of State, dear Tony.  It’s great to be here in Washington again and to meet again also in person after we have been in close contact over the past weeks.  As you have said, we have been on speed-dial mode, and it’s good because we have been coordinating a lot during those days.</p>
<p>And today’s discussion after our bilateral meeting has been about energy on the EU-U.S. Energy Council, and this has demonstrated again our strong transatlantic unity on geopolitical questions and around climate and energy issues.  This meeting could have not been more timely.  This ninth meeting of the Energy Council, after four years without meeting, has been a good occasion to deal with the current circumstances of the threats that Russia is putting on the eastern borders of Europe.</p>
<p>Our joint work is needed to accelerate a green energy transition to become neutral from the point of view of our climate in the future.  In the medium term, there is the climate neutrality.  In the short term, it’s security of supplies of gas.  Both things go together.  We need to face the current situation in the eastern border keeping in mind the purpose of decarbonizing our energy mix, because the only lasting solution to energy resilience, security, is going from fossil fuels to renewables.  It is the best way of facing the challenge of climate change.</p>
<p>Today our environment is characterized by the geopolitical turbulence in the context of Russia and Crimea crisis, and energy issues are central to this crisis because Russia doesn’t hesitate to use the significant energy supplies to Europe as the leverage for geopolitical gains.  And when gas prices in European Union have been increasing from 6 to 10 times higher than they were a year ago – 10 times higher than one year ago – this has a major impact on consumers and on the competitivity of the economy.</p>
<p>That’s why our immediate priority to diversify the sources of energy, in particular the gas flows, to avoid supply disruption from our main supplier, who is Russia, and to ensure that the world energy markets will be liquid, competitive, and well-supplied.  Keep in mind that for Europe, our dependency from gas is about 95 percent of our consumption, oil 97 percent, coal 70 percent.  These figures are a good indicator of the need of shifting our energy mix to renewables.</p>
<p>Today, dear Tony, we have sent a strong message of our joint determination to bolster energy security in Europe and in our direct neighborhood, and thinking on Ukraine but also on the Western Balkans.  As to the current crisis around Ukraine, we have seen eye-to-eye our determination to give a united response to Russia’s threats.  This is our best asset.</p>
<p>We have repeated our call to Russia to de-escalate.  Our multilayered diplomatic engagement will continue on various levels and in different formats, as bilateral contacts, the Normandy talks, the OSCE, and NATO.  We certainly at the European Union, we welcome the elements outlined in the U.S. and NATO responses to the Russian demands on European security coordination with the U.S. and NATO.  I think it’s exemplary and shows our unity and determination.</p>
<p>We believe that the diplomatic way out of the crisis is still possible, and this is our clear and first priority, and that’s what we are investing all our efforts.  But at the same time, we remain firm in our resolve that further aggression against Ukraine would have, as the Secretary of State said, massive consequences, and we hope for the best, but we prepare for the worst.  Should Russia continue on a path of aggression, the European Union and the United States actions will be closely aligned, including on sanctions.</p>
<p>Let me stress how important is Ukraine for us.  It is a strategic partner.  We have been supporting Ukraine since Russia grasped Crimea with more than €17 billion.  And this week we have provided another 1.5 billion in macro financial assistance.  We are helping them in countering cyber and hybrid threats, strengthen the capabilities of the Ukrainian Armed Forces, and tackling disinformation.</p>
<p>To conclude, let me express my appreciation to you, the U.S. Secretary of State, for the excellent cooperation over the last week in tackling so many challenges, and that’s what we are going to continue doing.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll now take two questions.  The first question goes to the BBC, Barbara Usher.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Good afternoon.  A question about diplomacy for you, Mr. Blinken.  The U.S. and Europe are pushing Minsk as the solution while Ukraine is completely against it.  Do you still think a measure of autonomy for Donbas, the autonomy stipulated in the agreement, is the way to go?</p>
<p>And a question for you, Mr. Borrell.  You’re welcome to comment on that as well, but with regards to security does the EU agree with the U.S. assessment that a potential imminent invasion of Ukraine is in the cards?  If so, why isn’t the EU raising the same alarm as the Americans?  And if not, do you have a different assessment of the situation?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you, Barbara.  I’m happy to start.</p>
<p>With regard to Minsk, the United States and Ukraine are united in believing that Minsk is the path forward to resolve the conflict in the Donbas that was created by Russia’s invasion in 2014, and the best way to restore Ukraine’s border, to restore its sovereignty, as well as to uphold the rights of Ukrainian citizens, including those living in the Donbas.</p>
<p>Repeatedly over the last years, Ukraine has sought to move forward with the implementation of Minsk.  The Normandy Format, as it’s called with France, Germany, Ukraine, and Russia involved has been the principal vehicle for trying to advance that.  I think if you look back over the requirements established in the Minsk Agreements, three agreements over the course of several months, it is a fair assessment to say that Ukraine has sought to move forward on most if not all of them, while Russia has made good on virtually none of its obligations under Minsk.</p>
<p>But in all of my conversations with our Ukrainian counterparts, they remain committed to it.  There was recently a meeting of senior officials in the Normandy Format.  Ukraine continues to put forward good-faith ideas on how to move forward.  Minsk does not spell out some issues of sequencing when it comes to the steps that the parties need to take.  Ukraine has been approaching this in good faith.  We have not to date seen Russia do the same.</p>
<p>The agreements speak of special status for the Donbas, and I believe that with the appropriate sequencing, the Ukrainians would be prepared to move forward.  But again, the overall picture on Minsk since 2014 has been one in which Ukraine has sought to move forward on most of its requirements and commitments; Russia has not.  So if Russia is serious about implementing Minsk, I think it will find a strong partner in Ukraine, and France and Germany are helping to lead this effort.  There&#8217;s supposed to be another meeting of the – in the Normandy Format in the next couple of weeks.  I hope Russia will demonstrate a seriousness of purpose.  There are some near-term steps that could be taken to continue to build confidence in – toward the implementation of Minsk.  We have one of them that&#8217;s already more or less in place, which is a ceasefire that brings things back to the levels of 2020.  It hasn&#8217;t been perfect, but it&#8217;s definitely been an improvement over what we were seeing just a few weeks ago, so that&#8217;s encouraging.</p>
<p>The Ukrainians have also talked about having a release of prisoners on both sides, and making sure as well that across the line of contact people can move much more freely.  Unfortunately, that&#8217;s been blocked by those on the separatist side.  I think that would be a good way to show seriousness of purpose, and then to pursue the actual implementation of the accords.  But bottom line is Ukraine is committed to Minsk.  If Russia is too, then I believe there&#8217;s a way to move forward and resolve this conflict.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Some in Ukraine are saying that the level of autonomy would be disruptive to your country.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>This is all for discussion and in progress.  Again, the Minsk Agreements talk about special status, but there are myriad other requirements that go to security, that go to restoring Ukraine&#8217;s border, that go to steps that unfortunately continue to be taken primarily by the Russian and separatist side that need to be addressed.  And I believe that those are addressed and addressed pursuant to what was agreed in 2014.  There&#8217;s a way to resolve this through the Minsk Agreements.</p>
<p><strong>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:  </strong>Thank you for your question.  We share a strong concern about the risk that are accumulating in the Ukrainian-Russian border.  And certainly, we are living, to my understanding, the most dangerous moment for the security in Europe after the end of the Cold War.  But at the same time, we believe that there is still room for diplomacy, there is still room for discussing, for knowing which are the concerns of everybody, also the Russian concerns, in order to avoid the worst.  Be prepared for the worst, and try to avoid it.</p>
<p>Nobody masses 104,000 soldiers heavily armed in the border of a country at the same time that you state about independency of this country in a way that certainly represents a strong threat –140,000 troops massed in the border is not to go to have tea.  So we have to increase our efforts in order to avoid a big risk for the peace and security.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>(Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:  </strong>I haven&#8217;t finished yet.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Sorry.</p>
<p><strong>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:  </strong>Minister Lavrov has sent a letter to all members of the European Union, to the member states, about it, asking for taking into consideration the security concerns of Russia.  I am coordinating the answer to this letter, and I insisting on the fact that there is still room for a diplomatic solution to the crisis.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Do you think that telegraphing the alarm about a potential invasion works against diplomatic efforts, the success of diplomatic efforts?</p>
<p><strong>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:  </strong>With the mask, it is difficult to understand you.  Can &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Do you think that telegraphing the alarm so much about the potential of an invasion works against chances for a diplomatic solution?</p>
<p><strong>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:  </strong>On one hand you have to warn about the situation, and on the other hand you have to work in order to solve the situation.  Both things go together.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Our next question will come from <em>El Pais</em>.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you so much.  I have a question for High Representative Borrell and I – and also for Secretary Blinken.</p>
<p><strong>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:</strong>  Speak louder, because with the mask it’s difficult to understand.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Secretary, for – question for High Representative Borrell and also Secretary Blinken.  It’s pretty much a follow-up question, actually.  The U.S. administration have been – has been sharing to the public several pieces of intelligence information or at least conclusions, and also specific sanctions regarding Russia&#8217;s intentions, and even how imminent an attack would be.  Do you think this can create alarmism, and do you think this is the smart strategy?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.  First, let me say I’ve been reading <em>El Pais</em> very attentively, especially in recent days.  This is not alarmism; this is simply the facts.  We have to deal with the facts.  We have to deal with the facts in the context of history and we have to deal with the facts in making sure that we are fully prepared, and the facts are, as Josep said, that we have seen over the last few months a massing of Russian forces on Ukraine’s borders.  That’s not happening in a vacuum.  It’s happening in the context of what Russia already did in 2014 in invading Ukraine, seizing Crimea, creating a conflict in the Donbas that continues to this day.</p>
<p>So that’s what we’re seeing.  That’s what we’re looking at.  That’s what we’re responding to.  And we’ve made very clear as well that there are two paths before Russia.  One path is the path of diplomacy and dialogue that we have been pursuing together and in an effort to strengthen collective security for everyone.  We have deep concerns in the United States and Europe about many actions that Russia has taken over the years that undermine security.  Russia says it has concerns about us.  We have demonstrated that we’re fully prepared to address those concerns on a reciprocal basis and doing that in full and very close coordination.</p>
<p>At the same time, though, given the facts that we’re seeing, given the history that we know, we have to be prepared for what could happen.  We – we don’t believe that Mr. – President Putin has made a decision, but he has put in place the capacity should he so decide to act very quickly against Ukraine, and in ways that would have terrible consequences for Ukraine, for Russia, but consequences also for all of us, because these actions – this aggression, this threatened aggression against Ukraine – would undermine the core principles that were hard established after World War II and after the Cold War that have helped to protect security, stability, peace, and prosperity in Europe and beyond ever since, principles like one country can’t simply go in by force and change the borders of another.  One country can’t simply dictate to another its choices, its decisions, including about with whom it will associate.  One country cannot exert a sphere of influence over its neighbors to try to subjugate those neighbors to its will.</p>
<p>All of those things are at stake, and that’s why it’s been so important not just in terms of Ukraine, as important as that is, but in terms of the larger principles that are endangered by Russia’s conduct.  As Josep said, we strongly believe together in the United States and Europe that the preferred course – the responsible course – is to work through the differences that we have diplomatically and through dialogue, and we’ve demonstrated our commitment to do that.  But equally, we are prepared if Russia chooses the path of aggression.</p>
<p>We’ve worked incredibly closely together in the last months, as I mentioned, nearly 200 engagements among us that continue every single day, and I think it demonstrates a solidarity of purpose, a commitment to engage together on this either way that Russia chooses.  I have to say as well that here in the United States we’ve had very strong bipartisan support for Ukraine, for upholding these principles, for working together.  I spent time with Congress last week, and that was abundantly clear from Republican and Democratic members alike.  So we will see what President Putin decides, but either way, he is going to find a Europe and United States that are fully aligned, fully coordinating, fully cooperative.</p>
<p>Last point I’d just make:  You mentioned at the very beginning the disinformation campaign that we see Russia engaged in.  We believe – and it’s why we’ve spoken about it repeatedly – that the best antidote to disinformation is information, and that’s what we’ve sought to provide to the best of our ability.  We know that part of Russia’s playbook is to create false provocations as justification for acts that Russia was preparing to commit in any event, and so we’ve sought to put light on those, hopefully to deter them from happening, but at the very least so that if they do happen, no one is surprised and no one misinterprets what’s actually going on.</p>
<p><strong>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:</strong>  Well, at the beginning of the crisis, you remember, Tony, we had the phone call, and that’s when I said nothing should be agreed about European security without Europeans.  And I am very happy to say that since then we have been working very closely, I think more than ever.  This crisis has been pushing the transatlantic unity, and I am strongly satisfied of the participation of European Union on the (inaudible), the exchanges of positions among the U.S., the NATO, and Russia.</p>
<p>European Union is not a military association.  It’s not a military organization or union.  But we have a lot of strength on the civilian side.  And when we talk about sanctions, we talk about personal sanctions, about trade and sectoral economic sanctions, and we talk about financial sanctions, it has not to be interpreted as a threat.  We are not threatening anyone.  But we want to make clear which would be the consequences of some actions, because this is the deterrence part of the diplomatic talks.</p>
<p>I think it’s our duty to make clear which will be the consequences of aggression against Ukraine.  If it doesn’t happen, good, and we will do everything on the diplomatic side in order to avoid it.  But we have to be prepared to answer, and from the European Union, we have a certain number of tools on the economic side, trade and financial side that could be mobilized and certainly will be very damaging for the Russian economy.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary and Mr. High Representative.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, folks.  Have a good afternoon.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Josep Borrell, European Union High Representative for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy and Vice President of the European Commission</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Dean Acheson Auditorium</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>I was just checking to make sure I can say good afternoon.  It is good afternoon.  Good afternoon, everyone.  And let me first start by thanking the High Representative Josep Borrell, Josep my friend, for traveling to Washington today for a meeting of the U.S.-EU Energy Council.  The timing could not be more important; this is a pivotal moment.</p>
<p>As President Biden and European Commission President von der Leyen described in their joint statement just a couple of weeks ago, we’re working together right now to protect Europe’s energy supply against supply shocks including those that could result from further Russian aggression against Ukraine.  Energy security is tied directly to national security, regional security, global security.  Europe needs reliable and affordable energy, especially in the winter months.</p>
<p>When Russia halted gas supplies to Europe over a dispute with Ukraine in 2009, people died from the cold.  And when energy supplies fail, economies falter.  We’re determined to prevent that from happening and to mitigate the impact on energy supplies and prices should Russia choose to cut natural gas supplies to Europe more than it already has.  For example, we’re talking with governments and major producers around the world about surging their production and distribution capacity; we’re coordinating with our allies and partners, with energy sector stakeholders, including about how best to share energy reserves in the event that Russia turns off the spigot or initiates a conflict that disrupts the flow of gas through Ukraine.</p>
<p>This is part of broader coordination between Europe and the United States during this crisis and, indeed, beyond this crisis.  We and our allies and partners are united across the board.  We’ve listened to Russia’s concerns and shared concerns of our own about the steps that they’re taking to undermine security.  The United States, the European Union, our NATO Allies, our OSCE partners throughout Europe have put forward ideas about how we and Russia can find common agreement that will strengthen collective security for everyone.  I reiterated this in my conversation with Russian Foreign Minister Lavrov a few days ago; others have reinforced these same concerns directly with Moscow.  We and our allies and partners have done so collectively at NATO, at the OSCE.</p>
<p>We’re all driving the same message:  We’re willing to continue a substantive conversation with Russia on mutual security concerns.  The diplomatic path is clear.  At the same time, we and our allies are resolved that there will be real and profound consequences should Russia choose to continue aggression.  We’ve developed a high-impact, quick action response that would inflict massive costs on the Russian economy and financial system, including sanctions and significant export controls that would have a long-term effect in denying Russia the technology that it needs in key sectors.  And we’re working closely with the EU as they prepare complementary actions.</p>
<p>At the same time, we continue to work closely with Congress and with allies and partners to significantly increase assistance to Ukraine to help it prepare to defend itself.  We’ve provided Ukraine with $650 million in security assistance last year, more than in any previous year; we authorized allies to provide U.S. origin equipment; we’ve deployed forces and put more on a heightened state of readiness to shore up NATO’s eastern flank; and we’re working with partners to support the Ukrainian economy.</p>
<p>We’ve done all of this through constant coordination, some 200 engagements to date by phone, screen, in-person.  What happens next will depend on whether President Putin will choose to engage in a meaningful path forward on diplomacy for enhanced collective security or if he will choose the path of further conflict with Ukraine.  Either way – either way, the United States and our allies and partners are prepared.</p>
<p>As we’ve done many times before, we’re acting in unity to defend the principles that have been at the core of security, stability, and prosperity for decades in Europe and beyond.  We can see that across our cooperation with the European Union, including our work together to support resilient infrastructure and developing economies through Build Back Better World and the EU’s Global Gateway, to boost the supply of vaccines and treatments to end the COVID-19 pandemic, and through the U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council we’re shaping emerging technologies so that they enhance our democracies, not undermine them.  Today’s meeting of the U.S.-EU Energy Council has continued vital work that we’re doing together both to build energy security and also to advance the critical work of responding to the climate crisis and pursuing new technologies, renewable energy, and doing that together.</p>
<p>When the EU and the United States are working together, we have a tremendous capacity to lead the world.  Together our economies represent about 45 percent of world GDP.  When we’re acting in concert we can move others, motivate others, and actually deal effectively with the challenges that are before our people and people around the world.  So I was particularly pleased to have this opportunity to focus today on energy, but almost quite literally every day in the work that we’re doing together.  Thank you.</p>
<p>Josep.</p>
<p><strong>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you very much, Secretary of State, dear Tony.  It’s great to be here in Washington again and to meet again also in person after we have been in close contact over the past weeks.  As you have said, we have been on speed-dial mode, and it’s good because we have been coordinating a lot during those days.</p>
<p>And today’s discussion after our bilateral meeting has been about energy on the EU-U.S. Energy Council, and this has demonstrated again our strong transatlantic unity on geopolitical questions and around climate and energy issues.  This meeting could have not been more timely.  This ninth meeting of the Energy Council, after four years without meeting, has been a good occasion to deal with the current circumstances of the threats that Russia is putting on the eastern borders of Europe.</p>
<p>Our joint work is needed to accelerate a green energy transition to become neutral from the point of view of our climate in the future.  In the medium term, there is the climate neutrality.  In the short term, it’s security of supplies of gas.  Both things go together.  We need to face the current situation in the eastern border keeping in mind the purpose of decarbonizing our energy mix, because the only lasting solution to energy resilience, security, is going from fossil fuels to renewables.  It is the best way of facing the challenge of climate change.</p>
<p>Today our environment is characterized by the geopolitical turbulence in the context of Russia and Crimea crisis, and energy issues are central to this crisis because Russia doesn’t hesitate to use the significant energy supplies to Europe as the leverage for geopolitical gains.  And when gas prices in European Union have been increasing from 6 to 10 times higher than they were a year ago – 10 times higher than one year ago – this has a major impact on consumers and on the competitivity of the economy.</p>
<p>That’s why our immediate priority to diversify the sources of energy, in particular the gas flows, to avoid supply disruption from our main supplier, who is Russia, and to ensure that the world energy markets will be liquid, competitive, and well-supplied.  Keep in mind that for Europe, our dependency from gas is about 95 percent of our consumption, oil 97 percent, coal 70 percent.  These figures are a good indicator of the need of shifting our energy mix to renewables.</p>
<p>Today, dear Tony, we have sent a strong message of our joint determination to bolster energy security in Europe and in our direct neighborhood, and thinking on Ukraine but also on the Western Balkans.  As to the current crisis around Ukraine, we have seen eye-to-eye our determination to give a united response to Russia’s threats.  This is our best asset.</p>
<p>We have repeated our call to Russia to de-escalate.  Our multilayered diplomatic engagement will continue on various levels and in different formats, as bilateral contacts, the Normandy talks, the OSCE, and NATO.  We certainly at the European Union, we welcome the elements outlined in the U.S. and NATO responses to the Russian demands on European security coordination with the U.S. and NATO.  I think it’s exemplary and shows our unity and determination.</p>
<p>We believe that the diplomatic way out of the crisis is still possible, and this is our clear and first priority, and that’s what we are investing all our efforts.  But at the same time, we remain firm in our resolve that further aggression against Ukraine would have, as the Secretary of State said, massive consequences, and we hope for the best, but we prepare for the worst.  Should Russia continue on a path of aggression, the European Union and the United States actions will be closely aligned, including on sanctions.</p>
<p>Let me stress how important is Ukraine for us.  It is a strategic partner.  We have been supporting Ukraine since Russia grasped Crimea with more than €17 billion.  And this week we have provided another 1.5 billion in macro financial assistance.  We are helping them in countering cyber and hybrid threats, strengthen the capabilities of the Ukrainian Armed Forces, and tackling disinformation.</p>
<p>To conclude, let me express my appreciation to you, the U.S. Secretary of State, for the excellent cooperation over the last week in tackling so many challenges, and that’s what we are going to continue doing.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll now take two questions.  The first question goes to the BBC, Barbara Usher.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Good afternoon.  A question about diplomacy for you, Mr. Blinken.  The U.S. and Europe are pushing Minsk as the solution while Ukraine is completely against it.  Do you still think a measure of autonomy for Donbas, the autonomy stipulated in the agreement, is the way to go?</p>
<p>And a question for you, Mr. Borrell.  You’re welcome to comment on that as well, but with regards to security does the EU agree with the U.S. assessment that a potential imminent invasion of Ukraine is in the cards?  If so, why isn’t the EU raising the same alarm as the Americans?  And if not, do you have a different assessment of the situation?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you, Barbara.  I’m happy to start.</p>
<p>With regard to Minsk, the United States and Ukraine are united in believing that Minsk is the path forward to resolve the conflict in the Donbas that was created by Russia’s invasion in 2014, and the best way to restore Ukraine’s border, to restore its sovereignty, as well as to uphold the rights of Ukrainian citizens, including those living in the Donbas.</p>
<p>Repeatedly over the last years, Ukraine has sought to move forward with the implementation of Minsk.  The Normandy Format, as it’s called with France, Germany, Ukraine, and Russia involved has been the principal vehicle for trying to advance that.  I think if you look back over the requirements established in the Minsk Agreements, three agreements over the course of several months, it is a fair assessment to say that Ukraine has sought to move forward on most if not all of them, while Russia has made good on virtually none of its obligations under Minsk.</p>
<p>But in all of my conversations with our Ukrainian counterparts, they remain committed to it.  There was recently a meeting of senior officials in the Normandy Format.  Ukraine continues to put forward good-faith ideas on how to move forward.  Minsk does not spell out some issues of sequencing when it comes to the steps that the parties need to take.  Ukraine has been approaching this in good faith.  We have not to date seen Russia do the same.</p>
<p>The agreements speak of special status for the Donbas, and I believe that with the appropriate sequencing, the Ukrainians would be prepared to move forward.  But again, the overall picture on Minsk since 2014 has been one in which Ukraine has sought to move forward on most of its requirements and commitments; Russia has not.  So if Russia is serious about implementing Minsk, I think it will find a strong partner in Ukraine, and France and Germany are helping to lead this effort.  There&#8217;s supposed to be another meeting of the – in the Normandy Format in the next couple of weeks.  I hope Russia will demonstrate a seriousness of purpose.  There are some near-term steps that could be taken to continue to build confidence in – toward the implementation of Minsk.  We have one of them that&#8217;s already more or less in place, which is a ceasefire that brings things back to the levels of 2020.  It hasn&#8217;t been perfect, but it&#8217;s definitely been an improvement over what we were seeing just a few weeks ago, so that&#8217;s encouraging.</p>
<p>The Ukrainians have also talked about having a release of prisoners on both sides, and making sure as well that across the line of contact people can move much more freely.  Unfortunately, that&#8217;s been blocked by those on the separatist side.  I think that would be a good way to show seriousness of purpose, and then to pursue the actual implementation of the accords.  But bottom line is Ukraine is committed to Minsk.  If Russia is too, then I believe there&#8217;s a way to move forward and resolve this conflict.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Some in Ukraine are saying that the level of autonomy would be disruptive to your country.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>This is all for discussion and in progress.  Again, the Minsk Agreements talk about special status, but there are myriad other requirements that go to security, that go to restoring Ukraine&#8217;s border, that go to steps that unfortunately continue to be taken primarily by the Russian and separatist side that need to be addressed.  And I believe that those are addressed and addressed pursuant to what was agreed in 2014.  There&#8217;s a way to resolve this through the Minsk Agreements.</p>
<p><strong>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:  </strong>Thank you for your question.  We share a strong concern about the risk that are accumulating in the Ukrainian-Russian border.  And certainly, we are living, to my understanding, the most dangerous moment for the security in Europe after the end of the Cold War.  But at the same time, we believe that there is still room for diplomacy, there is still room for discussing, for knowing which are the concerns of everybody, also the Russian concerns, in order to avoid the worst.  Be prepared for the worst, and try to avoid it.</p>
<p>Nobody masses 104,000 soldiers heavily armed in the border of a country at the same time that you state about independency of this country in a way that certainly represents a strong threat –140,000 troops massed in the border is not to go to have tea.  So we have to increase our efforts in order to avoid a big risk for the peace and security.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>(Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:  </strong>I haven&#8217;t finished yet.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Sorry.</p>
<p><strong>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:  </strong>Minister Lavrov has sent a letter to all members of the European Union, to the member states, about it, asking for taking into consideration the security concerns of Russia.  I am coordinating the answer to this letter, and I insisting on the fact that there is still room for a diplomatic solution to the crisis.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Do you think that telegraphing the alarm about a potential invasion works against diplomatic efforts, the success of diplomatic efforts?</p>
<p><strong>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:  </strong>With the mask, it is difficult to understand you.  Can &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Do you think that telegraphing the alarm so much about the potential of an invasion works against chances for a diplomatic solution?</p>
<p><strong>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:  </strong>On one hand you have to warn about the situation, and on the other hand you have to work in order to solve the situation.  Both things go together.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Our next question will come from <em>El Pais</em>.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you so much.  I have a question for High Representative Borrell and I – and also for Secretary Blinken.</p>
<p><strong>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:</strong>  Speak louder, because with the mask it’s difficult to understand.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Secretary, for – question for High Representative Borrell and also Secretary Blinken.  It’s pretty much a follow-up question, actually.  The U.S. administration have been – has been sharing to the public several pieces of intelligence information or at least conclusions, and also specific sanctions regarding Russia&#8217;s intentions, and even how imminent an attack would be.  Do you think this can create alarmism, and do you think this is the smart strategy?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.  First, let me say I’ve been reading <em>El Pais</em> very attentively, especially in recent days.  This is not alarmism; this is simply the facts.  We have to deal with the facts.  We have to deal with the facts in the context of history and we have to deal with the facts in making sure that we are fully prepared, and the facts are, as Josep said, that we have seen over the last few months a massing of Russian forces on Ukraine’s borders.  That’s not happening in a vacuum.  It’s happening in the context of what Russia already did in 2014 in invading Ukraine, seizing Crimea, creating a conflict in the Donbas that continues to this day.</p>
<p>So that’s what we’re seeing.  That’s what we’re looking at.  That’s what we’re responding to.  And we’ve made very clear as well that there are two paths before Russia.  One path is the path of diplomacy and dialogue that we have been pursuing together and in an effort to strengthen collective security for everyone.  We have deep concerns in the United States and Europe about many actions that Russia has taken over the years that undermine security.  Russia says it has concerns about us.  We have demonstrated that we’re fully prepared to address those concerns on a reciprocal basis and doing that in full and very close coordination.</p>
<p>At the same time, though, given the facts that we’re seeing, given the history that we know, we have to be prepared for what could happen.  We – we don’t believe that Mr. – President Putin has made a decision, but he has put in place the capacity should he so decide to act very quickly against Ukraine, and in ways that would have terrible consequences for Ukraine, for Russia, but consequences also for all of us, because these actions – this aggression, this threatened aggression against Ukraine – would undermine the core principles that were hard established after World War II and after the Cold War that have helped to protect security, stability, peace, and prosperity in Europe and beyond ever since, principles like one country can’t simply go in by force and change the borders of another.  One country can’t simply dictate to another its choices, its decisions, including about with whom it will associate.  One country cannot exert a sphere of influence over its neighbors to try to subjugate those neighbors to its will.</p>
<p>All of those things are at stake, and that’s why it’s been so important not just in terms of Ukraine, as important as that is, but in terms of the larger principles that are endangered by Russia’s conduct.  As Josep said, we strongly believe together in the United States and Europe that the preferred course – the responsible course – is to work through the differences that we have diplomatically and through dialogue, and we’ve demonstrated our commitment to do that.  But equally, we are prepared if Russia chooses the path of aggression.</p>
<p>We’ve worked incredibly closely together in the last months, as I mentioned, nearly 200 engagements among us that continue every single day, and I think it demonstrates a solidarity of purpose, a commitment to engage together on this either way that Russia chooses.  I have to say as well that here in the United States we’ve had very strong bipartisan support for Ukraine, for upholding these principles, for working together.  I spent time with Congress last week, and that was abundantly clear from Republican and Democratic members alike.  So we will see what President Putin decides, but either way, he is going to find a Europe and United States that are fully aligned, fully coordinating, fully cooperative.</p>
<p>Last point I’d just make:  You mentioned at the very beginning the disinformation campaign that we see Russia engaged in.  We believe – and it’s why we’ve spoken about it repeatedly – that the best antidote to disinformation is information, and that’s what we’ve sought to provide to the best of our ability.  We know that part of Russia’s playbook is to create false provocations as justification for acts that Russia was preparing to commit in any event, and so we’ve sought to put light on those, hopefully to deter them from happening, but at the very least so that if they do happen, no one is surprised and no one misinterprets what’s actually going on.</p>
<p><strong>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:</strong>  Well, at the beginning of the crisis, you remember, Tony, we had the phone call, and that’s when I said nothing should be agreed about European security without Europeans.  And I am very happy to say that since then we have been working very closely, I think more than ever.  This crisis has been pushing the transatlantic unity, and I am strongly satisfied of the participation of European Union on the (inaudible), the exchanges of positions among the U.S., the NATO, and Russia.</p>
<p>European Union is not a military association.  It’s not a military organization or union.  But we have a lot of strength on the civilian side.  And when we talk about sanctions, we talk about personal sanctions, about trade and sectoral economic sanctions, and we talk about financial sanctions, it has not to be interpreted as a threat.  We are not threatening anyone.  But we want to make clear which would be the consequences of some actions, because this is the deterrence part of the diplomatic talks.</p>
<p>I think it’s our duty to make clear which will be the consequences of aggression against Ukraine.  If it doesn’t happen, good, and we will do everything on the diplomatic side in order to avoid it.  But we have to be prepared to answer, and from the European Union, we have a certain number of tools on the economic side, trade and financial side that could be mobilized and certainly will be very damaging for the Russian economy.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary and Mr. High Representative.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, folks.  Have a good afternoon.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the U.S.-EU Energy Council</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-the-u-s-eu-energy-council/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 18:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=311985</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Government of the United States of America and the European Union on the occasion of the ninth meeting of the U.S.-EU Energy Council.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>The ninth United States &#8211; European Union Energy Council (“Council”) met today in Washington, D.C., chaired by U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken, U.S. Secretary of Energy Jennifer M. Granholm, EU High Representative/Vice President Josep Borrell Fontelles, and European Energy Commissioner Kadri Simson. The Ambassador of France to the United States Philippe Etienne represented the Presidency of the Council of the European Union (EU). As reconfirmed in the June 15, 2021 EU-U.S. Summit Statement, the U.S.-EU Energy Council is the lead transatlantic coordination forum on strategic energy issues. The Council built on the work announced by President von der Leyen and President Biden on U.S.-EU cooperation on energy security in their Joint Statement of 28 January 2022.</p>
<p>Mindful of the rapidly changing energy landscape and the continued risks to energy security, including cybersecurity of energy infrastructure, the U.S.-EU Energy Council works to enhance energy security and promote energy diversification. The parties emphasized that accelerating the just energy transition to a net-zero future will support the mitigation of energy market fluctuations and facilitate access to affordable and reliable energy. The Council discussed the urgency for action to address the gas supply situation in Europe and to ensure gas supply to Ukraine.</p>
<p>The United States and the EU each underlined their commitment to reaching net-zero emissions by 2050 and to working together to ensure a rapid decarbonization and clean energy transition, and to promote increasing investments in related technologies. Accordingly, the Council reiterated the need to phase out unabated coal for power generation and inefficient fossil fuel subsidies without delay. The Council also works to accelerate a just energy transition to climate neutrality for citizens of the EU, the United States, and around the globe, and to promote research and development, innovation and deployment in related fields.</p>
<p><strong>Bolstering Energy Security in the EU and its neighborhood, including in Ukraine and the Western Balkans</strong></p>
<p>The Council reaffirmed the importance of the United States and EU working together on our mutual net-zero energy transition as countries increase their climate ambitions to ensure that consumers have secure access to affordable and reliable energy. The EU and the United States affirmed their commitment to proactively cooperate to address any potential risks related to energy supply in the EU and its neighborhood. This cooperation endeavors to focus on avoiding energy and resource supply disruptions and improving diversification of energy suppliers, fuel types in line with our net-zero targets, and means of transport. The Council underlined that competitive and transparent global energy markets remain critical to ensuring a reliable, affordable, and secure energy supply for Europe. As we address geopolitical and climate impacts on current energy markets, the EU and the United States intend to work together so that global liquefied natural gas markets have the capacity to provide additional and diversified supplies in case of pipeline gas disruptions in the short term as countries move away from fossil fuels and towards a sustainable net-zero future. The EU and the United States also recognize the growing cyber related threats to energy infrastructure and plan to continue related cooperation including in the context of the synchronization of the Baltic States’ electricity networks with the Continental European Network.</p>
<p>The Council reiterated that it is unacceptable to use energy supply as a weapon or geopolitical lever. This conviction underpinned the Council&#8217;s support for enhancing the resilience and energy security of Eastern partners, such as the Republic of Moldova and Ukraine, including through reverse gas flows. Recognizing current geopolitical tensions, the United States and the EU discussed intensifying cooperation in the short-term to ensure sufficient energy supplies for the EU and its neighborhood.</p>
<p>The Council affirmed that Ukraine continues to be a key partner of both the EU and the United States and expressed firm support for a strong and resilient Ukraine. It emphasized that energy security is vital to a sovereign Ukraine. The Council reiterated that Ukraine is a strategic gas transit country for the EU and should continue to promote the integration of Ukraine into the EU’s energy market, with the goal of improving Ukraine’s energy security, accelerating its decarbonization and clean energy transition, and enhancing its potential for clean energy exports. The Council expressed continued support for exploring new gas transit routes and capacity from the EU to Ukraine. The Council emphasized the importance of continuing to support the synchronization process of the electricity networks of Ukraine and the Republic of Moldova with the Continental European Network. The Council dedicated itself to new efforts to invest in and support Ukraine’s decarbonization efforts and relevant infrastructure.</p>
<p>The Council reaffirmed the need for transparent, robust, and independent institutions in Ukraine&#8217;s energy sector, in particular the energy market regulatory authorities and financial markets authorities, including the State Nuclear Regulatory Inspectorate of Ukraine. It highlighted that strong corporate governance and supervisory board autonomy without political interference are fundamental components to national energy security. As we are moving towards Ukraine’s integration with the European energy market, we will aim at strengthening corporate governance and supervisory board autonomy in Ukraine. The Council also emphasized its support for speedy energy sector reforms.</p>
<p>The Council reaffirmed the importance of advancing transparent, integrated, and competitive energy markets in the Western Balkans, and associated market and regulatory reforms, in line with the EU enlargement policy and obligations under the Energy Community Treaty. The</p>
<p>Council confirmed the importance of the decarbonization of the Western Balkans and integration of their electricity markets with the EU neighboring electricity market. The Council should continue coordination on energy market and regulatory reforms and support for decarbonization in the Western Balkans, in particular to phase out unabated coal for power generation and inefficient fossil fuel subsidies. The Council also underlined the need to ensure the security of energy supply, notably through access to alternative supply sources. The Council welcomed the adoption of the Clean Energy Package and Decarbonisation Roadmap by the Energy Community, encouraged their speedy implementation, and acknowledged the importance of supporting the development of the region’s potential participation in renewable energy supply chains. The Council also emphasized the importance of close U.S.-EU coordination to foster regional cooperation.</p>
<p><strong>Energy Policy, Technology, and Innovation for a Clean and Just Energy Transition</strong></p>
<p>The Council underlined the importance of energy cooperation in research and innovation that supports global efforts towards achieving net-zero emissions by 2050 by offering policy and technological solutions that are aligned with the climate objectives of the Paris Agreement.</p>
<p>The EU and the United States share objectives to reduce methane emissions from all fossil fuels and along the entire supply chain. In this respect, the Council acknowledged successful EU-U.S. leadership in launching the Global Methane Pledge at the 26th Conference of the Parties (COP26) of the UN Climate Change Conference. The Council intends to initiate work on a common tool for life cycle analysis (LCA) of methane emissions for hydrocarbon suppliers that will advance global efforts to move towards consistency and accuracy of the measurement, reporting and verification of greenhouse gas emissions from the production of hydrocarbons and support improved reporting on methane in national greenhouse gas inventories. The International Methane Emissions Observatory will act as a key data collector and a validator to enhance methane measurement in alignment with the OGMP 2.0 standard. The EU and the United States plan to cooperate in the development of more uniform international methane emissions testing methodologies by bringing together centers of expertise in metrology.</p>
<p>The Council acknowledged the role that clean and renewable hydrogen will play in decarbonizing our energy systems. To that end, the Council expressed support for leveraging the bilateral relationship through multilateral engagement to advance work on hydrogen of this type including on codes, standards and certification, and regulatory frameworks, research and technology innovation, setting the foundation for open and resilient global hydrogen markets. The EU and the United States intend to explore engagement with the private sector on this topic. The Council noted the importance of coordinating and streamlining the work of different international initiatives on hydrogen.</p>
<p>The Council recognized the 2021 joint U.S.-EU Energy Council Energy Efficiency in Buildings Webinar Series, which emphasized the need for further efforts such as Mission Innovation and the International Energy Agency’s Energy in Buildings and Communities Programme that address energy efficiency and carbon performance of the buildings and construction sector, both domestically and internationally.</p>
<p>The United States and the EU consider that onshore and offshore wind power are key technologies for clean power generation. The Council announced planning for the third High-Level Business to Business Forum under the U.S.-EU Energy Council in 2022, which will focus on offshore wind, and looked forward to receiving a report on the event.</p>
<p>The Council emphasized that decarbonization efforts must be matched by adequate efforts to ensure a just and socially inclusive energy transition that leaves no one behind. To this end, a holistic approach is required to tackle energy poverty and support transitioning communities. Ahead, during, and after key international milestones, such as COP27, the EU and the United States are exchanging information on experiences regarding just transition and how to advance international cooperation. The Council noted that a roadmap with possible joint actions in 2022 should be prepared.</p>
<p><strong>Complementary Progress in Other Fora</strong></p>
<p>The Council acknowledged progress on multilateral and other bilateral initiatives and expressed its intent to discuss and coordinate positions ahead of major multilateral events. The strong EU-U.S. relationship has paved the way for more ambitious global climate and energy actions notably at COP26, G7, G20, International Energy Agency, Clean Energy Ministerial, Mission Innovation, the Partnership for Transatlantic Energy and Climate Cooperation (P-TECC), International Renewable Energy Agency, and in fusion through both the ITER international agreement and EURATOM research. The Council also welcomed the work of other U.S.-EU bilateral platforms, including the newly established Trade and Technology Council, which demonstrate both partners’ overall commitment to reaching net-zero emissions and increase access and availability of clean energy technologies. The United States and the EU plan to coordinate their efforts in support of third countries to promote relevant market and regulatory reforms to ensure robust decarbonization efforts, a swift, just and socially inclusive energy transition to a climate-neutral future, and to address energy poverty including in Africa. The Council reiterated the United States and EU’s commitment to provide trusted connections by promoting an infrastructure development globally that is high-standard, transparent, and climate resilient, through U.S., EU, regional, and multilateral initiatives including Build Back Better World and the Global Gateway.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Government of the United States of America and the European Union on the occasion of the ninth meeting of the U.S.-EU Energy Council.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>The ninth United States &#8211; European Union Energy Council (“Council”) met today in Washington, D.C., chaired by U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken, U.S. Secretary of Energy Jennifer M. Granholm, EU High Representative/Vice President Josep Borrell Fontelles, and European Energy Commissioner Kadri Simson. The Ambassador of France to the United States Philippe Etienne represented the Presidency of the Council of the European Union (EU). As reconfirmed in the June 15, 2021 EU-U.S. Summit Statement, the U.S.-EU Energy Council is the lead transatlantic coordination forum on strategic energy issues. The Council built on the work announced by President von der Leyen and President Biden on U.S.-EU cooperation on energy security in their Joint Statement of 28 January 2022.</p>
<p>Mindful of the rapidly changing energy landscape and the continued risks to energy security, including cybersecurity of energy infrastructure, the U.S.-EU Energy Council works to enhance energy security and promote energy diversification. The parties emphasized that accelerating the just energy transition to a net-zero future will support the mitigation of energy market fluctuations and facilitate access to affordable and reliable energy. The Council discussed the urgency for action to address the gas supply situation in Europe and to ensure gas supply to Ukraine.</p>
<p>The United States and the EU each underlined their commitment to reaching net-zero emissions by 2050 and to working together to ensure a rapid decarbonization and clean energy transition, and to promote increasing investments in related technologies. Accordingly, the Council reiterated the need to phase out unabated coal for power generation and inefficient fossil fuel subsidies without delay. The Council also works to accelerate a just energy transition to climate neutrality for citizens of the EU, the United States, and around the globe, and to promote research and development, innovation and deployment in related fields.</p>
<p><strong>Bolstering Energy Security in the EU and its neighborhood, including in Ukraine and the Western Balkans</strong></p>
<p>The Council reaffirmed the importance of the United States and EU working together on our mutual net-zero energy transition as countries increase their climate ambitions to ensure that consumers have secure access to affordable and reliable energy. The EU and the United States affirmed their commitment to proactively cooperate to address any potential risks related to energy supply in the EU and its neighborhood. This cooperation endeavors to focus on avoiding energy and resource supply disruptions and improving diversification of energy suppliers, fuel types in line with our net-zero targets, and means of transport. The Council underlined that competitive and transparent global energy markets remain critical to ensuring a reliable, affordable, and secure energy supply for Europe. As we address geopolitical and climate impacts on current energy markets, the EU and the United States intend to work together so that global liquefied natural gas markets have the capacity to provide additional and diversified supplies in case of pipeline gas disruptions in the short term as countries move away from fossil fuels and towards a sustainable net-zero future. The EU and the United States also recognize the growing cyber related threats to energy infrastructure and plan to continue related cooperation including in the context of the synchronization of the Baltic States’ electricity networks with the Continental European Network.</p>
<p>The Council reiterated that it is unacceptable to use energy supply as a weapon or geopolitical lever. This conviction underpinned the Council&#8217;s support for enhancing the resilience and energy security of Eastern partners, such as the Republic of Moldova and Ukraine, including through reverse gas flows. Recognizing current geopolitical tensions, the United States and the EU discussed intensifying cooperation in the short-term to ensure sufficient energy supplies for the EU and its neighborhood.</p>
<p>The Council affirmed that Ukraine continues to be a key partner of both the EU and the United States and expressed firm support for a strong and resilient Ukraine. It emphasized that energy security is vital to a sovereign Ukraine. The Council reiterated that Ukraine is a strategic gas transit country for the EU and should continue to promote the integration of Ukraine into the EU’s energy market, with the goal of improving Ukraine’s energy security, accelerating its decarbonization and clean energy transition, and enhancing its potential for clean energy exports. The Council expressed continued support for exploring new gas transit routes and capacity from the EU to Ukraine. The Council emphasized the importance of continuing to support the synchronization process of the electricity networks of Ukraine and the Republic of Moldova with the Continental European Network. The Council dedicated itself to new efforts to invest in and support Ukraine’s decarbonization efforts and relevant infrastructure.</p>
<p>The Council reaffirmed the need for transparent, robust, and independent institutions in Ukraine&#8217;s energy sector, in particular the energy market regulatory authorities and financial markets authorities, including the State Nuclear Regulatory Inspectorate of Ukraine. It highlighted that strong corporate governance and supervisory board autonomy without political interference are fundamental components to national energy security. As we are moving towards Ukraine’s integration with the European energy market, we will aim at strengthening corporate governance and supervisory board autonomy in Ukraine. The Council also emphasized its support for speedy energy sector reforms.</p>
<p>The Council reaffirmed the importance of advancing transparent, integrated, and competitive energy markets in the Western Balkans, and associated market and regulatory reforms, in line with the EU enlargement policy and obligations under the Energy Community Treaty. The</p>
<p>Council confirmed the importance of the decarbonization of the Western Balkans and integration of their electricity markets with the EU neighboring electricity market. The Council should continue coordination on energy market and regulatory reforms and support for decarbonization in the Western Balkans, in particular to phase out unabated coal for power generation and inefficient fossil fuel subsidies. The Council also underlined the need to ensure the security of energy supply, notably through access to alternative supply sources. The Council welcomed the adoption of the Clean Energy Package and Decarbonisation Roadmap by the Energy Community, encouraged their speedy implementation, and acknowledged the importance of supporting the development of the region’s potential participation in renewable energy supply chains. The Council also emphasized the importance of close U.S.-EU coordination to foster regional cooperation.</p>
<p><strong>Energy Policy, Technology, and Innovation for a Clean and Just Energy Transition</strong></p>
<p>The Council underlined the importance of energy cooperation in research and innovation that supports global efforts towards achieving net-zero emissions by 2050 by offering policy and technological solutions that are aligned with the climate objectives of the Paris Agreement.</p>
<p>The EU and the United States share objectives to reduce methane emissions from all fossil fuels and along the entire supply chain. In this respect, the Council acknowledged successful EU-U.S. leadership in launching the Global Methane Pledge at the 26th Conference of the Parties (COP26) of the UN Climate Change Conference. The Council intends to initiate work on a common tool for life cycle analysis (LCA) of methane emissions for hydrocarbon suppliers that will advance global efforts to move towards consistency and accuracy of the measurement, reporting and verification of greenhouse gas emissions from the production of hydrocarbons and support improved reporting on methane in national greenhouse gas inventories. The International Methane Emissions Observatory will act as a key data collector and a validator to enhance methane measurement in alignment with the OGMP 2.0 standard. The EU and the United States plan to cooperate in the development of more uniform international methane emissions testing methodologies by bringing together centers of expertise in metrology.</p>
<p>The Council acknowledged the role that clean and renewable hydrogen will play in decarbonizing our energy systems. To that end, the Council expressed support for leveraging the bilateral relationship through multilateral engagement to advance work on hydrogen of this type including on codes, standards and certification, and regulatory frameworks, research and technology innovation, setting the foundation for open and resilient global hydrogen markets. The EU and the United States intend to explore engagement with the private sector on this topic. The Council noted the importance of coordinating and streamlining the work of different international initiatives on hydrogen.</p>
<p>The Council recognized the 2021 joint U.S.-EU Energy Council Energy Efficiency in Buildings Webinar Series, which emphasized the need for further efforts such as Mission Innovation and the International Energy Agency’s Energy in Buildings and Communities Programme that address energy efficiency and carbon performance of the buildings and construction sector, both domestically and internationally.</p>
<p>The United States and the EU consider that onshore and offshore wind power are key technologies for clean power generation. The Council announced planning for the third High-Level Business to Business Forum under the U.S.-EU Energy Council in 2022, which will focus on offshore wind, and looked forward to receiving a report on the event.</p>
<p>The Council emphasized that decarbonization efforts must be matched by adequate efforts to ensure a just and socially inclusive energy transition that leaves no one behind. To this end, a holistic approach is required to tackle energy poverty and support transitioning communities. Ahead, during, and after key international milestones, such as COP27, the EU and the United States are exchanging information on experiences regarding just transition and how to advance international cooperation. The Council noted that a roadmap with possible joint actions in 2022 should be prepared.</p>
<p><strong>Complementary Progress in Other Fora</strong></p>
<p>The Council acknowledged progress on multilateral and other bilateral initiatives and expressed its intent to discuss and coordinate positions ahead of major multilateral events. The strong EU-U.S. relationship has paved the way for more ambitious global climate and energy actions notably at COP26, G7, G20, International Energy Agency, Clean Energy Ministerial, Mission Innovation, the Partnership for Transatlantic Energy and Climate Cooperation (P-TECC), International Renewable Energy Agency, and in fusion through both the ITER international agreement and EURATOM research. The Council also welcomed the work of other U.S.-EU bilateral platforms, including the newly established Trade and Technology Council, which demonstrate both partners’ overall commitment to reaching net-zero emissions and increase access and availability of clean energy technologies. The United States and the EU plan to coordinate their efforts in support of third countries to promote relevant market and regulatory reforms to ensure robust decarbonization efforts, a swift, just and socially inclusive energy transition to a climate-neutral future, and to address energy poverty including in Africa. The Council reiterated the United States and EU’s commitment to provide trusted connections by promoting an infrastructure development globally that is high-standard, transparent, and climate resilient, through U.S., EU, regional, and multilateral initiatives including Build Back Better World and the Global Gateway.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with UK Minister of State for Middle East, North Africa and North America Cleverly</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-uk-minister-of-state-for-middle-east-north-africa-and-north-america-cleverly/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 17:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=311979</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with UK Minister of State for Middle East, North Africa, and North America James Cleverly today in Washington, D.C. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Minister Cleverly discussed continued diplomatic engagement to prevent further Russian aggression against Ukraine, as well as deterrents including sanctions and security assistance to partners and Allies in the region. The two also discussed ongoing UK-EU negotiations to preserve the gains of the Belfast/Good Friday agreement, the PRC’s troubling economic practices, maintaining a free and open Indo-Pacific through the AUKUS trilateral security partnership with Australia, and the importance of ensuring Iran returns to mutual compliance with the JCPOA.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with UK Minister of State for Middle East, North Africa, and North America James Cleverly today in Washington, D.C. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Minister Cleverly discussed continued diplomatic engagement to prevent further Russian aggression against Ukraine, as well as deterrents including sanctions and security assistance to partners and Allies in the region. The two also discussed ongoing UK-EU negotiations to preserve the gains of the Belfast/Good Friday agreement, the PRC’s troubling economic practices, maintaining a free and open Indo-Pacific through the AUKUS trilateral security partnership with Australia, and the importance of ensuring Iran returns to mutual compliance with the JCPOA.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with U.S. Secretary of Energy Jennifer Granholm, EU High Representative for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy and Vice President of the European Commission Josep Borrell, and European Commissioner for Energy Kadri Simson at the U.S.-EU Energy Council Ministerial</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-u-s-secretary-of-energy-jennifer-granholm-eu-high-representative-for-foreign-affairs-and-security-policy-and-vice-president-of-the-european-commission-josep-borrell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 17:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=311962</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good morning, everyone, and welcome.  It’s wonderful to have our colleagues here.  High Representative Borrell, Josep, so wonderful as always to be with you, to see you.  Commissioner Simson, Ambassador Etienne, welcome to you all.  And we are so delighted to welcome you to the State Department for what is a truly critical discussion and one that I think could not be more timely.  We’ve had many engagements, conversations, meetings between the European Union and the United States over the past weeks and months, and Josep and I seem to be on speed dial, either video or telephone, but there is no substitute for actually being together in the same place.  And as I like to say, either face to face or mask to mask, unfortunately, as the case may be.</p>
<p>But the U.S.-EU Energy Council is one of the many mechanisms through which the EU and the U.S. are working together to strengthen our mutually reinforcing strategic relationship.  This partnership more broadly addresses the challenges that we all face and that our people face from ending COVID-19 to dealing with climate change to standing up to threats to democracy.  And it’s an increasingly ambitious partnership with the launch of a new dialogue on security and defense planned for a little bit later this year.</p>
<p>A moment like this demonstrates why this relationship is so vital to transatlantic and, indeed, to global security.  At precisely the time Europe most needs a stable energy supply to get people through the winter, Russia has attempted to increase its energy leverage.  As the International Energy Agency has noted, Russia’s state-owned companies are currently holding back natural gas supplies, the same supplies that could ease the record high prices the European people are currently facing.  As a result, we see people rationing the gas they use for heating, some skipping even a daily hot shower or cooking food in bulk to lower their bills.  And some small businesses are considering shutting doors because of high energy costs.</p>
<p>President Biden has pledged the United States will do everything we can to help ease any disruptions to Europe’s energy supply and, indeed, we already are.  In the short term, we’re in discussions with governments and major producers around the world about surging natural gas capacity, and the market itself is adjusting.  These efforts are aimed at shoring up energy supply throughout Europe, including Ukraine, whose energy security is particularly threatened by Russian aggression.</p>
<p>The United States is grateful to the European Union and its readiness to support projects that will allow gas to enter Ukraine from Europe and we’re prepared to help those efforts through both our diplomacy as well as technical expertise.  We’re also supporting Ukraine’s efforts to connect with the European electricity grid, an initiative to which we have contributed more than $138 million in recent years.  Ukraine’s grid is now ready and we’re hopeful it may soon be able to connect to Europe’s grid.</p>
<p>Even as we address current challenges, we’re also focused on the essential longer-term goal of accelerating the clean energy transition so that we can meet our net zero emissions targets and prevent a climate catastrophe.  Here too we’ve been working hand in hand, the United States and Europe.  And perhaps nowhere can we see the power of the U.S.-EU clean energy collaboration better than in the Western Balkans.  For years, the United States has supported efforts at connecting the energy grids of the Western Balkans with those of the European Union’s to speed up the transition away from coal and other fossil fuels.  Over that same time, the EU has provided grants and investments to help develop the Western Balkans energy grids, including most recently through the Green Agenda Action Plan.</p>
<p>We’ve seen the difference that these efforts have helped make.  Albania and Kosovo have established a common electricity market, renewable energy generation has skyrocketed, countries across the region are now diversifying how they get their energy.</p>
<p>So whether it’s confronting the immediate energy challenge or accelerating the clean energy transition, the partnership between us is critical and it grows stronger and stronger.  I’m looking forward to the discussions today for how we can build on the progress we have made and explore new areas for cooperation so that we can continue to enhance the collective security and prosperity for all of our people.</p>
<p>And again, welcome.  It’s wonderful to have you here.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:  </b>Secretary Blinken, Secretary Granholm, Commissioner, Ambassador Etienne, we come here today in an environment characterized by geopolitical turbulence, particularly in the eastern neighborhood of Europe.  And while we meet under the gathering storm cloud, our discussions take a greater relevance.  And we need to reassure people that our joint endeavor will make them safer now and more energy secure in the future.</p>
<p>I think that we have to send a strong message to show determination to bolster energy security for Europe and for our direct neighbors in Ukraine and in the Western Balkans.  So thank you for the extraordinary positive cooperation in our transatlantic relation that has becoming stronger.  You participate in our Foreign Affairs Council and we are doing with NATO and OSCE a lot, and we have the hope that these challenges will be overcome.</p>
<p>We are on the midst of a strong diplomatic crisis with Russia.  Russia don’t hesitate on using the energy supplies to Europe as weapon for geopolitical gain in the middle of a surge of energy prices worldwide.  We have been calling Russia to de-escalate and we are deploying a new mainly diplomatic effort to convince Russia to choose the path of dialogue, and this must continue.  But at the same time, we have to be clear all together that any further aggression against Ukraine would have massive consequences and severe costs in response, and we know how deep have we been working on this response.</p>
<p>We have also reached our major energy suppliers in order to boost our preparedness and to ensure the energy supply remains reliable, affordable, and secure not just for us, for the European Union, for our neighbors too, for Ukraine, Moldova, and the Western Balkans.  I think that this an important point in the agenda today.</p>
<p>At the same time, the situation has highlighted the need for Europe and the rest of the world to diversify energy supplies, and this is where our strategic cooperation on security comes in.  I think that our starting point today is that clean energy transition is now irreversible.  These are those who wish to slow it down – there are people who say well, in the current circumstances you better – to save the world can wait a couple of years.  No.  No.  In light of the climate emergency, we have to accelerate it and we want the transition to be just globally and inside our societies, because if it is not just it will not happen.</p>
<p>I think that also an excessive focus on the immediate needs risk distracting us from the bigger picture, because reliable, affordable and secure energy can only come from a decarbonized energy based largely on renewables.  We are far away of the objective of reaching 2 degrees, let alone 1.5 degrees with a worth – with a world still depending on fossil fuels for more than three quarters of its energy needs – three quarters – and with 600 million African people that have never seen (inaudible), and they need more energy.  So in a world where we have to increase the energy production to fit the needs of many people, we have to take massive urgent action to advance the transition to clean and renewable energies.</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s where our cooperation on climate is stronger – should be stronger than ever, and this Energy Council is a good opportunity to ensure that the ambitious transatlantic agenda agreed in COP26 will bring tangible results.  The Global Methane Pledge is a good example, initiated together, putting the methane squarely in the global climate agenda.  So thank you very much for this discussion.  I am looking forward for a lot of engagement from this meeting.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you, Josep.  Secretary Granholm.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:  </b>Thank you so much, High Representative Borrell.  Great words.  Secretary Blinken and I are really delighted to be able to welcome you and Commissioner Simson to Washington for what I think is a long overdue meeting of the U.S.-EU Energy Council.  I think it’s worth acknowledging that 30 years ago today, 12 European nations joined together to sign the Maastricht Treaty – if I&#8217;m pronouncing that right – and formed the foundation for the European Union.  And over the last three decades, the U.S. and the European Union obviously have nurtured this very fruitful relationship that&#8217;s proved to better the entire world&#8217;s wellbeing.  And so over the next three decades, I think few things will have greater impact on the world than how we leverage this relationship on energy matters, clean energy matters specifically.</p>
<p>So this ministerial arrives at a unique and a timely moment for all of us.  Obviously, high energy prices have been putting a strain on households on both sides of the Atlantic.  Europe, you have seen prices go through the roof.  Of course, tensions between Russia and Ukraine pose threats to the energy security of the European Union and our friends and partners.  And all of this, to your point, underscores the benefits of clean energy.  I was at a ministerial last week and the – my counterpart in Ireland, Minister Ryan, said words that I thought were very interesting: no country has been held hostage to access to the sun; no country has been hostage to the wind.  This is not just an energy and climate issue – it also is potentially the greatest peace plan that ever existed to be able to build out energy independence from clean energy.</p>
<p>So the faster we move, the faster we complete the clean energy transition, the faster we&#8217;ll be able to deliver more affordable energy, more diverse energy, more reliable power, and true energy independence, and therefore security – not to mention, obviously, the jobs and the economic growth that we’ll generate along the way.  So the President, President Biden, believes that greater collaboration with our European partners is essential to speeding our transition from both countries to clean energy.  In the last year, our teams have worked together on clean hydrogen, on energy efficiency, and on reductions in methane emissions.</p>
<p>The U.S. is obviously eager to deepen those partnerships on a variety of clean energy technologies.  I really look forward today to discussing a couple of things.  One, obviously, developing on the methane component, developing a common tool for the lifecycle analysis of methane emissions from hydrocarbons and more uniform testing methodologies for those emissions; second, to deepen our cooperation between our technical experts and researchers and scientists so we can maximize the impact of at least our national laboratories and the joint research centers; third, to deploy clean energy supplies in a manner that lifts communities up and leaves no one behind; and then to advocate as well for even more ambition, ambitious innovation, and climate action through multilateral fora, including the Clean Energy Ministerial and Mission Innovation.</p>
<p>So progress toward our net zero goals is going to unlock faster pathways to decarbonization all over the world, and of course, everyone benefits when we work together.  So I encourage staff to move forward with the planning for the U.S.-EU Energy Council High-Level Business Forum, and in the meantime, I look forward to a fruitful meeting with my colleagues.  And with that, I&#8217;m delighted, I think, if I can, turn it over to Commissioner Simson.</p>
<p><b>COMMISSIONER SIMSON:</b>  Thank you.  And dear colleagues, it is a pleasure to be here in Washington at a time that is crucial both for – both of us in the energy policy perspective.  And Jennifer Granholm knows very well that I have been working to organize this meeting since we first met, and this was already more than a year ago, so – because this council has always been the engine of progress in the transatlantic energy cooperation.  And I believe that today, more than ever, a strong partnership between the EU and United States is needed to promote our energy security and to drive forward the global energy transition.</p>
<p>In Europe, we are facing high energy prices driven by volatile gas markets and by tensions between Ukraine and Russia, and today’s situation is also exposing some structural challenges which we can address better if we work together.  First, high price volatility shows that the energy transition is not a linear process but a road with ups and downs, and working jointly we can better stay the course.</p>
<p>Despite high prices, we must preserve the public’s trust and support for the clean energy transition.  In the EU, we call it the European Green Deal.  There is a set of legislative initiatives waiting to be finalized both here in United States but also in Europe.  And together, the EU and U.S. can show that the clean energy technologies are competitive, create new jobs, and can benefit all territories and regions in a just transition.  And we can work jointly to scale up markets for renewables, create opportunities for industry like in offshore wind, and bring down the costs of the most innovative and promising technologies like clean hydrogen or small modular reactors.  And we can lead the way at global level as we did with the Global Methane Pledge to reduce methane emissions where now more than 100 countries have joined.</p>
<p>Secondly, this council will mark another milestone in our partnership for energy security in Europe.  Despite a decades-long effort for diversification of gas routes, we are very much aware that our gas market is still too dependent on one single supplier and that we need to continue to prioritize diversification not only for Europe but also for Ukraine and our partners in the neighborhood.  And while we are seeking to reduce the dependency on one single supplier, we naturally turn to U.S., our largest LNG supplier and reliable partner.  And I am confident that today we can follow up on the joint statement of President Biden and President von der Leyen and identify ways to sustain strong U.S. LNG exports to Europe in the coming months.</p>
<p>We can also better align our actions to support Ukraine in this critical moment and coordinate our help for the clean energy transition and the infrastructure development of the Western Balkan countries.  On all these subjects, strong cooperation can make a big difference.  The U.S. is our closest ally, and as we face geopolitical tensions and the challenge of the climate change we need more, not less, transatlantic cooperation.</p>
<p>So I very much look forward to this council and to our exchanges.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Commissioner, thank you very much.</p>
<p>Philippe, (in French).</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR ETIENNE:</b>  Thank you, Secretary.  Thank you, thank you, secretaries, High Commissioner, Commissioner, dear colleagues.  I am pleased to join you for this meeting on behalf of the French presidency of the Council of the European Union.  The EU-U.S. Energy Council has taken on a highly symbolic and strategic quality in the current geostrategic context and for our transatlantic partnership.</p>
<p>Cooperation between the EU and the U.S. is essential to speeding up the fair and clean energy transition which will move us closer to climate neutrality for all the world’s citizens.  Our cooperation will also help us to ensure our energy security.  That is also the spirit of the statement that was made by the President of the United States and the president of France in Rome in the margins of the G20.  The U.S. and the European Union have confirmed in the recent joint statement of President Biden and President von der Leyen that they are committed to Europe’s energy security and sustainability and to accelerating the global transition to clean energy.</p>
<p>We can consider different ways of ensuring the security of Europe’s natural gas supply while also recognizing the sovereignty and security of our partners in our neighborhood.  The situation around Ukraine reminds us this strategic challenge and the importance of the cooperation with the U.S., keeping also in mind that the most effective response in the immediate term is to focus on the energy transition and reduce our dependence on fossil fuels.</p>
<p>One of the top priorities of the French presidency of the EU is the decarbonization of our economies and the negotiation of an important legislative package proposed by the European Commission which will outline the path to achieve our goal of reducing greenhouse gas emissions by 55 percent by 2030.  Thanks to cooperation between the EU and the U.S., we can combine efforts to help develop clean energy, supporting new technology.  One such example is hydrogen, a source that will play a growing role in the decarbonization of energy systems, and also in fields where decarbonization is difficult, such as industrial transportation.</p>
<p>Thank you, Secretary, for having given me the floor.  I appreciate very much and be sure that the French presidency of the Council of the EU is delighted to take part to this important meeting, especially in those days during our presidency.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Philippe, thank you very much, and I think now we will start the discussion focusing first on energy security, and I’m happy to kick that off.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good morning, everyone, and welcome.  It’s wonderful to have our colleagues here.  High Representative Borrell, Josep, so wonderful as always to be with you, to see you.  Commissioner Simson, Ambassador Etienne, welcome to you all.  And we are so delighted to welcome you to the State Department for what is a truly critical discussion and one that I think could not be more timely.  We’ve had many engagements, conversations, meetings between the European Union and the United States over the past weeks and months, and Josep and I seem to be on speed dial, either video or telephone, but there is no substitute for actually being together in the same place.  And as I like to say, either face to face or mask to mask, unfortunately, as the case may be.</p>
<p>But the U.S.-EU Energy Council is one of the many mechanisms through which the EU and the U.S. are working together to strengthen our mutually reinforcing strategic relationship.  This partnership more broadly addresses the challenges that we all face and that our people face from ending COVID-19 to dealing with climate change to standing up to threats to democracy.  And it’s an increasingly ambitious partnership with the launch of a new dialogue on security and defense planned for a little bit later this year.</p>
<p>A moment like this demonstrates why this relationship is so vital to transatlantic and, indeed, to global security.  At precisely the time Europe most needs a stable energy supply to get people through the winter, Russia has attempted to increase its energy leverage.  As the International Energy Agency has noted, Russia’s state-owned companies are currently holding back natural gas supplies, the same supplies that could ease the record high prices the European people are currently facing.  As a result, we see people rationing the gas they use for heating, some skipping even a daily hot shower or cooking food in bulk to lower their bills.  And some small businesses are considering shutting doors because of high energy costs.</p>
<p>President Biden has pledged the United States will do everything we can to help ease any disruptions to Europe’s energy supply and, indeed, we already are.  In the short term, we’re in discussions with governments and major producers around the world about surging natural gas capacity, and the market itself is adjusting.  These efforts are aimed at shoring up energy supply throughout Europe, including Ukraine, whose energy security is particularly threatened by Russian aggression.</p>
<p>The United States is grateful to the European Union and its readiness to support projects that will allow gas to enter Ukraine from Europe and we’re prepared to help those efforts through both our diplomacy as well as technical expertise.  We’re also supporting Ukraine’s efforts to connect with the European electricity grid, an initiative to which we have contributed more than $138 million in recent years.  Ukraine’s grid is now ready and we’re hopeful it may soon be able to connect to Europe’s grid.</p>
<p>Even as we address current challenges, we’re also focused on the essential longer-term goal of accelerating the clean energy transition so that we can meet our net zero emissions targets and prevent a climate catastrophe.  Here too we’ve been working hand in hand, the United States and Europe.  And perhaps nowhere can we see the power of the U.S.-EU clean energy collaboration better than in the Western Balkans.  For years, the United States has supported efforts at connecting the energy grids of the Western Balkans with those of the European Union’s to speed up the transition away from coal and other fossil fuels.  Over that same time, the EU has provided grants and investments to help develop the Western Balkans energy grids, including most recently through the Green Agenda Action Plan.</p>
<p>We’ve seen the difference that these efforts have helped make.  Albania and Kosovo have established a common electricity market, renewable energy generation has skyrocketed, countries across the region are now diversifying how they get their energy.</p>
<p>So whether it’s confronting the immediate energy challenge or accelerating the clean energy transition, the partnership between us is critical and it grows stronger and stronger.  I’m looking forward to the discussions today for how we can build on the progress we have made and explore new areas for cooperation so that we can continue to enhance the collective security and prosperity for all of our people.</p>
<p>And again, welcome.  It’s wonderful to have you here.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:  </b>Secretary Blinken, Secretary Granholm, Commissioner, Ambassador Etienne, we come here today in an environment characterized by geopolitical turbulence, particularly in the eastern neighborhood of Europe.  And while we meet under the gathering storm cloud, our discussions take a greater relevance.  And we need to reassure people that our joint endeavor will make them safer now and more energy secure in the future.</p>
<p>I think that we have to send a strong message to show determination to bolster energy security for Europe and for our direct neighbors in Ukraine and in the Western Balkans.  So thank you for the extraordinary positive cooperation in our transatlantic relation that has becoming stronger.  You participate in our Foreign Affairs Council and we are doing with NATO and OSCE a lot, and we have the hope that these challenges will be overcome.</p>
<p>We are on the midst of a strong diplomatic crisis with Russia.  Russia don’t hesitate on using the energy supplies to Europe as weapon for geopolitical gain in the middle of a surge of energy prices worldwide.  We have been calling Russia to de-escalate and we are deploying a new mainly diplomatic effort to convince Russia to choose the path of dialogue, and this must continue.  But at the same time, we have to be clear all together that any further aggression against Ukraine would have massive consequences and severe costs in response, and we know how deep have we been working on this response.</p>
<p>We have also reached our major energy suppliers in order to boost our preparedness and to ensure the energy supply remains reliable, affordable, and secure not just for us, for the European Union, for our neighbors too, for Ukraine, Moldova, and the Western Balkans.  I think that this an important point in the agenda today.</p>
<p>At the same time, the situation has highlighted the need for Europe and the rest of the world to diversify energy supplies, and this is where our strategic cooperation on security comes in.  I think that our starting point today is that clean energy transition is now irreversible.  These are those who wish to slow it down – there are people who say well, in the current circumstances you better – to save the world can wait a couple of years.  No.  No.  In light of the climate emergency, we have to accelerate it and we want the transition to be just globally and inside our societies, because if it is not just it will not happen.</p>
<p>I think that also an excessive focus on the immediate needs risk distracting us from the bigger picture, because reliable, affordable and secure energy can only come from a decarbonized energy based largely on renewables.  We are far away of the objective of reaching 2 degrees, let alone 1.5 degrees with a worth – with a world still depending on fossil fuels for more than three quarters of its energy needs – three quarters – and with 600 million African people that have never seen (inaudible), and they need more energy.  So in a world where we have to increase the energy production to fit the needs of many people, we have to take massive urgent action to advance the transition to clean and renewable energies.</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s where our cooperation on climate is stronger – should be stronger than ever, and this Energy Council is a good opportunity to ensure that the ambitious transatlantic agenda agreed in COP26 will bring tangible results.  The Global Methane Pledge is a good example, initiated together, putting the methane squarely in the global climate agenda.  So thank you very much for this discussion.  I am looking forward for a lot of engagement from this meeting.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you, Josep.  Secretary Granholm.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:  </b>Thank you so much, High Representative Borrell.  Great words.  Secretary Blinken and I are really delighted to be able to welcome you and Commissioner Simson to Washington for what I think is a long overdue meeting of the U.S.-EU Energy Council.  I think it’s worth acknowledging that 30 years ago today, 12 European nations joined together to sign the Maastricht Treaty – if I&#8217;m pronouncing that right – and formed the foundation for the European Union.  And over the last three decades, the U.S. and the European Union obviously have nurtured this very fruitful relationship that&#8217;s proved to better the entire world&#8217;s wellbeing.  And so over the next three decades, I think few things will have greater impact on the world than how we leverage this relationship on energy matters, clean energy matters specifically.</p>
<p>So this ministerial arrives at a unique and a timely moment for all of us.  Obviously, high energy prices have been putting a strain on households on both sides of the Atlantic.  Europe, you have seen prices go through the roof.  Of course, tensions between Russia and Ukraine pose threats to the energy security of the European Union and our friends and partners.  And all of this, to your point, underscores the benefits of clean energy.  I was at a ministerial last week and the – my counterpart in Ireland, Minister Ryan, said words that I thought were very interesting: no country has been held hostage to access to the sun; no country has been hostage to the wind.  This is not just an energy and climate issue – it also is potentially the greatest peace plan that ever existed to be able to build out energy independence from clean energy.</p>
<p>So the faster we move, the faster we complete the clean energy transition, the faster we&#8217;ll be able to deliver more affordable energy, more diverse energy, more reliable power, and true energy independence, and therefore security – not to mention, obviously, the jobs and the economic growth that we’ll generate along the way.  So the President, President Biden, believes that greater collaboration with our European partners is essential to speeding our transition from both countries to clean energy.  In the last year, our teams have worked together on clean hydrogen, on energy efficiency, and on reductions in methane emissions.</p>
<p>The U.S. is obviously eager to deepen those partnerships on a variety of clean energy technologies.  I really look forward today to discussing a couple of things.  One, obviously, developing on the methane component, developing a common tool for the lifecycle analysis of methane emissions from hydrocarbons and more uniform testing methodologies for those emissions; second, to deepen our cooperation between our technical experts and researchers and scientists so we can maximize the impact of at least our national laboratories and the joint research centers; third, to deploy clean energy supplies in a manner that lifts communities up and leaves no one behind; and then to advocate as well for even more ambition, ambitious innovation, and climate action through multilateral fora, including the Clean Energy Ministerial and Mission Innovation.</p>
<p>So progress toward our net zero goals is going to unlock faster pathways to decarbonization all over the world, and of course, everyone benefits when we work together.  So I encourage staff to move forward with the planning for the U.S.-EU Energy Council High-Level Business Forum, and in the meantime, I look forward to a fruitful meeting with my colleagues.  And with that, I&#8217;m delighted, I think, if I can, turn it over to Commissioner Simson.</p>
<p><b>COMMISSIONER SIMSON:</b>  Thank you.  And dear colleagues, it is a pleasure to be here in Washington at a time that is crucial both for – both of us in the energy policy perspective.  And Jennifer Granholm knows very well that I have been working to organize this meeting since we first met, and this was already more than a year ago, so – because this council has always been the engine of progress in the transatlantic energy cooperation.  And I believe that today, more than ever, a strong partnership between the EU and United States is needed to promote our energy security and to drive forward the global energy transition.</p>
<p>In Europe, we are facing high energy prices driven by volatile gas markets and by tensions between Ukraine and Russia, and today’s situation is also exposing some structural challenges which we can address better if we work together.  First, high price volatility shows that the energy transition is not a linear process but a road with ups and downs, and working jointly we can better stay the course.</p>
<p>Despite high prices, we must preserve the public’s trust and support for the clean energy transition.  In the EU, we call it the European Green Deal.  There is a set of legislative initiatives waiting to be finalized both here in United States but also in Europe.  And together, the EU and U.S. can show that the clean energy technologies are competitive, create new jobs, and can benefit all territories and regions in a just transition.  And we can work jointly to scale up markets for renewables, create opportunities for industry like in offshore wind, and bring down the costs of the most innovative and promising technologies like clean hydrogen or small modular reactors.  And we can lead the way at global level as we did with the Global Methane Pledge to reduce methane emissions where now more than 100 countries have joined.</p>
<p>Secondly, this council will mark another milestone in our partnership for energy security in Europe.  Despite a decades-long effort for diversification of gas routes, we are very much aware that our gas market is still too dependent on one single supplier and that we need to continue to prioritize diversification not only for Europe but also for Ukraine and our partners in the neighborhood.  And while we are seeking to reduce the dependency on one single supplier, we naturally turn to U.S., our largest LNG supplier and reliable partner.  And I am confident that today we can follow up on the joint statement of President Biden and President von der Leyen and identify ways to sustain strong U.S. LNG exports to Europe in the coming months.</p>
<p>We can also better align our actions to support Ukraine in this critical moment and coordinate our help for the clean energy transition and the infrastructure development of the Western Balkan countries.  On all these subjects, strong cooperation can make a big difference.  The U.S. is our closest ally, and as we face geopolitical tensions and the challenge of the climate change we need more, not less, transatlantic cooperation.</p>
<p>So I very much look forward to this council and to our exchanges.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Commissioner, thank you very much.</p>
<p>Philippe, (in French).</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR ETIENNE:</b>  Thank you, Secretary.  Thank you, thank you, secretaries, High Commissioner, Commissioner, dear colleagues.  I am pleased to join you for this meeting on behalf of the French presidency of the Council of the European Union.  The EU-U.S. Energy Council has taken on a highly symbolic and strategic quality in the current geostrategic context and for our transatlantic partnership.</p>
<p>Cooperation between the EU and the U.S. is essential to speeding up the fair and clean energy transition which will move us closer to climate neutrality for all the world’s citizens.  Our cooperation will also help us to ensure our energy security.  That is also the spirit of the statement that was made by the President of the United States and the president of France in Rome in the margins of the G20.  The U.S. and the European Union have confirmed in the recent joint statement of President Biden and President von der Leyen that they are committed to Europe’s energy security and sustainability and to accelerating the global transition to clean energy.</p>
<p>We can consider different ways of ensuring the security of Europe’s natural gas supply while also recognizing the sovereignty and security of our partners in our neighborhood.  The situation around Ukraine reminds us this strategic challenge and the importance of the cooperation with the U.S., keeping also in mind that the most effective response in the immediate term is to focus on the energy transition and reduce our dependence on fossil fuels.</p>
<p>One of the top priorities of the French presidency of the EU is the decarbonization of our economies and the negotiation of an important legislative package proposed by the European Commission which will outline the path to achieve our goal of reducing greenhouse gas emissions by 55 percent by 2030.  Thanks to cooperation between the EU and the U.S., we can combine efforts to help develop clean energy, supporting new technology.  One such example is hydrogen, a source that will play a growing role in the decarbonization of energy systems, and also in fields where decarbonization is difficult, such as industrial transportation.</p>
<p>Thank you, Secretary, for having given me the floor.  I appreciate very much and be sure that the French presidency of the Council of the EU is delighted to take part to this important meeting, especially in those days during our presidency.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Philippe, thank you very much, and I think now we will start the discussion focusing first on energy security, and I’m happy to kick that off.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ambassador Hussain Travels to Mauritania</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/ambassador-hussain-travels-to-mauritania/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 17:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=311955</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom Rashad Hussain will embark on his first trip abroad to Nouakchott, Mauritania, February 7-9.</p>
<p>On February 9 at the “Making Peace for the World” Conference, Ambassador Hussain will deliver keynote remarks on addressing religious freedom threats around the globe, promoting mutual tolerance and respect, and establishing and maintaining just and equal societies.</p>
<p>During his trip, Ambassador Hussain will also meet with the President of Mauritania, Minister of Islamic Affairs, and Minister of Justice, along with other senior government officials, to discuss religious freedom and other democracy and human rights-related issues.</p>
<p>To keep up with Ambassador Hussain’s travel, follow @IRF_Ambassador and @StateIRF on Twitter. For more information, please contact <a href="mailto:IRFpress@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IRFpress@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom Rashad Hussain will embark on his first trip abroad to Nouakchott, Mauritania, February 7-9.</p>
<p>On February 9 at the “Making Peace for the World” Conference, Ambassador Hussain will deliver keynote remarks on addressing religious freedom threats around the globe, promoting mutual tolerance and respect, and establishing and maintaining just and equal societies.</p>
<p>During his trip, Ambassador Hussain will also meet with the President of Mauritania, Minister of Islamic Affairs, and Minister of Justice, along with other senior government officials, to discuss religious freedom and other democracy and human rights-related issues.</p>
<p>To keep up with Ambassador Hussain’s travel, follow @IRF_Ambassador and @StateIRF on Twitter. For more information, please contact <a href="mailto:IRFpress@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IRFpress@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary Nuland’s Travel to Bogotá, Colombia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-nulands-travel-to-bogota-colombia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 16:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=311947</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland will travel February 7-8 to Bogotá, Colombia, with an interagency delegation to engage with senior Colombian government and law enforcement officials and members of civil society. Under Secretary Nuland and the delegation will participate in the U.S.-Colombia High-Level Strategic Security Dialogue and discuss cooperation to advance regional security, democratic institutions, and economic ties.</p>
<p>Other senior members of the interagency delegation include Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere Affairs Brian A. Nichols, National Security Council Senior Director for the Western Hemisphere Juan S. Gonzalez, Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for the Western Hemisphere Daniel Erikson, and National Intelligence Manager for the Western Hemisphere Jon Stainbrook.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland will travel February 7-8 to Bogotá, Colombia, with an interagency delegation to engage with senior Colombian government and law enforcement officials and members of civil society. Under Secretary Nuland and the delegation will participate in the U.S.-Colombia High-Level Strategic Security Dialogue and discuss cooperation to advance regional security, democratic institutions, and economic ties.</p>
<p>Other senior members of the interagency delegation include Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere Affairs Brian A. Nichols, National Security Council Senior Director for the Western Hemisphere Juan S. Gonzalez, Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for the Western Hemisphere Daniel Erikson, and National Intelligence Manager for the Western Hemisphere Jon Stainbrook.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate Kerry’s Travel to Mexico</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-presidential-envoy-for-climate-kerrys-travel-to-mexico/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 16:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=311936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Mexico City February 9, 2022 to engage with government counterparts and accelerate cooperation on the climate crisis, including opportunities for expanding renewable power generation, creating a sound investment climate, combating methane pollution, transitioning to zero-emissions transportation, and ending deforestation. Secretary Kerry will meet with President Andrés Manuel López Obrador and other government officials.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:ClimateComms@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ClimateComms@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Mexico City February 9, 2022 to engage with government counterparts and accelerate cooperation on the climate crisis, including opportunities for expanding renewable power generation, creating a sound investment climate, combating methane pollution, transitioning to zero-emissions transportation, and ending deforestation. Secretary Kerry will meet with President Andrés Manuel López Obrador and other government officials.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:ClimateComms@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ClimateComms@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grenada Independence Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/grenada-independence-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 14:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=311902</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States, I congratulate the people of Grenada on the 48th anniversary of your independence.</p>
<p>Grenada and the United States share close ties and a strong, steadfast partnership.  We appreciate Grenada’s role in addressing the climate crisis and are proud to work together to improve regional security and advance the health and prosperity of the Caribbean.  Our collaboration with Grenada on education and entrepreneurship helps ensure a more prosperous future for the people of Grenada.  In the year ahead, we look forward to the inauguration of two emergency operations centers in Grenada and Carriacou that will support Grenada’s security and resilience.</p>
<p>The United States values the strong relationship between our two countries and wishes the citizens of Grenada a happy Independence Day.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States, I congratulate the people of Grenada on the 48th anniversary of your independence.</p>
<p>Grenada and the United States share close ties and a strong, steadfast partnership.  We appreciate Grenada’s role in addressing the climate crisis and are proud to work together to improve regional security and advance the health and prosperity of the Caribbean.  Our collaboration with Grenada on education and entrepreneurship helps ensure a more prosperous future for the people of Grenada.  In the year ahead, we look forward to the inauguration of two emergency operations centers in Grenada and Carriacou that will support Grenada’s security and resilience.</p>
<p>The United States values the strong relationship between our two countries and wishes the citizens of Grenada a happy Independence Day.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with French Foreign Minister Le Drian</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-french-foreign-minister-le-drian-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 19:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=311807</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian about ongoing efforts by NATO Allies, EU partners, G7 members, and other partners to address Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders, and the importance of continuing to support Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.  They discussed joint efforts to strengthen NATO’s Eastern Flank and to ensure Russia understands the high costs it would incur if it were to invade Ukraine further.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Le Drian also reviewed ongoing developments in the Sahel region of Africa. </span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian about ongoing efforts by NATO Allies, EU partners, G7 members, and other partners to address Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders, and the importance of continuing to support Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.  They discussed joint efforts to strengthen NATO’s Eastern Flank and to ensure Russia understands the high costs it would incur if it were to invade Ukraine further.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Le Drian also reviewed ongoing developments in the Sahel region of Africa. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Travel of Special Representative for the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK) Kim to Honolulu, Hawaii</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/travel-of-special-representative-for-the-democratic-peoples-republic-of-korea-dprk-kim-to-honolulu-hawaii/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 13:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=311782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Special Representative for the DPRK Ambassador Sung Kim will travel to Honolulu, Hawaii, February 10 to 15.  Special Representative Kim will host a trilateral meeting with Japanese Director-General for Asian and Oceanian Affairs Funakoshi Takehiro and Republic of Korea (ROK) Special Representative for Korean Peninsula Peace and Security Affairs Noh Kyu-duk to discuss a broad range of issues, including the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, the importance of trilateral cooperation, and the immediate resolution of the abductions issue.  Special Representative Kim, Special Representative Noh, and Director-General Funakoshi will also attend the February 12 Trilateral Ministerial meeting in which the U.S. will reiterate its commitment to regional security and lasting peace on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Special Representative for the DPRK Ambassador Sung Kim will travel to Honolulu, Hawaii, February 10 to 15.  Special Representative Kim will host a trilateral meeting with Japanese Director-General for Asian and Oceanian Affairs Funakoshi Takehiro and Republic of Korea (ROK) Special Representative for Korean Peninsula Peace and Security Affairs Noh Kyu-duk to discuss a broad range of issues, including the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, the importance of trilateral cooperation, and the immediate resolution of the abductions issue.  Special Representative Kim, Special Representative Noh, and Director-General Funakoshi will also attend the February 12 Trilateral Ministerial meeting in which the U.S. will reiterate its commitment to regional security and lasting peace on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
