<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 18:09:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Attack on Hospital in Afrin, Syria</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/attack-on-hospital-in-afrin-syria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 18:07:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251606</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We condemn in the strongest terms yesterday’s attacks on the al Shifaa Hospital in Afrin, Syria. This barbaric attack took the lives of children, medical staff, and first responders. Civilians and civilian infrastructure, including hospitals, must never be the target of military action. Additionally, we note that this hospital’s coordinates have been shared with the UN deconfliction mechanism for Syria. This attack is part of a recent escalation of violence in northwest Syria and must end. The United States calls for an immediate nation-wide ceasefire and a de-escalation of violence in Syria.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We condemn in the strongest terms yesterday’s attacks on the al Shifaa Hospital in Afrin, Syria. This barbaric attack took the lives of children, medical staff, and first responders. Civilians and civilian infrastructure, including hospitals, must never be the target of military action. Additionally, we note that this hospital’s coordinates have been shared with the UN deconfliction mechanism for Syria. This attack is part of a recent escalation of violence in northwest Syria and must end. The United States calls for an immediate nation-wide ceasefire and a de-escalation of violence in Syria.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken  With John Dickerson of CBS’s Face the Nation</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-john-dickerson-of-cbss-face-the-nation</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 16:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251602</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels Media Hub</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  We begin this morning with Secretary of State Antony Blinken, who is in Brussels.  Good morning, Mr. Secretary.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  John, good to see you.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Mr. Secretary, the President wrote in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Washington Post</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that one of the purposes of this meeting would be to demonstrate that democracies can confront autocracies, but the Russian gas pipeline is going into Germany.  China is heavily invested in many European countries.  What appetite did the President find for confrontation among these democracies whose economies are so enmeshed with autocracies?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, John, first, let&#8217;s take a step back.  The proposition that the President had is we need to demonstrate that democracies can deliver in all sorts of ways to better the lives of our people.  And that&#8217;s exactly what he&#8217;s demonstrated just in the last couple of days alone at the G7.  Look at what&#8217;s come out of this summit.  By the way, I&#8217;ve been involved in these G7s for probably 25 years. This is the most consequential one I&#8217;ve been involved in.  A billion shots in arms around the world with the COVID vaccine; dealing in a very meaningful way with climate change in terms of getting a prohibition on financing coal projects around the world, the largest single contributor to global warming; a commitment on the 15 percent minimum global corporate tax, a powerful way of increasing the tax base for countries around the world, avoiding a race to the bottom in terms of corporate taxation; making sure countries have the resources to invest in their people, in infrastructure, in health care, in technology and new markets for our products at the same time. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And finally, this Build Back Better World, which is taking to the world what we&#8217;re already doing at home, helping use this moment, this inflection point to pool the resources of all of the democracies to invest in and get the private sector to invest in low and middle-income countries to strengthen their health systems, their infrastructure, their technology.  And that&#8217;s going to also benefit us.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So I say all this because it&#8217;s important that the President&#8217;s basic proposition – we have to show democracies coming together can deliver real results.  That&#8217;s already what we’ve shown.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Right, those are &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  When it&#8217;s – when it comes to dealing with – go ahead, John.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, those are those are some results, but when it comes to confronting China, I mean, you&#8217;ve talked about the ongoing genocide in China.  That&#8217;s very strong language.  Other U.S. officials have said that China is assaulting basic human values.  What appetite is there among those the President is meeting to use that kind of harsh language?  And at the end of the day, what does that language do to change Chinese behavior in the first place?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, first, one of the things you&#8217;re seeing out of the G7 is in the communique that I think is about to be released, a focus on China.  Go back to 2018, the last time the G7 came together in person, there wasn&#8217;t even a mention of China in the communique.  I think that is evidence in and of itself that countries are concerned across the board in many of China&#8217;s actions.  It&#8217;s a complicated relationship for virtually all of the G7 countries.  It&#8217;s in some aspects adversarial, in other aspects competitive, and in other aspects cooperative.  But the common denominator, and I think this is where these countries are coming together, is we need to be able to deal with China in all of those areas coming from a position of strength and coming from a united position.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Let me &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  I think what the President was able to do in these last couple of days was bring countries closer together in dealing with some of the challenges posed by China.  And we can talk about Xinjiang or any of the others if you like.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  I&#8217;d like to move on to Russia in a moment, but let me ask about the Chinese have said they&#8217;re not going to help the US investigate the potential of a lab leak in the start of COVID-19.  Does the US have any sway in getting cooperation from the Chinese?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  I think the – not only the United States but the world is insisting on it.  One of the things that&#8217;s coming out of the G7 is an insistence that the WHO be able to move forward with China cooperating on this so-called phase two report to build on the initial report, which had real problems with it, not the least of which was China&#8217;s failure to cooperate. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And here&#8217;s the thing, John:  Coming out of this, we need a couple of things.  We need to understand what happened. We need to get to the bottom of it. And we&#8217;re working on that through the WHO.  We&#8217;re also working on that ourselves.  The President ordered a 90-day sprint led by our Intelligence Community to try to get to the bottom of it.  And the main purpose is to make sure that knowing what happened, why it happened, how it happened, we can put in place what&#8217;s necessary to prevent it from happening again or at least to mitigate the next outbreak.  China has to cooperate with that.  Transparency, access for international experts, information sharing – that has to happen.  And again, I think you&#8217;re seeing countries coming together to insist on that.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Let me move on to Russia. I asked one of your predecessors, Condoleezza Rice, former secretary of state, how to judge the meeting with Putin.  She said ignore the theater review – the theater reviews of it, ignore the moment.  But look several months down the road to see if the Russians have gotten the messages that have been delivered privately.  So what should we look for in six months or so that will show that there have been fruits of this actual meeting?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Look, I think Secretary Rice is exactly right.  This is not a light-switch moment.  This is about the President wanting to do two things, and he&#8217;s been very clear about it: to tell President Putin directly that we seek a more predictable, stable relationship, and if we&#8217;re able to do that, there are areas where it&#8217;s in our mutual interest to cooperate; but if Russia continues to take reckless and aggressive actions, we&#8217;ll respond forcefully, as we&#8217;ve already done when it comes to election interference, when it comes to the SolarWinds cyber attack, when it comes to the attempt to poison and kill Mr. Navalny.  And this is a beginning of testing that proposition.  And Russia will have to decide by its actions which direction it wants to go in.  And I think Secretary Rice is exactly right that we&#8217;ll see that play out in the months ahead.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Let me ask you:  Russia has joined a new agreement against cyber hacking, but those kinds of agreements have existed before.  And this is why people look to these kinds of international meetings with a heavy degree of skepticism. Why should the United States trust Russia in this new agreement when the United States believes that Russia has broken all the previous ones?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  It&#8217;s not a matter of trust.  I think someone once said trust but verify.  I&#8217;d say don&#8217;t trust and verify.  We&#8217;ll see by Russia&#8217;s actions whether it will make good on any commitments it makes.  Here&#8217;s the thing:  We&#8217;ve now been the victim of ransomware attacks, and many of these attacks come from criminal organizations, not necessarily from states, but countries have an obligation.  No responsible country should be in the business of harboring criminal groups engaged in these attacks.  And this is one of the things that President Biden&#8217;s going to be taking up with President Putin.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  When – during the early days after 9/11, the US position was if you harbored a terrorist, you&#8217;re just like the terrorist.  Is there an analogy there on cyber crime?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Yeah, there is an analogy there, because we know the tremendous damage this can do. We know the vulnerabilities. One of the things the President is insisting on is a very aggressive effort, first of all, to shore up our defenses.  And that means working very closely with the private sector, since a lot of this infrastructure is actually controlled by the private sector, not the government.  It means putting in place all of the tools that we need to disrupt these ransomware networks and efforts.  That requires a lot of coordination with other countries.  That&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;ve been engaged in, including here at the G7 and now at NATO.  And again, making it very clear that any country that harbors these groups, that&#8217;s not a sustainable proposition and we&#8217;re going to need to take action to stop that.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  As an illustration of the trickiness of the U.S. relationship with Russia, on the one hand, the US is working with Russia to revive the nuclear deal with Iran.  On the other hand, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Washington Post</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is reporting Russia is preparing to supply Iran with advanced satellite systems, which threaten US interests.  So are the Russians going to pay a penalty for offering those advanced satellite systems or do we need them in the nuclear talks so maybe we&#8217;ll move past that?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  First, when it comes to the nuclear talks, we&#8217;re not trading any other issues or interests for the sake of the nuclear talks.  They will stand and fall – or fall on their own merit and on their own weight.  So I want to be very clear about that. Second, I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President.  I suspect he&#8217;ll be taking this up with President Putin in a couple of days. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But John, let me say one more thing on this.  This meeting with President Putin is not happening in a vacuum.  The President will be coming off of the G7, the NATO summit, the meeting with the European Union&#8217;s leaders.  And collectively, when we bring the world&#8217;s democracies together, it&#8217;s an incredibly powerful force militarily, economically, politically, diplomatically.  A major poll just came out that showed that across these countries confidence in American leadership, President Biden&#8217;s leadership, in these countries is at 75 percent.  That&#8217;s up from 17 percent a year ago.  So we are now in a position as a result of reinvigorated American leadership to work and to bring all of these countries together in common cause and common purpose, including dealing with challenges from Russia or China.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Final quick question, Mr. Secretary.  Iran has made a lot of progress since the nuclear deal fell apart.  A lot of that is in material.  Other is knowledge.  How do you put the knowledge back in a box that they&#8217;ve gained during the period that the &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  That’s right.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  &#8212; agreement fell apart?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  John, that&#8217;s a great question, and you&#8217;re exactly right that since we pulled out of the nuclear deal and then Iran began to ignore the constraints that the deal had imposed on it, it has been galloping forward and it&#8217;s enriching more material.  It&#8217;s enriching at higher levels, degrees than were allowed under the agreement.  And you&#8217;re right, it is gaining knowledge.  And if this goes on a lot longer, if they continue to gallop ahead, then you&#8217;re right, they&#8217;re going to have knowledge that&#8217;s going to be very hard to reverse, which I think puts some urgency in seeing if we can put the nuclear problem back in the box that the agreement had put it in that, unfortunately, Iran is now out of as a result of us pulling out of the agreement.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  All right, Secretary Blinken, we&#8217;re out of time.  Thank you so much for being with us.  And Face the Nation will be back in a minute.  Stay with us.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels Media Hub</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  We begin this morning with Secretary of State Antony Blinken, who is in Brussels.  Good morning, Mr. Secretary.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  John, good to see you.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Mr. Secretary, the President wrote in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Washington Post</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that one of the purposes of this meeting would be to demonstrate that democracies can confront autocracies, but the Russian gas pipeline is going into Germany.  China is heavily invested in many European countries.  What appetite did the President find for confrontation among these democracies whose economies are so enmeshed with autocracies?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, John, first, let&#8217;s take a step back.  The proposition that the President had is we need to demonstrate that democracies can deliver in all sorts of ways to better the lives of our people.  And that&#8217;s exactly what he&#8217;s demonstrated just in the last couple of days alone at the G7.  Look at what&#8217;s come out of this summit.  By the way, I&#8217;ve been involved in these G7s for probably 25 years. This is the most consequential one I&#8217;ve been involved in.  A billion shots in arms around the world with the COVID vaccine; dealing in a very meaningful way with climate change in terms of getting a prohibition on financing coal projects around the world, the largest single contributor to global warming; a commitment on the 15 percent minimum global corporate tax, a powerful way of increasing the tax base for countries around the world, avoiding a race to the bottom in terms of corporate taxation; making sure countries have the resources to invest in their people, in infrastructure, in health care, in technology and new markets for our products at the same time. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And finally, this Build Back Better World, which is taking to the world what we&#8217;re already doing at home, helping use this moment, this inflection point to pool the resources of all of the democracies to invest in and get the private sector to invest in low and middle-income countries to strengthen their health systems, their infrastructure, their technology.  And that&#8217;s going to also benefit us.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So I say all this because it&#8217;s important that the President&#8217;s basic proposition – we have to show democracies coming together can deliver real results.  That&#8217;s already what we’ve shown.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Right, those are &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  When it&#8217;s – when it comes to dealing with – go ahead, John.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, those are those are some results, but when it comes to confronting China, I mean, you&#8217;ve talked about the ongoing genocide in China.  That&#8217;s very strong language.  Other U.S. officials have said that China is assaulting basic human values.  What appetite is there among those the President is meeting to use that kind of harsh language?  And at the end of the day, what does that language do to change Chinese behavior in the first place?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, first, one of the things you&#8217;re seeing out of the G7 is in the communique that I think is about to be released, a focus on China.  Go back to 2018, the last time the G7 came together in person, there wasn&#8217;t even a mention of China in the communique.  I think that is evidence in and of itself that countries are concerned across the board in many of China&#8217;s actions.  It&#8217;s a complicated relationship for virtually all of the G7 countries.  It&#8217;s in some aspects adversarial, in other aspects competitive, and in other aspects cooperative.  But the common denominator, and I think this is where these countries are coming together, is we need to be able to deal with China in all of those areas coming from a position of strength and coming from a united position.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Let me &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  I think what the President was able to do in these last couple of days was bring countries closer together in dealing with some of the challenges posed by China.  And we can talk about Xinjiang or any of the others if you like.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  I&#8217;d like to move on to Russia in a moment, but let me ask about the Chinese have said they&#8217;re not going to help the US investigate the potential of a lab leak in the start of COVID-19.  Does the US have any sway in getting cooperation from the Chinese?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  I think the – not only the United States but the world is insisting on it.  One of the things that&#8217;s coming out of the G7 is an insistence that the WHO be able to move forward with China cooperating on this so-called phase two report to build on the initial report, which had real problems with it, not the least of which was China&#8217;s failure to cooperate. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And here&#8217;s the thing, John:  Coming out of this, we need a couple of things.  We need to understand what happened. We need to get to the bottom of it. And we&#8217;re working on that through the WHO.  We&#8217;re also working on that ourselves.  The President ordered a 90-day sprint led by our Intelligence Community to try to get to the bottom of it.  And the main purpose is to make sure that knowing what happened, why it happened, how it happened, we can put in place what&#8217;s necessary to prevent it from happening again or at least to mitigate the next outbreak.  China has to cooperate with that.  Transparency, access for international experts, information sharing – that has to happen.  And again, I think you&#8217;re seeing countries coming together to insist on that.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Let me move on to Russia. I asked one of your predecessors, Condoleezza Rice, former secretary of state, how to judge the meeting with Putin.  She said ignore the theater review – the theater reviews of it, ignore the moment.  But look several months down the road to see if the Russians have gotten the messages that have been delivered privately.  So what should we look for in six months or so that will show that there have been fruits of this actual meeting?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Look, I think Secretary Rice is exactly right.  This is not a light-switch moment.  This is about the President wanting to do two things, and he&#8217;s been very clear about it: to tell President Putin directly that we seek a more predictable, stable relationship, and if we&#8217;re able to do that, there are areas where it&#8217;s in our mutual interest to cooperate; but if Russia continues to take reckless and aggressive actions, we&#8217;ll respond forcefully, as we&#8217;ve already done when it comes to election interference, when it comes to the SolarWinds cyber attack, when it comes to the attempt to poison and kill Mr. Navalny.  And this is a beginning of testing that proposition.  And Russia will have to decide by its actions which direction it wants to go in.  And I think Secretary Rice is exactly right that we&#8217;ll see that play out in the months ahead.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Let me ask you:  Russia has joined a new agreement against cyber hacking, but those kinds of agreements have existed before.  And this is why people look to these kinds of international meetings with a heavy degree of skepticism. Why should the United States trust Russia in this new agreement when the United States believes that Russia has broken all the previous ones?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  It&#8217;s not a matter of trust.  I think someone once said trust but verify.  I&#8217;d say don&#8217;t trust and verify.  We&#8217;ll see by Russia&#8217;s actions whether it will make good on any commitments it makes.  Here&#8217;s the thing:  We&#8217;ve now been the victim of ransomware attacks, and many of these attacks come from criminal organizations, not necessarily from states, but countries have an obligation.  No responsible country should be in the business of harboring criminal groups engaged in these attacks.  And this is one of the things that President Biden&#8217;s going to be taking up with President Putin.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  When – during the early days after 9/11, the US position was if you harbored a terrorist, you&#8217;re just like the terrorist.  Is there an analogy there on cyber crime?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Yeah, there is an analogy there, because we know the tremendous damage this can do. We know the vulnerabilities. One of the things the President is insisting on is a very aggressive effort, first of all, to shore up our defenses.  And that means working very closely with the private sector, since a lot of this infrastructure is actually controlled by the private sector, not the government.  It means putting in place all of the tools that we need to disrupt these ransomware networks and efforts.  That requires a lot of coordination with other countries.  That&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;ve been engaged in, including here at the G7 and now at NATO.  And again, making it very clear that any country that harbors these groups, that&#8217;s not a sustainable proposition and we&#8217;re going to need to take action to stop that.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  As an illustration of the trickiness of the U.S. relationship with Russia, on the one hand, the US is working with Russia to revive the nuclear deal with Iran.  On the other hand, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Washington Post</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is reporting Russia is preparing to supply Iran with advanced satellite systems, which threaten US interests.  So are the Russians going to pay a penalty for offering those advanced satellite systems or do we need them in the nuclear talks so maybe we&#8217;ll move past that?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  First, when it comes to the nuclear talks, we&#8217;re not trading any other issues or interests for the sake of the nuclear talks.  They will stand and fall – or fall on their own merit and on their own weight.  So I want to be very clear about that. Second, I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President.  I suspect he&#8217;ll be taking this up with President Putin in a couple of days. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But John, let me say one more thing on this.  This meeting with President Putin is not happening in a vacuum.  The President will be coming off of the G7, the NATO summit, the meeting with the European Union&#8217;s leaders.  And collectively, when we bring the world&#8217;s democracies together, it&#8217;s an incredibly powerful force militarily, economically, politically, diplomatically.  A major poll just came out that showed that across these countries confidence in American leadership, President Biden&#8217;s leadership, in these countries is at 75 percent.  That&#8217;s up from 17 percent a year ago.  So we are now in a position as a result of reinvigorated American leadership to work and to bring all of these countries together in common cause and common purpose, including dealing with challenges from Russia or China.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Final quick question, Mr. Secretary.  Iran has made a lot of progress since the nuclear deal fell apart.  A lot of that is in material.  Other is knowledge.  How do you put the knowledge back in a box that they&#8217;ve gained during the period that the &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  That’s right.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  &#8212; agreement fell apart?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  John, that&#8217;s a great question, and you&#8217;re exactly right that since we pulled out of the nuclear deal and then Iran began to ignore the constraints that the deal had imposed on it, it has been galloping forward and it&#8217;s enriching more material.  It&#8217;s enriching at higher levels, degrees than were allowed under the agreement.  And you&#8217;re right, it is gaining knowledge.  And if this goes on a lot longer, if they continue to gallop ahead, then you&#8217;re right, they&#8217;re going to have knowledge that&#8217;s going to be very hard to reverse, which I think puts some urgency in seeing if we can put the nuclear problem back in the box that the agreement had put it in that, unfortunately, Iran is now out of as a result of us pulling out of the agreement.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  All right, Secretary Blinken, we&#8217;re out of time.  Thank you so much for being with us.  And Face the Nation will be back in a minute.  Stay with us.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken  With Chris Wallace of Fox News Sunday</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-chris-wallace-of-fox-news-sunday</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 15:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels Media Hub</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  And joining us now, the Secretary of State, Antony Blinken.  Mr. Secretary, welcome back to Fox News Sunday.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Thanks, Chris.  It’s great to be with you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  This trip is building up to I guess the climax, the meeting with Russian President Putin in Geneva on Wednesday.  Here’s what Putin said this week about relations between the U.S. and Russia.  Take a look:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">        </span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">(Via interpreter) “We have a bilateral relationship that has deteriorated to its lowest point in recent years.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do you agree that relations between the U.S. and Russia are at the lowest point in recent years?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Well, that may be the one thing that I’d agree with President Putin on.  And one of the things that President Biden will begin to test is whether Russia is interested in a more stable, predictable relationship, which would be to everyone’s benefit.  But if not – if it continues to take reckless and aggressive actions directed at us or our allies and partners – the President’s going to make clear that we’ll respond forcefully, as we did in the case of election interference, the SolarWinds cyber hack, the attempt to murder Mr. Navalny.  So this is the beginning of testing the proposition about whether Russia wants a more stable, predictable relationship itself and whether, in some areas where there’s mutual interest, we can find some ways to cooperate.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  When the President arrived in Europe earlier this week, he was pretty general about the message he intends to convey to Mr. Putin.  Take a look at what he said then:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">        </span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">“Then to meet with Mr. Putin to let him know what I want him to know.”  (Applause.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So let’s get more specific.  Putin just said or it was reported that he said this morning that he’s willing to hand over cyber criminals to the U.S. if we hand over cyber criminals we’re harboring to him.  Is that a satisfactory resolution to the ransomware problem?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Chris, I don’t want to get ahead of the President, but let me say this:  When it comes to ransomware, no responsible country should be in the business of harboring criminal organizations engaged in those practices.  And that is something that the President very much intends to take up with President Putin.  That’s very much on the agenda.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  But what can he do about it, Mr. Secretary?  I mean, I know he can say there are these gangs, they’re shutting down our pipelines, they’re shutting down our food supply.  But other than complaining about it, what can the President do?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Look, let me take one step back for a second.  We’re not coming into – the President’s not coming into this meeting with President Putin in a void.  We’re coming off of a G7 summit, a NATO summit, a meeting with the EU leadership.  And what we’re demonstrating in each of these meetings and summits is that democracies can come together and work effectively to actually deliver results for our people and, by the way, for people around the world.  And also, when we’re working together militarily, economically, diplomatically, politically, we’re a very powerful force.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There was a major poll that just came out that showed that across those countries, 75 percent of the people on average now have confidence in American leadership and in President Biden.  That’s up from 17 percent a year ago.  So we’re now in a position where, when it comes to dealing with Russia and the challenges it poses or dealing with China and the challenges it poses, we can come with a much more united front.  And so I think you’ll see – and again, I’m not going to get ahead of the President, but when it comes to looking for action to deal with things like ransomware, we’re in a stronger position with tools of our own and the international community with us to elicit that action.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Why did the President decide to hold a solo news conference after his summit with Putin on Wednesday as opposed to the joint press conferences that he usually holds with foreign leaders and the joint press conference that President Trump and Putin held after their summit in 2018?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Chris, I think it’s the most effective way for the President to be able to talk with the free press and to share for as long as he can what was discussed in the meeting with President Putin, as well as to cover the entire week, to talk about what we’ve accomplished over the course of the G7, the NATO meetings, the EU meetings.  By the way, he’s doing a solo press conference I think almost right now in the UK after the G7, so this is not a rare practice.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  One of the President’s main objectives on this trip is to get the allies – both the G7, the EU, NATO – to join together – I guess not NATO, but the others to join together in calling out China for dumping its exports at unfair trade – unfair low prices, and also to call out China for human rights abuses.  Now, I know there’s a communique, but I want to ask you the practical effect.  Have the U.S. and the allies agreed that they are going to condemn forced labor, for instance by the Uyghurs?  Have they agreed that they’re going to go to the WTO and ask for duties on China for dumping exports?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  First, Chris, it’s important in and of itself that the communique, this document that comes out of the G7 and talks about what the G7 leaders have agreed on – it’s important in and of itself that there’s a focus on China.  Go back to 2018, the last time these leaders came together – no mention of China in the document summing up what the G7 was focused on.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Going forward, we had very detailed discussions about the kind of work that could be done, the kind of actions that could be taken, for example, in preventing the export of products made with forced labor in China or, for that matter, preventing the export of products that could be used to repress people in China.  All of that was on the table, and I think you can expect to see going forward different countries taking action across those areas.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But one other thing that’s really important – I just want to spend a second on it – one of the things that the leaders agreed to was this so-called Build Back Better for the World, and that is an agreement to work to start to pool all of our resources, our development resources; make investments in low and middle-income countries; get the private sector to make these investments, to build up their health care systems, infrastructure, technology, which will be strong markets for our products; but to do it in a way that’s a race to the top, not the bottom, in terms of the standards, in terms of respect for workers, for the environment, for privacy, all of these things. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That’s a very powerful positive alternative to what China is doing with its so-called Belt and Road Initiative.  We’re demonstrating that we have &#8212;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  There’s also &#8212;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  &#8212; a positive alternative vision in the – for the future and bringing countries along.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  There’s also the continuing controversy over the origins of COVID.  I know the President has ordered this 90-day review of U.S. intelligence on what we know, but one assumes if we knew anything, we’d already know it.  And I guess the more important question is what is the President prepared to do unilaterally – not through the WHO, which has already been stiffed by the Chinese – what is he prepared to do unilaterally to press China to provide, to share more evidence, more information, especially from the Wuhan lab?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Well, first, Chris, your – the premise of your question is entirely correct, which is we need to get to the bottom of what happened.  We need accountability, but we also need to understand what happened, why it happened, how it happened if we’re going to be able to put in place the necessary measures to prevent it from happening again, or at least to be in a better place to mitigate the next pandemic if we can’t fully prevent one.  And so we need this transparency; we need this information.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The WHO, you’re right – the first study that they put out was highly deficient.  The leaders of the G7 have come together insisting that China cooperate with the so-called Phase 2 study by the WHO to really get to the bottom of what happened, but that is – that’s not enough.  The President ordered this 90-day sprint.  We looked at this very hard.  He ordered back in March that we try to determine for ourselves the origins of the – of COVID-19, and we came up with two plausible explanations.  One is the so-called natural occurrence, going from animal to human; the other was a lab leak.  But we couldn’t determine with any degree of certainty which one it was.  What the President’s ordered now is to – with the Intelligence Community, bringing all of the different agencies of government and also our national labs, other experts, bringing all of that expertise to bear to look at every piece of information we have to see if we can make a determination. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Going forward, the thing that is most critical besides accountability is, again, making sure that every country, including China, cooperates with the international community in making sure we have the transparency, we have access for experts in real time, we have information sharing so that if something starts to percolate again, we’re on top of it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Finally, your immediate predecessor, Secretary Pompeo, is waiting on the wings.  He’s going to be coming up in the next segment.  Briefly, what would you tell him is the biggest difference between Biden foreign policy and Trump foreign policy?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Chris, I’m resolutely looking forward, not backward.  Please say hello to Mike.  We’ve had a lot of good conversations and I look forward to the next one, but we’re focused on the future, moving forward.  We’ve had a very good couple of days with the G7 in actually demonstrating that democracies can come together and deliver for people in real ways, real outcomes – a billion shots in arms, that’s remarkable – dealing more effectively with climate change, prohibiting financing of coal-fired plants, which is the biggest single contributor to emissions; this Build back Better for the World that I talked about; the 15 percent global corporate minimum tax that’s going to give countries around the world a stronger tax base, stronger markets for us, ultimately.  So that’s what we’re focused on, as well as strengthening NATO and working with the EU and dealing with Mr. Putin.  So please say hi to Mike.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  That is a very diplomatic answer for the Secretary of State.  Secretary Blinken, thank you.  Thanks for your time in the midst of the President’s trip, and please come back, sir.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels Media Hub</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  And joining us now, the Secretary of State, Antony Blinken.  Mr. Secretary, welcome back to Fox News Sunday.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Thanks, Chris.  It’s great to be with you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  This trip is building up to I guess the climax, the meeting with Russian President Putin in Geneva on Wednesday.  Here’s what Putin said this week about relations between the U.S. and Russia.  Take a look:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">        </span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">(Via interpreter) “We have a bilateral relationship that has deteriorated to its lowest point in recent years.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do you agree that relations between the U.S. and Russia are at the lowest point in recent years?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Well, that may be the one thing that I’d agree with President Putin on.  And one of the things that President Biden will begin to test is whether Russia is interested in a more stable, predictable relationship, which would be to everyone’s benefit.  But if not – if it continues to take reckless and aggressive actions directed at us or our allies and partners – the President’s going to make clear that we’ll respond forcefully, as we did in the case of election interference, the SolarWinds cyber hack, the attempt to murder Mr. Navalny.  So this is the beginning of testing the proposition about whether Russia wants a more stable, predictable relationship itself and whether, in some areas where there’s mutual interest, we can find some ways to cooperate.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  When the President arrived in Europe earlier this week, he was pretty general about the message he intends to convey to Mr. Putin.  Take a look at what he said then:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">        </span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">“Then to meet with Mr. Putin to let him know what I want him to know.”  (Applause.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So let’s get more specific.  Putin just said or it was reported that he said this morning that he’s willing to hand over cyber criminals to the U.S. if we hand over cyber criminals we’re harboring to him.  Is that a satisfactory resolution to the ransomware problem?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Chris, I don’t want to get ahead of the President, but let me say this:  When it comes to ransomware, no responsible country should be in the business of harboring criminal organizations engaged in those practices.  And that is something that the President very much intends to take up with President Putin.  That’s very much on the agenda.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  But what can he do about it, Mr. Secretary?  I mean, I know he can say there are these gangs, they’re shutting down our pipelines, they’re shutting down our food supply.  But other than complaining about it, what can the President do?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Look, let me take one step back for a second.  We’re not coming into – the President’s not coming into this meeting with President Putin in a void.  We’re coming off of a G7 summit, a NATO summit, a meeting with the EU leadership.  And what we’re demonstrating in each of these meetings and summits is that democracies can come together and work effectively to actually deliver results for our people and, by the way, for people around the world.  And also, when we’re working together militarily, economically, diplomatically, politically, we’re a very powerful force.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There was a major poll that just came out that showed that across those countries, 75 percent of the people on average now have confidence in American leadership and in President Biden.  That’s up from 17 percent a year ago.  So we’re now in a position where, when it comes to dealing with Russia and the challenges it poses or dealing with China and the challenges it poses, we can come with a much more united front.  And so I think you’ll see – and again, I’m not going to get ahead of the President, but when it comes to looking for action to deal with things like ransomware, we’re in a stronger position with tools of our own and the international community with us to elicit that action.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Why did the President decide to hold a solo news conference after his summit with Putin on Wednesday as opposed to the joint press conferences that he usually holds with foreign leaders and the joint press conference that President Trump and Putin held after their summit in 2018?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Chris, I think it’s the most effective way for the President to be able to talk with the free press and to share for as long as he can what was discussed in the meeting with President Putin, as well as to cover the entire week, to talk about what we’ve accomplished over the course of the G7, the NATO meetings, the EU meetings.  By the way, he’s doing a solo press conference I think almost right now in the UK after the G7, so this is not a rare practice.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  One of the President’s main objectives on this trip is to get the allies – both the G7, the EU, NATO – to join together – I guess not NATO, but the others to join together in calling out China for dumping its exports at unfair trade – unfair low prices, and also to call out China for human rights abuses.  Now, I know there’s a communique, but I want to ask you the practical effect.  Have the U.S. and the allies agreed that they are going to condemn forced labor, for instance by the Uyghurs?  Have they agreed that they’re going to go to the WTO and ask for duties on China for dumping exports?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  First, Chris, it’s important in and of itself that the communique, this document that comes out of the G7 and talks about what the G7 leaders have agreed on – it’s important in and of itself that there’s a focus on China.  Go back to 2018, the last time these leaders came together – no mention of China in the document summing up what the G7 was focused on.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Going forward, we had very detailed discussions about the kind of work that could be done, the kind of actions that could be taken, for example, in preventing the export of products made with forced labor in China or, for that matter, preventing the export of products that could be used to repress people in China.  All of that was on the table, and I think you can expect to see going forward different countries taking action across those areas.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But one other thing that’s really important – I just want to spend a second on it – one of the things that the leaders agreed to was this so-called Build Back Better for the World, and that is an agreement to work to start to pool all of our resources, our development resources; make investments in low and middle-income countries; get the private sector to make these investments, to build up their health care systems, infrastructure, technology, which will be strong markets for our products; but to do it in a way that’s a race to the top, not the bottom, in terms of the standards, in terms of respect for workers, for the environment, for privacy, all of these things. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That’s a very powerful positive alternative to what China is doing with its so-called Belt and Road Initiative.  We’re demonstrating that we have &#8212;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  There’s also &#8212;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  &#8212; a positive alternative vision in the – for the future and bringing countries along.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  There’s also the continuing controversy over the origins of COVID.  I know the President has ordered this 90-day review of U.S. intelligence on what we know, but one assumes if we knew anything, we’d already know it.  And I guess the more important question is what is the President prepared to do unilaterally – not through the WHO, which has already been stiffed by the Chinese – what is he prepared to do unilaterally to press China to provide, to share more evidence, more information, especially from the Wuhan lab?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Well, first, Chris, your – the premise of your question is entirely correct, which is we need to get to the bottom of what happened.  We need accountability, but we also need to understand what happened, why it happened, how it happened if we’re going to be able to put in place the necessary measures to prevent it from happening again, or at least to be in a better place to mitigate the next pandemic if we can’t fully prevent one.  And so we need this transparency; we need this information.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The WHO, you’re right – the first study that they put out was highly deficient.  The leaders of the G7 have come together insisting that China cooperate with the so-called Phase 2 study by the WHO to really get to the bottom of what happened, but that is – that’s not enough.  The President ordered this 90-day sprint.  We looked at this very hard.  He ordered back in March that we try to determine for ourselves the origins of the – of COVID-19, and we came up with two plausible explanations.  One is the so-called natural occurrence, going from animal to human; the other was a lab leak.  But we couldn’t determine with any degree of certainty which one it was.  What the President’s ordered now is to – with the Intelligence Community, bringing all of the different agencies of government and also our national labs, other experts, bringing all of that expertise to bear to look at every piece of information we have to see if we can make a determination. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Going forward, the thing that is most critical besides accountability is, again, making sure that every country, including China, cooperates with the international community in making sure we have the transparency, we have access for experts in real time, we have information sharing so that if something starts to percolate again, we’re on top of it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Finally, your immediate predecessor, Secretary Pompeo, is waiting on the wings.  He’s going to be coming up in the next segment.  Briefly, what would you tell him is the biggest difference between Biden foreign policy and Trump foreign policy?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Chris, I’m resolutely looking forward, not backward.  Please say hello to Mike.  We’ve had a lot of good conversations and I look forward to the next one, but we’re focused on the future, moving forward.  We’ve had a very good couple of days with the G7 in actually demonstrating that democracies can come together and deliver for people in real ways, real outcomes – a billion shots in arms, that’s remarkable – dealing more effectively with climate change, prohibiting financing of coal-fired plants, which is the biggest single contributor to emissions; this Build back Better for the World that I talked about; the 15 percent global corporate minimum tax that’s going to give countries around the world a stronger tax base, stronger markets for us, ultimately.  So that’s what we’re focused on, as well as strengthening NATO and working with the EU and dealing with Mr. Putin.  So please say hi to Mike.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  That is a very diplomatic answer for the Secretary of State.  Secretary Blinken, thank you.  Thanks for your time in the midst of the President’s trip, and please come back, sir.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken  On CNN&#8217;s State of the Union with Dana Bash</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-on-cnns-state-of-the-union-with-dana-bash/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 15:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251585</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels Media Hub</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Joining me now is the U.S. Secretary of State Tony Blinken.  Thank you so much for joining me.  Let me first ask about one of President Biden’s key goals in this summit – uniting the Western democracies around countering China’s influence, especially around the goal of building infrastructure around the world. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So the White House has not said yet that the U.S. allies are onboard for financial support, so do you have a deal on that?  Is there money behind it?  And if so, how much?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Well, first, Dana, just to take a step back, the President came into this meeting of the G7 determined to show that democracies can deliver, deliver for their people, deliver for people around the world.  And that’s exactly what we’ve done over the last couple of days, and I’ll come to the specific point in a second. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But a commitment to a billion vaccines to put shots in arms around the world, that’s a powerful demonstration of democracies delivering; a commitment to deal with and to stop financing coal-fired plants and projects around the world, the single largest contributor to emissions and to global warming; a 15 percent minimum global corporate tax, making sure that countries around the world have a strong tax base to provide for their citizens, provide better – new markets for us as well, and avoid a race to the bottom.  And yes, this project to pool our resources, our – to invest in low and middle-income countries, to get to the private sector to do the same so that we can help them build up their infrastructure, their health care systems, education, and do it in a more positive way than China is doing it with its Belt and Road Initiative. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So they’ve launched this project.  Our experts are going to come together over the coming months and we’ll look at the resources necessary to do that.  But individually, our countries can only do so much.  When we put all of these resources together and when we leverage the private sector, it’s a very powerful force, and we’ve got an agreement to move forward on that.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Let’s look ahead to President Biden’s meeting with Russian President Vladimir Putin that’s going to be on Wednesday in Geneva.  I know the President plans to confront him on human rights, on Ukraine, on recent cyber attacks.  How do you define success out of this meeting?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Dana, this is not going to be a flip-the-light-switch moment.  What the President is going to make clear to President Putin is that we seek a more stable, predictable relationship with Russia, and if so, there are areas where our interests overlap, and we may be able to find ways to work together.  But if Russia chooses to continue reckless and aggressive actions, we will respond forcefully, as the President has already demonstrated that he would when it comes to election interference or the SolarWinds cyber attack or the attempt to murder Mr. Navalny with a chemical weapon. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So this is a beginning of testing the proposition, the question of whether Russia is interested in a more stable and predictable relationship and finding areas to work together.  We’re not going to get the answer out of one meeting.  We’ll have to see what comes from that meeting. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But let me say one other thing that I think is really important.  This meeting is not happening in a vacuum.  We’re coming off the G7.  We’re coming off a NATO summit.  We’ll be coming off of an EU summit as well.  And our leadership and our engagement is a very powerful force.  There was a major poll that was just done that found across these countries, across these democracies, 75 percent of the people on average have confidence in American leadership.  That’s up from 17 percent a year ago.  That means we’re in a much stronger position to work together with these countries militarily, diplomatically, politically, economically, including when it comes to dealing with challenges posed by Russia or China.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  So the White House says that President Biden is not going to have a joint press conference with Vladimir Putin after the summit.  Is that because President Biden and Vladimir Putin are – or at least President Biden is worried that there is concern that this meeting simply will not go well? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  No, I think, Dana, the – for the President, the most effective way to be able to share with the free press what he and President Putin talked about is to do it in this way.  It’s also an opportunity, by the way, to sum up the entire week, the entire trip, the G7, the NATO summit, the EU summit.  But this is the best opportunity I have to make sure that the free press of the world gets in their questions, and the President can share what was discussed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  I’m sorry.  So are you saying that you’re not having a joint press conference because you’re worried about the Russian press being there?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  We’re – we think that having the press conference – by the way, the President, maybe even as we speak, is doing a solo press conference after the G7.  This is not exactly a rare occurrence.  But we think it’s the most effective way to be able to share with the free press what they talked about and what we’re focused on, and to make sure that you all get a chance to ask as many questions as possible.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Before I let you go, the U.S. military withdrawal from Afghanistan is proceeding rapidly.  There are growing calls from Congress and other forces to evacuate Afghans who helped the U.S. during this very long war.  So yes or no:  Is the administration planning an evacuation of those people?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Evacuation is the wrong word.  We’re determined to make good on our obligation to those who helped us, who put their lives on the line, put their families’ lives on the line working with our military, working with our diplomats.  And there’s a special program for so-called Special Immigrant Visas that give them a dedicated channel to apply to come to the United States. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We have put in significant resources into making sure that that program can work fast and work effectively so that we can process any requests that we get for these so-called Special Immigrant Visas.  We’ve added about 50 people here in Washington in the State Department to help do that.  We want to make sure that anyone who has helped us we are making good on our obligation to help them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  U.S. Secretary of State Tony Blinken, thank you so much for joining me.  Appreciate it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Thanks very much.  Good to be with you. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">###</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels Media Hub</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Joining me now is the U.S. Secretary of State Tony Blinken.  Thank you so much for joining me.  Let me first ask about one of President Biden’s key goals in this summit – uniting the Western democracies around countering China’s influence, especially around the goal of building infrastructure around the world. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So the White House has not said yet that the U.S. allies are onboard for financial support, so do you have a deal on that?  Is there money behind it?  And if so, how much?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Well, first, Dana, just to take a step back, the President came into this meeting of the G7 determined to show that democracies can deliver, deliver for their people, deliver for people around the world.  And that’s exactly what we’ve done over the last couple of days, and I’ll come to the specific point in a second. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But a commitment to a billion vaccines to put shots in arms around the world, that’s a powerful demonstration of democracies delivering; a commitment to deal with and to stop financing coal-fired plants and projects around the world, the single largest contributor to emissions and to global warming; a 15 percent minimum global corporate tax, making sure that countries around the world have a strong tax base to provide for their citizens, provide better – new markets for us as well, and avoid a race to the bottom.  And yes, this project to pool our resources, our – to invest in low and middle-income countries, to get to the private sector to do the same so that we can help them build up their infrastructure, their health care systems, education, and do it in a more positive way than China is doing it with its Belt and Road Initiative. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So they’ve launched this project.  Our experts are going to come together over the coming months and we’ll look at the resources necessary to do that.  But individually, our countries can only do so much.  When we put all of these resources together and when we leverage the private sector, it’s a very powerful force, and we’ve got an agreement to move forward on that.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Let’s look ahead to President Biden’s meeting with Russian President Vladimir Putin that’s going to be on Wednesday in Geneva.  I know the President plans to confront him on human rights, on Ukraine, on recent cyber attacks.  How do you define success out of this meeting?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Dana, this is not going to be a flip-the-light-switch moment.  What the President is going to make clear to President Putin is that we seek a more stable, predictable relationship with Russia, and if so, there are areas where our interests overlap, and we may be able to find ways to work together.  But if Russia chooses to continue reckless and aggressive actions, we will respond forcefully, as the President has already demonstrated that he would when it comes to election interference or the SolarWinds cyber attack or the attempt to murder Mr. Navalny with a chemical weapon. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So this is a beginning of testing the proposition, the question of whether Russia is interested in a more stable and predictable relationship and finding areas to work together.  We’re not going to get the answer out of one meeting.  We’ll have to see what comes from that meeting. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But let me say one other thing that I think is really important.  This meeting is not happening in a vacuum.  We’re coming off the G7.  We’re coming off a NATO summit.  We’ll be coming off of an EU summit as well.  And our leadership and our engagement is a very powerful force.  There was a major poll that was just done that found across these countries, across these democracies, 75 percent of the people on average have confidence in American leadership.  That’s up from 17 percent a year ago.  That means we’re in a much stronger position to work together with these countries militarily, diplomatically, politically, economically, including when it comes to dealing with challenges posed by Russia or China.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  So the White House says that President Biden is not going to have a joint press conference with Vladimir Putin after the summit.  Is that because President Biden and Vladimir Putin are – or at least President Biden is worried that there is concern that this meeting simply will not go well? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  No, I think, Dana, the – for the President, the most effective way to be able to share with the free press what he and President Putin talked about is to do it in this way.  It’s also an opportunity, by the way, to sum up the entire week, the entire trip, the G7, the NATO summit, the EU summit.  But this is the best opportunity I have to make sure that the free press of the world gets in their questions, and the President can share what was discussed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  I’m sorry.  So are you saying that you’re not having a joint press conference because you’re worried about the Russian press being there?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  We’re – we think that having the press conference – by the way, the President, maybe even as we speak, is doing a solo press conference after the G7.  This is not exactly a rare occurrence.  But we think it’s the most effective way to be able to share with the free press what they talked about and what we’re focused on, and to make sure that you all get a chance to ask as many questions as possible.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  Before I let you go, the U.S. military withdrawal from Afghanistan is proceeding rapidly.  There are growing calls from Congress and other forces to evacuate Afghans who helped the U.S. during this very long war.  So yes or no:  Is the administration planning an evacuation of those people?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Evacuation is the wrong word.  We’re determined to make good on our obligation to those who helped us, who put their lives on the line, put their families’ lives on the line working with our military, working with our diplomats.  And there’s a special program for so-called Special Immigrant Visas that give them a dedicated channel to apply to come to the United States. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We have put in significant resources into making sure that that program can work fast and work effectively so that we can process any requests that we get for these so-called Special Immigrant Visas.  We’ve added about 50 people here in Washington in the State Department to help do that.  We want to make sure that anyone who has helped us we are making good on our obligation to help them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">QUESTION:  U.S. Secretary of State Tony Blinken, thank you so much for joining me.  Appreciate it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Thanks very much.  Good to be with you. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">###</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Public Schedule – June 13, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/public-schedule-june-13-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 12:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251576</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>***THE DAILY PUBLIC SCHEDULE IS SUBJECT TO CHANGE*** </strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong><u>SECRETARY ANTONY J. BLINKEN</u></strong></p>
<p>Secretary Blinken accompanies President Biden on travel to Cornwall, United Kingdom; Brussels, Belgium; and Geneva, Switzerland.  Please click <a href="https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-the-uk-belgium-and-switzerland/">here</a> for more information.</p>
<p><strong>5:30 p.m. LOCAL</strong> Secretary Blinken meets with Albanian Prime Minister Edi Rama, in Brussels, Belgium.</p>
<p><strong>(POOLED CAMERA SPRAY AT BOTTOM)</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>***THE DAILY PUBLIC SCHEDULE IS SUBJECT TO CHANGE*** </strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong><u>SECRETARY ANTONY J. BLINKEN</u></strong></p>
<p>Secretary Blinken accompanies President Biden on travel to Cornwall, United Kingdom; Brussels, Belgium; and Geneva, Switzerland.  Please click <a href="https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-the-uk-belgium-and-switzerland/">here</a> for more information.</p>
<p><strong>5:30 p.m. LOCAL</strong> Secretary Blinken meets with Albanian Prime Minister Edi Rama, in Brussels, Belgium.</p>
<p><strong>(POOLED CAMERA SPRAY AT BOTTOM)</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Republic of Korea Foreign Minister Chung</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-republic-of-korea-foreign-minister-chung-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 22:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Republic of Korea Foreign Minister Chung Eui-yong in Cornwall today.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Chung reaffirmed that the U.S.-ROK Alliance is the linchpin of peace, security, and prosperity in Northeast Asia, the Indo-Pacific region, and beyond. The Secretary and the Foreign Minister highlighted the importance of U.S.-ROK cooperation to promoting our shared values and addressing the challenges of today and the future.  They stressed the importance of multilateral cooperation to address issues critical to regional stability, including the return to the path to democracy for the people of Burma. The Secretary and the Foreign Minister also reaffirmed commitment to close cooperation between and among the United States, the Republic of Korea, and Japan on a broad range of issues, including working towards the denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Republic of Korea Foreign Minister Chung Eui-yong in Cornwall today.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Chung reaffirmed that the U.S.-ROK Alliance is the linchpin of peace, security, and prosperity in Northeast Asia, the Indo-Pacific region, and beyond. The Secretary and the Foreign Minister highlighted the importance of U.S.-ROK cooperation to promoting our shared values and addressing the challenges of today and the future.  They stressed the importance of multilateral cooperation to address issues critical to regional stability, including the return to the path to democracy for the people of Burma. The Secretary and the Foreign Minister also reaffirmed commitment to close cooperation between and among the United States, the Republic of Korea, and Japan on a broad range of issues, including working towards the denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States Welcomes Actions by Armenia and Azerbaijan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-welcomes-actions-by-armenia-and-azerbaijan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 17:21:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States welcomes the release by Azerbaijan of 15 Armenian detainees and their return to their families in Armenia. We also welcome Armenia’s decision to provide Azerbaijan with important information that will facilitate humanitarian demining and avoid future casualties. We are grateful to Prime Minister Irakli Garibashvili and the Government of Georgia for the essential role Georgia played in facilitating these steps, which bring the people of the region closer to the peaceful and prosperous future they deserve.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States is pleased to support these steps and hopes they will lay the groundwork for additional cooperation. We continue to call for the return of all detainees and stand ready to assist the countries of the region in their efforts to continue cooperation and resolve outstanding issues between them. We also continue to urge Armenia and Azerbaijan to reengage in substantive negotiations under the auspices of the OSCE Minsk Group Co-Chairs to negotiate a comprehensive political settlement to the conflict.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States welcomes the release by Azerbaijan of 15 Armenian detainees and their return to their families in Armenia. We also welcome Armenia’s decision to provide Azerbaijan with important information that will facilitate humanitarian demining and avoid future casualties. We are grateful to Prime Minister Irakli Garibashvili and the Government of Georgia for the essential role Georgia played in facilitating these steps, which bring the people of the region closer to the peaceful and prosperous future they deserve.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States is pleased to support these steps and hopes they will lay the groundwork for additional cooperation. We continue to call for the return of all detainees and stand ready to assist the countries of the region in their efforts to continue cooperation and resolve outstanding issues between them. We also continue to urge Armenia and Azerbaijan to reengage in substantive negotiations under the auspices of the OSCE Minsk Group Co-Chairs to negotiate a comprehensive political settlement to the conflict.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russia National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/russia-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 04:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251457</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the citizens of Russia as you celebrate Russia Day.  This holiday marks the significant step Russia made on June 12, 1991, when it held its first free, open, and fair elections, and adopted the Declaration of Russian State Sovereignty.  This important document recognized the democratic aspirations and sovereignty of the peoples of Russia and guaranteed their rights and equal protections under the rule of law, and their right to life and dignity, honoring their centuries of history, culture, and traditions.</p>
<p>I take this opportunity to reaffirm the United States’ desire for constructive engagement with the government of the Russian Federation in the interest of promoting a more stable and predictable bilateral relationship.  Likewise, we remain steadfastly committed to supporting the Russian people as they continue to build on the aspirations outlined in the Declaration of Russian State Sovereignty and their desire to work together with the international community and cooperate peacefully on matters of global concern.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the citizens of Russia as you celebrate Russia Day.  This holiday marks the significant step Russia made on June 12, 1991, when it held its first free, open, and fair elections, and adopted the Declaration of Russian State Sovereignty.  This important document recognized the democratic aspirations and sovereignty of the peoples of Russia and guaranteed their rights and equal protections under the rule of law, and their right to life and dignity, honoring their centuries of history, culture, and traditions.</p>
<p>I take this opportunity to reaffirm the United States’ desire for constructive engagement with the government of the Russian Federation in the interest of promoting a more stable and predictable bilateral relationship.  Likewise, we remain steadfastly committed to supporting the Russian people as they continue to build on the aspirations outlined in the Declaration of Russian State Sovereignty and their desire to work together with the international community and cooperate peacefully on matters of global concern.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On the Occasion of the Official Birthday of Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/on-the-occasion-of-the-official-birthday-of-her-majesty-queen-elizabeth-ii/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251448</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I offer my best wishes to Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II and to the people of the United Kingdom as you celebrate Her Majesty’s birthday.</p>
<p>Queen Elizabeth’s lifetime of leadership and dedication to service is an example for all nations.  Under her stewardship, the United Kingdom has withstood great challenges and enjoyed longstanding stability.  Throughout her reign, the United States has partnered with the United Kingdom to advance globally the democratic freedoms and values that lie at the heart of our mutual prosperity and security.</p>
<p>As host of both the G7 and the United Nations Climate Change Conference, this is a historic year of leadership for the United Kingdom.  We look forward to continuing to partner with the United Kingdom bilaterally and multilaterally to address the most urgent global challenges: ending and recovering from the COVID-19 pandemic, addressing the threat of climate change, and defending democratic values and open societies.</p>
<p>On this special day, I wish Her Majesty the Queen and the British people a year of health, peace, prosperity, and happiness.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I offer my best wishes to Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II and to the people of the United Kingdom as you celebrate Her Majesty’s birthday.</p>
<p>Queen Elizabeth’s lifetime of leadership and dedication to service is an example for all nations.  Under her stewardship, the United Kingdom has withstood great challenges and enjoyed longstanding stability.  Throughout her reign, the United States has partnered with the United Kingdom to advance globally the democratic freedoms and values that lie at the heart of our mutual prosperity and security.</p>
<p>As host of both the G7 and the United Nations Climate Change Conference, this is a historic year of leadership for the United Kingdom.  We look forward to continuing to partner with the United Kingdom bilaterally and multilaterally to address the most urgent global challenges: ending and recovering from the COVID-19 pandemic, addressing the threat of climate change, and defending democratic values and open societies.</p>
<p>On this special day, I wish Her Majesty the Queen and the British people a year of health, peace, prosperity, and happiness.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>World Day Against Child Labor</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/world-day-against-child-labor/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 23:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251488</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Child labor harms the physical and mental development of children, depriving them of their childhood, their potential, and their dignity. For their future and for the world’s future, we must do more to combat child labor and protect children from this scourge. June 12 is the World Day Against Child Labor, and 2021 is the International Year for the Elimination of Child Labor. We pledge to renew our commitment to end child labor and call upon our international partners to do the same.</p>
<p>Last year, the Convention on the Elimination of the Worst Forms of Child Labor became the first convention ratified by every member of the International Labor Organization (ILO). The world agrees: Children should not be subjected to hazardous work or criminal exploitation. We have been making progress to protect children from exploitation. Since 2000, the number of children involved in child labor around the world steadily decreased. The ILO and UNICEF’s latest estimate, however, shows the first increase in child labor in two decades – the world’s progress combating child labor becoming another victim of the global pandemic. We must collectively do more.</p>
<p>The United States’ trade agreements, trade preference programs, and finance programs are conditioned on governments taking steps to enforce child labor and other labor laws. The Department of State continues to monitor and report on child labor in our annual Human Rights Report and Trafficking in Persons Report, and we contribute to the Department of Labor’s annual Findings on the Worst Forms of Child Labor, the most comprehensive global report on this subject. The United States is committed to continuing its fight to end these practices and protect children around the world.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Child labor harms the physical and mental development of children, depriving them of their childhood, their potential, and their dignity. For their future and for the world’s future, we must do more to combat child labor and protect children from this scourge. June 12 is the World Day Against Child Labor, and 2021 is the International Year for the Elimination of Child Labor. We pledge to renew our commitment to end child labor and call upon our international partners to do the same.</p>
<p>Last year, the Convention on the Elimination of the Worst Forms of Child Labor became the first convention ratified by every member of the International Labor Organization (ILO). The world agrees: Children should not be subjected to hazardous work or criminal exploitation. We have been making progress to protect children from exploitation. Since 2000, the number of children involved in child labor around the world steadily decreased. The ILO and UNICEF’s latest estimate, however, shows the first increase in child labor in two decades – the world’s progress combating child labor becoming another victim of the global pandemic. We must collectively do more.</p>
<p>The United States’ trade agreements, trade preference programs, and finance programs are conditioned on governments taking steps to enforce child labor and other labor laws. The Department of State continues to monitor and report on child labor in our annual Human Rights Report and Trafficking in Persons Report, and we contribute to the Department of Labor’s annual Findings on the Worst Forms of Child Labor, the most comprehensive global report on this subject. The United States is committed to continuing its fight to end these practices and protect children around the world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
