<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 16:11:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Under Secretary Fernandez’s Travel to Houston for CERAWeek</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-fernandezs-travel-to-houston-for-ceraweek/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 16:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">On March 7-8, 2022, Under Secretary for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment Jose W. Fernandez will travel to Houston, Texas, for CERAWeek 2022 to engage local stakeholders and foreign government officials on global issues, including supply chains, energy security, and building the clean energy economy of the future.  Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry, Special Advisor for Energy Security Amos Hochstein, and Bureau of Energy Resources Senior Bureau Official Harry Kamian will also participate in CERAWeek to promote clean energy and security policy objectives.</p>
<p align="left">During CERAWeek, Under Secretary Fernandez will participate in panels and discussions with senior leaders from governments, nonprofit organizations, and the private sector on a range of issues.  These include deepening collaboration to accelerate the energy transition, ensuring equitable access to U.S. government resources, supporting U.S. companies abroad and working together to address supply chain disruptions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">On March 7-8, 2022, Under Secretary for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment Jose W. Fernandez will travel to Houston, Texas, for CERAWeek 2022 to engage local stakeholders and foreign government officials on global issues, including supply chains, energy security, and building the clean energy economy of the future.  Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry, Special Advisor for Energy Security Amos Hochstein, and Bureau of Energy Resources Senior Bureau Official Harry Kamian will also participate in CERAWeek to promote clean energy and security policy objectives.</p>
<p align="left">During CERAWeek, Under Secretary Fernandez will participate in panels and discussions with senior leaders from governments, nonprofit organizations, and the private sector on a range of issues.  These include deepening collaboration to accelerate the energy transition, ensuring equitable access to U.S. government resources, supporting U.S. companies abroad and working together to address supply chain disruptions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken On CNN State of the Union with Jake Tapper</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-on-cnn-state-of-the-union-with-jake-tapper/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 15:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Chisinau, Moldova</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Joining me now from Moldova, the latest stop on his European trip, U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken.  Secretary Blinken, thanks for joining us.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks, Jake.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So you say Russian strikes are hitting schools, hitting hospitals, targeting drinking water, targeting electricity grids.  I understand that the U.S. doesn’t want to hurt European economies, the U.S. doesn’t want to risk direct military confrontation, but it seems clear that the sanctions that have been implemented so far have not immediately stopped Putin’s advance, that the line that’s being drawn right now is not likely going to be enough to stop him.  So what do you say to the innocent Ukrainian civilians who are saying, “Why has the West not directly intervened to save them from the slaughter?”</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, first, Jake, I’m here in Europe working with NATO Allies, European Union partners, and others working on, among other things, increasing even more the extraordinary pressure that’s already been exerted on Russia with unprecedented actions and sanctions that are having a crippling effect on the Russian economy as well as additional steps that we can take to help our friends in Ukraine, including getting them even more assistance on top of the historic aid we’ve gotten them to date and that has been effective.</p>
<p>Vladimir Putin has, unfortunately, the capacity, with the sheer manpower that he has in Ukraine and the overmatch that he has, the ability to keep grinding things down against incredibly resilient and courageous Ukrainians.  And I think we have to be prepared for this to last for some time.  But just winning a battle is not winning the war.  Taking a city does not mean he’s taking the hearts and minds of the Ukrainian people.  On the contrary, he is destined to lose.  The Ukrainian people have demonstrated that they will not allow themselves to be subjugated to Vladimir Putin or to Russia’s rule.  But it could take – it could take some time, and meanwhile the suffering is real.  It’s terrible.  I’ve met with people who are refugees from Ukraine who have been forced to flee, women and children who are in neighboring countries, the men remaining in Ukraine to fight.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Right.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We’re doing everything that we can to bring this to an end as quickly as we can, but this still may go on for a while.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So you point out accurately that the sanctions are unprecedented.  They are.  They’re stronger than they’ve ever been.  But the U.S. still has not moved as quickly as the EU has on sanctions against the Russian political elite.  I mean the Duma, the national security council, the cabinet, their families, the top 100 oligarchs.  The U.S. has not banned imports of Russian oil.  The U.S. has not rolled out trade sanctions.  We’re still working with the Russians on the Iran deal.  Why not do everything we can now?  Speaker Pelosi said she’s willing to cut off all imports of Russian oil.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We’re adding to the sanctions virtually every day.  We’re doing it in coordination with Europeans.  When there’s a difference between us, if there’s a loophole on one side or the other, we’re closing it.  That’s part of the work that I was doing here.  And when it comes to oil, Russian oil, I was on the phone yesterday with the President and other members of the cabinet on exactly this subject, and we are now talking to our European partners and allies to look in a coordinated way at the prospect of banning the import of Russian oil while making sure that there is still an appropriate supply of oil on world markets.  That’s a very active discussion as we speak.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  The U.S. has ruled out a no-fly zone for fears of getting into direct military conflict with Russia.  Zelenskyy said, quote, “Then give me the planes.”  Now, you’ve said you’re in active discussions about providing U.S. planes to Poland so that they can give planes that the Ukrainians are familiar with to Ukraine.  Are you going to do that?  And can you explain why the U.S. cannot give Ukraine the planes directly?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So we are working with Poland as we speak to see if we can backfill anything that they provide to the Ukrainians.  We very much support them, providing MiGs, SUs, planes that Ukrainian can fly, to the Ukrainians.  But we also want to see if we can be helpful, as I said, in making sure that whatever they provide to the Ukrainians, something goes to them to make up for any gap in the security for Poland that might result.  We’re actively talking about that right now.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  The International Criminal Court is opening an investigation into Russian war crimes.  The U.S. Embassy said it’s a war crime to attack a nuclear power plant.  They’ve tweeted that out – the U.S. Embassy in Kyiv.  But then the State Department told other embassies around the world to not retweet it, which is a confusing step.  Has the U.S. seen evidence that Russia is committing war crimes or not?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Jake, we’ve seen very credible reports of deliberate attacks on civilians, which would constitute a war crime.  We’ve seen very credible reports about the use of certain weapons.  And what we’re doing right now is documenting all of this, putting it all together, looking at it, and making sure that as people and the appropriate organizations and institutions investigate whether war crimes have been or are being committed, that we can support whatever they’re doing.  So right now we’re looking at these reports.  They’re very credible.  And we’re documenting everything.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Western intelligence suggests that China asked Russia to not invade Ukraine until after the Olympics.  You talked to the Chinese foreign minister yesterday.  You noted that, quote, “The world is watching to see which nations stand up for the basic principles of freedom, self-determination, and sovereignty,” unquote.  China’s not doing that, are they?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Jake, you’re right; I spent about an hour on the phone with my counterpart, the Chinese foreign minister, the other day.  And one of the things that I said to him, as I said actually before Russia committed this aggression against Ukraine, is that China speaks often about the sanctity of this principle of sovereignty, and here you have a permanent member of the United Nations Security Council, the council that came into existence with the responsibility of keeping peace and security around the world, respecting the sovereignty of states; you have one of its permanent members violating that very principle.</p>
<p>And so we would expect China, based on everything it’s said in the past, to stand up and make its voice heard.  Its voice is very important in this.  And 141 countries in the UN system came forward to condemn Russia’s aggression against Ukraine and to stand up for Ukraine.  So we are looking to China to make its voice heard.  That voice counts, and I hope that they’ll do that.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  More than 1.5 million refugees have already fled Ukraine.  Millions more are expected to do so.  The UN says it could be the largest refugee crisis in Europe this century.  And I know you visited with some of these refugees in Poland yesterday.  Is the U.S. willing to accept Ukrainian refugees, and if so how many?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Of course, we’ll look at that.  In fact, you’re right;  I was on the border.  There was a terrific CODEL from the House led by, I think, someone you’re going to have on shortly, Mike McCaul, and Greg Meeks, the – Mike the ranking member and Greg the chairman of the House Foreign Affairs Committee, a bipartisan delegation.  We all looked at this.  We met with many of the women and children who have been forced to flee Ukraine.  We’re committed – the United States is committed to doing anything we can, first of all, to support the countries that are bearing the immediate burden of taking in Ukrainians.  And then as appropriate, if people seek refugee status in the United States, of course, we will look at that and I’m sure act on that.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Secretary of State Antony Blinken, thank you so much for your time.  Really appreciate it.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you, Jake.  Good to be with you.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Chisinau, Moldova</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Joining me now from Moldova, the latest stop on his European trip, U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken.  Secretary Blinken, thanks for joining us.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks, Jake.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So you say Russian strikes are hitting schools, hitting hospitals, targeting drinking water, targeting electricity grids.  I understand that the U.S. doesn’t want to hurt European economies, the U.S. doesn’t want to risk direct military confrontation, but it seems clear that the sanctions that have been implemented so far have not immediately stopped Putin’s advance, that the line that’s being drawn right now is not likely going to be enough to stop him.  So what do you say to the innocent Ukrainian civilians who are saying, “Why has the West not directly intervened to save them from the slaughter?”</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, first, Jake, I’m here in Europe working with NATO Allies, European Union partners, and others working on, among other things, increasing even more the extraordinary pressure that’s already been exerted on Russia with unprecedented actions and sanctions that are having a crippling effect on the Russian economy as well as additional steps that we can take to help our friends in Ukraine, including getting them even more assistance on top of the historic aid we’ve gotten them to date and that has been effective.</p>
<p>Vladimir Putin has, unfortunately, the capacity, with the sheer manpower that he has in Ukraine and the overmatch that he has, the ability to keep grinding things down against incredibly resilient and courageous Ukrainians.  And I think we have to be prepared for this to last for some time.  But just winning a battle is not winning the war.  Taking a city does not mean he’s taking the hearts and minds of the Ukrainian people.  On the contrary, he is destined to lose.  The Ukrainian people have demonstrated that they will not allow themselves to be subjugated to Vladimir Putin or to Russia’s rule.  But it could take – it could take some time, and meanwhile the suffering is real.  It’s terrible.  I’ve met with people who are refugees from Ukraine who have been forced to flee, women and children who are in neighboring countries, the men remaining in Ukraine to fight.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Right.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We’re doing everything that we can to bring this to an end as quickly as we can, but this still may go on for a while.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So you point out accurately that the sanctions are unprecedented.  They are.  They’re stronger than they’ve ever been.  But the U.S. still has not moved as quickly as the EU has on sanctions against the Russian political elite.  I mean the Duma, the national security council, the cabinet, their families, the top 100 oligarchs.  The U.S. has not banned imports of Russian oil.  The U.S. has not rolled out trade sanctions.  We’re still working with the Russians on the Iran deal.  Why not do everything we can now?  Speaker Pelosi said she’s willing to cut off all imports of Russian oil.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We’re adding to the sanctions virtually every day.  We’re doing it in coordination with Europeans.  When there’s a difference between us, if there’s a loophole on one side or the other, we’re closing it.  That’s part of the work that I was doing here.  And when it comes to oil, Russian oil, I was on the phone yesterday with the President and other members of the cabinet on exactly this subject, and we are now talking to our European partners and allies to look in a coordinated way at the prospect of banning the import of Russian oil while making sure that there is still an appropriate supply of oil on world markets.  That’s a very active discussion as we speak.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  The U.S. has ruled out a no-fly zone for fears of getting into direct military conflict with Russia.  Zelenskyy said, quote, “Then give me the planes.”  Now, you’ve said you’re in active discussions about providing U.S. planes to Poland so that they can give planes that the Ukrainians are familiar with to Ukraine.  Are you going to do that?  And can you explain why the U.S. cannot give Ukraine the planes directly?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So we are working with Poland as we speak to see if we can backfill anything that they provide to the Ukrainians.  We very much support them, providing MiGs, SUs, planes that Ukrainian can fly, to the Ukrainians.  But we also want to see if we can be helpful, as I said, in making sure that whatever they provide to the Ukrainians, something goes to them to make up for any gap in the security for Poland that might result.  We’re actively talking about that right now.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  The International Criminal Court is opening an investigation into Russian war crimes.  The U.S. Embassy said it’s a war crime to attack a nuclear power plant.  They’ve tweeted that out – the U.S. Embassy in Kyiv.  But then the State Department told other embassies around the world to not retweet it, which is a confusing step.  Has the U.S. seen evidence that Russia is committing war crimes or not?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Jake, we’ve seen very credible reports of deliberate attacks on civilians, which would constitute a war crime.  We’ve seen very credible reports about the use of certain weapons.  And what we’re doing right now is documenting all of this, putting it all together, looking at it, and making sure that as people and the appropriate organizations and institutions investigate whether war crimes have been or are being committed, that we can support whatever they’re doing.  So right now we’re looking at these reports.  They’re very credible.  And we’re documenting everything.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Western intelligence suggests that China asked Russia to not invade Ukraine until after the Olympics.  You talked to the Chinese foreign minister yesterday.  You noted that, quote, “The world is watching to see which nations stand up for the basic principles of freedom, self-determination, and sovereignty,” unquote.  China’s not doing that, are they?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Jake, you’re right; I spent about an hour on the phone with my counterpart, the Chinese foreign minister, the other day.  And one of the things that I said to him, as I said actually before Russia committed this aggression against Ukraine, is that China speaks often about the sanctity of this principle of sovereignty, and here you have a permanent member of the United Nations Security Council, the council that came into existence with the responsibility of keeping peace and security around the world, respecting the sovereignty of states; you have one of its permanent members violating that very principle.</p>
<p>And so we would expect China, based on everything it’s said in the past, to stand up and make its voice heard.  Its voice is very important in this.  And 141 countries in the UN system came forward to condemn Russia’s aggression against Ukraine and to stand up for Ukraine.  So we are looking to China to make its voice heard.  That voice counts, and I hope that they’ll do that.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  More than 1.5 million refugees have already fled Ukraine.  Millions more are expected to do so.  The UN says it could be the largest refugee crisis in Europe this century.  And I know you visited with some of these refugees in Poland yesterday.  Is the U.S. willing to accept Ukrainian refugees, and if so how many?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Of course, we’ll look at that.  In fact, you’re right;  I was on the border.  There was a terrific CODEL from the House led by, I think, someone you’re going to have on shortly, Mike McCaul, and Greg Meeks, the – Mike the ranking member and Greg the chairman of the House Foreign Affairs Committee, a bipartisan delegation.  We all looked at this.  We met with many of the women and children who have been forced to flee Ukraine.  We’re committed – the United States is committed to doing anything we can, first of all, to support the countries that are bearing the immediate burden of taking in Ukrainians.  And then as appropriate, if people seek refugee status in the United States, of course, we will look at that and I’m sure act on that.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Secretary of State Antony Blinken, thank you so much for your time.  Really appreciate it.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you, Jake.  Good to be with you.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken At a Meeting With Moldovan Civil Society</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-meeting-with-moldovan-civil-society/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 14:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321212</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Chisinau, Moldova</p>
<p>MediaCor</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR LOGSDON:</b>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.  It’s great to have you here.  If it’s all right with you, I will go ahead and make a couple of opening remarks.<b></b></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Please.<b></b></p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR LOGSDON:</b>  Introduce you to the experts so you know who we’re talking to, and then ask you to maybe say a word or two.<b></b></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Wonderful.<b></b></p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR LOGSDON:</b>  And then I’ll have each of them say just a slight bit about what they’re interested in and what they’d like you to know.<b></b></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Wonderful.  Thank you.<b></b></p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR LOGSDON:</b>  Thanks.<b></b></p>
<p>So 30 years after independence, obviously, the Republic of Moldova is at a critical moment, its economy, its workforce, and the democratic aspirations of its people increasingly focused on closer integration with Europe.  As in many countries, civil society is a leader in advocating for the changes needed for Moldova to become a fully democratic and prosperous country, fully secure within its internationally recognized borders and with a government that’s accountable to all of its citizens.  On March 3rd, the Government of the Republic of Moldova submitted its formal request for EU accession, and as Moldova considers its next steps toward Europe while welcoming and protecting a large number of refugees from Ukraine, we wanted you to hear from some of those who are working on the front lines of Moldova’s thriving civil society sector.</p>
<p>First, we have Nadejda, Nadejda Hriptievschi, a leading advocate for democratic reforms and human rights, followed by Victor Parlicov.  He’s one of the country’s foremost energy policy experts.  Following we have Nadine Gogu, and she leads the Independent Journalism Center, which supports free media in Moldova.  Then we have Ludmila Nofit, and Ludmila’s with Moldova’s preeminent foreign policy think tank.  And finally, but not last, we have Vadim Pistrinciuc, and he’s an expert in strategic development and conflict settlement, former member of parliament.  So you’ve got quite a range of interests here.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Wonderful.  Well, Ambassador, thank you so much, and to each and every one of you, thank you for taking some time today.  I was eager to meet you, but mostly to hear from you, because the work that you’ve been doing day in, day out to build different aspects of Moldova’s democracy is so vital for Moldova, but it’s also, I think, a very important lesson for many parts of the world, because even as we’ve seen in recent years some democracies in different ways fall back, Moldova keeps moving forward.  And that’s in no small measure because of the kind of work that you’re doing. <b></b></p>
<p>And I know that that work’s taken on a different kind of intensity in recent days with the war in Ukraine and the aggression by Russia against Ukraine.  I know some of you have friends, colleagues, and others who are in Ukraine and at risk now, others who’ve come here, and Moldova’s hospitality and support has been absolutely remarkable.<b></b></p>
<p>But it also underscores something else that’s important, I think, which is that the very work you’re doing here to build Moldova’s democracy, to build civil society, to build nongovernmental organizations – that’s exactly the kind of work that, among other things, President Putin is trying to destroy in Ukraine, because the very success of democracy is a threat to President Putin and the direction he’s taken his own country, Russia.  And so it only amplifies how important the work you’re doing is not only for Moldova but as a powerful example for the world.<b></b></p>
<p>But I’m mostly anxious to just hear from you, hear about your experiences, hear about your challenges.  As the ambassador said, we know well Moldova’s European aspirations and the work necessary to continue to advance in that direction, the reforms that are so important across different aspects of Moldovan society, whether it’s rule of law, an independent judiciary, an independent media.  All the kinds of things that you’re working on I’m very anxious to hear about, so with that, let me stop talking and hear from you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Chisinau, Moldova</p>
<p>MediaCor</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR LOGSDON:</b>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.  It’s great to have you here.  If it’s all right with you, I will go ahead and make a couple of opening remarks.<b></b></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Please.<b></b></p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR LOGSDON:</b>  Introduce you to the experts so you know who we’re talking to, and then ask you to maybe say a word or two.<b></b></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Wonderful.<b></b></p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR LOGSDON:</b>  And then I’ll have each of them say just a slight bit about what they’re interested in and what they’d like you to know.<b></b></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Wonderful.  Thank you.<b></b></p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR LOGSDON:</b>  Thanks.<b></b></p>
<p>So 30 years after independence, obviously, the Republic of Moldova is at a critical moment, its economy, its workforce, and the democratic aspirations of its people increasingly focused on closer integration with Europe.  As in many countries, civil society is a leader in advocating for the changes needed for Moldova to become a fully democratic and prosperous country, fully secure within its internationally recognized borders and with a government that’s accountable to all of its citizens.  On March 3rd, the Government of the Republic of Moldova submitted its formal request for EU accession, and as Moldova considers its next steps toward Europe while welcoming and protecting a large number of refugees from Ukraine, we wanted you to hear from some of those who are working on the front lines of Moldova’s thriving civil society sector.</p>
<p>First, we have Nadejda, Nadejda Hriptievschi, a leading advocate for democratic reforms and human rights, followed by Victor Parlicov.  He’s one of the country’s foremost energy policy experts.  Following we have Nadine Gogu, and she leads the Independent Journalism Center, which supports free media in Moldova.  Then we have Ludmila Nofit, and Ludmila’s with Moldova’s preeminent foreign policy think tank.  And finally, but not last, we have Vadim Pistrinciuc, and he’s an expert in strategic development and conflict settlement, former member of parliament.  So you’ve got quite a range of interests here.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Wonderful.  Well, Ambassador, thank you so much, and to each and every one of you, thank you for taking some time today.  I was eager to meet you, but mostly to hear from you, because the work that you’ve been doing day in, day out to build different aspects of Moldova’s democracy is so vital for Moldova, but it’s also, I think, a very important lesson for many parts of the world, because even as we’ve seen in recent years some democracies in different ways fall back, Moldova keeps moving forward.  And that’s in no small measure because of the kind of work that you’re doing. <b></b></p>
<p>And I know that that work’s taken on a different kind of intensity in recent days with the war in Ukraine and the aggression by Russia against Ukraine.  I know some of you have friends, colleagues, and others who are in Ukraine and at risk now, others who’ve come here, and Moldova’s hospitality and support has been absolutely remarkable.<b></b></p>
<p>But it also underscores something else that’s important, I think, which is that the very work you’re doing here to build Moldova’s democracy, to build civil society, to build nongovernmental organizations – that’s exactly the kind of work that, among other things, President Putin is trying to destroy in Ukraine, because the very success of democracy is a threat to President Putin and the direction he’s taken his own country, Russia.  And so it only amplifies how important the work you’re doing is not only for Moldova but as a powerful example for the world.<b></b></p>
<p>But I’m mostly anxious to just hear from you, hear about your experiences, hear about your challenges.  As the ambassador said, we know well Moldova’s European aspirations and the work necessary to continue to advance in that direction, the reforms that are so important across different aspects of Moldovan society, whether it’s rule of law, an independent judiciary, an independent media.  All the kinds of things that you’re working on I’m very anxious to hear about, so with that, let me stop talking and hear from you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Moldovan President Maia Sandu At a Joint Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-moldovan-president-maia-sandu-at-a-joint-press-availability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 14:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321205</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Chisinau, Moldova</p>
<p>The Presidency</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>(Via interpreter)  Dear President Maia Sandu, dear Secretary of State of the United States of America Antony Blinken, we start off the briefing organized on the occasion – on the visit occasion of Mr. Antony Blinken, Secretary of State of the United States of America.  We offer the floor to Ms. President Maia Sandu.</p>
<p><b>PRESIDENT SANDU:  </b>(Via interpreter)  Dear Secretary of State, welcome to Chisinau.  On the 18th of February, just two weeks ago, we marked the 30th anniversary from the establishment of diplomatic relationship between the Republic of Moldova and the United States of America.</p>
<p>Over three decades, the United States supported our efforts to consolidate the society and the economy, to build up a democratic state where every single citizen can think freely and exist freely.  We are grateful for the whole assistance offered by the government and by the citizens of the United States of America over this period of time, which amounts to over 1.7 billion U.S. dollars in assistance which helped us out to get consolidated as a statehood.  We do appreciate the firm support of the United States for the sovereignty and the territorial integrity of the Republic of Moldova as well as for our European path.</p>
<p>I wish you visited our country in peaceful times in the context of the anniversary of our bilateral relationship.  We do have great plans for the transformation of Moldova: we initiated the reform of the justice system; we started eliminating the corruption from the public institutions; we started working in order to improve the business environment to attract investments into the economy of the country, to encourage the development of local communities, and to rethink the education system of our country in order to prepare Moldova to cope better with the challenges of the time.</p>
<p>We want to build a resilient, competitive, prosperous and innovative country – a country which does invest into its people and which is capable to channel energy and the creativity of its citizens in order to build a place where people really want to live.</p>
<p>The reality we woke up on the 24th of February, however, set our plans on hold.  We are now living a dark period of time – a dark period of time for the whole region where all efforts are being directed in order to strengthen the society around one single objective: peace in the region.  As far as you know, the war in Ukraine is unfolding exactly at the border with our country.  We firmly condemned the military aggression against Ukraine and we called to peace from the very first hour of the military actions.  We continue calling to dialogue as well as to the possibility to identify some peaceful solutions as the only way to seize cease those violent actions against Ukraine and its citizens.</p>
<p>As a neutral country – and this is a principle enshrined in our constitution – we decided to stretch a hand of help to the people which are directly affected by the plague of the war.  From the very first hours of the armed attack against Ukraine, Moldova received on its territory the citizens from the neighboring country which are trying to flee from the bombs.  Over 250,000 people crossed the border from Ukraine to the Republic of Moldova from the beginning of the war.  A big part of those people stay in our country so far.  The employees of the public services – border police, customs officers, (inaudible) medical doctors, social assistants, local authorities, diplomats, but also a lot of volunteers – mobilized their efforts in order to help out the refuges which are arriving from Ukraine.  Thousands of people from all the regions of the country joined this effort.</p>
<p>When entering the Republic of Moldova, the refugees immediately received some hot meal, transportation, and a shelter in a temporary placement center or even in the houses of our people.  Tens of thousands of families from the whole country housed people from Ukraine over those days.  It’s a significant effort for a country with a population which is below 3 million and with quite humble incomes.  But despite those high challenges which represent this increasing inflow of refugees from the neighboring country, we cannot turn our back to those people.  Majority of refugees are women, children, and elderly.  They cross our border being exhausted, desperate, after long hours of journey escaping from the war.  It is our moral duty to help them out, and we’ll continue fulfilling this mission to our best extent.</p>
<p>Dear Secretary of State, the Republic of Moldova does need assistance and immediate and significant contribution of the international community so that our people and our economy can cope with these challenges and the inflow of refugees.  We do need urgently assistance for the temporary accommodation of those people in order to offer them the most necessary items and also to be capable to redirect the inflow of refugees towards the European countries which have a high capacity to receive them.  Some states already expressed the availability to take up the refugees from Ukraine, also to accommodate them, in the upcoming period of time.  But only through joint efforts, consistent efforts, rapid efforts of all the partners we can help out Ukraine.</p>
<p>We do need rapid assistance and involvement of the international community first of all in order to cease the battles and to restore the peace.  I do hope that the tour that you are undertaking over those days in the countries of this region contributes, together with the visits of some other high-ranking officials, to the peace efforts of Ukraine.  This is what we all want.  This is what we all deserve, especially the Ukrainians.</p>
<p>Dear Secretary of State, Mr. Blinken, the Republic of Moldova and the United States have developed a very good relationship in those over 30 years of cooperation and friendship relationship.  I do appreciate the strategic partnership between our countries, and I do hope that we will see each other again in some better times when we will be able to discuss how to advance, how to move forwards on the subjects which are included on the bilateral agenda of our countries.  I do hope that your visit gives a new impetus to our partnership.  We want to continue the political dialogue, the security dialogue between our states; we want to develop projects which are directed towards the development of the energy resilience of our country; as well as to advance on the dialogue for justice and to collaborate in the field of the asset recovery.</p>
<p>The Moldo-American partnership will help us out to strengthen the resilience of the Republic of Moldova as well as to strengthen the capacity of our country to cope with the challenges of the time, while a stronger, more resilient Moldova can become a pole of stability and development in the region – a trustworthy partner as well as a stronghold of the free world.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you, Ms. President.  Now we pass the floor to the Secretary of State, Mr. Antony Blinken.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  President Sandu, thank you so much for the very warm welcome to the Republic of Moldova.  It’s actually been almost seven years to the day since my last visit here, and it’s great to be back – although, as you said, I wish it was under somewhat different circumstances.  Thank you as well to the prime minister, to the foreign minister, all our colleagues who have received us so well today.  And I’m also particularly glad that our new Ambassador Kent Logsdon has arrived here in Chisinau I think just last month.  For us, having confirmed ambassadors in place is vital for our cooperation with countries around the world, and that’s especially important now.</p>
<p>In the 30 years since Moldova and the United States began diplomatic relations, we’ve never faced a moment as urgent and as challenging as the one that we face today.  Russia’s unprovoked, unwarranted war on Ukraine has kicked off a humanitarian crisis that is already having a vast effect across the region, including here in the Republic of Moldova.  As of today, as the president said, an estimated 240,000 people from Ukraine have crossed the border into Moldova, fleeing for their lives.  They’re mostly women and children.  Their number will grow.</p>
<p>As I told President Sandu, Moldova deserves the world’s gratitude for welcoming and protecting Ukrainians.  And as the prime minister, president, and foreign minister and I discussed today, the United States will do all that we can to help Moldova as it cares for people who have already been through so much.  Our administration has requested of Congress $2.75 billion in emergency assistance, humanitarian assistance, both to meet the needs of vulnerable people and communities inside Ukraine and also to help countries like Moldova supporting refugees and address the humanitarian crisis from outside Ukraine.  The international community also has a responsibility to help Moldova deal with the impacts of war.  We’ll drive that message in our engagement with international organizations and other countries around the world.</p>
<p>Russia’s invasion of Ukraine is a violation of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity enshrined in the United Nations Charter.  One hundred and forty-one countries at the United Nations stood up for those principles and against Russia’s assault on them.  The United States wants to make clear our strong support for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all countries, including the Republic of Moldova.</p>
<p>Countries have a right to choose their own futures.  Moldova has chosen the path of democracy, a more inclusive economy, a closer relationship with the countries and institutions of Europe.  The United States supports Moldova in those efforts, grounded in our respect for the neutrality that’s enshrined in Moldova’s constitution.  Our partnership addresses the key challenges of our time, the things that we should be working on and focused on, which is exactly another reason why this war of choice is such a terrible thing – it takes us away from things that we need to be working on together.</p>
<p>But we’ll continue to do that.  The United States delivered hundreds of thousands of COVID-19 vaccines to Moldova and millions of dollars in pandemic-related assistance.  We will invest $18 million over the next years to help strengthen and diversify Moldova’s energy sector.  Greater energy security is vital for your sovereignty.  We support the OSCE-led 5+2 negotiations to find a comprehensive settlement to the Transnistrian conflict that upholds Moldova’s sovereignty and territorial integrity with a special status for Transnistria.  And we’ll seek every opportunity to deepen the ties between our countries – economic ties, educational ties, people-to-people ties, because we want our friendship with the people of Moldova to grow even stronger.</p>
<p>In the face of the global challenges that we face today, we’re all going to be much more successful when we work closely together as partners, especially among democratic partners.  We know that countries that respect human rights, uphold the rule of law, support inclusive and accountable governance for all their citizens, produce the best solutions to even the most difficult problems.  So we will support Moldova as you pursue your priorities: fighting corruption, driving democratic reform including increasing integrity and accountability in the public sector and the judiciary, and developing an independent media sector that can deliver reliable information and help fight disinformation.  As people around the world stand up to defend democratic values, Moldova is a powerful example of a democracy rising to the moment with vision and with determination.</p>
<p>This partnership between us is built on shared interests, it’s built on shared values.  We’re grateful to Moldova for 30 years of friendship.  We look forward to the next 30.  And on behalf of the American people, thank you again for your generosity toward the Ukrainian refugees at this urgent moment for democracy and for peace.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>(Via interpreter)  (Inaudible) the colleagues.  Now we’re going to take questions from the representatives of the Moldovan press and the United States media.  So we start off with the Moldovan media.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>(Via interpreter)  Radu Osipov, public TV Moldova.  I have a question for both Ms. Maia Sandu and Antony Blinken.  Figures prove that in the first 10 days of the war, Moldova received the biggest amount of refugees from Ukraine.  It’s again by comparison with the population of the Republic of Moldova.  It’s a huge effort for our country.  What can the international community do in order to directly help out those people and in order to cease the war in Ukraine?</p>
<p><b>PRESIDENT SANDU:  </b>(Via interpreter)  We will continue helping out all the people that have to flee from the war.  This is indeed a challenge, and this is exactly the reason why we have requested the international assistance in the shape of financial assistance that’s all to compensate all the expenditures that we suffer in order to be able to help out those people.  But secondly, we need some clear mechanisms to refer – to re-channel those refugees that would like to continue their journey to reach another country.  So those are two concrete requests that we have put forward, and obviously we also expect the expertise of the specialists that had been involved in managing this sort of situations earlier.  I mean, people that know how to deal with the refugees – so far, the Republic of Moldova had never faced such situations.</p>
<p>So those are the most important elements of assistance which we are expecting from the international community as well as from our partners.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Let me agree with what the president said.  There is a major effort underway involving countries around the world to support refugees arriving from the Ukraine, but first and foremost, the burden has been on neighboring countries like the Republic of Moldova, like Poland and others that are the immediate responders.  And what we’re seeing now is the international community join in to support these countries and to support the refugees.  And so you have the major international organizations, including the United Nations in particular, that’s bringing its expertise and resources to bear.</p>
<p>As I mentioned a moment ago, President Biden asked our Congress for emergency support to include very significant humanitarian support to help Ukraine deal with the humanitarian consequences of this war of aggression against Ukraine, both within Ukraine itself but also in the surrounding countries that are receiving refugees.</p>
<p>So we’re bringing our own technical expertise to bear, including here in the Republic of Moldova.  We’ll also be bringing resources to bear to help alleviate some of the burden that Moldova and other countries are carrying.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  (Via interpreter) Mihaela Ursu, TVR Moldova.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  A question to the Secretary of State.  Which way do you assess the submittal by the Republic of Moldova of the application to join European Union, and which way the United States of America can help us out in this process?  For example, could we expect maybe some support in order to strengthen our energy independence, which is vital, I think, in order to have independence – true independence in our country?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.  I of course can’t speak for the European Union, but I can say that we very much support Moldova’s European aspirations and welcome the work that’s being done in that direction.  This is the will of the Moldovan people, and we welcome the pursuit of closer ties and greater integration.  But ultimately, of course, that process is up to Moldova and the European Union and its member countries.</p>
<p>When it comes to energy independence, I think that’s absolutely vital.  That independence and energy security is actually critical to maintaining one’s sovereignty and independence, and that’s exactly why we are working to support Moldova in its efforts to build greater energy security and energy diversification.  We’re doing that with financial support to develop alternatives.  We’re doing it with expert support.  As it happens, our new ambassador, Ambassador Logsdon, is an expert in these very issues, and so we’ll be working very, very closely with Moldova as we have been already to help produce greater diversification, greater energy security in the coming years.  I think this is something vital to pursue for all countries, and we know also what can happen when any country is – it’s the case for many – overly reliant on others that prove in one way or another not to be reliable suppliers.</p>
<p>So this is very much a focus of what we’re doing together, and it’s something we’ll be pursuing very actively right now and in the months and years ahead.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  (In Moldovan.)</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  I’ll call on Lara – excuse me, Lara Jakes with <i>The New York Times</i>.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Good morning.  Hello, Madam President.  Thank you for having us.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken, given that the State Department has again urged Americans to leave Russia immediately, are you considering closing the U.S. Embassy in Moscow?  And regardless, what is the Biden administration doing about the detention of American basketball player Brittney Griner?  Was this a retaliatory move by the Russian Government and was the announcement of her arrest yesterday what prompted the new travel alert?</p>
<p>And then, finally:  How seriously is the U.S. considering selling additional F-16s to Poland so that Poland can give its MiGs to Ukraine?  And realistically, how quickly can this happen to help against the invasion?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Lara, thanks very much.  With regard to the individual you mentioned, there’s only so much I can say given the privacy considerations at this point.  Let me just say more generally, whenever an American is detained anywhere in the world, we of course stand ready to provide every possible assistance, and that includes in Russia, as you know, and we’ve talked about this for a long time when we talk about seeking the release of Paul Whelan and Trevor Reed for some time, both of whom are unjustly detained.  We have an embassy team that’s working on the cases of other Americans who are detained in Russia.  We’re doing everything we can to see to it that their rights are upheld and respected.</p>
<p>We’ve also advised Americans not to travel to Russia.  Similarly, we’re advising Americans in Russia to leave.  But from my perspective, in times like these it’s important that we maintain our diplomatic contacts, that we maintain the diplomatic support, particularly support that we can provide to Americans who may need it.  And so that’s what I’m focused on doing.</p>
<p>With regard to the planes, a couple of things.  First, just as a general proposition, over the past year we have provided more than a billion dollars in security assistance to Ukraine, more than in any single (inaudible) year.  We’re in very active conversations with Ukrainian officials, with the government, President Zelenskyy, Prime Minister Kuleba<a title="" href="https://mail.google.com/mail/u/0/#m_781799449323251992__ftn1" name="m_781799449323251992__ftnref1"></a> whom I saw yesterday, and others, to get an up-to-the-minute assessment of their needs.  And as we get that assessment, we’re working on seeing what we and allies and partners can deliver.</p>
<p>We are looking actively now at the question of airplanes that Poland may provide to Ukraine and looking at how we might be able to backfill should Poland decided to use those – to supply those planes.  I can’t speak to a timeline, but I can just tell you we’re looking at it very, very actively.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Yeah, thank you very much.  Madam President, what do you see as the implications of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine for Moldovan security?  And what concrete measures are you hoping to see from the U.S. in terms of support?  And additionally, if I may, have you seen any changes to the Russian troop levels in Transnistria?</p>
<p>And for Secretary Blinken, you’ve been very clear that the – about the U.S. commitment to NATO countries, but you’ve been equally clear that U.S. troops won’t fight to defend Ukraine.  In that context, what kind of assurances can the U.S. actually make to Moldova about its own security?</p>
<p><b>PRESIDENT SANDU:</b>  (Via interpreter)  Of course we do follow and we monitor the situation in Transnistria.  We do not have so far information or intelligence regarding some significant changes there.  However, this is a subject of high vulnerability.  I would like to remind you that on the territory of our country, we have troops of the Russian Federation which are deployed here illegally and this exists for decades.  Of course it’s a vulnerability.  We do not have information so far which would confirm the intention for those troops to be involved in some military actions in Ukraine.</p>
<p>However, in this region, of course, there is no possibility for us now to feel really safe or secure, especially when we watch what is going on, when we saw all those attacks and the war in Ukraine.  Obviously here, we think the Republic of Moldova, the authorities of the Republic of Moldova try to do their best in order to ensure the safety of the citizens of the Republic of Moldova.  Beyond this security aspect, there are multiple implications for us.  There are implications related to the economic field since the Republic of Moldova used to have some very close links, very close relationship with Ukraine, and now all the economic operators, all the companies, all the economic agents which used to be part of this relationship are being affected significantly currently.  Obviously it is very difficult now to reach out or to get some positive outcomes in attracting foreign investors currently, although we promised our citizens to bring investments to our country.  But in the current situation, of course, it is very typical, and as I mentioned earlier, this crisis of refugees places a high pressure over our economy.</p>
<p>Judging by the figures that we have available today, the number of refugees we chose to stay in the Republic of Moldova count for 3 percent of the number of the stable population, settled population.  You see just in 10 days such a significant figure, and obviously those figures will go up.  I want to repeat, it’s our moral duty to help out everyone who needs assistance, and we will help everyone who needs assistance.  However, we do need support from our partners in order to be capable to help out other people which will definitely continue arriving to our country.  And we do hope that this war is ceased as far – as soon as possible.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Peter, we strongly support Moldova’s territorial integrity, its sovereignty, as well as its constitutionally guaranteed neutrality.  You’ve seen the response that we’ve helped to mobilize around the world to Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.  Whenever and wherever that aggression might appear, we will do the same thing.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  (Via interpreter)  Dear Ms. President, dear Secretary of State, dear colleagues, thank you so much.  The briefing is over.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Chisinau, Moldova</p>
<p>The Presidency</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>(Via interpreter)  Dear President Maia Sandu, dear Secretary of State of the United States of America Antony Blinken, we start off the briefing organized on the occasion – on the visit occasion of Mr. Antony Blinken, Secretary of State of the United States of America.  We offer the floor to Ms. President Maia Sandu.</p>
<p><b>PRESIDENT SANDU:  </b>(Via interpreter)  Dear Secretary of State, welcome to Chisinau.  On the 18th of February, just two weeks ago, we marked the 30th anniversary from the establishment of diplomatic relationship between the Republic of Moldova and the United States of America.</p>
<p>Over three decades, the United States supported our efforts to consolidate the society and the economy, to build up a democratic state where every single citizen can think freely and exist freely.  We are grateful for the whole assistance offered by the government and by the citizens of the United States of America over this period of time, which amounts to over 1.7 billion U.S. dollars in assistance which helped us out to get consolidated as a statehood.  We do appreciate the firm support of the United States for the sovereignty and the territorial integrity of the Republic of Moldova as well as for our European path.</p>
<p>I wish you visited our country in peaceful times in the context of the anniversary of our bilateral relationship.  We do have great plans for the transformation of Moldova: we initiated the reform of the justice system; we started eliminating the corruption from the public institutions; we started working in order to improve the business environment to attract investments into the economy of the country, to encourage the development of local communities, and to rethink the education system of our country in order to prepare Moldova to cope better with the challenges of the time.</p>
<p>We want to build a resilient, competitive, prosperous and innovative country – a country which does invest into its people and which is capable to channel energy and the creativity of its citizens in order to build a place where people really want to live.</p>
<p>The reality we woke up on the 24th of February, however, set our plans on hold.  We are now living a dark period of time – a dark period of time for the whole region where all efforts are being directed in order to strengthen the society around one single objective: peace in the region.  As far as you know, the war in Ukraine is unfolding exactly at the border with our country.  We firmly condemned the military aggression against Ukraine and we called to peace from the very first hour of the military actions.  We continue calling to dialogue as well as to the possibility to identify some peaceful solutions as the only way to seize cease those violent actions against Ukraine and its citizens.</p>
<p>As a neutral country – and this is a principle enshrined in our constitution – we decided to stretch a hand of help to the people which are directly affected by the plague of the war.  From the very first hours of the armed attack against Ukraine, Moldova received on its territory the citizens from the neighboring country which are trying to flee from the bombs.  Over 250,000 people crossed the border from Ukraine to the Republic of Moldova from the beginning of the war.  A big part of those people stay in our country so far.  The employees of the public services – border police, customs officers, (inaudible) medical doctors, social assistants, local authorities, diplomats, but also a lot of volunteers – mobilized their efforts in order to help out the refuges which are arriving from Ukraine.  Thousands of people from all the regions of the country joined this effort.</p>
<p>When entering the Republic of Moldova, the refugees immediately received some hot meal, transportation, and a shelter in a temporary placement center or even in the houses of our people.  Tens of thousands of families from the whole country housed people from Ukraine over those days.  It’s a significant effort for a country with a population which is below 3 million and with quite humble incomes.  But despite those high challenges which represent this increasing inflow of refugees from the neighboring country, we cannot turn our back to those people.  Majority of refugees are women, children, and elderly.  They cross our border being exhausted, desperate, after long hours of journey escaping from the war.  It is our moral duty to help them out, and we’ll continue fulfilling this mission to our best extent.</p>
<p>Dear Secretary of State, the Republic of Moldova does need assistance and immediate and significant contribution of the international community so that our people and our economy can cope with these challenges and the inflow of refugees.  We do need urgently assistance for the temporary accommodation of those people in order to offer them the most necessary items and also to be capable to redirect the inflow of refugees towards the European countries which have a high capacity to receive them.  Some states already expressed the availability to take up the refugees from Ukraine, also to accommodate them, in the upcoming period of time.  But only through joint efforts, consistent efforts, rapid efforts of all the partners we can help out Ukraine.</p>
<p>We do need rapid assistance and involvement of the international community first of all in order to cease the battles and to restore the peace.  I do hope that the tour that you are undertaking over those days in the countries of this region contributes, together with the visits of some other high-ranking officials, to the peace efforts of Ukraine.  This is what we all want.  This is what we all deserve, especially the Ukrainians.</p>
<p>Dear Secretary of State, Mr. Blinken, the Republic of Moldova and the United States have developed a very good relationship in those over 30 years of cooperation and friendship relationship.  I do appreciate the strategic partnership between our countries, and I do hope that we will see each other again in some better times when we will be able to discuss how to advance, how to move forwards on the subjects which are included on the bilateral agenda of our countries.  I do hope that your visit gives a new impetus to our partnership.  We want to continue the political dialogue, the security dialogue between our states; we want to develop projects which are directed towards the development of the energy resilience of our country; as well as to advance on the dialogue for justice and to collaborate in the field of the asset recovery.</p>
<p>The Moldo-American partnership will help us out to strengthen the resilience of the Republic of Moldova as well as to strengthen the capacity of our country to cope with the challenges of the time, while a stronger, more resilient Moldova can become a pole of stability and development in the region – a trustworthy partner as well as a stronghold of the free world.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you, Ms. President.  Now we pass the floor to the Secretary of State, Mr. Antony Blinken.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  President Sandu, thank you so much for the very warm welcome to the Republic of Moldova.  It’s actually been almost seven years to the day since my last visit here, and it’s great to be back – although, as you said, I wish it was under somewhat different circumstances.  Thank you as well to the prime minister, to the foreign minister, all our colleagues who have received us so well today.  And I’m also particularly glad that our new Ambassador Kent Logsdon has arrived here in Chisinau I think just last month.  For us, having confirmed ambassadors in place is vital for our cooperation with countries around the world, and that’s especially important now.</p>
<p>In the 30 years since Moldova and the United States began diplomatic relations, we’ve never faced a moment as urgent and as challenging as the one that we face today.  Russia’s unprovoked, unwarranted war on Ukraine has kicked off a humanitarian crisis that is already having a vast effect across the region, including here in the Republic of Moldova.  As of today, as the president said, an estimated 240,000 people from Ukraine have crossed the border into Moldova, fleeing for their lives.  They’re mostly women and children.  Their number will grow.</p>
<p>As I told President Sandu, Moldova deserves the world’s gratitude for welcoming and protecting Ukrainians.  And as the prime minister, president, and foreign minister and I discussed today, the United States will do all that we can to help Moldova as it cares for people who have already been through so much.  Our administration has requested of Congress $2.75 billion in emergency assistance, humanitarian assistance, both to meet the needs of vulnerable people and communities inside Ukraine and also to help countries like Moldova supporting refugees and address the humanitarian crisis from outside Ukraine.  The international community also has a responsibility to help Moldova deal with the impacts of war.  We’ll drive that message in our engagement with international organizations and other countries around the world.</p>
<p>Russia’s invasion of Ukraine is a violation of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity enshrined in the United Nations Charter.  One hundred and forty-one countries at the United Nations stood up for those principles and against Russia’s assault on them.  The United States wants to make clear our strong support for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all countries, including the Republic of Moldova.</p>
<p>Countries have a right to choose their own futures.  Moldova has chosen the path of democracy, a more inclusive economy, a closer relationship with the countries and institutions of Europe.  The United States supports Moldova in those efforts, grounded in our respect for the neutrality that’s enshrined in Moldova’s constitution.  Our partnership addresses the key challenges of our time, the things that we should be working on and focused on, which is exactly another reason why this war of choice is such a terrible thing – it takes us away from things that we need to be working on together.</p>
<p>But we’ll continue to do that.  The United States delivered hundreds of thousands of COVID-19 vaccines to Moldova and millions of dollars in pandemic-related assistance.  We will invest $18 million over the next years to help strengthen and diversify Moldova’s energy sector.  Greater energy security is vital for your sovereignty.  We support the OSCE-led 5+2 negotiations to find a comprehensive settlement to the Transnistrian conflict that upholds Moldova’s sovereignty and territorial integrity with a special status for Transnistria.  And we’ll seek every opportunity to deepen the ties between our countries – economic ties, educational ties, people-to-people ties, because we want our friendship with the people of Moldova to grow even stronger.</p>
<p>In the face of the global challenges that we face today, we’re all going to be much more successful when we work closely together as partners, especially among democratic partners.  We know that countries that respect human rights, uphold the rule of law, support inclusive and accountable governance for all their citizens, produce the best solutions to even the most difficult problems.  So we will support Moldova as you pursue your priorities: fighting corruption, driving democratic reform including increasing integrity and accountability in the public sector and the judiciary, and developing an independent media sector that can deliver reliable information and help fight disinformation.  As people around the world stand up to defend democratic values, Moldova is a powerful example of a democracy rising to the moment with vision and with determination.</p>
<p>This partnership between us is built on shared interests, it’s built on shared values.  We’re grateful to Moldova for 30 years of friendship.  We look forward to the next 30.  And on behalf of the American people, thank you again for your generosity toward the Ukrainian refugees at this urgent moment for democracy and for peace.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>(Via interpreter)  (Inaudible) the colleagues.  Now we’re going to take questions from the representatives of the Moldovan press and the United States media.  So we start off with the Moldovan media.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>(Via interpreter)  Radu Osipov, public TV Moldova.  I have a question for both Ms. Maia Sandu and Antony Blinken.  Figures prove that in the first 10 days of the war, Moldova received the biggest amount of refugees from Ukraine.  It’s again by comparison with the population of the Republic of Moldova.  It’s a huge effort for our country.  What can the international community do in order to directly help out those people and in order to cease the war in Ukraine?</p>
<p><b>PRESIDENT SANDU:  </b>(Via interpreter)  We will continue helping out all the people that have to flee from the war.  This is indeed a challenge, and this is exactly the reason why we have requested the international assistance in the shape of financial assistance that’s all to compensate all the expenditures that we suffer in order to be able to help out those people.  But secondly, we need some clear mechanisms to refer – to re-channel those refugees that would like to continue their journey to reach another country.  So those are two concrete requests that we have put forward, and obviously we also expect the expertise of the specialists that had been involved in managing this sort of situations earlier.  I mean, people that know how to deal with the refugees – so far, the Republic of Moldova had never faced such situations.</p>
<p>So those are the most important elements of assistance which we are expecting from the international community as well as from our partners.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Let me agree with what the president said.  There is a major effort underway involving countries around the world to support refugees arriving from the Ukraine, but first and foremost, the burden has been on neighboring countries like the Republic of Moldova, like Poland and others that are the immediate responders.  And what we’re seeing now is the international community join in to support these countries and to support the refugees.  And so you have the major international organizations, including the United Nations in particular, that’s bringing its expertise and resources to bear.</p>
<p>As I mentioned a moment ago, President Biden asked our Congress for emergency support to include very significant humanitarian support to help Ukraine deal with the humanitarian consequences of this war of aggression against Ukraine, both within Ukraine itself but also in the surrounding countries that are receiving refugees.</p>
<p>So we’re bringing our own technical expertise to bear, including here in the Republic of Moldova.  We’ll also be bringing resources to bear to help alleviate some of the burden that Moldova and other countries are carrying.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  (Via interpreter) Mihaela Ursu, TVR Moldova.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  A question to the Secretary of State.  Which way do you assess the submittal by the Republic of Moldova of the application to join European Union, and which way the United States of America can help us out in this process?  For example, could we expect maybe some support in order to strengthen our energy independence, which is vital, I think, in order to have independence – true independence in our country?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.  I of course can’t speak for the European Union, but I can say that we very much support Moldova’s European aspirations and welcome the work that’s being done in that direction.  This is the will of the Moldovan people, and we welcome the pursuit of closer ties and greater integration.  But ultimately, of course, that process is up to Moldova and the European Union and its member countries.</p>
<p>When it comes to energy independence, I think that’s absolutely vital.  That independence and energy security is actually critical to maintaining one’s sovereignty and independence, and that’s exactly why we are working to support Moldova in its efforts to build greater energy security and energy diversification.  We’re doing that with financial support to develop alternatives.  We’re doing it with expert support.  As it happens, our new ambassador, Ambassador Logsdon, is an expert in these very issues, and so we’ll be working very, very closely with Moldova as we have been already to help produce greater diversification, greater energy security in the coming years.  I think this is something vital to pursue for all countries, and we know also what can happen when any country is – it’s the case for many – overly reliant on others that prove in one way or another not to be reliable suppliers.</p>
<p>So this is very much a focus of what we’re doing together, and it’s something we’ll be pursuing very actively right now and in the months and years ahead.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  (In Moldovan.)</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  I’ll call on Lara – excuse me, Lara Jakes with <i>The New York Times</i>.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Good morning.  Hello, Madam President.  Thank you for having us.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken, given that the State Department has again urged Americans to leave Russia immediately, are you considering closing the U.S. Embassy in Moscow?  And regardless, what is the Biden administration doing about the detention of American basketball player Brittney Griner?  Was this a retaliatory move by the Russian Government and was the announcement of her arrest yesterday what prompted the new travel alert?</p>
<p>And then, finally:  How seriously is the U.S. considering selling additional F-16s to Poland so that Poland can give its MiGs to Ukraine?  And realistically, how quickly can this happen to help against the invasion?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Lara, thanks very much.  With regard to the individual you mentioned, there’s only so much I can say given the privacy considerations at this point.  Let me just say more generally, whenever an American is detained anywhere in the world, we of course stand ready to provide every possible assistance, and that includes in Russia, as you know, and we’ve talked about this for a long time when we talk about seeking the release of Paul Whelan and Trevor Reed for some time, both of whom are unjustly detained.  We have an embassy team that’s working on the cases of other Americans who are detained in Russia.  We’re doing everything we can to see to it that their rights are upheld and respected.</p>
<p>We’ve also advised Americans not to travel to Russia.  Similarly, we’re advising Americans in Russia to leave.  But from my perspective, in times like these it’s important that we maintain our diplomatic contacts, that we maintain the diplomatic support, particularly support that we can provide to Americans who may need it.  And so that’s what I’m focused on doing.</p>
<p>With regard to the planes, a couple of things.  First, just as a general proposition, over the past year we have provided more than a billion dollars in security assistance to Ukraine, more than in any single (inaudible) year.  We’re in very active conversations with Ukrainian officials, with the government, President Zelenskyy, Prime Minister Kuleba<a title="" href="https://mail.google.com/mail/u/0/#m_781799449323251992__ftn1" name="m_781799449323251992__ftnref1"></a> whom I saw yesterday, and others, to get an up-to-the-minute assessment of their needs.  And as we get that assessment, we’re working on seeing what we and allies and partners can deliver.</p>
<p>We are looking actively now at the question of airplanes that Poland may provide to Ukraine and looking at how we might be able to backfill should Poland decided to use those – to supply those planes.  I can’t speak to a timeline, but I can just tell you we’re looking at it very, very actively.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Yeah, thank you very much.  Madam President, what do you see as the implications of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine for Moldovan security?  And what concrete measures are you hoping to see from the U.S. in terms of support?  And additionally, if I may, have you seen any changes to the Russian troop levels in Transnistria?</p>
<p>And for Secretary Blinken, you’ve been very clear that the – about the U.S. commitment to NATO countries, but you’ve been equally clear that U.S. troops won’t fight to defend Ukraine.  In that context, what kind of assurances can the U.S. actually make to Moldova about its own security?</p>
<p><b>PRESIDENT SANDU:</b>  (Via interpreter)  Of course we do follow and we monitor the situation in Transnistria.  We do not have so far information or intelligence regarding some significant changes there.  However, this is a subject of high vulnerability.  I would like to remind you that on the territory of our country, we have troops of the Russian Federation which are deployed here illegally and this exists for decades.  Of course it’s a vulnerability.  We do not have information so far which would confirm the intention for those troops to be involved in some military actions in Ukraine.</p>
<p>However, in this region, of course, there is no possibility for us now to feel really safe or secure, especially when we watch what is going on, when we saw all those attacks and the war in Ukraine.  Obviously here, we think the Republic of Moldova, the authorities of the Republic of Moldova try to do their best in order to ensure the safety of the citizens of the Republic of Moldova.  Beyond this security aspect, there are multiple implications for us.  There are implications related to the economic field since the Republic of Moldova used to have some very close links, very close relationship with Ukraine, and now all the economic operators, all the companies, all the economic agents which used to be part of this relationship are being affected significantly currently.  Obviously it is very difficult now to reach out or to get some positive outcomes in attracting foreign investors currently, although we promised our citizens to bring investments to our country.  But in the current situation, of course, it is very typical, and as I mentioned earlier, this crisis of refugees places a high pressure over our economy.</p>
<p>Judging by the figures that we have available today, the number of refugees we chose to stay in the Republic of Moldova count for 3 percent of the number of the stable population, settled population.  You see just in 10 days such a significant figure, and obviously those figures will go up.  I want to repeat, it’s our moral duty to help out everyone who needs assistance, and we will help everyone who needs assistance.  However, we do need support from our partners in order to be capable to help out other people which will definitely continue arriving to our country.  And we do hope that this war is ceased as far – as soon as possible.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Peter, we strongly support Moldova’s territorial integrity, its sovereignty, as well as its constitutionally guaranteed neutrality.  You’ve seen the response that we’ve helped to mobilize around the world to Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.  Whenever and wherever that aggression might appear, we will do the same thing.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  (Via interpreter)  Dear Ms. President, dear Secretary of State, dear colleagues, thank you so much.  The briefing is over.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Moldovan Prime Minister Natalia Gavrilita Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-moldovan-prime-minister-natalia-gavrilita-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 12:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Chisinau, Moldova</p>
<p>Government House</p>
<p><b>PRIME MINISTER GAVRILITA:</b>  Dear Secretary of State Blinken, welcome to Chisinau.  I’m sure we would have all loved to have met under different circumstances and for your visit to have occurred on a more positive occasion.  Yet precisely because our region has been plunged into war, it is even of more importance that your visit comes as a sign of strong support not only for our effort to deal with the large influx of refugees and to help the people of Ukraine, but also to support our aspiration to be part of the free world.</p>
<p>We strongly condemn the act of war on Ukraine and fully support the independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders.  We stand united with the people of Ukraine and our call is for restoration of peace as soon as possible, first and foremost through diplomatic efforts.</p>
<p>We are firmly committed to help those who are fleeing from Ukraine.  The government has put in place the most comprehensive humanitarian operation in the history of the Republic of Moldova.  As of this morning, we had more than 230,000 people who have crossed the border from Ukraine and 120,000 stayed in Moldova; 96,000 of them are Ukrainian citizens.  For a small country like Moldova, proportionately this is a very large number and managing such an influx has only been possible because of the extraordinary solidarity shown by every person, every company, every nongovernmental organization.  Everybody has come together to host, to provide shelter, to provide food, to provide assistance to those who are fleeing the war.</p>
<p>But we will need assistance to deal with this influx, and we need this quickly and through flexible instruments.  Unfortunately, this humanitarian crisis comes on top of the developmental challenges that Moldova already had, and it was dealing with global challenges like the pandemic and energy crisis and inflation.  So we were already in double-digit inflation.  This war will also not only cost us in terms of the humanitarian cost, but economically, trade with Ukraine has been a very important element of our economy and we see disruptions of transportation routes and we see a global impact economically of this war.</p>
<p>So we count on your quick and comprehensive support as we have always had, and we are very grateful for the support that the U.S. Government has provided for the development of Moldova and to ensure the well-being of its citizens.</p>
<p>And finally, I just want to mention that we’ve – while we are facing these unprecedented circumstances, we are firmly committed to our path for European integration.  We believe that this is an agenda to transform Moldova into a modern, prosperous European state based on the fundamental values of human rights and the rule of law.  And we are committed to steer towards membership in the European Union.  We have submitted our application on the 3rd of March.  And as we embark on this journey, we know that we can count on the friendship and the strong support with the United States.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Prime Minister, thank you very, very much.  And indeed, you can count on that support across the board.</p>
<p>Let me first say, as you noted so well, this terrible, unprovoked war of choice is having, of course, profound consequences for the Ukrainian people, who are suffering terribly as a result while showing extraordinary resilience, but it’s also having consequences beyond Ukraine’s borders, including here in Moldova.  We admire the generosity, the hospitality, the willingness to be such good friends to people who are in distress, and indeed, we want to do everything we can to help you deal with the burden that this is imposing.  But we’re grateful for it.</p>
<p>As you also noted, at a time when all of us have so many things that we need to do to make the lives of our citizens better – dealing with what’s left of COVID-19, advancing the economic recovery that touches everyone, meeting the challenge of climate change and transforming our economies to account for that, so many things that we need to do for our societies, for our people – the last thing anyone needed or anyone wanted was a war, especially one that was totally unnecessary, totally unprovoked and, I’m afraid, premeditated.  And so the consequences, as you point out, go beyond Ukraine.  They go beyond even Ukraine’s neighbors.  They are in fact global because this is having an impact on everything that we actually need to be doing and should be doing.  And like you, we want to see it brought to the swiftest possible conclusion.</p>
<p>But meanwhile, we’re prepared to do everything we can in support of the Ukrainian people, in support of Ukraine’s neighbors who are standing up for the Ukrainian people and helping those in distress, those fleeing, and, of course, continuing to put pressure on President Putin and his government to change course.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, though, we’re also very, very pleased to be working closely with you.  I am in effect back to Moldova because this is my second visit here.  I was here in 2016.  It’s wonderful to be back.  And it’s especially wonderful to be back because your story is such a powerful one and positive one at a time that we need powerful and positive stories.  It’s a story of democracy emerging and strengthening and taking root, and it’s something that I think is inspiring to the world because it’s coming at a moment when over some years, democracies have been moving backward, not forward.  You’re the example of the opposite.  You’re showing us and you’re showing the world how democracies can grow, strengthen, and we are and will be your partner in that.  So thank you for having us.</p>
<p><b>PRIME MINISTER GAVRILITA:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Chisinau, Moldova</p>
<p>Government House</p>
<p><b>PRIME MINISTER GAVRILITA:</b>  Dear Secretary of State Blinken, welcome to Chisinau.  I’m sure we would have all loved to have met under different circumstances and for your visit to have occurred on a more positive occasion.  Yet precisely because our region has been plunged into war, it is even of more importance that your visit comes as a sign of strong support not only for our effort to deal with the large influx of refugees and to help the people of Ukraine, but also to support our aspiration to be part of the free world.</p>
<p>We strongly condemn the act of war on Ukraine and fully support the independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders.  We stand united with the people of Ukraine and our call is for restoration of peace as soon as possible, first and foremost through diplomatic efforts.</p>
<p>We are firmly committed to help those who are fleeing from Ukraine.  The government has put in place the most comprehensive humanitarian operation in the history of the Republic of Moldova.  As of this morning, we had more than 230,000 people who have crossed the border from Ukraine and 120,000 stayed in Moldova; 96,000 of them are Ukrainian citizens.  For a small country like Moldova, proportionately this is a very large number and managing such an influx has only been possible because of the extraordinary solidarity shown by every person, every company, every nongovernmental organization.  Everybody has come together to host, to provide shelter, to provide food, to provide assistance to those who are fleeing the war.</p>
<p>But we will need assistance to deal with this influx, and we need this quickly and through flexible instruments.  Unfortunately, this humanitarian crisis comes on top of the developmental challenges that Moldova already had, and it was dealing with global challenges like the pandemic and energy crisis and inflation.  So we were already in double-digit inflation.  This war will also not only cost us in terms of the humanitarian cost, but economically, trade with Ukraine has been a very important element of our economy and we see disruptions of transportation routes and we see a global impact economically of this war.</p>
<p>So we count on your quick and comprehensive support as we have always had, and we are very grateful for the support that the U.S. Government has provided for the development of Moldova and to ensure the well-being of its citizens.</p>
<p>And finally, I just want to mention that we’ve – while we are facing these unprecedented circumstances, we are firmly committed to our path for European integration.  We believe that this is an agenda to transform Moldova into a modern, prosperous European state based on the fundamental values of human rights and the rule of law.  And we are committed to steer towards membership in the European Union.  We have submitted our application on the 3rd of March.  And as we embark on this journey, we know that we can count on the friendship and the strong support with the United States.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Prime Minister, thank you very, very much.  And indeed, you can count on that support across the board.</p>
<p>Let me first say, as you noted so well, this terrible, unprovoked war of choice is having, of course, profound consequences for the Ukrainian people, who are suffering terribly as a result while showing extraordinary resilience, but it’s also having consequences beyond Ukraine’s borders, including here in Moldova.  We admire the generosity, the hospitality, the willingness to be such good friends to people who are in distress, and indeed, we want to do everything we can to help you deal with the burden that this is imposing.  But we’re grateful for it.</p>
<p>As you also noted, at a time when all of us have so many things that we need to do to make the lives of our citizens better – dealing with what’s left of COVID-19, advancing the economic recovery that touches everyone, meeting the challenge of climate change and transforming our economies to account for that, so many things that we need to do for our societies, for our people – the last thing anyone needed or anyone wanted was a war, especially one that was totally unnecessary, totally unprovoked and, I’m afraid, premeditated.  And so the consequences, as you point out, go beyond Ukraine.  They go beyond even Ukraine’s neighbors.  They are in fact global because this is having an impact on everything that we actually need to be doing and should be doing.  And like you, we want to see it brought to the swiftest possible conclusion.</p>
<p>But meanwhile, we’re prepared to do everything we can in support of the Ukrainian people, in support of Ukraine’s neighbors who are standing up for the Ukrainian people and helping those in distress, those fleeing, and, of course, continuing to put pressure on President Putin and his government to change course.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, though, we’re also very, very pleased to be working closely with you.  I am in effect back to Moldova because this is my second visit here.  I was here in 2016.  It’s wonderful to be back.  And it’s especially wonderful to be back because your story is such a powerful one and positive one at a time that we need powerful and positive stories.  It’s a story of democracy emerging and strengthening and taking root, and it’s something that I think is inspiring to the world because it’s coming at a moment when over some years, democracies have been moving backward, not forward.  You’re the example of the opposite.  You’re showing us and you’re showing the world how democracies can grow, strengthen, and we are and will be your partner in that.  So thank you for having us.</p>
<p><b>PRIME MINISTER GAVRILITA:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Moldovan Foreign Minister Natalia Gavrilita Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-moldovan-foreign-minister-natalia-gavrilita-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 11:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321175</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Chisinau, Moldova</p>
<p>Government House</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER GAVRILITA:</strong>  Dear Secretary of State Blinken, welcome to Chisinau.  I’m sure we would have all loved to have met under different circumstances and for your visit to have occurred on a more positive occasion.  Yet precisely because our region has been plunged into war, it is even of more importance that your visit comes as a sign of strong support not only for our effort to deal with the large influx of refugees and to help the people of Ukraine, but also to support our aspiration to be part of the free world.</p>
<p>We strongly condemn the act of war on Ukraine and fully support the independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders.  We stand united with the people of Ukraine and our call is for restoration of peace as soon as possible, first and foremost through diplomatic efforts.</p>
<p>We are firmly committed to help those who are fleeing from Ukraine.  The government has put in place the most comprehensive humanitarian operation in the history of the Republic of Moldova.  As of this morning, we had more than 230,000 people who have crossed the border from Ukraine and 120,000 stayed in Moldova; 96,000 of them are Ukrainian citizens.  For a small country like Moldova, proportionately this is a very large number and managing such an influx has only been possible because of the extraordinary solidarity shown by every person, every company, every nongovernmental organization.  Everybody has come together to host, to provide shelter, to provide food, to provide assistance to those who are fleeing the war.</p>
<p>But we will need assistance to deal with this influx, and we need this quickly and through flexible instruments.  Unfortunately, this humanitarian crisis comes on top of the developmental challenges that Moldova already had, and it was dealing with global challenges like the pandemic and energy crisis and inflation.  So we were already in double-digit inflation.  This war will also not only cost us in terms of the humanitarian cost, but economically, trade with Ukraine has been a very important element of our economy and we see disruptions of transportation routes and we see a global impact economically of this war.</p>
<p>So we count on your quick and comprehensive support as we have always had, and we are very grateful for the support that the U.S. Government has provided for the development of Moldova and to ensure the well-being of its citizens.</p>
<p>And finally, I just want to mention that we’ve – while we are facing these unprecedented circumstances, we are firmly committed to our path for European integration.  We believe that this is an agenda to transform Moldova into a modern, prosperous European state based on the fundamental values of human rights and the rule of law.  And we are committed to steer towards membership in the European Union.  We have submitted our application on the 3rd of March.  And as we embark on this journey, we know that we can count on the friendship and the strong support with the United States.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Prime Minister, thank you very, very much.  And indeed, you can count on that support across the board.</p>
<p>Let me first say, as you noted so well, this terrible, unprovoked war of choice is having, of course, profound consequences for the Ukrainian people, who are suffering terribly as a result while showing extraordinary resilience, but it’s also having consequences beyond Ukraine’s borders, including here in Moldova.  We admire the generosity, the hospitality, the willingness to be such good friends to people who are in distress, and indeed, we want to do everything we can to help you deal with the burden that this is imposing.  But we’re grateful for it.</p>
<p>As you also noted, at a time when all of us have so many things that we need to do to make the lives of our citizens better – dealing with what’s left of COVID-19, advancing the economic recovery that touches everyone, meeting the challenge of climate change and transforming our economies to account for that, so many things that we need to do for our societies, for our people – the last thing anyone needed or anyone wanted was a war, especially one that was totally unnecessary, totally unprovoked and, I’m afraid, premeditated.  And so the consequences, as you point out, go beyond Ukraine.  They go beyond even Ukraine’s neighbors.  They are in fact global because this is having an impact on everything that we actually need to be doing and should be doing.  And like you, we want to see it brought to the swiftest possible conclusion.</p>
<p>But meanwhile, we’re prepared to do everything we can in support of the Ukrainian people, in support of Ukraine’s neighbors who are standing up for the Ukrainian people and helping those in distress, those fleeing, and, of course, continuing to put pressure on President Putin and his government to change course.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, though, we’re also very, very pleased to be working closely with you.  I am in effect back to Moldova because this is my second visit here.  I was here in 2016.  It’s wonderful to be back.  And it’s especially wonderful to be back because your story is such a powerful one and positive one at a time that we need powerful and positive stories.  It’s a story of democracy emerging and strengthening and taking root, and it’s something that I think is inspiring to the world because it’s coming at a moment when over some years, democracies have been moving backward, not forward.  You’re the example of the opposite.  You’re showing us and you’re showing the world how democracies can grow, strengthen, and we are and will be your partner in that.  So thank you for having us.</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER GAVRILITA:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Chisinau, Moldova</p>
<p>Government House</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER GAVRILITA:</strong>  Dear Secretary of State Blinken, welcome to Chisinau.  I’m sure we would have all loved to have met under different circumstances and for your visit to have occurred on a more positive occasion.  Yet precisely because our region has been plunged into war, it is even of more importance that your visit comes as a sign of strong support not only for our effort to deal with the large influx of refugees and to help the people of Ukraine, but also to support our aspiration to be part of the free world.</p>
<p>We strongly condemn the act of war on Ukraine and fully support the independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders.  We stand united with the people of Ukraine and our call is for restoration of peace as soon as possible, first and foremost through diplomatic efforts.</p>
<p>We are firmly committed to help those who are fleeing from Ukraine.  The government has put in place the most comprehensive humanitarian operation in the history of the Republic of Moldova.  As of this morning, we had more than 230,000 people who have crossed the border from Ukraine and 120,000 stayed in Moldova; 96,000 of them are Ukrainian citizens.  For a small country like Moldova, proportionately this is a very large number and managing such an influx has only been possible because of the extraordinary solidarity shown by every person, every company, every nongovernmental organization.  Everybody has come together to host, to provide shelter, to provide food, to provide assistance to those who are fleeing the war.</p>
<p>But we will need assistance to deal with this influx, and we need this quickly and through flexible instruments.  Unfortunately, this humanitarian crisis comes on top of the developmental challenges that Moldova already had, and it was dealing with global challenges like the pandemic and energy crisis and inflation.  So we were already in double-digit inflation.  This war will also not only cost us in terms of the humanitarian cost, but economically, trade with Ukraine has been a very important element of our economy and we see disruptions of transportation routes and we see a global impact economically of this war.</p>
<p>So we count on your quick and comprehensive support as we have always had, and we are very grateful for the support that the U.S. Government has provided for the development of Moldova and to ensure the well-being of its citizens.</p>
<p>And finally, I just want to mention that we’ve – while we are facing these unprecedented circumstances, we are firmly committed to our path for European integration.  We believe that this is an agenda to transform Moldova into a modern, prosperous European state based on the fundamental values of human rights and the rule of law.  And we are committed to steer towards membership in the European Union.  We have submitted our application on the 3rd of March.  And as we embark on this journey, we know that we can count on the friendship and the strong support with the United States.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Prime Minister, thank you very, very much.  And indeed, you can count on that support across the board.</p>
<p>Let me first say, as you noted so well, this terrible, unprovoked war of choice is having, of course, profound consequences for the Ukrainian people, who are suffering terribly as a result while showing extraordinary resilience, but it’s also having consequences beyond Ukraine’s borders, including here in Moldova.  We admire the generosity, the hospitality, the willingness to be such good friends to people who are in distress, and indeed, we want to do everything we can to help you deal with the burden that this is imposing.  But we’re grateful for it.</p>
<p>As you also noted, at a time when all of us have so many things that we need to do to make the lives of our citizens better – dealing with what’s left of COVID-19, advancing the economic recovery that touches everyone, meeting the challenge of climate change and transforming our economies to account for that, so many things that we need to do for our societies, for our people – the last thing anyone needed or anyone wanted was a war, especially one that was totally unnecessary, totally unprovoked and, I’m afraid, premeditated.  And so the consequences, as you point out, go beyond Ukraine.  They go beyond even Ukraine’s neighbors.  They are in fact global because this is having an impact on everything that we actually need to be doing and should be doing.  And like you, we want to see it brought to the swiftest possible conclusion.</p>
<p>But meanwhile, we’re prepared to do everything we can in support of the Ukrainian people, in support of Ukraine’s neighbors who are standing up for the Ukrainian people and helping those in distress, those fleeing, and, of course, continuing to put pressure on President Putin and his government to change course.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, though, we’re also very, very pleased to be working closely with you.  I am in effect back to Moldova because this is my second visit here.  I was here in 2016.  It’s wonderful to be back.  And it’s especially wonderful to be back because your story is such a powerful one and positive one at a time that we need powerful and positive stories.  It’s a story of democracy emerging and strengthening and taking root, and it’s something that I think is inspiring to the world because it’s coming at a moment when over some years, democracies have been moving backward, not forward.  You’re the example of the opposite.  You’re showing us and you’re showing the world how democracies can grow, strengthen, and we are and will be your partner in that.  So thank you for having us.</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER GAVRILITA:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Piotr Krasko of TVN</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-piotr-krasko-of-tvn/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 22:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321128</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rzeszow, Poland</p>
<p>Hotel Bristol</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Mr. Secretary, we really appreciate your presence.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>It’s a great honor for us.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>It’s very good to be with you tonight.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Mr. Secretary, you are one of more than 10,000 American citizens now in Poland. A lot of them are in this region – we are in Rzeszow now – most of them are soldiers.  We really, really appreciate your presence here, you and American soldiers.  You’ve had a lot of many different meetings today, including our prime minister, minister of foreign affairs.  Can you tell us about the results of these meetings?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, first, let me say this:  I am overwhelmed by the generosity of Poland and the Polish people.  I visited the welcome center for Ukrainians and others who are coming out of Ukraine because of the horrific aggression being committed by Vladimir Putin and Russia.  And to see the hospitality, to see the generosity of our Polish friends is very, very moving in and of itself.  And I think it speaks to a larger solidarity that exists and that we’re seeing between the United States and Poland, but also so much of the international community, in support of Ukraine and in opposition to a war of choice being committed by Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p>The strength of our own partnership, I think, has never been better, and that was very evident to me in the meetings that I had today with the prime minister, with my friend Zbigniew Rau – we’ve worked together very closely on a very regular basis.  And we’re united in this effort; that’s what’s so important.  That unity in support of Ukraine, in opposition to this aggression by Russia, is what will carry the day.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Half an hour ago, we’ve heard about your meeting with minister of foreign affairs of Ukraine, the Minister Kuleba.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Yes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>As far as I understand, you were in Ukraine – correct me if I&#8217;m wrong – you crossed the border.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>That’s correct.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>And can you tell us more about this conversation?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>First, Dmytro Kuleba is a remarkable colleague, a remarkable friend.  And he, like President Zelenskyy and others in the government, have been the face of the Ukrainian people in confronting this aggression.  But we’re on the phone regularly.  He’s somewhere in Ukraine.  I couldn’t say were for security reasons.  But I thought it was important when we met – symbolically – to cross the border and to have us stand together in Ukraine, because we’re standing together for Ukraine.  And we work very closely, and for me, it’s making sure that I understand as best possible what our Ukrainian friends and partners need, what we can do to continue to support them as well as to put the pressure on Russia.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Sir, in 1940, Churchill delivered his famous speech in British Parliament:  We’ll fight “in the streets,” “in the fields,” “on the landing grounds” until America, “with all its power and might,” would come to rescue us.  I would never imagine that they will say these words, but we have a war just next to us.  Would you be ready again to come with all your power and might to defend your European allies &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Yes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>&#8212; this time, including Poland in NATO?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Yes.  Yes, that’s the – it’s as simple as that. President Biden said this to the entire country.  He gave his State of the Union speech – this is the speech that a president gives where he talks to every American in their living rooms – just last week.  And what he said there – and he’s said repeatedly in recent weeks – is we will defend every inch of NATO territory.  That commitment, so-called Article 5 of the NATO Treaty, is sacrosanct for him and for the United States.  So no one should have any doubt about that, certainly not our allies and certainly not Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Putin expected NATO to withdraw its forces, to remove military installations from the territory of new members.  The result is the opposite, with more American troops.  But what may come in the future – would you be ready to send even more troops?</p>
<p>Well, we had already – before this aggression committed by Russia, we had about 5,000 American forces in Poland as part of the NATO mission.  It’s now double that.  We’ve sent another 5,000 from the 82nd Airborne Division who are here now.   And what’s so striking about what President Putin has done, over many years now, is he has precipitated everything he says he wants to prevent.  What’s happened in recent years as a result of Russian aggression starting back in 2014?  Ukraine, Ukrainian people have turned against Russia.  Whereas before 2014 there were favorable views in Ukraine of Russia, now 90 percent of the country honestly hate Russia and certainly hate Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p>At the same time, the NATO Alliance has come together as strongly as I’ve ever seen it, and the very forces of NATO that – a defensive alliance that has no aggressive intent against Russia, is here for our common defense.  That alliance has grown stronger, and it’s stronger closer to Russia as a result of Putin’s aggression.  So everything he’s done has been to create what he says he doesn’t want to see happen.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Vladimir Putin said today that Western sanctions on Russia are akin to declaration of war, which is a big lie, because even if Russian Central Bank lost billions of dollars &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>That’s right.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>&#8212; or some oligarchs lost your yachts and villas, it’s not a war.  War is killing Ukrainian kids.  What’s your assumption, sir?  Are these sanctions getting us closer to stop Putin?  Are they working?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>The sanctions are having a very, very powerful impact.  And I think the impact is, is far greater than most people would have imagined a month ago or six weeks ago.  That’s because so many countries are taking part and doing it together, and it’s because the sanctions themselves – going after the major financial institutions in Russia, denying Russia the technology it needs to modernize its most important industries, going directly at the oligarchs and their families – all of this is already having a big, powerful demonstrative effect.  The ruble has gone through the floor.  The ability of Russia to use the reserves that it’s built up to support its currency, we’ve taken that away by going right at the Central Bank of Russia.  In their daily lives – and it’s deeply unfortunate that the Russian people are suffering as a consequence, but this is what Putin has brought to them.</p>
<p>I have a list five pages long from yesterday – it’s probably longer even today – of all of the companies and businesses that have left Russia in the last week, the most important brands in the world that people know and – in their daily lives.  So the Russian people are feeling this in their bank accounts, in the value of the ruble.  They’re feeling this in the business that’s gone away.  And elites are feeling it and their inability to travel.  We’re now in the business for the oligarchs of seizing their yachts, their sports cars, their apartments.  So this is having a big impact already, and it will have an even bigger impact over time as Russia is unable to make the investments it wants in its future.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Mr. Secretary, one last question.  Millions of people are hoping and praying that the war would be over tonight.  But even if that’s the case, we all feel that the world has changed deeply, probably for a very long time.  What’s your assessment?  How much the world has changed since – in 10 days since the beginning of the invasion?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>I think you’re right, the world has changed, but it’s very possible that it ultimately changes in a positive way.  Here’s what I mean by that.  In the last couple of decades, democracies in one way or another, including our own, have in some ways moved backwards, or they’ve been on their heels, not on their toes.  What we’ve seen now is the most powerful response to an autocracy – Russia, under Putin, saying: oh, we’re going to do whatever we want, and we know democracies won’t respond.  We have responded; we are responding.  We’re standing with Ukraine; we’re standing against this aggression.  And it’s too early to say, because we have to see how this comes out, but this could be a positive inflection point where the world’s democracies say: there’s a line; enough is enough; we will act; we will come together.</p>
<p>And when we come together, when we’re united as we are at NATO, as we are with the European Union, as we are at the – even at the United Nations, 141 countries coming together and saying we condemn this aggression, we stand for Ukraine – that could be a moment of positive change, but only if we sustain this, if we see this through, if we make sure that Ukraine prevails, which I’m convinced it will because the Ukrainian people will insist on it, and that Russia does not succeed in what it’s doing.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Sir, thank you so much.  We really appreciate your time and thank you for this optimistic part – we all need it.  Thank you so much.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.  Great to be with you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rzeszow, Poland</p>
<p>Hotel Bristol</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Mr. Secretary, we really appreciate your presence.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>It’s a great honor for us.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>It’s very good to be with you tonight.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Mr. Secretary, you are one of more than 10,000 American citizens now in Poland. A lot of them are in this region – we are in Rzeszow now – most of them are soldiers.  We really, really appreciate your presence here, you and American soldiers.  You’ve had a lot of many different meetings today, including our prime minister, minister of foreign affairs.  Can you tell us about the results of these meetings?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, first, let me say this:  I am overwhelmed by the generosity of Poland and the Polish people.  I visited the welcome center for Ukrainians and others who are coming out of Ukraine because of the horrific aggression being committed by Vladimir Putin and Russia.  And to see the hospitality, to see the generosity of our Polish friends is very, very moving in and of itself.  And I think it speaks to a larger solidarity that exists and that we’re seeing between the United States and Poland, but also so much of the international community, in support of Ukraine and in opposition to a war of choice being committed by Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p>The strength of our own partnership, I think, has never been better, and that was very evident to me in the meetings that I had today with the prime minister, with my friend Zbigniew Rau – we’ve worked together very closely on a very regular basis.  And we’re united in this effort; that’s what’s so important.  That unity in support of Ukraine, in opposition to this aggression by Russia, is what will carry the day.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Half an hour ago, we’ve heard about your meeting with minister of foreign affairs of Ukraine, the Minister Kuleba.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Yes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>As far as I understand, you were in Ukraine – correct me if I&#8217;m wrong – you crossed the border.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>That’s correct.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>And can you tell us more about this conversation?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>First, Dmytro Kuleba is a remarkable colleague, a remarkable friend.  And he, like President Zelenskyy and others in the government, have been the face of the Ukrainian people in confronting this aggression.  But we’re on the phone regularly.  He’s somewhere in Ukraine.  I couldn’t say were for security reasons.  But I thought it was important when we met – symbolically – to cross the border and to have us stand together in Ukraine, because we’re standing together for Ukraine.  And we work very closely, and for me, it’s making sure that I understand as best possible what our Ukrainian friends and partners need, what we can do to continue to support them as well as to put the pressure on Russia.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Sir, in 1940, Churchill delivered his famous speech in British Parliament:  We’ll fight “in the streets,” “in the fields,” “on the landing grounds” until America, “with all its power and might,” would come to rescue us.  I would never imagine that they will say these words, but we have a war just next to us.  Would you be ready again to come with all your power and might to defend your European allies &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Yes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>&#8212; this time, including Poland in NATO?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Yes.  Yes, that’s the – it’s as simple as that. President Biden said this to the entire country.  He gave his State of the Union speech – this is the speech that a president gives where he talks to every American in their living rooms – just last week.  And what he said there – and he’s said repeatedly in recent weeks – is we will defend every inch of NATO territory.  That commitment, so-called Article 5 of the NATO Treaty, is sacrosanct for him and for the United States.  So no one should have any doubt about that, certainly not our allies and certainly not Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Putin expected NATO to withdraw its forces, to remove military installations from the territory of new members.  The result is the opposite, with more American troops.  But what may come in the future – would you be ready to send even more troops?</p>
<p>Well, we had already – before this aggression committed by Russia, we had about 5,000 American forces in Poland as part of the NATO mission.  It’s now double that.  We’ve sent another 5,000 from the 82nd Airborne Division who are here now.   And what’s so striking about what President Putin has done, over many years now, is he has precipitated everything he says he wants to prevent.  What’s happened in recent years as a result of Russian aggression starting back in 2014?  Ukraine, Ukrainian people have turned against Russia.  Whereas before 2014 there were favorable views in Ukraine of Russia, now 90 percent of the country honestly hate Russia and certainly hate Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p>At the same time, the NATO Alliance has come together as strongly as I’ve ever seen it, and the very forces of NATO that – a defensive alliance that has no aggressive intent against Russia, is here for our common defense.  That alliance has grown stronger, and it’s stronger closer to Russia as a result of Putin’s aggression.  So everything he’s done has been to create what he says he doesn’t want to see happen.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Vladimir Putin said today that Western sanctions on Russia are akin to declaration of war, which is a big lie, because even if Russian Central Bank lost billions of dollars &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>That’s right.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>&#8212; or some oligarchs lost your yachts and villas, it’s not a war.  War is killing Ukrainian kids.  What’s your assumption, sir?  Are these sanctions getting us closer to stop Putin?  Are they working?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>The sanctions are having a very, very powerful impact.  And I think the impact is, is far greater than most people would have imagined a month ago or six weeks ago.  That’s because so many countries are taking part and doing it together, and it’s because the sanctions themselves – going after the major financial institutions in Russia, denying Russia the technology it needs to modernize its most important industries, going directly at the oligarchs and their families – all of this is already having a big, powerful demonstrative effect.  The ruble has gone through the floor.  The ability of Russia to use the reserves that it’s built up to support its currency, we’ve taken that away by going right at the Central Bank of Russia.  In their daily lives – and it’s deeply unfortunate that the Russian people are suffering as a consequence, but this is what Putin has brought to them.</p>
<p>I have a list five pages long from yesterday – it’s probably longer even today – of all of the companies and businesses that have left Russia in the last week, the most important brands in the world that people know and – in their daily lives.  So the Russian people are feeling this in their bank accounts, in the value of the ruble.  They’re feeling this in the business that’s gone away.  And elites are feeling it and their inability to travel.  We’re now in the business for the oligarchs of seizing their yachts, their sports cars, their apartments.  So this is having a big impact already, and it will have an even bigger impact over time as Russia is unable to make the investments it wants in its future.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Mr. Secretary, one last question.  Millions of people are hoping and praying that the war would be over tonight.  But even if that’s the case, we all feel that the world has changed deeply, probably for a very long time.  What’s your assessment?  How much the world has changed since – in 10 days since the beginning of the invasion?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>I think you’re right, the world has changed, but it’s very possible that it ultimately changes in a positive way.  Here’s what I mean by that.  In the last couple of decades, democracies in one way or another, including our own, have in some ways moved backwards, or they’ve been on their heels, not on their toes.  What we’ve seen now is the most powerful response to an autocracy – Russia, under Putin, saying: oh, we’re going to do whatever we want, and we know democracies won’t respond.  We have responded; we are responding.  We’re standing with Ukraine; we’re standing against this aggression.  And it’s too early to say, because we have to see how this comes out, but this could be a positive inflection point where the world’s democracies say: there’s a line; enough is enough; we will act; we will come together.</p>
<p>And when we come together, when we’re united as we are at NATO, as we are with the European Union, as we are at the – even at the United Nations, 141 countries coming together and saying we condemn this aggression, we stand for Ukraine – that could be a moment of positive change, but only if we sustain this, if we see this through, if we make sure that Ukraine prevails, which I’m convinced it will because the Ukrainian people will insist on it, and that Russia does not succeed in what it’s doing.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Sir, thank you so much.  We really appreciate your time and thank you for this optimistic part – we all need it.  Thank you so much.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.  Great to be with you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meetings with Turkish Deputy Foreign Minister Onal</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meetings-with-turkish-deputy-foreign-minister-onal-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 21:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321115</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today in Ankara with Turkish Deputy Foreign Minister Sedat Onal to discuss Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine. Deputy Secretary Sherman thanked Turkey for its strong and vocal support in defense of Ukraine and expressed appreciation for the solidarity among partners and NATO Allies in confronting this crisis.  The Deputy Secretary also underscored the importance of the U.S. – Turkey Strategic Mechanism, which will deepen and expand the already robust cooperation between our two countries.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today in Ankara with Turkish Deputy Foreign Minister Sedat Onal to discuss Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine. Deputy Secretary Sherman thanked Turkey for its strong and vocal support in defense of Ukraine and expressed appreciation for the solidarity among partners and NATO Allies in confronting this crisis.  The Deputy Secretary also underscored the importance of the U.S. – Turkey Strategic Mechanism, which will deepen and expand the already robust cooperation between our two countries.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken At a Town Hall with Kyiv Embassy Personnel</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-town-hall-with-kyiv-embassy-personnel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 21:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rzeszow, Poland</p>
<p>Hotel Bristol</p>
<p><b>MS KVIEN:  </b>Well, it’s my great pleasure and honor to welcome Secretary Blinken to Embassy Kyiv-West here in Rzeszow, Poland.  What you have in front of you, Mr. Secretary, is about 50 folks who have been working night and day since we got here to help Ukrainians in need, to help American citizens in need to get out of Ukraine, to help bring assistance into Ukraine, and to help continue our work with the Ukrainian Government to make sure that we can do whatever we can to help them in their time of need.  So with that, I’ll just hand it over to you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.  Kristina, thank you very much.  And look, I really want to have a chance to hear from as many of you as possible, answer as many questions as I can in the time we have, and predictably, we’re running behind.  So I don&#8217;t want to talk at the beginning too much, except to say this:  I know that for virtually each and every one of you, this is not only professional – this is personal.  So many of you have deep ties, deep connections, deep feelings for Ukraine, for its people, for your friends that you’ve made, the professional relationships you’ve developed.</p>
<p>And I know how powerful that is, both as a driver but also, it’s a challenge, because I know what you’ve been through in the last weeks – shutting down in Kyiv, moving to Lviv, moving out of Lviv, back to Lviv, and out – and all the while determined to do everything that you can for our friends and partners in Ukraine.  And so again, I know this is this is deeply personal as well as professional.  And the professional part of the could not be more important, because you all know better than anyone what’s at stake in this effort.</p>
<p>What’s at stake is, of course, first and foremost, the lives, the wellbeing, the future of so many Ukrainians.  And for all the numbers we throw around, each and every one of those numbers has a real person behind it.  And that’s something I know you know better than anyone because you know the people, but it’s also big because the very principles that are at the heart of the international system, as challenged as it is, that are really important to try and keep peace and security – that we established after two world wars to try to make sure it never happened again – those principles are being assaulted by Vladimir Putin, along with the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p>And so our determination to make sure this doesn’t go with impunity is about Ukraine, and honestly, it’s about the whole world.  The part you’re playing in this town is vitally important, because you’re so much a part of the connectivity that we have with Ukraine and with Ukrainians, even from Embassy West here.  And I’m so grateful to all of you for doing this, not just doing it but, as Kristina said – and Kristina, thank you for your extraordinary leadership in this time – doing it with such determination, such passion, and such heart.</p>
<p>But with that, let me stop and let our friends from the press maybe get a espresso somewhere, and &#8212;</p>
<p><b>STAFF:  </b>All right, thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rzeszow, Poland</p>
<p>Hotel Bristol</p>
<p><b>MS KVIEN:  </b>Well, it’s my great pleasure and honor to welcome Secretary Blinken to Embassy Kyiv-West here in Rzeszow, Poland.  What you have in front of you, Mr. Secretary, is about 50 folks who have been working night and day since we got here to help Ukrainians in need, to help American citizens in need to get out of Ukraine, to help bring assistance into Ukraine, and to help continue our work with the Ukrainian Government to make sure that we can do whatever we can to help them in their time of need.  So with that, I’ll just hand it over to you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.  Kristina, thank you very much.  And look, I really want to have a chance to hear from as many of you as possible, answer as many questions as I can in the time we have, and predictably, we’re running behind.  So I don&#8217;t want to talk at the beginning too much, except to say this:  I know that for virtually each and every one of you, this is not only professional – this is personal.  So many of you have deep ties, deep connections, deep feelings for Ukraine, for its people, for your friends that you’ve made, the professional relationships you’ve developed.</p>
<p>And I know how powerful that is, both as a driver but also, it’s a challenge, because I know what you’ve been through in the last weeks – shutting down in Kyiv, moving to Lviv, moving out of Lviv, back to Lviv, and out – and all the while determined to do everything that you can for our friends and partners in Ukraine.  And so again, I know this is this is deeply personal as well as professional.  And the professional part of the could not be more important, because you all know better than anyone what’s at stake in this effort.</p>
<p>What’s at stake is, of course, first and foremost, the lives, the wellbeing, the future of so many Ukrainians.  And for all the numbers we throw around, each and every one of those numbers has a real person behind it.  And that’s something I know you know better than anyone because you know the people, but it’s also big because the very principles that are at the heart of the international system, as challenged as it is, that are really important to try and keep peace and security – that we established after two world wars to try to make sure it never happened again – those principles are being assaulted by Vladimir Putin, along with the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p>And so our determination to make sure this doesn’t go with impunity is about Ukraine, and honestly, it’s about the whole world.  The part you’re playing in this town is vitally important, because you’re so much a part of the connectivity that we have with Ukraine and with Ukrainians, even from Embassy West here.  And I’m so grateful to all of you for doing this, not just doing it but, as Kristina said – and Kristina, thank you for your extraordinary leadership in this time – doing it with such determination, such passion, and such heart.</p>
<p>But with that, let me stop and let our friends from the press maybe get a espresso somewhere, and &#8212;</p>
<p><b>STAFF:  </b>All right, thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken At a Meeting with Congressional Delegation</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-meeting-with-congressional-delegation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 20:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321102</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rzeszow, Poland</p>
<p>Hotel Bristol</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, greetings, everyone.  I’m particularly pleased to be here with friends and colleagues from the Congress.  This is, as always, very powerful to see a bipartisan group of leaders from Congress standing together, coming together in support of Ukraine, and standing strongly against Vladimir Putin’s war of choice and aggression that is not only – is first and foremost affecting the people of Ukraine, but poses a threat to the basic principles of the international order that all of us stand strongly for.  And we – I think we’re determined – as Republicans, as Democrats, as Americans – not to let this go with impunity.</p>
<p>So I think the fact that our colleagues are here with this strong show of support from the United States here in this moment at this time is a very powerful thing, and it’s just wonderful to be with you.</p>
<p><b>CHAIRMAN MEEKS:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>STAFF:  </b>All right, thanks, guys.</p>
<p><b>CHAIRMAN MEEKS:  </b>As you said, bipartisan group – many more members of Congress wanted to come.  We completely filled our plane, because we wanted to make sure that – number one, we wanted to say thank you to the Polish people.  The humanitarian concerns that they have had wreaked on them – now they’re able to help someone else.  And I thought, we all thought that it was extremely important for members of the Congress, in a bipartisan way, to come to say thank you and that we know – for those that had to leave their homes in Ukraine because of one man who decided that he’s going to make and commit war crimes, killing innocent men, women and children – that we wanted to also let them know that the United States has their back.  And we’re going to stay together.</p>
<p>So we’re definitely going to make sure that the – our NATO Ally here in Poland, we have your back.  We’re not going to leave you alone, and it’s a message united.  Mike McCaul is the ranking member – I’m the chair of the House Foreign Affairs Committee; he’s the ranking member.  Mike, why don’t you say something?</p>
<p><b>RANKING MEMBER MCCAUL:  </b>Well, (inaudible) we’re not here as Republicans or Democrats, but really as Americans supporting our NATO Ally, Poland, and the people of Ukraine.  We stand with you.  We just had a video conference with President Zelenskyy, one of the most courageous individuals I’ve ever seen.  Very inspiring.  And the chairman’s right:  Mr. Putin is a war criminal, he’s going to lose in the end, and we want to work with you and the administration to bring this to a – bring him to justice and stop the bloodshed.  And again, I just want to thank Poland and the people of Ukraine.  We are with you, and we will do everything we can to stop this.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rzeszow, Poland</p>
<p>Hotel Bristol</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, greetings, everyone.  I’m particularly pleased to be here with friends and colleagues from the Congress.  This is, as always, very powerful to see a bipartisan group of leaders from Congress standing together, coming together in support of Ukraine, and standing strongly against Vladimir Putin’s war of choice and aggression that is not only – is first and foremost affecting the people of Ukraine, but poses a threat to the basic principles of the international order that all of us stand strongly for.  And we – I think we’re determined – as Republicans, as Democrats, as Americans – not to let this go with impunity.</p>
<p>So I think the fact that our colleagues are here with this strong show of support from the United States here in this moment at this time is a very powerful thing, and it’s just wonderful to be with you.</p>
<p><b>CHAIRMAN MEEKS:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>STAFF:  </b>All right, thanks, guys.</p>
<p><b>CHAIRMAN MEEKS:  </b>As you said, bipartisan group – many more members of Congress wanted to come.  We completely filled our plane, because we wanted to make sure that – number one, we wanted to say thank you to the Polish people.  The humanitarian concerns that they have had wreaked on them – now they’re able to help someone else.  And I thought, we all thought that it was extremely important for members of the Congress, in a bipartisan way, to come to say thank you and that we know – for those that had to leave their homes in Ukraine because of one man who decided that he’s going to make and commit war crimes, killing innocent men, women and children – that we wanted to also let them know that the United States has their back.  And we’re going to stay together.</p>
<p>So we’re definitely going to make sure that the – our NATO Ally here in Poland, we have your back.  We’re not going to leave you alone, and it’s a message united.  Mike McCaul is the ranking member – I’m the chair of the House Foreign Affairs Committee; he’s the ranking member.  Mike, why don’t you say something?</p>
<p><b>RANKING MEMBER MCCAUL:  </b>Well, (inaudible) we’re not here as Republicans or Democrats, but really as Americans supporting our NATO Ally, Poland, and the people of Ukraine.  We stand with you.  We just had a video conference with President Zelenskyy, one of the most courageous individuals I’ve ever seen.  Very inspiring.  And the chairman’s right:  Mr. Putin is a war criminal, he’s going to lose in the end, and we want to work with you and the administration to bring this to a – bring him to justice and stop the bloodshed.  And again, I just want to thank Poland and the people of Ukraine.  We are with you, and we will do everything we can to stop this.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
