<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 22:25:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>ON-THE-RECORD BRIEFING: Secretary Blinken’s Upcoming Travel to Panama</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/on-the-record-briefing-secretary-blinkens-upcoming-travel-to-panama</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian A. Nichols, Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere AffairsBureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs, Marta Costanzo Youth, Acting Principal Deputy Assistant SecretaryBureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 21:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=334887</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Brian A. Nichols, Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere AffairsBureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs</p>
<p>Marta Costanzo Youth, Acting Principal Deputy Assistant SecretaryBureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT:</strong>  Thanks very much and thanks, everyone, for joining us today.  We’re happy to have you for this call previewing Secretary Blinken’s upcoming travel to Panama.  The trip was announced earlier today, and the Secretary departs for Panama on Tuesday, April 19th.  Just a reminder again, this call is on the record but embargoed until the call is completed.  And we’ll of course focus on answering questions related to the trip.  And as we always do, we’ll post a transcript after the fact on state.gov.</p>
<p>If you would like to ask a question at any time, please dial 1 then 0 to enter the queue.  Again, that’s 1 then 0 to enter the queue to ask a question.</p>
<p>It’s now my pleasure to introduce on the line with us our Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs Brian Nichols and our Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration Acting Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary Marta Youth.  They’ll offer some opening remarks each, and then we’ll take your questions.  Again, 1 then 0 to ask a question.</p>
<p>And with that, I’ll turn it over to Assistant Secretary Nichols to begin.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY NICHOLS:</strong>  Thank you and good afternoon.  Thank you all for joining us today as we preview Secretary Blinken’s upcoming trip to Panama City for a Ministerial on Migration and Protection and bilateral meetings with the Government of Panama.</p>
<p>On April 19th and 20th, Secretary Blinken will lead a U.S. delegation to Panama City to lead a ministerial conference co-hosted with the Government of Panama.  Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro Mayorkas and I will join Secretary Blinken on this trip, as will a number of other State Department, National Security Council, USAID, and DHS leaders.</p>
<p>While in Panama, our delegation will join senior representatives from more than 20 other countries in the Western Hemisphere at the ministerial conference.  Secretary Blinken will also meet with Panamanian President Laurentino Cortizo and Foreign Minister Erika Mouynes, as well as with civil society organizations and members of the press.</p>
<p>I note that this ministerial is part of our diplomatic build-up to the June Summit of the Americas, during which we will advance a number of initiatives that address irregular migration and its root causes and provide protection for refugees and asylum seekers.  With that for context, I’ll speak first about the Ministerial on Migration and Protection, and then detail our bilateral meetings.</p>
<p>In August of last year, Panama hosted a virtual migration gathering, and in October, 17 countries gathered in Bogota for a Ministerial on Migration and Protection.  Next week’s ministerial in Panama will further our shared commitment to collaboratively addressing the challenges of irregular migration throughout our hemisphere.</p>
<p>President Biden made addressing the challenges of irregular migration and providing protection a key priority for his administration.  In his first days in office, he outlined his vision for a comprehensive regional framework, which we further detailed in our Strategy to Address the Root Causes of Migration and our Collaborative Migration Management Strategy.  While we have made great progress in implementing that plan, this is a shared challenge.  And as Secretary Blinken said at the October ministerial, “It cannot be solved by any one country.  We have to solve it together.”</p>
<p>We must count on close collaboration with governments throughout the region to truly make progress on managing irregular migration and addressing the protection needs of the most vulnerable people in our hemisphere.  As mentioned, in October 2021, 17 countries from our region came together in Bogota in recognition of our shared responsibility.  At the conclusion of that ministerial, we all committed to continue the discussion and encourage more countries to join.</p>
<p>The United States has continued these discussions with many partners throughout the hemisphere, resulting in a bilateral Migration Arrangement with Costa Rica in March, and we are working on similar arrangements with a number of other countries.  This week in Panama we will meet the challenge set at the last ministerial with the addition of new national partners and further progress on our collective objectives.</p>
<p>In particular, at this ministerial we intend to focus on stabilization efforts for communities hosting migrants and refugees.  Countries hosting large migrant and refugee populations often need access to financing and assistance for development, humanitarian needs, public health, and climate resilience and adaptation.  This support is essential to enable migrants and refugees to integrate into host countries and rebuild their lives.  At the ministerial conference, we will discuss leveraging investments from multilateral development banks and international organizations to support communities in need.</p>
<p>We and our partners in the Americas understand the best way to address irregular migration is by generating opportunities and giving people a reason to build their lives at home.</p>
<p>We will also discuss the President’s framework for regional collaboration on migration issues and our intent to adopt a declaration on migration protection at the Summit of the Americas, which the United States will host in Los Angeles in June.</p>
<p>Given the expanding collaboration with our partners throughout the region in the past year, I am confident we will have fruitful discussions on this trip.</p>
<p>Turning now to the bilateral meetings for this trip, in his meetings with Panamanian President Cortizo and Foreign Minister Mouynes, Secretary Blinken will discuss issues of importance to citizens of both our countries, including migration, of course, and also Panama’s role as a regional leader in preventing democratic backsliding, promoting human rights, and tackling corruption, as well as the international response to Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Beyond this bilateral leadership discussion, the Secretary will also attend a special event with anticorruption activists to exchange ideas and extend support for their important work, and visit the Panama Canal, a bedrock of Panama’s economy and a key node for U.S. trade.</p>
<p>With that, I’ll pass it to my colleague, Deputy Assistant Secretary Marta Youth.</p>
<p><strong>MS YOUTH: </strong>  Thanks so much.  Good afternoon.  I’m very glad to be on the line with Assistant Secretary Nichols today ahead of Secretary Blinken’s trip to Panama to participate in the Ministerial on Migration and Protection next week.  As the assistant secretary mentioned, addressing the challenges of irregular migration and providing protection to refugees and asylum seekers is a key priority for the Biden-Harris administration.</p>
<p>Ahead of the Secretary’s trip, I would like to elaborate briefly on what the United States is doing to build capacity and provide protection in the hemisphere in the context of our commitment to collaborating with partners from across the region to humanely manage migration.  The United States works with international organizations and multilateral institutions to provide humanitarian assistance and help integrate refugees, asylum seekers, vulnerable migrants into their host communities, and help support those host communities.  We also support efforts to build capacity in the region to provide asylum and other protections.</p>
<p>In addition, we’re strengthening international protection and other legal migration pathways to the United States and elsewhere.  We collaborate with partners from across the region to underscore our shared responsibility and to develop a set of priorities to strengthen humane migration management, provide protection to those who need it throughout the hemisphere, and reduce incentives for irregular migrations.</p>
<p>The bilateral Migration Arrangements Assistant Secretary Nichols mentioned allow us to target our capacity-building programs and humanitarian assistance, and strengthen our partnerships with other countries and international organizations and NGO partners.  They foster collaboration towards our shared responsibility to ensure migration is safe, orderly, and humane.</p>
<p>The United States Government is firmly committed to welcoming people to the United States with humanity and respect, and reuniting families.  We are working to deliver on our promise to promote safe, orderly, and humane migration from Central America through the expansion of legal pathways that allow individuals to seek humanitarian protection in the United States.</p>
<p>We have a shared responsibility.  The ministerial in Panama is another opportunity to convene with regional governments, multi-development banks, international organizations, civil society, and others to discuss the continued critical actions necessary to strengthen humane migration management, provide protection to those who need it, and reduce irregular migration throughout the hemisphere.  The Secretary’s trip is an opportunity to seek greater collaboration.</p>
<p>Thank you for your time.  Look forward to your questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT: </strong>  Thank you both very much.  And again, if you’d like to ask a question of either Assistant Secretary Nichols or Acting Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary Marta Youth, please press 1 then 0.</p>
<p>We’ll first go to Ryohei Takagi from Kyodo News.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong>  Mr. Takagi, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT: </strong>  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks for briefing.  Panama established diplomatic relations with China and protocol affiliations with – relations with Taiwan in 2017.  So I’m just wondering whether the relationship with Taiwan and China would be one of the topics the Secretary will discuss with his counterpart, Panama foreign minister, or not.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY NICHOLS: </strong> Thanks very much.  In all of our conversations around the hemisphere, we talk about the importance of the shared values that we have as a region, the importance of respect for human rights, the rule of law, democracy, and we talk about being transparent and understanding what’s on offer when China is engaging with a country.</p>
<p>I’m sure that will be part of the discussions that we have in Panama.  The United States has a strong commercial relationship with China, obviously.  We’re not saying don’t trade with China.  What we’re saying is do so with your eyes open, understand what’s on the table, understand how China will use and its companies will use your data if they are in the data processing business like 5G.  And that’s a common conversation for us to have with all of our partners, and we just hope that people approach these issues with full knowledge and ask the right questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT:  </strong>Thanks.  Let’s next go to Conor Finnegan from ABC News.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>Mr. Finnegan, you are open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Great.  Thank you.  Two questions here.  First, will any representatives of the Maduro government be present for the ministerial?  And can any agreement – hemisphere-wide agreement solve the migration crisis without addressing Venezuela’s political, economic, and humanitarian crises?</p>
<p>And then second, the administration has announced plans to admit up to 100,000 Ukrainian refugees.  What impact would that have on your plans to admit – or process asylum claims at the border or otherwise address migration issues?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY NICHOLS:  </strong>So the Maduro regime will not attend the ministerial.  The – obviously the lack of access to opportunity, democracy, human rights, the rule of law inside the borders of Venezuela has led many Venezuelans to vote with their feet and depart that country.  Our goal is to encourage the Maduro regime and the interim government to return to the negotiating table in Mexico City where Venezuela negotiated and led solution to that country’s problems.  We continue to support that effort and believe it has the best prospects for a lasting solution to Venezuela’s problems.</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT:  </strong>Thanks.  Let’s next go to Gustau Alegaret from NTN 24.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>Please, go ahead, Mr. Alegaret.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you very much for this opportunity.  A couple of questions.  Do we have to expect any announcement from this meeting, first of all?  And second of all, if I may, some analysts and people in Panama at the beginning of the war in Ukraine were requesting the government to block any Russian vessels or ships going through the canal as a kind of punishment or sanctions against the Kremlin.  Is that a possibility?  Is the United States supporting this idea?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY NICHOLS:  </strong>Well, I think that we expect that all of the nations that are present will respect the sanctions that exist on the Russian Federation, financial institutions within it, and private companies operating with close links to the Russian Federation and the Putin government.  We believe that the private sectors of our region are already taking extensive steps to ensure that they respect those sanctions and other measures.  I can’t speak to the specifics of ship traffic, but I do believe that we will seek ever greater application of those measures by our partners and allies around the hemisphere and around the world.</p>
<p>The – I should just note that the unprecedented flow of migrants out of Ukraine has contributed to the larger global challenge of unprecedented levels of migration over the course of the past few months.  And we as an international community are working hard to manage that in a humane, safe, transparent, and legal way, and putting the resources in place both in Europe and certainly in our own hemisphere to address this new challenge while we continue to manage the migration situation and migrant flows around our own region.</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT:  </strong>Thank you.  Let’s next go to Priscilla Alvarez from CNN.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thanks for doing the call.  What does the State Department want to – or the U.S. want to walk away with?  Would it be an agreement?  An additional commitment from Panama or other attending countries?  What would sort of signify a successful trip?</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY NICHOLS:  </strong>So this is for us an important opportunity to begin the home stretch as we prepare for the Summit of the Americas in June.  And as I said, we expect that we will have a broad migration compact or agreement that specifically helps us keep populations safe and integrated and in place where they are in our hemisphere that increases information sharing among the governments and migratory authorities of our hemisphere that leverages the resources of multilateral development banks and other international organizations like the IOM and the UN to support migration requirements throughout our hemisphere, that countries continue to take steps to regularize migration by instituting visa requirements, while appropriate that countries continue to invest in things like services for migrants at risk and shelters.  Those are all things that we’ve made significant progress on since the last ministerial, and we believe that that process will continue through Panama right up to June and the Summit of the Americas.  But perhaps my colleague Marta Youth would like to make a comment as well.</p>
<p><strong>MS YOUTH:</strong>  Sir, I think you did a fantastic job covering it, but just to kind of sum up, I mean, this really – what we’re really looking at in Panama is really continuing the conversation that we began in the original virtual meeting that the Panamanian Government hosted last year and then the October migration ministerial which we co-hosted with Colombia in October.</p>
<p>This is – we really changed the narrative, I think, in the region in terms of understanding what is really meant by shared responsibility and how we can all work together on this really unprecedented challenge, which is really not just in this region but is actually a reflection of the challenges that we are seeing happening globally in terms of forced displacement throughout the world.  And this is an event where we can discuss and act on what we need to do together to address these challenges.  Over.</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT:</strong>  Thank you.  Let’s next go to Nick Kalman from Fox.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks.  I just had a follow-up to my colleague Conor’s question on the Maduro regime, and you said that no representatives from that regime are attending the ministerial.  Could you just advise as to whether or not any representatives from the regime were invited to attend?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY NICHOLS:</strong>  Not to my knowledge.</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT:</strong>  Thanks.  Let’s next go to Ted Hesson from Reuters.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, all.  Thank you for having the call.  My question is similar to what Priscilla asked, and I’m hoping maybe you could give us some more practical examples.  I guess I understand sort of symbolically what you’re working towards, and there have been many meetings and you’ve been at this for over a year, but has there been any tangible result, and is there anything you can show us that’s affected migration at the U.S.-Mexico border, for instance, that’s come out of these talks?</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY NICHOLS:</strong>  Well, we’re working on addressing the root causes of migration as a collective effort, and one of the things that I think has been quite powerful in the near term has been Vice President Harris’ call to action, which has mobilized over $1.2 billion in private sector investment in Northern Central America and created thousands of jobs in that part of the hemisphere.  And we know that those people are not migrating.  We know that our efforts to provide COVID-19 vaccines to countries throughout the hemisphere – some 60 million vaccines in the Western Hemisphere – have helped countries recover more quickly from the COVID-19 pandemic which was a driver of migration to our southern border.</p>
<p>We know that our efforts to provide assistance to communities that are hosting migrants in Colombia, Ecuador, Peru, Chile have all helped stabilize those populations to a greater degree.  But this comes in the context of literally millions of migrants on the move in our hemisphere; some six million Venezuelans are migrants outside of Venezuela right now, over five million of them in the Western Hemisphere.  There are half a million Nicaraguans who are displaced and living in Costa Rica right now, and I had the opportunity to meet with some of them when I was there a couple weeks ago.  We’re talking about hundreds of thousands of Haitian migrants in Chile, in Brazil.</p>
<p>There are really unprecedented challenges and I think that our assistance has helped to mitigate some of that migration movement, but the challenges did not begin yesterday and they will take time for us to resolve alongside our partners.  And as Marta signaled, one of the things we don’t hear anymore is that this is a U.S. problem.  What – no one has said that to me and they – all the countries that I have talked to very much accept that we have to work together to address this challenge, and that’s what we’re doing in Panama.</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT:  </strong>Thank you.  We’ll take a final question from Beatriz Pascual from EFE.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.  You have mentioned a couple of times that this meeting in Panama is in preparation for the Summit of the Americas.  So I was wondering if the United States has invited Cuba and Venezuela to the Summit of the Americas.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY NICHOLS:  </strong>So the White House will determine which leaders are invited to the Summit of the Americas, and the White House has not yet issued invitations.  I will note that the Western Hemisphere is a part of the world that has a broad commitment to democracy, as enshrined in the Inter-American Democratic Charter.  And I believe that as we move forward, we will see countries that share that commitment toward democracy as the key participants in the summit.</p>
<p><strong>MR BARNETT:  </strong>Thank you both again.  Thanks to our speakers.  And thanks to our participants for your questions.  We’ll post this transcript shortly on <a href="https://state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">state.gov</a>, and you know how to get in touch with us if you have questions in the lead-up to or during the trip.  Thank you, everybody, and have a great day.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brian A. Nichols, Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere AffairsBureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs</p>
<p>Marta Costanzo Youth, Acting Principal Deputy Assistant SecretaryBureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT:</strong>  Thanks very much and thanks, everyone, for joining us today.  We’re happy to have you for this call previewing Secretary Blinken’s upcoming travel to Panama.  The trip was announced earlier today, and the Secretary departs for Panama on Tuesday, April 19th.  Just a reminder again, this call is on the record but embargoed until the call is completed.  And we’ll of course focus on answering questions related to the trip.  And as we always do, we’ll post a transcript after the fact on state.gov.</p>
<p>If you would like to ask a question at any time, please dial 1 then 0 to enter the queue.  Again, that’s 1 then 0 to enter the queue to ask a question.</p>
<p>It’s now my pleasure to introduce on the line with us our Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs Brian Nichols and our Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration Acting Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary Marta Youth.  They’ll offer some opening remarks each, and then we’ll take your questions.  Again, 1 then 0 to ask a question.</p>
<p>And with that, I’ll turn it over to Assistant Secretary Nichols to begin.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY NICHOLS:</strong>  Thank you and good afternoon.  Thank you all for joining us today as we preview Secretary Blinken’s upcoming trip to Panama City for a Ministerial on Migration and Protection and bilateral meetings with the Government of Panama.</p>
<p>On April 19th and 20th, Secretary Blinken will lead a U.S. delegation to Panama City to lead a ministerial conference co-hosted with the Government of Panama.  Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro Mayorkas and I will join Secretary Blinken on this trip, as will a number of other State Department, National Security Council, USAID, and DHS leaders.</p>
<p>While in Panama, our delegation will join senior representatives from more than 20 other countries in the Western Hemisphere at the ministerial conference.  Secretary Blinken will also meet with Panamanian President Laurentino Cortizo and Foreign Minister Erika Mouynes, as well as with civil society organizations and members of the press.</p>
<p>I note that this ministerial is part of our diplomatic build-up to the June Summit of the Americas, during which we will advance a number of initiatives that address irregular migration and its root causes and provide protection for refugees and asylum seekers.  With that for context, I’ll speak first about the Ministerial on Migration and Protection, and then detail our bilateral meetings.</p>
<p>In August of last year, Panama hosted a virtual migration gathering, and in October, 17 countries gathered in Bogota for a Ministerial on Migration and Protection.  Next week’s ministerial in Panama will further our shared commitment to collaboratively addressing the challenges of irregular migration throughout our hemisphere.</p>
<p>President Biden made addressing the challenges of irregular migration and providing protection a key priority for his administration.  In his first days in office, he outlined his vision for a comprehensive regional framework, which we further detailed in our Strategy to Address the Root Causes of Migration and our Collaborative Migration Management Strategy.  While we have made great progress in implementing that plan, this is a shared challenge.  And as Secretary Blinken said at the October ministerial, “It cannot be solved by any one country.  We have to solve it together.”</p>
<p>We must count on close collaboration with governments throughout the region to truly make progress on managing irregular migration and addressing the protection needs of the most vulnerable people in our hemisphere.  As mentioned, in October 2021, 17 countries from our region came together in Bogota in recognition of our shared responsibility.  At the conclusion of that ministerial, we all committed to continue the discussion and encourage more countries to join.</p>
<p>The United States has continued these discussions with many partners throughout the hemisphere, resulting in a bilateral Migration Arrangement with Costa Rica in March, and we are working on similar arrangements with a number of other countries.  This week in Panama we will meet the challenge set at the last ministerial with the addition of new national partners and further progress on our collective objectives.</p>
<p>In particular, at this ministerial we intend to focus on stabilization efforts for communities hosting migrants and refugees.  Countries hosting large migrant and refugee populations often need access to financing and assistance for development, humanitarian needs, public health, and climate resilience and adaptation.  This support is essential to enable migrants and refugees to integrate into host countries and rebuild their lives.  At the ministerial conference, we will discuss leveraging investments from multilateral development banks and international organizations to support communities in need.</p>
<p>We and our partners in the Americas understand the best way to address irregular migration is by generating opportunities and giving people a reason to build their lives at home.</p>
<p>We will also discuss the President’s framework for regional collaboration on migration issues and our intent to adopt a declaration on migration protection at the Summit of the Americas, which the United States will host in Los Angeles in June.</p>
<p>Given the expanding collaboration with our partners throughout the region in the past year, I am confident we will have fruitful discussions on this trip.</p>
<p>Turning now to the bilateral meetings for this trip, in his meetings with Panamanian President Cortizo and Foreign Minister Mouynes, Secretary Blinken will discuss issues of importance to citizens of both our countries, including migration, of course, and also Panama’s role as a regional leader in preventing democratic backsliding, promoting human rights, and tackling corruption, as well as the international response to Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Beyond this bilateral leadership discussion, the Secretary will also attend a special event with anticorruption activists to exchange ideas and extend support for their important work, and visit the Panama Canal, a bedrock of Panama’s economy and a key node for U.S. trade.</p>
<p>With that, I’ll pass it to my colleague, Deputy Assistant Secretary Marta Youth.</p>
<p><strong>MS YOUTH: </strong>  Thanks so much.  Good afternoon.  I’m very glad to be on the line with Assistant Secretary Nichols today ahead of Secretary Blinken’s trip to Panama to participate in the Ministerial on Migration and Protection next week.  As the assistant secretary mentioned, addressing the challenges of irregular migration and providing protection to refugees and asylum seekers is a key priority for the Biden-Harris administration.</p>
<p>Ahead of the Secretary’s trip, I would like to elaborate briefly on what the United States is doing to build capacity and provide protection in the hemisphere in the context of our commitment to collaborating with partners from across the region to humanely manage migration.  The United States works with international organizations and multilateral institutions to provide humanitarian assistance and help integrate refugees, asylum seekers, vulnerable migrants into their host communities, and help support those host communities.  We also support efforts to build capacity in the region to provide asylum and other protections.</p>
<p>In addition, we’re strengthening international protection and other legal migration pathways to the United States and elsewhere.  We collaborate with partners from across the region to underscore our shared responsibility and to develop a set of priorities to strengthen humane migration management, provide protection to those who need it throughout the hemisphere, and reduce incentives for irregular migrations.</p>
<p>The bilateral Migration Arrangements Assistant Secretary Nichols mentioned allow us to target our capacity-building programs and humanitarian assistance, and strengthen our partnerships with other countries and international organizations and NGO partners.  They foster collaboration towards our shared responsibility to ensure migration is safe, orderly, and humane.</p>
<p>The United States Government is firmly committed to welcoming people to the United States with humanity and respect, and reuniting families.  We are working to deliver on our promise to promote safe, orderly, and humane migration from Central America through the expansion of legal pathways that allow individuals to seek humanitarian protection in the United States.</p>
<p>We have a shared responsibility.  The ministerial in Panama is another opportunity to convene with regional governments, multi-development banks, international organizations, civil society, and others to discuss the continued critical actions necessary to strengthen humane migration management, provide protection to those who need it, and reduce irregular migration throughout the hemisphere.  The Secretary’s trip is an opportunity to seek greater collaboration.</p>
<p>Thank you for your time.  Look forward to your questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT: </strong>  Thank you both very much.  And again, if you’d like to ask a question of either Assistant Secretary Nichols or Acting Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary Marta Youth, please press 1 then 0.</p>
<p>We’ll first go to Ryohei Takagi from Kyodo News.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong>  Mr. Takagi, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT: </strong>  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks for briefing.  Panama established diplomatic relations with China and protocol affiliations with – relations with Taiwan in 2017.  So I’m just wondering whether the relationship with Taiwan and China would be one of the topics the Secretary will discuss with his counterpart, Panama foreign minister, or not.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY NICHOLS: </strong> Thanks very much.  In all of our conversations around the hemisphere, we talk about the importance of the shared values that we have as a region, the importance of respect for human rights, the rule of law, democracy, and we talk about being transparent and understanding what’s on offer when China is engaging with a country.</p>
<p>I’m sure that will be part of the discussions that we have in Panama.  The United States has a strong commercial relationship with China, obviously.  We’re not saying don’t trade with China.  What we’re saying is do so with your eyes open, understand what’s on the table, understand how China will use and its companies will use your data if they are in the data processing business like 5G.  And that’s a common conversation for us to have with all of our partners, and we just hope that people approach these issues with full knowledge and ask the right questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT:  </strong>Thanks.  Let’s next go to Conor Finnegan from ABC News.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>Mr. Finnegan, you are open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Great.  Thank you.  Two questions here.  First, will any representatives of the Maduro government be present for the ministerial?  And can any agreement – hemisphere-wide agreement solve the migration crisis without addressing Venezuela’s political, economic, and humanitarian crises?</p>
<p>And then second, the administration has announced plans to admit up to 100,000 Ukrainian refugees.  What impact would that have on your plans to admit – or process asylum claims at the border or otherwise address migration issues?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY NICHOLS:  </strong>So the Maduro regime will not attend the ministerial.  The – obviously the lack of access to opportunity, democracy, human rights, the rule of law inside the borders of Venezuela has led many Venezuelans to vote with their feet and depart that country.  Our goal is to encourage the Maduro regime and the interim government to return to the negotiating table in Mexico City where Venezuela negotiated and led solution to that country’s problems.  We continue to support that effort and believe it has the best prospects for a lasting solution to Venezuela’s problems.</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT:  </strong>Thanks.  Let’s next go to Gustau Alegaret from NTN 24.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>Please, go ahead, Mr. Alegaret.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you very much for this opportunity.  A couple of questions.  Do we have to expect any announcement from this meeting, first of all?  And second of all, if I may, some analysts and people in Panama at the beginning of the war in Ukraine were requesting the government to block any Russian vessels or ships going through the canal as a kind of punishment or sanctions against the Kremlin.  Is that a possibility?  Is the United States supporting this idea?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY NICHOLS:  </strong>Well, I think that we expect that all of the nations that are present will respect the sanctions that exist on the Russian Federation, financial institutions within it, and private companies operating with close links to the Russian Federation and the Putin government.  We believe that the private sectors of our region are already taking extensive steps to ensure that they respect those sanctions and other measures.  I can’t speak to the specifics of ship traffic, but I do believe that we will seek ever greater application of those measures by our partners and allies around the hemisphere and around the world.</p>
<p>The – I should just note that the unprecedented flow of migrants out of Ukraine has contributed to the larger global challenge of unprecedented levels of migration over the course of the past few months.  And we as an international community are working hard to manage that in a humane, safe, transparent, and legal way, and putting the resources in place both in Europe and certainly in our own hemisphere to address this new challenge while we continue to manage the migration situation and migrant flows around our own region.</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT:  </strong>Thank you.  Let’s next go to Priscilla Alvarez from CNN.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thanks for doing the call.  What does the State Department want to – or the U.S. want to walk away with?  Would it be an agreement?  An additional commitment from Panama or other attending countries?  What would sort of signify a successful trip?</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY NICHOLS:  </strong>So this is for us an important opportunity to begin the home stretch as we prepare for the Summit of the Americas in June.  And as I said, we expect that we will have a broad migration compact or agreement that specifically helps us keep populations safe and integrated and in place where they are in our hemisphere that increases information sharing among the governments and migratory authorities of our hemisphere that leverages the resources of multilateral development banks and other international organizations like the IOM and the UN to support migration requirements throughout our hemisphere, that countries continue to take steps to regularize migration by instituting visa requirements, while appropriate that countries continue to invest in things like services for migrants at risk and shelters.  Those are all things that we’ve made significant progress on since the last ministerial, and we believe that that process will continue through Panama right up to June and the Summit of the Americas.  But perhaps my colleague Marta Youth would like to make a comment as well.</p>
<p><strong>MS YOUTH:</strong>  Sir, I think you did a fantastic job covering it, but just to kind of sum up, I mean, this really – what we’re really looking at in Panama is really continuing the conversation that we began in the original virtual meeting that the Panamanian Government hosted last year and then the October migration ministerial which we co-hosted with Colombia in October.</p>
<p>This is – we really changed the narrative, I think, in the region in terms of understanding what is really meant by shared responsibility and how we can all work together on this really unprecedented challenge, which is really not just in this region but is actually a reflection of the challenges that we are seeing happening globally in terms of forced displacement throughout the world.  And this is an event where we can discuss and act on what we need to do together to address these challenges.  Over.</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT:</strong>  Thank you.  Let’s next go to Nick Kalman from Fox.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks.  I just had a follow-up to my colleague Conor’s question on the Maduro regime, and you said that no representatives from that regime are attending the ministerial.  Could you just advise as to whether or not any representatives from the regime were invited to attend?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY NICHOLS:</strong>  Not to my knowledge.</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT:</strong>  Thanks.  Let’s next go to Ted Hesson from Reuters.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, all.  Thank you for having the call.  My question is similar to what Priscilla asked, and I’m hoping maybe you could give us some more practical examples.  I guess I understand sort of symbolically what you’re working towards, and there have been many meetings and you’ve been at this for over a year, but has there been any tangible result, and is there anything you can show us that’s affected migration at the U.S.-Mexico border, for instance, that’s come out of these talks?</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY NICHOLS:</strong>  Well, we’re working on addressing the root causes of migration as a collective effort, and one of the things that I think has been quite powerful in the near term has been Vice President Harris’ call to action, which has mobilized over $1.2 billion in private sector investment in Northern Central America and created thousands of jobs in that part of the hemisphere.  And we know that those people are not migrating.  We know that our efforts to provide COVID-19 vaccines to countries throughout the hemisphere – some 60 million vaccines in the Western Hemisphere – have helped countries recover more quickly from the COVID-19 pandemic which was a driver of migration to our southern border.</p>
<p>We know that our efforts to provide assistance to communities that are hosting migrants in Colombia, Ecuador, Peru, Chile have all helped stabilize those populations to a greater degree.  But this comes in the context of literally millions of migrants on the move in our hemisphere; some six million Venezuelans are migrants outside of Venezuela right now, over five million of them in the Western Hemisphere.  There are half a million Nicaraguans who are displaced and living in Costa Rica right now, and I had the opportunity to meet with some of them when I was there a couple weeks ago.  We’re talking about hundreds of thousands of Haitian migrants in Chile, in Brazil.</p>
<p>There are really unprecedented challenges and I think that our assistance has helped to mitigate some of that migration movement, but the challenges did not begin yesterday and they will take time for us to resolve alongside our partners.  And as Marta signaled, one of the things we don’t hear anymore is that this is a U.S. problem.  What – no one has said that to me and they – all the countries that I have talked to very much accept that we have to work together to address this challenge, and that’s what we’re doing in Panama.</p>
<p><strong>MR BARTLETT:  </strong>Thank you.  We’ll take a final question from Beatriz Pascual from EFE.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.  You have mentioned a couple of times that this meeting in Panama is in preparation for the Summit of the Americas.  So I was wondering if the United States has invited Cuba and Venezuela to the Summit of the Americas.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY NICHOLS:  </strong>So the White House will determine which leaders are invited to the Summit of the Americas, and the White House has not yet issued invitations.  I will note that the Western Hemisphere is a part of the world that has a broad commitment to democracy, as enshrined in the Inter-American Democratic Charter.  And I believe that as we move forward, we will see countries that share that commitment toward democracy as the key participants in the summit.</p>
<p><strong>MR BARNETT:  </strong>Thank you both again.  Thanks to our speakers.  And thanks to our participants for your questions.  We’ll post this transcript shortly on <a href="https://state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">state.gov</a>, and you know how to get in touch with us if you have questions in the lead-up to or during the trip.  Thank you, everybody, and have a great day.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Lenderking Concludes Regional Trip</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-special-envoy-for-yemen-lenderking-concludes-regional-trip/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 21:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=334884</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>At the end of a three-week trip to Saudi Arabia, Jordan, the United Arab Emirates, Kuwait, and Qatar by U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking, we have seen U.S. diplomatic efforts yield tangible results that improve the lives of Yemenis and advance peace.  The United States supported the UN’s efforts to secure a two-month truce, which began on April 2 and provides immediate relief to Yemenis by easing the movement of people and goods, including fuel.  In Special Envoy Lenderking’s subsequent engagements, he has urged the parties to adhere to the UN truce terms to pave the way for a viable, durable resolution to the conflict.</p>
<p>Over the past year, the Special Envoy has pressed for transparent, inclusive Yemeni-led efforts to reform the government of Yemen to ensure it meets the needs of all citizens and address their calls for justice, accountability, and redress for human rights violations and abuses.  On April 7, we welcomed Yemen’s establishment of a Presidential Leadership Council, which we urge to advance these goals in partnership with Yemeni civil society and members of marginalized communities.  We urge the Leadership Council to work closely with the Prime Minister and his government to strengthen basic services and economic stability as soon as possible, so that Yemenis can receive the tangible benefits of recent reforms.</p>
<p>During his trip, Special Envoy Lenderking continued his advocacy for additional humanitarian assistance to help close funding gaps that have reduced life-saving assistance for millions of Yemenis, as well as for additional economic assistance to address Yemen’s growing economic crisis.  In this regard, we welcomed the pledge by Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates to each provide $1 billion in economic support for the Central Bank of Yemen, and Saudi Arabia’s pledge to provide $1 billion for development projects and fuel support as well as $300 million for the UN’s humanitarian response plan.</p>
<p>The Special Envoy concluded his trip by joining a UN-led mission to raise awareness about the threat posed by the derelict <em>Safer </em>oil tanker and raise funds for an emergency UN plan to avert the devastating regional economic, humanitarian, and environmental consequences of a spill.  We commend those who have pledged financial support and encourage other donors to contribute to this new UN-coordinated plan to protect shipping, commerce, tourism, livelihoods, and coastal habitats across the Red Sea.</p>
<p>We must capitalize on this positive, unique momentum by securing a more lasting halt to fighting and a renewed, comprehensive peace process.  Yemenis are expressing cautious optimism for the first time in years as a result of the constructive steps in recent weeks.  All parties to the conflict must answer Yemenis’ demands for peace by choosing dialogue over destruction and cooperating with UN-led peace efforts.  There is hard work ahead and the United States remains committed to supporting the people of Yemen’s aspirations for a more prosperous and stable future.</p>
<p>For any questions, please contact <a href="mailto:NEA-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect"><strong>NEA-Press@state.gov</strong></a> and follow us on Twitter <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA5MTQuNDU5MjYxMTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3R3aXR0ZXIuY29tL1N0YXRlRGVwdF9ORUEjX2JsYW5rIn0.BC8vbu2qHz7aa7EEDxoMctn0whKeUVEvcLGlz0we7co%2Fs%2F1292923726%2Fbr%2F112353014981-l&amp;data=04%7C01%7CMacintoshRS%40state.gov%7C36e3f8506b864b10adc208da1e52b3ac%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637855637794459997%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000&amp;sdata=gE61UCJzCMr3NA%2F%2BpCwfub2Ofy6JalNvQ2T9shWLJAQ%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect"><strong>@StateDept_NEA</strong></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>At the end of a three-week trip to Saudi Arabia, Jordan, the United Arab Emirates, Kuwait, and Qatar by U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking, we have seen U.S. diplomatic efforts yield tangible results that improve the lives of Yemenis and advance peace.  The United States supported the UN’s efforts to secure a two-month truce, which began on April 2 and provides immediate relief to Yemenis by easing the movement of people and goods, including fuel.  In Special Envoy Lenderking’s subsequent engagements, he has urged the parties to adhere to the UN truce terms to pave the way for a viable, durable resolution to the conflict.</p>
<p>Over the past year, the Special Envoy has pressed for transparent, inclusive Yemeni-led efforts to reform the government of Yemen to ensure it meets the needs of all citizens and address their calls for justice, accountability, and redress for human rights violations and abuses.  On April 7, we welcomed Yemen’s establishment of a Presidential Leadership Council, which we urge to advance these goals in partnership with Yemeni civil society and members of marginalized communities.  We urge the Leadership Council to work closely with the Prime Minister and his government to strengthen basic services and economic stability as soon as possible, so that Yemenis can receive the tangible benefits of recent reforms.</p>
<p>During his trip, Special Envoy Lenderking continued his advocacy for additional humanitarian assistance to help close funding gaps that have reduced life-saving assistance for millions of Yemenis, as well as for additional economic assistance to address Yemen’s growing economic crisis.  In this regard, we welcomed the pledge by Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates to each provide $1 billion in economic support for the Central Bank of Yemen, and Saudi Arabia’s pledge to provide $1 billion for development projects and fuel support as well as $300 million for the UN’s humanitarian response plan.</p>
<p>The Special Envoy concluded his trip by joining a UN-led mission to raise awareness about the threat posed by the derelict <em>Safer </em>oil tanker and raise funds for an emergency UN plan to avert the devastating regional economic, humanitarian, and environmental consequences of a spill.  We commend those who have pledged financial support and encourage other donors to contribute to this new UN-coordinated plan to protect shipping, commerce, tourism, livelihoods, and coastal habitats across the Red Sea.</p>
<p>We must capitalize on this positive, unique momentum by securing a more lasting halt to fighting and a renewed, comprehensive peace process.  Yemenis are expressing cautious optimism for the first time in years as a result of the constructive steps in recent weeks.  All parties to the conflict must answer Yemenis’ demands for peace by choosing dialogue over destruction and cooperating with UN-led peace efforts.  There is hard work ahead and the United States remains committed to supporting the people of Yemen’s aspirations for a more prosperous and stable future.</p>
<p>For any questions, please contact <a href="mailto:NEA-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect"><strong>NEA-Press@state.gov</strong></a> and follow us on Twitter <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA5MTQuNDU5MjYxMTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3R3aXR0ZXIuY29tL1N0YXRlRGVwdF9ORUEjX2JsYW5rIn0.BC8vbu2qHz7aa7EEDxoMctn0whKeUVEvcLGlz0we7co%2Fs%2F1292923726%2Fbr%2F112353014981-l&amp;data=04%7C01%7CMacintoshRS%40state.gov%7C36e3f8506b864b10adc208da1e52b3ac%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637855637794459997%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000&amp;sdata=gE61UCJzCMr3NA%2F%2BpCwfub2Ofy6JalNvQ2T9shWLJAQ%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect"><strong>@StateDept_NEA</strong></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken&#8217;s Travel to Panama</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-panama/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 12:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=334728</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Panama April 19-20 to co-host a Ministerial Conference on Migration and Protection with the Government of Panama.  Following the commitments expressed at the Regional Migration Ministerial in Colombia in October 2021, Secretary Blinken and representatives of regional governments participating in the Ministerial will discuss collaboration on safe, orderly, and humane migration throughout our hemisphere.  Bringing together leaders from twenty Western Hemisphere nations, this Ministerial represents an important step forward in developing a migration management and protection framework for the Americas.</p>
<p>Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro N. Mayorkas will join Secretary Blinken in Panama.  The United States will also be represented by State Department Assistant Secretary for Western Hemisphere Affairs Brian A. Nichols and Assistant Secretary for Population, Refugees, and Migration Julieta Noyes, DHS Assistant Secretary for International Affairs Serena Hoy, DHS Assistant Secretary for Border and Immigration Policy Blas Nunez Neto, USAID Assistant Administrator for the Bureau of Latin America and the Caribbean Marcela Escobari, and Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for Transborder Security Catherine Tobin.</p>
<p>While in Panama, Secretary Blinken will meet with President Laurentino Cortizo Cohen, Foreign Minister Erika Mouynes, multilateral development banks, international financial institutions, international organizations, and NGOs to discuss economic recovery; migration; protection for refugees, asylum seekers, and vulnerable migrants; anti-corruption efforts; and support for civil society, in addition to other regional and bilateral issues of importance to the United States and Panama.  The Secretary will also tour the Panama Canal to review this vital component of regional and international trade and host a roundtable discussion with regional civil society leaders focused on transparency and anti-corruption efforts, a growing challenge for democracy and economic stability in the hemisphere.</p>
<p>Through this visit, the Secretary will draw further attention and excitement in the region towards the Ninth Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles, California on June 6-10, 2022, where Western Hemisphere leaders will expand on efforts to address our hemisphere’s most pressing issues with the aim of building a sustainable, resilient, and equitable future.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Panama April 19-20 to co-host a Ministerial Conference on Migration and Protection with the Government of Panama.  Following the commitments expressed at the Regional Migration Ministerial in Colombia in October 2021, Secretary Blinken and representatives of regional governments participating in the Ministerial will discuss collaboration on safe, orderly, and humane migration throughout our hemisphere.  Bringing together leaders from twenty Western Hemisphere nations, this Ministerial represents an important step forward in developing a migration management and protection framework for the Americas.</p>
<p>Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro N. Mayorkas will join Secretary Blinken in Panama.  The United States will also be represented by State Department Assistant Secretary for Western Hemisphere Affairs Brian A. Nichols and Assistant Secretary for Population, Refugees, and Migration Julieta Noyes, DHS Assistant Secretary for International Affairs Serena Hoy, DHS Assistant Secretary for Border and Immigration Policy Blas Nunez Neto, USAID Assistant Administrator for the Bureau of Latin America and the Caribbean Marcela Escobari, and Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for Transborder Security Catherine Tobin.</p>
<p>While in Panama, Secretary Blinken will meet with President Laurentino Cortizo Cohen, Foreign Minister Erika Mouynes, multilateral development banks, international financial institutions, international organizations, and NGOs to discuss economic recovery; migration; protection for refugees, asylum seekers, and vulnerable migrants; anti-corruption efforts; and support for civil society, in addition to other regional and bilateral issues of importance to the United States and Panama.  The Secretary will also tour the Panama Canal to review this vital component of regional and international trade and host a roundtable discussion with regional civil society leaders focused on transparency and anti-corruption efforts, a growing challenge for democracy and economic stability in the hemisphere.</p>
<p>Through this visit, the Secretary will draw further attention and excitement in the region towards the Ninth Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles, California on June 6-10, 2022, where Western Hemisphere leaders will expand on efforts to address our hemisphere’s most pressing issues with the aim of building a sustainable, resilient, and equitable future.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>COVID-19 Travel Advisory Updates</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/covid-19-travel-advisory-updates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 19:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=334584</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The Department of State has no greater responsibility than the safety and security of U.S. citizens overseas.  We are committed to providing U.S. citizens with up-to-date and timely information, so they are informed as they make international travel plans and when they are abroad.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Given the increases in international travel, the availability of effective COVID-19 mitigation measures, and recently announced changes to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s (CDC) COVID-19 Travel Health Notice (THN) process, we have reassessed how COVID-19 considerations factor into our Travel Advisory levels for U.S. citizens.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Starting next week, the State Department Travel Advisory levels will no longer automatically correlate with the CDC COVID-19 THN level.  However, if the CDC raises a country’s COVID-19 THN to a Level 4, the State Department’s Travel Advisory for that country will also be raised to a Level 4: Do Not Travel due to COVID-19.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">This update will leave approximately 10% of all Travel Advisories at Level 4: Do Not Travel.  This 10% includes Level 4 Travel Advisories for all risk indicators, not just COVID-19.  We believe the updated framework will help U.S. citizens make better informed decisions about the safety of international travel.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Although conditions have recently improved, the COVID-19 pandemic is not over.  We continue to advise travelers to consider COVID-19 conditions and restrictions at their destinations when considering international travel.  Our embassies and consulates around the world will continue to provide the latest country-specific COVID-19-related information on their<span> </span><a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/traveladvisories/COVID-19-Country-Specific-Information.html">websites</a>.  To see the latest State Department Travel Advisories for any country in the world, visit<span> </span><a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTQuNTY0MTEyNzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzLmh0bWwvIn0.C7cqloGI8MkiT5P5zJpM4iJ8E3yEosgtEjgDjCBlZ8Q%2Fs%2F402704358%2Fbr%2F129806199590-l&amp;data=04%7C01%7CTranMJ%40state.gov%7C4b26ab571062491264f808da1e1ae649%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637855398126092257%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000&amp;sdata=MpcHcvOH71wY4nTyIrQvuM7wO4f8ge4wSsntlFx2EOU%3D&amp;reserved=0">travel.state.gov</a>.  We encourage U.S. citizens who are considering international travel this summer to check their passport expiration date and act now to renew or apply for the first time.  Keep in mind many countries require passports to have at least six months’ remaining validity for entry.  Routine passport processing can take eight to eleven weeks. For information on U.S. passports, please visit<span> </span><a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en">travel.state.gov/content/travel/en</a>/passports.html.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">For press inquiries, please contact<span> </span><a href="mailto:CAPRESSREQUESTS@state.gov">CAPRESSREQUESTS@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The Department of State has no greater responsibility than the safety and security of U.S. citizens overseas.  We are committed to providing U.S. citizens with up-to-date and timely information, so they are informed as they make international travel plans and when they are abroad.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Given the increases in international travel, the availability of effective COVID-19 mitigation measures, and recently announced changes to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s (CDC) COVID-19 Travel Health Notice (THN) process, we have reassessed how COVID-19 considerations factor into our Travel Advisory levels for U.S. citizens.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Starting next week, the State Department Travel Advisory levels will no longer automatically correlate with the CDC COVID-19 THN level.  However, if the CDC raises a country’s COVID-19 THN to a Level 4, the State Department’s Travel Advisory for that country will also be raised to a Level 4: Do Not Travel due to COVID-19.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">This update will leave approximately 10% of all Travel Advisories at Level 4: Do Not Travel.  This 10% includes Level 4 Travel Advisories for all risk indicators, not just COVID-19.  We believe the updated framework will help U.S. citizens make better informed decisions about the safety of international travel.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Although conditions have recently improved, the COVID-19 pandemic is not over.  We continue to advise travelers to consider COVID-19 conditions and restrictions at their destinations when considering international travel.  Our embassies and consulates around the world will continue to provide the latest country-specific COVID-19-related information on their<span> </span><a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/traveladvisories/COVID-19-Country-Specific-Information.html">websites</a>.  To see the latest State Department Travel Advisories for any country in the world, visit<span> </span><a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTQuNTY0MTEyNzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzLmh0bWwvIn0.C7cqloGI8MkiT5P5zJpM4iJ8E3yEosgtEjgDjCBlZ8Q%2Fs%2F402704358%2Fbr%2F129806199590-l&amp;data=04%7C01%7CTranMJ%40state.gov%7C4b26ab571062491264f808da1e1ae649%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637855398126092257%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000&amp;sdata=MpcHcvOH71wY4nTyIrQvuM7wO4f8ge4wSsntlFx2EOU%3D&amp;reserved=0">travel.state.gov</a>.  We encourage U.S. citizens who are considering international travel this summer to check their passport expiration date and act now to renew or apply for the first time.  Keep in mind many countries require passports to have at least six months’ remaining validity for entry.  Routine passport processing can take eight to eleven weeks. For information on U.S. passports, please visit<span> </span><a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en">travel.state.gov/content/travel/en</a>/passports.html.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">For press inquiries, please contact<span> </span><a href="mailto:CAPRESSREQUESTS@state.gov">CAPRESSREQUESTS@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Dutch Foreign Minister Hoekstra</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-dutch-foreign-minister-hoekstra/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 18:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=334548</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Dutch Foreign Minister Wopke Hoekstra in Washington, D.C.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Hoekstra condemned the atrocities committed by Russia in Bucha and elsewhere in Ukraine, and underscored their support for holding accountable those behind them.  They agreed on the need to continue providing security and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and to increase pressure on Russia.  The Secretary expressed support for stronger European defense compatible with NATO, and they discussed ways to strengthen European security.  The Secretary thanked Foreign Minister Hoekstra for his country’s exemplary cooperation in addressing semiconductor supply chain shortages and energy volatility and emphasized the positive role of U.S.-Netherlands relations in forging a stronger Transatlantic partnership.  In anticipation of Dutch-American Friendship Day next week, the Secretary highlighted our shared values, strong economic relations, and outstanding political cooperation.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Dutch Foreign Minister Wopke Hoekstra in Washington, D.C.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Hoekstra condemned the atrocities committed by Russia in Bucha and elsewhere in Ukraine, and underscored their support for holding accountable those behind them.  They agreed on the need to continue providing security and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and to increase pressure on Russia.  The Secretary expressed support for stronger European defense compatible with NATO, and they discussed ways to strengthen European security.  The Secretary thanked Foreign Minister Hoekstra for his country’s exemplary cooperation in addressing semiconductor supply chain shortages and energy volatility and emphasized the positive role of U.S.-Netherlands relations in forging a stronger Transatlantic partnership.  In anticipation of Dutch-American Friendship Day next week, the Secretary highlighted our shared values, strong economic relations, and outstanding political cooperation.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Dutch Foreign Minister Wopke Hoekstra Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-dutch-foreign-minister-wopke-hoekstra-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 18:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=334521</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good morning, everyone.  It is a great pleasure to have my colleague and friend Foreign Minister Hoekstra here.  We’ve been seeing each other at NATO it seems on a now almost regular basis, on the phone, but it’s especially good to have you here in Washington.</p>
<p>And it’s simply evidence of the fact that the partnership between the United States and the Netherlands couldn’t be stronger and also couldn’t be more important.  At a time of tremendous challenge in Europe and around the world, we are standing strongly, resolutely together in support of Ukraine, against Russia’s aggression, in defense of the rules-based order that both of our countries are united in our determination to defend.  We could not be more grateful for this partnership.  It’s a longstanding one, one that we place tremendous value on, and particularly in challenging times it always demonstrates its great value.</p>
<p>So we’re grateful for the leadership that the Netherlands is showing throughout Europe and indeed around the world.  The voice is strong, the voice is important, the voice is valued, and so is the partnership.</p>
<p>We’ve got lots of other things to talk about, but I’m really grateful for the opportunity to actually have you here in Washington and to continue the conversations we’ve been having these many weeks.  So welcome.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HOEKSTRA:</strong>  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary, Dear Tony. Thank you very much for having us in what is truly an unprecedented era in history.  And it’s also a time where we see more than ever the tremendous importance of the transatlantic bonds.</p>
<p>Thank you very much for your leadership, for making sure that you and NATO work seamlessly together, for making sure the excellent bond between our two countries is as strong as ever.  And we will make sure that we continue to work together on all the challenging events – currently Ukraine, but there is much more to do, much more geopolitical challenges that we will face, and we value very much the bilateral bonds but also the excellent relationship between the U.S. and the European Union.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you, all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good morning, everyone.  It is a great pleasure to have my colleague and friend Foreign Minister Hoekstra here.  We’ve been seeing each other at NATO it seems on a now almost regular basis, on the phone, but it’s especially good to have you here in Washington.</p>
<p>And it’s simply evidence of the fact that the partnership between the United States and the Netherlands couldn’t be stronger and also couldn’t be more important.  At a time of tremendous challenge in Europe and around the world, we are standing strongly, resolutely together in support of Ukraine, against Russia’s aggression, in defense of the rules-based order that both of our countries are united in our determination to defend.  We could not be more grateful for this partnership.  It’s a longstanding one, one that we place tremendous value on, and particularly in challenging times it always demonstrates its great value.</p>
<p>So we’re grateful for the leadership that the Netherlands is showing throughout Europe and indeed around the world.  The voice is strong, the voice is important, the voice is valued, and so is the partnership.</p>
<p>We’ve got lots of other things to talk about, but I’m really grateful for the opportunity to actually have you here in Washington and to continue the conversations we’ve been having these many weeks.  So welcome.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HOEKSTRA:</strong>  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary, Dear Tony. Thank you very much for having us in what is truly an unprecedented era in history.  And it’s also a time where we see more than ever the tremendous importance of the transatlantic bonds.</p>
<p>Thank you very much for your leadership, for making sure that you and NATO work seamlessly together, for making sure the excellent bond between our two countries is as strong as ever.  And we will make sure that we continue to work together on all the challenging events – currently Ukraine, but there is much more to do, much more geopolitical challenges that we will face, and we value very much the bilateral bonds but also the excellent relationship between the U.S. and the European Union.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you, all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Travel of Special Representative for the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK) Kim to Seoul</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/travel-of-special-representative-for-the-democratic-peoples-republic-of-korea-dprk-kim-to-seoul/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 17:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=334512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Special Representative for the DPRK Ambassador Sung Kim will travel to Seoul from April 18-22.  During his visit, Special Representative Kim will meet with Republic of Korea (ROK) Special Representative for Korean Peninsula Peace and Security Affairs Noh Kyu-duk and other senior ROK officials to discuss the situation on the Korean Peninsula, including the international community’s response to the DPRK’s recent ICBM launches.  Deputy Special Representative for the DPRK Dr. Jung Pak will accompany Special Representative Kim on his trip.</p>
<p>The Special Representative and Deputy Special Representative’s travel to Seoul underscores the U.S. and ROK commitment to ongoing close collaboration on DPRK issues as we seek to advance complete denuclearization and permanent peace on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Special Representative for the DPRK Ambassador Sung Kim will travel to Seoul from April 18-22.  During his visit, Special Representative Kim will meet with Republic of Korea (ROK) Special Representative for Korean Peninsula Peace and Security Affairs Noh Kyu-duk and other senior ROK officials to discuss the situation on the Korean Peninsula, including the international community’s response to the DPRK’s recent ICBM launches.  Deputy Special Representative for the DPRK Dr. Jung Pak will accompany Special Representative Kim on his trip.</p>
<p>The Special Representative and Deputy Special Representative’s travel to Seoul underscores the U.S. and ROK commitment to ongoing close collaboration on DPRK issues as we seek to advance complete denuclearization and permanent peace on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Kuleba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-ukrainian-foreign-minister-kuleba-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 16:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=334502</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to reinforce the United States’ steadfast commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. We are resolved to continue to provide security, economic, and humanitarian support to the government and people of Ukraine as they defend against President Putin’s brutal and unprovoked war. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Kuleba discussed the most recent Presidential Drawdown for an additional $800 million for weapons, ammunition, and other security assistance for Ukraine’s defense. They noted that the steady supply of materiel from the United States and its Allies and partners has been instrumental in Ukraine’s successful fight against Russia’s forces. The Secretary provided an update on the most recent U.S. and global efforts to hold the Kremlin and its enablers accountable. The Secretary commended the bravery of the Ukrainian people, noting in particular those defending Mariupol.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to reinforce the United States’ steadfast commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. We are resolved to continue to provide security, economic, and humanitarian support to the government and people of Ukraine as they defend against President Putin’s brutal and unprovoked war. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Kuleba discussed the most recent Presidential Drawdown for an additional $800 million for weapons, ammunition, and other security assistance for Ukraine’s defense. They noted that the steady supply of materiel from the United States and its Allies and partners has been instrumental in Ukraine’s successful fight against Russia’s forces. The Secretary provided an update on the most recent U.S. and global efforts to hold the Kremlin and its enablers accountable. The Secretary commended the bravery of the Ukrainian people, noting in particular those defending Mariupol.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Department of State Hosts Virtual Discussion on Gender Equity in Sport Featuring Sports Icon Billie Jean King</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-department-of-state-hosts-virtual-discussion-on-gender-equity-in-sport-featuring-sports-icon-billie-jean-king/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 14:56:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=334416</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State’s Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs announced today it will host a virtual panel discussion on gender equity in sport on Monday, April 18 at 12:00 p.m. EDT, as part of its year-long programming around the 50th anniversary of Title IX, the United States’ landmark legislation that afforded equal opportunity for women in education and sport.</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for Educational and Cultural Affairs Lee Satterfield will join sports icon and equality champion Billie Jean King, International Tennis Federation Vice President Katrina Adams, and award-winning filmmaker Dawn Porter for a conversation with embassies and audiences from around the world to share their perspectives on gender and racial equity, visibility and representation, and inclusion in and through sports.</p>
<p>Watch the live panel discussion online at: <a class="external-link" href="https://www.facebook.com/SportsDiplomacyDivision" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Facebook.com/SportsDiplomacyDivision.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p>About the panelists: Billie Jean King, the first female athlete to receive the Presidential Medal of Freedom and who LIFE magazine named one of the “100 Most Important Americans of the 20th Century,” will headline the panel with Katrina Adams, Vice President of the International Tennis Federation. Ms. Adams was the first African American to lead the United States Tennis Association (USTA), the first two term Chairman and President of USTA, and the first former player to hold that honor. The panel will be moderated by Dawn Porter, an award-winning documentary filmmaker and executive producer of the film 37 Words for ESPN’s initiative Fifty/50, an in-depth look at the progress and challenges associated with Title IX implementation.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, please contact the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs at <u><a href="mailto:ECA-Press@state.gov"> ECA-Press@state.gov</a>.</u></p>
<p>Follow ECA social media accounts for updates and event highlights on Twitter <a class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/ecaatstate" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">@ECAatState</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> and @<a class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/ECA_AS" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">ECA_AS</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>; Facebook @ <a class="external-link" href="https://www.facebook.com/ExchangeProgramsAtState" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Exchange Programs – U.S. Department of State</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>; and Instagram @<a class="external-link" href="https://www.instagram.com/exchangeourworld/?hl=en" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">exchangeourworld</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State’s Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs announced today it will host a virtual panel discussion on gender equity in sport on Monday, April 18 at 12:00 p.m. EDT, as part of its year-long programming around the 50th anniversary of Title IX, the United States’ landmark legislation that afforded equal opportunity for women in education and sport.</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for Educational and Cultural Affairs Lee Satterfield will join sports icon and equality champion Billie Jean King, International Tennis Federation Vice President Katrina Adams, and award-winning filmmaker Dawn Porter for a conversation with embassies and audiences from around the world to share their perspectives on gender and racial equity, visibility and representation, and inclusion in and through sports.</p>
<p>Watch the live panel discussion online at: <a class="external-link" href="https://www.facebook.com/SportsDiplomacyDivision" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Facebook.com/SportsDiplomacyDivision.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p>About the panelists: Billie Jean King, the first female athlete to receive the Presidential Medal of Freedom and who LIFE magazine named one of the “100 Most Important Americans of the 20th Century,” will headline the panel with Katrina Adams, Vice President of the International Tennis Federation. Ms. Adams was the first African American to lead the United States Tennis Association (USTA), the first two term Chairman and President of USTA, and the first former player to hold that honor. The panel will be moderated by Dawn Porter, an award-winning documentary filmmaker and executive producer of the film 37 Words for ESPN’s initiative Fifty/50, an in-depth look at the progress and challenges associated with Title IX implementation.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, please contact the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs at <u><a href="mailto:ECA-Press@state.gov"> ECA-Press@state.gov</a>.</u></p>
<p>Follow ECA social media accounts for updates and event highlights on Twitter <a class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/ecaatstate" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">@ECAatState</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> and @<a class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/ECA_AS" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">ECA_AS</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>; Facebook @ <a class="external-link" href="https://www.facebook.com/ExchangeProgramsAtState" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Exchange Programs – U.S. Department of State</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>; and Instagram @<a class="external-link" href="https://www.instagram.com/exchangeourworld/?hl=en" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">exchangeourworld</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Department of State’s Equity Action Plan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-department-of-states-equity-action-plan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 13:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=334392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>This Equity Action Plan outlines specific actions, metrics, and accountability efforts to improve the efficiency and effectiveness to successfully integrate Executive Order (E.O) 13985 into all aspects of our foreign affairs mission.</p>
<p><strong>U.S. Foreign Policy </strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Prioritize engagements with diplomatic partners and individuals from underrepresented and underserved communities worldwide to better assess and embed equity into U.S. foreign policies.</li>
<li>Create a new three-part strategic framework to track progress and work with local stakeholders to reduce barriers to equity.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>U.S. Foreign Assistance</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Establish new reporting requirements and equity analysis tools to align priorities and operations with E.O. 13895 principles through international aid.</li>
<li>Work with stakeholders to inform data-driven operations and programming to integrate racial equity and support for underserved communities into U.S. foreign assistance.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Public Diplomacy and Public Affairs</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Embed E.O. 13985 principles into public diplomacy programming, exchanges, and communications strategies, and will use new equity assessment tools to track progress.</li>
<li>Increase inclusive messaging to combat disinformation, which can sow discord among communities and undermine democratic norms.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Consular Services</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Update the interpretation and application of the Immigration and Nationality Act to reflect advances in Assisted Reproductive Technology.</li>
<li>Offer U.S. citizenship products, such as passports, with inclusive gender markers.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Procurement, Contracts, and Grants</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Require reviews under current federal contracting processes to provide more equitable access to underserved and small business partners.</li>
<li>Grow the industrial supply base by E.O. 13985 principles into agency contracting partnerships and the federal marketplace and institute a new data-informed methodology with market research, internal business scorecards, and consultations with stakeholders.</li>
</ul>
<p>For further information, please visit <a href="https://www.state.gov/equity" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTQuNTY0MTI0MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi9lcXVpdHkifQ.FW-5Rm2hLr0tcMvoNfSbwshJAZp7GCRxRM-m4Jkx40Y/s/1006560560/br/129814168016-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1650030515674000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1jN99KvB-1Mzd1lhHKHUaA">www.state.gov/equity</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>This Equity Action Plan outlines specific actions, metrics, and accountability efforts to improve the efficiency and effectiveness to successfully integrate Executive Order (E.O) 13985 into all aspects of our foreign affairs mission.</p>
<p><strong>U.S. Foreign Policy </strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Prioritize engagements with diplomatic partners and individuals from underrepresented and underserved communities worldwide to better assess and embed equity into U.S. foreign policies.</li>
<li>Create a new three-part strategic framework to track progress and work with local stakeholders to reduce barriers to equity.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>U.S. Foreign Assistance</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Establish new reporting requirements and equity analysis tools to align priorities and operations with E.O. 13895 principles through international aid.</li>
<li>Work with stakeholders to inform data-driven operations and programming to integrate racial equity and support for underserved communities into U.S. foreign assistance.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Public Diplomacy and Public Affairs</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Embed E.O. 13985 principles into public diplomacy programming, exchanges, and communications strategies, and will use new equity assessment tools to track progress.</li>
<li>Increase inclusive messaging to combat disinformation, which can sow discord among communities and undermine democratic norms.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Consular Services</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Update the interpretation and application of the Immigration and Nationality Act to reflect advances in Assisted Reproductive Technology.</li>
<li>Offer U.S. citizenship products, such as passports, with inclusive gender markers.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Procurement, Contracts, and Grants</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Require reviews under current federal contracting processes to provide more equitable access to underserved and small business partners.</li>
<li>Grow the industrial supply base by E.O. 13985 principles into agency contracting partnerships and the federal marketplace and institute a new data-informed methodology with market research, internal business scorecards, and consultations with stakeholders.</li>
</ul>
<p>For further information, please visit <a href="https://www.state.gov/equity" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTQuNTY0MTI0MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi9lcXVpdHkifQ.FW-5Rm2hLr0tcMvoNfSbwshJAZp7GCRxRM-m4Jkx40Y/s/1006560560/br/129814168016-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1650030515674000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1jN99KvB-1Mzd1lhHKHUaA">www.state.gov/equity</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
