<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 21:54:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Kremlin Decision on Eastern Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/kremlin-decision-on-eastern-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 21:54:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=316263</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>We strongly condemn President Putin’s decision to recognize the so-called “Donetsk and Luhansk People’s Republics” as “independent.”  As we said when the Duma first made its request: this decision represents a complete rejection of Russia’s commitments under the Minsk agreements, directly contradicts Russia’s claimed commitment to diplomacy, and is a clear attack on Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>States have an obligation not to recognize a new “state” created through the threat or use of force, as well as an obligation not to disrupt another state’s borders.  Russia’s decision is yet another example of President Putin’s flagrant disrespect for international law and norms.</p>
<p>President Biden will sign an Executive Order that will prohibit all new investment, trade, and financing by U.S. persons to, from, or in the so-called “Donetsk and Luhansk People’s Republics” regions of Ukraine. We will continue to coordinate with Ukraine and our Allies and partners to take appropriate steps in response to this unprovoked and unacceptable action by Russia. The E.O. is designed to prevent Russia from profiting off of this blatant violation of international law. It is not directed at the people of Ukraine or the Ukrainian government and will allow humanitarian and other related activity to continue in these regions.</p>
<p>Our support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity as well as for the government and people of Ukraine is unwavering.  We stand with our Ukrainian partners in strongly condemning President Putin’s announcement.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>We strongly condemn President Putin’s decision to recognize the so-called “Donetsk and Luhansk People’s Republics” as “independent.”  As we said when the Duma first made its request: this decision represents a complete rejection of Russia’s commitments under the Minsk agreements, directly contradicts Russia’s claimed commitment to diplomacy, and is a clear attack on Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>States have an obligation not to recognize a new “state” created through the threat or use of force, as well as an obligation not to disrupt another state’s borders.  Russia’s decision is yet another example of President Putin’s flagrant disrespect for international law and norms.</p>
<p>President Biden will sign an Executive Order that will prohibit all new investment, trade, and financing by U.S. persons to, from, or in the so-called “Donetsk and Luhansk People’s Republics” regions of Ukraine. We will continue to coordinate with Ukraine and our Allies and partners to take appropriate steps in response to this unprovoked and unacceptable action by Russia. The E.O. is designed to prevent Russia from profiting off of this blatant violation of international law. It is not directed at the people of Ukraine or the Ukrainian government and will allow humanitarian and other related activity to continue in these regions.</p>
<p>Our support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity as well as for the government and people of Ukraine is unwavering.  We stand with our Ukrainian partners in strongly condemning President Putin’s announcement.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken On CBS Face the Nation with Margaret Brennan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-on-cbs-face-the-nation-with-margaret-brennan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 18:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=316135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  We go now to Secretary of State Antony Blinken, who was also in Munich and is here in Washington this morning.  Good morning to you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good morning, Margaret.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  President Biden says Vladimir Putin has made up his mind to invade.  But we spoke with Russia’s ambassador earlier this morning, and he insists there’s no invasion, no plan to invade, and only has troops on his own soil.  Do you have reason to believe Vladimir Putin is changing his mind?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  No, we don’t.  As President Biden said the other night, everything we’re seeing tells us that the decision we believe President Putin has made to invade is moving forward.  We’ve seen that with provocations created by the Russian or separatist forces over the weekend, false flag operations.  Now the news just this morning that the quote, unquote “exercises” Russia was engaged in in Belarus with 30,000 Russian forces that were supposed to end this weekend will now continue because of tensions in eastern Ukraine, tensions created by Russia and the separatist forces it backs there.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  We understand President Biden is calling a meeting of his National Security Council today.  What decisions will be made at that meeting?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, it’s an opportunity to review the latest information, the latest intelligence, to check signals, to check plans.  I just came back from Munich with the Vice President.  She led our delegation there to make sure that we are in lockstep with allies and partners on everything that we’re going to do both to see if we can still prevent President Putin from carrying forth his decision, and if not, making sure that we’re fully coordinated with allies and partners on the response.  They reiterated that massive consequences will follow if President Putin carries forth with the aggression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Well, when we last spoke on January 23rd, you told me that if Russia engages in other tactics short of invasion – hybrid actions, cyber attacks, efforts to bring the government down – there will be a swift, calibrated, and united response.  Aren’t they doing all of those things right now?  And where is the U.S. response?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>First of all, we’ve taken significant action over the – in recent months supplying Ukraine with more defensive – lethal defensive assistance over the last year than at any previous years.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But those cyber attacks were just attributed by the White House on Friday.  Those just happened.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  And we’ve worked closely with Ukraine to ward them off, to get back up and running.  We’ve now made an attribution to Russia for those cyber attacks.  We’re looking closely at the response that that may call for.  And we’re doing all of this in coordination with allies and partners.  If Russia commits the aggression that may be in train, all of that has been part of our plan, and we’re carrying it forward.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You said that you will meet with Russia’s top diplomat, but only if Russia does not invade.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  That’s right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But it seems contradictory because what you are saying is that’s tanks and that’s planes, but does that mean Russia has carte blanche to continue cyber attacks, to continue funding separatists in the east?  If they keep tensions at this low boil, is that acceptable to you?  Will you still sit down and negotiate?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  It’s – it’s not acceptable.  Two things.  There are two separate things there.</p>
<p>First of all, it’s not acceptable, and it’s one of the things that we’ve talked about in some detail with allies and partners this weekend.  That is a scenario by which Russia just keeps things at a low or medium boil, and there will be a response to that, too.</p>
<p>But in terms of engaging Russia, my job as a diplomat is to leave absolutely no stone unturned and see if we can prevent a war.  And if there’s anything that I can do to do that, I’m going to do it.  President Biden has made very clear that he’s prepared to meet President Putin at any time in any format if that can help prevent a war.  And as long as – even if the die is cast, until it’s settled, until we know that the tanks are rolling, the planes are flying, and the aggression has fully begun, we’re going to do everything we can to prevent it.</p>
<p>But we’re prepared either way, and we’re prepared with a response that will have massive consequences for Russia if it actually carries this through.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You have consistently described sanctions as a deterrent, but I know you heard President Zelenskyy really light into the Western allies in that speech in Munich.  And he accused you and the West of appeasement of Vladimir Putin over the past few years.  He said, “We don’t need your sanctions after the bombardment or after we have no borders or after we have no economy or after parts of our country will be occupied.  What are you waiting for?”</p>
<p>What are you waiting for?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I can’t speak, Margaret, to the last few years.  I can speak to the last few months and to the last year.  And in that period of time, the United States, again, has provided to Ukraine more assistance, including lethal military assistance, defense assistance, more in the past year than at any time in any previous year.  We have rallied other countries to stand in support of Ukraine, as well, to provide their own assistance.  We’ve rallied other countries to make clear and to put together in great detail the massive consequences that will befall Russia if it engages in this aggression.  The purpose of that is to do everything we can to deter it, to prevent a war, to deter the aggression.  And we don’t want to pull the trigger until we have to because we lose the deterrent effect.</p>
<p>At the same time, we also don’t want to detail in public exactly what we’re going to do because that will forewarn Russia; it will be able to prepare more effectively to try to mitigate the sanctions.  So, all of this is very well thought through.  And look, I recognize President Zelenskyy is in a very difficult position as the leader of a country that is under siege by Russia.  We are doing everything we can to both help Ukraine defend itself and to make clear what will happen to Russia if it undertakes this aggression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  When I spoke with the Russian ambassador, he referred to Crimea, that part of southern Ukraine that was annexed by Russia in 2014, as part of the Russian Federation.  Will the U.S. in any way consider recognizing that, ceding that territory or any territories in the east of Ukraine, as a diplomatic way out to avoid a larger war?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  No.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  No.  Hard stop.  That is not up for negotiation.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  That’s correct.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  The President has said that the United States will continue to support Ukraine in the future after an invasion.  If there is an occupation, does that mean the United States is committed to funding and arming an insurgency?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  The President said that we will, in the event of an invasion, double down on our support for Ukraine, and that means in terms of security assistance, economic assistance, diplomatic assistance, political assistance, humanitarian assistance – you name it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Secretary Blinken, good luck this week.  Thank you for your time this morning.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, Margaret.  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  We go now to Secretary of State Antony Blinken, who was also in Munich and is here in Washington this morning.  Good morning to you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good morning, Margaret.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  President Biden says Vladimir Putin has made up his mind to invade.  But we spoke with Russia’s ambassador earlier this morning, and he insists there’s no invasion, no plan to invade, and only has troops on his own soil.  Do you have reason to believe Vladimir Putin is changing his mind?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  No, we don’t.  As President Biden said the other night, everything we’re seeing tells us that the decision we believe President Putin has made to invade is moving forward.  We’ve seen that with provocations created by the Russian or separatist forces over the weekend, false flag operations.  Now the news just this morning that the quote, unquote “exercises” Russia was engaged in in Belarus with 30,000 Russian forces that were supposed to end this weekend will now continue because of tensions in eastern Ukraine, tensions created by Russia and the separatist forces it backs there.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  We understand President Biden is calling a meeting of his National Security Council today.  What decisions will be made at that meeting?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, it’s an opportunity to review the latest information, the latest intelligence, to check signals, to check plans.  I just came back from Munich with the Vice President.  She led our delegation there to make sure that we are in lockstep with allies and partners on everything that we’re going to do both to see if we can still prevent President Putin from carrying forth his decision, and if not, making sure that we’re fully coordinated with allies and partners on the response.  They reiterated that massive consequences will follow if President Putin carries forth with the aggression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Well, when we last spoke on January 23rd, you told me that if Russia engages in other tactics short of invasion – hybrid actions, cyber attacks, efforts to bring the government down – there will be a swift, calibrated, and united response.  Aren’t they doing all of those things right now?  And where is the U.S. response?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>First of all, we’ve taken significant action over the – in recent months supplying Ukraine with more defensive – lethal defensive assistance over the last year than at any previous years.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But those cyber attacks were just attributed by the White House on Friday.  Those just happened.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  And we’ve worked closely with Ukraine to ward them off, to get back up and running.  We’ve now made an attribution to Russia for those cyber attacks.  We’re looking closely at the response that that may call for.  And we’re doing all of this in coordination with allies and partners.  If Russia commits the aggression that may be in train, all of that has been part of our plan, and we’re carrying it forward.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You said that you will meet with Russia’s top diplomat, but only if Russia does not invade.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  That’s right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But it seems contradictory because what you are saying is that’s tanks and that’s planes, but does that mean Russia has carte blanche to continue cyber attacks, to continue funding separatists in the east?  If they keep tensions at this low boil, is that acceptable to you?  Will you still sit down and negotiate?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  It’s – it’s not acceptable.  Two things.  There are two separate things there.</p>
<p>First of all, it’s not acceptable, and it’s one of the things that we’ve talked about in some detail with allies and partners this weekend.  That is a scenario by which Russia just keeps things at a low or medium boil, and there will be a response to that, too.</p>
<p>But in terms of engaging Russia, my job as a diplomat is to leave absolutely no stone unturned and see if we can prevent a war.  And if there’s anything that I can do to do that, I’m going to do it.  President Biden has made very clear that he’s prepared to meet President Putin at any time in any format if that can help prevent a war.  And as long as – even if the die is cast, until it’s settled, until we know that the tanks are rolling, the planes are flying, and the aggression has fully begun, we’re going to do everything we can to prevent it.</p>
<p>But we’re prepared either way, and we’re prepared with a response that will have massive consequences for Russia if it actually carries this through.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You have consistently described sanctions as a deterrent, but I know you heard President Zelenskyy really light into the Western allies in that speech in Munich.  And he accused you and the West of appeasement of Vladimir Putin over the past few years.  He said, “We don’t need your sanctions after the bombardment or after we have no borders or after we have no economy or after parts of our country will be occupied.  What are you waiting for?”</p>
<p>What are you waiting for?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I can’t speak, Margaret, to the last few years.  I can speak to the last few months and to the last year.  And in that period of time, the United States, again, has provided to Ukraine more assistance, including lethal military assistance, defense assistance, more in the past year than at any time in any previous year.  We have rallied other countries to stand in support of Ukraine, as well, to provide their own assistance.  We’ve rallied other countries to make clear and to put together in great detail the massive consequences that will befall Russia if it engages in this aggression.  The purpose of that is to do everything we can to deter it, to prevent a war, to deter the aggression.  And we don’t want to pull the trigger until we have to because we lose the deterrent effect.</p>
<p>At the same time, we also don’t want to detail in public exactly what we’re going to do because that will forewarn Russia; it will be able to prepare more effectively to try to mitigate the sanctions.  So, all of this is very well thought through.  And look, I recognize President Zelenskyy is in a very difficult position as the leader of a country that is under siege by Russia.  We are doing everything we can to both help Ukraine defend itself and to make clear what will happen to Russia if it undertakes this aggression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  When I spoke with the Russian ambassador, he referred to Crimea, that part of southern Ukraine that was annexed by Russia in 2014, as part of the Russian Federation.  Will the U.S. in any way consider recognizing that, ceding that territory or any territories in the east of Ukraine, as a diplomatic way out to avoid a larger war?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  No.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  No.  Hard stop.  That is not up for negotiation.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  That’s correct.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  The President has said that the United States will continue to support Ukraine in the future after an invasion.  If there is an occupation, does that mean the United States is committed to funding and arming an insurgency?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  The President said that we will, in the event of an invasion, double down on our support for Ukraine, and that means in terms of security assistance, economic assistance, diplomatic assistance, political assistance, humanitarian assistance – you name it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Secretary Blinken, good luck this week.  Thank you for your time this morning.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, Margaret.  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken On NBC Meet the Press with Chuck Todd</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-on-nbc-meet-the-press-with-chuck-todd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 17:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=316130</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  And joining me now is the Secretary of the State Antony Blinken.  Secretary Blinken, welcome back to Meet the Press.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks, Chuck.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Based on everything you had hinted at, and U.S. intelligence had hinted at, between yourself and the President, has the invasion already begun?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, it certainly looks like everything we said was likely to occur in the leadup to the actual invasion is happening.  We’re seeing false flag operations taking place in eastern Ukraine, the manufacturing of provocations and justifications for Russia to go in.  We just heard this morning that “exercises” that – and I put that in quotation marks – that Russia was engaged in in Belarus with 30,000 Russian forces that were supposed to end are now not ending because of the alleged tension in eastern Ukraine that, of course, is being created by Russia and its proxies there.</p>
<p>So, all of this seems to be following the script that I laid out at the United Nations Security Council and that President Biden talked about to the nation just the other day.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  I want to get you to respond to President Zelenskyy in Munich over the last 24 hours.  He’s clearly frustrated, and he essentially said, well, if you’re so sure the invasion is here, you’re telling me that it’s 100 percent that the war will start in a couple of days, well, then, what are you waiting for?  He’s referring to the harsh sanctions, like it’s essentially if the war has begun, then let’s go.  Well?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  You also heard – Chuck, you also heard the President say that while the die may be cast, until it actually settles, until the tanks are rolling and the planes are in the air, that we’re going to try everything we possibly can to get President Putin to reverse the decision we believe he’s made and to dissuade him.  Part of that is the prospect of massive sanctions.  And just in Munich a day ago where we were all gathered, the G7 countries, the leading democratic economies in the world, reiterated very forcefully the massive consequences that would befall Russia and President Putin with sanctions if the aggression actually goes forward.</p>
<p>We continue to try to build everything we can to deter him from the course that he’s now set on.  And until the last minute, there is still an option to – for him to pull back.  That’s what we’re trying to do.  We’re trying to prevent a war.  As soon as you trigger the sanctions, of course, any deterrent effect they may have is gone.  They get absorbed by President Putin, and he moves on.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Why do you think Putin appears to not be taking these threats seriously?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, one of the challenges that we have, Chuck, I think, is that we all put our own frame of logic on what President Putin is doing that may not be the same frame that he has.  And it’s hard to put yourself in someone else’s mind, but he has decades of built-up grievances.  He has, I think, a conviction that Ukraine cannot in any way be Western-oriented, that it cannot be a successful democracy on his borders, and that fundamentally is what this is about.  He wants to reconstitute if not the Soviet empire at least a sphere of influence, and if not that at least to Finlandize his neighbors.</p>
<p>So, our logic is very different because what we’re seeing is President Putin precipitating everything he says he wants to prevent.  He’s alienated the Ukrainian people from Russia.  He’s actually caused NATO to bolster itself, and we’ll continue to do that, especially if the aggression actually goes forward.  And NATO is now closer to Russia than it was.  And so in terms of what would appear to us logically to be his interests, he is running – everything he is doing runs counter to them.  In his own logic, there may be a rationale.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So, if he goes through with this invasion and he goes to Kyiv, as President Biden seemed to indicate that this isn’t going to be just a limited thing, that he’s going all-in to Kyiv, then is President Zelenskyy right when he said yesterday in Munich that the security architecture of our world is obsolete?</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  The architecture is not obsolete.  On the contrary, what we’re seeing is it’s actually being reinforced, again, largely because of what President Putin is doing.  I just came back from Munich.  I was with all our allies and partners along with the Vice President.  And what the Vice President said very forcefully in Munich, and what I heard in private from all of our partners, is that NATO now is – has more cohesion, more solidarity than it’s had at any time in recent memory.  Leading officials from Europe said that publicly.  The Vice President certainly heard that in her meetings and in the response to her speech.  So, I think we’re seeing NATO solidified, unified by the actions that President Putin has taken.</p>
<p>Now, having said that, this aggression from Russia against Ukraine is a direct challenge to the basic principles that have undergirded our security and our peace for decades, the notion that one country doesn’t simply go in and change the borders of another by force – that it doesn’t try to subjugate another country to its will, to force its decisions on another country, including with whom that country may associate.</p>
<p>So that’s exactly why we are all standing up and standing firmly against what Russia is doing, coming together not only in support of Ukraine but also to bolster NATO and to make it clear that there will be massive consequences for Russia if it continues down this course.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Look, President Zelenskyy also brought up the fact that this isn’t vague promises that the West made to Ukraine, that Ukraine gave up its nuclear weapons.  And one of the reasons it – one of the prompt reassurances it got was essentially of protection from the West, from Europe, from the United States.  What do we owe Ukraine if Russia invades?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, first, Chuck, over the last year we’ve provided more than a billion dollars in assistance to Ukraine – in 2021, $650 million in security assistance, defensive lethal assistance.  That’s more in that year than in any previous year, along with humanitarian and economic assistance.  Just the other day we announced a billion-dollar loan guarantee for Ukraine.  We’ve been rallying other countries to do the same thing, to support it economically, militarily, diplomatically.  And if this aggression goes forward, that will continue.  Support for Ukraine across the board diplomatically, militarily, and economically will not only continue, it will deepen.  As the President said, we’ll double down on that.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Any Americans that – in Ukraine right now, will the United States Government do whatever it takes to get them out if war begins?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Chuck, we’ve been very clear for many, many weeks that in the event of a Russian invasion of Ukraine we will not be in a position to evacuate any remaining Americans from Ukraine.  I’ve said that repeatedly.  We’ve been in direct contact with every American we can possibly be in contact with – someone who is a resident, typically this is someone who is a long-term resident of Ukraine who happens to have an American passport.  We’ve communicated that directly to Congress.  We’ve urged them to communicate that to any Americans and groups that they’re in contact with.  We’ve been repeatedly clear about this, and we have seen people leave in recent weeks.</p>
<p>But we are not going to be in a position – our embassy is now shuttered in Kyiv.  We’ve moved it to Lviv toward – near the Polish border.  We are going to do everything we can to guide Americans who want to leave, to help them get out through – by telling them the best way to do that, to support them as best we can, to have consular services available for them, for example, along the border with Poland.  But in terms of an evacuation, that’s not going to happen.  And by the way, that almost never happens.  Every time in places around the world where for one reason or another we’ve had to shut down an embassy, Americans have remained.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So, the President, President Biden, indicated that Americans probably should be prepared for perhaps higher gas prices for a short period of time, if these sanctions go through.  What about the issue of cyber attacks?  How concerned are you that the Russians are going to attack us in cyber, if you will, to try to dissuade us from helping the Ukrainians?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  It’s certainly part of their playbook.  And we’ve been engaged for many months now, first of all in helping Ukraine itself bolster its cyber defenses, and of course very much focused on doing the same for ourselves in anticipation of the possibility that Russia would engage in cyber attacks in response to us standing up to their aggression.  This is a very, very dangerous game.  We’re, as I said, strengthening our own defenses.</p>
<p>When President Biden was with President Putin in Geneva a few months ago – this was at the time of ransomware attacks, including the Colonial pipeline – and the President was conveying to President Putin how seriously we take this and the need for Russia to do something about it because those engaged in the attacks were doing it from Russian soil.  And he noted to President Putin that if he were in President Putin’s shoes with this large oil and gas infrastructure, he knows how difficult it would be for President Putin, if something were to happen to that infrastructure.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Let me ask this question.  In your assessment, why did Putin – why is he escalating with Ukraine now?  Why didn’t he do this under the previous administration who wasn’t as supportive of NATO?  If you just look at it observationally, if he really wanted Ukraine and he didn’t want the United States getting in the way, he perhaps had a – more of a friendlier administration in the previous one.  Why do you think he didn’t act then?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I hope you get a chance to ask him.  But look, here’s what I can say.  I think, and I really don’t want to put myself in his mind because that – it’s very hard to do.  But I think it’s reasonable to think that as President Putin sees it, Ukraine was slipping further and further away from his grasp over time, increasingly Western-oriented, desirous of a future with Europe.  And as that was continuing year after year – by the way, largely, again as a result of his actions and alienating the Ukrainians by seizing Crimea and invading via separatists the Donbas – as that was happening, it no doubt got to a point where he thought if he didn’t do something to change the dynamic, it was just going to happen.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  It feels like that your meeting with Sergey Lavrov this week, if it happens, it means no war; if it doesn’t happen, it means war has begun.  Is that the fair way to look at that meeting?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  That’s a pretty good summary, Chuck, yes.  Look, we’re doing everything we can, and it’s my responsibility to do everything I can to try diplomatically to prevent a war.  And so, I will leave no stone unturned to do that.  I reached out to Foreign Minister Lavrov some days ago, suggested we meet this coming week in Europe to see if we can pursue conversations that would allow us to prevent a war and address the security concerns that we all have – the United States, Europe, and Russia – in that conversation.  He came back and said, yeah, let’s meet.  And we responded and said the meeting’s on provided you don’t invade Ukraine in the meantime.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So right now, that meeting’s on?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Right now, that meeting’s on.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Okay.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Stay tuned over the next few days.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Secretary of State Antony Blinken.  Appreciate you coming on and sharing your perspective with us.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks, Chuck.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  And joining me now is the Secretary of the State Antony Blinken.  Secretary Blinken, welcome back to Meet the Press.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks, Chuck.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Based on everything you had hinted at, and U.S. intelligence had hinted at, between yourself and the President, has the invasion already begun?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, it certainly looks like everything we said was likely to occur in the leadup to the actual invasion is happening.  We’re seeing false flag operations taking place in eastern Ukraine, the manufacturing of provocations and justifications for Russia to go in.  We just heard this morning that “exercises” that – and I put that in quotation marks – that Russia was engaged in in Belarus with 30,000 Russian forces that were supposed to end are now not ending because of the alleged tension in eastern Ukraine that, of course, is being created by Russia and its proxies there.</p>
<p>So, all of this seems to be following the script that I laid out at the United Nations Security Council and that President Biden talked about to the nation just the other day.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  I want to get you to respond to President Zelenskyy in Munich over the last 24 hours.  He’s clearly frustrated, and he essentially said, well, if you’re so sure the invasion is here, you’re telling me that it’s 100 percent that the war will start in a couple of days, well, then, what are you waiting for?  He’s referring to the harsh sanctions, like it’s essentially if the war has begun, then let’s go.  Well?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  You also heard – Chuck, you also heard the President say that while the die may be cast, until it actually settles, until the tanks are rolling and the planes are in the air, that we’re going to try everything we possibly can to get President Putin to reverse the decision we believe he’s made and to dissuade him.  Part of that is the prospect of massive sanctions.  And just in Munich a day ago where we were all gathered, the G7 countries, the leading democratic economies in the world, reiterated very forcefully the massive consequences that would befall Russia and President Putin with sanctions if the aggression actually goes forward.</p>
<p>We continue to try to build everything we can to deter him from the course that he’s now set on.  And until the last minute, there is still an option to – for him to pull back.  That’s what we’re trying to do.  We’re trying to prevent a war.  As soon as you trigger the sanctions, of course, any deterrent effect they may have is gone.  They get absorbed by President Putin, and he moves on.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Why do you think Putin appears to not be taking these threats seriously?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, one of the challenges that we have, Chuck, I think, is that we all put our own frame of logic on what President Putin is doing that may not be the same frame that he has.  And it’s hard to put yourself in someone else’s mind, but he has decades of built-up grievances.  He has, I think, a conviction that Ukraine cannot in any way be Western-oriented, that it cannot be a successful democracy on his borders, and that fundamentally is what this is about.  He wants to reconstitute if not the Soviet empire at least a sphere of influence, and if not that at least to Finlandize his neighbors.</p>
<p>So, our logic is very different because what we’re seeing is President Putin precipitating everything he says he wants to prevent.  He’s alienated the Ukrainian people from Russia.  He’s actually caused NATO to bolster itself, and we’ll continue to do that, especially if the aggression actually goes forward.  And NATO is now closer to Russia than it was.  And so in terms of what would appear to us logically to be his interests, he is running – everything he is doing runs counter to them.  In his own logic, there may be a rationale.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So, if he goes through with this invasion and he goes to Kyiv, as President Biden seemed to indicate that this isn’t going to be just a limited thing, that he’s going all-in to Kyiv, then is President Zelenskyy right when he said yesterday in Munich that the security architecture of our world is obsolete?</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  The architecture is not obsolete.  On the contrary, what we’re seeing is it’s actually being reinforced, again, largely because of what President Putin is doing.  I just came back from Munich.  I was with all our allies and partners along with the Vice President.  And what the Vice President said very forcefully in Munich, and what I heard in private from all of our partners, is that NATO now is – has more cohesion, more solidarity than it’s had at any time in recent memory.  Leading officials from Europe said that publicly.  The Vice President certainly heard that in her meetings and in the response to her speech.  So, I think we’re seeing NATO solidified, unified by the actions that President Putin has taken.</p>
<p>Now, having said that, this aggression from Russia against Ukraine is a direct challenge to the basic principles that have undergirded our security and our peace for decades, the notion that one country doesn’t simply go in and change the borders of another by force – that it doesn’t try to subjugate another country to its will, to force its decisions on another country, including with whom that country may associate.</p>
<p>So that’s exactly why we are all standing up and standing firmly against what Russia is doing, coming together not only in support of Ukraine but also to bolster NATO and to make it clear that there will be massive consequences for Russia if it continues down this course.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Look, President Zelenskyy also brought up the fact that this isn’t vague promises that the West made to Ukraine, that Ukraine gave up its nuclear weapons.  And one of the reasons it – one of the prompt reassurances it got was essentially of protection from the West, from Europe, from the United States.  What do we owe Ukraine if Russia invades?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, first, Chuck, over the last year we’ve provided more than a billion dollars in assistance to Ukraine – in 2021, $650 million in security assistance, defensive lethal assistance.  That’s more in that year than in any previous year, along with humanitarian and economic assistance.  Just the other day we announced a billion-dollar loan guarantee for Ukraine.  We’ve been rallying other countries to do the same thing, to support it economically, militarily, diplomatically.  And if this aggression goes forward, that will continue.  Support for Ukraine across the board diplomatically, militarily, and economically will not only continue, it will deepen.  As the President said, we’ll double down on that.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Any Americans that – in Ukraine right now, will the United States Government do whatever it takes to get them out if war begins?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Chuck, we’ve been very clear for many, many weeks that in the event of a Russian invasion of Ukraine we will not be in a position to evacuate any remaining Americans from Ukraine.  I’ve said that repeatedly.  We’ve been in direct contact with every American we can possibly be in contact with – someone who is a resident, typically this is someone who is a long-term resident of Ukraine who happens to have an American passport.  We’ve communicated that directly to Congress.  We’ve urged them to communicate that to any Americans and groups that they’re in contact with.  We’ve been repeatedly clear about this, and we have seen people leave in recent weeks.</p>
<p>But we are not going to be in a position – our embassy is now shuttered in Kyiv.  We’ve moved it to Lviv toward – near the Polish border.  We are going to do everything we can to guide Americans who want to leave, to help them get out through – by telling them the best way to do that, to support them as best we can, to have consular services available for them, for example, along the border with Poland.  But in terms of an evacuation, that’s not going to happen.  And by the way, that almost never happens.  Every time in places around the world where for one reason or another we’ve had to shut down an embassy, Americans have remained.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So, the President, President Biden, indicated that Americans probably should be prepared for perhaps higher gas prices for a short period of time, if these sanctions go through.  What about the issue of cyber attacks?  How concerned are you that the Russians are going to attack us in cyber, if you will, to try to dissuade us from helping the Ukrainians?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  It’s certainly part of their playbook.  And we’ve been engaged for many months now, first of all in helping Ukraine itself bolster its cyber defenses, and of course very much focused on doing the same for ourselves in anticipation of the possibility that Russia would engage in cyber attacks in response to us standing up to their aggression.  This is a very, very dangerous game.  We’re, as I said, strengthening our own defenses.</p>
<p>When President Biden was with President Putin in Geneva a few months ago – this was at the time of ransomware attacks, including the Colonial pipeline – and the President was conveying to President Putin how seriously we take this and the need for Russia to do something about it because those engaged in the attacks were doing it from Russian soil.  And he noted to President Putin that if he were in President Putin’s shoes with this large oil and gas infrastructure, he knows how difficult it would be for President Putin, if something were to happen to that infrastructure.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Let me ask this question.  In your assessment, why did Putin – why is he escalating with Ukraine now?  Why didn’t he do this under the previous administration who wasn’t as supportive of NATO?  If you just look at it observationally, if he really wanted Ukraine and he didn’t want the United States getting in the way, he perhaps had a – more of a friendlier administration in the previous one.  Why do you think he didn’t act then?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I hope you get a chance to ask him.  But look, here’s what I can say.  I think, and I really don’t want to put myself in his mind because that – it’s very hard to do.  But I think it’s reasonable to think that as President Putin sees it, Ukraine was slipping further and further away from his grasp over time, increasingly Western-oriented, desirous of a future with Europe.  And as that was continuing year after year – by the way, largely, again as a result of his actions and alienating the Ukrainians by seizing Crimea and invading via separatists the Donbas – as that was happening, it no doubt got to a point where he thought if he didn’t do something to change the dynamic, it was just going to happen.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  It feels like that your meeting with Sergey Lavrov this week, if it happens, it means no war; if it doesn’t happen, it means war has begun.  Is that the fair way to look at that meeting?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  That’s a pretty good summary, Chuck, yes.  Look, we’re doing everything we can, and it’s my responsibility to do everything I can to try diplomatically to prevent a war.  And so, I will leave no stone unturned to do that.  I reached out to Foreign Minister Lavrov some days ago, suggested we meet this coming week in Europe to see if we can pursue conversations that would allow us to prevent a war and address the security concerns that we all have – the United States, Europe, and Russia – in that conversation.  He came back and said, yeah, let’s meet.  And we responded and said the meeting’s on provided you don’t invade Ukraine in the meantime.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So right now, that meeting’s on?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Right now, that meeting’s on.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Okay.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Stay tuned over the next few days.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Secretary of State Antony Blinken.  Appreciate you coming on and sharing your perspective with us.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks, Chuck.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With State of the Union on CNN with Dana Bash</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-state-of-the-union-on-cnn-with-dana-bash/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 16:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=316121</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington D.C.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>And joining me now is the U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken.  Mr. Secretary, let’s start with what you just heard Clarissa reporting on, learning that troops from Russia and Belarus will continue those joint exercises there, past their planned end dates.  What does that tell you?  Does it make you more concerned about an invasion?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  It does.  And it tells us that the playbook that we laid out, I laid out at the UN Security Council last week about Russia trying to create a series of provocations as justifications for aggression against Ukraine, is going forward.  We’ve seen that over the last few days.  Now they’re justifying the continuation of exercises – “exercises,” in quotation marks – that they said would end now, the continuation indefinitely of those quote/unquote “exercises” on the situation in eastern Ukraine, a situation that they’ve created by continuing to ramp up tensions.  Meanwhile, they’ve been escalating the forces they have across Ukraine’s borders over the last months from 50,000 forces to 100,000 to now more than 150,000.  So, all of this along with the false flag operations we’ve seen unfold over the weekend tells us that the playbook that we laid out is moving forward.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So, you mentioned the false flag operation.  You have that.  You also have, as Clarissa talked about, a kindergarten hit by a shell.  And you have a cyber attack that’s already happened.  Ukraine is reporting dozens of ceasefire violations.  Is Russia’s plan to invade already in motion?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  It – as we’ve described it, everything leading up to the actual invasion appears to be taking place.  All of these false flag operations, all of these provocations to create justifications – all of that is already in train.  But you heard President Biden say this the other night:  We believe President Putin has made the decision, but until the tanks are actually rolling and the planes are flying, we will use every opportunity and every minute we have to see if diplomacy can still dissuade President Putin from carrying this forward.  President Biden is prepared to engage President Putin at any time in any format if that can help prevent a war.  I’ve reached out to my Russian counterpart, Foreign Minister Lavrov, to urge that we meet next week in Europe.  The plan is still to do that – unless Russia invades in the meantime.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Ukrainian President Zelenskyy called for the U.S. to impose sanctions now.  He did that in Munich yesterday.  I want you to take a listen:</p>
<p>“(Via interpreter)  What are you waiting for?  We don’t need your sanctions after the bombardment will happen, and after our country will be fired at or after we will have no borders and after we will have no economy or part of our countries will be occupied?  Why would we need those sanctions then?”</p>
<p>And he called on you at the very least to make a list of specific sanctions public.  What’s your response?<b></b></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, we’ve been in very close contact with President Zelenskyy and his entire team.  The Vice President in Munich met with him.  They had a very good meeting in which the Vice President reiterated all the support that we’ve been building for Ukraine over many months, including in the last year alone more support for defensive lethal military equipment in that one year than in any previous year.  Economic support – I announced a loan guarantee for Ukraine of a billion dollars just a week ago.  And we have rallied others to do the same thing.</p>
<p>When it comes to sanctions, we have built, with European partners and allies, a massive package of sanctions.  The G7 countries in Munich came together, reiterated that there would be massive consequences for Russia if it pursues this aggression.  The purpose of the sanctions, in the first instance, is to try to deter Russia from going to war.  As soon as you trigger them, that deterrent is gone.  And until the last minute, as long as we can try to bring a deterrent effect to this, we’re going to try to do that.</p>
<p>As to laying out in detail what the sanctions will be, two things.  First, Russia generally has a pretty good idea of what we’re going to do, but we don’t want to lay out the specifics in advance because that would allow Russia to try to plan against them.  So, we have very clearly – and the G7 could not have been more clear – a massive package that will unfold rapidly in unison between the United States and Europe and other countries beyond Europe.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>And Mr. Secretary, it seems as though we’re hearing two competing notions.  On the one hand, you’re saying and the President – President Biden said clearly Russia has decided to invade.  And then on the other hand you’re saying we don’t want to impose sanctions because that would get rid of a deterrent.  So, which one is it?  And especially given the fact that you have the Ukrainian leader with hundreds of thousands of troops on his border being told that they’re going to – Russia is going to invade at any minute, leaving his country going to a forum on the world stage in order to have that kind of platform to plead with you please impose sanctions now, how is the answer not yes?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, first, we’ve already imposed sanctions.  We’ve sanctioned various &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>More sanctions.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>First, we’ve imposed – as I said, Dana, we’ve imposed sanctions already on actors in Ukraine who are working for Russian security forces and trying to destabilize the country.  And again, and I – look, I understand where President Zelenskyy is coming from.  But these things are not at all inconsistent, because as President Biden said, while we believe President Putin has made the decision that the die is cast, until that die actually settles and until the tanks are actually moving, the planes are actually flying, the bombs are actually dropping, we’re going to do everything we can with diplomacy and with deterrence and dissuasion to get President Putin to reverse the decision that we believe he’s made.  And part of that is making very clear what he risks in terms of sanctions.</p>
<p>That’s why we’re reiterated so strongly this weekend with the world’s leading democratic economies, the G7.  We’re going to use every tool that we can to try to get him off the course that he’s on.  If that doesn’t succeed, if he goes forward nonetheless with the invasion, then the world is very clear that it’s going to come down on him and Russia very, very hard.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>What are the chances that Vladimir Putin is bluffing?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>There is always a chance, but every indication that we’ve seen, every move that he’s made that has followed the play that we laid out for the world to see in front of the United Nations Security Council, he is following the script almost to the letter.  So, I think while there’s always a chance, everything we’re seeing suggests that this is dead serious, that we are on the brink of an invasion.  We will do everything we can to try to prevent it before it happens.  But equally, we’re prepared, if he does follow through, to impose massive consequences, to defend – to provide for Ukraine’s ongoing defense, and to bolster NATO.</p>
<p>And here again, what is remarkable about this is President Putin will have precipitated everything he has sought to prevent, because all of this has only reinforced NATO, reinforced its solidarity, its commitment, and indeed reinforced NATO on its eastern flank.  I was just in Munich with all of the leaders of our European partners, and I think all of us who’ve been doing this for many years have never seen a time when NATO has been more unified and is, I think, going to further demonstrate that if Putin follows through with the invasion.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>President Zelenskyy also said yesterday that Ukraine’s economy is just getting crushed.  The head of the Council on Foreign Relations, Richard Haass, says that the U.S. should also be ready for this standoff to stretch out for months perhaps while Ukraine’s economy collapses.  What do you make of that scenario, and would Putin face consequences for that?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>First, that’s a possibility as well, and it’s exactly why we announced a billion-dollar loan guarantee just last week.  That’s on top of previous loan guarantees we’ve provided to Ukraine, for a total of $4 billion to shore up its economy.</p>
<p>At the same time, the Europeans are doing the same thing, both on a direct country-to-country basis but also the European Union making available to Ukraine, also a couple of weeks ago, a credit facility of more than a billion dollars.  We’re also helping Ukraine work directly and closely with the IMF to shore up its economy, to pursue reforms, to make sure that it’s able to stand on its feet economically.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>But would Putin face consequences if that is ultimately what he does, he just chokes the economy there?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>We are very focused, with all of our allies and partners on ensuring that Russia does face consequences for the actions that it takes, to include actions that would involve squeezing Ukraine going forward.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Before I let you go, you mentioned that you did accept a meeting with the Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov.  That’s going to happen this coming week.  Given that President Biden says President Putin has decided to invade, is the meeting for sure going happen, number one, and do you have kind of a “Hail Mary” offer for Russia to avoid war?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, I reached out to Foreign Minister Lavrov about a week ago suggesting we meet in Europe next week, and he came back and said yes.  I went back and said: okay, the meeting’s on, provided Russia doesn’t invade Ukraine in the interim.  So, it all depends on what Russia does in the coming days.  If it doesn’t invade, I’ll be there.  I hope he’ll be there too.  And I will do everything I can to see if we can advance a diplomatic resolution to this crisis created by Russia and its aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>We’ve put on the table a number of ideas that we can pursue that would strengthen security for Russia, for the United States, for Europe, if we engaged in them on a reciprocal basis.  So, there are things that we’re prepared to do if Russia is also prepared to take steps.  That’s the conversation I’d welcome having with Foreign Minister Lavrov, but it depends entirely on whether Russia invades or not.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Very busy day and week ahead.  Thank you so much, Mr. Secretary, for joining me this morning.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thanks, Dana.  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington D.C.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>And joining me now is the U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken.  Mr. Secretary, let’s start with what you just heard Clarissa reporting on, learning that troops from Russia and Belarus will continue those joint exercises there, past their planned end dates.  What does that tell you?  Does it make you more concerned about an invasion?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  It does.  And it tells us that the playbook that we laid out, I laid out at the UN Security Council last week about Russia trying to create a series of provocations as justifications for aggression against Ukraine, is going forward.  We’ve seen that over the last few days.  Now they’re justifying the continuation of exercises – “exercises,” in quotation marks – that they said would end now, the continuation indefinitely of those quote/unquote “exercises” on the situation in eastern Ukraine, a situation that they’ve created by continuing to ramp up tensions.  Meanwhile, they’ve been escalating the forces they have across Ukraine’s borders over the last months from 50,000 forces to 100,000 to now more than 150,000.  So, all of this along with the false flag operations we’ve seen unfold over the weekend tells us that the playbook that we laid out is moving forward.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So, you mentioned the false flag operation.  You have that.  You also have, as Clarissa talked about, a kindergarten hit by a shell.  And you have a cyber attack that’s already happened.  Ukraine is reporting dozens of ceasefire violations.  Is Russia’s plan to invade already in motion?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  It – as we’ve described it, everything leading up to the actual invasion appears to be taking place.  All of these false flag operations, all of these provocations to create justifications – all of that is already in train.  But you heard President Biden say this the other night:  We believe President Putin has made the decision, but until the tanks are actually rolling and the planes are flying, we will use every opportunity and every minute we have to see if diplomacy can still dissuade President Putin from carrying this forward.  President Biden is prepared to engage President Putin at any time in any format if that can help prevent a war.  I’ve reached out to my Russian counterpart, Foreign Minister Lavrov, to urge that we meet next week in Europe.  The plan is still to do that – unless Russia invades in the meantime.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Ukrainian President Zelenskyy called for the U.S. to impose sanctions now.  He did that in Munich yesterday.  I want you to take a listen:</p>
<p>“(Via interpreter)  What are you waiting for?  We don’t need your sanctions after the bombardment will happen, and after our country will be fired at or after we will have no borders and after we will have no economy or part of our countries will be occupied?  Why would we need those sanctions then?”</p>
<p>And he called on you at the very least to make a list of specific sanctions public.  What’s your response?<b></b></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, we’ve been in very close contact with President Zelenskyy and his entire team.  The Vice President in Munich met with him.  They had a very good meeting in which the Vice President reiterated all the support that we’ve been building for Ukraine over many months, including in the last year alone more support for defensive lethal military equipment in that one year than in any previous year.  Economic support – I announced a loan guarantee for Ukraine of a billion dollars just a week ago.  And we have rallied others to do the same thing.</p>
<p>When it comes to sanctions, we have built, with European partners and allies, a massive package of sanctions.  The G7 countries in Munich came together, reiterated that there would be massive consequences for Russia if it pursues this aggression.  The purpose of the sanctions, in the first instance, is to try to deter Russia from going to war.  As soon as you trigger them, that deterrent is gone.  And until the last minute, as long as we can try to bring a deterrent effect to this, we’re going to try to do that.</p>
<p>As to laying out in detail what the sanctions will be, two things.  First, Russia generally has a pretty good idea of what we’re going to do, but we don’t want to lay out the specifics in advance because that would allow Russia to try to plan against them.  So, we have very clearly – and the G7 could not have been more clear – a massive package that will unfold rapidly in unison between the United States and Europe and other countries beyond Europe.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>And Mr. Secretary, it seems as though we’re hearing two competing notions.  On the one hand, you’re saying and the President – President Biden said clearly Russia has decided to invade.  And then on the other hand you’re saying we don’t want to impose sanctions because that would get rid of a deterrent.  So, which one is it?  And especially given the fact that you have the Ukrainian leader with hundreds of thousands of troops on his border being told that they’re going to – Russia is going to invade at any minute, leaving his country going to a forum on the world stage in order to have that kind of platform to plead with you please impose sanctions now, how is the answer not yes?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, first, we’ve already imposed sanctions.  We’ve sanctioned various &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>More sanctions.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>First, we’ve imposed – as I said, Dana, we’ve imposed sanctions already on actors in Ukraine who are working for Russian security forces and trying to destabilize the country.  And again, and I – look, I understand where President Zelenskyy is coming from.  But these things are not at all inconsistent, because as President Biden said, while we believe President Putin has made the decision that the die is cast, until that die actually settles and until the tanks are actually moving, the planes are actually flying, the bombs are actually dropping, we’re going to do everything we can with diplomacy and with deterrence and dissuasion to get President Putin to reverse the decision that we believe he’s made.  And part of that is making very clear what he risks in terms of sanctions.</p>
<p>That’s why we’re reiterated so strongly this weekend with the world’s leading democratic economies, the G7.  We’re going to use every tool that we can to try to get him off the course that he’s on.  If that doesn’t succeed, if he goes forward nonetheless with the invasion, then the world is very clear that it’s going to come down on him and Russia very, very hard.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>What are the chances that Vladimir Putin is bluffing?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>There is always a chance, but every indication that we’ve seen, every move that he’s made that has followed the play that we laid out for the world to see in front of the United Nations Security Council, he is following the script almost to the letter.  So, I think while there’s always a chance, everything we’re seeing suggests that this is dead serious, that we are on the brink of an invasion.  We will do everything we can to try to prevent it before it happens.  But equally, we’re prepared, if he does follow through, to impose massive consequences, to defend – to provide for Ukraine’s ongoing defense, and to bolster NATO.</p>
<p>And here again, what is remarkable about this is President Putin will have precipitated everything he has sought to prevent, because all of this has only reinforced NATO, reinforced its solidarity, its commitment, and indeed reinforced NATO on its eastern flank.  I was just in Munich with all of the leaders of our European partners, and I think all of us who’ve been doing this for many years have never seen a time when NATO has been more unified and is, I think, going to further demonstrate that if Putin follows through with the invasion.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>President Zelenskyy also said yesterday that Ukraine’s economy is just getting crushed.  The head of the Council on Foreign Relations, Richard Haass, says that the U.S. should also be ready for this standoff to stretch out for months perhaps while Ukraine’s economy collapses.  What do you make of that scenario, and would Putin face consequences for that?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>First, that’s a possibility as well, and it’s exactly why we announced a billion-dollar loan guarantee just last week.  That’s on top of previous loan guarantees we’ve provided to Ukraine, for a total of $4 billion to shore up its economy.</p>
<p>At the same time, the Europeans are doing the same thing, both on a direct country-to-country basis but also the European Union making available to Ukraine, also a couple of weeks ago, a credit facility of more than a billion dollars.  We’re also helping Ukraine work directly and closely with the IMF to shore up its economy, to pursue reforms, to make sure that it’s able to stand on its feet economically.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>But would Putin face consequences if that is ultimately what he does, he just chokes the economy there?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>We are very focused, with all of our allies and partners on ensuring that Russia does face consequences for the actions that it takes, to include actions that would involve squeezing Ukraine going forward.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Before I let you go, you mentioned that you did accept a meeting with the Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov.  That’s going to happen this coming week.  Given that President Biden says President Putin has decided to invade, is the meeting for sure going happen, number one, and do you have kind of a “Hail Mary” offer for Russia to avoid war?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, I reached out to Foreign Minister Lavrov about a week ago suggesting we meet in Europe next week, and he came back and said yes.  I went back and said: okay, the meeting’s on, provided Russia doesn’t invade Ukraine in the interim.  So, it all depends on what Russia does in the coming days.  If it doesn’t invade, I’ll be there.  I hope he’ll be there too.  And I will do everything I can to see if we can advance a diplomatic resolution to this crisis created by Russia and its aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>We’ve put on the table a number of ideas that we can pursue that would strengthen security for Russia, for the United States, for Europe, if we engaged in them on a reciprocal basis.  So, there are things that we’re prepared to do if Russia is also prepared to take steps.  That’s the conversation I’d welcome having with Foreign Minister Lavrov, but it depends entirely on whether Russia invades or not.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Very busy day and week ahead.  Thank you so much, Mr. Secretary, for joining me this morning.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thanks, Dana.  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate Kerry’s Travel to Egypt</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-presidential-envoy-for-climate-kerrys-travel-to-egypt-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 13:06:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=316092</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Cairo, Egypt on February 20-21. On Monday, February 21 at 16:30 (GMT +2), Secretary Kerry will deliver an address at American University in Cairo on the future of international climate action in the leadup to COP27 in Sharm El-Sheikh. The remarks will be live-streamed at aucegypt.edu/streaming.</p>
<p>Secretary Kerry will also meet with government counterparts and business representatives to urge continued and increased climate ambition. Together with Egyptian Foreign Minister Sameh Shoukry, Secretary Kerry will launch the inaugural meeting of the U.S.-Egypt Climate Working Group, a joint endeavor to advance bilateral and multilateral climate goals ahead of COP27.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact ClimateComms@state.gov.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Cairo, Egypt on February 20-21. On Monday, February 21 at 16:30 (GMT +2), Secretary Kerry will deliver an address at American University in Cairo on the future of international climate action in the leadup to COP27 in Sharm El-Sheikh. The remarks will be live-streamed at aucegypt.edu/streaming.</p>
<p>Secretary Kerry will also meet with government counterparts and business representatives to urge continued and increased climate ambition. Together with Egyptian Foreign Minister Sameh Shoukry, Secretary Kerry will launch the inaugural meeting of the U.S.-Egypt Climate Working Group, a joint endeavor to advance bilateral and multilateral climate goals ahead of COP27.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact ClimateComms@state.gov.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Ekaterina Kotrikadze of Dozhd TV</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-ekaterina-kotrikadze-of-dozhd-tv/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 19:14:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=316048</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Munich, Germany</p>
<p>Munich Marriott Hotel</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  First of all, thank you so much, Mr. Secretary.  It’s a really important opportunity to us.  And the first question is about the war, actually.  President Biden has mentioned that Vladimir Putin has already made a decision.  Also, we have heard that Defense Secretary Austin said that the decision – I mean the invasion is not inevitable.  So on a scale from one to five, how would you evaluate the attack is imminent or not?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, it’s hard to put a number on it, but as President Biden said, based on the information we have, it appears that President Putin has made a decision to renew aggression against Ukraine.  But of course, until the very last moment that that actually happens, we will do everything we can to try to find a diplomatic resolution to this because conflict, war, aggression is in no one’s interest.  It’s the last thing that we want; it’s the last thing that anyone needs, starting with the Russian people.  How aggression against Ukraine meets the needs and interests of the Russian people, I don’t understand.  We have so much that we should be focused on, including together: dealing with COVID-19, which is a problem for everyone; dealing with climate change; working to strengthen and build our economies so people have better lives.  This is where our energy should be focused.</p>
<p>So how it is that attacking another country, trying to subjugate it, does anything good for anyone, including the Russian people, I don’t understand.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You are meeting your colleague, Russian colleague Sergey Lavrov, on the 23rd as I understand.  So are there any concessions the United States are ready to agree on to de-escalate the situation in Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’ve been working for many, many weeks now in close coordination with European partners and allies to look very carefully at what the Russian Government has put forward, the concerns that it’s raised about its security.  We’ve shared concerns about our security that we think is challenged by some of Russia’s actions.  And we’ve said we’re fully prepared to talk on a reciprocal basis about what we can do to improve security for everyone – for Russia, for the United States, for Europe.  We do have a planned meeting on the 24th, next week in Europe, but as I said to Foreign Minister Lavrov in the note I wrote back to him, that assumes that Russia does not invade Ukraine in the meantime.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So is there anything in particular that you can, I don’t know, offer – if this is the right word to use – to Sergey Lavrov?  Is there anything that maybe they are giving you some signals that they would be – they would be agreeing to something, something else, that you can offer?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We have already suggested that there are many areas where we actually could work together to improve everyone’s security.  There are confidence-building measures.  There are ways to reduce risks.  There’s further arms control.  There’s the question of placement of weapons and forces that, again, on a reciprocal basis could improve everyone’s security.  And I’ve already met with Foreign Minister Lavrov, including in Geneva a couple of weeks ago.  We’re fully prepared to work on that.</p>
<p>But doing that as well with a gun pointed to Ukraine’s head – 150,000 Russian forces to the north, to the east, to the south – it’s very difficult to make progress in that environment.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, the Russian side is insisting that this is a genocide going on in Ukraine, and that Kyiv is actually responsible for the situation and for pushing for war, and they are repeating it on and on.  So, what makes you so sure that Kyiv is not responsible for this escalation?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, first of all, the notion that there is a quote/unquote “genocide” going on is absolutely wrong and, frankly, offensive.  It’s a degradation of that word, to say the least.  It’s simply not happening.  How do we know this?  Because at least on the Ukrainian side of the line that’s been established as a result of the Russian incursion into Ukraine, we have the OSCE and monitors who verify what’s going on and what’s not going on.</p>
<p>And the notion that somehow there’s a threat now to Russia from Ukraine defies any logic given the size of the countries, and the notion that Ukraine is suddenly about to try to take back the Donbas, which it could have done anytime over the last eight years but it would choose now when there are 150,000 Russian forces surrounding Ukraine, defies any logic.  And unfortunately what we’re seeing is playing out exactly as I said a few days ago at the United Nations Security Council.  There is the fabrication of provocations that would be then used as a justification for Russian military intervention in the Donbas and in Ukraine more broadly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, what do you think President Zelenskyy should do in this situation and the circumstances?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, he has to make his own decisions as the democratically- elected leader of Ukraine, and we strongly support him and the government, the democratically elected Government of Ukraine.  But there’s another thing that defies logic – and here’s a challenge, and it’s a challenge for any system that has become, unfortunately as Russia has, an autocracy, which is that there are very few people who speak truth to power.  And, I worry that President Putin is not necessarily getting the facts and getting the truth.</p>
<p>If he believes that Russian forces would be accepted with open arms in Ukraine, I think he’s profoundly wrong.  And what’s happened since 2014 is very, very clear and very, very striking.  Before 2014, before Russia seized Crimea and went into the Donbas to support these separatist forces, actually in Ukraine, if you looked at public opinion polling, people had very favorable views of Russia, which is good.  Today, it’s entirely reversed: 90 percent of Ukrainians have been alienated from Russia as a result of Russia’s aggression.  Before 2014, before Crimea, before the Donbas, 25 percent of Ukrainians wanted to join NATO.  Now it’s 60 or 65 percent.  President Putin, by his actions and Russia’s actions, has precipitated what he says he wants to prevent.  And if this continues, if this goes forward, I think it will only get worse.  And the people who will suffer first and foremost are innocent Ukrainians.  If there is an attack on Kyiv, almost three million people, that will be disastrous.</p>
<p>But I have say, as well, I fear that Russians will suffer.  Russian forces will not be received with open arms by Ukrainians.  On the contrary.  And of course, the international community is united in making clear that if Russia commits new aggression against Ukraine, there will be very serious consequences.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You have just mentioned the information that Putin gets.  So there are some concerns and confusion even in Russia in terms of the information that you get from intelligence – the intelligence services.  And I just have to ask you:  What is the level of this intel that you get?  And about the different ways and scenarios of invasion. You know, what is the level of reliability of the sources?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  All I can tell you is this:  We’re very confident in the information that we have.  And as I said at the United Nations Security Council the other day, I recognize that in the past, sometimes we’ve come forward with information that’s turned out to be inaccurate.  We’re very confident in the information we have, and we bring it forward not to start a war, but to prevent a war – a war that’s in no one’s interests, starting with the Russian people.  That’s what we’re trying to do.  And if we can find a diplomatic way to do that, I’m determined to do that.  But if we have to respond to aggression from Russia, we’ll do that as well.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You are sure that all the scenarios were on the table, at Putin’s table?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yes, you are sure?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And the final thing, just very short:  Is there a meeting between the two presidents planned, Mr. Biden, Mr. Putin, when and where?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  President Biden is always fully prepared to meet if we think that can advance the cause of diplomacy and the cause of peace.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you very much.  I really appreciate your answers.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Munich, Germany</p>
<p>Munich Marriott Hotel</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  First of all, thank you so much, Mr. Secretary.  It’s a really important opportunity to us.  And the first question is about the war, actually.  President Biden has mentioned that Vladimir Putin has already made a decision.  Also, we have heard that Defense Secretary Austin said that the decision – I mean the invasion is not inevitable.  So on a scale from one to five, how would you evaluate the attack is imminent or not?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, it’s hard to put a number on it, but as President Biden said, based on the information we have, it appears that President Putin has made a decision to renew aggression against Ukraine.  But of course, until the very last moment that that actually happens, we will do everything we can to try to find a diplomatic resolution to this because conflict, war, aggression is in no one’s interest.  It’s the last thing that we want; it’s the last thing that anyone needs, starting with the Russian people.  How aggression against Ukraine meets the needs and interests of the Russian people, I don’t understand.  We have so much that we should be focused on, including together: dealing with COVID-19, which is a problem for everyone; dealing with climate change; working to strengthen and build our economies so people have better lives.  This is where our energy should be focused.</p>
<p>So how it is that attacking another country, trying to subjugate it, does anything good for anyone, including the Russian people, I don’t understand.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You are meeting your colleague, Russian colleague Sergey Lavrov, on the 23rd as I understand.  So are there any concessions the United States are ready to agree on to de-escalate the situation in Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’ve been working for many, many weeks now in close coordination with European partners and allies to look very carefully at what the Russian Government has put forward, the concerns that it’s raised about its security.  We’ve shared concerns about our security that we think is challenged by some of Russia’s actions.  And we’ve said we’re fully prepared to talk on a reciprocal basis about what we can do to improve security for everyone – for Russia, for the United States, for Europe.  We do have a planned meeting on the 24th, next week in Europe, but as I said to Foreign Minister Lavrov in the note I wrote back to him, that assumes that Russia does not invade Ukraine in the meantime.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So is there anything in particular that you can, I don’t know, offer – if this is the right word to use – to Sergey Lavrov?  Is there anything that maybe they are giving you some signals that they would be – they would be agreeing to something, something else, that you can offer?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We have already suggested that there are many areas where we actually could work together to improve everyone’s security.  There are confidence-building measures.  There are ways to reduce risks.  There’s further arms control.  There’s the question of placement of weapons and forces that, again, on a reciprocal basis could improve everyone’s security.  And I’ve already met with Foreign Minister Lavrov, including in Geneva a couple of weeks ago.  We’re fully prepared to work on that.</p>
<p>But doing that as well with a gun pointed to Ukraine’s head – 150,000 Russian forces to the north, to the east, to the south – it’s very difficult to make progress in that environment.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, the Russian side is insisting that this is a genocide going on in Ukraine, and that Kyiv is actually responsible for the situation and for pushing for war, and they are repeating it on and on.  So, what makes you so sure that Kyiv is not responsible for this escalation?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, first of all, the notion that there is a quote/unquote “genocide” going on is absolutely wrong and, frankly, offensive.  It’s a degradation of that word, to say the least.  It’s simply not happening.  How do we know this?  Because at least on the Ukrainian side of the line that’s been established as a result of the Russian incursion into Ukraine, we have the OSCE and monitors who verify what’s going on and what’s not going on.</p>
<p>And the notion that somehow there’s a threat now to Russia from Ukraine defies any logic given the size of the countries, and the notion that Ukraine is suddenly about to try to take back the Donbas, which it could have done anytime over the last eight years but it would choose now when there are 150,000 Russian forces surrounding Ukraine, defies any logic.  And unfortunately what we’re seeing is playing out exactly as I said a few days ago at the United Nations Security Council.  There is the fabrication of provocations that would be then used as a justification for Russian military intervention in the Donbas and in Ukraine more broadly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, what do you think President Zelenskyy should do in this situation and the circumstances?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, he has to make his own decisions as the democratically- elected leader of Ukraine, and we strongly support him and the government, the democratically elected Government of Ukraine.  But there’s another thing that defies logic – and here’s a challenge, and it’s a challenge for any system that has become, unfortunately as Russia has, an autocracy, which is that there are very few people who speak truth to power.  And, I worry that President Putin is not necessarily getting the facts and getting the truth.</p>
<p>If he believes that Russian forces would be accepted with open arms in Ukraine, I think he’s profoundly wrong.  And what’s happened since 2014 is very, very clear and very, very striking.  Before 2014, before Russia seized Crimea and went into the Donbas to support these separatist forces, actually in Ukraine, if you looked at public opinion polling, people had very favorable views of Russia, which is good.  Today, it’s entirely reversed: 90 percent of Ukrainians have been alienated from Russia as a result of Russia’s aggression.  Before 2014, before Crimea, before the Donbas, 25 percent of Ukrainians wanted to join NATO.  Now it’s 60 or 65 percent.  President Putin, by his actions and Russia’s actions, has precipitated what he says he wants to prevent.  And if this continues, if this goes forward, I think it will only get worse.  And the people who will suffer first and foremost are innocent Ukrainians.  If there is an attack on Kyiv, almost three million people, that will be disastrous.</p>
<p>But I have say, as well, I fear that Russians will suffer.  Russian forces will not be received with open arms by Ukrainians.  On the contrary.  And of course, the international community is united in making clear that if Russia commits new aggression against Ukraine, there will be very serious consequences.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You have just mentioned the information that Putin gets.  So there are some concerns and confusion even in Russia in terms of the information that you get from intelligence – the intelligence services.  And I just have to ask you:  What is the level of this intel that you get?  And about the different ways and scenarios of invasion. You know, what is the level of reliability of the sources?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  All I can tell you is this:  We’re very confident in the information that we have.  And as I said at the United Nations Security Council the other day, I recognize that in the past, sometimes we’ve come forward with information that’s turned out to be inaccurate.  We’re very confident in the information we have, and we bring it forward not to start a war, but to prevent a war – a war that’s in no one’s interests, starting with the Russian people.  That’s what we’re trying to do.  And if we can find a diplomatic way to do that, I’m determined to do that.  But if we have to respond to aggression from Russia, we’ll do that as well.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You are sure that all the scenarios were on the table, at Putin’s table?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yes, you are sure?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And the final thing, just very short:  Is there a meeting between the two presidents planned, Mr. Biden, Mr. Putin, when and where?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  President Biden is always fully prepared to meet if we think that can advance the cause of diplomacy and the cause of peace.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you very much.  I really appreciate your answers.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>G7 Foreign Ministers’ Statement on Russia and Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/g7-foreign-ministers-statement-on-russia-and-ukraine-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 18:32:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=316039</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom and the United States of America and the High Representative of the European Union, remain gravely concerned about Russia’s threatening military build-up around Ukraine, in illegally annexed Crimea and in Belarus. Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified massing of military forces, the largest deployment on the European continent since the end of the Cold War is a challenge to global security and the international order.</p>
<p>We call on Russia to choose the path of diplomacy, to de-escalate tensions, to substantively withdraw military forces from the proximity of Ukraine’s borders and to fully abide by international commitments including on risk reduction and transparency of military activities. As a first step, we expect Russia to implement the announced reduction of its military activities along Ukraine’s borders. We have seen no evidence of this reduction. We will judge Russia by its deeds.</p>
<p>We took note of Russia’s latest announcements that it is willing to engage diplomatically. We underline our commitment vis-à-vis Russia to pursue dialogue on issues of mutual concern, such as European security, risk reduction, transparency, confidence building and arms control. We also reiterate our commitment to find a peaceful and diplomatic solution to the current crisis, and we urge Russia to take up the offer of dialogue through the US-Russia Strategic Stability Dialogue, the NATO-Russia Council, and the OSCE. We commend the Renewed OSCE European Security Dialogue launched by the Polish OSCE Chairmanship-in-Office and express our strong hope that Russia will engage in a constructive way.</p>
<p>Any threat or use of force against the territorial integrity and sovereignty of states goes against the fundamental principles that underpin the rules-based international order as well as the European peace and security order enshrined in the Helsinki Final Act, the Paris Charter and other subsequent OSCE declarations. While we are ready to explore diplomatic solutions to address legitimate security concerns, Russia should be in no doubt that any further military aggression against Ukraine will have massive consequences, including financial and economic sanctions on a wide array of sectoral and individual targets that would impose severe and unprecedented costs on the Russian economy. We will take coordinated restrictive measures in case of such an event.</p>
<p>We reaffirm our solidarity with the people of Ukraine and our support to Ukraine’s efforts to strengthen its democracy and institutions, encouraging further progress on reform. We consider it of utmost importance to help preserve the economic and financial stability of Ukraine and the well-being of its people. Building on our assistance since 2014, we are committed to contribute, in close coordination with Ukraine’s authorities to support the strengthening of Ukraine’s resilience.</p>
<p>We reiterate our unwavering commitment to the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders and territorial waters. We reaffirm the right of any sovereign state to determine its own future and security arrangements. We commend Ukraine’s posture of restraint in the face of continued provocations and efforts at destabilization.</p>
<p>We underline our strong appreciation and continued support for Germany’s and France’s efforts through the Normandy Process to secure the full implementation of the Minsk Agreements, which is the only way forward for a lasting political solution to the conflict in eastern Ukraine. We acknowledge public statements by President Zelensky underlining Ukraine’s firm commitment to the Minsk Agreements and his readiness to contribute constructively to the process. Ukrainian overtures merit serious consideration by Russian negotiators and by the Government of the Russian Federation. We call on Russia to seize the opportunity which Ukraine’s proposals represent for the diplomatic path.</p>
<p>Russia must de-escalate and fulfil its commitments in implementing the Minsk Agreements. The increase in ceasefire violations along the line of contact in recent days is highly concerning. We condemn the use of heavy weaponry and indiscriminate shelling of civilian areas, which constitute a clear violation of the Minsk Agreements. We also condemn that the Russian Federation continues to hand out Russian passports to the inhabitants of the non-government controlled areas of Ukraine. This clearly runs counter to the spirit of the Minsk agreements.</p>
<p>We are particularly worried by measures taken by the self-proclaimed “People’s Republics” which must be seen as laying the ground for military escalation. We are concerned that staged incidents could be used as a pretext for possible military escalation. Russia must use its influence over the self-proclaimed republics to exercise restraint and de-escalate.</p>
<p>In this context, we firmly express our support for the OSCE’s Special Monitoring Mission, whose observers play a key role in de-escalation efforts. This mission must be allowed to carry out its full mandate without restrictions to its activities and freedom of movement to the benefit and security of the people in eastern Ukraine.</p>
<p><i>End Text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom and the United States of America and the High Representative of the European Union, remain gravely concerned about Russia’s threatening military build-up around Ukraine, in illegally annexed Crimea and in Belarus. Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified massing of military forces, the largest deployment on the European continent since the end of the Cold War is a challenge to global security and the international order.</p>
<p>We call on Russia to choose the path of diplomacy, to de-escalate tensions, to substantively withdraw military forces from the proximity of Ukraine’s borders and to fully abide by international commitments including on risk reduction and transparency of military activities. As a first step, we expect Russia to implement the announced reduction of its military activities along Ukraine’s borders. We have seen no evidence of this reduction. We will judge Russia by its deeds.</p>
<p>We took note of Russia’s latest announcements that it is willing to engage diplomatically. We underline our commitment vis-à-vis Russia to pursue dialogue on issues of mutual concern, such as European security, risk reduction, transparency, confidence building and arms control. We also reiterate our commitment to find a peaceful and diplomatic solution to the current crisis, and we urge Russia to take up the offer of dialogue through the US-Russia Strategic Stability Dialogue, the NATO-Russia Council, and the OSCE. We commend the Renewed OSCE European Security Dialogue launched by the Polish OSCE Chairmanship-in-Office and express our strong hope that Russia will engage in a constructive way.</p>
<p>Any threat or use of force against the territorial integrity and sovereignty of states goes against the fundamental principles that underpin the rules-based international order as well as the European peace and security order enshrined in the Helsinki Final Act, the Paris Charter and other subsequent OSCE declarations. While we are ready to explore diplomatic solutions to address legitimate security concerns, Russia should be in no doubt that any further military aggression against Ukraine will have massive consequences, including financial and economic sanctions on a wide array of sectoral and individual targets that would impose severe and unprecedented costs on the Russian economy. We will take coordinated restrictive measures in case of such an event.</p>
<p>We reaffirm our solidarity with the people of Ukraine and our support to Ukraine’s efforts to strengthen its democracy and institutions, encouraging further progress on reform. We consider it of utmost importance to help preserve the economic and financial stability of Ukraine and the well-being of its people. Building on our assistance since 2014, we are committed to contribute, in close coordination with Ukraine’s authorities to support the strengthening of Ukraine’s resilience.</p>
<p>We reiterate our unwavering commitment to the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders and territorial waters. We reaffirm the right of any sovereign state to determine its own future and security arrangements. We commend Ukraine’s posture of restraint in the face of continued provocations and efforts at destabilization.</p>
<p>We underline our strong appreciation and continued support for Germany’s and France’s efforts through the Normandy Process to secure the full implementation of the Minsk Agreements, which is the only way forward for a lasting political solution to the conflict in eastern Ukraine. We acknowledge public statements by President Zelensky underlining Ukraine’s firm commitment to the Minsk Agreements and his readiness to contribute constructively to the process. Ukrainian overtures merit serious consideration by Russian negotiators and by the Government of the Russian Federation. We call on Russia to seize the opportunity which Ukraine’s proposals represent for the diplomatic path.</p>
<p>Russia must de-escalate and fulfil its commitments in implementing the Minsk Agreements. The increase in ceasefire violations along the line of contact in recent days is highly concerning. We condemn the use of heavy weaponry and indiscriminate shelling of civilian areas, which constitute a clear violation of the Minsk Agreements. We also condemn that the Russian Federation continues to hand out Russian passports to the inhabitants of the non-government controlled areas of Ukraine. This clearly runs counter to the spirit of the Minsk agreements.</p>
<p>We are particularly worried by measures taken by the self-proclaimed “People’s Republics” which must be seen as laying the ground for military escalation. We are concerned that staged incidents could be used as a pretext for possible military escalation. Russia must use its influence over the self-proclaimed republics to exercise restraint and de-escalate.</p>
<p>In this context, we firmly express our support for the OSCE’s Special Monitoring Mission, whose observers play a key role in de-escalation efforts. This mission must be allowed to carry out its full mandate without restrictions to its activities and freedom of movement to the benefit and security of the people in eastern Ukraine.</p>
<p><i>End Text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Stefan Kornelius of Süddeutsche Zeitung</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-stefan-kornelius-of-suddeutsche-zeitung/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 18:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=316036</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Munich, Germany</p>
<p>Hotel Bayerischer Hof</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And you’ve pretty much said so much over the past days that I’m not sure what we else can add, but let me start with after the President last night gave that shrill warning.  What’s left to prevent war?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, I think as the President also said last night, while we’re convinced that President Putin has made his decision to go, until that – it actually happens, we will leave no stone unturned when it comes to diplomacy.  So we’ll continue to try and see if we can affect his thinking.  I think that’s very difficult, but it’s certainly my own obligation in terms of conducting our diplomacy to see if there’s still a possibility.  But I think the President was very clear.</p>
<p>And here’s the thing:  Either way, we are prepared, and that’s not an accident.  I was struck yesterday at the session with my friend and colleague Annalena Baerbock when Christoph Heusgen at the outset of our session said that in his experience he’s not seen greater coordination, collaboration, consultation between the United States and Europe in general, as well as between the United States and Germany in particular.  And that doesn’t just happen.  It’s the product of a very deliberate effort on both sides to do that, and I think in my own experience I agree with that assessment.  I have not seen this level of coordination before.</p>
<p>And that means that whether we’re proceeding with whatever diplomatic opportunities may still be left, we’re doing it in a fully coordinated way.  And if it comes to confronting Russian aggression, we’re also fully coordinated and the response will be swift, unified, and consequential.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Which stone is not unturned?  What – sort of concretely spoken their diplomatic idea now to re-engage in talk.  Foreign Minister Lavrov was very explicit in his letter two days ago.  You have answered to it.  Where do you see an opening?  What’s sort of left to talk through?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  As things stand right now, I proposed a few days ago that Foreign Minister Lavrov and I see each other again next week in Europe.  He responded a couple of days later and said yes, and I in turn responded and said good, I look forward to seeing you, provided, of course, Russia has not invaded Ukraine in the interim.  So depending on what happens in the coming days, I’ll see him.</p>
<p>We have the texts that we’ve exchanged.  They’re – I think are some very concrete ideas for discussion that we put forward that on a reciprocal basis could strengthen security for Russia, for the United States, for Europe, and so we’ll continue to see if Russia is willing to engage on those.  At the same time, in the Russian response they continue to hold to positions that are fundamentally at odds with our basic principles and that we are – that we’re committed to.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  One of the demands is to withdraw American troops from the front line.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  That’s right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Is this something you could accomplish (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So when it comes to things like shutting NATO’s open door or bringing NATO back to its pre-1997 positions, the answer is no.  When it comes to finding ways to build confidence, to reduce risks, to pursue arms control; to look at whether, when it comes to the positioning of weapon systems and forces or exercises on a reciprocal basis, there are steps that we can take that would strengthen collective security, the answer is yes.  We’re fully prepared to engage on all of those as we’ve discussed in detail with European partners and allies.</p>
<p>The question is really what is Russia actually seeking.  Is it to address in a practical way legitimate security concerns that all of us have or is it to reconstitute the Soviet empire or, short of that, to reassert a sphere of influence or, short of that, to Finlandize countries around it?  If that’s what we’re talking about, there’s not a lot to work with.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  What’s the impact of such a war, if it would happen, for the order in Europe?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, two things.  There is no doubt that a war would have terrible and devastating consequences, first and foremost for those immediately involved, innocent Ukrainians.  It would have consequences, of course, for Russia, including the very severe consequences that would be imposed by many countries.</p>
<p>But it’s also, I think, a profound challenge to the international order, because what’s at stake here is not – yes, of course, it’s Ukraine and its future, its territorial integrity, its sovereignty, its independence.  But more broadly what’s at stake are some fundamental principles that are the foundation of peace and security, principles that emerged from two world wars and a cold war, principles like one country cannot simply change the borders of another by force; that one country can’t dictate to another its choices, its policies, with whom it will associate; that one country can’t exert a sphere of influence to subjugate neighbors to its will.  Those principles are important not only in Europe, they’re important around the world.</p>
<p>And that’s why what’s happening now and the threat that Russia is posing, first and foremost to Ukraine but more broadly to those principles, should be of concern to countries around the world.  It’s why I went to the United Nations Security Council a few days ago to make it clear that that’s what’s at stake, and the Security Council, of course, is responsible for the maintenance of peace and security.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  What happens the day after it would start?  Is there sort of a game plan in &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  There is, and it’s fully coordinated among European partners, both European Union, NATO, on a bilateral basis as well.  And I think, again, we’ve been very clear that there will be a swift and united response when it comes, for example, to sanctions.  There will be a swift and united response when it comes to, depending on the exact situation, reinforcing further Ukraine’s defense.  There will be a swift and united response when it comes to reinforcing NATO and its eastern flank.</p>
<p>And one of the striking things here, Stefan, is that when you step back for a minute and try to put this in context, what President Putin has done over the last eight or nine years is to precipitate everything he says he wants to prevent.  And if you go back to 2014, before Russia went into Ukraine, into the Donbas and seized Crimea, favorability ratings for Russia in Ukraine among the Ukrainian people were very high, 70 percent.  Now it’s entirely reversed and he’s managed to alienate the overwhelming majority of Ukrainians against Russia.  Support for joining NATO before 2014 in Ukraine was probably 25 percent; now it’s 60 or 65 percent because of what President Putin did.</p>
<p>And when it comes to NATO itself, President Putin’s actions have concentrated minds and concentrated action at NATO in ways that we haven’t seen in years, including defense budgets and including the entire reinforcement of the eastern flank.  Before 2014, if you look at the evolution, the level of U.S. forces in Europe was coming down.  Armaments and equipment was also coming down after the end of the Cold War.  Everything that’s happened in terms of NATO’s reinforcement is a direct product of the aggressive actions taken by President Putin.  So this is what he says he wants to prevent; he’s precipitated it, and if he goes into Ukraine, I think it will only reinforce that.  Minds have been concentrated in Europe, across the Atlantic, and beyond in ways that they haven’t been in recent years because of Russia’s actions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  (Inaudible) final question &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You’re not extremely specific on sort of the – on their target list or what – the sanction list.  Nevertheless, it is your – is it your understanding that Nord Stream 2 will be (inaudible) closed, and will the U.S. be prepared to (inaudible) its own oil supply from Russia on that list?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, first, of course, our position on Nord Stream 2 is longstanding and well known.  And what I can say is – and I certainly don’t want to speak for anyone, but when asked about Nord Stream 2 in the context of Russian aggression, Chancellor Scholz said there would be a strong, united response.  I’ll let those words speak for themselves.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  The oil?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  And I am convinced across the board that as a result of all of the work we’ve done together – the incredibly close coordination between the United States and Germany on every aspect of this, on the diplomacy, on the response – that we will have a strong, united effort no matter what President Putin does.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Including oil supply for the U.S.?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I don’t want to get into specifics, but I can tell you that we – we will have a very strong, united response.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thanks very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Munich, Germany</p>
<p>Hotel Bayerischer Hof</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And you’ve pretty much said so much over the past days that I’m not sure what we else can add, but let me start with after the President last night gave that shrill warning.  What’s left to prevent war?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, I think as the President also said last night, while we’re convinced that President Putin has made his decision to go, until that – it actually happens, we will leave no stone unturned when it comes to diplomacy.  So we’ll continue to try and see if we can affect his thinking.  I think that’s very difficult, but it’s certainly my own obligation in terms of conducting our diplomacy to see if there’s still a possibility.  But I think the President was very clear.</p>
<p>And here’s the thing:  Either way, we are prepared, and that’s not an accident.  I was struck yesterday at the session with my friend and colleague Annalena Baerbock when Christoph Heusgen at the outset of our session said that in his experience he’s not seen greater coordination, collaboration, consultation between the United States and Europe in general, as well as between the United States and Germany in particular.  And that doesn’t just happen.  It’s the product of a very deliberate effort on both sides to do that, and I think in my own experience I agree with that assessment.  I have not seen this level of coordination before.</p>
<p>And that means that whether we’re proceeding with whatever diplomatic opportunities may still be left, we’re doing it in a fully coordinated way.  And if it comes to confronting Russian aggression, we’re also fully coordinated and the response will be swift, unified, and consequential.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Which stone is not unturned?  What – sort of concretely spoken their diplomatic idea now to re-engage in talk.  Foreign Minister Lavrov was very explicit in his letter two days ago.  You have answered to it.  Where do you see an opening?  What’s sort of left to talk through?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  As things stand right now, I proposed a few days ago that Foreign Minister Lavrov and I see each other again next week in Europe.  He responded a couple of days later and said yes, and I in turn responded and said good, I look forward to seeing you, provided, of course, Russia has not invaded Ukraine in the interim.  So depending on what happens in the coming days, I’ll see him.</p>
<p>We have the texts that we’ve exchanged.  They’re – I think are some very concrete ideas for discussion that we put forward that on a reciprocal basis could strengthen security for Russia, for the United States, for Europe, and so we’ll continue to see if Russia is willing to engage on those.  At the same time, in the Russian response they continue to hold to positions that are fundamentally at odds with our basic principles and that we are – that we’re committed to.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  One of the demands is to withdraw American troops from the front line.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  That’s right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Is this something you could accomplish (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So when it comes to things like shutting NATO’s open door or bringing NATO back to its pre-1997 positions, the answer is no.  When it comes to finding ways to build confidence, to reduce risks, to pursue arms control; to look at whether, when it comes to the positioning of weapon systems and forces or exercises on a reciprocal basis, there are steps that we can take that would strengthen collective security, the answer is yes.  We’re fully prepared to engage on all of those as we’ve discussed in detail with European partners and allies.</p>
<p>The question is really what is Russia actually seeking.  Is it to address in a practical way legitimate security concerns that all of us have or is it to reconstitute the Soviet empire or, short of that, to reassert a sphere of influence or, short of that, to Finlandize countries around it?  If that’s what we’re talking about, there’s not a lot to work with.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  What’s the impact of such a war, if it would happen, for the order in Europe?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, two things.  There is no doubt that a war would have terrible and devastating consequences, first and foremost for those immediately involved, innocent Ukrainians.  It would have consequences, of course, for Russia, including the very severe consequences that would be imposed by many countries.</p>
<p>But it’s also, I think, a profound challenge to the international order, because what’s at stake here is not – yes, of course, it’s Ukraine and its future, its territorial integrity, its sovereignty, its independence.  But more broadly what’s at stake are some fundamental principles that are the foundation of peace and security, principles that emerged from two world wars and a cold war, principles like one country cannot simply change the borders of another by force; that one country can’t dictate to another its choices, its policies, with whom it will associate; that one country can’t exert a sphere of influence to subjugate neighbors to its will.  Those principles are important not only in Europe, they’re important around the world.</p>
<p>And that’s why what’s happening now and the threat that Russia is posing, first and foremost to Ukraine but more broadly to those principles, should be of concern to countries around the world.  It’s why I went to the United Nations Security Council a few days ago to make it clear that that’s what’s at stake, and the Security Council, of course, is responsible for the maintenance of peace and security.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  What happens the day after it would start?  Is there sort of a game plan in &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  There is, and it’s fully coordinated among European partners, both European Union, NATO, on a bilateral basis as well.  And I think, again, we’ve been very clear that there will be a swift and united response when it comes, for example, to sanctions.  There will be a swift and united response when it comes to, depending on the exact situation, reinforcing further Ukraine’s defense.  There will be a swift and united response when it comes to reinforcing NATO and its eastern flank.</p>
<p>And one of the striking things here, Stefan, is that when you step back for a minute and try to put this in context, what President Putin has done over the last eight or nine years is to precipitate everything he says he wants to prevent.  And if you go back to 2014, before Russia went into Ukraine, into the Donbas and seized Crimea, favorability ratings for Russia in Ukraine among the Ukrainian people were very high, 70 percent.  Now it’s entirely reversed and he’s managed to alienate the overwhelming majority of Ukrainians against Russia.  Support for joining NATO before 2014 in Ukraine was probably 25 percent; now it’s 60 or 65 percent because of what President Putin did.</p>
<p>And when it comes to NATO itself, President Putin’s actions have concentrated minds and concentrated action at NATO in ways that we haven’t seen in years, including defense budgets and including the entire reinforcement of the eastern flank.  Before 2014, if you look at the evolution, the level of U.S. forces in Europe was coming down.  Armaments and equipment was also coming down after the end of the Cold War.  Everything that’s happened in terms of NATO’s reinforcement is a direct product of the aggressive actions taken by President Putin.  So this is what he says he wants to prevent; he’s precipitated it, and if he goes into Ukraine, I think it will only reinforce that.  Minds have been concentrated in Europe, across the Atlantic, and beyond in ways that they haven’t been in recent years because of Russia’s actions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  (Inaudible) final question &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You’re not extremely specific on sort of the – on their target list or what – the sanction list.  Nevertheless, it is your – is it your understanding that Nord Stream 2 will be (inaudible) closed, and will the U.S. be prepared to (inaudible) its own oil supply from Russia on that list?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, first, of course, our position on Nord Stream 2 is longstanding and well known.  And what I can say is – and I certainly don’t want to speak for anyone, but when asked about Nord Stream 2 in the context of Russian aggression, Chancellor Scholz said there would be a strong, united response.  I’ll let those words speak for themselves.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  The oil?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  And I am convinced across the board that as a result of all of the work we’ve done together – the incredibly close coordination between the United States and Germany on every aspect of this, on the diplomacy, on the response – that we will have a strong, united effort no matter what President Putin does.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Including oil supply for the U.S.?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I don’t want to get into specifics, but I can tell you that we – we will have a very strong, united response.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thanks very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Trilateral Meeting with Australian Foreign Minister Payne and UK Foreign Secretary Truss on AUKUS</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-trilateral-meeting-with-australian-foreign-minister-payne-and-uk-foreign-secretary-truss-on-aukus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 16:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=316026</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken, Australian Foreign Minister Marise Payne, and UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss held a trilateral meeting today on the margins of the Munich Security Conference.  In particular, they discussed progress made in implementing initiatives within the AUKUS trilateral security partnership, which is focused on sustaining peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken, Foreign Minister Payne, and Foreign Secretary Truss discussed the importance of ensuring the first AUKUS initiative – Australia’s acquisition of conventionally armed, nuclear-powered submarines for the Royal Australian Navy – be done in a manner that sets a strong nonproliferation example.  They also noted our collective desire to deepen collaboration on additional advanced military and technology capabilities.  Secretary Blinken underscored the importance of working with our allies and partners to advance a free and open, connected, prosperous, secure, and resilient Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken, Australian Foreign Minister Marise Payne, and UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss held a trilateral meeting today on the margins of the Munich Security Conference.  In particular, they discussed progress made in implementing initiatives within the AUKUS trilateral security partnership, which is focused on sustaining peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken, Foreign Minister Payne, and Foreign Secretary Truss discussed the importance of ensuring the first AUKUS initiative – Australia’s acquisition of conventionally armed, nuclear-powered submarines for the Royal Australian Navy – be done in a manner that sets a strong nonproliferation example.  They also noted our collective desire to deepen collaboration on additional advanced military and technology capabilities.  Secretary Blinken underscored the importance of working with our allies and partners to advance a free and open, connected, prosperous, secure, and resilient Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with French Foreign Minister Le Drian</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-french-foreign-minister-le-drian-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 12:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=315998</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian today on the sidelines of the Munich Security Conference to discuss ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts by NATO Allies, EU partners, G7 members, and other partners in response to the crisis Russia has needlessly precipitated. They reaffirmed their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, as well as the readiness of Allies and partners to impose severe consequences on Russia should it pursue further aggression against Ukraine. The Secretary welcomed France’s leadership role during the French Presidency of the Council of the European Union and its contributions to strengthening the U.S.-EU partnership. The two discussed the latest developments in the Sahel region of Africa, including the need for continued cooperation on counterterrorism and regional security. They also reviewed the status of efforts to seek a mutual return to compliance with the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action as well as developments in Lebanon.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian today on the sidelines of the Munich Security Conference to discuss ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts by NATO Allies, EU partners, G7 members, and other partners in response to the crisis Russia has needlessly precipitated. They reaffirmed their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, as well as the readiness of Allies and partners to impose severe consequences on Russia should it pursue further aggression against Ukraine. The Secretary welcomed France’s leadership role during the French Presidency of the Council of the European Union and its contributions to strengthening the U.S.-EU partnership. The two discussed the latest developments in the Sahel region of Africa, including the need for continued cooperation on counterterrorism and regional security. They also reviewed the status of efforts to seek a mutual return to compliance with the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action as well as developments in Lebanon.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
