<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 19:07:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Israeli Alternate Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Yair Lapid </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-israeli-alternate-prime-minister-and-foreign-minister-yair-lapid/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 19:02:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Israeli Alternate Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Yair Lapid in Rome.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister discussed support for stability in the region, building on regional normalization efforts, and the need to improve Israeli-Palestinian relations. Secretary Blinken and Foreign <wbr />Minister Lapid emphasized the strong partnership between the United States and Israel and America’s unwavering support for Israel’s security.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p align="center">
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Israeli Alternate Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Yair Lapid in Rome.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister discussed support for stability in the region, building on regional normalization efforts, and the need to improve Israeli-Palestinian relations. Secretary Blinken and Foreign <wbr />Minister Lapid emphasized the strong partnership between the United States and Israel and America’s unwavering support for Israel’s security.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p align="center">
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken  And Israeli Foreign Minister Yair Lapid  Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-israeli-foreign-minister-yair-lapid-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 17:37:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rome, Italy</p>
<p>Westin Excelsior</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LAPID:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hello, everybody.  Secretary Blinken and I represent new administrations, yours a few months old, ours a few weeks old, and two days.  But we also represent a very long and strong tradition of close friendship and cooperation.  There is no relationship more important to Israel than the United States of America.  There is no loyal friend of the United States of America than Israel.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the past few years, mistakes were made.  Israel’s bipartisan standing was hurt.  We will fix those mistakes together.  In the past few days I spoke with a series of American leaders, both Democrats and Republicans.  I reminded them all that we share America’s most basic values – freedom, democracy, free markets, the constant search for peace.  In the struggle for those values, Secretary Blinken is a great partner and a great friend.  Like me, he grew up in the home of a Holocaust survivor who always said that the world has a responsibility to ensure Israel’s peace and security.  Mr. Secretary, I know we can count on you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We will have disagreements, but they are not about the essence, they’re all about how to get there.  We want the same things.  We sometimes disagree about how to achieve them.  Israel has some serious reservations about the Iran nuclear deal that is being put together in Vienna.  We believe the way to discuss those disagreements is through direct and professional conversation, not in press conferences.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mr. Secretary, this is also the time to thank the United States for its support of Israel’s normalization efforts in the region.  In a couple of days, I will make the first trip, official trip by an Israeli minister to the United Arab Emirates.  That visit will be historic and I hope it will be the first of many.  I look forward to working with you to widen the circle of peace in our region.  That is the best way to bring stability and prosperity to the Middle East.  We will discuss a range of issues which concerns Israel, including strengthening our ability to defend ourselves, working to minimize conflict between us and the Palestinians, while making life better for Israelis and Palestinians alike.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before I finish, I’d like to take this opportunity, and I know, Mr. Secretary, that you will join me, to send our prayers to all those affected by the collapse of the building in Miami.  Our deepest condolences to the family of those killed in this terrible, terrible tragedy. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thank you very much.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, Foreign Minister Yair, thank you.  We had an opportunity to meet actually before the change of government, when I was in Israel a few weeks ago.  We’ve been on the phone a number of times since.  But I’m very glad, first of all, to see you and to see you in these new functions.  And you’re right, we’re both relatively new to the job.  I suspect you’ll find – you’ve already found quickly – that the inbox fills up very fast.  But I’m grateful for the opportunity to work with you, to work with your team.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And the foreign minister is exactly right:  Even though our administration is relatively new and his is extremely new, the foundation that we’re working on is one of an enduring partnership, relationship, friendship between the United States and Israel, and it is based, as the foreign minister said, on a set of shared values and shared interests.  And I very much look forward to working closely with you, with your team, across a whole series of issues. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We have a number of things that the foreign minister has already noted that will be on our agenda.  We have, of course, the situation in Gaza where there’s an urgent need both for humanitarian assistance and, more broadly, reconstruction.  I know we’ll talk about that.  The work, I hope, can be done to, as you say, offer a more hopeful future for everyone – Palestinians and Israelis alike – with equal measures of opportunity and dignity.  It is very important from our perspective.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You rightly noted our strong support for the normalization agreements, the Abraham Accords with Israel’s neighbors and beyond.  We strongly support this and hopefully there’ll be other participants.  I think we’ve also discovered or perhaps rediscovered that as important as they are, as vital as they are, they are not a substitute for engaging on the issues between Israelis and Palestinians that need to be resolved.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beyond that, we have many, many things to talk about when it comes to the region and beyond, including Iran.  I very much look forward to that. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But let me finish where we both started, and you said it extremely well:  We’re – as the closest of friends do, we will have occasional differences.  We have the same objectives; sometimes we differ on the tactics.  And we, I think, are very clear and direct with each other when that’s the case.  And that’s exactly the way it’s supposed to be.  But the foundation is a commitment, a deep, enduring, abiding commitment on the part of the United States to Israel’s security and a commitment that President Biden brought with him to office and feels very, very strongly about. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So thank you for being here, for taking the time to get here.  It’s great to see you face to face, and we can get down to work.  Thank you.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rome, Italy</p>
<p>Westin Excelsior</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LAPID:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hello, everybody.  Secretary Blinken and I represent new administrations, yours a few months old, ours a few weeks old, and two days.  But we also represent a very long and strong tradition of close friendship and cooperation.  There is no relationship more important to Israel than the United States of America.  There is no loyal friend of the United States of America than Israel.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the past few years, mistakes were made.  Israel’s bipartisan standing was hurt.  We will fix those mistakes together.  In the past few days I spoke with a series of American leaders, both Democrats and Republicans.  I reminded them all that we share America’s most basic values – freedom, democracy, free markets, the constant search for peace.  In the struggle for those values, Secretary Blinken is a great partner and a great friend.  Like me, he grew up in the home of a Holocaust survivor who always said that the world has a responsibility to ensure Israel’s peace and security.  Mr. Secretary, I know we can count on you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We will have disagreements, but they are not about the essence, they’re all about how to get there.  We want the same things.  We sometimes disagree about how to achieve them.  Israel has some serious reservations about the Iran nuclear deal that is being put together in Vienna.  We believe the way to discuss those disagreements is through direct and professional conversation, not in press conferences.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mr. Secretary, this is also the time to thank the United States for its support of Israel’s normalization efforts in the region.  In a couple of days, I will make the first trip, official trip by an Israeli minister to the United Arab Emirates.  That visit will be historic and I hope it will be the first of many.  I look forward to working with you to widen the circle of peace in our region.  That is the best way to bring stability and prosperity to the Middle East.  We will discuss a range of issues which concerns Israel, including strengthening our ability to defend ourselves, working to minimize conflict between us and the Palestinians, while making life better for Israelis and Palestinians alike.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before I finish, I’d like to take this opportunity, and I know, Mr. Secretary, that you will join me, to send our prayers to all those affected by the collapse of the building in Miami.  Our deepest condolences to the family of those killed in this terrible, terrible tragedy. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thank you very much.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, Foreign Minister Yair, thank you.  We had an opportunity to meet actually before the change of government, when I was in Israel a few weeks ago.  We’ve been on the phone a number of times since.  But I’m very glad, first of all, to see you and to see you in these new functions.  And you’re right, we’re both relatively new to the job.  I suspect you’ll find – you’ve already found quickly – that the inbox fills up very fast.  But I’m grateful for the opportunity to work with you, to work with your team.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And the foreign minister is exactly right:  Even though our administration is relatively new and his is extremely new, the foundation that we’re working on is one of an enduring partnership, relationship, friendship between the United States and Israel, and it is based, as the foreign minister said, on a set of shared values and shared interests.  And I very much look forward to working closely with you, with your team, across a whole series of issues. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We have a number of things that the foreign minister has already noted that will be on our agenda.  We have, of course, the situation in Gaza where there’s an urgent need both for humanitarian assistance and, more broadly, reconstruction.  I know we’ll talk about that.  The work, I hope, can be done to, as you say, offer a more hopeful future for everyone – Palestinians and Israelis alike – with equal measures of opportunity and dignity.  It is very important from our perspective.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You rightly noted our strong support for the normalization agreements, the Abraham Accords with Israel’s neighbors and beyond.  We strongly support this and hopefully there’ll be other participants.  I think we’ve also discovered or perhaps rediscovered that as important as they are, as vital as they are, they are not a substitute for engaging on the issues between Israelis and Palestinians that need to be resolved.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beyond that, we have many, many things to talk about when it comes to the region and beyond, including Iran.  I very much look forward to that. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But let me finish where we both started, and you said it extremely well:  We’re – as the closest of friends do, we will have occasional differences.  We have the same objectives; sometimes we differ on the tactics.  And we, I think, are very clear and direct with each other when that’s the case.  And that’s exactly the way it’s supposed to be.  But the foundation is a commitment, a deep, enduring, abiding commitment on the part of the United States to Israel’s security and a commitment that President Biden brought with him to office and feels very, very strongly about. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So thank you for being here, for taking the time to get here.  It’s great to see you face to face, and we can get down to work.  Thank you.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet and Greet with U.S. Tri-Mission Italy</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/meet-and-greet-with-u-s-tri-mission-italy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 17:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255544</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rome, Italy </p>
<p>Villa Taverna</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">MR SMITHAM:  (In progress) to the team.  Is that okay?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">More seriously, let me just, on behalf of the Tri-Mission and my colleagues Jenny and Patrick, welcome you, Mr. Secretary, to Rome.  A lot of what we do in diplomacy is build relationships, so let me just make a couple of introductions.  Mr. Secretary, this is your Tri-Mission Italy team.  It’s been a fantastic team that works every day to promote our interests and our joint interests with our partners here in Italy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve got to highlight that over the past 16 months, this has been more of a struggle than it had been before.  It’s hard to imagine on a beautiful sunny afternoon like this in Rome, what we’ve been going through for the past 16 months.  But on February 23rd we got a call about COVID, weren’t sure exactly what it was.  It was in the north of the country and we had to really react quickly to make sure that this community stayed safe and secure.  And this is the team that kept our community safe and secure throughout the many months when you couldn’t leave your house, couldn’t leave your neighborhood, then couldn’t leave your region, and now Italy is a bit open, or more open, and so we’re able to get out and about.  This is the team that built resilience among our community.  Our CLO has been fantastic in doing that as well as our medical staff and the rest of our management team.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Team, this is Secretary Blinken.  I don’t think he needs much of an introduction as he’s had a distinguished career in public service and in the private sector for the past 30 years.  But let me just highlight a couple of things.  We just had a very substantive meeting with the foreign minister of Italy and I understand with some UN officials as well.  But let me just highlight something else.  We’ve talked a little bit about COVID here, and I want to let you know that because of the Secretary and because of his tireless advocacy in Washington, he’s been making sure that we have the tools to keep our community safe and secure.  And the vaccines arrived here a couple of months ago due to the pressure that the Secretary and his team placed on other officials in Washington to make sure that our diplomatic communities around the world had access to the same vaccines that our team back in Washington had access to.  And I think for that, Mr. Secretary, we all owe you a big thanks and want to congratulate you and your team for bringing that about for our entire Foreign Service and broader diplomatic community.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Without further ado, let me introduce Antony Blinken, the 71st Secretary of State of the United States of America.  Mr. Blinken.  (Applause.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Well, thank you all very, very much, and Tom, thank you not just for your very kind words but thank you for your remarkable leadership here, and Jenny and Patrick, to both of you as well.  I can’t tell you how much I appreciate it, we appreciate it, the President appreciates it.  And I have to say, by the way, I’ve had an opportunity now getting out and about a little bit to talk to the teams at our missions in a number of places around the world.  I think you’re winning the prize for best setting today, so thank you.  (Laughter.)  And it’s really great to see everyone here.  As I’ve been saying, we’ve been – we were distant for a long time.  It’s been – it still is a little bit mask to mask; we’re getting to face to face.  But we’re getting there.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And I have to say, picking up where Tom left off, I know how challenging this last year and a half has been on a personal level for so many of you as well, of course, as on a professional level.  On a personal level, I know that there are a number of you here who have been directly affected by COVID, who’ve had a loss, family, friend, and that in and of itself is a profoundly life-changing thing.  But then to carry on the mission in the midst of that, and not only carry it on but do it so well and to come together as a community, I can’t tell you how grateful I am and we are for that.  Because being able to do the job in the midst of COVID – hats off for that.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Italy in particular, as Tom noted, was hit hard by multiple waves.  I think the fact that you were able to keep going and do it so well speaks volumes.  And yeah, we did have a challenge at the department.  When I was talking to our colleagues in the previous administration, there was – as we were doing the transition, there was the hope that the department would get 300,000 vaccines last December.  We got 13,000.  So we’ve been playing catchup ever since, and one of the things that I am very pleased with is the fact that thanks to a remarkable team back in Washington, but also extraordinary medical units, including here, we’ve been able to do that.  And by the way, as we were finally getting vaccines in, we were pushing 85 percent of what we got out to our missions in the field.  That was the number one priority.  And my number one priority as Secretary of State is to do what I can to look out for your safety, for your health, and for your wellbeing because you’re putting yourselves on the line for our country every single day, and that’s the least that we owe you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let me say, too, more broadly, I can’t think of a more important time for you to be doing what you’re doing on behalf of our country.  And it really comes down to this, and COVID is a great example but there are many, many more.  Virtually all of the big issues that we have to contend with that are actually having an impact on the lives of our fellow citizens back home as well as people around the world – whether it’s COVID, whether it’s climate, whether it’s the disruptive impact of all these new technologies that are shaping our lives – we know that not a single one can be effectively dealt with by any one country acting alone, even the United States with all of our resources and power.  There is a greater premium than ever before, at least in the time I’ve been working on this, to cooperate, to find ways to work with other countries through international institutions, if we’re going to get the job done.  And the hard reality is there is no wall high enough or strong enough to keep these problems at bay.  We have to find ways to cooperate, and that’s exactly where all of you come in.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every single day, you are on the front lines of building, strengthening, making even better our cooperation with one of our most critical partners and friends, Italy.  And we’re seeing the results of that every single day.  Just in what we’re doing here on these couple of days, between the bilateral work that we’re doing and, as Tom said, we had a terrific lunch with Foreign Minister Di Maio where we covered a lot of ground.  I’m really glad that there were multiple courses because we had so much to cover that if we had gotten – just had two courses, we never would have gotten through the agenda.  So I’m a little worried about dinner, but that’s another matter.  (Laughter.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And then you see the work that Italy is doing, its own leadership, with our support, bringing together the counter-ISIS coalition here, its leadership of the G20, work on Syria, on so many other things.  This is a demonstration in practice of this cooperation actually producing results, because ultimately that’s what it’s all about.  We have to demonstrate through this work that we’re doing, the work that you’re doing, that our country, our democracy can deliver real results for our people and hopefully for people around the world.  And it does not happen without you.  So I really mostly wanted this opportunity to say thank you for everything you’re doing to help lead our diplomacy and to demonstrate that we can actually produce results. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are a lot of people I actually want to give a quick shout-out to because so many of you have really stepped up, but there are a few that, besides Tom for his incredible leadership during this pandemic, I want to give a shout-out to a few folks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The management section at Tri-Mission, especially management officer Ken Meyer, who I think – is he here?  Is Ken here somewhere?  Let’s see.  Well, if he’s not here, I just want to say thank you for leading the COVID Tri-Mission Task Force.  Again, the work that was done here to try to deal with, contend with, and manage COVID is remarkable.  The mission health unit – I mentioned this a minute ago, and I don’t know if Rosa Tavano is here.  But to Rosa, to the entire team there, the work that you did to care for everyone – to care for the staff, to keep people informed, to oversee a very successful vaccination campaign – thank you, thank you, thank you.  And there goes my other thing.  Thank you. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Community liaison office, Janene LeMay – I don’t know if you’re here – Eric Oakley, Linda Modinger.  Keeping spirits up, a very important thing to do during COVID – I understand there were virtual happy hours.  I may not report that back to Washington, but I still think that’s a very good thing.  Wine tastings – virtual, but still very effective – tours, et cetera.  All of this, I say it a little bit in gest, but not, because keeping the mission together and focused, keeping morale high at this incredibly difficult time, that in and of itself was a critical mission and I’m grateful to the people who took that on.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So we’re now at a point where, as you know, Italy recently lifted most of its commercial restrictions.  More things are going forward in the weeks ahead.  U.S. tourists are coming back on COVID-tested flights.  To my knowledge, there hasn’t been a single – I shouldn’t even say this, but has not been a COVID case in the Tri-Mission in a number of weeks.  And I think today, hopefully, this is a little bit of a taste of what the very near future is going to look like.  And I know we are all incredibly anxious to get back to a semblance of life as we knew it, but we’re getting there.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finally, a few things I want to mention as well.  Six of you have 40 years of service or more to this mission, and that is in and of itself an extraordinary thing.  But I think – let me see, is our minister counselor for public affairs Beth Poisson here?  Beth, are you here anywhere?  Well, 40 years of service – extraordinary.  Special consular services assistant Domenico Taliani, 40 years of service.  Cultural affairs specialist Marzia Benini, supervisory financial assistant Maurizio Cicerchia – excuse me if I have the pronunciation wrong – motor vehicle services technician Stefano D’Amadio, administrative clerk Paolo Zuccheri.  It’s hard to put into words how much your work, your collaboration, your partnership has meant, and 40 years is truly extraordinary.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I especially want to say to those of you who are part of the locally employed staff, thank you, thank you, thank you.  I say this everywhere I go.  I mean it profoundly.  The locally employed staff are the lifeblood of our missions around the world.  No one does more for the connectivity between our missions and the country that we’re serving in than this team.  And to those of you who are locally employed staff, I am truly grateful.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But to everyone here, whether you work for the State Department, whether you work for I think more than 10 agencies represented at this mission, whether you are a direct hire, whether you’re locally employed staff, whether you’re one of the 33,000 servicemembers or a family member of anyone working here, for each and every one of you, your contribution is invaluable.  And each and every one of you is, in the truest sense of the term, a representative of our country, of the United States and for the partnership and relationship between the United States and Italy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our countries are celebrating 160 years of diplomatic relations.  It is genuinely one of the most important relationships we have.  But again, it ultimately comes down to you, to the work that you’re doing every day.  And so in this remarkably beautiful setting, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">grazie</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rome, Italy </p>
<p>Villa Taverna</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">MR SMITHAM:  (In progress) to the team.  Is that okay?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">More seriously, let me just, on behalf of the Tri-Mission and my colleagues Jenny and Patrick, welcome you, Mr. Secretary, to Rome.  A lot of what we do in diplomacy is build relationships, so let me just make a couple of introductions.  Mr. Secretary, this is your Tri-Mission Italy team.  It’s been a fantastic team that works every day to promote our interests and our joint interests with our partners here in Italy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve got to highlight that over the past 16 months, this has been more of a struggle than it had been before.  It’s hard to imagine on a beautiful sunny afternoon like this in Rome, what we’ve been going through for the past 16 months.  But on February 23rd we got a call about COVID, weren’t sure exactly what it was.  It was in the north of the country and we had to really react quickly to make sure that this community stayed safe and secure.  And this is the team that kept our community safe and secure throughout the many months when you couldn’t leave your house, couldn’t leave your neighborhood, then couldn’t leave your region, and now Italy is a bit open, or more open, and so we’re able to get out and about.  This is the team that built resilience among our community.  Our CLO has been fantastic in doing that as well as our medical staff and the rest of our management team.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Team, this is Secretary Blinken.  I don’t think he needs much of an introduction as he’s had a distinguished career in public service and in the private sector for the past 30 years.  But let me just highlight a couple of things.  We just had a very substantive meeting with the foreign minister of Italy and I understand with some UN officials as well.  But let me just highlight something else.  We’ve talked a little bit about COVID here, and I want to let you know that because of the Secretary and because of his tireless advocacy in Washington, he’s been making sure that we have the tools to keep our community safe and secure.  And the vaccines arrived here a couple of months ago due to the pressure that the Secretary and his team placed on other officials in Washington to make sure that our diplomatic communities around the world had access to the same vaccines that our team back in Washington had access to.  And I think for that, Mr. Secretary, we all owe you a big thanks and want to congratulate you and your team for bringing that about for our entire Foreign Service and broader diplomatic community.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Without further ado, let me introduce Antony Blinken, the 71st Secretary of State of the United States of America.  Mr. Blinken.  (Applause.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SECRETARY BLINKEN:  Well, thank you all very, very much, and Tom, thank you not just for your very kind words but thank you for your remarkable leadership here, and Jenny and Patrick, to both of you as well.  I can’t tell you how much I appreciate it, we appreciate it, the President appreciates it.  And I have to say, by the way, I’ve had an opportunity now getting out and about a little bit to talk to the teams at our missions in a number of places around the world.  I think you’re winning the prize for best setting today, so thank you.  (Laughter.)  And it’s really great to see everyone here.  As I’ve been saying, we’ve been – we were distant for a long time.  It’s been – it still is a little bit mask to mask; we’re getting to face to face.  But we’re getting there.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And I have to say, picking up where Tom left off, I know how challenging this last year and a half has been on a personal level for so many of you as well, of course, as on a professional level.  On a personal level, I know that there are a number of you here who have been directly affected by COVID, who’ve had a loss, family, friend, and that in and of itself is a profoundly life-changing thing.  But then to carry on the mission in the midst of that, and not only carry it on but do it so well and to come together as a community, I can’t tell you how grateful I am and we are for that.  Because being able to do the job in the midst of COVID – hats off for that.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Italy in particular, as Tom noted, was hit hard by multiple waves.  I think the fact that you were able to keep going and do it so well speaks volumes.  And yeah, we did have a challenge at the department.  When I was talking to our colleagues in the previous administration, there was – as we were doing the transition, there was the hope that the department would get 300,000 vaccines last December.  We got 13,000.  So we’ve been playing catchup ever since, and one of the things that I am very pleased with is the fact that thanks to a remarkable team back in Washington, but also extraordinary medical units, including here, we’ve been able to do that.  And by the way, as we were finally getting vaccines in, we were pushing 85 percent of what we got out to our missions in the field.  That was the number one priority.  And my number one priority as Secretary of State is to do what I can to look out for your safety, for your health, and for your wellbeing because you’re putting yourselves on the line for our country every single day, and that’s the least that we owe you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let me say, too, more broadly, I can’t think of a more important time for you to be doing what you’re doing on behalf of our country.  And it really comes down to this, and COVID is a great example but there are many, many more.  Virtually all of the big issues that we have to contend with that are actually having an impact on the lives of our fellow citizens back home as well as people around the world – whether it’s COVID, whether it’s climate, whether it’s the disruptive impact of all these new technologies that are shaping our lives – we know that not a single one can be effectively dealt with by any one country acting alone, even the United States with all of our resources and power.  There is a greater premium than ever before, at least in the time I’ve been working on this, to cooperate, to find ways to work with other countries through international institutions, if we’re going to get the job done.  And the hard reality is there is no wall high enough or strong enough to keep these problems at bay.  We have to find ways to cooperate, and that’s exactly where all of you come in.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every single day, you are on the front lines of building, strengthening, making even better our cooperation with one of our most critical partners and friends, Italy.  And we’re seeing the results of that every single day.  Just in what we’re doing here on these couple of days, between the bilateral work that we’re doing and, as Tom said, we had a terrific lunch with Foreign Minister Di Maio where we covered a lot of ground.  I’m really glad that there were multiple courses because we had so much to cover that if we had gotten – just had two courses, we never would have gotten through the agenda.  So I’m a little worried about dinner, but that’s another matter.  (Laughter.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And then you see the work that Italy is doing, its own leadership, with our support, bringing together the counter-ISIS coalition here, its leadership of the G20, work on Syria, on so many other things.  This is a demonstration in practice of this cooperation actually producing results, because ultimately that’s what it’s all about.  We have to demonstrate through this work that we’re doing, the work that you’re doing, that our country, our democracy can deliver real results for our people and hopefully for people around the world.  And it does not happen without you.  So I really mostly wanted this opportunity to say thank you for everything you’re doing to help lead our diplomacy and to demonstrate that we can actually produce results. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are a lot of people I actually want to give a quick shout-out to because so many of you have really stepped up, but there are a few that, besides Tom for his incredible leadership during this pandemic, I want to give a shout-out to a few folks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The management section at Tri-Mission, especially management officer Ken Meyer, who I think – is he here?  Is Ken here somewhere?  Let’s see.  Well, if he’s not here, I just want to say thank you for leading the COVID Tri-Mission Task Force.  Again, the work that was done here to try to deal with, contend with, and manage COVID is remarkable.  The mission health unit – I mentioned this a minute ago, and I don’t know if Rosa Tavano is here.  But to Rosa, to the entire team there, the work that you did to care for everyone – to care for the staff, to keep people informed, to oversee a very successful vaccination campaign – thank you, thank you, thank you.  And there goes my other thing.  Thank you. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Community liaison office, Janene LeMay – I don’t know if you’re here – Eric Oakley, Linda Modinger.  Keeping spirits up, a very important thing to do during COVID – I understand there were virtual happy hours.  I may not report that back to Washington, but I still think that’s a very good thing.  Wine tastings – virtual, but still very effective – tours, et cetera.  All of this, I say it a little bit in gest, but not, because keeping the mission together and focused, keeping morale high at this incredibly difficult time, that in and of itself was a critical mission and I’m grateful to the people who took that on.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So we’re now at a point where, as you know, Italy recently lifted most of its commercial restrictions.  More things are going forward in the weeks ahead.  U.S. tourists are coming back on COVID-tested flights.  To my knowledge, there hasn’t been a single – I shouldn’t even say this, but has not been a COVID case in the Tri-Mission in a number of weeks.  And I think today, hopefully, this is a little bit of a taste of what the very near future is going to look like.  And I know we are all incredibly anxious to get back to a semblance of life as we knew it, but we’re getting there.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finally, a few things I want to mention as well.  Six of you have 40 years of service or more to this mission, and that is in and of itself an extraordinary thing.  But I think – let me see, is our minister counselor for public affairs Beth Poisson here?  Beth, are you here anywhere?  Well, 40 years of service – extraordinary.  Special consular services assistant Domenico Taliani, 40 years of service.  Cultural affairs specialist Marzia Benini, supervisory financial assistant Maurizio Cicerchia – excuse me if I have the pronunciation wrong – motor vehicle services technician Stefano D’Amadio, administrative clerk Paolo Zuccheri.  It’s hard to put into words how much your work, your collaboration, your partnership has meant, and 40 years is truly extraordinary.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I especially want to say to those of you who are part of the locally employed staff, thank you, thank you, thank you.  I say this everywhere I go.  I mean it profoundly.  The locally employed staff are the lifeblood of our missions around the world.  No one does more for the connectivity between our missions and the country that we’re serving in than this team.  And to those of you who are locally employed staff, I am truly grateful.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But to everyone here, whether you work for the State Department, whether you work for I think more than 10 agencies represented at this mission, whether you are a direct hire, whether you’re locally employed staff, whether you’re one of the 33,000 servicemembers or a family member of anyone working here, for each and every one of you, your contribution is invaluable.  And each and every one of you is, in the truest sense of the term, a representative of our country, of the United States and for the partnership and relationship between the United States and Italy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our countries are celebrating 160 years of diplomatic relations.  It is genuinely one of the most important relationships we have.  But again, it ultimately comes down to you, to the work that you’re doing every day.  And so in this remarkably beautiful setting, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">grazie</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Rome-Based Food Security Agencies </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-rome-based-food-security-agencies/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 15:39:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255539</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price: </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with the heads of the Rome-Based Food Security Agencies today in Rome, including UN World Food Program (WFP) Executive Director David Beasley and UN Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) Director-General Qu Dongyu. Secretary Blinken affirmed the importance of combating global hunger as well as addressing the main drivers of hunger.  They discussed collaboration on the COVID-19 response, the climate crisis, the humanitarian emergency in Tigray, and the upcoming UN Food Systems Summit. </span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price: </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with the heads of the Rome-Based Food Security Agencies today in Rome, including UN World Food Program (WFP) Executive Director David Beasley and UN Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) Director-General Qu Dongyu. Secretary Blinken affirmed the importance of combating global hunger as well as addressing the main drivers of hunger.  They discussed collaboration on the COVID-19 response, the climate crisis, the humanitarian emergency in Tigray, and the upcoming UN Food Systems Summit. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Sudanese PM Abdalla Hamdok </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-sudanese-pm-abdalla-hamdok/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 13:38:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255530</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:‎ </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secretary Antony J. Blinken spoke with Sudanese Prime Minister Hamdok today to discuss progress in achieving peace and implementing political, security, and economic reform.  They also discussed regional stability, implementing Sudan’s peace agreements, and Sudan’s commitment to normalizing relations with Israel.  The Secretary reaffirmed U.S. support for Prime Minister Hamdok and the Civilian-led Transitional Government, and they discussed the Prime Minister’s new initiative to enhance national unity and implement steps to create a legislative council, reform the Sudanese Armed Forces and integrate other forces into it as a professional army, and provide justice and accountability.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:‎ </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secretary Antony J. Blinken spoke with Sudanese Prime Minister Hamdok today to discuss progress in achieving peace and implementing political, security, and economic reform.  They also discussed regional stability, implementing Sudan’s peace agreements, and Sudan’s commitment to normalizing relations with Israel.  The Secretary reaffirmed U.S. support for Prime Minister Hamdok and the Civilian-led Transitional Government, and they discussed the Prime Minister’s new initiative to enhance national unity and implement steps to create a legislative council, reform the Sudanese Armed Forces and integrate other forces into it as a professional army, and provide justice and accountability.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States and the Holy See:  Partners in Addressing Climate Change and Promoting Human Rights </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-and-the-holy-see-partners-in-addressing-climate-change-and-promoting-human-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 12:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255523</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secretary Antony J. Blinken will travel to Vatican City on June 28, where he will meet with Pope Francis and Archbishop Paul Gallagher to discuss efforts to work together to tackle the climate crisis and promote peace and human rights around the world.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States Celebrates Strong Relations with the Holy See </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States and Holy See enjoy a close partnership to promote human rights, combat human trafficking and climate change, and seek peaceful solutions to crises around the world. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Holy See maintains formal diplomatic relations with 183 countries. Its influence extends to more than 1.3 billion Catholics worldwide and millions of non-Catholics as well.  With a grassroots presence in almost every country in the world, the Holy See is a critical partner.  </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Holy See – through Catholic religious orders, lay communities, and faith-based organizations – is among the greatest humanitarian forces in the world. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States values its cooperation with the Holy See and Catholic organizations on the ground to deliver humanitarian aid successfully and efficiently to individuals and communities in need all around the world. By maintaining and strengthening diplomatic relations with the Holy See, the United States benefits from its unparalleled global presence. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tackling the Climate Crisis </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">His Holiness Pope Francis has shown longstanding leadership on the imperative to tackle the climate crisis, calling on political leaders and civil society to care for the environment. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States and Holy See are working together to raise countries’ collective ambition to address the climate crisis, including by raising and implementing national emissions reductions targets. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Promoting Human Rights is a U.S.-Holy See Priority </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The protection of human rights is a key priority for the United States. The Holy See has long been a global champion of human dignity, and the United States looks forward to working with the Vatican on this issue. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Holy See has a long history of promoting freedom of religion or belief, including through advocacy and interfaith dialogue. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Partnering with the Holy See to Combat Human Trafficking </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Human trafficking is a threat to international peace and security.  Traffickers undermine the rule of law and violate human dignity, robbing women, children, and men of their freedom. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Holy See and the United States share a common commitment to the fight against human trafficking, and the Holy See is a valued partner in the global effort to prevent this heinous crime. </span></li>
</ul>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secretary Antony J. Blinken will travel to Vatican City on June 28, where he will meet with Pope Francis and Archbishop Paul Gallagher to discuss efforts to work together to tackle the climate crisis and promote peace and human rights around the world.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States Celebrates Strong Relations with the Holy See </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States and Holy See enjoy a close partnership to promote human rights, combat human trafficking and climate change, and seek peaceful solutions to crises around the world. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Holy See maintains formal diplomatic relations with 183 countries. Its influence extends to more than 1.3 billion Catholics worldwide and millions of non-Catholics as well.  With a grassroots presence in almost every country in the world, the Holy See is a critical partner.  </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Holy See – through Catholic religious orders, lay communities, and faith-based organizations – is among the greatest humanitarian forces in the world. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States values its cooperation with the Holy See and Catholic organizations on the ground to deliver humanitarian aid successfully and efficiently to individuals and communities in need all around the world. By maintaining and strengthening diplomatic relations with the Holy See, the United States benefits from its unparalleled global presence. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tackling the Climate Crisis </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">His Holiness Pope Francis has shown longstanding leadership on the imperative to tackle the climate crisis, calling on political leaders and civil society to care for the environment. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States and Holy See are working together to raise countries’ collective ambition to address the climate crisis, including by raising and implementing national emissions reductions targets. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Promoting Human Rights is a U.S.-Holy See Priority </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The protection of human rights is a key priority for the United States. The Holy See has long been a global champion of human dignity, and the United States looks forward to working with the Vatican on this issue. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Holy See has a long history of promoting freedom of religion or belief, including through advocacy and interfaith dialogue. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Partnering with the Holy See to Combat Human Trafficking </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Human trafficking is a threat to international peace and security.  Traffickers undermine the rule of law and violate human dignity, robbing women, children, and men of their freedom. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Holy See and the United States share a common commitment to the fight against human trafficking, and the Holy See is a valued partner in the global effort to prevent this heinous crime. </span></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States-Italy Relationship and Transatlantic Unity</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-italy-relationship-and-transatlantic-unity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 12:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255519</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Congratulations, Prime Minister Mario Draghi. I look forward to working closely with you to deepen our strong bilateral relationship, cooperate during your leadership of the G20, and address global challenges from COVID to climate change</span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.”</span></i></p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">– President Joseph R. Biden, February 14, 2021</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secretary Antony J. Blinken will travel to Rome and Matera, Italy, June 27-29, where he will meet with Italian President Sergio Mattarella, Prime Minister Mario Draghi, and Foreign Minister Luigi Di Maio to discuss the importance of Transatlantic unity and our strong bilateral relationship.  They will also discuss the economic and security ties that strengthen our enduring partnership with Italy.  Secretary Blinken will then co-chair the D-ISIS Ministerial with Foreign Minister Di Maio, before traveling to Matera to attend the G20 Foreign Affairs Ministerial Meeting. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States and Italy are Close Partners and Allies </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States looks forward to strengthening the excellent cooperation between our two countries, both as NATO Allies and long-standing economic partners. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our relationship is deep and enduring.  The United States established diplomatic relations with the Kingdom of Italy in 1861 and reaffirmed them in 1946 when Italy became a republic. We have built a strong partnership based on common values and shared historical and familial bonds.  </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">More than 20 million Americans proudly claim Italian heritage. Throughout our history, Italian-Americans have greatly enriched the fabric of American life. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Italy and the United States share a commitment to the same values – democracy, human rights, the rule of law, security, and prosperity.  </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We welcome Italy’s focus on combatting the COVID-19 pandemic, tackling the climate crisis, and fostering a sustainable economic recovery during its G20 presidency this year. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Security Cooperation is at the Heart of Our Partnership </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Italy is a key NATO Ally, a leader and guarantor of security in the international community, and a reliable partner. Italy plays a crucial role in guaranteeing Transatlantic security, particularly in assuring NATO’s southern flank and through its participation in UN and NATO missions in Iraq, Kosovo, Lebanon, and Afghanistan.  </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Italy also plays an important role in marshaling international support for progress in Libya.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The U.S. military maintains a presence at five major military installations in Italy, where it is a welcoming host to more than 33,000 U.S. troops, Department of Defense civilians, and their family members.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Italy hosts the U.S. Navy’s 6th Fleet headquarters in Naples and NATO’s Joint Force Command outside of Naples in Lago Patria.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States and Italy agree that we must do more jointly to address shared threats in the Mediterranean region and around the world. At the June 14 NATO Summit, President Biden and Prime Minister Draghi endorsed a series of proposals to revitalize NATO through the NATO 2030 initiative.  The United States and Italy also collaborate closely as part of the Global Coalition’s efforts to defeat ISIS.  We look forward to continuing that work.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Economies and Workers Benefit from Our Close Economic and Educational Ties </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Un</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ited States represents Italy’s largest non-EU export market. Our two-way trade in goods and services amounted to $80 billion last year.  Our relationship, which ranges from trade in consumer goods and agricultural products to cooperation in the defense industries, has spurred collaboration in fields outside the economic realm, including security and space technology. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">As of 2019, Italy’s direct investment in the United States totaled $32.8 billion, while U.S. direct investment in Italy was $34.9 billion. As of 2018, U.S. jobs tied to Italian direct investment in the United States totaled 93,700, while 250,000 Italian jobs were tied to U.S. direct investment in Italy. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Italy is the second most popular destination for American study abroad students in the world, with more than 35,000 U.S. students studying there each year.  Italian students are also increasingly attracted to education exchange programs in the United States.  In the 2019/2020 academic year, more than 6,000 Italians chose to study at a U.S. college or university. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since the establishment of the U.S.-Italy Fulbright Commission in 1948, approximately 14,000 Italian and American students, teachers, lecturers, and researchers have participated in the Fulbright international exchange program, enhancing scholarship through educational exchange. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The U.S.-Italy Fulbright Program has produced alumni who have had enduring impacts on their fields, including Italian Prime Ministers Giuliano Amato and Lamberto Dini, eight Nobel laureates, twelve Pulitzer Prize winners, and five MacArthur Foundation Fellows.</span></li>
</ul>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Congratulations, Prime Minister Mario Draghi. I look forward to working closely with you to deepen our strong bilateral relationship, cooperate during your leadership of the G20, and address global challenges from COVID to climate change</span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.”</span></i></p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">– President Joseph R. Biden, February 14, 2021</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secretary Antony J. Blinken will travel to Rome and Matera, Italy, June 27-29, where he will meet with Italian President Sergio Mattarella, Prime Minister Mario Draghi, and Foreign Minister Luigi Di Maio to discuss the importance of Transatlantic unity and our strong bilateral relationship.  They will also discuss the economic and security ties that strengthen our enduring partnership with Italy.  Secretary Blinken will then co-chair the D-ISIS Ministerial with Foreign Minister Di Maio, before traveling to Matera to attend the G20 Foreign Affairs Ministerial Meeting. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States and Italy are Close Partners and Allies </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States looks forward to strengthening the excellent cooperation between our two countries, both as NATO Allies and long-standing economic partners. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our relationship is deep and enduring.  The United States established diplomatic relations with the Kingdom of Italy in 1861 and reaffirmed them in 1946 when Italy became a republic. We have built a strong partnership based on common values and shared historical and familial bonds.  </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">More than 20 million Americans proudly claim Italian heritage. Throughout our history, Italian-Americans have greatly enriched the fabric of American life. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Italy and the United States share a commitment to the same values – democracy, human rights, the rule of law, security, and prosperity.  </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We welcome Italy’s focus on combatting the COVID-19 pandemic, tackling the climate crisis, and fostering a sustainable economic recovery during its G20 presidency this year. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Security Cooperation is at the Heart of Our Partnership </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Italy is a key NATO Ally, a leader and guarantor of security in the international community, and a reliable partner. Italy plays a crucial role in guaranteeing Transatlantic security, particularly in assuring NATO’s southern flank and through its participation in UN and NATO missions in Iraq, Kosovo, Lebanon, and Afghanistan.  </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Italy also plays an important role in marshaling international support for progress in Libya.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The U.S. military maintains a presence at five major military installations in Italy, where it is a welcoming host to more than 33,000 U.S. troops, Department of Defense civilians, and their family members.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Italy hosts the U.S. Navy’s 6th Fleet headquarters in Naples and NATO’s Joint Force Command outside of Naples in Lago Patria.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States and Italy agree that we must do more jointly to address shared threats in the Mediterranean region and around the world. At the June 14 NATO Summit, President Biden and Prime Minister Draghi endorsed a series of proposals to revitalize NATO through the NATO 2030 initiative.  The United States and Italy also collaborate closely as part of the Global Coalition’s efforts to defeat ISIS.  We look forward to continuing that work.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Economies and Workers Benefit from Our Close Economic and Educational Ties </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Un</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ited States represents Italy’s largest non-EU export market. Our two-way trade in goods and services amounted to $80 billion last year.  Our relationship, which ranges from trade in consumer goods and agricultural products to cooperation in the defense industries, has spurred collaboration in fields outside the economic realm, including security and space technology. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">As of 2019, Italy’s direct investment in the United States totaled $32.8 billion, while U.S. direct investment in Italy was $34.9 billion. As of 2018, U.S. jobs tied to Italian direct investment in the United States totaled 93,700, while 250,000 Italian jobs were tied to U.S. direct investment in Italy. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Italy is the second most popular destination for American study abroad students in the world, with more than 35,000 U.S. students studying there each year.  Italian students are also increasingly attracted to education exchange programs in the United States.  In the 2019/2020 academic year, more than 6,000 Italians chose to study at a U.S. college or university. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since the establishment of the U.S.-Italy Fulbright Commission in 1948, approximately 14,000 Italian and American students, teachers, lecturers, and researchers have participated in the Fulbright international exchange program, enhancing scholarship through educational exchange. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The U.S.-Italy Fulbright Program has produced alumni who have had enduring impacts on their fields, including Italian Prime Ministers Giuliano Amato and Lamberto Dini, eight Nobel laureates, twelve Pulitzer Prize winners, and five MacArthur Foundation Fellows.</span></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Djibouti National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/djibouti-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 05:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255286</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Djibouti as you celebrate the 44<sup>th</sup> anniversary of your nation’s independence.</p>
<p>The United States and Djibouti are partners in fostering security, stability, and peace in the Horn of Africa.  We commend Djibouti’s leadership in the region, from its hosting the Executive Secretariat of the Intergovernmental Authority on Development to its contributions to the African Union Mission in Somalia, and the important mediating role it plays.</p>
<p>We will continue to work with the government and the people of Djibouti to strengthen democratic institutions, expand economic opportunities, and advance our common interests.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Djibouti as you celebrate the 44<sup>th</sup> anniversary of your nation’s independence.</p>
<p>The United States and Djibouti are partners in fostering security, stability, and peace in the Horn of Africa.  We commend Djibouti’s leadership in the region, from its hosting the Executive Secretariat of the Intergovernmental Authority on Development to its contributions to the African Union Mission in Somalia, and the important mediating role it plays.</p>
<p>We will continue to work with the government and the people of Djibouti to strengthen democratic institutions, expand economic opportunities, and advance our common interests.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Anne Claire Coudray of TF1</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-anne-claire-coudray-of-tf1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 13:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255492</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Quai d’Orsay</p>
<p>Paris, France</p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Via Translation</span></i></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Antony Blinken, good evening.  Thank you very much for agreeing to answer our questions.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s my pleasure.  Thank you.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, when Joe Biden appointed you head of American diplomacy, we, French people, wanted to see it as a sign because you speak absolutely perfect French.  You lived in France, in Paris, when you were a student.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Actually, you are too nice.  In fact, the good thing is that since January, I have had the opportunity to practice my French, especially when collaborating with my friend Jean-Yves Le Drian and with other French colleagues.  Indeed, I came to France at the age of 9.  I stayed until I was 18.  I passed my baccalaureate in Paris and then obviously, I’ve kept in touch ever since.  I even came back when I was 30 before starting a career in government.  I spent two more years in Paris.  I made friends then who are still friends today.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Precisely, it is often said that the French and the Americans are like cousins.  And yet, in recent years, we have also discovered sometimes rather brutally that we do not always think the same.  You are familiar with both ways of thinking.  What would you say? What makes us different sometimes?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes there are differences – nuances, changes in tactics, sometimes on issues.  That’s normal.  It’s normal in a family.  It’s normal with friends.  But, more important than our differences, are the things that bring us together on a deeper level.  That is what I learned in my youth. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are certain values, ​​and we use these words very easily, but there is something behind these values, which we, French and Americans, are trying to implement.  Liberty, equality, fraternity. That means something.  The obligation to support human rights means something.  And most importantly, right now we both live in democracies that are being significantly challenged, both internally and externally.  I think we both see the same challenge: it is to show through our actions, and especially our collective actions, to our citizens, that we can obtain results that will improve their lives and, hopefully, the lives of people around the world.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Antony Blinken, the French people know you too, since you appear in one of the most famous photos of the last ten years, in the Situation room, near Barack Obama during the assault on Osama bin Laden. Would you say that it is the highlight of your career?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s mostly – it’s true that it was a highlight. The strongest? I don’t know, but it’s something that I remember because it was a moment of justice, if you will, because he was the one who led the attack on the United States for seven years. So it was a moment of justice for him, for us and above all, of course, there was some tension because the mission was complicated.  And finally, it was a relief.  But it is indeed an important moment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That being said, I have to tell you that a few weeks after this photo was taken – I am in the background.  We have a TV show, back home, in the evening, with a comedian called David Letterman, you may also know him in France, who showed a close-up of this photo.  One of my government colleagues was on set with him.  He pointed at me, and he said, “Who is that guy in the back of the picture? Is this someone who got lost because he was trying to visit the White House?” So, this moment is both a moment I will remember all my life, and one that will keep things in perspective.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Joe Biden has chosen to travel to Europe for the first time for the sake of the Europeans, with a very strong message: to restore a relationship of trust battered by the four years of Donald Trump’s mandate.  How do you assess the damage caused by this Trump mandate in your mission?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m totally focused on today and tomorrow and the work we need to do together to face the challenges…</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">But when you arrive in a country, you must feel that these four years have been difficult and that they have damaged this relationship between Europe and America.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I remember two things.  First of all, there is a resurgence of confidence between the United States and our closest allies.  And especially with France.  This is very important, and this for a very practical reason.  When we look at the challenges that we’re facing – whether it be the challenge of this COVID pandemic, the climate, the emergence of new technologies that have major impacts on the lives of our citizens – we find that there is no one country acting alone that has the capacity to deal effectively with these problems and there is no wall that we can build high enough, strong enough, to avoid them. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, at the moment, I think there is a need to work together, to find the means to cooperate, to coordinate, to work together.  And that’s why President Biden wanted to focus on our partnerships during the first six months, our alliances with our closest friends, and our oldest ally: France.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Will it be a more balanced relationship? It is true that before, the United States appeared to be masters of the world.  During these four Trump years, there was also a lot of humiliation. The Europeans have been forced to find another balance.  It implies that you can’t go back to the same relationship as before.  Do we need a more balanced relationship?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">In any case, you can’t go back because the world has changed and is changing extremely quickly.  So, above all what we need is to work and face these challenges together and not look back.  And that also involves, maybe, doing things differently. Listening is as important as talking. And I think we have done some important work, especially these last six months, not only in terms of our commitment to our partners and friends, but above all by listening to them – whether it is bilaterally, or in the G7, in NATO, in the EU – and that allows us to establish a joint approach much more effectively.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is one point that we do not quite agree upon, and that is the way you see China.  It is true that you consider this country an adversary, even a commercial enemy, and it is true that it is a tone with which the Europeans take a little distance, in particular Emmanuel Macron.  Do you think we are being naive with China?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">What I’ve seen, especially these last few weeks, is a convergence with regard to the approach to China and I think we see it the same way.  It is, for all our countries, a very complicated relationship that cannot be simplified with a single word or a single sentence.  But what I will say, and I think we have the same point of view with France, is that there are antagonistic elements in the relationship, competitive elements, and elements of cooperation.  And what’s important, whether it’s antagonistic, whether it’s competitive, whether it’s cooperative, is that we will have a lot more impact when we approach China together than if we act alone.  And whether it is at the G7, NATO, or the EU, I think that we have seen a convergence in the declarations and in the decisions that have been made.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And I want to be clear on this, our goal is not to hold China back. It is not to establish a policy against China.  It is to support a free and open system based on the rules and standards that France and the United States established after WWII, and which have served us well.  Because if we don’t have a system where countries act according to the rules, respecting the agreements they have made, the alternative is war. It’s a jungle, it’s the law of the jungle, the survival of the fittest.  And we know from our common history that it leads somewhere we no longer want to go.  So, for us, the idea is to support this system with our allies and partners, not against China, but for a positive vision of the future and relations between countries.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I have two final questions.  There is one area in which our cooperation is unprecedented.  It is the military.  France and the United States are working together, and in particular in the Sahel.  We know that France is imagining another form of engagement in the field.  Will the United States participate in the future coalition, particularly in terms of intelligence and logistical support? How are you prepared to continue helping us in the Sahel?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">The answer is simple.  Quite simply: yes, we have a very important partnership with France in the Sahel.  We have a lot of appreciation for the leadership of France.  I think it makes perfect sense to rework the strategy.  It’s obviously been eight years now since France has been involved with the Sahel and above all, we are trying to strengthen the capacity of our partners on the ground, not only to strengthen their military capacities, but also their capacities for governance and to create a future for their people.  I believe this is the right thing to do, while obviously maintaining what it takes to counter terrorism, and we will do it together.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Joe Biden will receive Angela Merkel on July 15 at the White House.  It is said that the United States chose Germany as their main partner in Europe.  You yourself, a few days ago, said that there was no better friend of America than Germany.  Isn’t that a little surprising given our common history?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">No, our common history is that France is our oldest friend.  When we founded our country &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Independence.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">France was there for our independence.  Something we never forget.  The best symbol of our democracy is the Statue of Liberty from France.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Will there be a meeting between Joe Biden and Emmanuel Macron?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes, absolutely, there has obviously already been a meeting in Cornwall.  A very, very, not only positive, but productive meeting.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do you have an invitation to give to Emmanuel Macron?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am sure and convinced that we will have the opportunity and the chance to receive the President of the French Republic.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thank you very much Antony Blinken for agreeing to answer our questions.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thank you.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Quai d’Orsay</p>
<p>Paris, France</p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Via Translation</span></i></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Antony Blinken, good evening.  Thank you very much for agreeing to answer our questions.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s my pleasure.  Thank you.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, when Joe Biden appointed you head of American diplomacy, we, French people, wanted to see it as a sign because you speak absolutely perfect French.  You lived in France, in Paris, when you were a student.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Actually, you are too nice.  In fact, the good thing is that since January, I have had the opportunity to practice my French, especially when collaborating with my friend Jean-Yves Le Drian and with other French colleagues.  Indeed, I came to France at the age of 9.  I stayed until I was 18.  I passed my baccalaureate in Paris and then obviously, I’ve kept in touch ever since.  I even came back when I was 30 before starting a career in government.  I spent two more years in Paris.  I made friends then who are still friends today.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Precisely, it is often said that the French and the Americans are like cousins.  And yet, in recent years, we have also discovered sometimes rather brutally that we do not always think the same.  You are familiar with both ways of thinking.  What would you say? What makes us different sometimes?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes there are differences – nuances, changes in tactics, sometimes on issues.  That’s normal.  It’s normal in a family.  It’s normal with friends.  But, more important than our differences, are the things that bring us together on a deeper level.  That is what I learned in my youth. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are certain values, ​​and we use these words very easily, but there is something behind these values, which we, French and Americans, are trying to implement.  Liberty, equality, fraternity. That means something.  The obligation to support human rights means something.  And most importantly, right now we both live in democracies that are being significantly challenged, both internally and externally.  I think we both see the same challenge: it is to show through our actions, and especially our collective actions, to our citizens, that we can obtain results that will improve their lives and, hopefully, the lives of people around the world.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Antony Blinken, the French people know you too, since you appear in one of the most famous photos of the last ten years, in the Situation room, near Barack Obama during the assault on Osama bin Laden. Would you say that it is the highlight of your career?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s mostly – it’s true that it was a highlight. The strongest? I don’t know, but it’s something that I remember because it was a moment of justice, if you will, because he was the one who led the attack on the United States for seven years. So it was a moment of justice for him, for us and above all, of course, there was some tension because the mission was complicated.  And finally, it was a relief.  But it is indeed an important moment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That being said, I have to tell you that a few weeks after this photo was taken – I am in the background.  We have a TV show, back home, in the evening, with a comedian called David Letterman, you may also know him in France, who showed a close-up of this photo.  One of my government colleagues was on set with him.  He pointed at me, and he said, “Who is that guy in the back of the picture? Is this someone who got lost because he was trying to visit the White House?” So, this moment is both a moment I will remember all my life, and one that will keep things in perspective.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Joe Biden has chosen to travel to Europe for the first time for the sake of the Europeans, with a very strong message: to restore a relationship of trust battered by the four years of Donald Trump’s mandate.  How do you assess the damage caused by this Trump mandate in your mission?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m totally focused on today and tomorrow and the work we need to do together to face the challenges…</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">But when you arrive in a country, you must feel that these four years have been difficult and that they have damaged this relationship between Europe and America.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I remember two things.  First of all, there is a resurgence of confidence between the United States and our closest allies.  And especially with France.  This is very important, and this for a very practical reason.  When we look at the challenges that we’re facing – whether it be the challenge of this COVID pandemic, the climate, the emergence of new technologies that have major impacts on the lives of our citizens – we find that there is no one country acting alone that has the capacity to deal effectively with these problems and there is no wall that we can build high enough, strong enough, to avoid them. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, at the moment, I think there is a need to work together, to find the means to cooperate, to coordinate, to work together.  And that’s why President Biden wanted to focus on our partnerships during the first six months, our alliances with our closest friends, and our oldest ally: France.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Will it be a more balanced relationship? It is true that before, the United States appeared to be masters of the world.  During these four Trump years, there was also a lot of humiliation. The Europeans have been forced to find another balance.  It implies that you can’t go back to the same relationship as before.  Do we need a more balanced relationship?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">In any case, you can’t go back because the world has changed and is changing extremely quickly.  So, above all what we need is to work and face these challenges together and not look back.  And that also involves, maybe, doing things differently. Listening is as important as talking. And I think we have done some important work, especially these last six months, not only in terms of our commitment to our partners and friends, but above all by listening to them – whether it is bilaterally, or in the G7, in NATO, in the EU – and that allows us to establish a joint approach much more effectively.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is one point that we do not quite agree upon, and that is the way you see China.  It is true that you consider this country an adversary, even a commercial enemy, and it is true that it is a tone with which the Europeans take a little distance, in particular Emmanuel Macron.  Do you think we are being naive with China?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">What I’ve seen, especially these last few weeks, is a convergence with regard to the approach to China and I think we see it the same way.  It is, for all our countries, a very complicated relationship that cannot be simplified with a single word or a single sentence.  But what I will say, and I think we have the same point of view with France, is that there are antagonistic elements in the relationship, competitive elements, and elements of cooperation.  And what’s important, whether it’s antagonistic, whether it’s competitive, whether it’s cooperative, is that we will have a lot more impact when we approach China together than if we act alone.  And whether it is at the G7, NATO, or the EU, I think that we have seen a convergence in the declarations and in the decisions that have been made.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And I want to be clear on this, our goal is not to hold China back. It is not to establish a policy against China.  It is to support a free and open system based on the rules and standards that France and the United States established after WWII, and which have served us well.  Because if we don’t have a system where countries act according to the rules, respecting the agreements they have made, the alternative is war. It’s a jungle, it’s the law of the jungle, the survival of the fittest.  And we know from our common history that it leads somewhere we no longer want to go.  So, for us, the idea is to support this system with our allies and partners, not against China, but for a positive vision of the future and relations between countries.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I have two final questions.  There is one area in which our cooperation is unprecedented.  It is the military.  France and the United States are working together, and in particular in the Sahel.  We know that France is imagining another form of engagement in the field.  Will the United States participate in the future coalition, particularly in terms of intelligence and logistical support? How are you prepared to continue helping us in the Sahel?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">The answer is simple.  Quite simply: yes, we have a very important partnership with France in the Sahel.  We have a lot of appreciation for the leadership of France.  I think it makes perfect sense to rework the strategy.  It’s obviously been eight years now since France has been involved with the Sahel and above all, we are trying to strengthen the capacity of our partners on the ground, not only to strengthen their military capacities, but also their capacities for governance and to create a future for their people.  I believe this is the right thing to do, while obviously maintaining what it takes to counter terrorism, and we will do it together.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Joe Biden will receive Angela Merkel on July 15 at the White House.  It is said that the United States chose Germany as their main partner in Europe.  You yourself, a few days ago, said that there was no better friend of America than Germany.  Isn’t that a little surprising given our common history?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">No, our common history is that France is our oldest friend.  When we founded our country &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Independence.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">France was there for our independence.  Something we never forget.  The best symbol of our democracy is the Statue of Liberty from France.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Will there be a meeting between Joe Biden and Emmanuel Macron?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes, absolutely, there has obviously already been a meeting in Cornwall.  A very, very, not only positive, but productive meeting.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do you have an invitation to give to Emmanuel Macron?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am sure and convinced that we will have the opportunity and the chance to receive the President of the French Republic.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thank you very much Antony Blinken for agreeing to answer our questions.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thank you.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>International Day in Support of Victims of Torture  </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/international-day-in-support-of-victims-of-torture/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 12:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the International Day in Support of Victims of Torture, we recognize the bravery and humanity of victims and survivors of torture around the world.  The absolute prohibition of torture is a human right enshrined in international law.  Since its inception in 1987, 171 countries—including the United States—have become parties to the Convention against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman, or Degrading Treatment or Punishment, which is inspired by Article 5 of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights and its core tenet: “No one shall be subjected to torture or to cruel, inhuman or degrading treatment or punishment.”  </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nevertheless, we continue to see governments using torture and other violations of human rights as tools of ongoing repression against political opponents, members of minority groups and marginalized populations, human rights advocates, and those who simply voice an opinion that these governments do not like.  The United States condemns torture wherever and whenever it occurs and strongly urges governments to abide by their international obligations and end impunity for these crimes.  We also underscore the importance of rehabilitation and transitional justice so victims and survivors can transition from horror to healing.  For this reason, the United States is the largest contributor to the UN Voluntary Fund for Victims of Torture that provides support to survivors and their families. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today is an opportunity for UN Member States, civil society, and individuals around the globe to unite against torture and urge truth, justice, and accountability for perpetrators of this human rights violation.  As long as there are those who would commit torture, the United States will not waver in its commitment to eliminate it. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the International Day in Support of Victims of Torture, we recognize the bravery and humanity of victims and survivors of torture around the world.  The absolute prohibition of torture is a human right enshrined in international law.  Since its inception in 1987, 171 countries—including the United States—have become parties to the Convention against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman, or Degrading Treatment or Punishment, which is inspired by Article 5 of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights and its core tenet: “No one shall be subjected to torture or to cruel, inhuman or degrading treatment or punishment.”  </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nevertheless, we continue to see governments using torture and other violations of human rights as tools of ongoing repression against political opponents, members of minority groups and marginalized populations, human rights advocates, and those who simply voice an opinion that these governments do not like.  The United States condemns torture wherever and whenever it occurs and strongly urges governments to abide by their international obligations and end impunity for these crimes.  We also underscore the importance of rehabilitation and transitional justice so victims and survivors can transition from horror to healing.  For this reason, the United States is the largest contributor to the UN Voluntary Fund for Victims of Torture that provides support to survivors and their families. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today is an opportunity for UN Member States, civil society, and individuals around the globe to unite against torture and urge truth, justice, and accountability for perpetrators of this human rights violation.  As long as there are those who would commit torture, the United States will not waver in its commitment to eliminate it. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
