<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 22:18:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Timor-Leste Presidential Election</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/timor-leste-presidential-election/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 22:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336497</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We congratulate President-elect José Ramos-Horta on his election as Timor-Leste’s next president and look forward to working with President-elect Ramos-Horta to strengthen the enduring partnership between the United States and Timor-Leste.  Rooted in shared values and interests, our partnership has delivered opportunities to improve the livelihoods of the Timorese people through economic development, public health, security cooperation, and educational exchanges and training.</p>
<p>We commend Timorese authorities, including the Technical Secretariat for Electoral Administration and the National Elections Commission, for administering a free, fair, and transparent election and the hundreds of thousands of Timorese voters who cast their ballots peacefully.  Timor-Leste’s election serves as an inspiration for democracy in Southeast Asia, the Indo-Pacific region, and the world.  This achievement represents another milestone in Timor-Leste’s tremendous work to build and strengthen its robust, vibrant democracy over its nearly 20-year history as an independent nation.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We congratulate President-elect José Ramos-Horta on his election as Timor-Leste’s next president and look forward to working with President-elect Ramos-Horta to strengthen the enduring partnership between the United States and Timor-Leste.  Rooted in shared values and interests, our partnership has delivered opportunities to improve the livelihoods of the Timorese people through economic development, public health, security cooperation, and educational exchanges and training.</p>
<p>We commend Timorese authorities, including the Technical Secretariat for Electoral Administration and the National Elections Commission, for administering a free, fair, and transparent election and the hundreds of thousands of Timorese voters who cast their ballots peacefully.  Timor-Leste’s election serves as an inspiration for democracy in Southeast Asia, the Indo-Pacific region, and the world.  This achievement represents another milestone in Timor-Leste’s tremendous work to build and strengthen its robust, vibrant democracy over its nearly 20-year history as an independent nation.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States Announces Commitments at Seventh Our Ocean Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-announces-commitments-at-seventh-our-ocean-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 22:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336494</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The seventh Our Ocean Conference – hosted by the Republic of Palau and the United States –brought together governments and non-state actors to make concrete commitments to protect ocean health and security.  The United States announced more than 110 commitments, from 14 agencies and offices, worth nearly $2.64 billion.  These commitments spanned the issue areas of the conference, including climate change, sustainable fisheries, sustainable blue economies, marine protected areas, maritime security, and marine pollution.</p>
<p>Titles of commitments appear below by issue area.  For more details on individual commitments – including descriptions, agency/department, and budget, if applicable – see the map viewer at <a href="https://ourocean2022.pw/commitments/">https://ourocean2022.pw/commitments/</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Climate Change</strong></p>
<p>The seventh Our Ocean Conference highlighted the ocean-climate nexus and the role of ocean-based climate solutions – including shipping decarbonization, marine nature-based solutions, and offshore renewable energy – in keeping the 1.5°C goal within reach and improving global climate resilience.  As the ocean-climate nexus was a cross-cutting theme of the conference, climate commitments appeared throughout the six sessions (see, for example, the sustainable blue economies session).  U.S. announcements included:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>USD 582 Million to Enhance Ocean and Climate Observations, Modeling, and Services</li>
<li>USD 161.5 Million for the National Coastal Resilience Fund</li>
<li>USD 107.9 Million for the Development and Operation of a NASA Instrument to Observe Coastal Ecosystems</li>
<li>USD 65 Million from NSF to Launch the Global Ocean Biogeochemistry Array (GO-BGC Array)</li>
<li>USD 52 Million from NSF for the Coastlines and People (CoPe) Hubs for Research and Broadening Participation</li>
<li>USD 25 Million from NSF for the Science and Technology Center for Chemical Currencies of a Microbial Planet</li>
<li>USD 20 Million from NSF for the AI Institute for Research on Trustworthy AI in Weather, Climate, and Coastal Oceanography (AI2ES)</li>
<li>USD 15 Million for the Delta-X Mission</li>
<li>The Climate Resilient Cities Project in the Philippines</li>
<li>USD 12 Million over 4 Years for a Coordinated Effort to Better Understand Sea Level Rise and Develop Improved Projections of its Future Changes</li>
<li>USD 11 Million for the ECCO (Estimating Circulation and Climate of the Ocean) Science Team</li>
<li>USD 7.5 Million for a Coordinated Effort to Better Understand Biological Changes at High Latitudes</li>
<li>USD 7 Million for the SASSIE (Salinity and Stratification at the Sea Ice Edge) Mission</li>
<li>The Local Works Program in Bangladesh</li>
<li>Intention to Provide USD 5 Million in Climate-Focused Funds for the Pacific Islands Subject to Domestic Approvals and Other Requirements</li>
<li>Support for Climate Change Adaptation in Sri Lanka and the Maldives</li>
<li>USD 4 Million Toward Launch of New Climate Information for Sanctuaries Initiative</li>
<li>Intention to Provide USD 3 Million to Support Placing a Climate Fellow in Koror, Subject to Completion of Domestic Procedures</li>
<li>USD 1.3 Million to Monitor Ocean Acidification</li>
<li>Intention to Provide USD 1 Million to Support the Ocean Risk and Resilience Action Alliance, Subject to Completion of Domestic Procedures and Other Requirements</li>
<li>Technical Assistance to Help Countries Deploy Additional Offshore Wind Assets Subject to Domestic Procedures and Other Requirements</li>
<li>USD 1 Million for Capacity Development in the Pacific Islands to Monitor Ocean Acidification</li>
<li>Intention to Provide $500,000 to Support a New Climate Early Warning and Adaptation Initiative to Increase the Capacity for Anticipating and Preparing for Current and Future Climates in Island Countries, Subject to Completion of Domestic Procedures and Other Requirements, as part of PREPARE</li>
<li>Intention to Provide USD 500,000 to Support Mission Innovation, specifically the Zero-Emission Shipping Mission, Subject to Completion of Domestic Procedures and Other Requirements</li>
<li>USD 300,000 to Support the Pacific Islands Health Officers Association in Crafting a Climate-Based Dengue Early Warning System in the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, and the Republic of Palau</li>
<li>Embassy Koror will Become the First Net-Zero U.S. Diplomatic Mission</li>
<li>A New International Partnership on MPAs, Biodiversity and Climate Change with Chile, France, Costa Rica, and the UK</li>
<li>The Carbon Negative Shot – the All-Hands-on-Deck Call for Innovation in Technologies and Approaches</li>
<li>The Blue Carbon Inventory Project</li>
<li>The Launch of a New Climate and Fisheries Initiative</li>
<li>The 2022 Sea Level Rise Technical Report</li>
<li>The United States Assumed Leadership of and Will Provide Financial Support for the International Coral Reef Initiative and Offers a Three-Year Plan of Action</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Sustainable Fisheries</strong></p>
<p>The sustainable fisheries session underscored issues including the contribution of fisheries to food security, the importance of considering labor conditions in the fisheries value chain, and the need to address illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing.  U.S. announcements included:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>The Feed the Future Innovation Lab for Fish</li>
<li>The Feed the Future Ghana Fisheries Recovery Activity (GFRA)</li>
<li>The OurFish OurFuture Program</li>
<li>Enhanced Coastal Fisheries in Bangladesh (ECOFISH) II</li>
<li>Support for Regional Efforts to Combat IUU Fishing in Southeast Asia as the USAID Sustainable Fish Asia (SUFIA) Technical Services</li>
<li>A Project to Mitigate Risk in Fisheries via USAID Bureau of Humanitarian Assistance</li>
<li>An Initiative to Enhance Cooperative Fisheries Management and Compliance in Coastal Pacific Fisheries</li>
<li>USD 5 Million to Strengthen Decent Work in the Fishing Sector in South America</li>
<li>The Establishment of the USAID Sustainable Fish Asia Local Capacity Development Activity</li>
<li>USD 4 Million to Strengthen Rural Worker Rights, including in the Philippine Fishing Sector</li>
<li>USD 2.5 Million to Address Labor Exploitation in the Fishing Sector in Southeast Asia</li>
<li>A USAID and NOAA Joint Effort to Support PSMA Implementation, Combat IUU Fishing, and Strengthen Fisheries Management in Peru, Ecuador, and Colombia</li>
<li>The Women Shellfishers and Food Security Project</li>
<li>Support to Strengthen Natural Resource Governance in Ecuador</li>
<li>An Additional Year and Funding for the Seafood Alliance for Legality and Traceability</li>
<li>The Distant Water Fleet Research Agenda</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Sustainable Blue Economies</strong></p>
<p>Sustainable blue economies advance ocean health alongside economic prosperity, providing sustainable food, power, and transportation.  U.S. announcements included:</p>
<ul>
<li>Continued Support for the Integrated Ocean Observing System Regional Associations</li>
<li>Support for Critical Wave Energy Test Facility PacWave</li>
<li>USD 30 Million to Support Implementation of the UN Decade of Ocean Science for Sustainable Development</li>
<li>USD 25 Million for Open-Water R&amp;D at PacWave</li>
<li>Technical Assistance for Energy Transition Planning for Remote, Island, and Islanded Communities</li>
<li>A Multi-Agency Goal to Deploy 30 Gigawatts of Offshore Wind by 2030</li>
<li>USD 11 Million from NSF for the Networked Blue Economy Convergence Accelerator</li>
<li>The United States Is Sending Six Wave-Powered Autonomous Underwater Vehicles to a Wave Tank Test at Carderock in the Fourth Stage of the Ocean Observing Prize</li>
<li>USD 8.3 Million to Support Ocean Observing, Mapping, and Exploration Efforts</li>
<li>Support for Ocean Testing of Four Wave-Powered Desalination Devices in the Final Stage of the Waves to Water Prize</li>
<li>The Marine and Coastal Areas Restored through Innovative and Sustainable Aquaculture (MARISA) Partnership</li>
<li>Funding for Six Projects for the Co-existence of Offshore Energy with Northeast United States Fishing and Coastal Communities</li>
<li>A Framework for Green Shipping Corridors</li>
<li>Joining of the High-Level Panel for a Sustainable Ocean Economy</li>
<li>The National Institute of Standards and Technology will Develop and Update Reference Materials to Support the Sustainable Blue Economy and Marine Pollution Research</li>
<li>Efforts to Advance the Development of Marine Aquaculture to Support the Blue Economy</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Marine Protected Areas</strong></p>
<p>The marine protected areas session focused on the climate, biodiversity, and community benefits of marine protection; it also highlighted funding for research and monitoring, improved implementation and management of marine protected areas, and resilience, adaptation, and restoration.  U.S. announcements included:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>Efforts to Support Coastal Zone Management, Restoration, and Habitat Conservation</li>
<li>Sustainable Interventions for Biodiversity, Ocean, and Landscapes</li>
<li>The Mekong Delta Coastal Habitat Conservation Activity</li>
<li>Support for Ocean Mapping of Palau National Marine Sanctuary</li>
<li>Efforts to Enhance Coral Conservation and Resilience Through the Launch of Domestic and Global Status Reports, Strategies for the Prevention of and Response to Stony Coral Tissue Loss Disease, and Grants for Coral Restoration</li>
<li>Nearly USD 200,000 to improve MPA Management in Indonesia by Supporting Efforts to Expand Small-Scale Vessel Tracking</li>
<li>The Designation of New Marine Protected Areas in Wisconsin and Connecticut</li>
<li>The “Memorandum of Understanding between the U.S. National Park Service of the Department of the Interior of the United States of America and the Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Palau Concerning Protected Area Planning, Training, and Technical Collaboration”</li>
<li>Forthcoming Launch of a Working Group or Commission to Evaluate Naming Practices for Existing and Future Marine National Monuments and National Marine Sanctuaries</li>
<li>Joining of the High Ambition Coalition for People and Nature</li>
<li>A New Global “Ocean Conservation Pledge,” Which Aims to Encourage Countries to Commit to Conserve, Protect, or Restore at Least 30% of Waters under Their National Jurisdiction by 2030</li>
<li>The Initiation of Three National Marine Sanctuary Designations</li>
<li>The Establishment and Development of the Northern Bering Sea Climate Resilience Area</li>
<li>An Expansion of Membership of the Marine Protected Area Agency Partnership (MPAAP)</li>
<li>The Signing of an Indo-Pacific MPA Partnership with the Republic of Palau</li>
<li>The Development of a New Climate Ready MPA Assessment Tool</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Maritime Security</strong></p>
<p>The maritime security session emphasized the links between maritime security and IUU fishing, the need for law enforcement capacity building aimed at multiple illicit activities, and the need for improved information sharing and international coordination.   U.S. announcements included:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>USD 6.5 Million from NSF for the Design and Construction of a New Generation of Ocean-Bottom Seismographs for the U.S. Academic Community</li>
<li>USD 5 Million to Advance Labor Compliance in Colombia’s Port Sector</li>
<li>Support for Interpol’s Efforts to Reduce Illegal Fishing</li>
<li>New Arrangements Between the U.S. Coast Guard and the Coast Guards of Italy, and Taiwan</li>
<li>The Establishment of the U.S. Interagency Working Group on IUU Fishing</li>
<li>A Maritime Security Advisor Program in the Pacific</li>
<li>A Commitment Towards Cooperative Fisheries Law Enforcement on the High Seas</li>
<li>Support for Partner Capacity Building to Combat IUU Fishing via a New Five-Day Counter-IUU Fishing Course</li>
<li>A Maritime Information Sharing (MIS) Table-Top exercise with the EU-funded project CRIMARIO II, in Palau</li>
<li>The Ocean Prosperity and Maritime Security (OPMS) Partnership</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Marine Pollution</strong></p>
<p>The marine pollution session featured efforts and programs that target marine plastic, the fisheries sector, maritime transport, and infrastructure development.  It also featured recycling initiatives and lifecycle approaches for plastics; clean-ups and remediation/restoration efforts; and research and innovation.  U.S. announcements included:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>USD 350 Million in Improvements to Recycling Infrastructure to Reduce Land-Based Sources of Plastic Waste to the Marine Environment</li>
<li>USD 200 Million to Prevent and Remove Marine Debris</li>
<li>National Estuary Program Infrastructure Investments for Projects that will Reduce Pollutant Loadings into Freshwater Ecosystems and the Ocean</li>
<li>Support for U.S. States to Implement the Gulf Hypoxia Action Plan</li>
<li>The USAID Clean Cities, Blue Ocean Program</li>
<li>USD 37 Million for the Department of Energy’s BOTTLE Program to Improve Plastic Recycling</li>
<li>A Funding Opportunity for Research on Chemical Upcycling of Polymers</li>
<li>More than USD 24 Million for Two Energy Frontier Research Centers Related to Plastics</li>
<li>USD 8 Million from NSF for the Emerging Frontiers in Research and Innovation Engineering the Elimination of End-of-Life Plastics Program (EFRI E3P)</li>
<li>Intention to Provide USD 5 Million to Combat Marine Pollution via Support for Pillar 2 of the World Bank’s PROBLUE Multi-Donor Trust Fund Subject to Congressional Notification and Availability of Funds</li>
<li>A USAID Blended Finance Partnership with Circulate Capital</li>
<li>USAID’s Local Solutions for Plastic Pollution Activity</li>
<li>The Plastics Solution Alliance</li>
<li>Over USD 859,000 to Monitor Nutrient Drivers of Coastal Dead Zones</li>
<li>USD 810,000 to Establish the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation Marine Debris Management and Innovation Sub-Fund</li>
<li>USD 180,000 for a Grant to Build Capacity for Environmentally Sound Management of Plastic Waste in West Africa</li>
<li>A Cooperative Arrangement to Establish Center for Marine Debris Research</li>
<li>The Department of Energy’s Plastics Innovation Research and Development Strategy</li>
<li>Joining of the Global Ghost Gear Initiative</li>
<li>The National Institute of Standards and Technology Biorepository Will Archive Marine Animal Tissues to Support Marine Research</li>
<li>A Forthcoming Strategy for Post-Consumer Materials Management and Water Management</li>
</ul>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The seventh Our Ocean Conference – hosted by the Republic of Palau and the United States –brought together governments and non-state actors to make concrete commitments to protect ocean health and security.  The United States announced more than 110 commitments, from 14 agencies and offices, worth nearly $2.64 billion.  These commitments spanned the issue areas of the conference, including climate change, sustainable fisheries, sustainable blue economies, marine protected areas, maritime security, and marine pollution.</p>
<p>Titles of commitments appear below by issue area.  For more details on individual commitments – including descriptions, agency/department, and budget, if applicable – see the map viewer at <a href="https://ourocean2022.pw/commitments/">https://ourocean2022.pw/commitments/</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Climate Change</strong></p>
<p>The seventh Our Ocean Conference highlighted the ocean-climate nexus and the role of ocean-based climate solutions – including shipping decarbonization, marine nature-based solutions, and offshore renewable energy – in keeping the 1.5°C goal within reach and improving global climate resilience.  As the ocean-climate nexus was a cross-cutting theme of the conference, climate commitments appeared throughout the six sessions (see, for example, the sustainable blue economies session).  U.S. announcements included:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>USD 582 Million to Enhance Ocean and Climate Observations, Modeling, and Services</li>
<li>USD 161.5 Million for the National Coastal Resilience Fund</li>
<li>USD 107.9 Million for the Development and Operation of a NASA Instrument to Observe Coastal Ecosystems</li>
<li>USD 65 Million from NSF to Launch the Global Ocean Biogeochemistry Array (GO-BGC Array)</li>
<li>USD 52 Million from NSF for the Coastlines and People (CoPe) Hubs for Research and Broadening Participation</li>
<li>USD 25 Million from NSF for the Science and Technology Center for Chemical Currencies of a Microbial Planet</li>
<li>USD 20 Million from NSF for the AI Institute for Research on Trustworthy AI in Weather, Climate, and Coastal Oceanography (AI2ES)</li>
<li>USD 15 Million for the Delta-X Mission</li>
<li>The Climate Resilient Cities Project in the Philippines</li>
<li>USD 12 Million over 4 Years for a Coordinated Effort to Better Understand Sea Level Rise and Develop Improved Projections of its Future Changes</li>
<li>USD 11 Million for the ECCO (Estimating Circulation and Climate of the Ocean) Science Team</li>
<li>USD 7.5 Million for a Coordinated Effort to Better Understand Biological Changes at High Latitudes</li>
<li>USD 7 Million for the SASSIE (Salinity and Stratification at the Sea Ice Edge) Mission</li>
<li>The Local Works Program in Bangladesh</li>
<li>Intention to Provide USD 5 Million in Climate-Focused Funds for the Pacific Islands Subject to Domestic Approvals and Other Requirements</li>
<li>Support for Climate Change Adaptation in Sri Lanka and the Maldives</li>
<li>USD 4 Million Toward Launch of New Climate Information for Sanctuaries Initiative</li>
<li>Intention to Provide USD 3 Million to Support Placing a Climate Fellow in Koror, Subject to Completion of Domestic Procedures</li>
<li>USD 1.3 Million to Monitor Ocean Acidification</li>
<li>Intention to Provide USD 1 Million to Support the Ocean Risk and Resilience Action Alliance, Subject to Completion of Domestic Procedures and Other Requirements</li>
<li>Technical Assistance to Help Countries Deploy Additional Offshore Wind Assets Subject to Domestic Procedures and Other Requirements</li>
<li>USD 1 Million for Capacity Development in the Pacific Islands to Monitor Ocean Acidification</li>
<li>Intention to Provide $500,000 to Support a New Climate Early Warning and Adaptation Initiative to Increase the Capacity for Anticipating and Preparing for Current and Future Climates in Island Countries, Subject to Completion of Domestic Procedures and Other Requirements, as part of PREPARE</li>
<li>Intention to Provide USD 500,000 to Support Mission Innovation, specifically the Zero-Emission Shipping Mission, Subject to Completion of Domestic Procedures and Other Requirements</li>
<li>USD 300,000 to Support the Pacific Islands Health Officers Association in Crafting a Climate-Based Dengue Early Warning System in the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, and the Republic of Palau</li>
<li>Embassy Koror will Become the First Net-Zero U.S. Diplomatic Mission</li>
<li>A New International Partnership on MPAs, Biodiversity and Climate Change with Chile, France, Costa Rica, and the UK</li>
<li>The Carbon Negative Shot – the All-Hands-on-Deck Call for Innovation in Technologies and Approaches</li>
<li>The Blue Carbon Inventory Project</li>
<li>The Launch of a New Climate and Fisheries Initiative</li>
<li>The 2022 Sea Level Rise Technical Report</li>
<li>The United States Assumed Leadership of and Will Provide Financial Support for the International Coral Reef Initiative and Offers a Three-Year Plan of Action</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Sustainable Fisheries</strong></p>
<p>The sustainable fisheries session underscored issues including the contribution of fisheries to food security, the importance of considering labor conditions in the fisheries value chain, and the need to address illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing.  U.S. announcements included:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>The Feed the Future Innovation Lab for Fish</li>
<li>The Feed the Future Ghana Fisheries Recovery Activity (GFRA)</li>
<li>The OurFish OurFuture Program</li>
<li>Enhanced Coastal Fisheries in Bangladesh (ECOFISH) II</li>
<li>Support for Regional Efforts to Combat IUU Fishing in Southeast Asia as the USAID Sustainable Fish Asia (SUFIA) Technical Services</li>
<li>A Project to Mitigate Risk in Fisheries via USAID Bureau of Humanitarian Assistance</li>
<li>An Initiative to Enhance Cooperative Fisheries Management and Compliance in Coastal Pacific Fisheries</li>
<li>USD 5 Million to Strengthen Decent Work in the Fishing Sector in South America</li>
<li>The Establishment of the USAID Sustainable Fish Asia Local Capacity Development Activity</li>
<li>USD 4 Million to Strengthen Rural Worker Rights, including in the Philippine Fishing Sector</li>
<li>USD 2.5 Million to Address Labor Exploitation in the Fishing Sector in Southeast Asia</li>
<li>A USAID and NOAA Joint Effort to Support PSMA Implementation, Combat IUU Fishing, and Strengthen Fisheries Management in Peru, Ecuador, and Colombia</li>
<li>The Women Shellfishers and Food Security Project</li>
<li>Support to Strengthen Natural Resource Governance in Ecuador</li>
<li>An Additional Year and Funding for the Seafood Alliance for Legality and Traceability</li>
<li>The Distant Water Fleet Research Agenda</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Sustainable Blue Economies</strong></p>
<p>Sustainable blue economies advance ocean health alongside economic prosperity, providing sustainable food, power, and transportation.  U.S. announcements included:</p>
<ul>
<li>Continued Support for the Integrated Ocean Observing System Regional Associations</li>
<li>Support for Critical Wave Energy Test Facility PacWave</li>
<li>USD 30 Million to Support Implementation of the UN Decade of Ocean Science for Sustainable Development</li>
<li>USD 25 Million for Open-Water R&amp;D at PacWave</li>
<li>Technical Assistance for Energy Transition Planning for Remote, Island, and Islanded Communities</li>
<li>A Multi-Agency Goal to Deploy 30 Gigawatts of Offshore Wind by 2030</li>
<li>USD 11 Million from NSF for the Networked Blue Economy Convergence Accelerator</li>
<li>The United States Is Sending Six Wave-Powered Autonomous Underwater Vehicles to a Wave Tank Test at Carderock in the Fourth Stage of the Ocean Observing Prize</li>
<li>USD 8.3 Million to Support Ocean Observing, Mapping, and Exploration Efforts</li>
<li>Support for Ocean Testing of Four Wave-Powered Desalination Devices in the Final Stage of the Waves to Water Prize</li>
<li>The Marine and Coastal Areas Restored through Innovative and Sustainable Aquaculture (MARISA) Partnership</li>
<li>Funding for Six Projects for the Co-existence of Offshore Energy with Northeast United States Fishing and Coastal Communities</li>
<li>A Framework for Green Shipping Corridors</li>
<li>Joining of the High-Level Panel for a Sustainable Ocean Economy</li>
<li>The National Institute of Standards and Technology will Develop and Update Reference Materials to Support the Sustainable Blue Economy and Marine Pollution Research</li>
<li>Efforts to Advance the Development of Marine Aquaculture to Support the Blue Economy</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Marine Protected Areas</strong></p>
<p>The marine protected areas session focused on the climate, biodiversity, and community benefits of marine protection; it also highlighted funding for research and monitoring, improved implementation and management of marine protected areas, and resilience, adaptation, and restoration.  U.S. announcements included:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>Efforts to Support Coastal Zone Management, Restoration, and Habitat Conservation</li>
<li>Sustainable Interventions for Biodiversity, Ocean, and Landscapes</li>
<li>The Mekong Delta Coastal Habitat Conservation Activity</li>
<li>Support for Ocean Mapping of Palau National Marine Sanctuary</li>
<li>Efforts to Enhance Coral Conservation and Resilience Through the Launch of Domestic and Global Status Reports, Strategies for the Prevention of and Response to Stony Coral Tissue Loss Disease, and Grants for Coral Restoration</li>
<li>Nearly USD 200,000 to improve MPA Management in Indonesia by Supporting Efforts to Expand Small-Scale Vessel Tracking</li>
<li>The Designation of New Marine Protected Areas in Wisconsin and Connecticut</li>
<li>The “Memorandum of Understanding between the U.S. National Park Service of the Department of the Interior of the United States of America and the Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Palau Concerning Protected Area Planning, Training, and Technical Collaboration”</li>
<li>Forthcoming Launch of a Working Group or Commission to Evaluate Naming Practices for Existing and Future Marine National Monuments and National Marine Sanctuaries</li>
<li>Joining of the High Ambition Coalition for People and Nature</li>
<li>A New Global “Ocean Conservation Pledge,” Which Aims to Encourage Countries to Commit to Conserve, Protect, or Restore at Least 30% of Waters under Their National Jurisdiction by 2030</li>
<li>The Initiation of Three National Marine Sanctuary Designations</li>
<li>The Establishment and Development of the Northern Bering Sea Climate Resilience Area</li>
<li>An Expansion of Membership of the Marine Protected Area Agency Partnership (MPAAP)</li>
<li>The Signing of an Indo-Pacific MPA Partnership with the Republic of Palau</li>
<li>The Development of a New Climate Ready MPA Assessment Tool</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Maritime Security</strong></p>
<p>The maritime security session emphasized the links between maritime security and IUU fishing, the need for law enforcement capacity building aimed at multiple illicit activities, and the need for improved information sharing and international coordination.   U.S. announcements included:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>USD 6.5 Million from NSF for the Design and Construction of a New Generation of Ocean-Bottom Seismographs for the U.S. Academic Community</li>
<li>USD 5 Million to Advance Labor Compliance in Colombia’s Port Sector</li>
<li>Support for Interpol’s Efforts to Reduce Illegal Fishing</li>
<li>New Arrangements Between the U.S. Coast Guard and the Coast Guards of Italy, and Taiwan</li>
<li>The Establishment of the U.S. Interagency Working Group on IUU Fishing</li>
<li>A Maritime Security Advisor Program in the Pacific</li>
<li>A Commitment Towards Cooperative Fisheries Law Enforcement on the High Seas</li>
<li>Support for Partner Capacity Building to Combat IUU Fishing via a New Five-Day Counter-IUU Fishing Course</li>
<li>A Maritime Information Sharing (MIS) Table-Top exercise with the EU-funded project CRIMARIO II, in Palau</li>
<li>The Ocean Prosperity and Maritime Security (OPMS) Partnership</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Marine Pollution</strong></p>
<p>The marine pollution session featured efforts and programs that target marine plastic, the fisheries sector, maritime transport, and infrastructure development.  It also featured recycling initiatives and lifecycle approaches for plastics; clean-ups and remediation/restoration efforts; and research and innovation.  U.S. announcements included:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>USD 350 Million in Improvements to Recycling Infrastructure to Reduce Land-Based Sources of Plastic Waste to the Marine Environment</li>
<li>USD 200 Million to Prevent and Remove Marine Debris</li>
<li>National Estuary Program Infrastructure Investments for Projects that will Reduce Pollutant Loadings into Freshwater Ecosystems and the Ocean</li>
<li>Support for U.S. States to Implement the Gulf Hypoxia Action Plan</li>
<li>The USAID Clean Cities, Blue Ocean Program</li>
<li>USD 37 Million for the Department of Energy’s BOTTLE Program to Improve Plastic Recycling</li>
<li>A Funding Opportunity for Research on Chemical Upcycling of Polymers</li>
<li>More than USD 24 Million for Two Energy Frontier Research Centers Related to Plastics</li>
<li>USD 8 Million from NSF for the Emerging Frontiers in Research and Innovation Engineering the Elimination of End-of-Life Plastics Program (EFRI E3P)</li>
<li>Intention to Provide USD 5 Million to Combat Marine Pollution via Support for Pillar 2 of the World Bank’s PROBLUE Multi-Donor Trust Fund Subject to Congressional Notification and Availability of Funds</li>
<li>A USAID Blended Finance Partnership with Circulate Capital</li>
<li>USAID’s Local Solutions for Plastic Pollution Activity</li>
<li>The Plastics Solution Alliance</li>
<li>Over USD 859,000 to Monitor Nutrient Drivers of Coastal Dead Zones</li>
<li>USD 810,000 to Establish the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation Marine Debris Management and Innovation Sub-Fund</li>
<li>USD 180,000 for a Grant to Build Capacity for Environmentally Sound Management of Plastic Waste in West Africa</li>
<li>A Cooperative Arrangement to Establish Center for Marine Debris Research</li>
<li>The Department of Energy’s Plastics Innovation Research and Development Strategy</li>
<li>Joining of the Global Ghost Gear Initiative</li>
<li>The National Institute of Standards and Technology Biorepository Will Archive Marine Animal Tissues to Support Marine Research</li>
<li>A Forthcoming Strategy for Post-Consumer Materials Management and Water Management</li>
</ul>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Migration Talks with the Government of Cuba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/migration-talks-with-the-government-of-cuba/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 20:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336440</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On April 21, U.S. and Cuban officials met in Washington, D.C. to discuss the implementation of the U.S.-Cuba Migration Accords. These bilateral discussions on migration are generally held semiannually, reflecting a commitment by both countries to regularly review the implementation of the Accords. Deputy Assistant Secretary for Western Hemisphere Affairs Emily Mendrala led the U.S. interagency delegation, and Cuba’s Vice Foreign Minister Carlos Fernandez de Cossio led the Cuban delegation. These migration talks provide an opportunity for discussions on mutual implementation of the Migration Accords (comprised of a series of bilateral agreements between the United States and Cuba done in 1984, 1994, 1995, and 2017). The U.S. delegation highlighted areas of successful cooperation on migration, while also identifying issues that have been obstacles to fulfilling the goals of the Accords. Engaging in these talks underscores our commitment to pursuing constructive discussions with the Government of Cuba where appropriate to advance U.S. interests. These discussions represent the first Migration Accord talks between the United States and Cuba since 2018.</p>
<p>The United States also addressed consular services at U.S. Embassy Havana, to include resumption of immigrant visa services on a limited basis starting in May, current American citizen services, and current issuance of emergency non-immigrant visas. Enabling safe, legal, and orderly migration between Cuba and the United States remains a mutual interest between the United States and Cuba and is consistent with U.S. interests in fostering family reunification and promoting greater respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms in Cuba.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On April 21, U.S. and Cuban officials met in Washington, D.C. to discuss the implementation of the U.S.-Cuba Migration Accords. These bilateral discussions on migration are generally held semiannually, reflecting a commitment by both countries to regularly review the implementation of the Accords. Deputy Assistant Secretary for Western Hemisphere Affairs Emily Mendrala led the U.S. interagency delegation, and Cuba’s Vice Foreign Minister Carlos Fernandez de Cossio led the Cuban delegation. These migration talks provide an opportunity for discussions on mutual implementation of the Migration Accords (comprised of a series of bilateral agreements between the United States and Cuba done in 1984, 1994, 1995, and 2017). The U.S. delegation highlighted areas of successful cooperation on migration, while also identifying issues that have been obstacles to fulfilling the goals of the Accords. Engaging in these talks underscores our commitment to pursuing constructive discussions with the Government of Cuba where appropriate to advance U.S. interests. These discussions represent the first Migration Accord talks between the United States and Cuba since 2018.</p>
<p>The United States also addressed consular services at U.S. Embassy Havana, to include resumption of immigrant visa services on a limited basis starting in May, current American citizen services, and current issuance of emergency non-immigrant visas. Enabling safe, legal, and orderly migration between Cuba and the United States remains a mutual interest between the United States and Cuba and is consistent with U.S. interests in fostering family reunification and promoting greater respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms in Cuba.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Suspension of Russia’s Permanent Observer Status at the Organization of American States</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/suspension-of-russias-permanent-observer-status-at-the-organization-of-american-states/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 20:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336433</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Today, the United States welcomes the adoption of a resolution at the Organization of American States (OAS) suspending Russia as a Permanent Observer to that institution.  With the passage of this resolution, OAS member states demonstrated that we do not stand on the sidelines in the face of the Russian government’s violations of international humanitarian law and human rights abuses.  Our Hemisphere stands with Ukraine.</p>
<p>The Kremlin’s inhumanity in its premeditated, unprovoked, unjust war against Ukraine is horrifically clear.   Deaths and destruction mount daily.  More than 10 million Ukrainian citizens and others have been uprooted by the Kremlin’s coldblooded aggression.  On a global scale, Putin’s senseless war of choice has hurt economies and threatened the food security of the world’s most vulnerable.  As President Biden stated, “An overwhelming majority of nations recognize that Putin is not only attacking Ukraine, he is attacking the very foundations of global peace and security.”</p>
<p>The Russian government’s brutal attack against Ukraine’s territorial integrity and sovereignty demonstrates the Kremlin’s utter contempt for the values of democracy and respect for human rights, values that form the bedrock of the Inter American system.  We commend the governments of Antigua and Barbuda and Guatemala for leading the adoption of the resolution, and all the governments that supported it.</p>
<p>The OAS action today sends a clear message to the Kremlin.   The overwhelming number of countries in the Americas called upon the Kremlin to end its unconscionable war of choice, withdraw its forces, and comply with international law.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Today, the United States welcomes the adoption of a resolution at the Organization of American States (OAS) suspending Russia as a Permanent Observer to that institution.  With the passage of this resolution, OAS member states demonstrated that we do not stand on the sidelines in the face of the Russian government’s violations of international humanitarian law and human rights abuses.  Our Hemisphere stands with Ukraine.</p>
<p>The Kremlin’s inhumanity in its premeditated, unprovoked, unjust war against Ukraine is horrifically clear.   Deaths and destruction mount daily.  More than 10 million Ukrainian citizens and others have been uprooted by the Kremlin’s coldblooded aggression.  On a global scale, Putin’s senseless war of choice has hurt economies and threatened the food security of the world’s most vulnerable.  As President Biden stated, “An overwhelming majority of nations recognize that Putin is not only attacking Ukraine, he is attacking the very foundations of global peace and security.”</p>
<p>The Russian government’s brutal attack against Ukraine’s territorial integrity and sovereignty demonstrates the Kremlin’s utter contempt for the values of democracy and respect for human rights, values that form the bedrock of the Inter American system.  We commend the governments of Antigua and Barbuda and Guatemala for leading the adoption of the resolution, and all the governments that supported it.</p>
<p>The OAS action today sends a clear message to the Kremlin.   The overwhelming number of countries in the Americas called upon the Kremlin to end its unconscionable war of choice, withdraw its forces, and comply with international law.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary Fernandez’s Travel to Chile </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-fernandezs-travel-to-chile/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State for Economic Growth, Energy, and Environment Jose W. Fernandez will travel to Santiago, Chile, April 21-23 to engage with government officials, business leaders, and civil society, in support of regional trade and investment objectives, climate and environment programs, and pandemic response and preparedness.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Fernandez will meet with officials from the Chilean Ministries of Foreign Affairs, Health, and Mining, and with private sector representatives to discuss our joint COVID-19 pandemic response, regional economic recovery, and ways to deepen our bilateral economic ties to promote increased economic inclusion and prosperity for U.S. and Chilean citizens. The Under Secretary will also meet with the Chilean Minister of Environment and Chilean environmental organizations to discuss additional opportunities for U.S.-Chilean collaboration on combatting the climate crisis and supporting sustainable trade and development. On Earth Day, he will also meet with Economic Commission for Latin America and the Caribbean Acting Executive Secretary Mario Cimoli.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State for Economic Growth, Energy, and Environment Jose W. Fernandez will travel to Santiago, Chile, April 21-23 to engage with government officials, business leaders, and civil society, in support of regional trade and investment objectives, climate and environment programs, and pandemic response and preparedness.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Fernandez will meet with officials from the Chilean Ministries of Foreign Affairs, Health, and Mining, and with private sector representatives to discuss our joint COVID-19 pandemic response, regional economic recovery, and ways to deepen our bilateral economic ties to promote increased economic inclusion and prosperity for U.S. and Chilean citizens. The Under Secretary will also meet with the Chilean Minister of Environment and Chilean environmental organizations to discuss additional opportunities for U.S.-Chilean collaboration on combatting the climate crisis and supporting sustainable trade and development. On Earth Day, he will also meet with Economic Commission for Latin America and the Caribbean Acting Executive Secretary Mario Cimoli.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary Donfried’s Travel to the Western Balkans</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-donfrieds-travel-to-the-western-balkans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336402</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs Dr. Karen Donfried will travel to the Western Balkans from April 25 to 29, with stops in Albania, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Kosovo, Montenegro, North Macedonia, and Serbia.</p>
<p>On April 25, she will thank Kosovo for providing refuge to Afghans and Ukrainians, encourage work on reforms for democratic consolidation and integration into European and Euro-Atlantic institutions, and review prospects for progress in the U.S.-supported, EU-facilitated Dialogue with Serbia toward an agreement on normalized relations centered on mutual recognition.</p>
<p>She will travel to Serbia on April 26 to urge Serbia to advance reforms for its European integration, enhance regional stability and prosperity, discuss opportunities for further energy diversification, and broaden our bilateral security and economic ties.  She will reiterate the need for Serbia and Kosovo to reengage in the EU-facilitated Dialogue.</p>
<p>On April 27, in Bosnia and Herzegovina (BiH), Dr. Donfried will encourage officials to resume institutional participation at all levels of government to advance functionality and common-sense reforms for greater prosperity and for BiH to obtain EU candidate status.  She will urge BiH to hold fall elections on time and make progress in fighting endemic corruption.</p>
<p>In North Macedonia on April 28, she will meet with government leaders to signal our strong support for North Macedonia’s EU accession negotiations and thank them for their ongoing assistance to Ukraine. She will urge NATO’s newest member to continue close cooperation on a range of regional, security, and defense issues to promote democracy and regional stability.</p>
<p>On April 28 she will commemorate 100 years of U.S.-Albanian diplomatic relations and thank Albania for our partnership on the United Nations Security Council and for its commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Russian aggression.  She will also underscore our strong support for Albania&#8217;s EU accession and regional economic integration, as well as emphasize the need to fully implement justice reform and combat corruption.</p>
<p>Dr. Donfried will travel to Montenegro on April 29, where she will highlight U.S. support for and the need to accelerate work on Montenegro’s Euro-Atlantic path and EU accession, strengthening NATO membership, and on supporting shared values, including tackling corruption.  She will also thank Montenegro for joining EU sanctions on Russia in support of Ukraine, and for providing humanitarian and security assistance, as well as for closing its airspace to Russian aircraft.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs Dr. Karen Donfried will travel to the Western Balkans from April 25 to 29, with stops in Albania, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Kosovo, Montenegro, North Macedonia, and Serbia.</p>
<p>On April 25, she will thank Kosovo for providing refuge to Afghans and Ukrainians, encourage work on reforms for democratic consolidation and integration into European and Euro-Atlantic institutions, and review prospects for progress in the U.S.-supported, EU-facilitated Dialogue with Serbia toward an agreement on normalized relations centered on mutual recognition.</p>
<p>She will travel to Serbia on April 26 to urge Serbia to advance reforms for its European integration, enhance regional stability and prosperity, discuss opportunities for further energy diversification, and broaden our bilateral security and economic ties.  She will reiterate the need for Serbia and Kosovo to reengage in the EU-facilitated Dialogue.</p>
<p>On April 27, in Bosnia and Herzegovina (BiH), Dr. Donfried will encourage officials to resume institutional participation at all levels of government to advance functionality and common-sense reforms for greater prosperity and for BiH to obtain EU candidate status.  She will urge BiH to hold fall elections on time and make progress in fighting endemic corruption.</p>
<p>In North Macedonia on April 28, she will meet with government leaders to signal our strong support for North Macedonia’s EU accession negotiations and thank them for their ongoing assistance to Ukraine. She will urge NATO’s newest member to continue close cooperation on a range of regional, security, and defense issues to promote democracy and regional stability.</p>
<p>On April 28 she will commemorate 100 years of U.S.-Albanian diplomatic relations and thank Albania for our partnership on the United Nations Security Council and for its commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Russian aggression.  She will also underscore our strong support for Albania&#8217;s EU accession and regional economic integration, as well as emphasize the need to fully implement justice reform and combat corruption.</p>
<p>Dr. Donfried will travel to Montenegro on April 29, where she will highlight U.S. support for and the need to accelerate work on Montenegro’s Euro-Atlantic path and EU accession, strengthening NATO membership, and on supporting shared values, including tackling corruption.  She will also thank Montenegro for joining EU sanctions on Russia in support of Ukraine, and for providing humanitarian and security assistance, as well as for closing its airspace to Russian aircraft.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Third Senior-Level International Partners Meeting on Haiti</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/third-senior-level-international-partners-meeting-on-haiti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336396</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs, Brian A. Nichols, attended a senior-level international partners meeting on Haiti on April 21.  Hosted by France, this meeting convened international partner countries and international organizations for the third time in the past four months in support of progress on the challenges facing Haiti.  Participants encouraged political accord among Haitian actors so elections can take place as soon as conditions permit.</p>
<p>On April 1, the United States announced it would partner with Haiti through the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability, which complements our existing programming in Haiti.  As the international community encourages Haitian political actors, civil society, and other stakeholders to find consensus and reach a political accord, this is an opportune time for coordinating future support for security, good governance, democratic institutions, and elections.</p>
<p>This meeting also reaffirms our efforts in providing advisory support, training, and other resources to the Haitian National Police (HNP).  In addition to deploying additional trainers and refurbishing HNP training facilities, the United States has delivered 60 new vehicles to the HNP.  The United States is working with HNP leadership to develop an elite unit capable of high-impact arrests and anti-gang operations, as well as expand its community policing efforts to regain the trust of citizens in gang-affected neighborhoods.</p>
<p>We commend our partners who have also contributed to building the operational capacity of the HNP.  We continue to work with international partners and organizations to support Haiti’s response to complex security challenges.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs, Brian A. Nichols, attended a senior-level international partners meeting on Haiti on April 21.  Hosted by France, this meeting convened international partner countries and international organizations for the third time in the past four months in support of progress on the challenges facing Haiti.  Participants encouraged political accord among Haitian actors so elections can take place as soon as conditions permit.</p>
<p>On April 1, the United States announced it would partner with Haiti through the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability, which complements our existing programming in Haiti.  As the international community encourages Haitian political actors, civil society, and other stakeholders to find consensus and reach a political accord, this is an opportune time for coordinating future support for security, good governance, democratic institutions, and elections.</p>
<p>This meeting also reaffirms our efforts in providing advisory support, training, and other resources to the Haitian National Police (HNP).  In addition to deploying additional trainers and refurbishing HNP training facilities, the United States has delivered 60 new vehicles to the HNP.  The United States is working with HNP leadership to develop an elite unit capable of high-impact arrests and anti-gang operations, as well as expand its community policing efforts to regain the trust of citizens in gang-affected neighborhoods.</p>
<p>We commend our partners who have also contributed to building the operational capacity of the HNP.  We continue to work with international partners and organizations to support Haiti’s response to complex security challenges.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with French, German, Italian, and UK Counterparts</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-french-german-italian-and-uk-counterparts-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with French MFA Secretary General Francois Delattre, German MFA State Secretary Andreas Michaelis, Italian MFA Secretary General Ettore Sequi, and UK Minister of State for Europe and North America James Cleverly. Deputy Secretary Sherman condemned Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war of choice against Ukraine and its brutal tactics, including egregious atrocities. The participants discussed the importance of providing further military and humanitarian aid to Ukraine and to assist the millions who have been forced to leave their homes. They also discussed the imposition of additional sanctions and other economic measures to hold the Russian Federation accountable. All expressed concern over food security due to Russia’s war and pledged to work together to find solutions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with French MFA Secretary General Francois Delattre, German MFA State Secretary Andreas Michaelis, Italian MFA Secretary General Ettore Sequi, and UK Minister of State for Europe and North America James Cleverly. Deputy Secretary Sherman condemned Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war of choice against Ukraine and its brutal tactics, including egregious atrocities. The participants discussed the importance of providing further military and humanitarian aid to Ukraine and to assist the millions who have been forced to leave their homes. They also discussed the imposition of additional sanctions and other economic measures to hold the Russian Federation accountable. All expressed concern over food security due to Russia’s war and pledged to work together to find solutions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opening of U.S.-Czech Republic Defense Cooperation Agreement Negotiations</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/opening-of-u-s-czech-republic-defense-cooperation-agreement-negotiations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 16:17:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes <wbr />Czech Defense Minister Jana Černochová’s announcement today to begin negotiating a bilateral Defense Cooperation Agreement. When concluded, this agreement will deepen our close security partnership, further strengthen cooperation in NATO operations, and together, contribute to continued growth in Transatlantic security.</p>
<p>The agreement builds on the provisions of the NATO Status of Forces Agreement (SOFA) and is similar to other bilateral agreements the United States has concluded with other NATO Allies, including many of the Czech Republic’s neighbors along NATO’s Eastern Flank.  This agreement, when concluded, will help create an overarching framework to codify already existing cooperation between our two militaries, formalizing procedures, and providing a more transparent, predictable, and robust framework for both bilateral and enhanced NATO cooperation.</p>
<p>Our alliances are a tremendous source of American strength.  Since 1993, the United States and the Czech Republic have worked closely together on a wide range of issues important to both countries, the NATO Alliance, and the world.  Opening these consultations with the Czech Republic reflects our commitment to reaffirming and reinvigorating America’s alliances to meet common security challenges while protecting shared interests and values.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes <wbr />Czech Defense Minister Jana Černochová’s announcement today to begin negotiating a bilateral Defense Cooperation Agreement. When concluded, this agreement will deepen our close security partnership, further strengthen cooperation in NATO operations, and together, contribute to continued growth in Transatlantic security.</p>
<p>The agreement builds on the provisions of the NATO Status of Forces Agreement (SOFA) and is similar to other bilateral agreements the United States has concluded with other NATO Allies, including many of the Czech Republic’s neighbors along NATO’s Eastern Flank.  This agreement, when concluded, will help create an overarching framework to codify already existing cooperation between our two militaries, formalizing procedures, and providing a more transparent, predictable, and robust framework for both bilateral and enhanced NATO cooperation.</p>
<p>Our alliances are a tremendous source of American strength.  Since 1993, the United States and the Czech Republic have worked closely together on a wide range of issues important to both countries, the NATO Alliance, and the world.  Opening these consultations with the Czech Republic reflects our commitment to reaffirming and reinvigorating America’s alliances to meet common security challenges while protecting shared interests and values.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Yemeni Presidential Leadership Council President Al-Alimi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-yemeni-presidential-leadership-council-president-al-alimi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 16:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336316</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Yemeni Presidential Leadership Council President Dr. Rashad al-Alimi.  Secretary Blinken congratulated President al-Alimi on his new position and welcomed the gathering in Aden this week of the Council, Cabinet, House of Representatives, and Shura Council.  The Secretary underscored the importance of an effective and transparent government that advances efforts to end the Yemeni conflict and protects human rights.</p>
<p>The Secretary reaffirmed U.S. support for the ongoing truce and the opportunity to provide relief to Yemenis by easing the movement of people and goods, including fuel.  He further stressed the importance of opening roads to Taiz and other areas.  The Secretary underscored the need to seize the momentum from these positive developments to secure a lasting ceasefire and a comprehensive peace process.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Yemeni Presidential Leadership Council President Dr. Rashad al-Alimi.  Secretary Blinken congratulated President al-Alimi on his new position and welcomed the gathering in Aden this week of the Council, Cabinet, House of Representatives, and Shura Council.  The Secretary underscored the importance of an effective and transparent government that advances efforts to end the Yemeni conflict and protects human rights.</p>
<p>The Secretary reaffirmed U.S. support for the ongoing truce and the opportunity to provide relief to Yemenis by easing the movement of people and goods, including fuel.  He further stressed the importance of opening roads to Taiz and other areas.  The Secretary underscored the need to seize the momentum from these positive developments to secure a lasting ceasefire and a comprehensive peace process.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
