<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 20:52:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Israeli Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Lapid</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-israeli-foreign-minister-and-alternate-prime-minister-lapid-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 20:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321628</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today in Riga, Latvia with Israeli Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Yair Lapid to exchange views regarding how to stop the premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack by Putin’s military forces on Ukraine and its people as well as the urgent need for Russia to cease its aggression, allow for humanitarian corridors, and fully withdraw from Ukrainian territory.  They also discussed challenges posed by Iran, and both agreed that Iran must never be allowed to acquire a nuclear weapon.  Secretary Blinken reiterated the Administration’s ironclad commitment to Israel’s security.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today in Riga, Latvia with Israeli Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Yair Lapid to exchange views regarding how to stop the premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack by Putin’s military forces on Ukraine and its people as well as the urgent need for Russia to cease its aggression, allow for humanitarian corridors, and fully withdraw from Ukrainian territory.  They also discussed challenges posed by Iran, and both agreed that Iran must never be allowed to acquire a nuclear weapon.  Secretary Blinken reiterated the Administration’s ironclad commitment to Israel’s security.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Terrorist Designation of Katibat al Tawhid wal Jihad</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/terrorist-designation-of-katibat-al-tawhid-wal-jihad/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 19:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is committed to addressing terrorist activity in ungoverned spaces in Syria through the judicious use of our counterterrorism tools and constructive engagement with our partners.</p>
<p>In keeping with that commitment, the Department of State is designating Katibat al Tawhid wal Jihad (KTJ) as a Specially Designated Global Terrorist (SDGT) pursuant to Executive Order 13224, as amended. In addition to this SDGT designation, KTJ has also been added to the UNSC 1267/1989/2253/2610 ISIL (Da’esh) and Al-Qaida Sanctions List, requiring all UN member states to implement an assets freeze, a travel ban, and an arms embargo against KTJ.</p>
<p>Affiliated with al-Qa’ida, KTJ operates primarily in Idlib Province, Syria alongside Hay’at Tahrir al-Sham and cooperates with other designated terrorist groups such as Katibat al-Imam al-Bukhari and Islamic Jihad Group. In addition to engaging in terrorist activities in Syria, KTJ has also been responsible for conducting external attacks, such as the Saint Petersburg metro attack in April 2017 which killed 14 passengers and injured 50 others, as well as a suicide car bombing of the Chinese Embassy in Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan in August 2016 which wounded three people.</p>
<p>As a result of the SDGT designation, all property and interests in property of KTJ that are subject to U.S. jurisdiction are blocked, and U.S. persons are generally prohibited from engaging in any transactions with it. Foreign financial institutions that knowingly conduct or facilitate any significant transaction on behalf of KTJ could also be subject to U.S. sanctions.</p>
<p>Designations of terrorist individuals and groups expose and isolate them and deny them access to the resources they need to carry out attacks. Moreover, designations can assist the law enforcement actions of other U.S. agencies and governments.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is committed to addressing terrorist activity in ungoverned spaces in Syria through the judicious use of our counterterrorism tools and constructive engagement with our partners.</p>
<p>In keeping with that commitment, the Department of State is designating Katibat al Tawhid wal Jihad (KTJ) as a Specially Designated Global Terrorist (SDGT) pursuant to Executive Order 13224, as amended. In addition to this SDGT designation, KTJ has also been added to the UNSC 1267/1989/2253/2610 ISIL (Da’esh) and Al-Qaida Sanctions List, requiring all UN member states to implement an assets freeze, a travel ban, and an arms embargo against KTJ.</p>
<p>Affiliated with al-Qa’ida, KTJ operates primarily in Idlib Province, Syria alongside Hay’at Tahrir al-Sham and cooperates with other designated terrorist groups such as Katibat al-Imam al-Bukhari and Islamic Jihad Group. In addition to engaging in terrorist activities in Syria, KTJ has also been responsible for conducting external attacks, such as the Saint Petersburg metro attack in April 2017 which killed 14 passengers and injured 50 others, as well as a suicide car bombing of the Chinese Embassy in Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan in August 2016 which wounded three people.</p>
<p>As a result of the SDGT designation, all property and interests in property of KTJ that are subject to U.S. jurisdiction are blocked, and U.S. persons are generally prohibited from engaging in any transactions with it. Foreign financial institutions that knowingly conduct or facilitate any significant transaction on behalf of KTJ could also be subject to U.S. sanctions.</p>
<p>Designations of terrorist individuals and groups expose and isolate them and deny them access to the resources they need to carry out attacks. Moreover, designations can assist the law enforcement actions of other U.S. agencies and governments.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Israeli Foreign Minister Yair Lapid Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-israeli-foreign-minister-yair-lapid-before-their-meeting-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Yair Lapid, Israeli Foreign Minister]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 19:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321585</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Yair Lapid, Israeli Foreign Minister</p>
<p>Riga, Latvia</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LAPID:</b>  Okay, I’ll go first.  So I came here to meet with a friend and a partner in a moment in which world order is changing.  The war that is going on in the Ukraine – in Ukraine and the nuclear talks in Vienna are events that are changing the world as we know it.</p>
<p>And I want to thank the administration to you, my friend, for the leadership you have demonstrated in these days.  There is no real alternative to American leadership determined to prevent wars and bloodshed.</p>
<p>Israel is totally committed to do everything possible to stop the war in Ukraine.  We have condemned the Russian invasion, and we still do.  And Israel is a partner in the global effort to make sure and verify that this war must be stopped.</p>
<p>The way to stop a war is to negotiate.  Israel is speaking with both sides, both with Russia and Ukraine, and we are working in full coordination with our greatest ally, the United States, and with our European partners.  And we will also discuss the status of the nuclear talks in Vienna.  It’s no secret we have our differences on this, but it’s a conversation between allies that have a common goal, which is preventing Iran from becoming a nuclear threshold country, and to stop Iran’s ability to spread terror and instability around the world.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, thank you, Yair.  It’s great to see you anywhere – in Israel, in the United States, anywhere in between – and we’ve met on a few occasions in different places.  And very much appreciate all of your engagement in the effort to stop this Russian aggression in Ukraine, a war that has already done tremendous damage to Ukraine, to its people, that continues as we speak with more than a million and a half people having fled the country because of the Russian war of choice, and so many more who are in danger at this moment.  People killed, people injured.</p>
<p>So it’s imperative that this war come to an end, and Russia has to end it because it started it with no provocation, unwarranted, and – but also premeditated.  So we very much appreciate the efforts that any of our close partners and friends and allies can make to see if there is any opening to end the war, consistent, of course, with the principles that we’ve all established, starting with the Ukrainian Government and the Ukrainian people, who must have their sovereignty, their independence, and their territorial integrity.</p>
<p>So I look forward to hearing your ideas, hearing about some of the engagements that Israel has had, but we appreciate all efforts by friends and allies to look for a diplomatic resolution.  That’s clearly – that’s always been preferable, from the start.  Unfortunately, Russia chose not to pursue the path of diplomacy.  It chose aggression, and now we have to all contend with that.</p>
<p>And I also look forward to speaking to you about, in the time we have, some of the other issues and challenges that we’re facing together.  And we’re united and committed to the proposition that Iran must never obtain a nuclear weapon, and I look forward to bringing you up to date on the latest on where we are on the talks with the Europeans, the Iranians, Russia, and China on the JCPOA.</p>
<p>So it’s great to see you, and thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Yair Lapid, Israeli Foreign Minister</p>
<p>Riga, Latvia</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LAPID:</b>  Okay, I’ll go first.  So I came here to meet with a friend and a partner in a moment in which world order is changing.  The war that is going on in the Ukraine – in Ukraine and the nuclear talks in Vienna are events that are changing the world as we know it.</p>
<p>And I want to thank the administration to you, my friend, for the leadership you have demonstrated in these days.  There is no real alternative to American leadership determined to prevent wars and bloodshed.</p>
<p>Israel is totally committed to do everything possible to stop the war in Ukraine.  We have condemned the Russian invasion, and we still do.  And Israel is a partner in the global effort to make sure and verify that this war must be stopped.</p>
<p>The way to stop a war is to negotiate.  Israel is speaking with both sides, both with Russia and Ukraine, and we are working in full coordination with our greatest ally, the United States, and with our European partners.  And we will also discuss the status of the nuclear talks in Vienna.  It’s no secret we have our differences on this, but it’s a conversation between allies that have a common goal, which is preventing Iran from becoming a nuclear threshold country, and to stop Iran’s ability to spread terror and instability around the world.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, thank you, Yair.  It’s great to see you anywhere – in Israel, in the United States, anywhere in between – and we’ve met on a few occasions in different places.  And very much appreciate all of your engagement in the effort to stop this Russian aggression in Ukraine, a war that has already done tremendous damage to Ukraine, to its people, that continues as we speak with more than a million and a half people having fled the country because of the Russian war of choice, and so many more who are in danger at this moment.  People killed, people injured.</p>
<p>So it’s imperative that this war come to an end, and Russia has to end it because it started it with no provocation, unwarranted, and – but also premeditated.  So we very much appreciate the efforts that any of our close partners and friends and allies can make to see if there is any opening to end the war, consistent, of course, with the principles that we’ve all established, starting with the Ukrainian Government and the Ukrainian people, who must have their sovereignty, their independence, and their territorial integrity.</p>
<p>So I look forward to hearing your ideas, hearing about some of the engagements that Israel has had, but we appreciate all efforts by friends and allies to look for a diplomatic resolution.  That’s clearly – that’s always been preferable, from the start.  Unfortunately, Russia chose not to pursue the path of diplomacy.  It chose aggression, and now we have to all contend with that.</p>
<p>And I also look forward to speaking to you about, in the time we have, some of the other issues and challenges that we’re facing together.  And we’re united and committed to the proposition that Iran must never obtain a nuclear weapon, and I look forward to bringing you up to date on the latest on where we are on the talks with the Europeans, the Iranians, Russia, and China on the JCPOA.</p>
<p>So it’s great to see you, and thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the Strategic Dialogue between the United States and Austria</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-the-strategic-dialogue-between-the-united-states-and-austria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 18:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321563</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and the Republic of Austria on the occasion of the U.S.-Austria Strategic Dialogue.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The Governments of the United States and Austria held the U.S.-Austria Strategic Dialogue in Washington, D.C. on March 3, 2022, which included virtual consultations between Austrian Secretary General for Foreign Affairs Peter Launsky-Tieffenthal and U.S. Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman.</p>
<p>The United States and Austria, also in its capacity as a member state of the European Union, are dedicated to deepening the Transatlantic relationship and strengthening our commitment to our shared values of advancing democracy and human rights and condemning Russia’s unjustified, unprovoked and premeditated war against Ukraine, including through multilateral action at the United Nations. Both parties expressed firm dedication to the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine. We acknowledge the European aspirations of Ukraine, welcome its European choice, and support its political association and economic integration with the EU. The United States and Austria support the democratic aspirations of the Belarusian people. We fully support the objective of European integration of the Western Balkan countries.</p>
<p>In the framework of our Strategic Partnership, the United States and Austria emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Austria relationship in addressing Transatlantic issues. The Strategic Dialogue in Washington, D.C. focused on common interests and shared values, reaffirming the dedicated bilateral relationship between the United States and Austria and our joint commitment to enhance cooperation on a broad range of topics, such as establishing a civil society dialogue and fostering educational and people-to-people exchanges.</p>
<p>Topics discussed during the Strategic Dialogue included global and regional security issues, including Russia’s attack on Ukraine; the Western Balkans; energy security, including climate change; economic prosperity; and strengthening democratic values and institutions through the OSCE in Europe and Eurasia and in our own countries. The United States and Austria highlighted their common concern about ongoing disregard for the Helsinki Final Act by Russia and Belarus and consulted on the importance of the OSCE in reaching diplomatic resolutions to regional conflicts. Concerning the ongoing Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA) negotiations, both sides reaffirmed the need to come to a swift conclusion. The United States thanked Austria for hosting the JCPOA talks.</p>
<p>The Strategic Dialogue was hosted by the U.S. Department of State and included interagency and inter-ministerial representatives from both governments. The meeting featured senior U.S. representatives from the Department of State, the Department of the Treasury, and the Department of Commerce, and from the Austrian side, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and the Ministry of Finance.</p>
<p>Both sides expressed a strong interest in continuing and deepening the bilateral strategic partnership. The parties plan to hold the next meeting in Vienna in the first half of 2023.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and the Republic of Austria on the occasion of the U.S.-Austria Strategic Dialogue.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The Governments of the United States and Austria held the U.S.-Austria Strategic Dialogue in Washington, D.C. on March 3, 2022, which included virtual consultations between Austrian Secretary General for Foreign Affairs Peter Launsky-Tieffenthal and U.S. Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman.</p>
<p>The United States and Austria, also in its capacity as a member state of the European Union, are dedicated to deepening the Transatlantic relationship and strengthening our commitment to our shared values of advancing democracy and human rights and condemning Russia’s unjustified, unprovoked and premeditated war against Ukraine, including through multilateral action at the United Nations. Both parties expressed firm dedication to the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine. We acknowledge the European aspirations of Ukraine, welcome its European choice, and support its political association and economic integration with the EU. The United States and Austria support the democratic aspirations of the Belarusian people. We fully support the objective of European integration of the Western Balkan countries.</p>
<p>In the framework of our Strategic Partnership, the United States and Austria emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Austria relationship in addressing Transatlantic issues. The Strategic Dialogue in Washington, D.C. focused on common interests and shared values, reaffirming the dedicated bilateral relationship between the United States and Austria and our joint commitment to enhance cooperation on a broad range of topics, such as establishing a civil society dialogue and fostering educational and people-to-people exchanges.</p>
<p>Topics discussed during the Strategic Dialogue included global and regional security issues, including Russia’s attack on Ukraine; the Western Balkans; energy security, including climate change; economic prosperity; and strengthening democratic values and institutions through the OSCE in Europe and Eurasia and in our own countries. The United States and Austria highlighted their common concern about ongoing disregard for the Helsinki Final Act by Russia and Belarus and consulted on the importance of the OSCE in reaching diplomatic resolutions to regional conflicts. Concerning the ongoing Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA) negotiations, both sides reaffirmed the need to come to a swift conclusion. The United States thanked Austria for hosting the JCPOA talks.</p>
<p>The Strategic Dialogue was hosted by the U.S. Department of State and included interagency and inter-ministerial representatives from both governments. The meeting featured senior U.S. representatives from the Department of State, the Department of the Treasury, and the Department of Commerce, and from the Austrian side, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and the Ministry of Finance.</p>
<p>Both sides expressed a strong interest in continuing and deepening the bilateral strategic partnership. The parties plan to hold the next meeting in Vienna in the first half of 2023.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken and Latvian Foreign Minister Edgars Rinkēvičs at a Joint Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-of-state-antony-j-blinken-and-latvian-foreign-minister-edgars-rinkevics-at-a-joint-press-availability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Edgars Rinkēvičs, Latvian Foreign Minister]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 18:34:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321558</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Edgars Rinkēvičs, Latvian Foreign Minister</p>
<p>Riga, Latvia</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER RINKĒVIČS:</b>  (Via Interpreter)  Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen.  And indeed, today I had the honor to welcome my U.S. counterpart here in the National Museum of Latvia, Mr. Blinken.  When we met last time in December, when the foreign ministers of NATO countries met here in Riga, we couldn’t have imagined we would meet so soon again.  It is always, of course, a big pleasure to meet with our American friends, but we are currently meeting in very grave circumstances, and we discussed a broad range of issues – of course, primarily our support and assistance to Ukraine.</p>
<p>I reassured my American colleague of Latvia’s commitment to continue providing all kinds of support and help in close cooperation with our allies and the United States of America.  We also talked about more efficient ways of countering Russian aggression.  We also discussed potential timing of sanctions.  But sanctions are not – not only have to be imposed, but they also have to be efficient.  We agreed on exchange of information to identify all oligarch properties, all accounts, all properties, all assets, all kinds of real estate, and movable property.  And transatlantic bonded cooperation is absolutely essential in this regard, and we will continue working with our colleagues in the EU as well as in the United States on further sanctions.</p>
<p>We also talked about further reinforcement of the eastern flank of NATO, reinforcement or strengthening of the regional security of Baltic countries.  I would like to thank the United States, Canada, Spain, other Allies, who are already contributing to our security and have contributed additionally to our security more recently.</p>
<p>Of course, looking at the most recent developments, we are very happy about the permanent presence of U.S. forces here in Latvia.  We have no illusions about Putin’s Russia anymore.  I don’t really see any reason, any good reason, to assume that Russia might change its policy.</p>
<p>Before I hand it over to my colleague, I would like to also underline that we – NATO also supports journalists and media, media in Russia and Belarus, who represent free, independent media, not only by helping them leave their country and also facilitating their work here or outside Belarus and Russia.  It is important to make sure that Russian residents, Russians living in other countries, have access to impartial information, unbiased information, and not from Russian propaganda channels.  And we also agreed to cooperate on that as well.</p>
<p>That is as far as my introduction goes.  Now I’d like to hand it over to Antony Blinken.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Edgars, thank you very, very much.  And to be – it’s always good to be back, but I wish it was under different circumstances.  We remember well the extraordinary job you did, Latvia did, in hosting us and hosting our NATO colleagues.  And that spirit very much is (inaudible) all the work we’ve been doing together in recent weeks, particularly the work that’s been made necessary by Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>I should note that we’re here now in what is the 100th anniversary year of diplomatic relations between the United States and Latvia.  When we were here (inaudible) NATO (inaudible), I reflected at the time on how strong the partnership between our countries has grown, especially in the last 30 years, since Latvia’s independence, rooted in a shared commitment to democracy, to human rights, to the rule of law.  And I said that while those principles could feel a little bit abstract at times, we were seeing serious challenges to them by autocratic governments that were seeking to erode the international rules-based order that is so essential to peace and security.  Well, that abstraction has become, unfortunately, three months later a very powerful reality.  And any question of how vital it is that we protect those values I think has been put to rest.</p>
<p>Since Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine began, hundreds of civilians have been killed, hundreds more wounded.  As it is today, more than 1.5 million people, mostly women and children, have had to flee Ukraine, flee their homes.  Many more people are trying to flee, but they cannot get out of besieged areas.  In the last several days, more strikes have killed and wounded civilians as they try to leave the cities that are being surrounded by Russian forces.  Women and children, the elderly, wounded civilians, people with disabilities, are trying to escape cities where there’s no heat, no electricity, relentless bombardment, and where they’re running out of food and medicine.  And there continue to be reports of attacks by Russian forces on agreed-upon humanitarian corridors.</p>
<p>We’ve seen scenes like this before in Europe.  Every Russian has lived or learned about the horrific siege of Leningrad during World War II, in which that city’s civilian population was systematically starved and intentionally destroyed over nearly 900 days, leading to hundreds of thousands of deaths.  That siege affected millions of Russian families, including President Putin’s, whose one-year-old brother was one of the many victims.  Now, Russia is starving out cities like Mariupol.  It’s shameful.  The world is saying to Russia:  Stop these attacks immediately.  Let the food and medicine in.  Let the people out safely, and end this war of choice against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Latvians who lived through decades of Soviet occupation understand deeply how wrong this is, and how the world must defend Ukraine’s right to exist as a sovereign, democratic country, free to choose its own future.  Latvia has done just that.  It quickly provided security assistance to Ukraine, including Stinger missiles, anti-tank weapons, small arms, ammunition, protective gear, medical supplies.  And the Latvian people have stepped forward as well with an outpouring of humanitarian donations, a pledge to welcome more than 10,000 refugees from Ukraine into their homes and into their communities.</p>
<p>Latvia and the United States, together with our allies and partners, will continue to stand with Ukraine.  We’re surging our security assistance to strengthen Ukraine’s capacity to defend itself.  We’re increasing humanitarian aid to the Ukrainian people, both those still inside Ukraine and those who have had to flee.  We’re raising costs on the Kremlin, and all who aid and enable it, for continuing this war.</p>
<p>We’re also bolstering our shared defense.  We and our NATO Allies are prepared to meet any threat.  President Biden spoke to the American people just a few days ago in his State of the Union address, and he made clear again something he’s affirmed repeatedly:  We will defend every inch of NATO territory against aggression coming from anywhere at any time.  Our commitment to Article 5 – an attack on one is an attack on all – is ironclad.  The President has called it sacrosanct.  And no one – no one – should have any doubt about that.</p>
<p>NATO activated our defense plans for the eastern flank for the first time in history, giving the Supreme Allied Commander Europe authority to deploy the NATO response force as needed.  Many Allies have increased their troop presence and contributed additional equipment and capabilities to this effort.  President Biden ordered the deployment of an additional 7,000 U.S. troops to Europe, and moved forces already in Europe to NATO’s eastern flank, including to Latvia.</p>
<p>We now have more than a thousand U.S. soldiers here in Latvia.  We’ll continue to rotate our forces to Latvia and the Baltic region to train alongside the NATO-enhanced forward presence battle group led by Canada in partnership with Latvia’s armed forces.  And we deployed F-35 strike fighter jets to the region to augment NATO’s enhanced air policing mission.</p>
<p>We’re also working with Latvia and multi-partners on security in other realms: cybersecurity to protect critical infrastructure against malicious actors, and energy security so that Latvia’s energy supply is not dependent upon Russia.</p>
<p>Latvia hosts the NATO Strategic Communications Centre of Excellence, a critical resource in this time of information warfare, something Edgars and I talked about, and we’re working together to support independent media to push back against disinformation, including by helping young people to be able to identify it.  Our collaboration in these areas is, quite simply, more important than ever, and I look forward to continuing that.</p>
<p>This is my second stop in a visit to all three Baltic countries.  Over the past 30 years, the Baltics have formed a democratic wall that is now standing against the tide of autocracy that Moscow is seeking to push further into Europe.  And my message on behalf of the United States to the people of Latvia, to all of the Baltics, is that the United States is more committed than ever to standing with you as our democracies rise to the challenge of this moment.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s very moving to see the blue and yellow colors of the Ukrainian flag in this city, in Lithuania where I just came from, on public monuments, homes, schools, businesses.  The incredibly brave and resilient Ukrainian people will fight for as long as it takes for their country.  I know and they know that they can count on the support of Latvia, the United States, and many countries in Europe and around the world.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  You will be needing your interpreting &#8212;</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) Now we move to questions and answers and Latvian Television, Ina Strazdina.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  (Via interpreter) Thank you for this opportunity.  Ina Strazdina, Latvian Television.  I would like to ask Mr. Rinkēvičs, first of all:  You already mentioned this – the possibility of having troops in Latvia, standing.  Have you discussed it with Mr. Blinken, the possibility to increase the troops here in Latvia, and have permanently deployed American soldiers here in Latvia?  And what was the answer given to you?</p>
<p>And the question to Mr. Blinken, closing the skies.  This is what Ukraine is demanding very intensively.  NATO has provided its explanation that it would complicate the situation even more, turning this into large-scale war.  But you have also said that the countries have been given green light to give planes to the states.  And Poland was mentioned, that you had offered substitute fleet to Poland if it offered its planes to Ukraine, but the answer is not clear.  What would be the practical solution to this, practical assistance to Ukraine in defending its sky?</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER RINKĒVIČS:</b>  (Via interpreter) I have to say, thank you for the question.  Indeed, we discussed the matter of how to reinforce the presence of NATO forces and also of the United States as part of NATO here in the region.  And I underscored that I would like to have permanent solutions to this thing.  This situation is developing.</p>
<p>And of course, my colleague – because it wouldn’t be right to re-tell the opinion of the United States’ Secretary of State, he will state his (inaudible) himself (inaudible) the ministry of foreign affairs and defense are preparing for NATO summit in Madrid, preparing the new strategic concept, responding to the changing in the situation.  We are going to work on what Antony said to have effective protection of all NATO states, what with the measures that would be needed, and the presence should be as long as it is necessary while, of course, as constant Putin’s regime is, as constant this presence is going to be, and even beyond it, perhaps.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you, and I very much agree with what Edgars has said.  Just a couple of things in response to questions.</p>
<p>First, as I noted, we have and NATO has already significantly reinforced the eastern flank, including right here in Latvia with the addition of forces, with the addition of equipment, with the addition of the F-35 strike fighter planes.  We’re doing this in close partnership with NATO Allies.  Canada, of course, is playing a lead role here in Latvia.</p>
<p>We also are on a regular basis reviewing our global posture, and that will continue.  And of course, as we do that, we have to factor in the latest developments, including this aggression from Russia.  So all of that will factor into our thinking, into our decisions about what we do going forward.  And of course, we’re working all of these issues within the NATO Alliance.  That’s vital as well.</p>
<p>Second, it’s very important to note everything that has been done, and continues to be done, to help the Ukrainians defend themselves.  Over the last year, the United States has provided more than a billion dollars in security assistance to Ukraine.  Just within the last couple of weeks, President Biden created the authority to provide an additional $350 million in defense support to Ukraine.  And within a week, most of that – about 70 percent – is already in the hands of Ukrainians, being used very effectively against Russian aggression.</p>
<p>A few days ago, the President made a request of our Congress for emergency aid of $10 billion.  And that $10 billion, which I believe Congress will provide very quickly, will go to additional security assistance for Ukraine.  It will go to humanitarian assistance for Ukraine, both inside Ukraine and outside.  And it will go to further efforts to reinforce NATO’s eastern flank.</p>
<p>So all of that is ongoing.  And as Edgars said, what we are focused on is what can we do to continue to help the Ukrainians be as effective as possible in what they’re doing, which is defending their country against this Russian aggression.  That’s what we’re focused on and our military experts are focused on.</p>
<p>I’ve talked about and the secretary general of NATO has talked about the question of the no-fly zone before.  And just to be clear and to repeat where we are: our efforts are all in the direction of ending this war as quickly as possible, ending the suffering as quickly as possible.  And what we don’t want to do is to widen it, and to widen it to our own countries, to our own territory.  The no-fly zone, to be very clear about what that involves, is – that means that if a Russian plane violate the zone as declared, we shoot them down.  And that runs the considerable risk of creating a direct conflict between our countries and Russia, and thus a wider war, which is in no one’s interest, including in the interest of the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p>But – and I want to repeat this very clearly – when it comes to any aggression of any kind against NATO territory by Russia or anyone else for that matter, we are absolutely committed to the defense of that territory – every square inch.  President Biden has made that repeatedly clear that as well.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  <i>Wall Street Journal, </i>William Mauldin.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Thank you very much for doing this.  For Minister Rinkēvičs, you mentioned effective protection is needed for Latvia and the Baltic countries.  What constitutes effective protection?  Did you ask for any to – any new types of military hardware or other support?  And did that include anti-aircraft systems?  And did the U.S. seem willing to provide it?</p>
<p>I also wanted to ask Secretary Blinken:  You have upcoming meetings with Foreign Minister Lapid of Israel, with President Macron of France.  What role does Israel play, especially in any possible mediation or engagement with Russia, during this conflict?  And do you have any message to send to Russia other than the general need to de-escalate or stop fighting in Ukraine?</p>
<p>And then just to clarify one thing you said earlier in Vilnius, you mentioned more permanent basing of troops here.  Does that mean there is a decision or there isn’t a decision to base troops permanently here in the Baltics countries, specifically?  And – because there was a little bit of ambiguity with that, and so I’m just very curious.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER RINKĒVIČS:  </b>Thank you very much.  I’ll answer in English.  Well, yes, indeed, we discussed the further steps when it comes to providing additional protection.  And we see the need and we are also learning from what is happening in Ukraine.  We are seeing what Russians are doing and we understand that we need to bolster our air defense.  That’s absolutely clear.  We also feel that we need to bolster our coastal defense, cyber defense.  And we are discussing and talking not only with the Secretary of State, but also with the Secretary of Defense.  We see the willingness to work with us, and to look into the needs.  And of course, that requires some process, but I’m pretty confident that there is understanding about the need to work together and to address some of those issues.</p>
<p>But let me also mention another thing that is equally important than defense, and that’s energy.  I think that what we all understand that we need to work, and it is not only Latvia or Lithuania or Estonia – that’s entire European Union, Europe as a whole.  We need to work to reduce dependency on Russian gas and oil.  We discussed at some length and detail also what could be done.  And I say that here, the United States can play a critical role, and we are willing to continue.  And this region is connecting from Russia, the Russian electricity grid, and connecting to European electricity grid.  Some work is being done.  And also that means, of course, reducing dependency of gas.  But here we need a bit wider effort through LNG, through renewable energy issues.</p>
<p>So I would put now military defense and energy defense on an equal footing, and also the cyber defense, so three areas.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Did you ask for anti-aircraft assistance from NATO?</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER RINKĒVIČS:  </b>We do work on those issues, yes, we do work.  But I think that we will not go into details before there are more substantial efforts.  And we are working through NATO and with our partners on some additional needs that we see we need.  And I’m very glad that both NATO and our partners are addressing those challenges seriously.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Will, first, on the last part of your question, just to be clear – and I’m sorry if I wasn’t before, earlier today – as I said and as I just mentioned again now, we’re on a regular basis reviewing the global posture of our forces, to include of course here in Europe.  And we have to factor in any developments, any changes in the threat – and we will do that.  And when it comes to questions such as permanent basing, these questions come up and we’ll certainly look to answer them in the context of doing the review of our of our posture.  But just to be very clear, no, there’s no decision of that kind.  I was just saying that this is a question that’s come up, and we’ll, in the context of doing reviews of our posture in Europe and elsewhere, be looking at that.</p>
<p>Second, with regard to the meetings, I’ll – I’m not going to get ahead of them.  I’ll let them more or less speak for themselves, once I’ve had the chance to actually compare notes with my friend Yair Lapid later this evening here, and then with President Macron tomorrow in France.  But I think there is – there’s certainly no change in our message to Moscow, our message to Russia, to President Putin:  End the war.  End it now.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary of State, Your Excellency Minister, dear media representatives.  This concludes our press conference.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Edgars Rinkēvičs, Latvian Foreign Minister</p>
<p>Riga, Latvia</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER RINKĒVIČS:</b>  (Via Interpreter)  Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen.  And indeed, today I had the honor to welcome my U.S. counterpart here in the National Museum of Latvia, Mr. Blinken.  When we met last time in December, when the foreign ministers of NATO countries met here in Riga, we couldn’t have imagined we would meet so soon again.  It is always, of course, a big pleasure to meet with our American friends, but we are currently meeting in very grave circumstances, and we discussed a broad range of issues – of course, primarily our support and assistance to Ukraine.</p>
<p>I reassured my American colleague of Latvia’s commitment to continue providing all kinds of support and help in close cooperation with our allies and the United States of America.  We also talked about more efficient ways of countering Russian aggression.  We also discussed potential timing of sanctions.  But sanctions are not – not only have to be imposed, but they also have to be efficient.  We agreed on exchange of information to identify all oligarch properties, all accounts, all properties, all assets, all kinds of real estate, and movable property.  And transatlantic bonded cooperation is absolutely essential in this regard, and we will continue working with our colleagues in the EU as well as in the United States on further sanctions.</p>
<p>We also talked about further reinforcement of the eastern flank of NATO, reinforcement or strengthening of the regional security of Baltic countries.  I would like to thank the United States, Canada, Spain, other Allies, who are already contributing to our security and have contributed additionally to our security more recently.</p>
<p>Of course, looking at the most recent developments, we are very happy about the permanent presence of U.S. forces here in Latvia.  We have no illusions about Putin’s Russia anymore.  I don’t really see any reason, any good reason, to assume that Russia might change its policy.</p>
<p>Before I hand it over to my colleague, I would like to also underline that we – NATO also supports journalists and media, media in Russia and Belarus, who represent free, independent media, not only by helping them leave their country and also facilitating their work here or outside Belarus and Russia.  It is important to make sure that Russian residents, Russians living in other countries, have access to impartial information, unbiased information, and not from Russian propaganda channels.  And we also agreed to cooperate on that as well.</p>
<p>That is as far as my introduction goes.  Now I’d like to hand it over to Antony Blinken.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Edgars, thank you very, very much.  And to be – it’s always good to be back, but I wish it was under different circumstances.  We remember well the extraordinary job you did, Latvia did, in hosting us and hosting our NATO colleagues.  And that spirit very much is (inaudible) all the work we’ve been doing together in recent weeks, particularly the work that’s been made necessary by Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>I should note that we’re here now in what is the 100th anniversary year of diplomatic relations between the United States and Latvia.  When we were here (inaudible) NATO (inaudible), I reflected at the time on how strong the partnership between our countries has grown, especially in the last 30 years, since Latvia’s independence, rooted in a shared commitment to democracy, to human rights, to the rule of law.  And I said that while those principles could feel a little bit abstract at times, we were seeing serious challenges to them by autocratic governments that were seeking to erode the international rules-based order that is so essential to peace and security.  Well, that abstraction has become, unfortunately, three months later a very powerful reality.  And any question of how vital it is that we protect those values I think has been put to rest.</p>
<p>Since Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine began, hundreds of civilians have been killed, hundreds more wounded.  As it is today, more than 1.5 million people, mostly women and children, have had to flee Ukraine, flee their homes.  Many more people are trying to flee, but they cannot get out of besieged areas.  In the last several days, more strikes have killed and wounded civilians as they try to leave the cities that are being surrounded by Russian forces.  Women and children, the elderly, wounded civilians, people with disabilities, are trying to escape cities where there’s no heat, no electricity, relentless bombardment, and where they’re running out of food and medicine.  And there continue to be reports of attacks by Russian forces on agreed-upon humanitarian corridors.</p>
<p>We’ve seen scenes like this before in Europe.  Every Russian has lived or learned about the horrific siege of Leningrad during World War II, in which that city’s civilian population was systematically starved and intentionally destroyed over nearly 900 days, leading to hundreds of thousands of deaths.  That siege affected millions of Russian families, including President Putin’s, whose one-year-old brother was one of the many victims.  Now, Russia is starving out cities like Mariupol.  It’s shameful.  The world is saying to Russia:  Stop these attacks immediately.  Let the food and medicine in.  Let the people out safely, and end this war of choice against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Latvians who lived through decades of Soviet occupation understand deeply how wrong this is, and how the world must defend Ukraine’s right to exist as a sovereign, democratic country, free to choose its own future.  Latvia has done just that.  It quickly provided security assistance to Ukraine, including Stinger missiles, anti-tank weapons, small arms, ammunition, protective gear, medical supplies.  And the Latvian people have stepped forward as well with an outpouring of humanitarian donations, a pledge to welcome more than 10,000 refugees from Ukraine into their homes and into their communities.</p>
<p>Latvia and the United States, together with our allies and partners, will continue to stand with Ukraine.  We’re surging our security assistance to strengthen Ukraine’s capacity to defend itself.  We’re increasing humanitarian aid to the Ukrainian people, both those still inside Ukraine and those who have had to flee.  We’re raising costs on the Kremlin, and all who aid and enable it, for continuing this war.</p>
<p>We’re also bolstering our shared defense.  We and our NATO Allies are prepared to meet any threat.  President Biden spoke to the American people just a few days ago in his State of the Union address, and he made clear again something he’s affirmed repeatedly:  We will defend every inch of NATO territory against aggression coming from anywhere at any time.  Our commitment to Article 5 – an attack on one is an attack on all – is ironclad.  The President has called it sacrosanct.  And no one – no one – should have any doubt about that.</p>
<p>NATO activated our defense plans for the eastern flank for the first time in history, giving the Supreme Allied Commander Europe authority to deploy the NATO response force as needed.  Many Allies have increased their troop presence and contributed additional equipment and capabilities to this effort.  President Biden ordered the deployment of an additional 7,000 U.S. troops to Europe, and moved forces already in Europe to NATO’s eastern flank, including to Latvia.</p>
<p>We now have more than a thousand U.S. soldiers here in Latvia.  We’ll continue to rotate our forces to Latvia and the Baltic region to train alongside the NATO-enhanced forward presence battle group led by Canada in partnership with Latvia’s armed forces.  And we deployed F-35 strike fighter jets to the region to augment NATO’s enhanced air policing mission.</p>
<p>We’re also working with Latvia and multi-partners on security in other realms: cybersecurity to protect critical infrastructure against malicious actors, and energy security so that Latvia’s energy supply is not dependent upon Russia.</p>
<p>Latvia hosts the NATO Strategic Communications Centre of Excellence, a critical resource in this time of information warfare, something Edgars and I talked about, and we’re working together to support independent media to push back against disinformation, including by helping young people to be able to identify it.  Our collaboration in these areas is, quite simply, more important than ever, and I look forward to continuing that.</p>
<p>This is my second stop in a visit to all three Baltic countries.  Over the past 30 years, the Baltics have formed a democratic wall that is now standing against the tide of autocracy that Moscow is seeking to push further into Europe.  And my message on behalf of the United States to the people of Latvia, to all of the Baltics, is that the United States is more committed than ever to standing with you as our democracies rise to the challenge of this moment.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s very moving to see the blue and yellow colors of the Ukrainian flag in this city, in Lithuania where I just came from, on public monuments, homes, schools, businesses.  The incredibly brave and resilient Ukrainian people will fight for as long as it takes for their country.  I know and they know that they can count on the support of Latvia, the United States, and many countries in Europe and around the world.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  You will be needing your interpreting &#8212;</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) Now we move to questions and answers and Latvian Television, Ina Strazdina.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  (Via interpreter) Thank you for this opportunity.  Ina Strazdina, Latvian Television.  I would like to ask Mr. Rinkēvičs, first of all:  You already mentioned this – the possibility of having troops in Latvia, standing.  Have you discussed it with Mr. Blinken, the possibility to increase the troops here in Latvia, and have permanently deployed American soldiers here in Latvia?  And what was the answer given to you?</p>
<p>And the question to Mr. Blinken, closing the skies.  This is what Ukraine is demanding very intensively.  NATO has provided its explanation that it would complicate the situation even more, turning this into large-scale war.  But you have also said that the countries have been given green light to give planes to the states.  And Poland was mentioned, that you had offered substitute fleet to Poland if it offered its planes to Ukraine, but the answer is not clear.  What would be the practical solution to this, practical assistance to Ukraine in defending its sky?</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER RINKĒVIČS:</b>  (Via interpreter) I have to say, thank you for the question.  Indeed, we discussed the matter of how to reinforce the presence of NATO forces and also of the United States as part of NATO here in the region.  And I underscored that I would like to have permanent solutions to this thing.  This situation is developing.</p>
<p>And of course, my colleague – because it wouldn’t be right to re-tell the opinion of the United States’ Secretary of State, he will state his (inaudible) himself (inaudible) the ministry of foreign affairs and defense are preparing for NATO summit in Madrid, preparing the new strategic concept, responding to the changing in the situation.  We are going to work on what Antony said to have effective protection of all NATO states, what with the measures that would be needed, and the presence should be as long as it is necessary while, of course, as constant Putin’s regime is, as constant this presence is going to be, and even beyond it, perhaps.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you, and I very much agree with what Edgars has said.  Just a couple of things in response to questions.</p>
<p>First, as I noted, we have and NATO has already significantly reinforced the eastern flank, including right here in Latvia with the addition of forces, with the addition of equipment, with the addition of the F-35 strike fighter planes.  We’re doing this in close partnership with NATO Allies.  Canada, of course, is playing a lead role here in Latvia.</p>
<p>We also are on a regular basis reviewing our global posture, and that will continue.  And of course, as we do that, we have to factor in the latest developments, including this aggression from Russia.  So all of that will factor into our thinking, into our decisions about what we do going forward.  And of course, we’re working all of these issues within the NATO Alliance.  That’s vital as well.</p>
<p>Second, it’s very important to note everything that has been done, and continues to be done, to help the Ukrainians defend themselves.  Over the last year, the United States has provided more than a billion dollars in security assistance to Ukraine.  Just within the last couple of weeks, President Biden created the authority to provide an additional $350 million in defense support to Ukraine.  And within a week, most of that – about 70 percent – is already in the hands of Ukrainians, being used very effectively against Russian aggression.</p>
<p>A few days ago, the President made a request of our Congress for emergency aid of $10 billion.  And that $10 billion, which I believe Congress will provide very quickly, will go to additional security assistance for Ukraine.  It will go to humanitarian assistance for Ukraine, both inside Ukraine and outside.  And it will go to further efforts to reinforce NATO’s eastern flank.</p>
<p>So all of that is ongoing.  And as Edgars said, what we are focused on is what can we do to continue to help the Ukrainians be as effective as possible in what they’re doing, which is defending their country against this Russian aggression.  That’s what we’re focused on and our military experts are focused on.</p>
<p>I’ve talked about and the secretary general of NATO has talked about the question of the no-fly zone before.  And just to be clear and to repeat where we are: our efforts are all in the direction of ending this war as quickly as possible, ending the suffering as quickly as possible.  And what we don’t want to do is to widen it, and to widen it to our own countries, to our own territory.  The no-fly zone, to be very clear about what that involves, is – that means that if a Russian plane violate the zone as declared, we shoot them down.  And that runs the considerable risk of creating a direct conflict between our countries and Russia, and thus a wider war, which is in no one’s interest, including in the interest of the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p>But – and I want to repeat this very clearly – when it comes to any aggression of any kind against NATO territory by Russia or anyone else for that matter, we are absolutely committed to the defense of that territory – every square inch.  President Biden has made that repeatedly clear that as well.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  <i>Wall Street Journal, </i>William Mauldin.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Thank you very much for doing this.  For Minister Rinkēvičs, you mentioned effective protection is needed for Latvia and the Baltic countries.  What constitutes effective protection?  Did you ask for any to – any new types of military hardware or other support?  And did that include anti-aircraft systems?  And did the U.S. seem willing to provide it?</p>
<p>I also wanted to ask Secretary Blinken:  You have upcoming meetings with Foreign Minister Lapid of Israel, with President Macron of France.  What role does Israel play, especially in any possible mediation or engagement with Russia, during this conflict?  And do you have any message to send to Russia other than the general need to de-escalate or stop fighting in Ukraine?</p>
<p>And then just to clarify one thing you said earlier in Vilnius, you mentioned more permanent basing of troops here.  Does that mean there is a decision or there isn’t a decision to base troops permanently here in the Baltics countries, specifically?  And – because there was a little bit of ambiguity with that, and so I’m just very curious.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER RINKĒVIČS:  </b>Thank you very much.  I’ll answer in English.  Well, yes, indeed, we discussed the further steps when it comes to providing additional protection.  And we see the need and we are also learning from what is happening in Ukraine.  We are seeing what Russians are doing and we understand that we need to bolster our air defense.  That’s absolutely clear.  We also feel that we need to bolster our coastal defense, cyber defense.  And we are discussing and talking not only with the Secretary of State, but also with the Secretary of Defense.  We see the willingness to work with us, and to look into the needs.  And of course, that requires some process, but I’m pretty confident that there is understanding about the need to work together and to address some of those issues.</p>
<p>But let me also mention another thing that is equally important than defense, and that’s energy.  I think that what we all understand that we need to work, and it is not only Latvia or Lithuania or Estonia – that’s entire European Union, Europe as a whole.  We need to work to reduce dependency on Russian gas and oil.  We discussed at some length and detail also what could be done.  And I say that here, the United States can play a critical role, and we are willing to continue.  And this region is connecting from Russia, the Russian electricity grid, and connecting to European electricity grid.  Some work is being done.  And also that means, of course, reducing dependency of gas.  But here we need a bit wider effort through LNG, through renewable energy issues.</p>
<p>So I would put now military defense and energy defense on an equal footing, and also the cyber defense, so three areas.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Did you ask for anti-aircraft assistance from NATO?</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER RINKĒVIČS:  </b>We do work on those issues, yes, we do work.  But I think that we will not go into details before there are more substantial efforts.  And we are working through NATO and with our partners on some additional needs that we see we need.  And I’m very glad that both NATO and our partners are addressing those challenges seriously.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Will, first, on the last part of your question, just to be clear – and I’m sorry if I wasn’t before, earlier today – as I said and as I just mentioned again now, we’re on a regular basis reviewing the global posture of our forces, to include of course here in Europe.  And we have to factor in any developments, any changes in the threat – and we will do that.  And when it comes to questions such as permanent basing, these questions come up and we’ll certainly look to answer them in the context of doing the review of our of our posture.  But just to be very clear, no, there’s no decision of that kind.  I was just saying that this is a question that’s come up, and we’ll, in the context of doing reviews of our posture in Europe and elsewhere, be looking at that.</p>
<p>Second, with regard to the meetings, I’ll – I’m not going to get ahead of them.  I’ll let them more or less speak for themselves, once I’ve had the chance to actually compare notes with my friend Yair Lapid later this evening here, and then with President Macron tomorrow in France.  But I think there is – there’s certainly no change in our message to Moscow, our message to Russia, to President Putin:  End the war.  End it now.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary of State, Your Excellency Minister, dear media representatives.  This concludes our press conference.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Spanish State Secretary for Foreign and Global Affairs Moreno Bau</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-spanish-state-secretary-for-foreign-and-global-affairs-moreno-bau/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 18:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321549</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with Spanish State Secretary for Foreign and Global Affairs Angeles Moreno Bau in Madrid. They reaffirmed their steadfast support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and condemned President Putin’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified Russian invasion of Ukraine and its devastating humanitarian toll. Deputy Secretary Sherman and State Secretary Moreno Bau discussed the sweeping, coordinated economic sanctions and export controls the United States and EU have imposed and will continue to impose in response, as well as measures to provide defensive military assistance and robust humanitarian aid to the Ukrainian people. They also discussed issues of mutual concern in Latin America, Africa, and the Indo-Pacific, including ways to strengthen democracy and expand bilateral cooperation in Central America.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with Spanish State Secretary for Foreign and Global Affairs Angeles Moreno Bau in Madrid. They reaffirmed their steadfast support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and condemned President Putin’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified Russian invasion of Ukraine and its devastating humanitarian toll. Deputy Secretary Sherman and State Secretary Moreno Bau discussed the sweeping, coordinated economic sanctions and export controls the United States and EU have imposed and will continue to impose in response, as well as measures to provide defensive military assistance and robust humanitarian aid to the Ukrainian people. They also discussed issues of mutual concern in Latin America, Africa, and the Indo-Pacific, including ways to strengthen democracy and expand bilateral cooperation in Central America.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Global Sports Mentoring Program: Sport for Community on Disability Rights Welcomes New Class</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/global-sports-mentoring-program-sport-for-community-on-disability-rights-welcomes-new-class/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 17:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321528</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State will virtually welcome 12 international emerging leaders in the adaptive sports sector for the Global Sports Mentoring Program: Sport for Community professional development exchange program from March 7 to April 1. With the growth in prominence and attention around mega-sporting events such as the Paralympic Games and Special Olympics, Sport for Community is designed to spread the global lessons of the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) and promote disability rights and inclusion worldwide.</p>
<p>Delegates will participate in a four-week virtual program focused on the theme, “Leading in Times of Crisis,” and work closely with American executives at top adaptive sports sector organizations across the country. They will attend leadership development sessions, engage in mentorship activities, and create a final multimedia project. The project will outline strategic plans that use sports to advance opportunities for people with disabilities by promoting their rights, dignity, value, and full inclusion in all aspects of society.</p>
<p>The participant roster includes emerging leaders from Belgium, Bosnia and Herzegovina, China, Croatia, Georgia, Hungary, Nepal, Nigeria, Saudi Arabia, Thailand, and Zambia. The mentors represent University of Arizona, Special Olympics, Ability 360, Arts for All, Spaulding Rehabilitation Network, U.S. Tennis Association, TIRR Memorial Herman Hospital, Turnstone, University of Texas at Arlington, Chicago Parks District and Shirley Ryan AbilityLab, and Mesa Parks.</p>
<p>The program is conducted in partnership with the University of Tennessee’s Center for Sport, Peace, and Society. For more information, please contact the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs at <a href="mailto:ECA-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ECA-Press@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State will virtually welcome 12 international emerging leaders in the adaptive sports sector for the Global Sports Mentoring Program: Sport for Community professional development exchange program from March 7 to April 1. With the growth in prominence and attention around mega-sporting events such as the Paralympic Games and Special Olympics, Sport for Community is designed to spread the global lessons of the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) and promote disability rights and inclusion worldwide.</p>
<p>Delegates will participate in a four-week virtual program focused on the theme, “Leading in Times of Crisis,” and work closely with American executives at top adaptive sports sector organizations across the country. They will attend leadership development sessions, engage in mentorship activities, and create a final multimedia project. The project will outline strategic plans that use sports to advance opportunities for people with disabilities by promoting their rights, dignity, value, and full inclusion in all aspects of society.</p>
<p>The participant roster includes emerging leaders from Belgium, Bosnia and Herzegovina, China, Croatia, Georgia, Hungary, Nepal, Nigeria, Saudi Arabia, Thailand, and Zambia. The mentors represent University of Arizona, Special Olympics, Ability 360, Arts for All, Spaulding Rehabilitation Network, U.S. Tennis Association, TIRR Memorial Herman Hospital, Turnstone, University of Texas at Arlington, Chicago Parks District and Shirley Ryan AbilityLab, and Mesa Parks.</p>
<p>The program is conducted in partnership with the University of Tennessee’s Center for Sport, Peace, and Society. For more information, please contact the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs at <a href="mailto:ECA-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ECA-Press@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Lithuanian Foreign Minister Gabrielius Landsbergis at a Joint Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-lithuanian-foreign-minister-gabrielius-landsbergis-at-a-joint-press-availability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 13:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321407</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Vilnius, Lithuania</p>
<p>Ministry of Foreign Affairs</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LANDSBERGIS:</b>  (Via interpreter)  Colleagues, good morning.  I’m delighted with the opportunity to welcome the U.S. State Secretary and a good friend of mine, Antony Blinken, in Lithuania.  We had an opportunity to discuss key and most concerning issues, including Russian war against Ukraine and further actions in support to Ukraine, and how we should strengthen the security of Lithuanian and the entire region.  The Untied States, Lithuania, and other partners of the alliance are doing a lot, but we cannot stop.  We cannot afford for Ukrainian cities to become another Srebrenica, Grozny, or Aleppo.</p>
<p>Providing assistance to Ukraine has to continue.  We have to urge our partners to check their inventories to increase their orders and continue supplying assistance to Ukraine that it needs so much.  The Russia initiated war also means humanitarian as well as climate crisis, and we have to do everything that is possible to prevent the humanitarian corridors and safe areas around nuclear power plants from becoming targets of Russian war machine.  I’m happy that the U.S. is increasing its presence in the Baltic region in troops and in equipment.  U.S. troops are protecting our country, together with other NATO partners.  We know that the commitments of our – of the Allies are ironclad, and if we want to continue building even stronger NATO, politically stronger, we need to ensure security of the Baltic states.</p>
<p>Russian economic blockade has not reached total isolation level, and we heard that there were attempts to use unsanctioned banks to evade the already-existing sanctions.  So we have to close all the possible gaps.  And energy resources that we are using allows Russia to fund its military operation, and we cannot pay for oil and gas with Ukrainian blood.  The U.S. stands with Lithuania and the Baltic states.  The United States stand here with their commitments, with their troops and capabilities.  They are here in reality and not in front of a green screen with the fake microphones.</p>
<p>Together – I’m sorry – today, the Secretary’s visit shows once again that United States stands with Lithuania and the Baltic states, and it also stands with Ukraine and its people.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you very, very much.  Gabrielius, thank you so much for the warm welcome.  It’s been a real pleasure to be here to be able to spend time with the president, with the prime minister, and with you.  And I just have to say for starts, on a personal note, how much I appreciate you as a colleague, how much I appreciate the strength of your voice, your conviction in our own relationship, at NATO, throughout Europe.  It makes a big difference, and it’s greatly appreciated.  And I’m pleased to be here with our ambassador to Lithuania, Bob Gilchrist, who’s been a terrific leader for the team that I was able to meet with this morning before meeting with our colleagues in the government.</p>
<p>We’re celebrating, the United States and Lithuania, 100 years of diplomatic relations this year.  We’re NATO Allies.  We’re economic partners.  And we share together a deep commitment to democracy, to human rights, to the international rules-based order, which we recognize is the foundation of our shared security and which is being directly threatened by Russia’s unprovoked, unjustified war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Lithuanians understand the critical importance of every nation’s sovereignty and territorial integrity being respected, having lived through decades of Soviet occupation, a forceful occupation that the United States always refused to recognize.  In recent years, Moscow has sought to undermine Lithuania’s democracy and sow polarization within its population through cyber attacks and disinformation campaigns.  That’s because the free, open, vibrant, prosperous society that the people of Lithuania have built since the end of Soviet occupation shows what’s possible when people choose the path of democracy over autocracy.  That’s why the United States supported and advocated for Lithuania’s membership in NATO and the European Union; and this country, Lithuania, has consistently made outsized contributions to both organizations.</p>
<p>Lithuania’s commitment to freedom was evident at the Summit for Democracy that President Biden convened late last year, where Vilnius pledged to expand its efforts to support and provide refuge for pro-democracy activists from Belarus and Russia, to promote international accountability measures for gross human rights violations, to increase support for media freedom and the safety of journalists.  How prescient and necessary those commitments proved to be.</p>
<p>In the face of the current crisis, the United States and Lithuania are united in our resolve to stand with Ukraine.  We’re surging security assistance to strengthen Ukraine’s capacity to defend itself.  We’re increasing humanitarian aid to the Ukrainian people.  We’re raising the costs on the Kremlin – and all who aid and enable it – for continuing this war of choice.  And we’re bolstering our shared defense so that we and our allies are prepared to meet any threat.</p>
<p>The United States has deployed an additional 7,000 forces to Europe.  We’re repositioned forces already in Europe to strengthen NATO’s eastern flank.  That includes the extension, as of last week, of the U.S. Army’s 366 Armored Battalion, which was deployed to Lithuania in July; the deployment of F-35 strike fighters to the region to augment NATO’s enhanced air policing mission.  An addition 400 personnel from the 1st Armored Brigade combat team will be arriving in Lithuania in the days to come.</p>
<p>The United States commitment to Article 5 – an attack on one is an attack on all – that commitment is sacrosanct.  And as President Biden repeated to the American people in his State of the Union address just a few days ago, we will defend every inch of NATO territory if it comes under attack.  No one should doubt our readiness; no one should doubt our resolve.</p>
<p>Over the past several weeks, I authorized allies to provide U.S.-origin defense equipment to our Ukrainian partners.  Lithuania stepped up with Stinger anti-aircraft missiles, M-72 light anti-tank weapons, and other supplies to help the extraordinarily courageous Ukrainian people defend their country from Russian aggression.  Vilnius is also sending about $4 million Euros in emergency medical assistance for Ukraine – 30 truckloads packed with aid, urgently needed given the growing carnage that’s being influenced by the Kremlin’s sieges and attacks on civilians.</p>
<p>When the Lithuanian Red Cross issued a call just last week for donations to help people in Ukraine, it filled 50 trucks the very first day.  We see blue and yellow flags hanging from homes and businesses across this country.  And a Lithuanian NGO has reportedly registered nearly 6,000 households willing to take in Ukrainian refugees.  The Ukrainians who eventually arrive in Lithuania will join hundreds of anti-corruption activists, opposition politicians, journalists, human rights defenders who already have found safe haven here after being forced to flee attacks, threats, imprisonment in Russia and Belarus in recent years.</p>
<p>Vilnius is the temporary home of Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya, the leader of Belarus’s pro-democracy movement, with whom I’ve had the privilege of meeting on several occasions, including most recently in Munich during the security conference.</p>
<p>We’re very grateful to Lithuania for hosting in the State Department’s Belarus Affairs unit, led by Ambassador Julie Fisher.  That unit is focused on supporting the democratic aspirations of the Belarusian people and holding the Lukashenka regime accountable for its widespread human rights violations.</p>
<p>Until last May, Vilnius also provided refuge for Belarusian blogger and dissident Roman Protasevich until a commercial jet that he was traveling on was intercepted by a Belarusian fighter jet and he was arbitrarily detained.  We join Lithuania in continuing to call for his immediate release and the release of all people being unjustly detained in Russia and in Belarus, including the growing number arrested for protesting the Kremlin’s ongoing war.  Yesterday alone, the Russian Government reportedly detained more than 4,600 people demonstrating against the war in 65 Russian cities and towns.</p>
<p>Vilnius recognized that a threat to the rules-based order anywhere has the potential to weaken it everywhere.  This includes the principle that every nation is free to associate with whom it chooses.  That’s why we respect and support Lithuania’s decision to expand commercial ties with Taiwan, another leading democracy.  Beijing has responded to Vilnius’s decision with economic coercion and political pressure designed to divide the European Union – and punishing Lithuania into reversing course.  We support the EU’s decision to launch a legal challenge against China at the WTO.  We have to defend the rules that keep trade fair.</p>
<p>Beijing talks a lot about the importance of upholding international order, stability, respecting sovereignty.  But from its coercion of Vilnius to its failure thus far to condemn Moscow’s flagrant violation of the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine, today and in 2014, Beijing’s actions are speaking much louder than its words.</p>
<p>The United States continues to stand by Lithuania and the right of every nation to choose its own path.  We’re supporting Lithuania as it reorients its supply chains and deepens its economic resilience.  In November we created a $600 million Export-Import Bank credit facility here, and that will help facilitate U.S. exports to Lithuania, but also help Lithuanian businesses in the sectors that have been hardest hit by the PRC’s measures like semiconductors, like biotechnology.  Our Undersecretary for Economic Affairs Jose Fernandez was just here – with colleagues from the Export-Import Bank – to support these efforts and deepen our economic cooperation.  As Lithuania continues to stand for these principles, it can count on the United States to stand with it.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>(Via interpreter)  Now is the time for questions.  Žygintas Abromaitis from Lithuanian National Television.  Žygintas Abromaitis.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b> Žygintas Abromaitis, Lithuanian national broadcaster on behalf of all Lithuanian media.  It’s a question for you, Mr. Blinken.  President Nausėda warned about World War III if Putin is not stopped, but it looks like the only war could stop him, and not sanctions or political pressure or even deterrence.  Putin is now saying that he’ll go till the end and Russia is threatening NATO countries over support of Ukraine.  You keep saying that you will defend every inch of NATO territory.  So will you send American troops to the Baltic region permanently, air defense systems?  Where is the red line after crossing it NATO will enter the war directly, and how likely Russia is ready to start a nuclear war?  And furthermore, could you confirm that Poland will send fighter jets in exchange for American F-16s?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you very much.  A few things.  First, as I noted, in response to Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, one of the things we did is exactly what we said we’d do for many, many months, which is, in the event of Russian aggression, we would reinforce NATO’s eastern flank.  And that’s exactly what we’ve done, and we’re in the midst of continuing to do that now, including with the deployment of additional forces, including American forces, here to Lithuania – F-35 fighters, various pieces of important equipment, all of which is being deployed here, deployed to the other states in the Baltics.</p>
<p>At the same time, we’re continuously reviewing within NATO our defense posture, including looking at questions of extending the deployment of forces, looking at questions of more permanent deployments.  All of that is under regular review, and we’re engaged with NATO Allies in doing just that.  Gabrielius and I were just at a meeting of the NATO foreign ministers a few days ago in Brussels, and this is one of the issues, of course, that came up.</p>
<p>Second, we said a few other things for many, many months as we saw – the two of us, our countries – the likelihood of Russian aggression against Ukraine.  And even as we tried everything we could to push Russia to a diplomatic path to try to resolve whatever concerns it had that might be – that anyone would consider legitimate through diplomacy and dialogue – even as we were doing that, we said then we would be fully prepared if it chose the path of aggression. We said that we would reinforce NATO’s eastern flank – we are.  We said that we would come to the aid of Ukraine by providing it more and more assistance – we are.  We said that we impose massive consequences on Russia for its aggression – we are.  And I think those consequences, the severity of the economic sanctions and other measures that have been taken, are well beyond what I think many people anticipated and are certainly unprecedented.</p>
<p>And they are having a dramatic impact already.  We see the ruble going through the floor.  We see Russia’s credit rating coming basically to zero, to “junk status,” as we would call it.  We see its stock market shut down.  We see an exodus of virtually every leading company from Russia. All of those things are happening; they’re happening in real time.  At the same time, other steps that we’ve taken, including export controls on the most important technology that Russia needs to modernize for the future – including its defense and aerospace industries, including its energy sector – that technology is being denied to Russia.  That’s going to have a powerful impact over time.</p>
<p>We’re also seeing the effect of the assistance that we have been able to provide to Ukraine and we’re continuing to provide to Ukraine – in Ukraine – when it comes to the incredible courage they’re showing in the effectiveness they’re having in standing against Russian aggression.  So all of these things, as we said, are happening.  They’re having an impact.  Having said that, it’s also true and clear that Russia has a hugely disproportionate force compared to what Ukraine has.  It has the ability to continue to grind down the Ukrainian military and, of course, to take horrific actions against the Ukrainian people, including attacking civilians.</p>
<p>We want this to come to a stop as quickly as possible, which is why we will continue to increase pressure on Russia, continue to support Ukraine.  But as I said yesterday, even if and as Russia might win a battle in Ukraine, that doesn’t mean it’s winning the war.  If and as Russia might take a city in Ukraine, that doesn’t mean that it’s taking the hearts and minds of the Ukrainian people.  It can’t; it won’t.  And whether it’s a week, whether it’s a month, whether it’s longer, I am utterly convinced that Ukraine will prevail.</p>
<p>Finally, when it comes to NATO, the line is very clear.  And I’ll repeat it:  If there is any aggression anywhere on NATO territory, on NATO countries, we the United States, all of our allies and partners, will take action to defend every inch of NATO territory.  It’s as clear and direct as that.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Simon Lewis, Reuters.  Your question, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Thank you.  Thanks for doing this.  For Secretary Blinken, I wondered if you would be able to comment on reports that the U.S. believes that Russia has begun recruiting Syrians to fight in the war in Ukraine.</p>
<p>And to the foreign minister:  Even before this invasion of Ukraine and the current tense security situation, Lithuania was already dealing with the threat from another power, from – of economic and diplomatic pressure from China over your stance towards Taiwan.  How can you balance those two threats, and what can the United States provide?  What are you asking for the United States to provide that to help you deal with both of those?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>I’m happy to start.  Simon, I’ve seen the reports that you refer to.  I can’t confirm them at this time.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LANDSBERGIS:  </b>Well, I think that – and as Secretary Blinken mentioned – both cases are about defending a similar principle.  One power is challenging the rules-based order when it comes to the borders of other countries, when it comes to geopolitics, when it comes to the security architecture of – one might say Europe, but I would say that it’s a global architecture, because it doesn’t matter where the country is – where the country is.  Is it in the Indo-Pacific?  Is it in Europe?  Is it in any other continent?  Every country has hopes and wants guarantees that its borders, its sovereignty will not be violated.</p>
<p>The other top power is trying to bend globally agreed rules of trade and is trying to use trade as a political instrument, in some cases even as a weapon, to force countries to change the course – no matter that it’s legal, no matter that it’s a sovereign right of the country to do so.  So not by our design, Lithuania becomes a case of defending both principles and becomes a country which in some cases leads by example what it means to defend the global rules-based order, be it geopolitical or economic.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Vilnius, Lithuania</p>
<p>Ministry of Foreign Affairs</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LANDSBERGIS:</b>  (Via interpreter)  Colleagues, good morning.  I’m delighted with the opportunity to welcome the U.S. State Secretary and a good friend of mine, Antony Blinken, in Lithuania.  We had an opportunity to discuss key and most concerning issues, including Russian war against Ukraine and further actions in support to Ukraine, and how we should strengthen the security of Lithuanian and the entire region.  The Untied States, Lithuania, and other partners of the alliance are doing a lot, but we cannot stop.  We cannot afford for Ukrainian cities to become another Srebrenica, Grozny, or Aleppo.</p>
<p>Providing assistance to Ukraine has to continue.  We have to urge our partners to check their inventories to increase their orders and continue supplying assistance to Ukraine that it needs so much.  The Russia initiated war also means humanitarian as well as climate crisis, and we have to do everything that is possible to prevent the humanitarian corridors and safe areas around nuclear power plants from becoming targets of Russian war machine.  I’m happy that the U.S. is increasing its presence in the Baltic region in troops and in equipment.  U.S. troops are protecting our country, together with other NATO partners.  We know that the commitments of our – of the Allies are ironclad, and if we want to continue building even stronger NATO, politically stronger, we need to ensure security of the Baltic states.</p>
<p>Russian economic blockade has not reached total isolation level, and we heard that there were attempts to use unsanctioned banks to evade the already-existing sanctions.  So we have to close all the possible gaps.  And energy resources that we are using allows Russia to fund its military operation, and we cannot pay for oil and gas with Ukrainian blood.  The U.S. stands with Lithuania and the Baltic states.  The United States stand here with their commitments, with their troops and capabilities.  They are here in reality and not in front of a green screen with the fake microphones.</p>
<p>Together – I’m sorry – today, the Secretary’s visit shows once again that United States stands with Lithuania and the Baltic states, and it also stands with Ukraine and its people.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you very, very much.  Gabrielius, thank you so much for the warm welcome.  It’s been a real pleasure to be here to be able to spend time with the president, with the prime minister, and with you.  And I just have to say for starts, on a personal note, how much I appreciate you as a colleague, how much I appreciate the strength of your voice, your conviction in our own relationship, at NATO, throughout Europe.  It makes a big difference, and it’s greatly appreciated.  And I’m pleased to be here with our ambassador to Lithuania, Bob Gilchrist, who’s been a terrific leader for the team that I was able to meet with this morning before meeting with our colleagues in the government.</p>
<p>We’re celebrating, the United States and Lithuania, 100 years of diplomatic relations this year.  We’re NATO Allies.  We’re economic partners.  And we share together a deep commitment to democracy, to human rights, to the international rules-based order, which we recognize is the foundation of our shared security and which is being directly threatened by Russia’s unprovoked, unjustified war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Lithuanians understand the critical importance of every nation’s sovereignty and territorial integrity being respected, having lived through decades of Soviet occupation, a forceful occupation that the United States always refused to recognize.  In recent years, Moscow has sought to undermine Lithuania’s democracy and sow polarization within its population through cyber attacks and disinformation campaigns.  That’s because the free, open, vibrant, prosperous society that the people of Lithuania have built since the end of Soviet occupation shows what’s possible when people choose the path of democracy over autocracy.  That’s why the United States supported and advocated for Lithuania’s membership in NATO and the European Union; and this country, Lithuania, has consistently made outsized contributions to both organizations.</p>
<p>Lithuania’s commitment to freedom was evident at the Summit for Democracy that President Biden convened late last year, where Vilnius pledged to expand its efforts to support and provide refuge for pro-democracy activists from Belarus and Russia, to promote international accountability measures for gross human rights violations, to increase support for media freedom and the safety of journalists.  How prescient and necessary those commitments proved to be.</p>
<p>In the face of the current crisis, the United States and Lithuania are united in our resolve to stand with Ukraine.  We’re surging security assistance to strengthen Ukraine’s capacity to defend itself.  We’re increasing humanitarian aid to the Ukrainian people.  We’re raising the costs on the Kremlin – and all who aid and enable it – for continuing this war of choice.  And we’re bolstering our shared defense so that we and our allies are prepared to meet any threat.</p>
<p>The United States has deployed an additional 7,000 forces to Europe.  We’re repositioned forces already in Europe to strengthen NATO’s eastern flank.  That includes the extension, as of last week, of the U.S. Army’s 366 Armored Battalion, which was deployed to Lithuania in July; the deployment of F-35 strike fighters to the region to augment NATO’s enhanced air policing mission.  An addition 400 personnel from the 1st Armored Brigade combat team will be arriving in Lithuania in the days to come.</p>
<p>The United States commitment to Article 5 – an attack on one is an attack on all – that commitment is sacrosanct.  And as President Biden repeated to the American people in his State of the Union address just a few days ago, we will defend every inch of NATO territory if it comes under attack.  No one should doubt our readiness; no one should doubt our resolve.</p>
<p>Over the past several weeks, I authorized allies to provide U.S.-origin defense equipment to our Ukrainian partners.  Lithuania stepped up with Stinger anti-aircraft missiles, M-72 light anti-tank weapons, and other supplies to help the extraordinarily courageous Ukrainian people defend their country from Russian aggression.  Vilnius is also sending about $4 million Euros in emergency medical assistance for Ukraine – 30 truckloads packed with aid, urgently needed given the growing carnage that’s being influenced by the Kremlin’s sieges and attacks on civilians.</p>
<p>When the Lithuanian Red Cross issued a call just last week for donations to help people in Ukraine, it filled 50 trucks the very first day.  We see blue and yellow flags hanging from homes and businesses across this country.  And a Lithuanian NGO has reportedly registered nearly 6,000 households willing to take in Ukrainian refugees.  The Ukrainians who eventually arrive in Lithuania will join hundreds of anti-corruption activists, opposition politicians, journalists, human rights defenders who already have found safe haven here after being forced to flee attacks, threats, imprisonment in Russia and Belarus in recent years.</p>
<p>Vilnius is the temporary home of Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya, the leader of Belarus’s pro-democracy movement, with whom I’ve had the privilege of meeting on several occasions, including most recently in Munich during the security conference.</p>
<p>We’re very grateful to Lithuania for hosting in the State Department’s Belarus Affairs unit, led by Ambassador Julie Fisher.  That unit is focused on supporting the democratic aspirations of the Belarusian people and holding the Lukashenka regime accountable for its widespread human rights violations.</p>
<p>Until last May, Vilnius also provided refuge for Belarusian blogger and dissident Roman Protasevich until a commercial jet that he was traveling on was intercepted by a Belarusian fighter jet and he was arbitrarily detained.  We join Lithuania in continuing to call for his immediate release and the release of all people being unjustly detained in Russia and in Belarus, including the growing number arrested for protesting the Kremlin’s ongoing war.  Yesterday alone, the Russian Government reportedly detained more than 4,600 people demonstrating against the war in 65 Russian cities and towns.</p>
<p>Vilnius recognized that a threat to the rules-based order anywhere has the potential to weaken it everywhere.  This includes the principle that every nation is free to associate with whom it chooses.  That’s why we respect and support Lithuania’s decision to expand commercial ties with Taiwan, another leading democracy.  Beijing has responded to Vilnius’s decision with economic coercion and political pressure designed to divide the European Union – and punishing Lithuania into reversing course.  We support the EU’s decision to launch a legal challenge against China at the WTO.  We have to defend the rules that keep trade fair.</p>
<p>Beijing talks a lot about the importance of upholding international order, stability, respecting sovereignty.  But from its coercion of Vilnius to its failure thus far to condemn Moscow’s flagrant violation of the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine, today and in 2014, Beijing’s actions are speaking much louder than its words.</p>
<p>The United States continues to stand by Lithuania and the right of every nation to choose its own path.  We’re supporting Lithuania as it reorients its supply chains and deepens its economic resilience.  In November we created a $600 million Export-Import Bank credit facility here, and that will help facilitate U.S. exports to Lithuania, but also help Lithuanian businesses in the sectors that have been hardest hit by the PRC’s measures like semiconductors, like biotechnology.  Our Undersecretary for Economic Affairs Jose Fernandez was just here – with colleagues from the Export-Import Bank – to support these efforts and deepen our economic cooperation.  As Lithuania continues to stand for these principles, it can count on the United States to stand with it.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>(Via interpreter)  Now is the time for questions.  Žygintas Abromaitis from Lithuanian National Television.  Žygintas Abromaitis.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b> Žygintas Abromaitis, Lithuanian national broadcaster on behalf of all Lithuanian media.  It’s a question for you, Mr. Blinken.  President Nausėda warned about World War III if Putin is not stopped, but it looks like the only war could stop him, and not sanctions or political pressure or even deterrence.  Putin is now saying that he’ll go till the end and Russia is threatening NATO countries over support of Ukraine.  You keep saying that you will defend every inch of NATO territory.  So will you send American troops to the Baltic region permanently, air defense systems?  Where is the red line after crossing it NATO will enter the war directly, and how likely Russia is ready to start a nuclear war?  And furthermore, could you confirm that Poland will send fighter jets in exchange for American F-16s?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you very much.  A few things.  First, as I noted, in response to Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, one of the things we did is exactly what we said we’d do for many, many months, which is, in the event of Russian aggression, we would reinforce NATO’s eastern flank.  And that’s exactly what we’ve done, and we’re in the midst of continuing to do that now, including with the deployment of additional forces, including American forces, here to Lithuania – F-35 fighters, various pieces of important equipment, all of which is being deployed here, deployed to the other states in the Baltics.</p>
<p>At the same time, we’re continuously reviewing within NATO our defense posture, including looking at questions of extending the deployment of forces, looking at questions of more permanent deployments.  All of that is under regular review, and we’re engaged with NATO Allies in doing just that.  Gabrielius and I were just at a meeting of the NATO foreign ministers a few days ago in Brussels, and this is one of the issues, of course, that came up.</p>
<p>Second, we said a few other things for many, many months as we saw – the two of us, our countries – the likelihood of Russian aggression against Ukraine.  And even as we tried everything we could to push Russia to a diplomatic path to try to resolve whatever concerns it had that might be – that anyone would consider legitimate through diplomacy and dialogue – even as we were doing that, we said then we would be fully prepared if it chose the path of aggression. We said that we would reinforce NATO’s eastern flank – we are.  We said that we would come to the aid of Ukraine by providing it more and more assistance – we are.  We said that we impose massive consequences on Russia for its aggression – we are.  And I think those consequences, the severity of the economic sanctions and other measures that have been taken, are well beyond what I think many people anticipated and are certainly unprecedented.</p>
<p>And they are having a dramatic impact already.  We see the ruble going through the floor.  We see Russia’s credit rating coming basically to zero, to “junk status,” as we would call it.  We see its stock market shut down.  We see an exodus of virtually every leading company from Russia. All of those things are happening; they’re happening in real time.  At the same time, other steps that we’ve taken, including export controls on the most important technology that Russia needs to modernize for the future – including its defense and aerospace industries, including its energy sector – that technology is being denied to Russia.  That’s going to have a powerful impact over time.</p>
<p>We’re also seeing the effect of the assistance that we have been able to provide to Ukraine and we’re continuing to provide to Ukraine – in Ukraine – when it comes to the incredible courage they’re showing in the effectiveness they’re having in standing against Russian aggression.  So all of these things, as we said, are happening.  They’re having an impact.  Having said that, it’s also true and clear that Russia has a hugely disproportionate force compared to what Ukraine has.  It has the ability to continue to grind down the Ukrainian military and, of course, to take horrific actions against the Ukrainian people, including attacking civilians.</p>
<p>We want this to come to a stop as quickly as possible, which is why we will continue to increase pressure on Russia, continue to support Ukraine.  But as I said yesterday, even if and as Russia might win a battle in Ukraine, that doesn’t mean it’s winning the war.  If and as Russia might take a city in Ukraine, that doesn’t mean that it’s taking the hearts and minds of the Ukrainian people.  It can’t; it won’t.  And whether it’s a week, whether it’s a month, whether it’s longer, I am utterly convinced that Ukraine will prevail.</p>
<p>Finally, when it comes to NATO, the line is very clear.  And I’ll repeat it:  If there is any aggression anywhere on NATO territory, on NATO countries, we the United States, all of our allies and partners, will take action to defend every inch of NATO territory.  It’s as clear and direct as that.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Simon Lewis, Reuters.  Your question, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Thank you.  Thanks for doing this.  For Secretary Blinken, I wondered if you would be able to comment on reports that the U.S. believes that Russia has begun recruiting Syrians to fight in the war in Ukraine.</p>
<p>And to the foreign minister:  Even before this invasion of Ukraine and the current tense security situation, Lithuania was already dealing with the threat from another power, from – of economic and diplomatic pressure from China over your stance towards Taiwan.  How can you balance those two threats, and what can the United States provide?  What are you asking for the United States to provide that to help you deal with both of those?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>I’m happy to start.  Simon, I’ve seen the reports that you refer to.  I can’t confirm them at this time.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LANDSBERGIS:  </b>Well, I think that – and as Secretary Blinken mentioned – both cases are about defending a similar principle.  One power is challenging the rules-based order when it comes to the borders of other countries, when it comes to geopolitics, when it comes to the security architecture of – one might say Europe, but I would say that it’s a global architecture, because it doesn’t matter where the country is – where the country is.  Is it in the Indo-Pacific?  Is it in Europe?  Is it in any other continent?  Every country has hopes and wants guarantees that its borders, its sovereignty will not be violated.</p>
<p>The other top power is trying to bend globally agreed rules of trade and is trying to use trade as a political instrument, in some cases even as a weapon, to force countries to change the course – no matter that it’s legal, no matter that it’s a sovereign right of the country to do so.  So not by our design, Lithuania becomes a case of defending both principles and becomes a country which in some cases leads by example what it means to defend the global rules-based order, be it geopolitical or economic.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Representative for the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK) Kim’s Calls with Republic of Korea (ROK) Special Representative Noh and Japanese Director General Funakoshi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-representative-for-the-democratic-peoples-republic-of-korea-dprk-kims-calls-with-republic-of-korea-rok-special-representative-noh-and-japanese-director-general-funakoshi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 13:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321391</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">In separate March 4 calls, Special Representative for the DPRK Sung Kim discussed the DPRK’s March 4 ballistic missile test with Japanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs Director General for Asian and Oceanian Affairs Bureau Funakoshi Takehiro and ROK Special Representative for Korean Peninsula Peace and Security Affairs Noh Kyu-duk.</p>
<p align="left">Special Representative Kim denounced the DPRK ballistic missile launch as a violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions and a threat to regional stability.  He reaffirmed the shared goal of complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and U.S. ironclad commitment to the defense of the ROK and Japan.  Special Representative Kim underscored the U.S. commitment to coordination with allies and our continued readiness to engage in serious and sustained diplomacy with the DPRK.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">In separate March 4 calls, Special Representative for the DPRK Sung Kim discussed the DPRK’s March 4 ballistic missile test with Japanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs Director General for Asian and Oceanian Affairs Bureau Funakoshi Takehiro and ROK Special Representative for Korean Peninsula Peace and Security Affairs Noh Kyu-duk.</p>
<p align="left">Special Representative Kim denounced the DPRK ballistic missile launch as a violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions and a threat to regional stability.  He reaffirmed the shared goal of complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and U.S. ironclad commitment to the defense of the ROK and Japan.  Special Representative Kim underscored the U.S. commitment to coordination with allies and our continued readiness to engage in serious and sustained diplomacy with the DPRK.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Lithuanian President Gitanas Nauseda Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-lithuanian-president-gitanas-nauseda-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 11:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321372</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Vilnius, Lithuania</p>
<p>Presidentura</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT NAUSEDA:  </strong>(Inaudible.)  Mr. Secretary, appreciate your visit to Vilnius.  Thankful for support of President Biden and you personally, Secretary, extend to Lithuania.  Always good to talk to a closest friend and ally.  I hope that the leaders of the Baltic countries will meet President Biden later this year to mark the 100th-year anniversary of the diplomatic relations between the United States and Lithuania.  And I think it will be very a very good opportunity to debut our U.S.-Baltic charter.</p>
<p>Thank you also for your leadership in uniting the world and for heavy support you bring.  Unfortunately, worsening security situation in the Baltic region is of great concern to – on all of us and around the globe.  Russia’s reckless aggression against Ukraine once again proves that it is a long-term threat to the European security, the security of the entire alliance, no matter how and when the war in Ukraine ends.  Furthermore, the fact of obstruction of Belarus and Russia is an additional very dangerous factor for us, for the region.  And probably this is a very good opportunity to rethink, rethink the alliance response, alliance defense plans, procedures.  And I’m happy to conclude that this process is underway.</p>
<p>I must say that, Antony, deterrence is no longer enough, and we need more defense here (inaudible), because otherwise it will be too late here, Mr. Secretary.  Putin will not stop in Ukraine; he will not stop.  It is our collective duty and obligation to help (inaudible) Ukrainians live all peace available by saying: all I need and need, all needs – if you want to avoid the third world war.  The choice is in our hands.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Mr. President, thank you very much.  Thank you for receiving us today.  Thank you for the historic partnership between our countries that, indeed, goes back a hundred years (inaudible) the extraordinary ups and downs (inaudible).  But throughout, we’ve been together, and we remain together in this moment, this a moment of tremendous challenge as a result of Russia’s unprovoked, unwarranted, premediated aggression against Ukraine, but also along with extraordinary solidarity.  We have seen countries throughout Europe, across the Atlantic, and, indeed, around the world come together in condemnation of Russia’s aggression and its support for Ukraine.  We’ve seen the alliance that we are both (inaudible) come together, not only in support of Ukraine, but also in reaffirmation of our common (inaudible) to Article 5, (inaudible) commitment that President Biden feels absolutely is sacrosanct.  An attack on one is an attack on all.  The United States, with all allies and partners, will defend every – every inch of NATO territory should it come under attack, and there should be no doubt about that on anyone’s mind.</p>
<p>To your point, we have a moment where not only is the solidarity necessary, but it&#8217;s also important to think (inaudible) how you approach our common (inaudible) – through NATO, together in our partnership – and that work is being done (inaudible).  But meanwhile, the most urgent matter is supporting our friends in Ukraine against this aggression.  Increasing pressure on Russia to stop this war of aggression – and doing everything we can (inaudible) to strengthen our alliance and ensure that it’s prepared for anything.  NATO has no aggressive intent, does not to seek out conflict, has never sought conflict, but we will always be prepared (inaudible).  Thank you.  (Inaudible) talking about these things in more detail.  Thank you.<input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Vilnius, Lithuania</p>
<p>Presidentura</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT NAUSEDA:  </strong>(Inaudible.)  Mr. Secretary, appreciate your visit to Vilnius.  Thankful for support of President Biden and you personally, Secretary, extend to Lithuania.  Always good to talk to a closest friend and ally.  I hope that the leaders of the Baltic countries will meet President Biden later this year to mark the 100th-year anniversary of the diplomatic relations between the United States and Lithuania.  And I think it will be very a very good opportunity to debut our U.S.-Baltic charter.</p>
<p>Thank you also for your leadership in uniting the world and for heavy support you bring.  Unfortunately, worsening security situation in the Baltic region is of great concern to – on all of us and around the globe.  Russia’s reckless aggression against Ukraine once again proves that it is a long-term threat to the European security, the security of the entire alliance, no matter how and when the war in Ukraine ends.  Furthermore, the fact of obstruction of Belarus and Russia is an additional very dangerous factor for us, for the region.  And probably this is a very good opportunity to rethink, rethink the alliance response, alliance defense plans, procedures.  And I’m happy to conclude that this process is underway.</p>
<p>I must say that, Antony, deterrence is no longer enough, and we need more defense here (inaudible), because otherwise it will be too late here, Mr. Secretary.  Putin will not stop in Ukraine; he will not stop.  It is our collective duty and obligation to help (inaudible) Ukrainians live all peace available by saying: all I need and need, all needs – if you want to avoid the third world war.  The choice is in our hands.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Mr. President, thank you very much.  Thank you for receiving us today.  Thank you for the historic partnership between our countries that, indeed, goes back a hundred years (inaudible) the extraordinary ups and downs (inaudible).  But throughout, we’ve been together, and we remain together in this moment, this a moment of tremendous challenge as a result of Russia’s unprovoked, unwarranted, premediated aggression against Ukraine, but also along with extraordinary solidarity.  We have seen countries throughout Europe, across the Atlantic, and, indeed, around the world come together in condemnation of Russia’s aggression and its support for Ukraine.  We’ve seen the alliance that we are both (inaudible) come together, not only in support of Ukraine, but also in reaffirmation of our common (inaudible) to Article 5, (inaudible) commitment that President Biden feels absolutely is sacrosanct.  An attack on one is an attack on all.  The United States, with all allies and partners, will defend every – every inch of NATO territory should it come under attack, and there should be no doubt about that on anyone’s mind.</p>
<p>To your point, we have a moment where not only is the solidarity necessary, but it&#8217;s also important to think (inaudible) how you approach our common (inaudible) – through NATO, together in our partnership – and that work is being done (inaudible).  But meanwhile, the most urgent matter is supporting our friends in Ukraine against this aggression.  Increasing pressure on Russia to stop this war of aggression – and doing everything we can (inaudible) to strengthen our alliance and ensure that it’s prepared for anything.  NATO has no aggressive intent, does not to seek out conflict, has never sought conflict, but we will always be prepared (inaudible).  Thank you.  (Inaudible) talking about these things in more detail.  Thank you.<input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
