<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 13:33:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Paraguay Independence Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/paraguay-independence-day-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 13:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the people of the United States, I congratulate the people of Paraguay as you celebrate the 211th anniversary of your independence.</p>
<p>We reaffirm our strong partnership with Paraguay as we work together to recover from the COVID-19 pandemic.  We will continue to work together to advance our many shared interests, such as promoting transparency, combating corruption, fighting transnational crime, and supporting economic inclusivity for our two nations.  We look forward to engaging with Paraguay on these and other important issues at the Ninth Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles, California.</p>
<p>As we unite in celebration of Paraguay’s democratic achievements on this great occasion, the United States renews our partnership to promote peace, prosperity, and security in the Americas.  We look forward to deepening our enduring friendship, based on shared values and commitments, in the coming years.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the people of the United States, I congratulate the people of Paraguay as you celebrate the 211th anniversary of your independence.</p>
<p>We reaffirm our strong partnership with Paraguay as we work together to recover from the COVID-19 pandemic.  We will continue to work together to advance our many shared interests, such as promoting transparency, combating corruption, fighting transnational crime, and supporting economic inclusivity for our two nations.  We look forward to engaging with Paraguay on these and other important issues at the Ninth Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles, California.</p>
<p>As we unite in celebration of Paraguay’s democratic achievements on this great occasion, the United States renews our partnership to promote peace, prosperity, and security in the Americas.  We look forward to deepening our enduring friendship, based on shared values and commitments, in the coming years.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Thai Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-thai-deputy-prime-minister-and-foreign-minister-don-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;"><span>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met yesterday with Thai Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don Pramudwinai in Washington, D.C.  Secretary Blinken emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Thailand alliance and partnership to the security and prosperity of the region and discussed potential cooperation under<i> </i>the new Indo-Pacific Economic Framework<b><i>.</i></b></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;"><span>Highlighting closely aligned aspirations for the respective Thai and U.S. 2022 and 2023 APEC host years, the Secretary highlighted the need to tackle the climate crisis and bolster climate-friendly economic growth. He also underscored the importance of upholding shared values across the Mekong region, including by providing humanitarian assistance to the people of Burma and working through ASEAN to restore Burma’s path to democracy.  </span></span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;"><span>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met yesterday with Thai Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don Pramudwinai in Washington, D.C.  Secretary Blinken emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Thailand alliance and partnership to the security and prosperity of the region and discussed potential cooperation under<i> </i>the new Indo-Pacific Economic Framework<b><i>.</i></b></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;"><span>Highlighting closely aligned aspirations for the respective Thai and U.S. 2022 and 2023 APEC host years, the Secretary highlighted the need to tackle the climate crisis and bolster climate-friendly economic growth. He also underscored the importance of upholding shared values across the Mekong region, including by providing humanitarian assistance to the people of Burma and working through ASEAN to restore Burma’s path to democracy.  </span></span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Escalations in Jerusalem at the Funeral of Shireen Abu Akleh</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/escalations-in-jerusalem-at-the-funeral-of-shireen-abu-akleh/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 21:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States again extends our deepest condolences to the family and loved ones of Shireen Abu Akleh, a renowned Palestinian American journalist. We were deeply troubled to see the images of Israeli police intruding into her funeral procession today. Every family deserves to be able to lay their loved ones to rest in a dignified and unimpeded manner. We remain in close contact with our Israeli and Palestinian counterparts and call on all to maintain calm and avoid any actions that could further escalate tensions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States again extends our deepest condolences to the family and loved ones of Shireen Abu Akleh, a renowned Palestinian American journalist. We were deeply troubled to see the images of Israeli police intruding into her funeral procession today. Every family deserves to be able to lay their loved ones to rest in a dignified and unimpeded manner. We remain in close contact with our Israeli and Palestinian counterparts and call on all to maintain calm and avoid any actions that could further escalate tensions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Cambodian Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Prak Sokhonn</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-cambodian-deputy-prime-minister-and-foreign-minister-prak-sokhonn/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Prak Sokhonn, Cambodian Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 20:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Prak Sokhonn, Cambodian Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a pleasure to be here with the deputy prime minister of Cambodia.  I really want to thank you, Deputy Prime Minister, and Cambodia for your leadership of ASEAN and for everything you’ve done to make this such a successful special summit between the United States and ASEAN.</p>
<p>We’ve had an opportunity to deepen the work that we’re doing together, and to put out – I think, a very important vision statement for the future, and Cambodia’s work to bring us to this point is greatly appreciated.  We’re working very closely together as partners to try to advance a shared vision for the region, including regional security.  And of course, we welcome the leadership role that you’re playing in ASEAN on a number of issues, including hopefully working to restore the democratic path in Myanmar.</p>
<p>So, it’s very good to have you here.  Welcome again to the State Department.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY PRIME MINISTER PRAK SOKHONN:</strong>  Thank you very much, Secretary Blinken.  It’s a real honor, pleasure to be here to have this meeting with you.  It’s an opportunity for us to exchange views, especially to strengthen our bilateral cooperation.  And it’s a wonderful for Cambodia as a chair to have been able to organize – co-organize this summit between ASEAN leaders and the U.S.</p>
<p>I am ready to have a good discussion with Secretary Blinken, in order to strengthen our bilateral relationship and to push forward for solution in a number of regional issues.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you, everyone.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Prak Sokhonn, Cambodian Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a pleasure to be here with the deputy prime minister of Cambodia.  I really want to thank you, Deputy Prime Minister, and Cambodia for your leadership of ASEAN and for everything you’ve done to make this such a successful special summit between the United States and ASEAN.</p>
<p>We’ve had an opportunity to deepen the work that we’re doing together, and to put out – I think, a very important vision statement for the future, and Cambodia’s work to bring us to this point is greatly appreciated.  We’re working very closely together as partners to try to advance a shared vision for the region, including regional security.  And of course, we welcome the leadership role that you’re playing in ASEAN on a number of issues, including hopefully working to restore the democratic path in Myanmar.</p>
<p>So, it’s very good to have you here.  Welcome again to the State Department.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY PRIME MINISTER PRAK SOKHONN:</strong>  Thank you very much, Secretary Blinken.  It’s a real honor, pleasure to be here to have this meeting with you.  It’s an opportunity for us to exchange views, especially to strengthen our bilateral cooperation.  And it’s a wonderful for Cambodia as a chair to have been able to organize – co-organize this summit between ASEAN leaders and the U.S.</p>
<p>I am ready to have a good discussion with Secretary Blinken, in order to strengthen our bilateral relationship and to push forward for solution in a number of regional issues.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you, everyone.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Launch Event for the Establishment of the Counterterrorism Law Enforcement Forum</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/launch-event-for-the-establishment-of-the-counterterrorism-law-enforcement-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 19:33:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344137</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On May 11-12 in Berlin, the Departments of State and Justice launched the Counterterrorism Law Enforcement Forum (CTLEF), co-hosted by the Government of Germany. The CTLEF, which focuses on countering racially or ethnically motivated violent extremism (REMVE) globally, brought together law enforcement, prosecutors, and other criminal justice practitioners from Europe, North and South America, and the Indo-Pacific, alongside specialists from INTERPOL, Europol, the International Institute for Justice and the Rule of Law, the UN Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC), and other multilateral organizations.</p>
<p>The inaugural CTLEF meeting increased awareness and information sharing among law enforcement and criminal justice partners about global REMVE activity, including the transnational linkages between and among REMVE actors. Participants also learned about recent law enforcement actions undertaken by governments to disrupt REMVE actors’ global activity.</p>
<p>Officials from the U.S. Departments of State, Justice, and the Treasury, as well as the Federal Bureau of Investigation, participated. The CTLEF will convene again in the spring of 2023.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On May 11-12 in Berlin, the Departments of State and Justice launched the Counterterrorism Law Enforcement Forum (CTLEF), co-hosted by the Government of Germany. The CTLEF, which focuses on countering racially or ethnically motivated violent extremism (REMVE) globally, brought together law enforcement, prosecutors, and other criminal justice practitioners from Europe, North and South America, and the Indo-Pacific, alongside specialists from INTERPOL, Europol, the International Institute for Justice and the Rule of Law, the UN Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC), and other multilateral organizations.</p>
<p>The inaugural CTLEF meeting increased awareness and information sharing among law enforcement and criminal justice partners about global REMVE activity, including the transnational linkages between and among REMVE actors. Participants also learned about recent law enforcement actions undertaken by governments to disrupt REMVE actors’ global activity.</p>
<p>Officials from the U.S. Departments of State, Justice, and the Treasury, as well as the Federal Bureau of Investigation, participated. The CTLEF will convene again in the spring of 2023.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Indonesian Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-indonesian-foreign-minister-retno-marsudi-before-their-meeting-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 15:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=344029</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good morning, everyone.  It’s a real pleasure to be here with my friend and colleague, the foreign minister of Indonesia.  Retno, thank you for being here, but thank you more broadly for Indonesia’s remarkable leadership.  We just had – we’re still having what is truly a historic summit between the United States and ASEAN.  And the success of this effort is in no small measure due to Indonesia’s leadership as our country coordinator, but also as the leader of ASEAN.  I know from speaking to President Biden that the meetings have been already a significant success.  And it just puts an emphasis on the great importance that we attach, the United States attaches to ASEAN, our relationship, ASEAN centrality.  But so much of this is due to Indonesia’s leadership.</p>
<p>We are working together across the board to advance a shared vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific region.  We’re working to strengthen economic ties among countries in the region.  We’re working together to deal with global challenges, like COVID-19.  Just yesterday at the summit that the President was also convening, I had the opportunity to do a session with your health minister about how we can strengthen the global health security system for the future.  So here, again, Indonesia is playing a leadership role.</p>
<p>We have a lot to talk about, including the situation in Myanmar and other occupations, but I think most important is that what I’ve seen over the last year and a half is a increasingly strong relationship, partnership between our countries, for which the United States is truly appreciative.  So welcome.  It’s great to have you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MARSUDI:</strong>  Well, thank you very much, Secretary Blinken.  Thank you very much, Tony.  It’s very – I feel so glad to be back to D.C. again, and this time is for the ASEAN-U.S. Summit.  And I’m also very glad that we are able to have separately a bilateral meeting to discuss various issues of bilateral relation as well as regional and global issue.</p>
<p>U.S. and Indonesia are strategic partner.  With this strategic partnership, I am very glad to see intensified communication and cooperation between our two countries.  And we should use this strategic partnership also to contribute to the peace, stability, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>So, I also hope to see synergy between the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework with implementation of cooperation under the ASEAN Outlook on the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>On the global issue, I would like to reiterate the very consistent of the principle of Indonesia on the importance of respecting territorial integrity and sovereignty of a country to another country.  So, this principle is upheld by Indonesia very consistently.</p>
<p>Our hope is to see the war in Ukraine stop as soon as possible, and we give the peaceful resolution of a conflict a chance to succeed.  Because we know that if the war continues, all of us will suffer.</p>
<p>And finally, looking forward to welcoming you on the foreign ministers meeting of the G20 in July 2022 in Bali.</p>
<p>So once again, thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MARSUDI:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Come on in.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good morning, everyone.  It’s a real pleasure to be here with my friend and colleague, the foreign minister of Indonesia.  Retno, thank you for being here, but thank you more broadly for Indonesia’s remarkable leadership.  We just had – we’re still having what is truly a historic summit between the United States and ASEAN.  And the success of this effort is in no small measure due to Indonesia’s leadership as our country coordinator, but also as the leader of ASEAN.  I know from speaking to President Biden that the meetings have been already a significant success.  And it just puts an emphasis on the great importance that we attach, the United States attaches to ASEAN, our relationship, ASEAN centrality.  But so much of this is due to Indonesia’s leadership.</p>
<p>We are working together across the board to advance a shared vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific region.  We’re working to strengthen economic ties among countries in the region.  We’re working together to deal with global challenges, like COVID-19.  Just yesterday at the summit that the President was also convening, I had the opportunity to do a session with your health minister about how we can strengthen the global health security system for the future.  So here, again, Indonesia is playing a leadership role.</p>
<p>We have a lot to talk about, including the situation in Myanmar and other occupations, but I think most important is that what I’ve seen over the last year and a half is a increasingly strong relationship, partnership between our countries, for which the United States is truly appreciative.  So welcome.  It’s great to have you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MARSUDI:</strong>  Well, thank you very much, Secretary Blinken.  Thank you very much, Tony.  It’s very – I feel so glad to be back to D.C. again, and this time is for the ASEAN-U.S. Summit.  And I’m also very glad that we are able to have separately a bilateral meeting to discuss various issues of bilateral relation as well as regional and global issue.</p>
<p>U.S. and Indonesia are strategic partner.  With this strategic partnership, I am very glad to see intensified communication and cooperation between our two countries.  And we should use this strategic partnership also to contribute to the peace, stability, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>So, I also hope to see synergy between the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework with implementation of cooperation under the ASEAN Outlook on the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>On the global issue, I would like to reiterate the very consistent of the principle of Indonesia on the importance of respecting territorial integrity and sovereignty of a country to another country.  So, this principle is upheld by Indonesia very consistently.</p>
<p>Our hope is to see the war in Ukraine stop as soon as possible, and we give the peaceful resolution of a conflict a chance to succeed.  Because we know that if the war continues, all of us will suffer.</p>
<p>And finally, looking forward to welcoming you on the foreign ministers meeting of the G20 in July 2022 in Bali.</p>
<p>So once again, thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MARSUDI:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Come on in.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Republic of Korea Foreign Minister Park</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-republic-of-korea-foreign-minister-park/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=343992</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken held his introductory call yesterday with Republic of Korea (ROK) Minister of Foreign Affairs Park Jin to discuss continued U.S.-ROK cooperation to address critical global challenges. The Secretary congratulated Foreign Minister Park on his May 12 appointment as foreign minister and reaffirmed the U.S. resolve to work closely with the ROK on the wide range of important bilateral, regional, and global issues. The Secretary emphasized our ironclad, mutual commitment to the defense of the ROK and our shared goal of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, as well as the importance of trilateral cooperation with Japan in support of peace and security in the Indo-Pacific. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Park condemned recent DPRK ballistic missile launches. In addition, the Secretary and the Foreign Minister discussed U.S. and ROK efforts to provide assistance to Ukraine and hold the Kremlin and its enablers accountable for President Putin’s brutal, unprovoked war.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken held his introductory call yesterday with Republic of Korea (ROK) Minister of Foreign Affairs Park Jin to discuss continued U.S.-ROK cooperation to address critical global challenges. The Secretary congratulated Foreign Minister Park on his May 12 appointment as foreign minister and reaffirmed the U.S. resolve to work closely with the ROK on the wide range of important bilateral, regional, and global issues. The Secretary emphasized our ironclad, mutual commitment to the defense of the ROK and our shared goal of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, as well as the importance of trilateral cooperation with Japan in support of peace and security in the Indo-Pacific. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Park condemned recent DPRK ballistic missile launches. In addition, the Secretary and the Foreign Minister discussed U.S. and ROK efforts to provide assistance to Ukraine and hold the Kremlin and its enablers accountable for President Putin’s brutal, unprovoked war.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Condolences on the Passing of His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/condolences-on-the-passing-of-his-highness-sheikh-khalifa-bin-zayed-al-nahyan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 13:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=343976</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>We are deeply saddened to learn of the death of the President of the United Arab Emirates, His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan. We extend our sincere condolences to his family and the people of the United Arab Emirates. His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan was a true friend of the United States. We deeply valued his support in building the extraordinary partnership our countries enjoy today. We mourn his passing, honor his legacy, and remain committed to our steadfast friendship and cooperation with the United Arab Emirates.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>We are deeply saddened to learn of the death of the President of the United Arab Emirates, His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan. We extend our sincere condolences to his family and the people of the United Arab Emirates. His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan was a true friend of the United States. We deeply valued his support in building the extraordinary partnership our countries enjoy today. We mourn his passing, honor his legacy, and remain committed to our steadfast friendship and cooperation with the United Arab Emirates.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>G7 Foreign Ministers’ Statement on the Situation of Women and Girls in Afghanistan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/g7-foreign-ministers-statement-on-the-situation-of-women-and-girls-in-afghanistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 01:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=343909</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p><i>Begin Text.</i></p>
<p>We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union, express our strongest opposition and deplore the increasing restrictions imposed on the rights and freedoms of women and girls in Afghanistan by the Taliban.</p>
<p>We stand with the Afghan people in their demand for equal rights in line with the Taliban’s commitments to all Afghans and Afghanistan’s obligations under international law. We condemn the imposition of increasingly restrictive measures that severely limit half the population’s ability to fully, equally, and meaningfully participate in society, including the recent announcement on women’s appearance in public along with new punishments for family members to enforce compliance with these restrictions.</p>
<p>With these moves, the Taliban are further isolating themselves from the international community. Echoing our joint statement, together with Norway, from March 24, we call on the Taliban to urgently take steps to lift restrictions on women and girls, respect their human rights, and meet the expectations of Afghans and the world to permit their full, equal, and meaningful participation in work, education and public life, as well as freedom of movement and freedom of speech, which is crucial for long-term peace, stability and development of the country.</p>
<p><i>End Text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p><i>Begin Text.</i></p>
<p>We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union, express our strongest opposition and deplore the increasing restrictions imposed on the rights and freedoms of women and girls in Afghanistan by the Taliban.</p>
<p>We stand with the Afghan people in their demand for equal rights in line with the Taliban’s commitments to all Afghans and Afghanistan’s obligations under international law. We condemn the imposition of increasingly restrictive measures that severely limit half the population’s ability to fully, equally, and meaningfully participate in society, including the recent announcement on women’s appearance in public along with new punishments for family members to enforce compliance with these restrictions.</p>
<p>With these moves, the Taliban are further isolating themselves from the international community. Echoing our joint statement, together with Norway, from March 24, we call on the Taliban to urgently take steps to lift restrictions on women and girls, respect their human rights, and meet the expectations of Afghans and the world to permit their full, equal, and meaningful participation in work, education and public life, as well as freedom of movement and freedom of speech, which is crucial for long-term peace, stability and development of the country.</p>
<p><i>End Text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Vietnamese Deputy Foreign Minister Ngoc</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-vietnamese-deputy-foreign-minister-ngoc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:40:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=343905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Wendy Sherman met today in Washington with Vietnamese Deputy Foreign Minister Ha Kim Ngoc to discuss the remarkable progress made over the years in bilateral relations between the United States and Vietnam.  The two leaders discussed the strong security and economic cooperation between the United States and Vietnam, which has proven vital in contributing to a rules-based, interconnected, and open Indo-Pacific region.  They also discussed our shared efforts to confront climate change and the COVID-19 pandemic. The Deputy Secretary also raised human rights and the importance of Vietnam’s fulfillment of its international human rights obligations and commitments.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Wendy Sherman met today in Washington with Vietnamese Deputy Foreign Minister Ha Kim Ngoc to discuss the remarkable progress made over the years in bilateral relations between the United States and Vietnam.  The two leaders discussed the strong security and economic cooperation between the United States and Vietnam, which has proven vital in contributing to a rules-based, interconnected, and open Indo-Pacific region.  They also discussed our shared efforts to confront climate change and the COVID-19 pandemic. The Deputy Secretary also raised human rights and the importance of Vietnam’s fulfillment of its international human rights obligations and commitments.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
