<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 17:28:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And UN High Commissioner for Refugees Filippo Grandi Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-un-high-commissioner-for-refugees-filippo-grandi-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 17:28:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333691</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Good morning, everyone.  I am very pleased for this opportunity to meet with the High Commissioner for Refugees at the UN Filippo Grandi.  It’s safe to say that this is a time of extraordinary challenge for everything that you’re doing and everything that we’re so indebted to you and your team for doing.</p>
<p>I believe, as you said, the number of displaced people around the world now is somewhere in the vicinity of 95 million people.  And within that huge number of refugees, I think if you added up all of the refugees and tried to put them in one country, it would be larger than the population of Spain, South Korea, any number of countries.  This is a challenge that has been with us for well over the past decade.  When I was last in government, we were dealing with particularly acute challenges – of course, Syria, Iraq, but also in many other parts of the world from Africa to Southeast Asia to our own hemisphere.</p>
<p>We’ve only seen that challenge increase, and of course, Ukraine has now added to the mix with Russian aggression displacing within Ukraine or outside of Ukraine two thirds of the children in that country, as well as of, course, many, many adults.</p>
<p>So we are simply grateful for the work that you’re doing every single day to try to meet the needs of those who have been forced in one way or another from their homes.</p>
<p>The partnership that we have between the United States and UNHCR, working together to find ways to resettle people, to care for them, and I think as well the work that we need to do together not only to resettle, ultimately end conflicts so that people can go home, but also to find more effective ways in helping those communities support the refugees that are with them.</p>
<p>So in all of these ways, there is a lot of work to be done, a lot of work we’re doing every single day between us.  But mostly this is an opportunity as well just to say thank you, because what you’re doing is an invaluable service to humanity at a time when it’s more needed than ever.  So welcome.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Mr. Secretary, how will the U.S. expedite getting Ukrainians &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Please.</p>
<p><b>MR GRANDI:</b>  Bear with me, just a few words also on my side to thank Secretary Blinken and his colleagues for welcoming us here at the State Department.  And I just want – he said it all, really.  I just want to add, this figure that he mentioned, 95 million – maybe 96 by the way, who knows – has gone up by 12 million in less than two months with the crisis in Ukraine, with the Russian offensive against Ukraine and the flight of so many people.  So that will be a priority for us to discuss and already I’ve been here a couple of days in Washington and had very good discussions on how to respond to this crisis both in neighboring countries and inside Ukraine.</p>
<p>But then, of course, an important message that I’m sure everybody will agree here around the table is that that crisis should not make us forget everything else.  We’ve been dealing intensely together with the Afghanistan situation for the past few months, but there are many, unfortunately many, crises in Africa, in the Western Hemisphere, that involve a huge displacement component, and therefore I look forward to continuing our cooperation.</p>
<p>The United States is UNHCR’s by far largest donor.  It is the largest resettlement country and with our partnership with the United States in these areas has been extremely strong.  And I want to take this opportunity to thank this administration.  Without the United States, we could not be as effective as you kindly recognized us to be, and we look forward to even strengthening even further this partnership, which is globally and domestically extremely important.  So thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Good morning, everyone.  I am very pleased for this opportunity to meet with the High Commissioner for Refugees at the UN Filippo Grandi.  It’s safe to say that this is a time of extraordinary challenge for everything that you’re doing and everything that we’re so indebted to you and your team for doing.</p>
<p>I believe, as you said, the number of displaced people around the world now is somewhere in the vicinity of 95 million people.  And within that huge number of refugees, I think if you added up all of the refugees and tried to put them in one country, it would be larger than the population of Spain, South Korea, any number of countries.  This is a challenge that has been with us for well over the past decade.  When I was last in government, we were dealing with particularly acute challenges – of course, Syria, Iraq, but also in many other parts of the world from Africa to Southeast Asia to our own hemisphere.</p>
<p>We’ve only seen that challenge increase, and of course, Ukraine has now added to the mix with Russian aggression displacing within Ukraine or outside of Ukraine two thirds of the children in that country, as well as of, course, many, many adults.</p>
<p>So we are simply grateful for the work that you’re doing every single day to try to meet the needs of those who have been forced in one way or another from their homes.</p>
<p>The partnership that we have between the United States and UNHCR, working together to find ways to resettle people, to care for them, and I think as well the work that we need to do together not only to resettle, ultimately end conflicts so that people can go home, but also to find more effective ways in helping those communities support the refugees that are with them.</p>
<p>So in all of these ways, there is a lot of work to be done, a lot of work we’re doing every single day between us.  But mostly this is an opportunity as well just to say thank you, because what you’re doing is an invaluable service to humanity at a time when it’s more needed than ever.  So welcome.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Mr. Secretary, how will the U.S. expedite getting Ukrainians &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Please.</p>
<p><b>MR GRANDI:</b>  Bear with me, just a few words also on my side to thank Secretary Blinken and his colleagues for welcoming us here at the State Department.  And I just want – he said it all, really.  I just want to add, this figure that he mentioned, 95 million – maybe 96 by the way, who knows – has gone up by 12 million in less than two months with the crisis in Ukraine, with the Russian offensive against Ukraine and the flight of so many people.  So that will be a priority for us to discuss and already I’ve been here a couple of days in Washington and had very good discussions on how to respond to this crisis both in neighboring countries and inside Ukraine.</p>
<p>But then, of course, an important message that I’m sure everybody will agree here around the table is that that crisis should not make us forget everything else.  We’ve been dealing intensely together with the Afghanistan situation for the past few months, but there are many, unfortunately many, crises in Africa, in the Western Hemisphere, that involve a huge displacement component, and therefore I look forward to continuing our cooperation.</p>
<p>The United States is UNHCR’s by far largest donor.  It is the largest resettlement country and with our partnership with the United States in these areas has been extremely strong.  And I want to take this opportunity to thank this administration.  Without the United States, we could not be as effective as you kindly recognized us to be, and we look forward to even strengthening even further this partnership, which is globally and domestically extremely important.  So thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Green Shipping Corridors</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/green-shipping-corridors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 17:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><i>In support of the effort to achieve global net-zero greenhouse gas emissions by no later than 2050, and in support of the effort to achieve zero greenhouse gas emissions from the international shipping sector by the same year, the United States is charting a course to advance domestic and international green shipping corridors.</i></p>
<p>&#8212;</p>
<p>Greenhouse gas emissions from the shipping sector are significant and rising.  Shipping would be the eighth largest emitter if it were a “country,” and by 2050, emissions from the sector are projected to increase by up to 50% from 2018 levels under a business-as-usual scenario.  This trajectory is not compatible with the goals of the Paris Agreement.  To support the effort to achieve global net-zero greenhouse gas emissions by no later than 2050, the United States has committed to work with countries to reach zero emissions from international shipping by the same year.</p>
<p>Green shipping corridors can spur early and rapid adoption of fuels and technologies that, on a lifecycle basis, deliver low- and zero-emissions across the maritime sector, placing the sector on a pathway to full decarbonization.  <b>The United States envisions green shipping corridors as maritime routes that showcase low- and zero-emission lifecycle fuels and technologies with the ambition to achieve zero greenhouse gas emissions across all aspects of the corridor in support of sector-wide decarbonization no later than 2050.</b>  There are multiple pathways through which a fully decarbonized corridor can be achieved; this green shipping corridors framework therefore provides maritime stakeholders the flexibility to choose the path that best suits their needs.</p>
<p>There is a growing movement of countries and non-state actors that are focused on green shipping corridors.  In addition, private sector actors, including major users of maritime shipping, are increasingly making climate commitments and seeking opportunities to decarbonize their supply chains.  For our part, the United States is partnering internationally, working on implementation domestically, and investing in the research and development needed to help ensure we have the solutions necessary to meet our commitments.<sup>1</sup>  Within this growing movement, however, there is not yet a shared understanding of what it means for a maritime corridor to be “green.”  This document is intended to contribute to a common vision of green shipping corridors and advance the effort to establish them across the ocean and along coasts and inland waterways, so that maritime stakeholders may act as a united front to tackle the climate crisis.<i> </i></p>
<p><b>Charting a Course for Green Shipping Corridors</b></p>
<p>Achieving zero emissions from maritime transportation over the coming years and decades will require research, development, demonstration, and deployment at a massive scale, as well as enabling policies that incentivize the shift to low- and zero-emission fuels and technologies as soon as possible.  Adoption of these fuels and technologies, while limited in the short term, will rapidly accelerate once the supply chain is established and governments and the shipping sector signal their intent for energy transition.</p>
<p>Green shipping corridors are meant to accelerate this early adoption phase. They therefore should strive for emissions reductions that push the envelope beyond business-as-usual, demonstrating a commitment to achieve full decarbonization through sustained efforts.  Green shipping corridors will not achieve zero emissions across all aspects of the corridor overnight.  Instead, the journey to establish a fully decarbonized corridor is a series of steps and actions taken over time to cover all aspects of the route.</p>
<p>One of the first steps in creating a green shipping corridor is to convene relevant stakeholders across the value chain and to outline anticipated timelines, targets, and achievements.  Creating a fully decarbonized green shipping corridor is a process, which will require long-term plans to help participants achieve their emissions reduction goals.  Stakeholder engagement will be critical, especially with residents in communities with environmental justice concerns, to ensure strategies are tailored to address the priorities and goals of near-port communities.</p>
<p><b>Demonstrating Progress and Success  </b></p>
<p>In the effort to confront the climate crisis, advance environmental justice, and drive maritime emissions to zero, it is not enough to only announce intentions.  Ports, carriers, and other actors in the value chain are encouraged to demonstrate progress, commitment, and accountability.  Local and state governments, as well as the Federal Government, can help by convening stakeholders, enforcing regulations, and crafting policy that supports green corridor development.  All stakeholders should share information on green corridor development on a regular basis and to be as transparent as possible in the data and information shared.</p>
<p>Such information sharing should include publication of baseline emissions and energy inventories with regular updates on progress toward targets and goals.  As additional data on the successes of the corridor operations become available, those data should be reported using verifiable methods and metrics that can be replicated over time to demonstrate improvement.  This data and information sharing helps to ensure that metrics and calculations are comparable across other corridors and varying technologies, sharing information for those considering similar measures and providing unbiased information for decision-making.  To achieve zero-emission operations, stakeholders should use lifecycle emissions assessment tools and analyses that incorporate internationally accepted methodologies.</p>
<p>Participants in a green shipping corridor effort should be transparent not only about data but also about their role in the effort.  As such, publicly available information should also include value-chain actors such as ports, terminal operators, vessel owners and operators, charter companies, beneficial cargo owners, and others such as logistics companies that are engaged in this important effort.</p>
<p><b>Building Blocks for Green Shipping Corridors</b></p>
<p>Planning for green corridors should consider the needs and abilities of all corridor stakeholders.  Possible components of the green shipping corridor planning process could include, but are not limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li><i>Identify and convene relevant stakeholders</i><i></i></li>
<li><i>Define the scope, boundaries, metrics, and the framework for analysis</i><i></i></li>
<li><i>Incorporate lifecycle-emissions estimates into equipment, materials, and fueling infrastructure planning and development decisions</i><i></i></li>
<li><i>Estimate a baseline emissions inventory for port and/or vessel operations that can be publicly available and used to craft emissions reduction targets</i><i></i></li>
<li><i>Work with stakeholders and communities to develop an implementation plan that outlines a pathway to achieving emissions reductions targets</i></li>
</ul>
<p>Building on the planning process, there are a number of building blocks for implementation of green corridors to reach the goal of full decarbonization.  Elements of this implementation process could include, but are not limited to, the deployment and/or operation of:</p>
<ul>
<li><i>Alternative refueling or recharging infrastructure to support zero emissions port and terminal equipment operations</i><i></i></li>
<li><i>Support vessels and commercial harbor craft using low- or zero-emission</i><i>fuels and technologies</i><i></i></li>
<li><i>Ocean-going vessels using low- or zero-emission fuels and technologies</i><i></i></li>
<li><i>Zero-emissions fuels, bunkering, and refueling capabilities for vessels</i><i>including electrification and cold ironing</i><i></i></li>
<li><i>Energy efficiency and operations optimization activities that lead to reduced overall energy consumption and reduce greenhouse gas emissions</i></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Looking Ahead</b></p>
<p>Green shipping corridors are a key means of spurring the early adoption of zero-emission fuels and technologies that will help place the sector on a credible pathway to achieve zero emissions no later than 2050.  The United States welcomes and encourages the growing movement to establish green shipping corridors and calls on countries and value-chain actors around the world to adopt ambitious actions to implement green shipping corridors and to create a clean future for maritime transportation.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><i>In support of the effort to achieve global net-zero greenhouse gas emissions by no later than 2050, and in support of the effort to achieve zero greenhouse gas emissions from the international shipping sector by the same year, the United States is charting a course to advance domestic and international green shipping corridors.</i></p>
<p>&#8212;</p>
<p>Greenhouse gas emissions from the shipping sector are significant and rising.  Shipping would be the eighth largest emitter if it were a “country,” and by 2050, emissions from the sector are projected to increase by up to 50% from 2018 levels under a business-as-usual scenario.  This trajectory is not compatible with the goals of the Paris Agreement.  To support the effort to achieve global net-zero greenhouse gas emissions by no later than 2050, the United States has committed to work with countries to reach zero emissions from international shipping by the same year.</p>
<p>Green shipping corridors can spur early and rapid adoption of fuels and technologies that, on a lifecycle basis, deliver low- and zero-emissions across the maritime sector, placing the sector on a pathway to full decarbonization.  <b>The United States envisions green shipping corridors as maritime routes that showcase low- and zero-emission lifecycle fuels and technologies with the ambition to achieve zero greenhouse gas emissions across all aspects of the corridor in support of sector-wide decarbonization no later than 2050.</b>  There are multiple pathways through which a fully decarbonized corridor can be achieved; this green shipping corridors framework therefore provides maritime stakeholders the flexibility to choose the path that best suits their needs.</p>
<p>There is a growing movement of countries and non-state actors that are focused on green shipping corridors.  In addition, private sector actors, including major users of maritime shipping, are increasingly making climate commitments and seeking opportunities to decarbonize their supply chains.  For our part, the United States is partnering internationally, working on implementation domestically, and investing in the research and development needed to help ensure we have the solutions necessary to meet our commitments.<sup>1</sup>  Within this growing movement, however, there is not yet a shared understanding of what it means for a maritime corridor to be “green.”  This document is intended to contribute to a common vision of green shipping corridors and advance the effort to establish them across the ocean and along coasts and inland waterways, so that maritime stakeholders may act as a united front to tackle the climate crisis.<i> </i></p>
<p><b>Charting a Course for Green Shipping Corridors</b></p>
<p>Achieving zero emissions from maritime transportation over the coming years and decades will require research, development, demonstration, and deployment at a massive scale, as well as enabling policies that incentivize the shift to low- and zero-emission fuels and technologies as soon as possible.  Adoption of these fuels and technologies, while limited in the short term, will rapidly accelerate once the supply chain is established and governments and the shipping sector signal their intent for energy transition.</p>
<p>Green shipping corridors are meant to accelerate this early adoption phase. They therefore should strive for emissions reductions that push the envelope beyond business-as-usual, demonstrating a commitment to achieve full decarbonization through sustained efforts.  Green shipping corridors will not achieve zero emissions across all aspects of the corridor overnight.  Instead, the journey to establish a fully decarbonized corridor is a series of steps and actions taken over time to cover all aspects of the route.</p>
<p>One of the first steps in creating a green shipping corridor is to convene relevant stakeholders across the value chain and to outline anticipated timelines, targets, and achievements.  Creating a fully decarbonized green shipping corridor is a process, which will require long-term plans to help participants achieve their emissions reduction goals.  Stakeholder engagement will be critical, especially with residents in communities with environmental justice concerns, to ensure strategies are tailored to address the priorities and goals of near-port communities.</p>
<p><b>Demonstrating Progress and Success  </b></p>
<p>In the effort to confront the climate crisis, advance environmental justice, and drive maritime emissions to zero, it is not enough to only announce intentions.  Ports, carriers, and other actors in the value chain are encouraged to demonstrate progress, commitment, and accountability.  Local and state governments, as well as the Federal Government, can help by convening stakeholders, enforcing regulations, and crafting policy that supports green corridor development.  All stakeholders should share information on green corridor development on a regular basis and to be as transparent as possible in the data and information shared.</p>
<p>Such information sharing should include publication of baseline emissions and energy inventories with regular updates on progress toward targets and goals.  As additional data on the successes of the corridor operations become available, those data should be reported using verifiable methods and metrics that can be replicated over time to demonstrate improvement.  This data and information sharing helps to ensure that metrics and calculations are comparable across other corridors and varying technologies, sharing information for those considering similar measures and providing unbiased information for decision-making.  To achieve zero-emission operations, stakeholders should use lifecycle emissions assessment tools and analyses that incorporate internationally accepted methodologies.</p>
<p>Participants in a green shipping corridor effort should be transparent not only about data but also about their role in the effort.  As such, publicly available information should also include value-chain actors such as ports, terminal operators, vessel owners and operators, charter companies, beneficial cargo owners, and others such as logistics companies that are engaged in this important effort.</p>
<p><b>Building Blocks for Green Shipping Corridors</b></p>
<p>Planning for green corridors should consider the needs and abilities of all corridor stakeholders.  Possible components of the green shipping corridor planning process could include, but are not limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li><i>Identify and convene relevant stakeholders</i><i></i></li>
<li><i>Define the scope, boundaries, metrics, and the framework for analysis</i><i></i></li>
<li><i>Incorporate lifecycle-emissions estimates into equipment, materials, and fueling infrastructure planning and development decisions</i><i></i></li>
<li><i>Estimate a baseline emissions inventory for port and/or vessel operations that can be publicly available and used to craft emissions reduction targets</i><i></i></li>
<li><i>Work with stakeholders and communities to develop an implementation plan that outlines a pathway to achieving emissions reductions targets</i></li>
</ul>
<p>Building on the planning process, there are a number of building blocks for implementation of green corridors to reach the goal of full decarbonization.  Elements of this implementation process could include, but are not limited to, the deployment and/or operation of:</p>
<ul>
<li><i>Alternative refueling or recharging infrastructure to support zero emissions port and terminal equipment operations</i><i></i></li>
<li><i>Support vessels and commercial harbor craft using low- or zero-emission</i><i>fuels and technologies</i><i></i></li>
<li><i>Ocean-going vessels using low- or zero-emission fuels and technologies</i><i></i></li>
<li><i>Zero-emissions fuels, bunkering, and refueling capabilities for vessels</i><i>including electrification and cold ironing</i><i></i></li>
<li><i>Energy efficiency and operations optimization activities that lead to reduced overall energy consumption and reduce greenhouse gas emissions</i></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Looking Ahead</b></p>
<p>Green shipping corridors are a key means of spurring the early adoption of zero-emission fuels and technologies that will help place the sector on a credible pathway to achieve zero emissions no later than 2050.  The United States welcomes and encourages the growing movement to establish green shipping corridors and calls on countries and value-chain actors around the world to adopt ambitious actions to implement green shipping corridors and to create a clean future for maritime transportation.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meeting of the Advisory Committee on International Postal and Delivery Services</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/meeting-of-the-advisory-committee-on-international-postal-and-delivery-services-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 17:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On April 27, 2022, the Department of State’s Advisory Committee on International Postal and Delivery Services will convene to review the results of the August 2021 Abidjan Congress of the Universal Postal Union.  At the meeting, the State Department will present key elements of a reform proposal it will submit to the recently convened Task Force on opening the UPU to the wider postal sector, a body tasked to prepare for the UPU’s late-2023 Extraordinary Congress.</p>
<p>The meeting will take place from 1:00 p.m. to 5:00 p.m. Eastern Time via a Zoom platform, as follows:</p>
<p>Meeting:</p>
<p><a class="external-link" href="https://statedept.zoomgov.com/j/1617289259?pwd=VnA1Q1ZIS0IrNlZFN0FHV2FGT0l5QT09" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://statedept.zoomgov.com/j/1617289259?pwd=VnA1Q1ZIS0IrNlZFN0FHV2FGT0l5QT09</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p>Meeting ID: 161 728 9259</p>
<p>Passcode: 123456</p>
<p>One tap mobile</p>
<p>+16692545252,,1617289259# US (San Jose)</p>
<p>+16468287666,,1617289259# US (New York)</p>
<p>Dial by your location</p>
<p>+1 669 254 5252 US (San Jose)</p>
<p>+1 646 828 7666 US (New York)</p>
<p>+1 669 216 1590 US (San Jose)</p>
<p>+1 551 285 1373 US</p>
<p>Any member of the public may observe the proceedings.</p>
<p>For questions concerning the meeting or access to the meeting documents please contact</p>
<p><a href="mailto:IO-Press-DL@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IO-Press-DL@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On April 27, 2022, the Department of State’s Advisory Committee on International Postal and Delivery Services will convene to review the results of the August 2021 Abidjan Congress of the Universal Postal Union.  At the meeting, the State Department will present key elements of a reform proposal it will submit to the recently convened Task Force on opening the UPU to the wider postal sector, a body tasked to prepare for the UPU’s late-2023 Extraordinary Congress.</p>
<p>The meeting will take place from 1:00 p.m. to 5:00 p.m. Eastern Time via a Zoom platform, as follows:</p>
<p>Meeting:</p>
<p><a class="external-link" href="https://statedept.zoomgov.com/j/1617289259?pwd=VnA1Q1ZIS0IrNlZFN0FHV2FGT0l5QT09" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://statedept.zoomgov.com/j/1617289259?pwd=VnA1Q1ZIS0IrNlZFN0FHV2FGT0l5QT09</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p>Meeting ID: 161 728 9259</p>
<p>Passcode: 123456</p>
<p>One tap mobile</p>
<p>+16692545252,,1617289259# US (San Jose)</p>
<p>+16468287666,,1617289259# US (New York)</p>
<p>Dial by your location</p>
<p>+1 669 254 5252 US (San Jose)</p>
<p>+1 646 828 7666 US (New York)</p>
<p>+1 669 216 1590 US (San Jose)</p>
<p>+1 551 285 1373 US</p>
<p>Any member of the public may observe the proceedings.</p>
<p>For questions concerning the meeting or access to the meeting documents please contact</p>
<p><a href="mailto:IO-Press-DL@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IO-Press-DL@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary of State for Consular Affairs Rena Bitter Travels to Tokyo, Jakarta, Singapore, Manila, and Los Angeles</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-of-state-for-consular-affairs-rena-bitter-travels-to-tokyo-jakarta-singapore-manila-and-los-angeles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 14:56:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for Consular Affairs Rena Bitter will travel April 12-22 to Tokyo, Jakarta, Singapore, Manila, and Los Angeles.  During the overseas portion of her trip, she will observe consular operations and meet with consular staff to see first-hand their work to serve U.S. citizens overseas and reduce visa wait times, in support of international travel and its key role in economic revitalization.  She will also meet with host government officials to discuss topics of mutual interest and underscore bilateral cooperation on a wide range of consular issues.  In Los Angeles, she will observe U.S. passport facility operations and meet with staff.</p>
<p>For press inquiries please contact <a href="mailto:CAPRESSREQUESTS@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CAPRESSREQUESTS@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for Consular Affairs Rena Bitter will travel April 12-22 to Tokyo, Jakarta, Singapore, Manila, and Los Angeles.  During the overseas portion of her trip, she will observe consular operations and meet with consular staff to see first-hand their work to serve U.S. citizens overseas and reduce visa wait times, in support of international travel and its key role in economic revitalization.  She will also meet with host government officials to discuss topics of mutual interest and underscore bilateral cooperation on a wide range of consular issues.  In Los Angeles, she will observe U.S. passport facility operations and meet with staff.</p>
<p>For press inquiries please contact <a href="mailto:CAPRESSREQUESTS@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CAPRESSREQUESTS@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken to Deliver Remarks and Participate in the U.S.-India Higher Education Discussion with Indian External Affairs Minister Jaishankar at Howard University</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinken-to-deliver-remarks-and-participate-in-the-u-s-india-higher-education-discussion-with-indian-external-affairs-minister-jaishankar-at-howard-university/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 14:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333617</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will deliver remarks and participate in a conversation with students, faculty, and leadership of Howard University at 4:30 p.m. today, Tuesday, April 12, 2022.  The Secretary will be joined by Indian External Affairs Minister Dr. S. Jaishankar and State Department Assistant Secretary for Educational and Cultural Affairs Lee Satterfield.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken and Minister Jaishankar will meet with Indian students, scholars, and researchers who have worked in the United States, and U.S. students, scholars, and researchers who have studied, worked, or conducted research at an Indian higher education institution.  This event is an opportunity to build off yesterday’s announcement during the 2+2 Ministerial of the formation of a ‘Working Group on Education and Skill Training.’  Howard University’s significant role deepening people-to-people ties between India and the United States make this an ideal setting to continue developing the links between our citizens in such an important area of cooperation.</p>
<p>The event will be pooled in-person press coverage and will be live-streamed on <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTIuNTYyODc1MzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi8ifQ.5JjckXzWv4jyHSEyupDQXx0WwQNcq1X83REPE3TpKls/s/1039202793/br/129674987556-l" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTIuNTYyODc1MzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi8ifQ.5JjckXzWv4jyHSEyupDQXx0WwQNcq1X83REPE3TpKls/s/1039202793/br/129674987556-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649860420600000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0YoKVWhwOXIAQk0igHq1yW">www.state.gov</a> and <a class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/statedept" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">www.YouTube.com/statedept</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact the Office of Press Relations at <a href="mailto:EventsandTravel@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EventsandTravel@state.gov</a>. <wbr /></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will deliver remarks and participate in a conversation with students, faculty, and leadership of Howard University at 4:30 p.m. today, Tuesday, April 12, 2022.  The Secretary will be joined by Indian External Affairs Minister Dr. S. Jaishankar and State Department Assistant Secretary for Educational and Cultural Affairs Lee Satterfield.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken and Minister Jaishankar will meet with Indian students, scholars, and researchers who have worked in the United States, and U.S. students, scholars, and researchers who have studied, worked, or conducted research at an Indian higher education institution.  This event is an opportunity to build off yesterday’s announcement during the 2+2 Ministerial of the formation of a ‘Working Group on Education and Skill Training.’  Howard University’s significant role deepening people-to-people ties between India and the United States make this an ideal setting to continue developing the links between our citizens in such an important area of cooperation.</p>
<p>The event will be pooled in-person press coverage and will be live-streamed on <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTIuNTYyODc1MzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi8ifQ.5JjckXzWv4jyHSEyupDQXx0WwQNcq1X83REPE3TpKls/s/1039202793/br/129674987556-l" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTIuNTYyODc1MzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi8ifQ.5JjckXzWv4jyHSEyupDQXx0WwQNcq1X83REPE3TpKls/s/1039202793/br/129674987556-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649860420600000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0YoKVWhwOXIAQk0igHq1yW">www.state.gov</a> and <a class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/statedept" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">www.YouTube.com/statedept</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact the Office of Press Relations at <a href="mailto:EventsandTravel@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EventsandTravel@state.gov</a>. <wbr /></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thailand New Year – Songkran</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/thailand-new-year-songkran/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 14:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333610</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I wish the people of the Kingdom of Thailand a healthy and prosperous year ahead as you celebrate Songkran, the Thai New Year.</p>
<p>The alliance and friendship between the United States and Thailand are built on a shared commitment to a safe and secure future for all American and Thai people.  Together, we have fought infectious diseases, responded to natural disasters, and protected economic security across the Pacific Ocean.  Our partnership endures, and we stand ready to face evolving challenges &#8212; like the pandemic and the climate crisis &#8212; that impact all global citizens.  At the same time, we will continue to build on our strong people-to-people ties and shared values.</p>
<p>After two years in which the COVID-19 pandemic has dampened festivities, this year’s celebration is a particularly poignant reminder of how holiday traditions express a nation’s deepest values and aspirations.  We offer our best wishes to all Thai people in the coming year.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I wish the people of the Kingdom of Thailand a healthy and prosperous year ahead as you celebrate Songkran, the Thai New Year.</p>
<p>The alliance and friendship between the United States and Thailand are built on a shared commitment to a safe and secure future for all American and Thai people.  Together, we have fought infectious diseases, responded to natural disasters, and protected economic security across the Pacific Ocean.  Our partnership endures, and we stand ready to face evolving challenges &#8212; like the pandemic and the climate crisis &#8212; that impact all global citizens.  At the same time, we will continue to build on our strong people-to-people ties and shared values.</p>
<p>After two years in which the COVID-19 pandemic has dampened festivities, this year’s celebration is a particularly poignant reminder of how holiday traditions express a nation’s deepest values and aspirations.  We offer our best wishes to all Thai people in the coming year.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lao New Year 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/lao-new-year-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 14:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I convey my best wishes to the Lao People’s Democratic Republic on the occasion of the Lao New Year.</p>
<p>As our Comprehensive Partnership with Laos continues to grow, we look forward to strengthening our relationship based on mutual respect, common interests, and a shared desire to build a stronger foundation for the future of our countries.  As we advance our shared global and Indo-Pacific priorities together, we are committed to bolstering people-to-people ties and promoting our cooperative efforts on public health, regional security, and expanded trade and investment.</p>
<p>We wish all in the Lao People’s Democratic Republic a happy and healthy New Year.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I convey my best wishes to the Lao People’s Democratic Republic on the occasion of the Lao New Year.</p>
<p>As our Comprehensive Partnership with Laos continues to grow, we look forward to strengthening our relationship based on mutual respect, common interests, and a shared desire to build a stronger foundation for the future of our countries.  As we advance our shared global and Indo-Pacific priorities together, we are committed to bolstering people-to-people ties and promoting our cooperative efforts on public health, regional security, and expanded trade and investment.</p>
<p>We wish all in the Lao People’s Democratic Republic a happy and healthy New Year.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Khmer New Year 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/khmer-new-year-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 14:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I extend my best wishes to the Cambodian people on the occasion of the Khmer New Year.</p>
<p>As Cambodians gather to celebrate, we are reminded of Cambodia’s rich and vibrant culture. We are honored to continue building the strong cultural connections between the United States and the Kingdom of Cambodia, and we look forward to further advancing our relationship to build a more prosperous, democratic, and independent Cambodia.</p>
<p>May all Cambodians enjoy a prosperous and healthy new year.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I extend my best wishes to the Cambodian people on the occasion of the Khmer New Year.</p>
<p>As Cambodians gather to celebrate, we are reminded of Cambodia’s rich and vibrant culture. We are honored to continue building the strong cultural connections between the United States and the Kingdom of Cambodia, and we look forward to further advancing our relationship to build a more prosperous, democratic, and independent Cambodia.</p>
<p>May all Cambodians enjoy a prosperous and healthy new year.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department of State Offers Reward for Information to Bring Three Irish Transnational Criminals to Justice</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/department-of-state-offers-reward-for-information-to-bring-three-irish-transnational-criminals-to-justice/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 12:27:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333527</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State is announcing rewards of up to $5 million for information leading to each of the arrests and/or convictions of Irish transnational organized criminal Christopher Vincent Kinahan and his two sons, Daniel Joseph Kinahan and Christopher Kinahan, Jr.<u>,</u> for participating in, or conspiring to participate in, transnational organized crime.  After initially distributing South American cocaine and heroin in Ireland, the Kinahans later expanded their narcotics trafficking organization to include the United Kingdom and then throughout mainland Europe.  In addition to narcotics trafficking, the Kinahans have engaged in money laundering, firearms trafficking, and murder.</p>
<p>Today’s reward offer announcement complements the Department of Treasury’s announcement of sanctions against the Kinahans pursuant to Executive Order 14059, <i>Imposing Sanctions on Foreign Persons Involved in the Global Illicit Drug Trade. </i>The reward is offered jointly with the An Garda Síochana (AGS) in Ireland and the National Crime Agency (NCA) in the United Kingdom. Together with the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA), these agencies will work to combat drug trafficking and transnational crime by the Kinahan Transnational Criminal Organization wherever it exists.</p>
<p>This reward is offered under the Department of State’s Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program (TOCRP).  The TOCRP and Narcot<wbr />ics Rewards Program (NRP) have helped bring more than 75 transnational criminals and major narcotics traffickers to justice since the inception of the NRP in 1986.  The Department has paid more than $135 million in rewards under these programs for information leading to apprehensions and convictions.</p>
<p>The Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs manages the TOCRP in close coordination with federal law enforcement partners and other U.S. government agencies.  These actions demonstrate the Department’s commitment to supporting law enforcement efforts to bring transnational criminals to justice.</p>
<p>For more information on the individuals listed above and the NRP and TOCRP, please see <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs/inl-rewards-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTIuNTYyNzY2NzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1LW9mLWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtbmFyY290aWNzLWFuZC1sYXctZW5mb3JjZW1lbnQtYWZmYWlycy9pbmwtcmV3YXJkcy1wcm9ncmFtLyJ9.-l-2wo-ZLZhu_S-zmvLRUYEzCtyH10ouiqRa58kBYkE/s/2171565732/br/129667581271-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649852470627000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3el3fUnkbevB9e2kONcuIA">https://www.state.gov/<wbr />bureau-of-international-<wbr />narcotics-and-law-enforcement-<wbr />affairs/inl-rewards-program/</a><u>.</u></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State is announcing rewards of up to $5 million for information leading to each of the arrests and/or convictions of Irish transnational organized criminal Christopher Vincent Kinahan and his two sons, Daniel Joseph Kinahan and Christopher Kinahan, Jr.<u>,</u> for participating in, or conspiring to participate in, transnational organized crime.  After initially distributing South American cocaine and heroin in Ireland, the Kinahans later expanded their narcotics trafficking organization to include the United Kingdom and then throughout mainland Europe.  In addition to narcotics trafficking, the Kinahans have engaged in money laundering, firearms trafficking, and murder.</p>
<p>Today’s reward offer announcement complements the Department of Treasury’s announcement of sanctions against the Kinahans pursuant to Executive Order 14059, <i>Imposing Sanctions on Foreign Persons Involved in the Global Illicit Drug Trade. </i>The reward is offered jointly with the An Garda Síochana (AGS) in Ireland and the National Crime Agency (NCA) in the United Kingdom. Together with the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA), these agencies will work to combat drug trafficking and transnational crime by the Kinahan Transnational Criminal Organization wherever it exists.</p>
<p>This reward is offered under the Department of State’s Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program (TOCRP).  The TOCRP and Narcot<wbr />ics Rewards Program (NRP) have helped bring more than 75 transnational criminals and major narcotics traffickers to justice since the inception of the NRP in 1986.  The Department has paid more than $135 million in rewards under these programs for information leading to apprehensions and convictions.</p>
<p>The Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs manages the TOCRP in close coordination with federal law enforcement partners and other U.S. government agencies.  These actions demonstrate the Department’s commitment to supporting law enforcement efforts to bring transnational criminals to justice.</p>
<p>For more information on the individuals listed above and the NRP and TOCRP, please see <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs/inl-rewards-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTIuNTYyNzY2NzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1LW9mLWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtbmFyY290aWNzLWFuZC1sYXctZW5mb3JjZW1lbnQtYWZmYWlycy9pbmwtcmV3YXJkcy1wcm9ncmFtLyJ9.-l-2wo-ZLZhu_S-zmvLRUYEzCtyH10ouiqRa58kBYkE/s/2171565732/br/129667581271-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649852470627000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3el3fUnkbevB9e2kONcuIA">https://www.state.gov/<wbr />bureau-of-international-<wbr />narcotics-and-law-enforcement-<wbr />affairs/inl-rewards-program/</a><u>.</u></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fourth Annual U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/fourth-annual-u-s-india-22-ministerial-dialogue/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 04:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333498</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and India on the occasion of the Fourth Annual U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue in 2022.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken and Secretary of Defense Lloyd J. Austin III welcomed Minister of Defence Rajnath Singh and Minister of External Affairs Dr. S. Jaishankar to Washington, D.C., on April 11, 2022, for the fourth U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue. The Dialogue was preceded by a virtual meeting between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and President Joseph Biden.</p>
<p>As natural and trusted partners celebrating 75 years of diplomatic relations between the United States and independent India, with a shared commitment to democracy and pluralism, a multifaceted bilateral agenda, and growing convergence of strategic interests, both countries seek to continue to promote a resilient, rules-based international order that safeguards sovereignty and territorial integrity, upholds democratic values, and promotes peace and prosperity for all.</p>
<p>Building upon the September 2021 meeting between President Biden and Prime Minister Modi, and their respective participation in Summits related to COVID-19, climate, infrastructure and supply chain resilience, the Ministers reaffirmed the importance of the U.S.-India Comprehensive Global Strategic Partnership to international peace and security.</p>
<p><em>Global Partnership and Indo-Pacific Cooperation</em></p>
<p>The Ministers reviewed mutual efforts to respond to the worsening humanitarian crisis in Ukraine and assessed its broader implications. They urged an immediate cessation of hostilities. The Ministers unequivocally condemned civilian deaths.  They underscored that the contemporary global order has been built on the UN Charter, respect for international law, and the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states.</p>
<p>Recalling the inaugural virtual Quad Leaders’ Summit in March 2021, the in-person Quad Leaders’ Summit in September 2021 in Washington, the February 2022 Quad Foreign Ministers’ meeting in Melbourne, and looking forward to the next Quad Leaders’ Summit in Tokyo in 2022, the Ministers reaffirmed their commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific in which the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states are respected, and countries are free from military, economic, and political coercion. They further reaffirmed their dedication to promoting regional stability and prosperity, with an inclusive regional architecture, abiding by the rule of law, the freedom of navigation and overflight, peaceful resolution of disputes, and ASEAN centrality. They also reiterated the importance of adherence to international law to meet challenges to the rules-based order, including in the South China Sea.</p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the progress made in the last year on developing a positive and constructive agenda for the Quad to deliver peace and prosperity to the region in pursuance of their shared vision for a free, open, and inclusive Indo-Pacific. The Ministers reiterated their commitment to the take forward the initiatives announced by the Leaders, to empower the Quad as a force for global good for the Indo-Pacific region and welcomed ongoing discussions in the Quad Working Groups on vaccines, climate change, infrastructure, space, cyber security, and critical and emerging technologies for delivering practical and tangible benefits to the region.</p>
<p>Welcoming the remarkable progress made under the Quad Vaccine Partnership to augment the manufacturing capacity of the Biological E facility in India, supported by the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC), the Ministers committed to expedite delivery of the first batch of vaccines to countries of the Indo-Pacific and beyond and to diversify the basket of vaccines in the context of changes in the global demand and supply landscape.</p>
<p>Following up on the October 2021 virtual meeting of the Foreign Ministers of India, Israel, the United Arab Emirates, and the United States, the Ministers welcomed the opportunity to enhance engagement in this forum on shared priorities such as food security, clean energy, waste management, and infrastructure development.</p>
<p>The United States congratulated India for its significant contributions as a member of the United Nations Security Council (UNSC) for the term 2021-2022. In this context, the United States expressed its appreciation for India’s leadership as the Chair of the three Committees of the Security Council: the 1988 Taliban Sanctions Committee, the 1970 Libya Sanctions Committee and the 1373 Counter Terrorism Committee.</p>
<p>The Ministers reiterated their commitment to work together in close coordination at the UNSC and in international organizations. The United States reaffirmed its continued support for India’s permanent membership in a reformed UNSC and for India’s entry to the Nuclear Suppliers’ Group.</p>
<p>Considering growing national security threats from both state and non-state malicious cyber actors, the Ministers recognized the importance of an open, interoperable, secure, and reliable Internet and stable cyberspace.  Both sides reaffirmed the 2021 reports of the UN Open Ended Working Group and the UN Group of Governmental Experts, which articulate a framework of responsible state behavior in cyberspace and committed to work together in future multilateral negotiations to encourage States to implement the framework. They confirmed their intent to work closely as part of ongoing efforts to counter the use of information communications technologies for criminal purposes.</p>
<p>Acknowledging India’s distinguished history of leading peacekeeping missions, the United States welcomed India’s commitment to participate in multilateral peacekeeping training in 2022, expand joint-capacity building efforts with third-country partners, and launch a new joint National Investigation Officers Training of Trainers course in partnership with the United Nations.</p>
<p>The Ministers called on the Taliban to abide by UNSC Resolution 2593 (2021), which demands that Afghan territory must never again be used to threaten or attack any country or to shelter or train terrorists, or to plan or finance terrorist attacks.  The Ministers urged the Taliban to adhere to these and all other commitments; respect the human rights of all Afghans, including women, children, and members of minority groups; and uphold freedom of travel. They also emphasized the importance of an inclusive Afghan government and unhindered access for the United Nations and its implementing partners to deliver humanitarian assistance. The Ministers recommitted to close consultations on Afghanistan to help facilitate an inclusive and peaceful future for all Afghans.</p>
<p>The Ministers called for the cessation of violence in Myanmar, the release of all those arbitrarily detained, and a swift return to the path of democracy and inclusive governance. They also called for urgent implementation of the ASEAN Five Point Consensus.</p>
<p>The Ministers recalled U.S. and Indian initiatives announced during the first Summit for Democracy and looked forward to further cooperation in the current Year of Action ahead of the next Summit.</p>
<p>Leveraging the recently extended U.S.-India Statement of Guiding Principles on Triangular Cooperation for Global Development, the Ministers called for greater cooperation to address global development challenges around the world, including in Asia and Africa.  In this regard, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and India’s Development Partnership Administration (DPA) have decided to expand triangular development activity with third countries.  In addition, the Ministers looked forward to continuing discussions on the establishment of the U.S.-India Gandhi-King Development Foundation.</p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the 2021 Indo-Pacific Business Forum, co-hosted by the United States and India, and convened for the first time in South Asia. They affirmed their interest in expanding efforts to promote sustainable and durable infrastructure across the Indo-Pacific and affirmed they would remain engaged through the Blue Dot Network and Build Back Better World (B3W) Initiative. The United States appreciated the opportunity for USAID to co-chair the Coalition for Disaster Resilient Infrastructure (CDRI)’s Governing Council.  Both sides reaffirmed plans to collaborate through CDRI in supporting countries most impacted by natural disasters, including those resulting from climate change.</p>
<p>The United States welcomed India’s announcement at COP26 to intensify its climate action including its long-term vision to achieve net-zero emissions by 2070.  Both sides looked forward to further cooperation to support negotiations on ocean plastic pollution launched by the UN Environment Assembly (UNEA 5.2) in February 2022. India welcomed the United States’ signing of the Framework Agreement of the International Solar Alliance (ISA) and looked forward to supporting projects to expand the availability of reliable and affordable solar power including the $500 million investment by the DFC in First Solar’s facility to produce solar panels in India.</p>
<p>The United States conveyed its full support to India’s upcoming G20 Presidency from December 2022 to November 2023.  In this context, the Ministers reiterated their commitment to work closely on international security, social, and economic issues of global interest and impact.</p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the March 21, 2022, Foreign Office Consultations, and affirmed that closer regional and multilateral coordination was integral to the bilateral Comprehensive Global Strategic Partnership. <em> </em>The Ministers look forward to reconvening the Global Issues Forum to further exchange perspectives on issues of mutual interest.</p>
<p><em>Mutual Prosperity, Innovation, and Resilient Supply Chains</em></p>
<p>The Ministers underlined the importance of strengthening the commercial and economic pillar of the U.S.-India partnership to advance economic growth and deliver mutual prosperity for both countries. They applauded the rebound in bilateral trade between the two countries over the last year, surpassing $113 billion in goods. They welcomed the 12<sup>th</sup> Ministerial-level meeting of the U.S.-India Trade Policy Forum (TPF) and the renewal of Working Group discussions to expand bilateral trade, remove market access barriers, and improve ease of business.  They looked forward to both sides developing action plans that identify and prioritize the resolution of specific trade concerns to build on the progress made during the last TPF Ministerial meeting.</p>
<p>The Ministers reiterated the importance of a transparent and predictable business environment to facilitate private-sector investment. They looked forward to reconvening the U.S.-India Commercial Dialogue and the CEO Forum this year to enhance economic cooperation, boost commercial ties, and develop private-sector recommendations for both governments. The Ministers appreciated the discussions held during the eighth ministerial-level US-India Economic and Financial Partnership meeting in October 2021, which focused on continued cooperation on a range of subjects including financial regulatory and technical collaboration, multilateral engagement, climate finance, and anti-money laundering and combating the financing of terrorism. The United States appreciated recent economic reform initiatives in India, which help improve the ease of doing business, and efforts to accelerate the start-up and innovation sector.</p>
<p>The Ministers reaffirmed the vital role of secure, resilient, reliable, and diverse supply chains for Critical and Emerging Technologies (CET), and the need to enable regional and global innovation.  The Ministers decided to put in place a framework to advance cooperation in CET such as advanced communication technology, artificial intelligence, quantum science, STEM, semi-conductors and biotechnology.</p>
<p>The Ministers noted the substantial progress in negotiations for an Investment Incentive Agreement (IIA) between the Governments of India and the United States, which provides a framework for DFC to continue to expand its investment in India – for private sector-led projects in critical areas such as renewable energy, agriculture, healthcare, and SME financing. The Ministers encouraged negotiators to resolve remaining issues so that the IIA may be concluded as soon as possible.</p>
<p><em>Climate, Environment, and Clean Energy</em></p>
<p>The Ministers commended ongoing engagement under the two main tracks of the U.S.-India Climate and Clean Energy Agenda 2030 Partnership – the Climate Action and Finance Mobilization Dialogue (CAFMD) and the Strategic Clean Energy Partnership (SCEP) – to explore and identify low carbon pathways to develop and undertake joint research and development projects, mobilize finance, develop and promote green technologies, and enhance technical collaboration aimed at building on complementarities for facilitating energy transition. To this end, the Ministers affirmed the intent to work together for the exchange of best practices and development of technology transfer to enable the affordable deployment of clean and emerging energy technologies, including commercialization and scaling up of battery storage, offshore wind, green hydrogen, and rooftop solar technology in India.</p>
<p>Both sides welcomed the expanding cooperation between the energy sectors of both countries. Recognizing that access to energy must be affordable and reliable, they committed to work together bilaterally and at the global level towards these objectives. Noting that volatility in energy markets could threaten orderly and predictable global energy transition they welcomed initiatives taken by both countries to stabilize prices, including through the coordinated release from strategic petroleum reserves.</p>
<p>The Ministers expressed satisfaction on the progress made on different collaborative initiatives under the U.S.-India Civil Nuclear Energy Working Group and the Global Centre for Nuclear Energy Partnership Joint Working Group.  The Ministers noted ongoing negotiations between the Nuclear Power Corporation of India Limited (NPCIL) and Westinghouse Electric Company (WEC) for the construction of six nuclear reactors in India. They welcomed progress through consultations between the U.S. Department of Energy and India’s Department of Atomic Energy for facilitating opportunities for WEC to develop a techno-commercial offer for the Kovvada nuclear project. They also noted the ongoing discussion on developing next generation small modular reactor technologies in a collaborative mode for the domestic market as well as for export.</p>
<p>The Ministers also recognized the efforts of USAID and other U.S. agencies to support and augment production of clean and accessible energy and engage with private sector through its initiatives such as South Asia Regional Energy Partnership, Flexible Resources Initiative, and Smart Grid Knowledge Center.</p>
<p><em>Science, Technology, Cybersecurity, and Space</em></p>
<p>Reflecting on the positive science and technology cooperation between the two countries, the Ministers welcomed the announcement of a Joint Commission Meeting on Science and Technology in 2022, to discuss future science and technology collaboration.</p>
<p>The Ministers applauded the recent and upcoming meetings of the U.S.-India Cyber Dialogue and the Information and Communication Technology (ICT) Working Group to deepen cybersecurity cooperation. They strongly condemned ransomware and other cyber-related crimes and recognized the need to bolster protection of critical networks and infrastructure.</p>
<p>Recalling their countries’ strong tradition of space exploration and endeavors, the Ministers announced the conclusion of a Memorandum of Understanding on Space Situational Awareness and pledged to expand bilateral space cooperation, acknowledging the pivotal role international cooperation plays in the long-term sustainability and safety of the outer-space environment. They applauded the ongoing development of the NASA-ISRO Synthetic Aperture Radar (NISAR) satellite, planned for launch from India in 2023.  The NISAR mission will collect data vital to tackling the climate crisis. The Ministers also looked forward to the convening of the next India-U.S. Civil Space Joint Working Group in 2022.</p>
<p>The Ministers expressed appreciation for the continued cooperation between the U.S. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) and India’s Ministry of Earth Science (MoES) and ISRO in areas such as ocean and fisheries science, meteorology, and earth observation to better understand climate change and save lives through improved weather and ocean modeling and information sharing.  In support of climate and disaster resilience goals, the United States and India are driving advancements in climate and monsoon prediction and forecasting through collaborative work in the Indian Ocean.  As part of that work, MoES recently launched a joint data portal providing near-real-time public data from the NOAA Research Moored Array for African-Asian-Australian Monsoon Analysis and Prediction (RAMA) and the MoES Ocean Moored Buoy Network for the Northern Indian Ocean (OMNI).  The data supports improved monsoon prediction capabilities and sub-seasonal weather forecasting including for the United States, whose weather and atmosphere are impacted by systems that develop in the Indian Ocean. The Ministers also welcomed expansion of collaboration between NOAA and MoES under EKAMSAT program (Enhancing Knowledge of the Arabian Sea Marine Environment through Science and Advanced Technology).</p>
<p><em>Global Health</em></p>
<p>The Ministers recognized the pivotal role of the U.S.-India partnership in combating the COVID-19 pandemic and other contemporary global health challenges.  They welcomed joint U.S.-India leadership under the COVID-19 Global Action Plan to get shots in arms, diversify and secure global supply chains, build capacity for health care workers, and scientific cooperation.  They appreciated U.S.-India collaboration in vaccine R&amp;D and production including the Janssen and Corbevax vaccines being manufactured by Biological E., and the Novovax vaccines by Serum Institute of India, and expressed appreciation that due to efforts to increase manufacturing, safe, effective, and affordable COVID vaccines are readily available to third countries, further strengthening global vaccination efforts. The Ministers reaffirmed their commitment to facilitate joint research and information sharing, and work together to address barriers to pandemic-related vaccines and medical production so that global supply chains for vaccines are more resilient, stable, and predictable.</p>
<p>Recalling the recent U.S.-India Health Dialogue, the Ministers commended our ongoing collaboration on biomedical research, strengthening regulatory procedures and pandemic preparedness. The Ministers welcomed the signing of an overarching Memorandum of Understanding between India’s Ministry of Health and Family Welfare (MoHFW) and the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (DHHS) to work together to strengthen public health preparedness and response by expanding training on disease surveillance, improve response to and containment of outbreaks, strengthen laboratory networks and diagnostics, enhance pan-respiratory disease surveillance, develop sub-national emergency operation centers, and integrate a “One Health” approach into all public health initiatives.</p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the renewal of our joint commitment to undertake collaborative research on infectious diseases of global health significance and conclude a Memorandum of Understanding to continue joint support for an Indo-U.S. International Centre for Excellence in Research between the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID) of National Institutes of Health (NIH) and the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR).</p>
<p>The Ministers also welcomed the launch of ICMR-NIH Clinical Research Fellowship program, under which clinicians from both sides can come to conduct research in laboratories in India and the United States. The Ministers welcomed a new regulatory partnership in furtherance of shrimp safety between the Food and Drug Administration and Marine Product Export Development Authority (MPEDA), and reaffirmed plans to finalize a Memorandum of Understanding to undertake further research on diabetes between the U.S. National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases and ICMR.</p>
<p>The Ministers looked forward to expansion of the USAID-supported COVID-19 Learning Exchange virtual platform, to include programs for more population groups and allow cities and health officials to share best practices to improve routine immunization, strengthen urban health, and launch an interactive web-based platform to enhance knowledge management and operational reach.</p>
<p><em>Defense and Security</em></p>
<p>The Ministers commended the significant and continuing progress in the U.S.-India Major Defense Partnership.  Drawing on the momentum from the U.S.-India Defense Policy Group meeting in October 2021, they reaffirmed their ambitions for building an advanced and comprehensive defense partnership in which the U.S. and Indian militaries coordinate closely together across all domains.</p>
<p>The Ministers acknowledged the importance of deepening collaboration in science and technology in the U.S.-India Joint Technical Group (JTG), and in evolving new defense domains, including space, artificial intelligence (AI), and cyber.  The Ministers underscored the importance of cooperation in space and welcomed plans to conduct an inaugural Defense Space Dialogue in 2022. They welcomed the second Defense Cyber Dialogue held in 2021 and look forward to the next round this year.  They decided to hold an inaugural AI Dialogue this year to harness opportunities for joint innovation and cooperation in new domains.  The Ministers also discussed additional training opportunities for our respective militaries, and the United States welcomed enhanced Indian participation in advanced courses across these emerging domains.</p>
<p>As information-sharing forms an important pillar of the U.S.-India defense cooperation, the Ministers underlined the importance of building a comprehensive framework under which our militaries are equipped to exchange information in real time across domains.  The Ministers welcomed progress made toward full implementation of the Basic Exchange and Cooperation Agreement (BECA) to support the exchange of geospatial information. The Ministers noted that information exchange and placement of liaison officers in each other’s military organizations will spur joint service cooperation between our militaries to support integrated and multi-domain cooperation.</p>
<p>Acknowledging that our navies have been a driving force in advancing the United States and India’s shared interests in the Indian Ocean Region and the wider Indo-Pacific, the Ministers discussed opportunities to further advance and deepen maritime cooperation, including in underwater domain awareness.</p>
<p>The United States also welcomed India’s decision to join the Combined Maritime Forces Task Force as an Associate Partner to expand multilateral cooperation in the Indian Ocean. The Ministers lauded the 2022 Indo-Pacific Military Health Exchange, which India and the United States co-hosted to bring together experts from 38 countries to discuss challenges and solutions to military medical issues. Both sides look forward to India’s co-hosting of the Indo-Pacific Armies Chiefs Conference (IPACC) and Indo-Pacific Armies Management Seminar (IPAMS) in 2023.</p>
<p>In support of the Indian military’s expanding operational reach and emerging opportunities for cooperation in the Indian Ocean and the wider region, the Ministers welcomed regular bilateral logistics operations such as replenishments at sea, air-to-air and ground-refueling and committed to increasing such cooperation, including through the Logistics Exchange Memorandum of Agreement (LEMOA).</p>
<p>Both sides reaffirmed the importance of regular bilateral and multilateral exercises, including the MALABAR exercise with inclusion of Australia, the tri-service TIGER TRIUMPH exercise, the multilateral MILAN naval exercise, the bilateral YUDH ABHYAS and VAJRA PRAHAR Army exercises, the bilateral COPE India air exercise, and Indian participation in RED FLAG. They supported increasing the scope and complexity of these exercises. They looked forward to deepening cooperation between the Special Forces of both countries.</p>
<p>Recognizing the importance of building robust private industry collaboration, the Ministers welcomed ongoing projects under the auspices of the U.S.-India Defense Technology and Trade Initiative (DTTI), including a project agreement to co-develop Air-Launched UAVs.  They called on both sides to consider additional DTTI projects, such as a counter-unmanned aerial systems (UAS) system and an Intelligence, Surveillance, Target Acquisition and Reconnaissance (ISTAR) platform.  They also lauded the rapid growth in bilateral defense trade over the past decade.</p>
<p>Seeking trusted and resilient defense supply chains, the Ministers welcomed the progress made towards implementation of the Industrial Security Agreement to facilitate collaboration on cutting edge defense technologies between industries. Both sides would explore and further promote the means to encourage reciprocal participation of U.S. and Indian vendors in each other’s defense supply chains. Acknowledging India’s focus on developing its domestic capabilities and helping to ensure reliable defense supplies, the Ministers committed to work closely across their respective governments on co-production, co-development, cooperative testing of advanced systems, investment promotion, and the development of Maintenance Repair and Overhaul (MRO) facilities in India. To further enhance defense industrial cooperation in the naval sector, both sides agreed to explore possibilities of utilizing the Indian shipyards for repair and maintenance of ships of the U.S. Maritime Sealift Command (MSC) to support mid-voyage repair of U.S. Naval ships.</p>
<p><em>Counterterrorism and Counter Narcotics</em></p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the convening of the 18th Meeting of the India-U.S. Joint Working Group on Counter Terrorism and the 4th Session of the India-U.S. Designations Dialogue in October 2021.  The Ministers strongly condemned any use of terrorist proxies and cross-border terrorism in all its forms and called for the perpetrators of the 26/11 Mumbai attack, and Pathankot attack, to be brought to justice.  They called for concerted action against all terrorist groups, including groups proscribed by the UNSC 1267 Sanctions Committee, such as al-Qa’ida, ISIS/Daesh, Lashkar-e-Tayyiba (LeT), and Jaish-e-Mohammad (JeM), and Hizb ul Mujahideen. The Ministers called on Pakistan to take immediate, sustained, and irreversible action to ensure that no territory under its control is used for terrorist attacks.  The Ministers committed to continued exchange of information about sanctions and designations against terror groups and individuals, countering violent radicalism, use of the Internet for terrorist purposes, and cross-border movement of terrorists.  The Ministers also emphasized the importance of upholding international standards on anti-money laundering and combating the financing of terrorism by all countries, consistent with FATF recommendations.</p>
<p>The Ministers also reaffirmed their support for the early adoption of a UN Comprehensive Convention on International Terrorism (CCIT) that advances and strengthens the framework for global cooperation and reinforces that no cause or grievance justifies terrorism.</p>
<p>Both sides looked forward to the next U.S.-India Counter Narcotics Working Group meeting in 2022 and enhancing cooperation through a bilateral Counter-Narcotics Framework to combat drug trafficking, illicit narcotics production, and precursor chemical supply chains.</p>
<p>Building upon the recent Senior Officials Meeting between the U.S. Department of Homeland Security and India’s Ministry of Home Affairs, both sides looked forward to reconvening a Ministerial meeting of the U.S.-India Homeland Security Dialogue in 2022.</p>
<p><em>Education and People-to-People Ties</em></p>
<p>Lauding the vibrant educational linkages between India and the United States, the Ministers reiterated their support to further strengthen cooperation in the field of education and skill development through joint collaborations and promote student and scholar mobility to build people-to-people linkages between the two countries.  In this regard, the ministers announced the intent to establish a new U.S.-India Education and Skills Development Working Group.  The Ministers also appreciated the contribution of the Fulbright-Nehru program in furthering the exchange of outstanding academics and professionals between both countries and the special role the four million strong Indian-American diaspora play in deepening U.S.-India relations.</p>
<p>Welcoming the resumption of regular air travel between the two countries and expressing hope that this would encourage tourism and business travel, the Ministers acknowledged that the movement of skilled professionals, students, entrepreneurs, investors, and business travelers between our countries plays an important role in catalyzing innovation and economic opportunity.  India welcomed the waiver, through December 31, 2022, of in-person visa interviews for applicants that were previously issued any type of visa and are now applying for certain nonimmigrant visa classifications, which include those for Persons in Specialty Occupation, Academic and Vocational Students, and Intracompany Transferees.  The Ministers underlined the importance of continued engagement on visa issues, welcomed the December 2021 meeting of the bilateral Consular Dialogue, and resolved to continue efforts to facilitate the reciprocal movement of professionals, businesspersons, skilled workers, experts, and scientific personnel.</p>
<p>The Ministers also acknowledged the importance of continued discussions on a Social Security Totalization Agreement and welcomed the opportunity to further engage on pursuing such an agreement.</p>
<p>Both sides looked forward to commencing a dialogue on contemporary issues related to women in the context of people to people linkages.</p>
<p>Recognizing the importance of protecting cultural heritage, the Ministers committed to work toward negotiating a Memorandum of Understanding that will deepen cooperation in this area and assist authorities in combatting the trade in cultural artifacts and facilitating their repatriation.</p>
<p>The United States thanked India for its support for the Defense POW/MIA Accounting Agency (DPAA) missions in India. The Ministers reiterated their commitment to future DPAA‎ missions.</p>
<p>India looks forward to hosting the next 2+2 Ministerial.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and India on the occasion of the Fourth Annual U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue in 2022.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken and Secretary of Defense Lloyd J. Austin III welcomed Minister of Defence Rajnath Singh and Minister of External Affairs Dr. S. Jaishankar to Washington, D.C., on April 11, 2022, for the fourth U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue. The Dialogue was preceded by a virtual meeting between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and President Joseph Biden.</p>
<p>As natural and trusted partners celebrating 75 years of diplomatic relations between the United States and independent India, with a shared commitment to democracy and pluralism, a multifaceted bilateral agenda, and growing convergence of strategic interests, both countries seek to continue to promote a resilient, rules-based international order that safeguards sovereignty and territorial integrity, upholds democratic values, and promotes peace and prosperity for all.</p>
<p>Building upon the September 2021 meeting between President Biden and Prime Minister Modi, and their respective participation in Summits related to COVID-19, climate, infrastructure and supply chain resilience, the Ministers reaffirmed the importance of the U.S.-India Comprehensive Global Strategic Partnership to international peace and security.</p>
<p><em>Global Partnership and Indo-Pacific Cooperation</em></p>
<p>The Ministers reviewed mutual efforts to respond to the worsening humanitarian crisis in Ukraine and assessed its broader implications. They urged an immediate cessation of hostilities. The Ministers unequivocally condemned civilian deaths.  They underscored that the contemporary global order has been built on the UN Charter, respect for international law, and the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states.</p>
<p>Recalling the inaugural virtual Quad Leaders’ Summit in March 2021, the in-person Quad Leaders’ Summit in September 2021 in Washington, the February 2022 Quad Foreign Ministers’ meeting in Melbourne, and looking forward to the next Quad Leaders’ Summit in Tokyo in 2022, the Ministers reaffirmed their commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific in which the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states are respected, and countries are free from military, economic, and political coercion. They further reaffirmed their dedication to promoting regional stability and prosperity, with an inclusive regional architecture, abiding by the rule of law, the freedom of navigation and overflight, peaceful resolution of disputes, and ASEAN centrality. They also reiterated the importance of adherence to international law to meet challenges to the rules-based order, including in the South China Sea.</p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the progress made in the last year on developing a positive and constructive agenda for the Quad to deliver peace and prosperity to the region in pursuance of their shared vision for a free, open, and inclusive Indo-Pacific. The Ministers reiterated their commitment to the take forward the initiatives announced by the Leaders, to empower the Quad as a force for global good for the Indo-Pacific region and welcomed ongoing discussions in the Quad Working Groups on vaccines, climate change, infrastructure, space, cyber security, and critical and emerging technologies for delivering practical and tangible benefits to the region.</p>
<p>Welcoming the remarkable progress made under the Quad Vaccine Partnership to augment the manufacturing capacity of the Biological E facility in India, supported by the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC), the Ministers committed to expedite delivery of the first batch of vaccines to countries of the Indo-Pacific and beyond and to diversify the basket of vaccines in the context of changes in the global demand and supply landscape.</p>
<p>Following up on the October 2021 virtual meeting of the Foreign Ministers of India, Israel, the United Arab Emirates, and the United States, the Ministers welcomed the opportunity to enhance engagement in this forum on shared priorities such as food security, clean energy, waste management, and infrastructure development.</p>
<p>The United States congratulated India for its significant contributions as a member of the United Nations Security Council (UNSC) for the term 2021-2022. In this context, the United States expressed its appreciation for India’s leadership as the Chair of the three Committees of the Security Council: the 1988 Taliban Sanctions Committee, the 1970 Libya Sanctions Committee and the 1373 Counter Terrorism Committee.</p>
<p>The Ministers reiterated their commitment to work together in close coordination at the UNSC and in international organizations. The United States reaffirmed its continued support for India’s permanent membership in a reformed UNSC and for India’s entry to the Nuclear Suppliers’ Group.</p>
<p>Considering growing national security threats from both state and non-state malicious cyber actors, the Ministers recognized the importance of an open, interoperable, secure, and reliable Internet and stable cyberspace.  Both sides reaffirmed the 2021 reports of the UN Open Ended Working Group and the UN Group of Governmental Experts, which articulate a framework of responsible state behavior in cyberspace and committed to work together in future multilateral negotiations to encourage States to implement the framework. They confirmed their intent to work closely as part of ongoing efforts to counter the use of information communications technologies for criminal purposes.</p>
<p>Acknowledging India’s distinguished history of leading peacekeeping missions, the United States welcomed India’s commitment to participate in multilateral peacekeeping training in 2022, expand joint-capacity building efforts with third-country partners, and launch a new joint National Investigation Officers Training of Trainers course in partnership with the United Nations.</p>
<p>The Ministers called on the Taliban to abide by UNSC Resolution 2593 (2021), which demands that Afghan territory must never again be used to threaten or attack any country or to shelter or train terrorists, or to plan or finance terrorist attacks.  The Ministers urged the Taliban to adhere to these and all other commitments; respect the human rights of all Afghans, including women, children, and members of minority groups; and uphold freedom of travel. They also emphasized the importance of an inclusive Afghan government and unhindered access for the United Nations and its implementing partners to deliver humanitarian assistance. The Ministers recommitted to close consultations on Afghanistan to help facilitate an inclusive and peaceful future for all Afghans.</p>
<p>The Ministers called for the cessation of violence in Myanmar, the release of all those arbitrarily detained, and a swift return to the path of democracy and inclusive governance. They also called for urgent implementation of the ASEAN Five Point Consensus.</p>
<p>The Ministers recalled U.S. and Indian initiatives announced during the first Summit for Democracy and looked forward to further cooperation in the current Year of Action ahead of the next Summit.</p>
<p>Leveraging the recently extended U.S.-India Statement of Guiding Principles on Triangular Cooperation for Global Development, the Ministers called for greater cooperation to address global development challenges around the world, including in Asia and Africa.  In this regard, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and India’s Development Partnership Administration (DPA) have decided to expand triangular development activity with third countries.  In addition, the Ministers looked forward to continuing discussions on the establishment of the U.S.-India Gandhi-King Development Foundation.</p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the 2021 Indo-Pacific Business Forum, co-hosted by the United States and India, and convened for the first time in South Asia. They affirmed their interest in expanding efforts to promote sustainable and durable infrastructure across the Indo-Pacific and affirmed they would remain engaged through the Blue Dot Network and Build Back Better World (B3W) Initiative. The United States appreciated the opportunity for USAID to co-chair the Coalition for Disaster Resilient Infrastructure (CDRI)’s Governing Council.  Both sides reaffirmed plans to collaborate through CDRI in supporting countries most impacted by natural disasters, including those resulting from climate change.</p>
<p>The United States welcomed India’s announcement at COP26 to intensify its climate action including its long-term vision to achieve net-zero emissions by 2070.  Both sides looked forward to further cooperation to support negotiations on ocean plastic pollution launched by the UN Environment Assembly (UNEA 5.2) in February 2022. India welcomed the United States’ signing of the Framework Agreement of the International Solar Alliance (ISA) and looked forward to supporting projects to expand the availability of reliable and affordable solar power including the $500 million investment by the DFC in First Solar’s facility to produce solar panels in India.</p>
<p>The United States conveyed its full support to India’s upcoming G20 Presidency from December 2022 to November 2023.  In this context, the Ministers reiterated their commitment to work closely on international security, social, and economic issues of global interest and impact.</p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the March 21, 2022, Foreign Office Consultations, and affirmed that closer regional and multilateral coordination was integral to the bilateral Comprehensive Global Strategic Partnership. <em> </em>The Ministers look forward to reconvening the Global Issues Forum to further exchange perspectives on issues of mutual interest.</p>
<p><em>Mutual Prosperity, Innovation, and Resilient Supply Chains</em></p>
<p>The Ministers underlined the importance of strengthening the commercial and economic pillar of the U.S.-India partnership to advance economic growth and deliver mutual prosperity for both countries. They applauded the rebound in bilateral trade between the two countries over the last year, surpassing $113 billion in goods. They welcomed the 12<sup>th</sup> Ministerial-level meeting of the U.S.-India Trade Policy Forum (TPF) and the renewal of Working Group discussions to expand bilateral trade, remove market access barriers, and improve ease of business.  They looked forward to both sides developing action plans that identify and prioritize the resolution of specific trade concerns to build on the progress made during the last TPF Ministerial meeting.</p>
<p>The Ministers reiterated the importance of a transparent and predictable business environment to facilitate private-sector investment. They looked forward to reconvening the U.S.-India Commercial Dialogue and the CEO Forum this year to enhance economic cooperation, boost commercial ties, and develop private-sector recommendations for both governments. The Ministers appreciated the discussions held during the eighth ministerial-level US-India Economic and Financial Partnership meeting in October 2021, which focused on continued cooperation on a range of subjects including financial regulatory and technical collaboration, multilateral engagement, climate finance, and anti-money laundering and combating the financing of terrorism. The United States appreciated recent economic reform initiatives in India, which help improve the ease of doing business, and efforts to accelerate the start-up and innovation sector.</p>
<p>The Ministers reaffirmed the vital role of secure, resilient, reliable, and diverse supply chains for Critical and Emerging Technologies (CET), and the need to enable regional and global innovation.  The Ministers decided to put in place a framework to advance cooperation in CET such as advanced communication technology, artificial intelligence, quantum science, STEM, semi-conductors and biotechnology.</p>
<p>The Ministers noted the substantial progress in negotiations for an Investment Incentive Agreement (IIA) between the Governments of India and the United States, which provides a framework for DFC to continue to expand its investment in India – for private sector-led projects in critical areas such as renewable energy, agriculture, healthcare, and SME financing. The Ministers encouraged negotiators to resolve remaining issues so that the IIA may be concluded as soon as possible.</p>
<p><em>Climate, Environment, and Clean Energy</em></p>
<p>The Ministers commended ongoing engagement under the two main tracks of the U.S.-India Climate and Clean Energy Agenda 2030 Partnership – the Climate Action and Finance Mobilization Dialogue (CAFMD) and the Strategic Clean Energy Partnership (SCEP) – to explore and identify low carbon pathways to develop and undertake joint research and development projects, mobilize finance, develop and promote green technologies, and enhance technical collaboration aimed at building on complementarities for facilitating energy transition. To this end, the Ministers affirmed the intent to work together for the exchange of best practices and development of technology transfer to enable the affordable deployment of clean and emerging energy technologies, including commercialization and scaling up of battery storage, offshore wind, green hydrogen, and rooftop solar technology in India.</p>
<p>Both sides welcomed the expanding cooperation between the energy sectors of both countries. Recognizing that access to energy must be affordable and reliable, they committed to work together bilaterally and at the global level towards these objectives. Noting that volatility in energy markets could threaten orderly and predictable global energy transition they welcomed initiatives taken by both countries to stabilize prices, including through the coordinated release from strategic petroleum reserves.</p>
<p>The Ministers expressed satisfaction on the progress made on different collaborative initiatives under the U.S.-India Civil Nuclear Energy Working Group and the Global Centre for Nuclear Energy Partnership Joint Working Group.  The Ministers noted ongoing negotiations between the Nuclear Power Corporation of India Limited (NPCIL) and Westinghouse Electric Company (WEC) for the construction of six nuclear reactors in India. They welcomed progress through consultations between the U.S. Department of Energy and India’s Department of Atomic Energy for facilitating opportunities for WEC to develop a techno-commercial offer for the Kovvada nuclear project. They also noted the ongoing discussion on developing next generation small modular reactor technologies in a collaborative mode for the domestic market as well as for export.</p>
<p>The Ministers also recognized the efforts of USAID and other U.S. agencies to support and augment production of clean and accessible energy and engage with private sector through its initiatives such as South Asia Regional Energy Partnership, Flexible Resources Initiative, and Smart Grid Knowledge Center.</p>
<p><em>Science, Technology, Cybersecurity, and Space</em></p>
<p>Reflecting on the positive science and technology cooperation between the two countries, the Ministers welcomed the announcement of a Joint Commission Meeting on Science and Technology in 2022, to discuss future science and technology collaboration.</p>
<p>The Ministers applauded the recent and upcoming meetings of the U.S.-India Cyber Dialogue and the Information and Communication Technology (ICT) Working Group to deepen cybersecurity cooperation. They strongly condemned ransomware and other cyber-related crimes and recognized the need to bolster protection of critical networks and infrastructure.</p>
<p>Recalling their countries’ strong tradition of space exploration and endeavors, the Ministers announced the conclusion of a Memorandum of Understanding on Space Situational Awareness and pledged to expand bilateral space cooperation, acknowledging the pivotal role international cooperation plays in the long-term sustainability and safety of the outer-space environment. They applauded the ongoing development of the NASA-ISRO Synthetic Aperture Radar (NISAR) satellite, planned for launch from India in 2023.  The NISAR mission will collect data vital to tackling the climate crisis. The Ministers also looked forward to the convening of the next India-U.S. Civil Space Joint Working Group in 2022.</p>
<p>The Ministers expressed appreciation for the continued cooperation between the U.S. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) and India’s Ministry of Earth Science (MoES) and ISRO in areas such as ocean and fisheries science, meteorology, and earth observation to better understand climate change and save lives through improved weather and ocean modeling and information sharing.  In support of climate and disaster resilience goals, the United States and India are driving advancements in climate and monsoon prediction and forecasting through collaborative work in the Indian Ocean.  As part of that work, MoES recently launched a joint data portal providing near-real-time public data from the NOAA Research Moored Array for African-Asian-Australian Monsoon Analysis and Prediction (RAMA) and the MoES Ocean Moored Buoy Network for the Northern Indian Ocean (OMNI).  The data supports improved monsoon prediction capabilities and sub-seasonal weather forecasting including for the United States, whose weather and atmosphere are impacted by systems that develop in the Indian Ocean. The Ministers also welcomed expansion of collaboration between NOAA and MoES under EKAMSAT program (Enhancing Knowledge of the Arabian Sea Marine Environment through Science and Advanced Technology).</p>
<p><em>Global Health</em></p>
<p>The Ministers recognized the pivotal role of the U.S.-India partnership in combating the COVID-19 pandemic and other contemporary global health challenges.  They welcomed joint U.S.-India leadership under the COVID-19 Global Action Plan to get shots in arms, diversify and secure global supply chains, build capacity for health care workers, and scientific cooperation.  They appreciated U.S.-India collaboration in vaccine R&amp;D and production including the Janssen and Corbevax vaccines being manufactured by Biological E., and the Novovax vaccines by Serum Institute of India, and expressed appreciation that due to efforts to increase manufacturing, safe, effective, and affordable COVID vaccines are readily available to third countries, further strengthening global vaccination efforts. The Ministers reaffirmed their commitment to facilitate joint research and information sharing, and work together to address barriers to pandemic-related vaccines and medical production so that global supply chains for vaccines are more resilient, stable, and predictable.</p>
<p>Recalling the recent U.S.-India Health Dialogue, the Ministers commended our ongoing collaboration on biomedical research, strengthening regulatory procedures and pandemic preparedness. The Ministers welcomed the signing of an overarching Memorandum of Understanding between India’s Ministry of Health and Family Welfare (MoHFW) and the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (DHHS) to work together to strengthen public health preparedness and response by expanding training on disease surveillance, improve response to and containment of outbreaks, strengthen laboratory networks and diagnostics, enhance pan-respiratory disease surveillance, develop sub-national emergency operation centers, and integrate a “One Health” approach into all public health initiatives.</p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the renewal of our joint commitment to undertake collaborative research on infectious diseases of global health significance and conclude a Memorandum of Understanding to continue joint support for an Indo-U.S. International Centre for Excellence in Research between the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID) of National Institutes of Health (NIH) and the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR).</p>
<p>The Ministers also welcomed the launch of ICMR-NIH Clinical Research Fellowship program, under which clinicians from both sides can come to conduct research in laboratories in India and the United States. The Ministers welcomed a new regulatory partnership in furtherance of shrimp safety between the Food and Drug Administration and Marine Product Export Development Authority (MPEDA), and reaffirmed plans to finalize a Memorandum of Understanding to undertake further research on diabetes between the U.S. National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases and ICMR.</p>
<p>The Ministers looked forward to expansion of the USAID-supported COVID-19 Learning Exchange virtual platform, to include programs for more population groups and allow cities and health officials to share best practices to improve routine immunization, strengthen urban health, and launch an interactive web-based platform to enhance knowledge management and operational reach.</p>
<p><em>Defense and Security</em></p>
<p>The Ministers commended the significant and continuing progress in the U.S.-India Major Defense Partnership.  Drawing on the momentum from the U.S.-India Defense Policy Group meeting in October 2021, they reaffirmed their ambitions for building an advanced and comprehensive defense partnership in which the U.S. and Indian militaries coordinate closely together across all domains.</p>
<p>The Ministers acknowledged the importance of deepening collaboration in science and technology in the U.S.-India Joint Technical Group (JTG), and in evolving new defense domains, including space, artificial intelligence (AI), and cyber.  The Ministers underscored the importance of cooperation in space and welcomed plans to conduct an inaugural Defense Space Dialogue in 2022. They welcomed the second Defense Cyber Dialogue held in 2021 and look forward to the next round this year.  They decided to hold an inaugural AI Dialogue this year to harness opportunities for joint innovation and cooperation in new domains.  The Ministers also discussed additional training opportunities for our respective militaries, and the United States welcomed enhanced Indian participation in advanced courses across these emerging domains.</p>
<p>As information-sharing forms an important pillar of the U.S.-India defense cooperation, the Ministers underlined the importance of building a comprehensive framework under which our militaries are equipped to exchange information in real time across domains.  The Ministers welcomed progress made toward full implementation of the Basic Exchange and Cooperation Agreement (BECA) to support the exchange of geospatial information. The Ministers noted that information exchange and placement of liaison officers in each other’s military organizations will spur joint service cooperation between our militaries to support integrated and multi-domain cooperation.</p>
<p>Acknowledging that our navies have been a driving force in advancing the United States and India’s shared interests in the Indian Ocean Region and the wider Indo-Pacific, the Ministers discussed opportunities to further advance and deepen maritime cooperation, including in underwater domain awareness.</p>
<p>The United States also welcomed India’s decision to join the Combined Maritime Forces Task Force as an Associate Partner to expand multilateral cooperation in the Indian Ocean. The Ministers lauded the 2022 Indo-Pacific Military Health Exchange, which India and the United States co-hosted to bring together experts from 38 countries to discuss challenges and solutions to military medical issues. Both sides look forward to India’s co-hosting of the Indo-Pacific Armies Chiefs Conference (IPACC) and Indo-Pacific Armies Management Seminar (IPAMS) in 2023.</p>
<p>In support of the Indian military’s expanding operational reach and emerging opportunities for cooperation in the Indian Ocean and the wider region, the Ministers welcomed regular bilateral logistics operations such as replenishments at sea, air-to-air and ground-refueling and committed to increasing such cooperation, including through the Logistics Exchange Memorandum of Agreement (LEMOA).</p>
<p>Both sides reaffirmed the importance of regular bilateral and multilateral exercises, including the MALABAR exercise with inclusion of Australia, the tri-service TIGER TRIUMPH exercise, the multilateral MILAN naval exercise, the bilateral YUDH ABHYAS and VAJRA PRAHAR Army exercises, the bilateral COPE India air exercise, and Indian participation in RED FLAG. They supported increasing the scope and complexity of these exercises. They looked forward to deepening cooperation between the Special Forces of both countries.</p>
<p>Recognizing the importance of building robust private industry collaboration, the Ministers welcomed ongoing projects under the auspices of the U.S.-India Defense Technology and Trade Initiative (DTTI), including a project agreement to co-develop Air-Launched UAVs.  They called on both sides to consider additional DTTI projects, such as a counter-unmanned aerial systems (UAS) system and an Intelligence, Surveillance, Target Acquisition and Reconnaissance (ISTAR) platform.  They also lauded the rapid growth in bilateral defense trade over the past decade.</p>
<p>Seeking trusted and resilient defense supply chains, the Ministers welcomed the progress made towards implementation of the Industrial Security Agreement to facilitate collaboration on cutting edge defense technologies between industries. Both sides would explore and further promote the means to encourage reciprocal participation of U.S. and Indian vendors in each other’s defense supply chains. Acknowledging India’s focus on developing its domestic capabilities and helping to ensure reliable defense supplies, the Ministers committed to work closely across their respective governments on co-production, co-development, cooperative testing of advanced systems, investment promotion, and the development of Maintenance Repair and Overhaul (MRO) facilities in India. To further enhance defense industrial cooperation in the naval sector, both sides agreed to explore possibilities of utilizing the Indian shipyards for repair and maintenance of ships of the U.S. Maritime Sealift Command (MSC) to support mid-voyage repair of U.S. Naval ships.</p>
<p><em>Counterterrorism and Counter Narcotics</em></p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the convening of the 18th Meeting of the India-U.S. Joint Working Group on Counter Terrorism and the 4th Session of the India-U.S. Designations Dialogue in October 2021.  The Ministers strongly condemned any use of terrorist proxies and cross-border terrorism in all its forms and called for the perpetrators of the 26/11 Mumbai attack, and Pathankot attack, to be brought to justice.  They called for concerted action against all terrorist groups, including groups proscribed by the UNSC 1267 Sanctions Committee, such as al-Qa’ida, ISIS/Daesh, Lashkar-e-Tayyiba (LeT), and Jaish-e-Mohammad (JeM), and Hizb ul Mujahideen. The Ministers called on Pakistan to take immediate, sustained, and irreversible action to ensure that no territory under its control is used for terrorist attacks.  The Ministers committed to continued exchange of information about sanctions and designations against terror groups and individuals, countering violent radicalism, use of the Internet for terrorist purposes, and cross-border movement of terrorists.  The Ministers also emphasized the importance of upholding international standards on anti-money laundering and combating the financing of terrorism by all countries, consistent with FATF recommendations.</p>
<p>The Ministers also reaffirmed their support for the early adoption of a UN Comprehensive Convention on International Terrorism (CCIT) that advances and strengthens the framework for global cooperation and reinforces that no cause or grievance justifies terrorism.</p>
<p>Both sides looked forward to the next U.S.-India Counter Narcotics Working Group meeting in 2022 and enhancing cooperation through a bilateral Counter-Narcotics Framework to combat drug trafficking, illicit narcotics production, and precursor chemical supply chains.</p>
<p>Building upon the recent Senior Officials Meeting between the U.S. Department of Homeland Security and India’s Ministry of Home Affairs, both sides looked forward to reconvening a Ministerial meeting of the U.S.-India Homeland Security Dialogue in 2022.</p>
<p><em>Education and People-to-People Ties</em></p>
<p>Lauding the vibrant educational linkages between India and the United States, the Ministers reiterated their support to further strengthen cooperation in the field of education and skill development through joint collaborations and promote student and scholar mobility to build people-to-people linkages between the two countries.  In this regard, the ministers announced the intent to establish a new U.S.-India Education and Skills Development Working Group.  The Ministers also appreciated the contribution of the Fulbright-Nehru program in furthering the exchange of outstanding academics and professionals between both countries and the special role the four million strong Indian-American diaspora play in deepening U.S.-India relations.</p>
<p>Welcoming the resumption of regular air travel between the two countries and expressing hope that this would encourage tourism and business travel, the Ministers acknowledged that the movement of skilled professionals, students, entrepreneurs, investors, and business travelers between our countries plays an important role in catalyzing innovation and economic opportunity.  India welcomed the waiver, through December 31, 2022, of in-person visa interviews for applicants that were previously issued any type of visa and are now applying for certain nonimmigrant visa classifications, which include those for Persons in Specialty Occupation, Academic and Vocational Students, and Intracompany Transferees.  The Ministers underlined the importance of continued engagement on visa issues, welcomed the December 2021 meeting of the bilateral Consular Dialogue, and resolved to continue efforts to facilitate the reciprocal movement of professionals, businesspersons, skilled workers, experts, and scientific personnel.</p>
<p>The Ministers also acknowledged the importance of continued discussions on a Social Security Totalization Agreement and welcomed the opportunity to further engage on pursuing such an agreement.</p>
<p>Both sides looked forward to commencing a dialogue on contemporary issues related to women in the context of people to people linkages.</p>
<p>Recognizing the importance of protecting cultural heritage, the Ministers committed to work toward negotiating a Memorandum of Understanding that will deepen cooperation in this area and assist authorities in combatting the trade in cultural artifacts and facilitating their repatriation.</p>
<p>The United States thanked India for its support for the Defense POW/MIA Accounting Agency (DPAA) missions in India. The Ministers reiterated their commitment to future DPAA‎ missions.</p>
<p>India looks forward to hosting the next 2+2 Ministerial.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
