<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 16:51:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with Chief of Staff for the President of the European Commission Seibert</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-chief-of-staff-for-the-president-of-the-european-commission-seibert/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 16:51:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=314110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Bjoern Seibert, Chief of Staff for European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen, to follow up on their February 11 call and President Biden’s February 11 video call with transatlantic leaders.  The Deputy Secretary and Chief of Staff discussed diplomatic efforts to urge Russia to deescalate and choose diplomacy and reiterated that further Russian escalation would be met with massive, coordinated consequences and severe costs for the Russian Federation.  Both expressed the United States’ and EU’s resolute support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and commitment to strong transatlantic coordination.  Deputy Secretary Sherman also raised EU-UK negotiations on the implementation of the Northern Ireland Protocol and the importance of preserving the gains of the Belfast/Good Friday Agreement.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Bjoern Seibert, Chief of Staff for European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen, to follow up on their February 11 call and President Biden’s February 11 video call with transatlantic leaders.  The Deputy Secretary and Chief of Staff discussed diplomatic efforts to urge Russia to deescalate and choose diplomacy and reiterated that further Russian escalation would be met with massive, coordinated consequences and severe costs for the Russian Federation.  Both expressed the United States’ and EU’s resolute support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and commitment to strong transatlantic coordination.  Deputy Secretary Sherman also raised EU-UK negotiations on the implementation of the Northern Ireland Protocol and the importance of preserving the gains of the Belfast/Good Friday Agreement.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at a Virtual COVID-19 Small Group Minister Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-virtual-covid-19-small-group-minister-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 15:54:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=314087</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Greetings, everyone.  Good morning, good afternoon, good evening.  Thank you, thank you, thank you for joining from wherever you are around the world.</p>
<p>We are meeting at what is, I think, a decisive moment in the fight against COVID-19.  On the one hand, the Omicron variant is receding in many places, and thanks to the ingenuity of modern science, we’re armed with lifesaving vaccines; millions of people are getting vaccinated each day, and that’s in no small part due to the measures and efforts that many of you have undertaken, stretching back to the beginning of this pandemic.</p>
<p>At the same time, we all know the reality that the pandemic is far from over.  As you know, the World Health Organization set the goal of vaccinating 70 percent of people in every country across every income level by this September.  At the rate we’re going, we are well below our target.  One recent analysis found that while nearly 80 percent of people are vaccinated in upper, middle, and high-income countries, the number falls to less than 11 percent in low-income countries.  And last month, the World Health Organization warned that nearly 90 countries from around the world are not on track to reach the 70 percent goal.  That means billions of people remain vulnerable to COVID, and the world remains vulnerable to new variants, which may be even more lethal and transmissible than the ones we’ve experienced so far.</p>
<p>So we need to take all efforts and contributions that our countries are already making and intensify them and better coordinate them so that we can achieve our targets and end the acute phase of COVID-19 this year.  That’s why we’re getting together today.</p>
<p>The Global Action Plan that we’re launching today takes on what the international community has identified as the biggest barriers left in the fight to end this pandemic.  It’s our clearest roadmap yet, laying out six key lines of effort that, when pursued together, will help us achieve the goals laid out by President Biden at the Global COVID-19 Summit last year: vaccinate the world, save lives now, prepare the world against future pandemics.  It’s designed explicitly to match a country’s unique strengths with pressing areas of need.  Maybe that’s logistics and operations.  Maybe it’s a strong pharmaceutical industry.</p>
<p>Our challenge now is to connect these capacities with where they can do the most good for the most people.  We’ve identified gaps, and we’re closing gaps.  That’s what the Global Action Plan plans to do.  Let me briefly lay out each line of effort.</p>
<p>First, and most important, we’ve got to continue to get more shots into more arms more quickly.  That means addressing equity gaps by increasing access to effective vaccines around the world.  But we know that increasing supply by itself is not enough to turn vaccines into vaccinations.  We must also solve last-mile challenges, like access to cooling technologies for vaccines in transit.  Japan has shown leadership in this area with its “Last One Mile Support” program to about 60 countries.  We’ve got to keep building on that progress.</p>
<p>Second, we must strengthen the supply chains for vaccines and other critical supplies, like syringes, test kits, treatments.  The pandemic has highlighted just how vulnerable they are.  We can’t hit the WHO target without these supplies.</p>
<p>Third, we’ve got to address the information gaps that lead to low confidence in vaccines.  In some cases, bad actors are spreading misinformation and disinformation.  In others, there’s a lack of clear information about how safe and effective the vaccines are.  By tailoring our message to local audiences, we can provide clear guidance, push back against disinformation, and increase vaccine confidence.</p>
<p>Fourth, we need to provide more support, including vaccinations, equipment, training to health care workers who have been on the front lines of this pandemic from the start, risking their own lives to save others.</p>
<p>Fifth, we’ve got to make it easier for COVID patients to access treatments and therapeutics, because ending the pandemic isn’t only about protecting people from the virus; it’s also helping save lives of those who get sick.</p>
<p>And sixth and finally, we have to look to the future and strengthen global health security for the next emergency.  Among other things, that means ensuring sustainable financing for pandemic preparedness and response, including well financed international institutions and a new fund at the World Bank that focuses specifically on providing for the capacity that we need to prevent, to detect, to respond to future threats.  And I want to commend Indonesia for using its leadership of the G20 this year to move us forward on this front.</p>
<p>Again, thank you to everyone in this meeting for embracing the Global Action Plan and for leading the coordination of this effort with concrete commitments.  Our work today will help lay the groundwork for the next Global COVID-19 Summit, which President Biden will host later this spring.</p>
<p>For our part, the United States will continue to provide vaccine doses around the world through COVAX.  To date, we’ve delivered over 435 million safe, effective vaccines free of charge with no political strings attached as part of our overall commitment to donate 1.2 billion doses by the end of the year.  This includes our latest donation of 5 million Johnson &amp; Johnson doses to the African Vaccine Acquisition Trust, the innovative effort by the African Union to help smaller countries negotiate as a group for vaccine purchases.</p>
<p>Beyond our vaccine donations, the United States has committed to staying involved in all six lines of effort and playing a lead coordinating role on bolstering supply chain resilience and strengthening global health security.</p>
<p>In everything we do, we’ll seek to work closely with our partners, because this pandemic is the definition of a crisis that no country can solve alone.  We know it’s possible when we work together.  Just look at what Uganda recently accomplished.</p>
<p>In early November, only 14 percent of all Ugandan adults had received their first dose of the vaccine.  Then a major team effort commenced.  The Ugandan Government led a mass vaccination campaign, carried out by hundreds of health care workers.  They tracked their progress with a tool developed by the WHO.  Influential community leaders batted down misinformation.  Donors from around the world contributed doses.  And by late December, almost half of all adults in Uganda had received their first shot – from 14 to 47 percent in just six weeks.</p>
<p>That’s what’s possible when all of us – governments, international organizations, civil society, health care workers, individual citizens – work in unison.  With that level of coordination, partnership, and commitment, we can and we will end this pandemic.</p>
<p>So thanks again to everyone for joining today, and for the days ahead, as we work together, as we move together, as we coordinate together.  I’m looking forward to the conversation, and even more to this work, and to finally getting ahead of COVID-19 this year.  Thanks very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Greetings, everyone.  Good morning, good afternoon, good evening.  Thank you, thank you, thank you for joining from wherever you are around the world.</p>
<p>We are meeting at what is, I think, a decisive moment in the fight against COVID-19.  On the one hand, the Omicron variant is receding in many places, and thanks to the ingenuity of modern science, we’re armed with lifesaving vaccines; millions of people are getting vaccinated each day, and that’s in no small part due to the measures and efforts that many of you have undertaken, stretching back to the beginning of this pandemic.</p>
<p>At the same time, we all know the reality that the pandemic is far from over.  As you know, the World Health Organization set the goal of vaccinating 70 percent of people in every country across every income level by this September.  At the rate we’re going, we are well below our target.  One recent analysis found that while nearly 80 percent of people are vaccinated in upper, middle, and high-income countries, the number falls to less than 11 percent in low-income countries.  And last month, the World Health Organization warned that nearly 90 countries from around the world are not on track to reach the 70 percent goal.  That means billions of people remain vulnerable to COVID, and the world remains vulnerable to new variants, which may be even more lethal and transmissible than the ones we’ve experienced so far.</p>
<p>So we need to take all efforts and contributions that our countries are already making and intensify them and better coordinate them so that we can achieve our targets and end the acute phase of COVID-19 this year.  That’s why we’re getting together today.</p>
<p>The Global Action Plan that we’re launching today takes on what the international community has identified as the biggest barriers left in the fight to end this pandemic.  It’s our clearest roadmap yet, laying out six key lines of effort that, when pursued together, will help us achieve the goals laid out by President Biden at the Global COVID-19 Summit last year: vaccinate the world, save lives now, prepare the world against future pandemics.  It’s designed explicitly to match a country’s unique strengths with pressing areas of need.  Maybe that’s logistics and operations.  Maybe it’s a strong pharmaceutical industry.</p>
<p>Our challenge now is to connect these capacities with where they can do the most good for the most people.  We’ve identified gaps, and we’re closing gaps.  That’s what the Global Action Plan plans to do.  Let me briefly lay out each line of effort.</p>
<p>First, and most important, we’ve got to continue to get more shots into more arms more quickly.  That means addressing equity gaps by increasing access to effective vaccines around the world.  But we know that increasing supply by itself is not enough to turn vaccines into vaccinations.  We must also solve last-mile challenges, like access to cooling technologies for vaccines in transit.  Japan has shown leadership in this area with its “Last One Mile Support” program to about 60 countries.  We’ve got to keep building on that progress.</p>
<p>Second, we must strengthen the supply chains for vaccines and other critical supplies, like syringes, test kits, treatments.  The pandemic has highlighted just how vulnerable they are.  We can’t hit the WHO target without these supplies.</p>
<p>Third, we’ve got to address the information gaps that lead to low confidence in vaccines.  In some cases, bad actors are spreading misinformation and disinformation.  In others, there’s a lack of clear information about how safe and effective the vaccines are.  By tailoring our message to local audiences, we can provide clear guidance, push back against disinformation, and increase vaccine confidence.</p>
<p>Fourth, we need to provide more support, including vaccinations, equipment, training to health care workers who have been on the front lines of this pandemic from the start, risking their own lives to save others.</p>
<p>Fifth, we’ve got to make it easier for COVID patients to access treatments and therapeutics, because ending the pandemic isn’t only about protecting people from the virus; it’s also helping save lives of those who get sick.</p>
<p>And sixth and finally, we have to look to the future and strengthen global health security for the next emergency.  Among other things, that means ensuring sustainable financing for pandemic preparedness and response, including well financed international institutions and a new fund at the World Bank that focuses specifically on providing for the capacity that we need to prevent, to detect, to respond to future threats.  And I want to commend Indonesia for using its leadership of the G20 this year to move us forward on this front.</p>
<p>Again, thank you to everyone in this meeting for embracing the Global Action Plan and for leading the coordination of this effort with concrete commitments.  Our work today will help lay the groundwork for the next Global COVID-19 Summit, which President Biden will host later this spring.</p>
<p>For our part, the United States will continue to provide vaccine doses around the world through COVAX.  To date, we’ve delivered over 435 million safe, effective vaccines free of charge with no political strings attached as part of our overall commitment to donate 1.2 billion doses by the end of the year.  This includes our latest donation of 5 million Johnson &amp; Johnson doses to the African Vaccine Acquisition Trust, the innovative effort by the African Union to help smaller countries negotiate as a group for vaccine purchases.</p>
<p>Beyond our vaccine donations, the United States has committed to staying involved in all six lines of effort and playing a lead coordinating role on bolstering supply chain resilience and strengthening global health security.</p>
<p>In everything we do, we’ll seek to work closely with our partners, because this pandemic is the definition of a crisis that no country can solve alone.  We know it’s possible when we work together.  Just look at what Uganda recently accomplished.</p>
<p>In early November, only 14 percent of all Ugandan adults had received their first dose of the vaccine.  Then a major team effort commenced.  The Ugandan Government led a mass vaccination campaign, carried out by hundreds of health care workers.  They tracked their progress with a tool developed by the WHO.  Influential community leaders batted down misinformation.  Donors from around the world contributed doses.  And by late December, almost half of all adults in Uganda had received their first shot – from 14 to 47 percent in just six weeks.</p>
<p>That’s what’s possible when all of us – governments, international organizations, civil society, health care workers, individual citizens – work in unison.  With that level of coordination, partnership, and commitment, we can and we will end this pandemic.</p>
<p>So thanks again to everyone for joining today, and for the days ahead, as we work together, as we move together, as we coordinate together.  I’m looking forward to the conversation, and even more to this work, and to finally getting ahead of COVID-19 this year.  Thanks very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Kuleba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-ukrainian-foreign-minister-kuleba-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 15:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=314072</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke by phone today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba.  The Secretary noted the United States and partners remain united in our commitment to the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine, including its economic and financial stability.  The Secretary highlighted that, although the United States’ immediate priority is to support efforts to de-escalate the situation, any further military aggression by Russia against Ukraine will be met with a swift, coordinated, and forceful response.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke by phone today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba.  The Secretary noted the United States and partners remain united in our commitment to the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine, including its economic and financial stability.  The Secretary highlighted that, although the United States’ immediate priority is to support efforts to de-escalate the situation, any further military aggression by Russia against Ukraine will be met with a swift, coordinated, and forceful response.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Envoy for the Horn of Africa Satterfield Travel to Addis Ababa</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-envoy-for-the-horn-of-africa-satterfield-travel-to-addis-ababa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 21:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313923</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Envoy for the Horn of Africa David Satterfield will travel to Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, February 13-14. Special Envoy Satterfield will meet with Ethiopian government, African Union, and United Nations officials, as well as representatives of humanitarian organizations.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Envoy for the Horn of Africa David Satterfield will travel to Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, February 13-14. Special Envoy Satterfield will meet with Ethiopian government, African Union, and United Nations officials, as well as representatives of humanitarian organizations.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Joint Press Availability with Republic of Korea Foreign Minister Chung Eui-yong and Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Yoshimasa</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-joint-press-availability-with-republic-of-korea-foreign-minister-chung-eui-yong-and-japanese-foreign-minister-hayashi-yoshimasa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[U.S. Department of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 09:03:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313894</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Honolulu, Hawaii</p>
<p>Asia-Pacific Center for Security Studies</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone.  I am very grateful to my colleagues, Foreign Ministers Hayashi and Chung, for a very productive set of meetings today.  And it’s good to be not just with colleagues, but with friends.  (Inaudible.)</p>
<p>For decades, the United States’ alliances with Japan and the Republic of Korea have been among our most important not only in the Indo-Pacific, but around the world.  They’re rooted in an ironclad security relationship, America’s steadfast commitment to defend both allies, in our deep and growing economic and trade ties, and in the abiding bonds between our people.</p>
<p>But we increasingly recognize that if we’re going to meet the complex challenges of our time – and take full advantage of the opportunities for our people – the Republic of Korea, Japan, and the United States must do more together.  We have to learn to do trilaterally what’s become natural to do bilaterally.</p>
<p>That takes intense engagement, which is exactly what we’ve been pursuing.  The result is unprecedented cooperation among us, as evidenced by the substance of today’s meeting.  The U.S. is also committed to helping our partners work through challenges in their relations, which is manifestly in the collective interest of the region and of the people in all three of our countries.</p>
<p>The last time I was here at the Daniel K. Inouye Asia-Pacific Center was in 2016, with the Vice President at the time, Joe Biden.  We were here for a trilateral meeting with the Republic of Korea and Japan.  And as the then Vice President said at that meeting, “We’re making trilateral engagements between our countries a habit…and good habits form good relationships.”</p>
<p>That’s why we’ve held three trilateral ministerial meetings in the last year.  We’re also making it a habit to work together across our governments – at every level – including when Deputy Secretary Sherman hosted her trilateral counterparts in November, and she will continue to carry that process forward.</p>
<p>It’s also essential to delivering on our strategy for a free and open Indo-Pacific, which we released yesterday.  That strategy reflects the fundamental truth that, more any other part of the world, what happens in this region is going to shape the lives of Americans and people around the world in this 21st century.  The strategy sets out several concrete ways that we’ll work to turn this vision into reality – benchmarks that we can hold ourselves to over the next couple of years.  Strengthening trilateral cooperation among Korea, Japan, and the United States is one of those benchmarks.  It’s indispensable to virtually everything we want to do in the region.  So, as with my entire trip, we&#8217;re not just talking about focusing on the Indo-Pacific; we’re actually doing it.</p>
<p>And that’s what we did in today’s trilateral meeting, across a range of important issues, reflected in the joint statement that we will issue.</p>
<p>We discussed ways to deepen our trilateral efforts to end the COVID-19 pandemic, from boosting vaccine manufacturing and improving distribution, to increasing financing for global health security, so that we can detect and prevent the next pandemic.  The Republic of Korea and Japan will play key roles in a meeting that I’ll convene on Monday to set out a new Global Action Plan, which will drive greater coordination and urgency in our shared push to end the pandemic.</p>
<p>We explored ways that we can work together to meet the ambitious targets that each of our countries set when it comes to tackling climate change, and how we can team up to help other countries meet their goals.  That includes coordinating our investments in sustainable infrastructure and in building resilience to the inevitable changes that come from climate change.</p>
<p>And we focused on ways we can strengthen our economic security, which is increasingly interconnected.  That means shoring up vulnerabilities in our supply chains that have been exposed by the pandemic – from semiconductors to critical minerals – which will also make us less reliant on suppliers who violate human rights or flout environmental standards.  This, also, is much easier to do with three advanced economies than two or one.</p>
<p>Our economic security also depends on upholding the rules of the road that have enabled decades of unprecedented security for our people and prosperity across the region and around the world.  This includes ensuring that our workers and businesses can compete on a fair and level playing field, and protecting freedom of navigation and overflight, including in the South and East China Seas.</p>
<p>And it includes working together to shape new norms and standards that align with our values and interests, such as in emerging technologies, which are driving big sectors of our intertwined economies and touch on virtually every aspect of the lives of our people.</p>
<p>Finally, we discussed how to advance our shared goal of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and finding lasting peace there.  We condemn the DPRK’s recent ballistic missile launches and its unlawful nuclear and ballistic programs, which are clear violations of UN Security Council resolutions. And we continue to work to find ways to hold the DPRK accountable, as we did by imposing sanctions on eight DPRK-linked individuals and entities last month.</p>
<p>Together with our respective special representatives on this topic – Ambassador Sung Kim, who is here, Special Representative Noh, Director General Funakoshi – we discussed ways that we can deepen trilateral cooperation to deter the DPRK, limit the reach of its most dangerous weapons, defend against its provocations or use of force, and above all, keep the American, Japanese, and Korean people safe, which is our highest responsibility.</p>
<p>I want to underscore, we have no hostile intent toward the DPRK.  We remain open to dialogue without preconditions, if Pyongyang chooses that path.</p>
<p>Before I turn to my colleagues, and with their indulgence, let me give a brief update on the crisis in Ukraine, which we also discussed at some length in today’s meetings.</p>
<p>I spoke by phone last night with Russian Foreign Minister Lavrov, where I raised our serious concerns that Moscow may be considering launching a military attack against Ukraine in the coming days.  I made clear, as President Biden did today in his conversation with President Putin, that a diplomatic path to resolving this crisis – a crisis created by the unprovoked massing of Russian forces all around Ukraine – that diplomatic path remains open.</p>
<p>The way for Moscow to show that it wants to pursue that path is simple: it should de-escalate, rather than escalate.  And it should not only talk about seeking a diplomatic outcome, but actually work toward one.  On our call, Foreign Minister Lavrov said that the Russians are working on a response to the paper that we sent to Moscow more than two weeks ago proposing concrete areas for discussion.  It remains to be seen if they’ll follow through on that.  But if they do, we’ll be ready to engage, together with our allies and partners.</p>
<p>I also underscored that if Moscow chooses the path of aggression and further invades Ukraine, the response from the United States and our allies and partners will be swift, it will be united, it will be severe.</p>
<p>Yesterday, we ordered the departure of most of the Americans still at the U.S. embassy in Kyiv.  The risk of Russian military action is high enough, and the threat is imminent enough, that this is the prudent thing to do.  No one should be surprised if Russia instigates a provocation or incident, which it then uses to justify military action it had planned all along.</p>
<p>A core team will remain in Ukraine with our dedicated Ukrainian colleagues as we continue to work relentlessly to resolve this crisis through deterrence and diplomacy.   Our security assistance to Ukraine – as well as aid for other sectors like public health, economic development – all of that will continue.</p>
<p>In the meeting that the three of us had, we discussed the threat that Russia’s aggression poses – not only to Ukraine, but to the entire international rules-based order, which has provided a foundation for decades of shared security and prosperity, for our people here in this region and, again, around the globe.</p>
<p>When one country seeks to flout the sovereignty and territorial integrity of another, when it seeks to change the borders of another by force, when it seeks to dictate to that country its choices, its policies, with whom it may associate; when it seeks to exert a sphere of influence to subjugate a neighbor to its will, that is profoundly corrosive and undermining of these very rules and norms that undermine – underscore our own security, and again, not just in Europe but around the world.  And if we allow that to go unchallenged, if we allow it to proceed with impunity, then we open a Pandora’s box – again, not just in Europe but around the world.  And that’s why we agreed to stick together in our response to Russia no matter which path it chooses.</p>
<p>Times like these are the reason that we’ve invested decades in building America’s unmatched set of alliances and partnerships.  They underscore why the work our three countries are doing here today is so crucial: so that we can meet this challenge, and others to come, from a position of unity, solidarity, and strength.</p>
<p>With that, let me turn it over to Foreign Minister Chung.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER CHUNG:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  Thank you.  This U.S-Japan-Republic of Korea trilateral ministerial meeting has been convened successfully.  I extend my sincere appreciation to Secretary Blinken and the Government of the United States.  The meeting was indeed highly timely, constructive, and informative.  We have engaged in informative exchange of information amongst ourselves.  We welcome the Biden administration’s commitment to the value of alliances and its willingness to proactively engage in the Indo-Pacific and through the strengthening of the ROK-U.S. alliance and trilateral coordination among Korea, the U.S., and Japan. We are determined to continue working in concert.</p>
<p>Today, we addressed a top priority of our three countries, issues of the DPRK and its nuclear program, through in-depth discussion.  And at the same time, major regional and global pending issues were also covered during our highly fruitful conversation.  We reaffirmed our shared goals of achieving complete denuclearization and establishment of lasting peace on the Korean Peninsula through dialogue and diplomacy, and we reached consensus in three aspects.</p>
<p>First, we expressed concern over the DPRK’s recent series of missile launches and other actions that heightened tensions in the region, resolving to prevent the situation on the Korean Peninsula from deteriorating further by making proactive endeavors.</p>
<p>We reaffirmed that diplomacy and dialogue with the North is of greater importance than ever, and to bring forward engagement with Pyongyang we exchanged views on a variety of realistic measures.  Thus far, the Biden administration has confirmed that it held no hostile intent towards the DPRK, emphasizing its openness to meeting their country without any preconditions anywhere, anytime, on numerous occasions.  I call on the DPRK to reciprocate and promptly return to dialogue and diplomacy.</p>
<p>Third, going forward as well our three countries agreed to engage in active communication at various levels and closely coordinate on issues on the Korean Peninsula.  We have reaffirmed that regional and international peace, stability, and prosperity are our common interests and goals, and resolved also to step up our cooperation going further.</p>
<p>We are greatly concerned about violence and human rights infringement in Myanmar and to restore democracy and improve the human rights situation therein concurrent to work together with ASEAN and the international community.</p>
<p>On the situation in Ukraine as well, we shared our deep concern.  Through diplomacy and dialogue, Ukraine’s peace and stability should be re-established as early as possible, a position we reaffirmed.</p>
<p>Cooperation among Korea, the United States, and Japan ranges from ensuring stable global supply chains including for critical minerals and promoting other mutually beneficial, future-oriented, and practical cooperation to addressing global challenges such as economic and security cooperation, and its scope continues to expand.</p>
<p>We share democracy, human rights, market economy, and other core values as likeminded countries, and as such agree to continue to our cooperation for global peace and prosperity. Notably, to address COVID-19 and the immediate challenge facing the entire humanity, we’re actively and making endeavors in this regard and supporting U.S. initiative for the COVID-19 Global Action Plan.</p>
<p>Today, we reaffirmed importance and usefulness of trilateral cooperation among Korea, the U.S., and Japan.  As we move forward, we’ll be getting together often on various occasions, including multilateral meetings, to continue our strategic communication and coordination.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you very much.  I just concluded Japan-U.S.-ROK foreign ministers meeting with Secretary Blinken and Minister Chung.  We had a very fruitful discussion, and I would like to thank Secretary Blinken once again for the wonderful hospitality.</p>
<p>To begin with, regarding North Korea, we shared serious concerns over North Korea’s recent and repeated launches of ballistic missiles, including the latest launch of IRBM class ballistic missile on January 30th.  Based on the shared understanding that North Korea’s nuclear and missile activities pose a threat to the peace and stability of the region and the international community, we aligned our recognition on future measures.</p>
<p>Firstly, we concurred to further strengthen regional deterrence.  While the Japan-U.S. alliance as well as U.S.-ROK alliance each play an important role in this regard, we concurred on advancing security cooperation among Japan, U.S., and the ROK.</p>
<p>Second, we agreed on the importance of fully implementing United Nations Security Council resolutions and concurred to coordinate even more closely on future responses by the Security Council.</p>
<p>Thirdly, we shared the recognition that even in such a situation diplomatic efforts are important and we agreed to deepen the discussion among Japan, U.S., and ROK.  In this vein, Prime Minister Kishida had repeatedly expressed his determination to meet with Chairman Kim Jong-un face to face.</p>
<p>I also asked for continued understanding and cooperation from the two ministers on abductions issue, and to which they expressed their strong support.</p>
<p>We also had a candid discussion on the regional affairs with the recognition about the collaboration among Japan, U.S., and the ROK is of strategic importance beyond North Korean related issue.  In this context, I once again welcomed the Indo-Pacific strategy that the U.S. announced yesterday.  We also affirmed to expand cooperation and collaboration for the peace and stability of the region with our shared concern about activities that undermine the rules-based international order and concurred that we strongly oppose any unilateral actions that seek to alter the status quo and increase tensions in the region.  We are strongly opposed to unilateral action that seeks to alter status quo.</p>
<p>We also exchanged our views – furthermore, we also discussed global issues such as climate change and COVID-19 and other global health issues now pressing challenge for international community.  We concurred on the continued cooperation among Japan, U.S. and ROK in dealing with such challenges.</p>
<p>Lastly, we agreed to further enhance the collaboration among Japan, U.S., and ROK at multiple levels.  Based on today’s discussion as well as joint statement we issued, I would like to work even more closely with you as and ROK for the peace, stability, and prosperity of the region and the international community, including dealing with North Korea.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll now turn to questions.  We’ll take one question from each delegation.  The first question goes to Nike Ching of VOA.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Good afternoon, gentlemen.  Aloha.</p>
<p>For Secretary Blinken, would the United States consider bold steps toward North Korea, and are you concerned that the dispute between Japan and South Korea over island sovereignty and historical issues are getting in the way?  How close are the United, is the United States watching the presidential election in South Korea?</p>
<p>And for Foreign Minister Chung, for Foreign Minister Chung, do you have a assessment of North Korea leader Kim Jong-un’s health?  What do you think is the intention, and how do you evaluate recent missiles launches by North Korea?</p>
<p>And for Foreign Minister Hayashi, do you assess the result of the presidential election in South Korea may complicate a joint trilateral approach toward North Korea?</p>
<p>And separately, if I may, on Ukraine for both Foreign Minister Hayashi and Foreign Minister Chung, has the United States asked Japan to provide more LNG, liquified natural gas, to Europe, supplies to Europe?  And are Japan and South Korea worried over the economic disruptions of a war, and what assurances have you gotten?</p>
<p>(In Japanese and Korean.)  Thank you very much, gentlemen.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Nike, thank you for the excellent multipart, multiperson question.  (Laughter.)  You covered a lot of ground.  I’m happy to start and then hand it over to my colleagues.</p>
<p>I think it is clear to all of us that the DPRK is in a phase of provocation.  We condemned the recent missile launches, violations of UN Security Council resolutions.  We will continue to hold the DPRK accountable even as we seek to engage in diplomacy.  As you know, we imposed sanctions on eight DPRK-linked individuals and entities last month, and we are very closely consulting together on further steps.</p>
<p>At the same time, we remain prepared to meet without preconditions to pursue practical steps toward diplomacy.  The goal remains the same and it’s a shared goal.  It’s the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, and it is lasting peace.  We have no hostile intent toward North Korea.  And again, we unfortunately have seen their response to our making it clear that we’re prepared to pursue diplomacy with – unfortunately, that response has been a series now of provocative actions.</p>
<p>I think what’s important and that comes out of today, and this will be reflected in the joint statement that we’ll put out shortly, is that we are absolutely united in our approach, in our determination.  And that unity of purpose is, I think, vitally important for dealing with the challenge posed by the DPRK and also pursuing a more – a more hopeful future.  But I’ll – I invite you to take a look at the joint statement.</p>
<p>When it comes to elections and the like, happily, in my job I don’t do politics.  I don’t do them in my own country.  I don’t do them in other countries.  So I’ll leave it at that.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER CHUNG:</strong>  Thank you. (Via interpreter) Well, there was a question regarding the relations between Korea and Japan.  Although the question was not directed towards myself, regarding the Dokdo Island issue the Korean Government’s position is very clear, so I do not want to repeat that view myself.  But that does not have any impact whatsoever regarding our relations concerning the issue of the DPRK.  In the recent month, the DPRK’s test-firing of ballistic missiles is a conduct that is clearly wrong.  And regarding such launches we have – we are deeply concerned and we expressed regret, and we are strongly urging North Korea to not repeat such testing.</p>
<p>But as was just stated by Secretary Blinken, complete denuclearization and establishment of lasting peace on the Korean Peninsula, our commitment to that goal has never changed.  And for us to be able to achieve these shared goals, diplomacy and dialogue is a way to go for us.  Our commitment to that goal and approach is also unchanged.</p>
<p>Recently, the DPRK is making its own decisions and has been talking about the possibility of lifting its self-imposed moratorium on missile launches.  We are deeply concerned about that, and I strongly urged the DPRK not to put its words into action.</p>
<p>Concerning the situation in Ukraine, the developments have been going into the wrong direction.  And regarding the support of LNG to Europe, if there are any difficulties in that regard concerning the assistance of gas supply to Europe, we are taking that matter into account proactively.  I hope that through diplomacy and dialogue we hope to see the resolution of the situation in Ukraine as well.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you.  I had a frank exchange of views during the bilateral discussions and through the trilateral meeting.  Please refer to the announcement that will be shared later. The position of Takeshima is already known.</p>
<p>And about the special elections in South Korea – there was a question raised – that is a internal affair of a different country, so I will refer from answering the question.</p>
<p>And to supply of natural gas was requested from U.S. and Europe, and Japan has decided to supply the natural gas.  And recently we – there was appreciation expressed from American government as well.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Gyu Kim, JTBC.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you, Ned.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter)  First of all, I have a question to Minister Chung.  The three countries have been actually urging on North Korea to come to dialogue, but we have not been able to see any concrete measures, though.  In order to accelerate their involvement, have you discussed any realistic measures?  I think you said that in your statement.  So what are some concrete measures that you are going to propose to North Korea?  Could you give us more details?</p>
<p>I have a question to Secretary Blinken.  In relation to the Ukraine’s situations, for example, do you believe that ICBM can be launched by North Korea in line with the current situation that’s worsening in Ukraine?  Would you think that United States will be able to manage these two situations at the same time?</p>
<p>And also going beyond urging dialogue from North Korea, perhaps sending a personal letter from President Biden to North Korea?  There are some people who are saying that there should be high-level intervention.</p>
<p>And last, I have a question to Minister Hayashi.  You said that you understand the need to have a trilateral coordination between the three countries.  Perhaps the three leaders have to get together.  So in terms of the bilateral meeting between the Japan and Korea on this, and also there are some historical issues that are underway.</p>
<p><strong>INTERPRETER: </strong> I’m very sorry, but there are disruptions to the feedback – the sound feed that we’re getting from the speaker.  The interpretation booth was not able to get any sound from the microphone.  I believe that the last question by the journalist would have to be repeated again.  There were some technical issues.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  So three countries understand the importance of trilateral cooperation.  In order to emphasize and underscore that, we need to have a leader-level meeting at the highest level.  So for example, between the bilateral – the bilateral summit between Korea and Japan, and between the trilateral meetings.  So what is the commitment from Japan?</p>
<p>And also because of the historical issues, do you see a stalemate between the bilateral relations between Korea and Japan?  Of course, two countries would have to work harder.  Are there any specific efforts that are currently undertaken by the Japanese Government in order to improve relations with Korea?</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:</strong>  (Via interpreter) I believe the first question was posed to me, so let met me answer that question.  Yes, we actually discussed a lot of measures to deal with this issue, but we are unable to disclose that information at this point of time.  At an opportune time in the future, I believe that information will be disclosed to the public in due course.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I certainly don’t rule out that North Korea could engage in further provocative actions as things are happening in other parts of the world, including in Europe with regard to Ukraine.  In fact, as we’ve been dealing with the challenge posed by Russia’s threats of aggression against Ukraine, we’ve, of course, had a series of missile launches and tests by North Korea that we’ve responded to in solidarity with our allies and partners.</p>
<p>The bottom line is – and I think in a sense this week is a reasonable demonstration of that – we walk and chew gum at the same time.  Even as I’ve spent the week in the Indo-Pacific region – in Australia, in Fiji, now here in Hawaii, working with the Quad countries, working with our partners in the Pacific Islands, and of course, here today with our close allies and partners from Japan and Korea – I’ve also been engaged, we’ve also been engaged, in managing the challenge that Russia is currently posing to security in Europe and Ukraine.</p>
<p>And in a sense, these things are also inherently linked, because whether it is provocative actions undertaken by the DPRK, Russian aggression toward Ukraine, other actions in this region by large countries that seek to undermine the rules-based order that we have established together, these are – these are of a piece.  And the common denominator is when basic principles that we’ve established together that are vital to the security and the prosperity of people in all of our countries are being challenged, we stand up together to defend them.</p>
<p>Our three countries – and again, I think this will come out in the joint statement – we have a profoundly affirmative vision for what we want to do together for the future, for the citizens of our countries and for people around the world.  But we’re also committed together as allies and partners to stand up and defend the rules-based order and to act together in solidarity when the principles of that order are being challenged, wherever that challenge is taking place, whether it’s in Europe or here in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p>And that’s, again, I think a hallmark and the reason why the United States over many years has established these partnerships, these alliances, bringing countries together in common cause and common purpose.  That enables us very effectively to deal with multiple challenges at the same time.  And again, beyond that I think there’s a common denominator to all of them, which is why, as you’ve heard from my colleagues today, there is tremendous solidarity not only when it comes to dealing with challenges immediately in the Indo-Pacific but when it comes to dealing with the threat of Russian aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN  MINISTER CHUNG:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you very much.  Cooperation between U.S. and South Korea is essential for the peace and stability in this region.  (Inaudible) North Korea, we discussed about the recent situation, including China and Ukraine, and we had a very good exchange of views.  So going forward for the peace and stability for the region, cooperation between the three countries should be further developed.</p>
<p><strong>INTERPRETER:</strong>  Yes, one correction from Japanese-to-English interpreter.  When Minister Hayashi made initial statement, the interpreter skipped one paragraph, which reads as follows:</p>
<p>We also exchanged our views on Ukraine while sharing views about tensions are escalating.  We confirmed our unwavering support for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine and concurred to continued close coordination.  Apology from interpreter.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you.  Our final question will come from Yuichi Nobira from Asahi Shimbun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Nobira from Asahi Shimbun.  I have a question to the three ministers.  Although regional stability cooperation between the three countries is important, but currently China is enhancing its advancement into the sea.  And both Japan, the U.S., at the defense ministerial meeting in January and sort of online meeting, they confirmed the strengthening of the alliance.  Between Japan, U.S. and ROK, do you plan to take common measure with agreement with respect to the approaches to China?  How do you think such approaches would be important?  I have question to all of you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I would again invite you to look at the joint statement that we will issue shortly after this meeting comes to an end.  We discussed and I think the statement reflects the shared concern that we have about activities that undermine the rules-based international order, as we were just discussing.  We reaffirmed the desire that we share for a peaceful and stable region that would allow all countries to reach their full potential free from coercion.  We strongly oppose any unilateral actions that seek to alter the status quo and increase tensions in the region.  And we reiterated our very strong support, longstanding support, for international law, highlighting in particular the importance of compliance with international law as reflected in the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Seas.</p>
<p>So I think you’ll see that in the joint statement.  We also emphasized the importance of peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait.  So I invite you to look at the statement when we put it out shortly.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER CHUNG:</strong>  (In Korean) (Via interpreter)  Thank you.  As far as we’re concerned in this Northeast Asian region, based on order –</p>
<p><strong>INTERPRETER:</strong> My apologies, the audio feed is cut off.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER CHUNG:</strong> (Via interpreter) We have reached a full agreement on that aspect.  Maintaining peace and stability in the region is extremely important, and any conduct that goes against maintaining the status quo is something that we opposed.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:</strong> (In Japanese) (Via interpreter)  So as a solution that both ministers of the three countries must expand, it’s cooperation that was confirmed and the activities that are damaging to international cooperation, which is made in rule or attempts to change the status quo and other actions of trying to enhance tension, is something we agree to strongly oppose such action.</p>
<p>As I have mentioned, cooperation between U.S., ROK, and Japan (inaudible) measures against North Korea, but these are essential for peace and stability of the whole region.  So in addition to responses of North Korea, we had a frank exchange of views of the recent situation, including the situation of China and Ukraine.  So we want to further develop the cooperation between our three countries for the peace and stability of the region.</p>
<p>Based on the rules – I misspoke on my – let me make my apologies.  The order, based on rules, the rules-based order.  International order is something that we value.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  That concludes the press conference.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, everyone.  I invite you to go outside and enjoy the day. <input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Honolulu, Hawaii</p>
<p>Asia-Pacific Center for Security Studies</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone.  I am very grateful to my colleagues, Foreign Ministers Hayashi and Chung, for a very productive set of meetings today.  And it’s good to be not just with colleagues, but with friends.  (Inaudible.)</p>
<p>For decades, the United States’ alliances with Japan and the Republic of Korea have been among our most important not only in the Indo-Pacific, but around the world.  They’re rooted in an ironclad security relationship, America’s steadfast commitment to defend both allies, in our deep and growing economic and trade ties, and in the abiding bonds between our people.</p>
<p>But we increasingly recognize that if we’re going to meet the complex challenges of our time – and take full advantage of the opportunities for our people – the Republic of Korea, Japan, and the United States must do more together.  We have to learn to do trilaterally what’s become natural to do bilaterally.</p>
<p>That takes intense engagement, which is exactly what we’ve been pursuing.  The result is unprecedented cooperation among us, as evidenced by the substance of today’s meeting.  The U.S. is also committed to helping our partners work through challenges in their relations, which is manifestly in the collective interest of the region and of the people in all three of our countries.</p>
<p>The last time I was here at the Daniel K. Inouye Asia-Pacific Center was in 2016, with the Vice President at the time, Joe Biden.  We were here for a trilateral meeting with the Republic of Korea and Japan.  And as the then Vice President said at that meeting, “We’re making trilateral engagements between our countries a habit…and good habits form good relationships.”</p>
<p>That’s why we’ve held three trilateral ministerial meetings in the last year.  We’re also making it a habit to work together across our governments – at every level – including when Deputy Secretary Sherman hosted her trilateral counterparts in November, and she will continue to carry that process forward.</p>
<p>It’s also essential to delivering on our strategy for a free and open Indo-Pacific, which we released yesterday.  That strategy reflects the fundamental truth that, more any other part of the world, what happens in this region is going to shape the lives of Americans and people around the world in this 21st century.  The strategy sets out several concrete ways that we’ll work to turn this vision into reality – benchmarks that we can hold ourselves to over the next couple of years.  Strengthening trilateral cooperation among Korea, Japan, and the United States is one of those benchmarks.  It’s indispensable to virtually everything we want to do in the region.  So, as with my entire trip, we&#8217;re not just talking about focusing on the Indo-Pacific; we’re actually doing it.</p>
<p>And that’s what we did in today’s trilateral meeting, across a range of important issues, reflected in the joint statement that we will issue.</p>
<p>We discussed ways to deepen our trilateral efforts to end the COVID-19 pandemic, from boosting vaccine manufacturing and improving distribution, to increasing financing for global health security, so that we can detect and prevent the next pandemic.  The Republic of Korea and Japan will play key roles in a meeting that I’ll convene on Monday to set out a new Global Action Plan, which will drive greater coordination and urgency in our shared push to end the pandemic.</p>
<p>We explored ways that we can work together to meet the ambitious targets that each of our countries set when it comes to tackling climate change, and how we can team up to help other countries meet their goals.  That includes coordinating our investments in sustainable infrastructure and in building resilience to the inevitable changes that come from climate change.</p>
<p>And we focused on ways we can strengthen our economic security, which is increasingly interconnected.  That means shoring up vulnerabilities in our supply chains that have been exposed by the pandemic – from semiconductors to critical minerals – which will also make us less reliant on suppliers who violate human rights or flout environmental standards.  This, also, is much easier to do with three advanced economies than two or one.</p>
<p>Our economic security also depends on upholding the rules of the road that have enabled decades of unprecedented security for our people and prosperity across the region and around the world.  This includes ensuring that our workers and businesses can compete on a fair and level playing field, and protecting freedom of navigation and overflight, including in the South and East China Seas.</p>
<p>And it includes working together to shape new norms and standards that align with our values and interests, such as in emerging technologies, which are driving big sectors of our intertwined economies and touch on virtually every aspect of the lives of our people.</p>
<p>Finally, we discussed how to advance our shared goal of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and finding lasting peace there.  We condemn the DPRK’s recent ballistic missile launches and its unlawful nuclear and ballistic programs, which are clear violations of UN Security Council resolutions. And we continue to work to find ways to hold the DPRK accountable, as we did by imposing sanctions on eight DPRK-linked individuals and entities last month.</p>
<p>Together with our respective special representatives on this topic – Ambassador Sung Kim, who is here, Special Representative Noh, Director General Funakoshi – we discussed ways that we can deepen trilateral cooperation to deter the DPRK, limit the reach of its most dangerous weapons, defend against its provocations or use of force, and above all, keep the American, Japanese, and Korean people safe, which is our highest responsibility.</p>
<p>I want to underscore, we have no hostile intent toward the DPRK.  We remain open to dialogue without preconditions, if Pyongyang chooses that path.</p>
<p>Before I turn to my colleagues, and with their indulgence, let me give a brief update on the crisis in Ukraine, which we also discussed at some length in today’s meetings.</p>
<p>I spoke by phone last night with Russian Foreign Minister Lavrov, where I raised our serious concerns that Moscow may be considering launching a military attack against Ukraine in the coming days.  I made clear, as President Biden did today in his conversation with President Putin, that a diplomatic path to resolving this crisis – a crisis created by the unprovoked massing of Russian forces all around Ukraine – that diplomatic path remains open.</p>
<p>The way for Moscow to show that it wants to pursue that path is simple: it should de-escalate, rather than escalate.  And it should not only talk about seeking a diplomatic outcome, but actually work toward one.  On our call, Foreign Minister Lavrov said that the Russians are working on a response to the paper that we sent to Moscow more than two weeks ago proposing concrete areas for discussion.  It remains to be seen if they’ll follow through on that.  But if they do, we’ll be ready to engage, together with our allies and partners.</p>
<p>I also underscored that if Moscow chooses the path of aggression and further invades Ukraine, the response from the United States and our allies and partners will be swift, it will be united, it will be severe.</p>
<p>Yesterday, we ordered the departure of most of the Americans still at the U.S. embassy in Kyiv.  The risk of Russian military action is high enough, and the threat is imminent enough, that this is the prudent thing to do.  No one should be surprised if Russia instigates a provocation or incident, which it then uses to justify military action it had planned all along.</p>
<p>A core team will remain in Ukraine with our dedicated Ukrainian colleagues as we continue to work relentlessly to resolve this crisis through deterrence and diplomacy.   Our security assistance to Ukraine – as well as aid for other sectors like public health, economic development – all of that will continue.</p>
<p>In the meeting that the three of us had, we discussed the threat that Russia’s aggression poses – not only to Ukraine, but to the entire international rules-based order, which has provided a foundation for decades of shared security and prosperity, for our people here in this region and, again, around the globe.</p>
<p>When one country seeks to flout the sovereignty and territorial integrity of another, when it seeks to change the borders of another by force, when it seeks to dictate to that country its choices, its policies, with whom it may associate; when it seeks to exert a sphere of influence to subjugate a neighbor to its will, that is profoundly corrosive and undermining of these very rules and norms that undermine – underscore our own security, and again, not just in Europe but around the world.  And if we allow that to go unchallenged, if we allow it to proceed with impunity, then we open a Pandora’s box – again, not just in Europe but around the world.  And that’s why we agreed to stick together in our response to Russia no matter which path it chooses.</p>
<p>Times like these are the reason that we’ve invested decades in building America’s unmatched set of alliances and partnerships.  They underscore why the work our three countries are doing here today is so crucial: so that we can meet this challenge, and others to come, from a position of unity, solidarity, and strength.</p>
<p>With that, let me turn it over to Foreign Minister Chung.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER CHUNG:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  Thank you.  This U.S-Japan-Republic of Korea trilateral ministerial meeting has been convened successfully.  I extend my sincere appreciation to Secretary Blinken and the Government of the United States.  The meeting was indeed highly timely, constructive, and informative.  We have engaged in informative exchange of information amongst ourselves.  We welcome the Biden administration’s commitment to the value of alliances and its willingness to proactively engage in the Indo-Pacific and through the strengthening of the ROK-U.S. alliance and trilateral coordination among Korea, the U.S., and Japan. We are determined to continue working in concert.</p>
<p>Today, we addressed a top priority of our three countries, issues of the DPRK and its nuclear program, through in-depth discussion.  And at the same time, major regional and global pending issues were also covered during our highly fruitful conversation.  We reaffirmed our shared goals of achieving complete denuclearization and establishment of lasting peace on the Korean Peninsula through dialogue and diplomacy, and we reached consensus in three aspects.</p>
<p>First, we expressed concern over the DPRK’s recent series of missile launches and other actions that heightened tensions in the region, resolving to prevent the situation on the Korean Peninsula from deteriorating further by making proactive endeavors.</p>
<p>We reaffirmed that diplomacy and dialogue with the North is of greater importance than ever, and to bring forward engagement with Pyongyang we exchanged views on a variety of realistic measures.  Thus far, the Biden administration has confirmed that it held no hostile intent towards the DPRK, emphasizing its openness to meeting their country without any preconditions anywhere, anytime, on numerous occasions.  I call on the DPRK to reciprocate and promptly return to dialogue and diplomacy.</p>
<p>Third, going forward as well our three countries agreed to engage in active communication at various levels and closely coordinate on issues on the Korean Peninsula.  We have reaffirmed that regional and international peace, stability, and prosperity are our common interests and goals, and resolved also to step up our cooperation going further.</p>
<p>We are greatly concerned about violence and human rights infringement in Myanmar and to restore democracy and improve the human rights situation therein concurrent to work together with ASEAN and the international community.</p>
<p>On the situation in Ukraine as well, we shared our deep concern.  Through diplomacy and dialogue, Ukraine’s peace and stability should be re-established as early as possible, a position we reaffirmed.</p>
<p>Cooperation among Korea, the United States, and Japan ranges from ensuring stable global supply chains including for critical minerals and promoting other mutually beneficial, future-oriented, and practical cooperation to addressing global challenges such as economic and security cooperation, and its scope continues to expand.</p>
<p>We share democracy, human rights, market economy, and other core values as likeminded countries, and as such agree to continue to our cooperation for global peace and prosperity. Notably, to address COVID-19 and the immediate challenge facing the entire humanity, we’re actively and making endeavors in this regard and supporting U.S. initiative for the COVID-19 Global Action Plan.</p>
<p>Today, we reaffirmed importance and usefulness of trilateral cooperation among Korea, the U.S., and Japan.  As we move forward, we’ll be getting together often on various occasions, including multilateral meetings, to continue our strategic communication and coordination.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you very much.  I just concluded Japan-U.S.-ROK foreign ministers meeting with Secretary Blinken and Minister Chung.  We had a very fruitful discussion, and I would like to thank Secretary Blinken once again for the wonderful hospitality.</p>
<p>To begin with, regarding North Korea, we shared serious concerns over North Korea’s recent and repeated launches of ballistic missiles, including the latest launch of IRBM class ballistic missile on January 30th.  Based on the shared understanding that North Korea’s nuclear and missile activities pose a threat to the peace and stability of the region and the international community, we aligned our recognition on future measures.</p>
<p>Firstly, we concurred to further strengthen regional deterrence.  While the Japan-U.S. alliance as well as U.S.-ROK alliance each play an important role in this regard, we concurred on advancing security cooperation among Japan, U.S., and the ROK.</p>
<p>Second, we agreed on the importance of fully implementing United Nations Security Council resolutions and concurred to coordinate even more closely on future responses by the Security Council.</p>
<p>Thirdly, we shared the recognition that even in such a situation diplomatic efforts are important and we agreed to deepen the discussion among Japan, U.S., and ROK.  In this vein, Prime Minister Kishida had repeatedly expressed his determination to meet with Chairman Kim Jong-un face to face.</p>
<p>I also asked for continued understanding and cooperation from the two ministers on abductions issue, and to which they expressed their strong support.</p>
<p>We also had a candid discussion on the regional affairs with the recognition about the collaboration among Japan, U.S., and the ROK is of strategic importance beyond North Korean related issue.  In this context, I once again welcomed the Indo-Pacific strategy that the U.S. announced yesterday.  We also affirmed to expand cooperation and collaboration for the peace and stability of the region with our shared concern about activities that undermine the rules-based international order and concurred that we strongly oppose any unilateral actions that seek to alter the status quo and increase tensions in the region.  We are strongly opposed to unilateral action that seeks to alter status quo.</p>
<p>We also exchanged our views – furthermore, we also discussed global issues such as climate change and COVID-19 and other global health issues now pressing challenge for international community.  We concurred on the continued cooperation among Japan, U.S. and ROK in dealing with such challenges.</p>
<p>Lastly, we agreed to further enhance the collaboration among Japan, U.S., and ROK at multiple levels.  Based on today’s discussion as well as joint statement we issued, I would like to work even more closely with you as and ROK for the peace, stability, and prosperity of the region and the international community, including dealing with North Korea.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll now turn to questions.  We’ll take one question from each delegation.  The first question goes to Nike Ching of VOA.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Good afternoon, gentlemen.  Aloha.</p>
<p>For Secretary Blinken, would the United States consider bold steps toward North Korea, and are you concerned that the dispute between Japan and South Korea over island sovereignty and historical issues are getting in the way?  How close are the United, is the United States watching the presidential election in South Korea?</p>
<p>And for Foreign Minister Chung, for Foreign Minister Chung, do you have a assessment of North Korea leader Kim Jong-un’s health?  What do you think is the intention, and how do you evaluate recent missiles launches by North Korea?</p>
<p>And for Foreign Minister Hayashi, do you assess the result of the presidential election in South Korea may complicate a joint trilateral approach toward North Korea?</p>
<p>And separately, if I may, on Ukraine for both Foreign Minister Hayashi and Foreign Minister Chung, has the United States asked Japan to provide more LNG, liquified natural gas, to Europe, supplies to Europe?  And are Japan and South Korea worried over the economic disruptions of a war, and what assurances have you gotten?</p>
<p>(In Japanese and Korean.)  Thank you very much, gentlemen.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Nike, thank you for the excellent multipart, multiperson question.  (Laughter.)  You covered a lot of ground.  I’m happy to start and then hand it over to my colleagues.</p>
<p>I think it is clear to all of us that the DPRK is in a phase of provocation.  We condemned the recent missile launches, violations of UN Security Council resolutions.  We will continue to hold the DPRK accountable even as we seek to engage in diplomacy.  As you know, we imposed sanctions on eight DPRK-linked individuals and entities last month, and we are very closely consulting together on further steps.</p>
<p>At the same time, we remain prepared to meet without preconditions to pursue practical steps toward diplomacy.  The goal remains the same and it’s a shared goal.  It’s the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, and it is lasting peace.  We have no hostile intent toward North Korea.  And again, we unfortunately have seen their response to our making it clear that we’re prepared to pursue diplomacy with – unfortunately, that response has been a series now of provocative actions.</p>
<p>I think what’s important and that comes out of today, and this will be reflected in the joint statement that we’ll put out shortly, is that we are absolutely united in our approach, in our determination.  And that unity of purpose is, I think, vitally important for dealing with the challenge posed by the DPRK and also pursuing a more – a more hopeful future.  But I’ll – I invite you to take a look at the joint statement.</p>
<p>When it comes to elections and the like, happily, in my job I don’t do politics.  I don’t do them in my own country.  I don’t do them in other countries.  So I’ll leave it at that.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER CHUNG:</strong>  Thank you. (Via interpreter) Well, there was a question regarding the relations between Korea and Japan.  Although the question was not directed towards myself, regarding the Dokdo Island issue the Korean Government’s position is very clear, so I do not want to repeat that view myself.  But that does not have any impact whatsoever regarding our relations concerning the issue of the DPRK.  In the recent month, the DPRK’s test-firing of ballistic missiles is a conduct that is clearly wrong.  And regarding such launches we have – we are deeply concerned and we expressed regret, and we are strongly urging North Korea to not repeat such testing.</p>
<p>But as was just stated by Secretary Blinken, complete denuclearization and establishment of lasting peace on the Korean Peninsula, our commitment to that goal has never changed.  And for us to be able to achieve these shared goals, diplomacy and dialogue is a way to go for us.  Our commitment to that goal and approach is also unchanged.</p>
<p>Recently, the DPRK is making its own decisions and has been talking about the possibility of lifting its self-imposed moratorium on missile launches.  We are deeply concerned about that, and I strongly urged the DPRK not to put its words into action.</p>
<p>Concerning the situation in Ukraine, the developments have been going into the wrong direction.  And regarding the support of LNG to Europe, if there are any difficulties in that regard concerning the assistance of gas supply to Europe, we are taking that matter into account proactively.  I hope that through diplomacy and dialogue we hope to see the resolution of the situation in Ukraine as well.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you.  I had a frank exchange of views during the bilateral discussions and through the trilateral meeting.  Please refer to the announcement that will be shared later. The position of Takeshima is already known.</p>
<p>And about the special elections in South Korea – there was a question raised – that is a internal affair of a different country, so I will refer from answering the question.</p>
<p>And to supply of natural gas was requested from U.S. and Europe, and Japan has decided to supply the natural gas.  And recently we – there was appreciation expressed from American government as well.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Gyu Kim, JTBC.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you, Ned.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter)  First of all, I have a question to Minister Chung.  The three countries have been actually urging on North Korea to come to dialogue, but we have not been able to see any concrete measures, though.  In order to accelerate their involvement, have you discussed any realistic measures?  I think you said that in your statement.  So what are some concrete measures that you are going to propose to North Korea?  Could you give us more details?</p>
<p>I have a question to Secretary Blinken.  In relation to the Ukraine’s situations, for example, do you believe that ICBM can be launched by North Korea in line with the current situation that’s worsening in Ukraine?  Would you think that United States will be able to manage these two situations at the same time?</p>
<p>And also going beyond urging dialogue from North Korea, perhaps sending a personal letter from President Biden to North Korea?  There are some people who are saying that there should be high-level intervention.</p>
<p>And last, I have a question to Minister Hayashi.  You said that you understand the need to have a trilateral coordination between the three countries.  Perhaps the three leaders have to get together.  So in terms of the bilateral meeting between the Japan and Korea on this, and also there are some historical issues that are underway.</p>
<p><strong>INTERPRETER: </strong> I’m very sorry, but there are disruptions to the feedback – the sound feed that we’re getting from the speaker.  The interpretation booth was not able to get any sound from the microphone.  I believe that the last question by the journalist would have to be repeated again.  There were some technical issues.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  So three countries understand the importance of trilateral cooperation.  In order to emphasize and underscore that, we need to have a leader-level meeting at the highest level.  So for example, between the bilateral – the bilateral summit between Korea and Japan, and between the trilateral meetings.  So what is the commitment from Japan?</p>
<p>And also because of the historical issues, do you see a stalemate between the bilateral relations between Korea and Japan?  Of course, two countries would have to work harder.  Are there any specific efforts that are currently undertaken by the Japanese Government in order to improve relations with Korea?</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:</strong>  (Via interpreter) I believe the first question was posed to me, so let met me answer that question.  Yes, we actually discussed a lot of measures to deal with this issue, but we are unable to disclose that information at this point of time.  At an opportune time in the future, I believe that information will be disclosed to the public in due course.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I certainly don’t rule out that North Korea could engage in further provocative actions as things are happening in other parts of the world, including in Europe with regard to Ukraine.  In fact, as we’ve been dealing with the challenge posed by Russia’s threats of aggression against Ukraine, we’ve, of course, had a series of missile launches and tests by North Korea that we’ve responded to in solidarity with our allies and partners.</p>
<p>The bottom line is – and I think in a sense this week is a reasonable demonstration of that – we walk and chew gum at the same time.  Even as I’ve spent the week in the Indo-Pacific region – in Australia, in Fiji, now here in Hawaii, working with the Quad countries, working with our partners in the Pacific Islands, and of course, here today with our close allies and partners from Japan and Korea – I’ve also been engaged, we’ve also been engaged, in managing the challenge that Russia is currently posing to security in Europe and Ukraine.</p>
<p>And in a sense, these things are also inherently linked, because whether it is provocative actions undertaken by the DPRK, Russian aggression toward Ukraine, other actions in this region by large countries that seek to undermine the rules-based order that we have established together, these are – these are of a piece.  And the common denominator is when basic principles that we’ve established together that are vital to the security and the prosperity of people in all of our countries are being challenged, we stand up together to defend them.</p>
<p>Our three countries – and again, I think this will come out in the joint statement – we have a profoundly affirmative vision for what we want to do together for the future, for the citizens of our countries and for people around the world.  But we’re also committed together as allies and partners to stand up and defend the rules-based order and to act together in solidarity when the principles of that order are being challenged, wherever that challenge is taking place, whether it’s in Europe or here in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p>And that’s, again, I think a hallmark and the reason why the United States over many years has established these partnerships, these alliances, bringing countries together in common cause and common purpose.  That enables us very effectively to deal with multiple challenges at the same time.  And again, beyond that I think there’s a common denominator to all of them, which is why, as you’ve heard from my colleagues today, there is tremendous solidarity not only when it comes to dealing with challenges immediately in the Indo-Pacific but when it comes to dealing with the threat of Russian aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN  MINISTER CHUNG:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you very much.  Cooperation between U.S. and South Korea is essential for the peace and stability in this region.  (Inaudible) North Korea, we discussed about the recent situation, including China and Ukraine, and we had a very good exchange of views.  So going forward for the peace and stability for the region, cooperation between the three countries should be further developed.</p>
<p><strong>INTERPRETER:</strong>  Yes, one correction from Japanese-to-English interpreter.  When Minister Hayashi made initial statement, the interpreter skipped one paragraph, which reads as follows:</p>
<p>We also exchanged our views on Ukraine while sharing views about tensions are escalating.  We confirmed our unwavering support for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine and concurred to continued close coordination.  Apology from interpreter.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you.  Our final question will come from Yuichi Nobira from Asahi Shimbun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Nobira from Asahi Shimbun.  I have a question to the three ministers.  Although regional stability cooperation between the three countries is important, but currently China is enhancing its advancement into the sea.  And both Japan, the U.S., at the defense ministerial meeting in January and sort of online meeting, they confirmed the strengthening of the alliance.  Between Japan, U.S. and ROK, do you plan to take common measure with agreement with respect to the approaches to China?  How do you think such approaches would be important?  I have question to all of you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I would again invite you to look at the joint statement that we will issue shortly after this meeting comes to an end.  We discussed and I think the statement reflects the shared concern that we have about activities that undermine the rules-based international order, as we were just discussing.  We reaffirmed the desire that we share for a peaceful and stable region that would allow all countries to reach their full potential free from coercion.  We strongly oppose any unilateral actions that seek to alter the status quo and increase tensions in the region.  And we reiterated our very strong support, longstanding support, for international law, highlighting in particular the importance of compliance with international law as reflected in the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Seas.</p>
<p>So I think you’ll see that in the joint statement.  We also emphasized the importance of peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait.  So I invite you to look at the statement when we put it out shortly.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER CHUNG:</strong>  (In Korean) (Via interpreter)  Thank you.  As far as we’re concerned in this Northeast Asian region, based on order –</p>
<p><strong>INTERPRETER:</strong> My apologies, the audio feed is cut off.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER CHUNG:</strong> (Via interpreter) We have reached a full agreement on that aspect.  Maintaining peace and stability in the region is extremely important, and any conduct that goes against maintaining the status quo is something that we opposed.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:</strong> (In Japanese) (Via interpreter)  So as a solution that both ministers of the three countries must expand, it’s cooperation that was confirmed and the activities that are damaging to international cooperation, which is made in rule or attempts to change the status quo and other actions of trying to enhance tension, is something we agree to strongly oppose such action.</p>
<p>As I have mentioned, cooperation between U.S., ROK, and Japan (inaudible) measures against North Korea, but these are essential for peace and stability of the whole region.  So in addition to responses of North Korea, we had a frank exchange of views of the recent situation, including the situation of China and Ukraine.  So we want to further develop the cooperation between our three countries for the peace and stability of the region.</p>
<p>Based on the rules – I misspoke on my – let me make my apologies.  The order, based on rules, the rules-based order.  International order is something that we value.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  That concludes the press conference.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, everyone.  I invite you to go outside and enjoy the day. <input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the U.S.-Japan-Republic of Korea Trilateral Ministerial Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-the-u-s-japan-republic-of-korea-trilateral-ministerial-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 04:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313889</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is the joint statement released by the Secretary of State of the United States and the Foreign Ministers of the Governments of Japan, and the Republic of Korea.</p>
<p><i>Begin Text</i></p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken, Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Yoshimasa and Republic of Korea (ROK) Minister of Foreign Affairs Chung Eui-yong met today in Honolulu, Hawaii, to reaffirm the critical importance of strong U.S.-Japan-ROK trilateral cooperation as we seek to address the most pressing 21st Century challenges.  The U.S. alliances with the ROK and Japan span decades, and our enduring friendship and shared values guide us in our efforts to achieve a prosperous and secure future.</p>
<p>The 21st Century has brought not only new and unprecedented challenges but also tremendous opportunities for our three countries to work together.  Underscoring the importance of trilateral cooperation as we navigate an increasingly complicated world, the Secretary and Foreign Ministers committed to expand cooperation and collaboration across a range of regional and global security and economic priorities.</p>
<p>The Secretary and Foreign Ministers emphasized their three countries share a common view of a free and open Indo-Pacific, which is inclusive, and shared respect for the rules-based international order and pledged to further expand their cooperative relationships.  The Foreign Ministers welcomed the United States’ newly released Indo-Pacific Strategy.</p>
<p>The Secretary and Foreign Ministers condemned the DPRK’s recent ballistic missile launches and expressed deep concern about the destabilizing nature of these actions.  They committed to close trilateral cooperation to achieve complete denuclearization and lasting peace on the Korean Peninsula.  They called for full implementation by the international community of relevant UN Security Council resolutions relating to the DPRK and called on the DPRK to cease its unlawful activities and instead engage in dialogue.  The Secretary and Foreign Ministers emphasized they held no hostile intent towards the DPRK and underscored continued openness to meeting the DPRK without preconditions.  The Secretary and Foreign Ministers reaffirmed that the U.S.-Japan and U.S.-ROK alliances are essential to the maintenance of peace and stability in the region.  In this context, they committed to advance trilateral security cooperation.  They commended the frequent trilateral discussions between the respective Special Representatives for the DPRK.  The Secretary and Foreign Ministers discussed the importance of reuniting separated Korean families, and the swift resolution of the abductions issue.</p>
<p>The Secretary and Foreign Ministers discussed the Russian military build-up along Ukraine’s borders and shared unwavering support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. They committed to work closely together to deter further Russian escalation.</p>
<p>Noting their shared concern about activities that undermine the rules-based international order, the Secretary and Foreign Ministers reaffirmed their desire for a peaceful and stable region that would allow all countries to reach their potential. They expressed strong opposition to any unilateral actions that seek to alter the status quo and increase tensions in the region. The Secretary and Foreign Ministers reiterated their governments’ longstanding support for international law, highlighting in particular the importance of compliance with international law as reflected in the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea. They emphasized the importance of peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait. The Secretary and Foreign Ministers reaffirmed support for the unity and centrality of ASEAN, which is currently chaired by Cambodia, as well as ASEAN’s efforts to resolve the crisis in Myanmar.  They also condemned the Myanmar regime’s violence committed against the people of Myanmar and committed to intensify efforts toward the immediate cessation of all violence, the release of those who are arbitrarily detained, and a swift return to the path of inclusive democracy.</p>
<p>The Secretary and Foreign Ministers emphasized the importance of trilateral cooperation to strengthen the rules-based economic order and ensure prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region and the world.  They discussed common approaches to address priorities including the climate crisis; critical supply chains; gender equality and empowerment; development finance; and global health security including efforts to end the COVID-19 pandemic and prevent the next.  They highlighted the importance of collaboration to strengthen information and cyber security, and also to improve economic security, including by promoting innovation of critical and emerging technologies based on democratic values and respect for universal human rights.</p>
<p>Reaffirming their commitment to U.S.-ROK-Japan trilateral cooperation that is grounded in our shared values and desire for regional peace, stability, and prosperity, the Secretary and Foreign Ministers pledged to continue regular trilateral ministerial consultations.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is the joint statement released by the Secretary of State of the United States and the Foreign Ministers of the Governments of Japan, and the Republic of Korea.</p>
<p><i>Begin Text</i></p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken, Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Yoshimasa and Republic of Korea (ROK) Minister of Foreign Affairs Chung Eui-yong met today in Honolulu, Hawaii, to reaffirm the critical importance of strong U.S.-Japan-ROK trilateral cooperation as we seek to address the most pressing 21st Century challenges.  The U.S. alliances with the ROK and Japan span decades, and our enduring friendship and shared values guide us in our efforts to achieve a prosperous and secure future.</p>
<p>The 21st Century has brought not only new and unprecedented challenges but also tremendous opportunities for our three countries to work together.  Underscoring the importance of trilateral cooperation as we navigate an increasingly complicated world, the Secretary and Foreign Ministers committed to expand cooperation and collaboration across a range of regional and global security and economic priorities.</p>
<p>The Secretary and Foreign Ministers emphasized their three countries share a common view of a free and open Indo-Pacific, which is inclusive, and shared respect for the rules-based international order and pledged to further expand their cooperative relationships.  The Foreign Ministers welcomed the United States’ newly released Indo-Pacific Strategy.</p>
<p>The Secretary and Foreign Ministers condemned the DPRK’s recent ballistic missile launches and expressed deep concern about the destabilizing nature of these actions.  They committed to close trilateral cooperation to achieve complete denuclearization and lasting peace on the Korean Peninsula.  They called for full implementation by the international community of relevant UN Security Council resolutions relating to the DPRK and called on the DPRK to cease its unlawful activities and instead engage in dialogue.  The Secretary and Foreign Ministers emphasized they held no hostile intent towards the DPRK and underscored continued openness to meeting the DPRK without preconditions.  The Secretary and Foreign Ministers reaffirmed that the U.S.-Japan and U.S.-ROK alliances are essential to the maintenance of peace and stability in the region.  In this context, they committed to advance trilateral security cooperation.  They commended the frequent trilateral discussions between the respective Special Representatives for the DPRK.  The Secretary and Foreign Ministers discussed the importance of reuniting separated Korean families, and the swift resolution of the abductions issue.</p>
<p>The Secretary and Foreign Ministers discussed the Russian military build-up along Ukraine’s borders and shared unwavering support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. They committed to work closely together to deter further Russian escalation.</p>
<p>Noting their shared concern about activities that undermine the rules-based international order, the Secretary and Foreign Ministers reaffirmed their desire for a peaceful and stable region that would allow all countries to reach their potential. They expressed strong opposition to any unilateral actions that seek to alter the status quo and increase tensions in the region. The Secretary and Foreign Ministers reiterated their governments’ longstanding support for international law, highlighting in particular the importance of compliance with international law as reflected in the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea. They emphasized the importance of peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait. The Secretary and Foreign Ministers reaffirmed support for the unity and centrality of ASEAN, which is currently chaired by Cambodia, as well as ASEAN’s efforts to resolve the crisis in Myanmar.  They also condemned the Myanmar regime’s violence committed against the people of Myanmar and committed to intensify efforts toward the immediate cessation of all violence, the release of those who are arbitrarily detained, and a swift return to the path of inclusive democracy.</p>
<p>The Secretary and Foreign Ministers emphasized the importance of trilateral cooperation to strengthen the rules-based economic order and ensure prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region and the world.  They discussed common approaches to address priorities including the climate crisis; critical supply chains; gender equality and empowerment; development finance; and global health security including efforts to end the COVID-19 pandemic and prevent the next.  They highlighted the importance of collaboration to strengthen information and cyber security, and also to improve economic security, including by promoting innovation of critical and emerging technologies based on democratic values and respect for universal human rights.</p>
<p>Reaffirming their commitment to U.S.-ROK-Japan trilateral cooperation that is grounded in our shared values and desire for regional peace, stability, and prosperity, the Secretary and Foreign Ministers pledged to continue regular trilateral ministerial consultations.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Republic of Korea Foreign Minister Chung</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-republic-of-korea-foreign-minister-chung-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 03:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313875</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Republic of Korea (ROK) Foreign Minister Chung Eui-yong in Honolulu. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Chung reaffirmed the importance of the U.S.-ROK Alliance in tackling today’s most pressing global challenges and ensuring a peaceful, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region. They highlighted our shared commitment to combatting the COVID-19 pandemic, including through the KORUS Global Vaccine Partnership. They also affirmed bilateral cooperation in this decisive decade for action to combat the climate crisis.</p>
<p>The Secretary and Foreign Minister condemned the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea’s (DPRK) recent ballistic missile launches, which were in violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions, and reaffirmed openness to diplomacy and dialogue with the DPRK. The Secretary also emphasized close cooperation with the Republic of Korea and other allies and partners towards the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. Secretary Blinken reaffirmed the ironclad U.S. commitment to the defense of the ROK. The Secretary and the Foreign Minister discussed the need to deepen trilateral cooperation with Japan as we work together to address our shared challenges. On Burma, the Secretary stressed the importance of working with international partners to address human rights abuses and press the regime to cease the violence, release all those unjustly detained, allow unhindered humanitarian access, and restore Burma’s path to democracy. Secretary Blinken also shared concerns about Russia’s efforts to destabilize Ukraine and emphasized the importance of responding swiftly, effectively, and in a united way to further Russian aggression.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Republic of Korea (ROK) Foreign Minister Chung Eui-yong in Honolulu. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Chung reaffirmed the importance of the U.S.-ROK Alliance in tackling today’s most pressing global challenges and ensuring a peaceful, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region. They highlighted our shared commitment to combatting the COVID-19 pandemic, including through the KORUS Global Vaccine Partnership. They also affirmed bilateral cooperation in this decisive decade for action to combat the climate crisis.</p>
<p>The Secretary and Foreign Minister condemned the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea’s (DPRK) recent ballistic missile launches, which were in violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions, and reaffirmed openness to diplomacy and dialogue with the DPRK. The Secretary also emphasized close cooperation with the Republic of Korea and other allies and partners towards the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. Secretary Blinken reaffirmed the ironclad U.S. commitment to the defense of the ROK. The Secretary and the Foreign Minister discussed the need to deepen trilateral cooperation with Japan as we work together to address our shared challenges. On Burma, the Secretary stressed the importance of working with international partners to address human rights abuses and press the regime to cease the violence, release all those unjustly detained, allow unhindered humanitarian access, and restore Burma’s path to democracy. Secretary Blinken also shared concerns about Russia’s efforts to destabilize Ukraine and emphasized the importance of responding swiftly, effectively, and in a united way to further Russian aggression.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Republic of Korea Foreign Minister Chung Eui-yong Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-republic-of-korea-foreign-minister-chung-eui-yong-before-their-meeting-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 02:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313855</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Honolulu, Hawaii</p>
<p>Asia-Pacific Center for Security Studies</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a real pleasure to have this opportunity to be with our friends and partners.  Eui-yong and I have been working very closely together for many months now and – just a testament to the absolute vitality of the relationship, the partnership between the United States and the Republic of Korea.  I’d like to say one of the hallmarks is the fact that we have what is truly a global partnership.  Of course, we work on bilateral issues, we’re working on regional issues together, but we&#8217;re also working on global issues – everything from COVID to climate.  So we have a lot to talk about.  I was very much looking forward to this opportunity to compare notes with you, and then we’ll be spending time with our colleague from Japan in our trilateral.  But thank you for being here and I look forward to good conversation.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER CHUNG:  </b>Well, thank you, Tony, for inviting (inaudible) my delegation to Hawaii.  It’s a real treat for us to be here.  Well, first of all, I thank you for your concern and interest in the safety of Koreans living in the United States.  We do appreciate your effort to provide safety for all (inaudible).  And I also thank you and welcome (inaudible) to such a seasoned diplomat like Mr. Philip Goldberg as new U.S. ambassador to Korea.  We are very much looking forward to closely working with the new ambassador, and I hope he’ll be installed soon.  And I will also say that we hope to continue our consultations on how to further strengthen our bilateral relationship, not only to (inaudible), but also promote our global partnership.  We have a lot to cover.  And we are very concerned about the – all of the situation of the Korean Peninsula in particular, and I hope we can also have – with exchange of views in how to deal with the situation.</p>
<p>And I&#8217;m also very happy to have a trilat meeting (inaudible) in the region.  I had a good meeting with Minister Hayashi (inaudible).  Although we have differences – and it&#8217;s not easy for us to get over with all these differences – but we agreed to continue our close diplomatic consultation.  And I think that is a very positive (inaudible), and I&#8217;m very much looking forward to having this close trilateral cooperation amongst three of us.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Honolulu, Hawaii</p>
<p>Asia-Pacific Center for Security Studies</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a real pleasure to have this opportunity to be with our friends and partners.  Eui-yong and I have been working very closely together for many months now and – just a testament to the absolute vitality of the relationship, the partnership between the United States and the Republic of Korea.  I’d like to say one of the hallmarks is the fact that we have what is truly a global partnership.  Of course, we work on bilateral issues, we’re working on regional issues together, but we&#8217;re also working on global issues – everything from COVID to climate.  So we have a lot to talk about.  I was very much looking forward to this opportunity to compare notes with you, and then we’ll be spending time with our colleague from Japan in our trilateral.  But thank you for being here and I look forward to good conversation.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER CHUNG:  </b>Well, thank you, Tony, for inviting (inaudible) my delegation to Hawaii.  It’s a real treat for us to be here.  Well, first of all, I thank you for your concern and interest in the safety of Koreans living in the United States.  We do appreciate your effort to provide safety for all (inaudible).  And I also thank you and welcome (inaudible) to such a seasoned diplomat like Mr. Philip Goldberg as new U.S. ambassador to Korea.  We are very much looking forward to closely working with the new ambassador, and I hope he’ll be installed soon.  And I will also say that we hope to continue our consultations on how to further strengthen our bilateral relationship, not only to (inaudible), but also promote our global partnership.  We have a lot to cover.  And we are very concerned about the – all of the situation of the Korean Peninsula in particular, and I hope we can also have – with exchange of views in how to deal with the situation.</p>
<p>And I&#8217;m also very happy to have a trilat meeting (inaudible) in the region.  I had a good meeting with Minister Hayashi (inaudible).  Although we have differences – and it&#8217;s not easy for us to get over with all these differences – but we agreed to continue our close diplomatic consultation.  And I think that is a very positive (inaudible), and I&#8217;m very much looking forward to having this close trilateral cooperation amongst three of us.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Assistant Secretary Akunna Cook Leads State Department Prosper Africa Economic Diplomacy Delegation to Africa</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-assistant-secretary-akunna-cook-leads-state-department-prosper-africa-economic-diplomacy-delegation-to-africa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 20:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313832</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Assistant Secretary of State Akunna Cook and Prosper Africa Acting Chief Operating Officer Leslie Marbury will travel to Nigeria, Kenya, South Africa, and Namibia on a State Department Prosper Africa economic diplomacy visit, February 14 &#8211; March 1. The delegation will meet with entrepreneurs, women-owned and small and medium-sized enterprises, investors, and policy-makers to drive U.S. trade and investment in Africa’s creative industries, ICT and digital technologies, and energy and infrastructure, among other fast-growing sectors.</p>
<p>Last November, Secretary Antony Blinken traveled to the continent signaling the United States’ commitment to strengthen economic, social, and political ties with our partners in Africa. The delegation will advance this commitment by connecting businesses and investors with Prosper Africa tools and resources to remove trade and investment barriers, drive transactions forward, and promote market opportunities.</p>
<p>This is the first in a series of economic diplomacy visits the State Department will undertake to advance U.S. trade and investment with Africa as part of the whole-of-government Prosper Africa initiative. By working hand-in-hand with the private sector and our African partners, the U.S. government is driving investment in African innovation, opportunity, and creative solutions to the world’s most pressing problems.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Assistant Secretary of State Akunna Cook and Prosper Africa Acting Chief Operating Officer Leslie Marbury will travel to Nigeria, Kenya, South Africa, and Namibia on a State Department Prosper Africa economic diplomacy visit, February 14 &#8211; March 1. The delegation will meet with entrepreneurs, women-owned and small and medium-sized enterprises, investors, and policy-makers to drive U.S. trade and investment in Africa’s creative industries, ICT and digital technologies, and energy and infrastructure, among other fast-growing sectors.</p>
<p>Last November, Secretary Antony Blinken traveled to the continent signaling the United States’ commitment to strengthen economic, social, and political ties with our partners in Africa. The delegation will advance this commitment by connecting businesses and investors with Prosper Africa tools and resources to remove trade and investment barriers, drive transactions forward, and promote market opportunities.</p>
<p>This is the first in a series of economic diplomacy visits the State Department will undertake to advance U.S. trade and investment with Africa as part of the whole-of-government Prosper Africa initiative. By working hand-in-hand with the private sector and our African partners, the U.S. government is driving investment in African innovation, opportunity, and creative solutions to the world’s most pressing problems.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with UK Foreign Secretary Truss</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-uk-foreign-secretary-truss-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 16:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313810</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss today about acute and shared concerns that Russia may be considering launching further military aggression against Ukraine in the coming days. Secretary Blinken emphasized the importance of working with our NATO Allies and European partners in the region to impose swift, severe costs on Russia in response to any further military aggression by Russia against Ukraine. They also discussed that international efforts should continue to seek a meaningful dialogue with Russia on mutual security concerns that could lead to a diplomatic resolution. Secretary Blinken reaffirmed that any decision the United States makes in Europe will be in consultation with our Allies and partners. The two also discussed UK-EU negotiations over the implementation of the Northern Ireland Protocol and preserving the gains of the Belfast/Good Friday agreement, as well the importance of reaching a successful conclusion on talks with Iran on mutual return to full implementation of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss today about acute and shared concerns that Russia may be considering launching further military aggression against Ukraine in the coming days. Secretary Blinken emphasized the importance of working with our NATO Allies and European partners in the region to impose swift, severe costs on Russia in response to any further military aggression by Russia against Ukraine. They also discussed that international efforts should continue to seek a meaningful dialogue with Russia on mutual security concerns that could lead to a diplomatic resolution. Secretary Blinken reaffirmed that any decision the United States makes in Europe will be in consultation with our Allies and partners. The two also discussed UK-EU negotiations over the implementation of the Northern Ireland Protocol and preserving the gains of the Belfast/Good Friday agreement, as well the importance of reaching a successful conclusion on talks with Iran on mutual return to full implementation of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
