<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 20:34:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; July 23, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-july-23-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 20:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=261735</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:05 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hello and Happy Friday, everyone. Thank you so much for joining today’s department press briefing. I have three updates at the top before I start taking your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-SouthKorea"></a> To start, Deputy Secretary Sherman continued her travel to Asia today with a second day in Seoul, meeting with Republic of Korea First Vice Minister Choi – or, excuse me, First Vice Foreign Minister Choi. Vice Foreign Minister Choi.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Vice Foreign Minister Choi emphasized the importance of the U.S.-ROK Alliance promoting peace, security, and prosperity in Northeast Asia, the Indo-Pacific region, and around the world.</p>
<p>The Deputy Secretary and the Vice Foreign Minister discussed bilateral and multilateral cooperation to achieve the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, address the climate crisis, provide pandemic relief, and promote post-COVID-19 economic recovery.</p>
<p>They also reaffirmed the importance of the U.S.-ROK-Japan trilateral cooperation to address the global challenges of the 21st century following their trilateral meeting in Tokyo earlier this week.</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-Vaccines"></a> Moving on to some vaccine shipment updates. The Biden administration is making good on its promise to be an arsenal of vaccines to the world.</p>
<p>We shipped a record number of doses to a record number of countries this week, 22 million doses to 23 countries, including: Guatemala, Senegal, Zambia, Niger, Gambia, El Salvador, Honduras, the Central African Republic, Cameroon, Panama, Vietnam, Georgia, Pakistan, Tanzania, Mozambique, Benin, Morocco, Tajikistan, Colombia, Madagascar, Liberia, and Eswatini.</p>
<p>Every day, driven by the singular goal of saving lives, we continue to make progress on the global vaccination effort.</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-Afghanistan"></a> And finally, while the Taliban have stated they will not harm former interpreters or others who worked for foreign forces, recent reports of violence and atrocities against interpreters and other Afghans indicate local Taliban forces are showing little regard for human life and human rights on the ground.</p>
<p>We vehemently condemn these targeted attacks, the destruction of vital infrastructure, as well as other attacks against the people of Afghanistan.</p>
<p>The Taliban must go beyond issuing statements denying territorial offensives and targeted attacks. If this is truly not Taliban policy, their leadership should condemn these atrocities and violations of basic rights. They must proactively prevent their forces from carrying out these actions on the ground.</p>
<p>We continue to call for an immediate end to ongoing violence, which is largely driven by the Taliban. We call on the Taliban to engage in serious negotiations to determine a political roadmap for Afghanistan’s future that leads to a just and durable settlement. A negotiated settlement between the Islamic Republic and the Taliban is the only way to end 40 years of war,and bring Afghans the peace that they seek and deserve.</p>
<p>The world will not accept the imposition by force of a government in Afghanistan. Legitimacy and assistance for any Afghan government can only be possible if that government has a basic right – basic respect, excuse me, for human rights.</p>
<p>We continue to do all we can to galvanize and support the diplomatic process toward peace. Together, with the international community, we urge all parties to reach a negotiated political settlement and a permanent and comprehensive ceasefire.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Eunjung Cho, VOA.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. Your line is now open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi Jalina, thank you. I want to ask you about North Korea. Human Rights Watch says at least 1,170 North Koreans are currently detained in China and are facing forced repatriation to North Korea. The group says North Korea recently reopened its borders, increasing the risk of forced repatriation. What is the State Department’s stance on China forcefully returning North Korean refugees back to North Korea?</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-NorthKorea"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you for your question. Well, at large, I can say that the United States is certainly committed to placing human rights at the center of our foreign policy, and that’s something you’ve heard President Biden say in the past as well as Secretary Blinken. And of course, this would include in the DPRK.</p>
<p>We’ll also continue to prioritize human rights in our overall approach when it comes to the DPRK. Even when we disagree with a regime like the DPRK, we must work to the best of our ability to alleviate the suffering of its people, and we strive to act in a manner that does not harm the North Korean people and continue to support international efforts aimed at the provision of critical humanitarian aid in the hope that the DPRK will accept it.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Pearl Matibe.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Happy Friday, Jalina. Thank you so much. My question is regarding Zimbabwe. Now I know that in recent past, the relations between the United States and Zimbabwe have always kind of toppled, gone back and forth, and may not have been the best of relations in recent past.</p>
<p>So, the president’s spokesperson has kind of made some outrageous remarks regarding the vaccines that are going out to Africa. And although the embassy has kind of hit back a little bit about those remarks, what I’m wondering is: Are there any steps between both yourselves and the Government of Zimbabwe that you might be taking to better the relationship between the two countries? I’m really interested to find out what is it that can be done. Or are any – are there any maybe backchannel things that you might be doing or anything that you can share at this point as to where you would like to see this relationship, and is there any hope that this relationship will get better? Thanks, Jalina.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you for your question, Pearl. While I don’t have anything specific for <a id="post-261735-AFRICA"></a>you on Zimbabwe today, I’d just like to reiterate that Africa is certainly a priority for the Biden administration, and we certainly intend to engage with African countries in pursuing our shared interests and values. And of course, that would include global health and climate change, freedom and democracy, as well as shared prosperity.</p>
<p>We’ll also continue to reinvigorate and restore our partnerships all along the continent as well as build partnerships with African governments and institutions as well as civil society.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Laura Kelly, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. There’s some breaking news from <a id="post-261735-Haiti"></a>NBC and Reuters that U.S. Ambassador to the UN Linda Thomas-Greenfield has left Haiti after gunshots were heard at the funeral for assassinated President Jovenel Moise. I wonder if you can comment on that. And then if I may just ask a second question.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>All right. Well, to your first question, we definitely can – we’re aware of reports that there was gunfire outside of the funeral of President Moise, and the presidential delegation that was there is safe and accounted for and, of course, en route back to the United States. And of course, the United States is deeply concerned about the unrest in Haiti. And of course, in this critical moment, Haiti’s leaders must come together to chart a united path that reflects the will of the Haitian people.</p>
<p>While we still have you, we’ll take your second question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you so much. I appreciate it. House Democrats are calling for the State Department to establish a special envoy for monitoring and combating Islamophobia and to include anti-Muslim violence per se in next year’s annual human rights reports. Can you offer any reaction to this?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>So, I don’t have any personnel announcements to make at this time, but I’m certainly happy to do so whenever we have that ability. Thank you.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Guita Aryan.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. My question is about Iran and the ongoing demonstrations in the south protesting the lack of water. Michelle Bachelet, the Human Rights – High Commissioner for Human Rights, has had harsh words for the Government of Iran, saying that they should tend to the people’s demands instead of using excessive force, and arresting people and crushing the protests.</p>
<p>I was wondering whether the United States also agrees that the Iranian Government’s reaction has been harsh. And how can the United States and the international community intervene here and have the government in Iran listen and tend to the people’s demands? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-Iran"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks for your question. So, we’re certainly following, closely following, the reports on protests in Iran’s Khuzestan’s province, including reports that security forces have opened fire on protesters, which sadly has resulted in multiple deaths. Of course, years of government neglect and a mismanagement of water resources have exacerbated the worst drought Iran has faced in at least 50 years.</p>
<p>The Iranian people have a right to freely voice their frustrations and hold their government accountable. And plainly, we support the rights of Iranians. We support their rights to peacefully assemble, as well as their rights to express themselves freely. And they should be able to do so without fear of violence or arbitrary detention by security forces.</p>
<p>We’re also monitoring reports of government-imposed internet shutdowns in the region, and we urge the Iranian Government to allow its citizens to exercise their universal rights of freedom of expression, as well as freely access internet – excuse me, freely access information online.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Simon Lewis.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thank you, Jalina. I wanted to follow up on the statement that you guys put out that said the Secretary spoke to Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer about the case of American journalist Danny Fenster, who’s jailed in Myanmar. It’s been two months, maybe three months since Danny was detained and he’s being held in Insein Prison, where we understand COVID is rampaging through the population, as it is elsewhere among the population in Myanmar. And it seems, from what he’s said to his family, it sounds like he might be infected himself. I wondered if you could give us an update on what the U.S. officials have been able to learn about Danny’s situation, from consular access or what consular access you have, and what U.S. is doing to try to get him released. And, also, if you have an update on what the administration’s doing towards Myanmar given the broader COVID outbreak there. Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-Burma"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Simon. Of course, we remain deeply concerned over the continued detention of Danny Fenster, who of course was working as a journalist in Burma. As far as any updates, Daniel had a virtual hearing on July 15th, which was procedural, and his next hearing is scheduled for July 28th. We’re closely monitoring the progression of Daniel’s case, and we’ll always call for free and independent media as indispensable to building prosperous, resilient, and free societies.</p>
<p>When it comes to the situation – the COVID situation in Burma, of course we’re still deeply troubled by the deteriorating public health situation in Burma, and of course the recent strike – spike in COVID-19 infections. The United States has provided over $20 million in COVID‑related assistance to Burma since the pandemic began, which has helped people protect themselves from infections as well as detecting and clinical care. Since the military coup, regrettably the COVID situation has sharply deteriorated, and we continue to work with international partners to identify ways to effectively respond to the current public health crisis as well as continue to support the people of Burma.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Nadia Bilbassy.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for doing this, and happy Friday. We’re following the Iraq strategic dialogue. Can you tell us if we expect a final communique? If they’re breaking into groups, what are these groups, and high representation on each? And, also, as you know, the security and military cooperation is part of it. Do we expect anything indicating the withdrawal or redeployment of U.S. troops in Iraq? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Nadia, if we have you on the line, can you repeat your last question, please? It was hard to (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> One moment for that. Nadia, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, great. I’m sorry about this. Thank you for doing this. My question was about the Iraq strategic dialogue, and whether to expect a final communique. And if you just put us – give us some information about the meeting today, what kind of groups they were breaking into. And as you know, security and military cooperation was discussed. Do we expect anything indicating talking about withdrawal of troops or deployment of U.S. troops in Iraq? Thank you so much.</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-Iraq"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So, we did issue a note that’s available on our website at the start of the strategic dialogue, and I suspect we’ll have more to read out about that, the details as well. Thank you.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jenny Hansler, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong>Thank you. Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi, Jalina, thanks for doing this. I wanted to follow up on Simon’s question about Danny Fenster. Are you able to say when he was last – or when the embassy was last given consular access to him and whether they’ve been able to confirm whether he has or had COVID‑19? And then separately on Afghanistan, we’re hearing reports among these interpreters that some of them have been disqualified from the SIV process because they failed polygraph tests. They feel that the tests were not fair – were not given out properly. Is the State Department considering changing this policy on polygraphs? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-Burma2"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Jenny. We’re going to have to take that last question back to – back for you. On your question on Danny, I’ll just reiterate that he had a virtual hearing on the 15th which was procedural and that’s when our consular had access to him. And, of course, his next one is on the 28th. As far as his health, the status of his health, I’m not able to share distinct details at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s take one final question from Barbara Usher.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong>Thank you. Your line is open. Barbara, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You can hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. Great. Yeah, could you please clarify a few points about the funeral in Haiti. Did the U.S. delegation leave early because of the security concerns, the gunshots that you mentioned? And you also said the delegation was on its way back to the U.S. Did it cut short the trip for Haiti or was that part of the plan?</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-Haiti2"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you, Barbara. So, I’ll just reiterate the same points I made earlier, and is that the presidential delegation that went – they’re all safe and they’re accounted for, and they’re back to the United States. As far as any details on the entirety of their trip, I don’t have anything to preview at this time. But – and that’s all we’ll share on that today unless you have any follow-on questions.</p>
<p>All right. That concludes today’s department press briefing. Thank you so much for joining, and have a great rest of your weekend.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:26 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:05 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hello and Happy Friday, everyone. Thank you so much for joining today’s department press briefing. I have three updates at the top before I start taking your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-SouthKorea"></a> To start, Deputy Secretary Sherman continued her travel to Asia today with a second day in Seoul, meeting with Republic of Korea First Vice Minister Choi – or, excuse me, First Vice Foreign Minister Choi. Vice Foreign Minister Choi.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman and Vice Foreign Minister Choi emphasized the importance of the U.S.-ROK Alliance promoting peace, security, and prosperity in Northeast Asia, the Indo-Pacific region, and around the world.</p>
<p>The Deputy Secretary and the Vice Foreign Minister discussed bilateral and multilateral cooperation to achieve the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, address the climate crisis, provide pandemic relief, and promote post-COVID-19 economic recovery.</p>
<p>They also reaffirmed the importance of the U.S.-ROK-Japan trilateral cooperation to address the global challenges of the 21st century following their trilateral meeting in Tokyo earlier this week.</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-Vaccines"></a> Moving on to some vaccine shipment updates. The Biden administration is making good on its promise to be an arsenal of vaccines to the world.</p>
<p>We shipped a record number of doses to a record number of countries this week, 22 million doses to 23 countries, including: Guatemala, Senegal, Zambia, Niger, Gambia, El Salvador, Honduras, the Central African Republic, Cameroon, Panama, Vietnam, Georgia, Pakistan, Tanzania, Mozambique, Benin, Morocco, Tajikistan, Colombia, Madagascar, Liberia, and Eswatini.</p>
<p>Every day, driven by the singular goal of saving lives, we continue to make progress on the global vaccination effort.</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-Afghanistan"></a> And finally, while the Taliban have stated they will not harm former interpreters or others who worked for foreign forces, recent reports of violence and atrocities against interpreters and other Afghans indicate local Taliban forces are showing little regard for human life and human rights on the ground.</p>
<p>We vehemently condemn these targeted attacks, the destruction of vital infrastructure, as well as other attacks against the people of Afghanistan.</p>
<p>The Taliban must go beyond issuing statements denying territorial offensives and targeted attacks. If this is truly not Taliban policy, their leadership should condemn these atrocities and violations of basic rights. They must proactively prevent their forces from carrying out these actions on the ground.</p>
<p>We continue to call for an immediate end to ongoing violence, which is largely driven by the Taliban. We call on the Taliban to engage in serious negotiations to determine a political roadmap for Afghanistan’s future that leads to a just and durable settlement. A negotiated settlement between the Islamic Republic and the Taliban is the only way to end 40 years of war,and bring Afghans the peace that they seek and deserve.</p>
<p>The world will not accept the imposition by force of a government in Afghanistan. Legitimacy and assistance for any Afghan government can only be possible if that government has a basic right – basic respect, excuse me, for human rights.</p>
<p>We continue to do all we can to galvanize and support the diplomatic process toward peace. Together, with the international community, we urge all parties to reach a negotiated political settlement and a permanent and comprehensive ceasefire.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Eunjung Cho, VOA.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. Your line is now open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi Jalina, thank you. I want to ask you about North Korea. Human Rights Watch says at least 1,170 North Koreans are currently detained in China and are facing forced repatriation to North Korea. The group says North Korea recently reopened its borders, increasing the risk of forced repatriation. What is the State Department’s stance on China forcefully returning North Korean refugees back to North Korea?</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-NorthKorea"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you for your question. Well, at large, I can say that the United States is certainly committed to placing human rights at the center of our foreign policy, and that’s something you’ve heard President Biden say in the past as well as Secretary Blinken. And of course, this would include in the DPRK.</p>
<p>We’ll also continue to prioritize human rights in our overall approach when it comes to the DPRK. Even when we disagree with a regime like the DPRK, we must work to the best of our ability to alleviate the suffering of its people, and we strive to act in a manner that does not harm the North Korean people and continue to support international efforts aimed at the provision of critical humanitarian aid in the hope that the DPRK will accept it.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Pearl Matibe.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Happy Friday, Jalina. Thank you so much. My question is regarding Zimbabwe. Now I know that in recent past, the relations between the United States and Zimbabwe have always kind of toppled, gone back and forth, and may not have been the best of relations in recent past.</p>
<p>So, the president’s spokesperson has kind of made some outrageous remarks regarding the vaccines that are going out to Africa. And although the embassy has kind of hit back a little bit about those remarks, what I’m wondering is: Are there any steps between both yourselves and the Government of Zimbabwe that you might be taking to better the relationship between the two countries? I’m really interested to find out what is it that can be done. Or are any – are there any maybe backchannel things that you might be doing or anything that you can share at this point as to where you would like to see this relationship, and is there any hope that this relationship will get better? Thanks, Jalina.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you for your question, Pearl. While I don’t have anything specific for <a id="post-261735-AFRICA"></a>you on Zimbabwe today, I’d just like to reiterate that Africa is certainly a priority for the Biden administration, and we certainly intend to engage with African countries in pursuing our shared interests and values. And of course, that would include global health and climate change, freedom and democracy, as well as shared prosperity.</p>
<p>We’ll also continue to reinvigorate and restore our partnerships all along the continent as well as build partnerships with African governments and institutions as well as civil society.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Laura Kelly, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. There’s some breaking news from <a id="post-261735-Haiti"></a>NBC and Reuters that U.S. Ambassador to the UN Linda Thomas-Greenfield has left Haiti after gunshots were heard at the funeral for assassinated President Jovenel Moise. I wonder if you can comment on that. And then if I may just ask a second question.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>All right. Well, to your first question, we definitely can – we’re aware of reports that there was gunfire outside of the funeral of President Moise, and the presidential delegation that was there is safe and accounted for and, of course, en route back to the United States. And of course, the United States is deeply concerned about the unrest in Haiti. And of course, in this critical moment, Haiti’s leaders must come together to chart a united path that reflects the will of the Haitian people.</p>
<p>While we still have you, we’ll take your second question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you so much. I appreciate it. House Democrats are calling for the State Department to establish a special envoy for monitoring and combating Islamophobia and to include anti-Muslim violence per se in next year’s annual human rights reports. Can you offer any reaction to this?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>So, I don’t have any personnel announcements to make at this time, but I’m certainly happy to do so whenever we have that ability. Thank you.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Guita Aryan.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. My question is about Iran and the ongoing demonstrations in the south protesting the lack of water. Michelle Bachelet, the Human Rights – High Commissioner for Human Rights, has had harsh words for the Government of Iran, saying that they should tend to the people’s demands instead of using excessive force, and arresting people and crushing the protests.</p>
<p>I was wondering whether the United States also agrees that the Iranian Government’s reaction has been harsh. And how can the United States and the international community intervene here and have the government in Iran listen and tend to the people’s demands? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-Iran"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks for your question. So, we’re certainly following, closely following, the reports on protests in Iran’s Khuzestan’s province, including reports that security forces have opened fire on protesters, which sadly has resulted in multiple deaths. Of course, years of government neglect and a mismanagement of water resources have exacerbated the worst drought Iran has faced in at least 50 years.</p>
<p>The Iranian people have a right to freely voice their frustrations and hold their government accountable. And plainly, we support the rights of Iranians. We support their rights to peacefully assemble, as well as their rights to express themselves freely. And they should be able to do so without fear of violence or arbitrary detention by security forces.</p>
<p>We’re also monitoring reports of government-imposed internet shutdowns in the region, and we urge the Iranian Government to allow its citizens to exercise their universal rights of freedom of expression, as well as freely access internet – excuse me, freely access information online.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Simon Lewis.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thank you, Jalina. I wanted to follow up on the statement that you guys put out that said the Secretary spoke to Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer about the case of American journalist Danny Fenster, who’s jailed in Myanmar. It’s been two months, maybe three months since Danny was detained and he’s being held in Insein Prison, where we understand COVID is rampaging through the population, as it is elsewhere among the population in Myanmar. And it seems, from what he’s said to his family, it sounds like he might be infected himself. I wondered if you could give us an update on what the U.S. officials have been able to learn about Danny’s situation, from consular access or what consular access you have, and what U.S. is doing to try to get him released. And, also, if you have an update on what the administration’s doing towards Myanmar given the broader COVID outbreak there. Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-Burma"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Simon. Of course, we remain deeply concerned over the continued detention of Danny Fenster, who of course was working as a journalist in Burma. As far as any updates, Daniel had a virtual hearing on July 15th, which was procedural, and his next hearing is scheduled for July 28th. We’re closely monitoring the progression of Daniel’s case, and we’ll always call for free and independent media as indispensable to building prosperous, resilient, and free societies.</p>
<p>When it comes to the situation – the COVID situation in Burma, of course we’re still deeply troubled by the deteriorating public health situation in Burma, and of course the recent strike – spike in COVID-19 infections. The United States has provided over $20 million in COVID‑related assistance to Burma since the pandemic began, which has helped people protect themselves from infections as well as detecting and clinical care. Since the military coup, regrettably the COVID situation has sharply deteriorated, and we continue to work with international partners to identify ways to effectively respond to the current public health crisis as well as continue to support the people of Burma.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Nadia Bilbassy.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for doing this, and happy Friday. We’re following the Iraq strategic dialogue. Can you tell us if we expect a final communique? If they’re breaking into groups, what are these groups, and high representation on each? And, also, as you know, the security and military cooperation is part of it. Do we expect anything indicating the withdrawal or redeployment of U.S. troops in Iraq? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Nadia, if we have you on the line, can you repeat your last question, please? It was hard to (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> One moment for that. Nadia, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, great. I’m sorry about this. Thank you for doing this. My question was about the Iraq strategic dialogue, and whether to expect a final communique. And if you just put us – give us some information about the meeting today, what kind of groups they were breaking into. And as you know, security and military cooperation was discussed. Do we expect anything indicating talking about withdrawal of troops or deployment of U.S. troops in Iraq? Thank you so much.</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-Iraq"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So, we did issue a note that’s available on our website at the start of the strategic dialogue, and I suspect we’ll have more to read out about that, the details as well. Thank you.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jenny Hansler, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong>Thank you. Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi, Jalina, thanks for doing this. I wanted to follow up on Simon’s question about Danny Fenster. Are you able to say when he was last – or when the embassy was last given consular access to him and whether they’ve been able to confirm whether he has or had COVID‑19? And then separately on Afghanistan, we’re hearing reports among these interpreters that some of them have been disqualified from the SIV process because they failed polygraph tests. They feel that the tests were not fair – were not given out properly. Is the State Department considering changing this policy on polygraphs? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-Burma2"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Jenny. We’re going to have to take that last question back to – back for you. On your question on Danny, I’ll just reiterate that he had a virtual hearing on the 15th which was procedural and that’s when our consular had access to him. And, of course, his next one is on the 28th. As far as his health, the status of his health, I’m not able to share distinct details at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s take one final question from Barbara Usher.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong>Thank you. Your line is open. Barbara, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You can hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. Great. Yeah, could you please clarify a few points about the funeral in Haiti. Did the U.S. delegation leave early because of the security concerns, the gunshots that you mentioned? And you also said the delegation was on its way back to the U.S. Did it cut short the trip for Haiti or was that part of the plan?</p>
<p><a id="post-261735-Haiti2"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you, Barbara. So, I’ll just reiterate the same points I made earlier, and is that the presidential delegation that went – they’re all safe and they’re accounted for, and they’re back to the United States. As far as any details on the entirety of their trip, I don’t have anything to preview at this time. But – and that’s all we’ll share on that today unless you have any follow-on questions.</p>
<p>All right. That concludes today’s department press briefing. Thank you so much for joining, and have a great rest of your weekend.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:26 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-Europe Communiqué on Afghanistan and Peace Efforts</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-europe-communique-on-afghanistan-and-peace-efforts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 20:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261726</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is the text of a communiqué issued by the United States of America, the European Union, France, Germany, Italy, NATO, Norway, and the United Kingdom.</p>
<p><em>Begin text. </em></p>
<p>The Special Representatives and Special Envoys of the United States of America, the European Union, France, Germany, Italy, NATO, Norway, and the United Kingdom met in Rome on 22 July 2021 to discuss the situation in Afghanistan and the developments in Afghanistan peace negotiations after the latest round of high-level talks in Doha on July 17-18, 2021.</p>
<p>We affirm that:</p>
<ol>
<li>Our countries and organizations are committed to a strong partnership with Afghanistan and will be closely monitoring ongoing developments in this new phase of transition with the withdrawal of international forces.</li>
<li>The people of Afghanistan have suffered for too long from conflict. We are deeply concerned about the high levels of violence, the Taliban’s military offensive, and the number of reported serious human rights abuses and violations alleged in communities most affected by the ongoing armed conflict across the country.</li>
<li>We call on all parties to reduce violence and protect civilians, respecting their obligations under international humanitarian law. We call on the Taliban to end their military offensive, and on both the Islamic Republic and the Taliban to engage meaningfully in the peace process. We reiterate the urgency of reaching a ceasefire to ensure the success of negotiations, and we acknowledge the sacrifices of the Afghan security forces.</li>
<li>We reaffirm that there is no military solution to the conflict in Afghanistan, we stand by UNSC resolution 2513 (2020), and we do not support any government in Afghanistan imposed through military force.</li>
<li>We express our full support to an inclusive Afghan-owned and Afghan-led peace process with full and meaningful participation of women that leads to a just and durable political settlement. We also highlight five elements of a final settlement that are most critical: (1) inclusive governance; (2) the right to elect political leaders; (3) protections for human rights, including rights of women, youth and minorities; (4) commitments on counter-terrorism, including to ensure that Afghanistan does not again serve as a safe haven for terrorists; and (5) adherence to international law, including international humanitarian law. We emphasize that international support to any future government will depend, at least in part, on adherence to these five elements.</li>
<li>We intend to maintain our support for Afghan institutions, including defense and security forces, to address the country’s urgent needs. We also reiterate that future assistance to Afghanistan is dependent on good governance and a commitment to the rule of law and human rights, including preservation of the gains made by women and girls over the past two decades, as well as the government taking meaningful steps to tackle corruption and to meeting commitments made at the November 2020 Geneva Conference.</li>
<li>We took due note of yesterday’s briefings by the representatives of the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan and the Taliban and welcome the talks held in Doha on July 17 and 18 between senior leaders of the two sides. We further welcome the declared commitment of the two sides to accelerate negotiations toward an inclusive political settlement and to meet again in the near future. We believe future meetings should focus on core issues that will be fundamental to reaching an inclusive political settlement.</li>
<li>We acknowledge that reaching a final political settlement, including on the Constitution, will likely take time. We urge the two sides to agree on a permanent and comprehensive ceasefire and on foundational principles for the future Afghan State and details of transitional governing arrangements until a final political settlement is reached. We emphasize that any transitional governing arrangements must be inclusive, respect the rights of all Afghans in line with Afghanistan’s international commitments and also uphold counter-terrorism commitments.</li>
<li>We welcome in particular the commitments made by the Taliban yesterday to inclusive governance, respecting human rights including the rights of women and minorities, to abide by international law, including international humanitarian law, and to upholding counter terrorism commitments. We also welcome their openness to negotiate a mechanism for representative government with the Islamic Republic negotiation team.</li>
<li>We call on the two parties to negotiate in good faith in order to reach a just and durable political settlement. To promote progress in the negotiations, we support any third-party facilitation or mediation welcomed by the two sides.</li>
<li>We seize this opportunity to reiterate appreciation to Qatar as host of the negotiations, and we commend it for bringing the parties together and for its overall contribution to the process. We also commend the United Nations for the essential and expanded role it is playing in support of the process.</li>
<li>We reiterate that the Taliban and the Islamic Republic must deliver on their commitments (1) to prevent the use of Afghan soil by al Qaeda, Da’esh or other terrorist groups from launching attacks against, or threatening the security of, any other country; and (2) not to host members of these groups nor to allow them to recruit, train, fundraise or transit through Afghanistan.</li>
<li>We urge the Taliban to reduce violence, uphold their commitments to protect Afghanistan’s infrastructure, protect civilians and cooperate on humanitarian assistance, particularly as the Afghan people suffer acutely from the effects of COVID-19 and drought, in addition to violence. We call on the Taliban to allow and facilitate, without preconditions and consistent with international humanitarian law, access for delivery of humanitarian aid, to areas under their control.</li>
<li>We believe that Afghanistan can contribute to regional and international stability and connectivity. We encourage Afghanistan’s neighbors to intensify their support to the Afghan people and to contribute to a lasting peace settlement and economic development in the interests of all.</li>
<li>We also call upon all parties to ensure the safety of foreign embassies and other diplomatic missions, multilateral agencies, media representatives, airports and non-governmental organizations and their Afghan and international staff. We particularly appreciate Turkey’s readiness and commitment to assist with airport security as needed.</li>
<li>We express our appreciation to Italy for organizing these consultations and agreed to set the date and venue of the next meeting through diplomatic channels.</li>
</ol>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is the text of a communiqué issued by the United States of America, the European Union, France, Germany, Italy, NATO, Norway, and the United Kingdom.</p>
<p><em>Begin text. </em></p>
<p>The Special Representatives and Special Envoys of the United States of America, the European Union, France, Germany, Italy, NATO, Norway, and the United Kingdom met in Rome on 22 July 2021 to discuss the situation in Afghanistan and the developments in Afghanistan peace negotiations after the latest round of high-level talks in Doha on July 17-18, 2021.</p>
<p>We affirm that:</p>
<ol>
<li>Our countries and organizations are committed to a strong partnership with Afghanistan and will be closely monitoring ongoing developments in this new phase of transition with the withdrawal of international forces.</li>
<li>The people of Afghanistan have suffered for too long from conflict. We are deeply concerned about the high levels of violence, the Taliban’s military offensive, and the number of reported serious human rights abuses and violations alleged in communities most affected by the ongoing armed conflict across the country.</li>
<li>We call on all parties to reduce violence and protect civilians, respecting their obligations under international humanitarian law. We call on the Taliban to end their military offensive, and on both the Islamic Republic and the Taliban to engage meaningfully in the peace process. We reiterate the urgency of reaching a ceasefire to ensure the success of negotiations, and we acknowledge the sacrifices of the Afghan security forces.</li>
<li>We reaffirm that there is no military solution to the conflict in Afghanistan, we stand by UNSC resolution 2513 (2020), and we do not support any government in Afghanistan imposed through military force.</li>
<li>We express our full support to an inclusive Afghan-owned and Afghan-led peace process with full and meaningful participation of women that leads to a just and durable political settlement. We also highlight five elements of a final settlement that are most critical: (1) inclusive governance; (2) the right to elect political leaders; (3) protections for human rights, including rights of women, youth and minorities; (4) commitments on counter-terrorism, including to ensure that Afghanistan does not again serve as a safe haven for terrorists; and (5) adherence to international law, including international humanitarian law. We emphasize that international support to any future government will depend, at least in part, on adherence to these five elements.</li>
<li>We intend to maintain our support for Afghan institutions, including defense and security forces, to address the country’s urgent needs. We also reiterate that future assistance to Afghanistan is dependent on good governance and a commitment to the rule of law and human rights, including preservation of the gains made by women and girls over the past two decades, as well as the government taking meaningful steps to tackle corruption and to meeting commitments made at the November 2020 Geneva Conference.</li>
<li>We took due note of yesterday’s briefings by the representatives of the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan and the Taliban and welcome the talks held in Doha on July 17 and 18 between senior leaders of the two sides. We further welcome the declared commitment of the two sides to accelerate negotiations toward an inclusive political settlement and to meet again in the near future. We believe future meetings should focus on core issues that will be fundamental to reaching an inclusive political settlement.</li>
<li>We acknowledge that reaching a final political settlement, including on the Constitution, will likely take time. We urge the two sides to agree on a permanent and comprehensive ceasefire and on foundational principles for the future Afghan State and details of transitional governing arrangements until a final political settlement is reached. We emphasize that any transitional governing arrangements must be inclusive, respect the rights of all Afghans in line with Afghanistan’s international commitments and also uphold counter-terrorism commitments.</li>
<li>We welcome in particular the commitments made by the Taliban yesterday to inclusive governance, respecting human rights including the rights of women and minorities, to abide by international law, including international humanitarian law, and to upholding counter terrorism commitments. We also welcome their openness to negotiate a mechanism for representative government with the Islamic Republic negotiation team.</li>
<li>We call on the two parties to negotiate in good faith in order to reach a just and durable political settlement. To promote progress in the negotiations, we support any third-party facilitation or mediation welcomed by the two sides.</li>
<li>We seize this opportunity to reiterate appreciation to Qatar as host of the negotiations, and we commend it for bringing the parties together and for its overall contribution to the process. We also commend the United Nations for the essential and expanded role it is playing in support of the process.</li>
<li>We reiterate that the Taliban and the Islamic Republic must deliver on their commitments (1) to prevent the use of Afghan soil by al Qaeda, Da’esh or other terrorist groups from launching attacks against, or threatening the security of, any other country; and (2) not to host members of these groups nor to allow them to recruit, train, fundraise or transit through Afghanistan.</li>
<li>We urge the Taliban to reduce violence, uphold their commitments to protect Afghanistan’s infrastructure, protect civilians and cooperate on humanitarian assistance, particularly as the Afghan people suffer acutely from the effects of COVID-19 and drought, in addition to violence. We call on the Taliban to allow and facilitate, without preconditions and consistent with international humanitarian law, access for delivery of humanitarian aid, to areas under their control.</li>
<li>We believe that Afghanistan can contribute to regional and international stability and connectivity. We encourage Afghanistan’s neighbors to intensify their support to the Afghan people and to contribute to a lasting peace settlement and economic development in the interests of all.</li>
<li>We also call upon all parties to ensure the safety of foreign embassies and other diplomatic missions, multilateral agencies, media representatives, airports and non-governmental organizations and their Afghan and international staff. We particularly appreciate Turkey’s readiness and commitment to assist with airport security as needed.</li>
<li>We express our appreciation to Italy for organizing these consultations and agreed to set the date and venue of the next meeting through diplomatic channels.</li>
</ol>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Announces Humanitarian Assistance for Iraq</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-announces-humanitarian-assistance-for-iraq/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 19:44:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261691</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is pleased to announce nearly $155 million in additional humanitarian assistance for the people of Iraq as well as Iraqi refugees in the region and generous communities hosting them. With this additional funding from the State Department and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), U.S. humanitarian support for Iraq amounts to more than $200 million to-date in Fiscal Year (FY) 2021. Since FY 2014, the United States has provided more than $3 billion in humanitarian assistance in Iraq and for Iraqis in the region.</p>
<p>This funding will provide critical shelter, essential healthcare, emergency food assistance, protection services such as gender-based violence response, and water, sanitation, and hygiene services throughout Iraq. U.S. funded programs will support Iraqis displaced by ISIS, many of whom also continue to face hardships from the COVID-19 pandemic by promoting access to civil documentation and legal services, improving the capacity of health care facilities, and increasing access to education and livelihood opportunities.</p>
<p>The United States remains the largest single donor of humanitarian assistance in Iraq and globally. We appreciate all donors who have stepped up and continue to encourage both existing and new donors to increase their support to help meet the needs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is pleased to announce nearly $155 million in additional humanitarian assistance for the people of Iraq as well as Iraqi refugees in the region and generous communities hosting them. With this additional funding from the State Department and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), U.S. humanitarian support for Iraq amounts to more than $200 million to-date in Fiscal Year (FY) 2021. Since FY 2014, the United States has provided more than $3 billion in humanitarian assistance in Iraq and for Iraqis in the region.</p>
<p>This funding will provide critical shelter, essential healthcare, emergency food assistance, protection services such as gender-based violence response, and water, sanitation, and hygiene services throughout Iraq. U.S. funded programs will support Iraqis displaced by ISIS, many of whom also continue to face hardships from the COVID-19 pandemic by promoting access to civil documentation and legal services, improving the capacity of health care facilities, and increasing access to education and livelihood opportunities.</p>
<p>The United States remains the largest single donor of humanitarian assistance in Iraq and globally. We appreciate all donors who have stepped up and continue to encourage both existing and new donors to increase their support to help meet the needs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken&#8217;s Meeting with Foreign Minister Hussein</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-foreign-minister-hussein/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 18:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Iraqi Foreign Minister Dr. Fuad Hussein today on the margins of the U.S.-Iraq Strategic Dialogue in Washington, D.C. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Hussein reviewed the Strategic Dialogue and reaffirmed the principles agreed upon by the two sides in the Strategic Framework Agreement (SFA). The Secretary encouraged the Government of Iraq to continue efforts to address the Iraqi people’s demands for equity and justice and expressed his support for Iraq’s anti-corruption and economic reform efforts, as well as for elections later this year. The Secretary reiterated that the United States remains committed to assisting the Government of Iraq to achieve a secure, stable, and prosperous future.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Iraqi Foreign Minister Dr. Fuad Hussein today on the margins of the U.S.-Iraq Strategic Dialogue in Washington, D.C. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Hussein reviewed the Strategic Dialogue and reaffirmed the principles agreed upon by the two sides in the Strategic Framework Agreement (SFA). The Secretary encouraged the Government of Iraq to continue efforts to address the Iraqi people’s demands for equity and justice and expressed his support for Iraq’s anti-corruption and economic reform efforts, as well as for elections later this year. The Secretary reiterated that the United States remains committed to assisting the Government of Iraq to achieve a secure, stable, and prosperous future.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman to Lead U.S. Delegation in Strategic Stability Dialogue with Russian Federation</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-sherman-to-lead-u-s-delegation-in-strategic-stability-dialogue-with-russian-federation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 18:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman will travel to Geneva, Switzerland to lead the U.S. delegation’s participation in a U.S.-Russia bilateral Strategic Stability Dialogue on July 28, 2021. She will be joined by Under Secretary of State for Arms Control and International Security Bonnie Jenkins, who will provide additional leadership for the delegation. This meeting follows up on a commitment made between President Biden and Russian President Putin to have a deliberate and robust dialogue between our two nations that will seek to lay the groundwork for future arms control and risk reduction measures.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman will travel to Geneva, Switzerland to lead the U.S. delegation’s participation in a U.S.-Russia bilateral Strategic Stability Dialogue on July 28, 2021. She will be joined by Under Secretary of State for Arms Control and International Security Bonnie Jenkins, who will provide additional leadership for the delegation. This meeting follows up on a commitment made between President Biden and Russian President Putin to have a deliberate and robust dialogue between our two nations that will seek to lay the groundwork for future arms control and risk reduction measures.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony Blinken to Highlight Value of International Education at the Department’s 12th Annual EducationUSA Forum</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-blinken-to-highlight-value-of-international-education-at-the-departments-12th-annual-educationusa-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 18:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261665</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony Blinken will highlight the value of international education to U.S. diplomacy, national security, economic prosperity, and U.S. leadership in research and innovation via pre-recorded video remarks at the 12th annual EducationUSA Forum on Monday, July 26, at 10 a.m. U.S. Secretary of Education Dr. Miguel Cardona will also address the Forum to highlight the Department of Education’s commitment to a renewed focus on the benefits of international education at home and abroad.</p>
<p>International students, numbering over a million for the fifth consecutive year in 2019-2020, contributed over $39 billion to the U.S. economy in 2020, and supported an estimated 415,000 U.S. jobs. With more than 4,000 U.S. colleges and universities, the United States offers international students world-class academic opportunities. In turn, international students enrich American classrooms and communities with diverse perspectives and develop ties with their American peers. These ties form the basis of continued American success in business and trade, science and innovation, and governmental relations.</p>
<p>Held virtually from July 26-30, the 2021 EducationUSA Forum will convene more than 2,000 international education professionals from accredited U.S. colleges and universities to explore best practices and strategies for maintaining and growing the United States as the top study destination for international students from around the globe. The 2021 EducationUSA Forum will feature over 30 virtual conference sessions on issues such as global student mobility trends, student recruitment strategies, best practices in diversifying the international student pipeline, and practical updates for virtual programming during COVID-19. At the Forum, the first in a new series of global marketing assets promoting study in the United States will be also be released.</p>
<p>EducationUSA is the U.S. Department of State’s global network of international student advising centers operating in more than 175 countries and territories to highlight U.S. higher education opportunities to students around the world. The network supports the Department’s mission to promote U.S. higher education and exchanges to international students to create and sustain mutual understanding with other countries, which is necessary in advancing U.S. foreign policy goals.</p>
<p>Members of the press can register for the event <a class="external-link" href="https://educationusaforum2021.vfairs.com/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">here</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> to watch the video as it is broadcast at the forum. The video and other releases throughout the event will also be posted on <a href="http://educationusa.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://educationusa.state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1627149136241000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGnOsx3TcEwjGtIfHXcgG9lfI5F6Q">educationusa.state.gov</a>. Please contact <a href="mailto:ECA-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ECA-Press@state.gov</a> with questions. Follow the conversation on Twitter using #EdUSAForum. Visit this <a href="https://educationusa.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MjMuNDM2MjE1MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2VkdWNhdGlvbnVzYS5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvIn0.ah4TE9A-yHEeNoVhK9oCbxpN_x7W3udcm62E6A5FCHM/s/1039202793/br/109824997536-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1627149136241000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEjueK9plV2RWiPOJWSvite7g8zeg">website</a> to learn more about EducationUSA and the 2021 EducationUSA Forum.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony Blinken will highlight the value of international education to U.S. diplomacy, national security, economic prosperity, and U.S. leadership in research and innovation via pre-recorded video remarks at the 12th annual EducationUSA Forum on Monday, July 26, at 10 a.m. U.S. Secretary of Education Dr. Miguel Cardona will also address the Forum to highlight the Department of Education’s commitment to a renewed focus on the benefits of international education at home and abroad.</p>
<p>International students, numbering over a million for the fifth consecutive year in 2019-2020, contributed over $39 billion to the U.S. economy in 2020, and supported an estimated 415,000 U.S. jobs. With more than 4,000 U.S. colleges and universities, the United States offers international students world-class academic opportunities. In turn, international students enrich American classrooms and communities with diverse perspectives and develop ties with their American peers. These ties form the basis of continued American success in business and trade, science and innovation, and governmental relations.</p>
<p>Held virtually from July 26-30, the 2021 EducationUSA Forum will convene more than 2,000 international education professionals from accredited U.S. colleges and universities to explore best practices and strategies for maintaining and growing the United States as the top study destination for international students from around the globe. The 2021 EducationUSA Forum will feature over 30 virtual conference sessions on issues such as global student mobility trends, student recruitment strategies, best practices in diversifying the international student pipeline, and practical updates for virtual programming during COVID-19. At the Forum, the first in a new series of global marketing assets promoting study in the United States will be also be released.</p>
<p>EducationUSA is the U.S. Department of State’s global network of international student advising centers operating in more than 175 countries and territories to highlight U.S. higher education opportunities to students around the world. The network supports the Department’s mission to promote U.S. higher education and exchanges to international students to create and sustain mutual understanding with other countries, which is necessary in advancing U.S. foreign policy goals.</p>
<p>Members of the press can register for the event <a class="external-link" href="https://educationusaforum2021.vfairs.com/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">here</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> to watch the video as it is broadcast at the forum. The video and other releases throughout the event will also be posted on <a href="http://educationusa.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://educationusa.state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1627149136241000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGnOsx3TcEwjGtIfHXcgG9lfI5F6Q">educationusa.state.gov</a>. Please contact <a href="mailto:ECA-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ECA-Press@state.gov</a> with questions. Follow the conversation on Twitter using #EdUSAForum. Visit this <a href="https://educationusa.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MjMuNDM2MjE1MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2VkdWNhdGlvbnVzYS5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvIn0.ah4TE9A-yHEeNoVhK9oCbxpN_x7W3udcm62E6A5FCHM/s/1039202793/br/109824997536-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1627149136241000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEjueK9plV2RWiPOJWSvite7g8zeg">website</a> to learn more about EducationUSA and the 2021 EducationUSA Forum.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Iraqi Foreign Minister Dr. Fuad Hussein Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-iraqi-foreign-minister-dr-fuad-hussein-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 16:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261632</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good morning, everyone.  It’s a particular pleasure to have Foreign Minister Hussein, my friend of many years, colleague of many years here at the State Department, with his delegation for the Strategic Dialogue with the United States and Iraq.</p>
<p>We are, of course, the closest of partners in the fight against ISIS, and we can take tremendous pride in the work we’ve done together to defeat ISIS and to make sure that it stays defeated.  But I think what today is demonstrating is that the partnership between the United States and Iraq is much broader and deeper than even the common fight against ISIS.</p>
<p>The United States is proud to be partnered with Iraq in meeting some of the most important challenges of our time, whether it’s the fight against the COVID-19 pandemic, dealing with climate change and making investments in renewable energy.  Whether it is as the leading provider of humanitarian assistance to Iraq, and building opportunity for Iraqis, this partnership has tremendous breadth as well as tremendous depth.</p>
<p>And, of course, the United States is proud to be leading international efforts to support Iraq’s elections in October, free and fair elections, so that the Iraqi people can have their voices heard and choose their leaders.</p>
<p>Most of all, we are proceeding together in partnership based on mutual respect and mutual interests, and the work we’re doing today is going to carry that forward.</p>
<p>So, Fuad, welcome.  It’s wonderful to have you here.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HUSSEIN:</strong>  Thank you very much.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) Thank you very much.  Thank you very much, my dear friend Tony, Tony Blinken, Secretary of State.  In fact, this relationship, this partnership goes back a long way to the joint work against ISIS, and building the political (inaudible) and – for Iraq.</p>
<p>Our presence here in Washington is to conduct the dialogue and the discussions with the United States under the leadership of the U.S. delegation under the honorable Secretary of State Tony Blinken, and I thank him for this invitation, and we hope that the outcome of this dialogue is to serve the interests of the two countries and the two people.</p>
<p>And the foundations of this dialogue are the basic principles that were mentioned: joint operation, mutual respect, and cooperation in various fields – military and security, economic, trade, also energy and all its different fields like clean energy, gas, fuel, electricity, as well as the health field and countering the pandemic – COVID-19 pandemic, and the work and cooperation on the field of education.</p>
<p>And with the efforts and operation of the Iraqi forces, of all its branches, the support of the Iraqi people and the cooperation of the international coalition, we were able to defeat the so-called Islamic State – that is, ISIS – and to eradicate it from its presence in Iraq.</p>
<p>However, ISIS the terrorist organization remains as a terrorist organization and as a military organization that depends on particular ideology.</p>
<p>There’s still terrorist activities for ISIS in Iraq.  A few days ago, there was a suicide operation in Sadr City that resulted in the martyrdom of tens of – number of the citizens as well as a larger number of injuries amongst the citizens.  So, these ISIS activities continue, are still present, and they represent a danger to the Iraqi society, to the regional society, and to the international society.</p>
<p>And because the terrorist organization ISIS is a local and active organization inside Iraq, but also a regional and international organization that depends on an international ideology, that requires international work and international cooperation.</p>
<p>And so, we need the cooperation with the international coalition and to work with the international coalition, under the leadership of the United States against ISIS, and to exchange information with the international coalition, the United States, and with Iraq to defeat Daesh.</p>
<p>Our relationships with the United States are not just military relationships, but they are vast and broad relationships. And in the future, we will have a much broader cooperation in all the fields that were mentioned, the strategic dialogues that depend and relies on pushing forward these efforts to improve the lives of people and to improve the future of Iraq.  And we thank the United States for helping and supporting Iraq in the Security Council to get a unanimous position to support Iraq, and send monitors to monitor the electoral efforts, which are very important for the future of Iraq, and future of the people of Iraq, and democracy in Iraq.</p>
<p>At the end, again, I reiterate my thanks to my dear friend and colleague, Secretary Tony Blinken, for receiving us.  And we anticipate to have deep discussions that will bring us to fruitful results for the good interest of the two countries.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HUSSEIN:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong><em>Shukran.</em>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HUSSEIN:  </strong><em>Shukran.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110010000" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good morning, everyone.  It’s a particular pleasure to have Foreign Minister Hussein, my friend of many years, colleague of many years here at the State Department, with his delegation for the Strategic Dialogue with the United States and Iraq.</p>
<p>We are, of course, the closest of partners in the fight against ISIS, and we can take tremendous pride in the work we’ve done together to defeat ISIS and to make sure that it stays defeated.  But I think what today is demonstrating is that the partnership between the United States and Iraq is much broader and deeper than even the common fight against ISIS.</p>
<p>The United States is proud to be partnered with Iraq in meeting some of the most important challenges of our time, whether it’s the fight against the COVID-19 pandemic, dealing with climate change and making investments in renewable energy.  Whether it is as the leading provider of humanitarian assistance to Iraq, and building opportunity for Iraqis, this partnership has tremendous breadth as well as tremendous depth.</p>
<p>And, of course, the United States is proud to be leading international efforts to support Iraq’s elections in October, free and fair elections, so that the Iraqi people can have their voices heard and choose their leaders.</p>
<p>Most of all, we are proceeding together in partnership based on mutual respect and mutual interests, and the work we’re doing today is going to carry that forward.</p>
<p>So, Fuad, welcome.  It’s wonderful to have you here.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HUSSEIN:</strong>  Thank you very much.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) Thank you very much.  Thank you very much, my dear friend Tony, Tony Blinken, Secretary of State.  In fact, this relationship, this partnership goes back a long way to the joint work against ISIS, and building the political (inaudible) and – for Iraq.</p>
<p>Our presence here in Washington is to conduct the dialogue and the discussions with the United States under the leadership of the U.S. delegation under the honorable Secretary of State Tony Blinken, and I thank him for this invitation, and we hope that the outcome of this dialogue is to serve the interests of the two countries and the two people.</p>
<p>And the foundations of this dialogue are the basic principles that were mentioned: joint operation, mutual respect, and cooperation in various fields – military and security, economic, trade, also energy and all its different fields like clean energy, gas, fuel, electricity, as well as the health field and countering the pandemic – COVID-19 pandemic, and the work and cooperation on the field of education.</p>
<p>And with the efforts and operation of the Iraqi forces, of all its branches, the support of the Iraqi people and the cooperation of the international coalition, we were able to defeat the so-called Islamic State – that is, ISIS – and to eradicate it from its presence in Iraq.</p>
<p>However, ISIS the terrorist organization remains as a terrorist organization and as a military organization that depends on particular ideology.</p>
<p>There’s still terrorist activities for ISIS in Iraq.  A few days ago, there was a suicide operation in Sadr City that resulted in the martyrdom of tens of – number of the citizens as well as a larger number of injuries amongst the citizens.  So, these ISIS activities continue, are still present, and they represent a danger to the Iraqi society, to the regional society, and to the international society.</p>
<p>And because the terrorist organization ISIS is a local and active organization inside Iraq, but also a regional and international organization that depends on an international ideology, that requires international work and international cooperation.</p>
<p>And so, we need the cooperation with the international coalition and to work with the international coalition, under the leadership of the United States against ISIS, and to exchange information with the international coalition, the United States, and with Iraq to defeat Daesh.</p>
<p>Our relationships with the United States are not just military relationships, but they are vast and broad relationships. And in the future, we will have a much broader cooperation in all the fields that were mentioned, the strategic dialogues that depend and relies on pushing forward these efforts to improve the lives of people and to improve the future of Iraq.  And we thank the United States for helping and supporting Iraq in the Security Council to get a unanimous position to support Iraq, and send monitors to monitor the electoral efforts, which are very important for the future of Iraq, and future of the people of Iraq, and democracy in Iraq.</p>
<p>At the end, again, I reiterate my thanks to my dear friend and colleague, Secretary Tony Blinken, for receiving us.  And we anticipate to have deep discussions that will bring us to fruitful results for the good interest of the two countries.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HUSSEIN:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong><em>Shukran.</em>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HUSSEIN:  </strong><em>Shukran.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110010000" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Mika Brzezinski and Willie Geist of MSNBC’s Morning Joe</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-mika-brzezinski-and-willie-geist-of-msnbcs-morning-joe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 15:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261601</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> As COVID-19 cases rise once again in America, health officials say the Delta variant is now the most dominant strain not only in the U.S., but across the world. This setback comes just weeks after the Biden administration pledged to lead the way in global vaccination efforts. Will the virus’s re-emergence at home slow down efforts to vaccinate the rest of the world?</p>
<p>Joining us now, U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken, and Tony, it’s great to have you back on the show and to speak with you. And I guess we’ll start right there. As we – as it pertains to the coronavirus, how will the United States collaborate on the world stage, lead on the world stage, when you have a rejection of the vaccine here at home that is creating a pandemic among the unvaccinated?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Mika, first, it’s great to see you and great to be with you too. Look, we are leading on both fronts – at home and around the world. And we have to do both because as long as this virus is out there anywhere replicating, we’re going to see more variants, and those variants are going to come back and bite us, as we’re already experiencing with Delta. And so as we’re pursuing every effort to get every American vaccinated, we’re also very much engaged in the world at the President’s direction.</p>
<p>And as you know, we had vaccines in our stockpile, 80 million that we’re making available to countries around the world. We started doing that about a month ago. Of the 80 million, 60 million have been distributed. And the President announced when he was in Europe at the G7 that the United States was going to purchase 500 million, a half a billion vaccines to distribute around the world – no strings attached – to countries around the world to make sure that we can do everything we can to win this race against variants.</p>
<p>The other thing that’s happening is because of our leadership, other countries are stepping up. The G7 countries, our European partners, Japan are also committing additional vaccines. And production is increasing. What we have to do is get to a place where we’re getting as many vaccines as we possibly can to as many countries, as many people as fast as we can. If we do that, we can get ahead of the variants and win the race.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> So I understand you’re announcing a trip where you will take this show on the road and this message on the road. I’d like to hear more about that and I’d like to push you a little bit on the pandemic among the unvaccinated here at home, which really appears to be based on disinformation. We’re hearing even Republican governors like Kay Ivey just fed up with the disinformation and with the choice of people to not vaccinate themselves, to not protect themselves from a virus that could kill them. Meanwhile, there is many countries around the world just hoping to get their hands on the vaccine.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, Mika, that’s right, and look, we know it. The numbers are very, very clear. Of the people hospitalized now or people dying from COVID-19 in the United States, 97, 98, 99 percent are unvaccinated. It’s as clear and stark as that. That’s the reality. And hopefully, as more and more people speak out about this, people will listen and take action. And this is not a partisan issue. It’s an American issue. We’re all in this together, and I hope everyone will do what is necessary to protect ourselves against COVID-19.</p>
<p>And yes, I’m going to India this week. This is such a critical country in the fight against COVID-19. The Indians stood up for us in the early days when we were having great challenges, helping to provide PPE, for example. We’ve now stood up for them as they have encountered wave after wave of COVID-19, including providing more than a quarter of a billion dollars of assistance to them. We have millions of vaccines ready to go to them when they finish their own legal process to bring them in. And India is the leading country when it comes to the production of vaccines.</p>
<p>Of course, they’re focused understandably on their own internal challenges now, but when that production engine gets fully going and can distribute again to the rest of the world, that’s going to make a big difference, too. So I’ll be talking to our Indian friends about that next week.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Will you be addressing in the weeks and months to come the disinformation from U.S. tech companies, perhaps even happening abroad, where companies like Facebook and others have so much information that is just flat wrong about COVID and is leading to deadly decisions on the part of people around the world?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Look, Mika, all we can do is ask everyone to step up to their responsibilities, to try to get accurate information out there to people who need it, whether that’s here at home or whether that’s around the world. And ultimately, because this is a global challenge, because no one is safe until everyone is safe, countries or groups that may engage in misinformation or disinformation are doing themselves ultimately a huge disservice.</p>
<p>And so what we can do, what we have to do, what we are doing, is making sure, one, that the right information gets out there, and two, the resources get out there, the vaccines get out there, the production’s out there. One of the other things we’re doing is investing now in production in different parts of the world – for example, in Africa. We need to make sure that we’re doing that both to get ahead of COVID-19, this pandemic, but also to set ourselves up for the next time. Because unfortunately, there will be a next time. But we have to make sure that we’re in a much better place around the world to prevent it, to see it, to mitigate it more effectively than we’re able to do this time.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> I want to move on to Cuba, which has seen protests over the past few weeks. And yesterday the White House announced new sanctions against Cuba’s defense minister and special forces brigade for the suppression of peaceful protests. What are those sanctions, and what happens if there is not the result the United States would like to see in reaction, in response to those sanctions?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, Mika, I think what we saw just a little over a week ago is quite extraordinary. Thousands of people, tens of thousands of people taking to the streets across Cuba – not just in Havana but in dozens of cities and towns across Cuba – to say they’re fed up – fed up with the repression, fed up with the lack of freedom, fed up with the fact that they don’t have food and medicines, that they have a government that is not providing for them, and making their voices heard. And I think it’s evidence of a government that – and a regime that certainly lacks confidence in itself when it has to try to stifle the voices of its own people.</p>
<p>The smartest thing the regime in Cuba can do is to listen to its own people instead of repress them. But unfortunately, they are – they continue to repress them, they took violent action against those who were speaking up. We went ahead and sanctioned the leaders of the military, the leaders of something called the Black Berets. They were on the front lines of taking violent action against people speaking out for their freedom, speaking out for their needs. We’ll continue to do that.</p>
<p>And also it’s very important that the Cuban people have an ability to communicate, and one of the things we’re very focused on now, working with the private sector, working with others, is doing everything we can to make sure that they have internet access so they can speak to one another, so they can have contact and communication with folks off the island. That is a very active effort.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> And is the regime responding, showing any signs of improvement, of responding to what the United States is requiring for the sanctions to either be pulled back or for more sanctions not to come their way?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> No. We haven’t seen that kind of response. The regime tends to double down in these situations. But again, this is not about us. This is about the Cuban people. And I think one of the big mistakes the regime makes is to try to point the finger at the United States, saying we’re responsible for these protests. We’re not. These are the Cuban people. They are speaking up. They are standing – they’re speaking out. They’re standing up. And a regime that doesn’t understand that and that has – lacks the confidence to allow the voices of its own people to be heard I think is making a very, very big mistake.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Let’s jump to Russia and the issue of cyberwarfare, which I think also then ends us up in China. (Laughter.) What is the United States prepared to do to make sure this doesn’t happen again? What’s next, when the next attack happens, to kind of send a message to Vladimir Putin that there’s a new sheriff in town?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, I think that message has been sent and, as necessary, will be sent again. The – President Biden addressed this directly with President Putin, both at the meeting in Geneva that I took part in as well as more recently on the phone. And one of the things that we’re seeing, as you know, is an increased use of so-called ransomware. And this is tremendously destructive. Overall, one-in-four Americans has been a victim of a cyber crime. About $40 billion lost on an annual basis. And ransomware in particular is increasingly dangerous. And what we’ve made clear to Russia, but to other countries around the world, is if you’re harboring individuals or organizations engaged in cyber crime, engaged in ransomware, that is unacceptable. And if you will not take action against them, we will.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Secretary Blinken, it’s Willie Geist. Good to see you this morning.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Hey, Willie.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> I want to ask you about Afghanistan. The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs, General Milley, said the other day that the Taliban has strategic momentum, that it may well over-run the country, though he didn’t concede that point just yet. So as the troops come home from Afghanistan, how should Americans be thinking about the mission there from our point of view? If it does become a training ground for terrorists again, if there does – some threat is posed to the United States, what will be the American reaction there?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b>Well, Willie, we’re determined that it not become a training ground for terrorism directed against the United States or our allies and partners. That’s exactly why we went there in the first place, which is important to remember. We were attacked on 9/11, we went to Afghanistan to get the folks who attacked us, to bring them to justice. Osama bin Laden was brought to justice 10 years ago, and the group, al-Qaida, responsible for those attacks has been dramatically diminished in terms of its capacity to attack anyone from Afghanistan. We’re going to make sure that we keep our eyes on that. If we see the threat re-emerging, we’re going to be in a position to take action against it. But that’s why we were there, and now we’re 20 years and a trillion dollars and thousands of Americans lost later in this – in that campaign. I think the reason we went there is what we have to keep the focus on, and we’ve largely succeeded in doing what we needed to do.</p>
<p>We do have deep concerns about the actions the Taliban is taking indicating that it may be trying to take the country by force, but were that to happen, Afghanistan would be a pariah state. It would not get the assistance that it’s looking for and that the Taliban says it wants if it has any responsibility for the country. It would not get the support from the international community that it says it wants. We’re actively engaged in diplomacy because there is no military solution to this conflict that’s been going on for more than 40 years in Afghanistan, and we’re working to try to bring that to an end.</p>
<p>But one other thing: We’re sustaining our support through our embassy, through other embassies for the Afghan people, and at the same time we’re working to make good on our commitment to those who helped us and put their lives on the line – interpreters, translators – they’re benefiting from a program called Special Immigrant Visa programs that allow them to seek visas to come to the United States. We are moving very, very rapidly ahead with that program.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>When you say “take action,” Mr. Secretary, is that airstrikes? Or can you see a world where American troops are back in Afghanistan?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b>Look, I don’t want to get into hypotheticals about where this might go in the future. What I can tell you, Willie, is that we’re going to make sure that we have the capacity to see if the terrorist threat from Afghanistan re-emerges and to be in a position to do something about it.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Mr. Secretary, a final question, and it’s not really a fun one, but I have to ask. We had a president for four years who openly admitted to getting dirt on political rivals from a foreign leader, meeting without notetakers with Vladimir Putin, having these meetings with Kim Jong-un, which were a joke at best. Geo-strategically, how much ground was lost during the Donald Trump presidency with his corrupt and undemocratic approach to foreign policy? Are we less secure, and if so, how much?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b>Well, Mika, happily, in my job, I don’t do politics. I’m focused on the future. But I can tell you this: Just a short while ago, the President traveled to Europe. He met with our G7 partners, with our NATO Allies, with our partners in the European Union, and then, of course, he met with Vladimir Putin. And he has asked us these first six months of the administration to focus first and foremost on revitalizing our relationships, our partnerships with allies, with partners. That’s exactly what we’ve done. And there was a very, very telling poll that came out during his trip. Across the democratic countries that we’ve been engaged with and that the President engaged with in Europe, on average, 75 percent of the people have confidence, trust in American leadership. That’s up from 17 percent a year ago. I think that speaks volumes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Secretary of State Antony Blinken, thank you so much for coming on the show this morning, and we look forward to hearing about the trip to India and the fight against COVID. Thank you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> As COVID-19 cases rise once again in America, health officials say the Delta variant is now the most dominant strain not only in the U.S., but across the world. This setback comes just weeks after the Biden administration pledged to lead the way in global vaccination efforts. Will the virus’s re-emergence at home slow down efforts to vaccinate the rest of the world?</p>
<p>Joining us now, U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken, and Tony, it’s great to have you back on the show and to speak with you. And I guess we’ll start right there. As we – as it pertains to the coronavirus, how will the United States collaborate on the world stage, lead on the world stage, when you have a rejection of the vaccine here at home that is creating a pandemic among the unvaccinated?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Mika, first, it’s great to see you and great to be with you too. Look, we are leading on both fronts – at home and around the world. And we have to do both because as long as this virus is out there anywhere replicating, we’re going to see more variants, and those variants are going to come back and bite us, as we’re already experiencing with Delta. And so as we’re pursuing every effort to get every American vaccinated, we’re also very much engaged in the world at the President’s direction.</p>
<p>And as you know, we had vaccines in our stockpile, 80 million that we’re making available to countries around the world. We started doing that about a month ago. Of the 80 million, 60 million have been distributed. And the President announced when he was in Europe at the G7 that the United States was going to purchase 500 million, a half a billion vaccines to distribute around the world – no strings attached – to countries around the world to make sure that we can do everything we can to win this race against variants.</p>
<p>The other thing that’s happening is because of our leadership, other countries are stepping up. The G7 countries, our European partners, Japan are also committing additional vaccines. And production is increasing. What we have to do is get to a place where we’re getting as many vaccines as we possibly can to as many countries, as many people as fast as we can. If we do that, we can get ahead of the variants and win the race.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> So I understand you’re announcing a trip where you will take this show on the road and this message on the road. I’d like to hear more about that and I’d like to push you a little bit on the pandemic among the unvaccinated here at home, which really appears to be based on disinformation. We’re hearing even Republican governors like Kay Ivey just fed up with the disinformation and with the choice of people to not vaccinate themselves, to not protect themselves from a virus that could kill them. Meanwhile, there is many countries around the world just hoping to get their hands on the vaccine.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, Mika, that’s right, and look, we know it. The numbers are very, very clear. Of the people hospitalized now or people dying from COVID-19 in the United States, 97, 98, 99 percent are unvaccinated. It’s as clear and stark as that. That’s the reality. And hopefully, as more and more people speak out about this, people will listen and take action. And this is not a partisan issue. It’s an American issue. We’re all in this together, and I hope everyone will do what is necessary to protect ourselves against COVID-19.</p>
<p>And yes, I’m going to India this week. This is such a critical country in the fight against COVID-19. The Indians stood up for us in the early days when we were having great challenges, helping to provide PPE, for example. We’ve now stood up for them as they have encountered wave after wave of COVID-19, including providing more than a quarter of a billion dollars of assistance to them. We have millions of vaccines ready to go to them when they finish their own legal process to bring them in. And India is the leading country when it comes to the production of vaccines.</p>
<p>Of course, they’re focused understandably on their own internal challenges now, but when that production engine gets fully going and can distribute again to the rest of the world, that’s going to make a big difference, too. So I’ll be talking to our Indian friends about that next week.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Will you be addressing in the weeks and months to come the disinformation from U.S. tech companies, perhaps even happening abroad, where companies like Facebook and others have so much information that is just flat wrong about COVID and is leading to deadly decisions on the part of people around the world?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Look, Mika, all we can do is ask everyone to step up to their responsibilities, to try to get accurate information out there to people who need it, whether that’s here at home or whether that’s around the world. And ultimately, because this is a global challenge, because no one is safe until everyone is safe, countries or groups that may engage in misinformation or disinformation are doing themselves ultimately a huge disservice.</p>
<p>And so what we can do, what we have to do, what we are doing, is making sure, one, that the right information gets out there, and two, the resources get out there, the vaccines get out there, the production’s out there. One of the other things we’re doing is investing now in production in different parts of the world – for example, in Africa. We need to make sure that we’re doing that both to get ahead of COVID-19, this pandemic, but also to set ourselves up for the next time. Because unfortunately, there will be a next time. But we have to make sure that we’re in a much better place around the world to prevent it, to see it, to mitigate it more effectively than we’re able to do this time.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> I want to move on to Cuba, which has seen protests over the past few weeks. And yesterday the White House announced new sanctions against Cuba’s defense minister and special forces brigade for the suppression of peaceful protests. What are those sanctions, and what happens if there is not the result the United States would like to see in reaction, in response to those sanctions?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, Mika, I think what we saw just a little over a week ago is quite extraordinary. Thousands of people, tens of thousands of people taking to the streets across Cuba – not just in Havana but in dozens of cities and towns across Cuba – to say they’re fed up – fed up with the repression, fed up with the lack of freedom, fed up with the fact that they don’t have food and medicines, that they have a government that is not providing for them, and making their voices heard. And I think it’s evidence of a government that – and a regime that certainly lacks confidence in itself when it has to try to stifle the voices of its own people.</p>
<p>The smartest thing the regime in Cuba can do is to listen to its own people instead of repress them. But unfortunately, they are – they continue to repress them, they took violent action against those who were speaking up. We went ahead and sanctioned the leaders of the military, the leaders of something called the Black Berets. They were on the front lines of taking violent action against people speaking out for their freedom, speaking out for their needs. We’ll continue to do that.</p>
<p>And also it’s very important that the Cuban people have an ability to communicate, and one of the things we’re very focused on now, working with the private sector, working with others, is doing everything we can to make sure that they have internet access so they can speak to one another, so they can have contact and communication with folks off the island. That is a very active effort.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> And is the regime responding, showing any signs of improvement, of responding to what the United States is requiring for the sanctions to either be pulled back or for more sanctions not to come their way?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> No. We haven’t seen that kind of response. The regime tends to double down in these situations. But again, this is not about us. This is about the Cuban people. And I think one of the big mistakes the regime makes is to try to point the finger at the United States, saying we’re responsible for these protests. We’re not. These are the Cuban people. They are speaking up. They are standing – they’re speaking out. They’re standing up. And a regime that doesn’t understand that and that has – lacks the confidence to allow the voices of its own people to be heard I think is making a very, very big mistake.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Let’s jump to Russia and the issue of cyberwarfare, which I think also then ends us up in China. (Laughter.) What is the United States prepared to do to make sure this doesn’t happen again? What’s next, when the next attack happens, to kind of send a message to Vladimir Putin that there’s a new sheriff in town?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, I think that message has been sent and, as necessary, will be sent again. The – President Biden addressed this directly with President Putin, both at the meeting in Geneva that I took part in as well as more recently on the phone. And one of the things that we’re seeing, as you know, is an increased use of so-called ransomware. And this is tremendously destructive. Overall, one-in-four Americans has been a victim of a cyber crime. About $40 billion lost on an annual basis. And ransomware in particular is increasingly dangerous. And what we’ve made clear to Russia, but to other countries around the world, is if you’re harboring individuals or organizations engaged in cyber crime, engaged in ransomware, that is unacceptable. And if you will not take action against them, we will.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Secretary Blinken, it’s Willie Geist. Good to see you this morning.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Hey, Willie.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> I want to ask you about Afghanistan. The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs, General Milley, said the other day that the Taliban has strategic momentum, that it may well over-run the country, though he didn’t concede that point just yet. So as the troops come home from Afghanistan, how should Americans be thinking about the mission there from our point of view? If it does become a training ground for terrorists again, if there does – some threat is posed to the United States, what will be the American reaction there?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b>Well, Willie, we’re determined that it not become a training ground for terrorism directed against the United States or our allies and partners. That’s exactly why we went there in the first place, which is important to remember. We were attacked on 9/11, we went to Afghanistan to get the folks who attacked us, to bring them to justice. Osama bin Laden was brought to justice 10 years ago, and the group, al-Qaida, responsible for those attacks has been dramatically diminished in terms of its capacity to attack anyone from Afghanistan. We’re going to make sure that we keep our eyes on that. If we see the threat re-emerging, we’re going to be in a position to take action against it. But that’s why we were there, and now we’re 20 years and a trillion dollars and thousands of Americans lost later in this – in that campaign. I think the reason we went there is what we have to keep the focus on, and we’ve largely succeeded in doing what we needed to do.</p>
<p>We do have deep concerns about the actions the Taliban is taking indicating that it may be trying to take the country by force, but were that to happen, Afghanistan would be a pariah state. It would not get the assistance that it’s looking for and that the Taliban says it wants if it has any responsibility for the country. It would not get the support from the international community that it says it wants. We’re actively engaged in diplomacy because there is no military solution to this conflict that’s been going on for more than 40 years in Afghanistan, and we’re working to try to bring that to an end.</p>
<p>But one other thing: We’re sustaining our support through our embassy, through other embassies for the Afghan people, and at the same time we’re working to make good on our commitment to those who helped us and put their lives on the line – interpreters, translators – they’re benefiting from a program called Special Immigrant Visa programs that allow them to seek visas to come to the United States. We are moving very, very rapidly ahead with that program.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>When you say “take action,” Mr. Secretary, is that airstrikes? Or can you see a world where American troops are back in Afghanistan?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b>Look, I don’t want to get into hypotheticals about where this might go in the future. What I can tell you, Willie, is that we’re going to make sure that we have the capacity to see if the terrorist threat from Afghanistan re-emerges and to be in a position to do something about it.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Mr. Secretary, a final question, and it’s not really a fun one, but I have to ask. We had a president for four years who openly admitted to getting dirt on political rivals from a foreign leader, meeting without notetakers with Vladimir Putin, having these meetings with Kim Jong-un, which were a joke at best. Geo-strategically, how much ground was lost during the Donald Trump presidency with his corrupt and undemocratic approach to foreign policy? Are we less secure, and if so, how much?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b>Well, Mika, happily, in my job, I don’t do politics. I’m focused on the future. But I can tell you this: Just a short while ago, the President traveled to Europe. He met with our G7 partners, with our NATO Allies, with our partners in the European Union, and then, of course, he met with Vladimir Putin. And he has asked us these first six months of the administration to focus first and foremost on revitalizing our relationships, our partnerships with allies, with partners. That’s exactly what we’ve done. And there was a very, very telling poll that came out during his trip. Across the democratic countries that we’ve been engaged with and that the President engaged with in Europe, on average, 75 percent of the people have confidence, trust in American leadership. That’s up from 17 percent a year ago. I think that speaks volumes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Secretary of State Antony Blinken, thank you so much for coming on the show this morning, and we look forward to hearing about the trip to India and the fight against COVID. Thank you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Michigan Governor Whitmer</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-michigan-governor-whitmer/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 13:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261572</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Governor Gretchen Whitmer last week about the case of U.S. citizen Danny Fenster, a journalist and Michigan native currently detained in Burma. Governor Whitmer expressed thanks for the State Department’s continued commitment to secure Fenster’s release. Secretary Blinken and Governor Whitmer also discussed Enbridge Energy’s Line 5, which crosses the U.S. border with Canada in Michigan and is the subject of litigation between the State of Michigan and Enbridge in U.S. domestic courts. Secretary Blinken noted that there is no formal bilateral process between the federal governments of the United States and Canada concerning Line 5.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Governor Gretchen Whitmer last week about the case of U.S. citizen Danny Fenster, a journalist and Michigan native currently detained in Burma. Governor Whitmer expressed thanks for the State Department’s continued commitment to secure Fenster’s release. Secretary Blinken and Governor Whitmer also discussed Enbridge Energy’s Line 5, which crosses the U.S. border with Canada in Michigan and is the subject of litigation between the State of Michigan and Enbridge in U.S. domestic courts. Secretary Blinken noted that there is no formal bilateral process between the federal governments of the United States and Canada concerning Line 5.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Travel to India and Kuwait</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-india-and-kuwait/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 13:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261568</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to New Delhi, India and Kuwait City, Kuwait July 26-29 to reaffirm the United States’ commitment to strengthening our partnerships and underscore cooperation on our shared priorities.</p>
<p>In New Delhi on July 28, Secretary Blinken will meet with External Affairs Minister Dr. S. Jaishankar and Prime Minister Narendra Modi to discuss a wide range of issues including continued cooperation on COVID-19 response efforts, Indo-Pacific engagement, shared regional security interests, shared democratic values, and addressing the climate crisis.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken will travel on July 28 to Kuwait City where he will meet with senior Kuwaiti officials to continue discussions of key bilateral issues that underscore the importance of our 60 years of diplomatic ties.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken will return to Washington, D.C. on July 29.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to New Delhi, India and Kuwait City, Kuwait July 26-29 to reaffirm the United States’ commitment to strengthening our partnerships and underscore cooperation on our shared priorities.</p>
<p>In New Delhi on July 28, Secretary Blinken will meet with External Affairs Minister Dr. S. Jaishankar and Prime Minister Narendra Modi to discuss a wide range of issues including continued cooperation on COVID-19 response efforts, Indo-Pacific engagement, shared regional security interests, shared democratic values, and addressing the climate crisis.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken will travel on July 28 to Kuwait City where he will meet with senior Kuwaiti officials to continue discussions of key bilateral issues that underscore the importance of our 60 years of diplomatic ties.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken will return to Washington, D.C. on July 29.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
