<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 13:07:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Kenyan Cabinet Secretary for Foreign Affairs Omamo</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-kenyan-cabinet-secretary-for-foreign-affairs-omamo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 22:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:‎</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Kenyan Cabinet Secretary for Foreign Affairs Raychelle Omamo.  Secretary Blinken and Cabinet Secretary Omamo reaffirmed the importance of the U.S.-Kenya strategic partnership, highlighting shared global priorities including responding to the COVID-19 pandemic, addressing climate change, and investing in democracy and security in Africa.  Secretary Blinken and Cabinet Secretary Omamo discussed the importance of Kenyan engagement on the ongoing crises in Ethiopia and South Sudan.  Secretary Blinken affirmed the United States’ commitment to maintain a strategic dialogue with Kenya.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:‎</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Kenyan Cabinet Secretary for Foreign Affairs Raychelle Omamo.  Secretary Blinken and Cabinet Secretary Omamo reaffirmed the importance of the U.S.-Kenya strategic partnership, highlighting shared global priorities including responding to the COVID-19 pandemic, addressing climate change, and investing in democracy and security in Africa.  Secretary Blinken and Cabinet Secretary Omamo discussed the importance of Kenyan engagement on the ongoing crises in Ethiopia and South Sudan.  Secretary Blinken affirmed the United States’ commitment to maintain a strategic dialogue with Kenya.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; July 16, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-july-16-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 22:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=260304</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:03 p.m. EST</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Good afternoon and Happy Friday. Thank you for joining today’s department press briefing. I have two updates at the top before I start taking your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-AFGHANISTAN1"></a> We are deeply saddened to hear that Reuters photojournalist Danish Siddiqui was killed while covering fighting in Afghanistan. Mr. Siddiqui was celebrated for his work on some of the world’s most urgent and challenging news stories and for creating striking images that conveyed a wealth of emotion and the face – and the human face behind the headlines. His brilliant reporting on the Rohingya refugee crisis earned him a Pulitzer Prize in 2018. Siddiqui’s death is a tremendous loss, not only for Reuters and for his media colleagues, but also for the rest of the world. Far too many journalists have been killed in Afghanistan. We continue to call for an end to the violence. A just and durable peace settlement is the only way forward in Afghanistan.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-COVID"></a> Next, a quick note here on the U.S. response to the COVID-19 pandemic: The Biden administration continues to send vaccines to countries all around the world. By Monday, we expect to deliver millions of vaccines to Bhutan, Nepal, Moldova, Costa Rica, Haiti, Laos, Sri Lanka, Fiji, the Philippines, Argentina, and Jordan. Additionally, in the partnership with the African Union and COVAX, the United States is proud to announce the donation of 25 million COVID-19 vaccines to 49 African countries. The first shipments, planned for the coming days, will head to Ethiopia, Djibouti, and Burkina Faso. We are making progress on this global vaccination effort each day and we will continue to update you as additional doses are shipped.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jenny Hansler to start us off, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-AFGHANISTAN2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thanks so much for doing this. I was wondering if you could provide us an update on the SIV operation to relocate these Afghans, and whether or not you’re considering expanding that pool out to women and minorities who may be at risk as well. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Jenny. So our immediate focus are on eligible and interested Afghan nationals and their families – and of course, that would include women and minorities who are vulnerable and at risk – who have supported the United States and our partners in Afghanistan and are in the SIV application pipeline. As it stands, there are approximately 20,000 Afghan principal applicants at some stage of the SIV process, and as of July of 2021, approximately 50 percent of these applicants are at the initial stage of the process and are pending applicant application. And out of that 20,000, approximately 10,000 of these applicants, they would need to take some action before the U.S. Government can begin processing their case.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Said Arikat.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina. First, I want to add my voice to mourning Danish Siddiqui. A tremendous loss, tremendous loss.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-ISPAL"></a> And second, two quick questions on the Palestinian issue. It is reported that Mr. Hady Amr has informed the Israelis that there is a tremendous crisis within the Palestinian Authority, especially an economic one, and asked them to help. Can you give us – can you update us on this, and what kind of help is he seeking?</p>
<p>And second, Jalina, very quickly, I mean, 2021 has been a really terrible year for the Palestinians. I mean, so far, according to B’Tselem, the Israeli human rights organization, 474 Palestinian-owned homes and structures have been destroyed, including 150 donor-funded ones, displacing about 656 people, including 259 children. My question is: When will the U.S. say – will say enough is enough on this, time to end it? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Said. To your first question, well, we don’t have – we don’t discuss private diplomatic conversations, so I don’t have anything further to add to you on that.</p>
<p>And to your second question, I’ll just continue to underscore from here that we know for a fact that President Biden, now obviously Secretary Blinken as well, have always said that the U.S. will center our foreign policy on human rights, and that has not changed. And we believe it is critical to refrain from any unilateral steps that increase tensions and make it more difficult to advance a negotiated two-state solution, and of course, this includes demolition.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Simon Lewis.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-AFGHANISTAN3"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for your comments about our colleague. I wanted to follow up on that, actually, since that’s something that’s happened in Afghanistan and kind of reflects the worsening security situation in the country. I was wondering, given that the U.S. is in the middle of a pullout of troops from the country, I wondered if you could comment on the worsening security situation. And do you – is this what was expected when the pullout happened, that the country would sort of descend into more violence and more chaos? And is that what you expect to continue to happen as this pullout continues? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Well, Simon, I will tell you that we will always call for peace and, of course, an ongoing end to the violence that plagues Afghanistan. We have urged both sides to, of course, engage in serious negotiations when it comes to a just and durable peace settlement, and outside of that I don’t have anything else to preview for you today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Eunjung Cho, and I apologize if I mispronounced your name.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-ASIA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you, Jalina. That was perfect. My name is Eunjung Cho with the Voice of America. Can you give us an update on Deputy Secretary Sherman&#8217;s trip to Asia? There are reports today quoting senior State Department official that her – she may visit China and that she may discuss North Korea with China. Is it in deputy secretary’s plans to discuss North Korea with China during her trip to Asia?</p>
<p>And my second question: The trilateral meeting among the vice foreign ministers of the U.S., South Korea, and Japan are being resumed after being suspended during the Trump administration. What does the State Department hope to achieve with the revival of this trilateral meeting?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks for your question. So what I&#8217;ll say is that the – Deputy Secretary Sherman will travel to the region. I don&#8217;t have anything else to go on beyond what we have in our readouts. I certainly don&#8217;t have any travel to announce at this time. If we do, we&#8217;ll certainly make those. And I certainly don&#8217;t want to get ahead of her meetings for her trip, but that&#8217;s all we’ll preview today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Rosiland Jordan.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-HONGKONG"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi, Jalina. Happy Friday. I wanted to get some more information about the advisory to U.S. businesses about doing any business in Hong Kong with any entities based there and the possible risks to their running afoul of U.S. law. Can you give more context on why the U.S. decided to issue this advisory now, and perhaps just as important, to issue sanctions, secondary sanctions against seven people who work in the office that essentially oversees Hong Kong?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Rosiland. I&#8217;ll start off by saying that the United States resolutely stands with the people in Hong Kong. And we&#8217;re promoting accountability with additional sanctions on officials connected with the undermining of Hong Kong&#8217;s autonomy as well as their democratic institutions and freedoms. And we&#8217;re also promoting transparency with a business advisory outlining some of the increased risks of doing business in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>And just to your specific question on sanctions, of course, yes, seven officials were sanctioned today for their actions threatening the peace, security, and stability and autonomy of Hong Kong. Anything beyond that will be issued in our statement online.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Endale Getahun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yes, Jalina, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you. Thank you so much for taking my call from KETO.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-ETHIOPIA"></a> I just wanted to follow up on your statement earlier regarding the COVID assistance to Africa. I just wanted to just get to the hotspot in Ethiopia. I know Ethiopian Government is using a – whatever in Tigray region. So how are you going to be verifying this assistance will be a benefit to Tigray region, for the COVID assistance?</p>
<p>And also, I have another follow-up, maybe if you can just touch up – do you have any statements from your embassy in Addis Ababa or the others for the Tigrayans (inaudible) in Addis Ababa and some of them have been detained and incarcerated in an undisclosed area with the Ethiopian Government, and at the same time there – another region, also there is a conflict (inaudible). So what’s your statements on the current situation in Ethiopia? Thank you for taking my call.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you for your questions. So the United States, of course, is gravely concerned by reports of ongoing hostilities in Tigray, and evidence of escalating military confluence – conflict in Tigray’s western and southern zones. There is, of course, significant risk that such conflict may expand outside of that region. All parties need to end the hostilities and pursue a negotiated ceasefire immediately. Escalating fire will only undermine critical ongoing efforts to deliver much-needed humanitarian relief to the famine-affected populations in Tigray.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Rich Edson.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hey, thanks, Jalina. I’m just wondering if I can get a response from you on the WHO’s director general saying that there needs to be more access within China to discover the origins of COVID and whether the U.S. views this as sort of the international community – an additional sense of it – pushing more pressure on the Chinese Government.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks for your question, Rich. I don’t have anything for you on that today, but happy to get back to you with any updates forthcoming.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Guita Aryan.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-IRAN"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi, Jalina. My question is about Iran. Demonstrations have snowballed, and starting from demonstrations against past-due salaries and wages to shortage of electricity and now shortage of water. Do you have any comment on that?</p>
<p>And then my second question is about the Vienna talks. At the end of the sixth round it was reported that the Iranians want guarantee from the U.S. that future administrations will not leave the JCPOA should they come to an agreement now. And now I’m seeing reports that they specifically want the agreement – should any future administration want to leave the agreement, that it should be taken up at the UN Security Council. Can you comment on that as well, please? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you. I won’t – I certainly won’t project or comment on any future administrations, but I’ll talk about the one for the time being. Of course, we haven’t gotten to the seventh round of talks yet, but as Secretary Blinken has noted, we are certainly committed to seeking a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA by both the United States and Iran. And if we succeed in doing so, we intend to build on that as a part of a comprehensive approach using a variety of policy tools to address nuclear and other issues of concern.</p>
<p>Now, your question on – to your first question, we’ve certainly seen the reports of Iran shortages and resulting protests, and we continue to urge the Iranian Government to support the Iranian people as they exercise their universal rights to freedom of expression as well as freedom of peaceful assembly.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Doug Byun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi. Can you hear?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hi, yes. I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Hi. Thanks for taking my question. I was just wondering if you have any updates on U.S. overtures to North Korea? I mean, has there been any direct or meaningful response from North Korea since Special Envoy Sung Kim reached out to them saying the United States is ready to meet with them anytime, anywhere? And I also have a short follow-up about the deputy secretary’s trip.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So I don’t have any updates to your first question, so while I still have you on the line, let’s take your second one, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sure. I was just wondering if Special Envoy Sung Kim would be joining the deputy secretary in Tokyo or Seoul since her trip is going to be somewhat focused on North Korea as well.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> I don’t have any updates to make about her trip. For anything further or for any other specific details, I would have to guide you to her announcement with those details.</p>
<p>Let’s take our final question from Owen Churchill.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-HONGKONG2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, yeah. Thanks so much for taking my question, Jalina. Going back to Hong Kong, a couple of questions on that. First of all, what would be your – what would be the State Department’s measure of success with these new sanctions and the business advisory? Are you anticipating any kind of change in Beijing’s behavior as a result of the actions?</p>
<p>And then secondly, we also understand that there were some calls on the administration from advocacy groups to roll out immigration measures to support those fleeing Hong Kong, like either offering asylum or relaxing immigration processes for those people. Can you give us an update on any – on the deliberations on that front, whether there will be any kind of executive action in that department? Thanks a lot.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So to answer both of your questions, I’ll just say that we stand with Hong Kongers against the PRC’s egregious policies and their actions as well. PRC and Hong Kong authorities wield the national security law and other legislation to make politically motivated arrests as well as prosecution of journalists, opposition politicians, activists, and peaceful protesters. These authorities have created an atmosphere of fear and censorship among the general populace.</p>
<p>So our measures today are in response to these and other actions by the PRC and Hong Kong authorities to undermine protected rights and freedoms as well as democratic institutions and the high degree of autonomy promised to Hong Kong. We will deliver all options to respond to the PRC’s further undermining of protected freedoms and Hong Kong’s high degree of autonomy. The United States supports the aspirations of people in Hong Kong to sustain the protected freedoms and rights that were promised to them in the Sino-British Joint Declaration, a binding international agreement.</p>
<p>That concludes today’s department briefing. Thank you so much for joining us today and have a great weekend ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:25 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:03 p.m. EST</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Good afternoon and Happy Friday. Thank you for joining today’s department press briefing. I have two updates at the top before I start taking your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-AFGHANISTAN1"></a> We are deeply saddened to hear that Reuters photojournalist Danish Siddiqui was killed while covering fighting in Afghanistan. Mr. Siddiqui was celebrated for his work on some of the world’s most urgent and challenging news stories and for creating striking images that conveyed a wealth of emotion and the face – and the human face behind the headlines. His brilliant reporting on the Rohingya refugee crisis earned him a Pulitzer Prize in 2018. Siddiqui’s death is a tremendous loss, not only for Reuters and for his media colleagues, but also for the rest of the world. Far too many journalists have been killed in Afghanistan. We continue to call for an end to the violence. A just and durable peace settlement is the only way forward in Afghanistan.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-COVID"></a> Next, a quick note here on the U.S. response to the COVID-19 pandemic: The Biden administration continues to send vaccines to countries all around the world. By Monday, we expect to deliver millions of vaccines to Bhutan, Nepal, Moldova, Costa Rica, Haiti, Laos, Sri Lanka, Fiji, the Philippines, Argentina, and Jordan. Additionally, in the partnership with the African Union and COVAX, the United States is proud to announce the donation of 25 million COVID-19 vaccines to 49 African countries. The first shipments, planned for the coming days, will head to Ethiopia, Djibouti, and Burkina Faso. We are making progress on this global vaccination effort each day and we will continue to update you as additional doses are shipped.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jenny Hansler to start us off, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-AFGHANISTAN2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thanks so much for doing this. I was wondering if you could provide us an update on the SIV operation to relocate these Afghans, and whether or not you’re considering expanding that pool out to women and minorities who may be at risk as well. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Jenny. So our immediate focus are on eligible and interested Afghan nationals and their families – and of course, that would include women and minorities who are vulnerable and at risk – who have supported the United States and our partners in Afghanistan and are in the SIV application pipeline. As it stands, there are approximately 20,000 Afghan principal applicants at some stage of the SIV process, and as of July of 2021, approximately 50 percent of these applicants are at the initial stage of the process and are pending applicant application. And out of that 20,000, approximately 10,000 of these applicants, they would need to take some action before the U.S. Government can begin processing their case.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Said Arikat.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina. First, I want to add my voice to mourning Danish Siddiqui. A tremendous loss, tremendous loss.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-ISPAL"></a> And second, two quick questions on the Palestinian issue. It is reported that Mr. Hady Amr has informed the Israelis that there is a tremendous crisis within the Palestinian Authority, especially an economic one, and asked them to help. Can you give us – can you update us on this, and what kind of help is he seeking?</p>
<p>And second, Jalina, very quickly, I mean, 2021 has been a really terrible year for the Palestinians. I mean, so far, according to B’Tselem, the Israeli human rights organization, 474 Palestinian-owned homes and structures have been destroyed, including 150 donor-funded ones, displacing about 656 people, including 259 children. My question is: When will the U.S. say – will say enough is enough on this, time to end it? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Said. To your first question, well, we don’t have – we don’t discuss private diplomatic conversations, so I don’t have anything further to add to you on that.</p>
<p>And to your second question, I’ll just continue to underscore from here that we know for a fact that President Biden, now obviously Secretary Blinken as well, have always said that the U.S. will center our foreign policy on human rights, and that has not changed. And we believe it is critical to refrain from any unilateral steps that increase tensions and make it more difficult to advance a negotiated two-state solution, and of course, this includes demolition.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Simon Lewis.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-AFGHANISTAN3"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for your comments about our colleague. I wanted to follow up on that, actually, since that’s something that’s happened in Afghanistan and kind of reflects the worsening security situation in the country. I was wondering, given that the U.S. is in the middle of a pullout of troops from the country, I wondered if you could comment on the worsening security situation. And do you – is this what was expected when the pullout happened, that the country would sort of descend into more violence and more chaos? And is that what you expect to continue to happen as this pullout continues? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Well, Simon, I will tell you that we will always call for peace and, of course, an ongoing end to the violence that plagues Afghanistan. We have urged both sides to, of course, engage in serious negotiations when it comes to a just and durable peace settlement, and outside of that I don’t have anything else to preview for you today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Eunjung Cho, and I apologize if I mispronounced your name.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-ASIA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you, Jalina. That was perfect. My name is Eunjung Cho with the Voice of America. Can you give us an update on Deputy Secretary Sherman&#8217;s trip to Asia? There are reports today quoting senior State Department official that her – she may visit China and that she may discuss North Korea with China. Is it in deputy secretary’s plans to discuss North Korea with China during her trip to Asia?</p>
<p>And my second question: The trilateral meeting among the vice foreign ministers of the U.S., South Korea, and Japan are being resumed after being suspended during the Trump administration. What does the State Department hope to achieve with the revival of this trilateral meeting?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks for your question. So what I&#8217;ll say is that the – Deputy Secretary Sherman will travel to the region. I don&#8217;t have anything else to go on beyond what we have in our readouts. I certainly don&#8217;t have any travel to announce at this time. If we do, we&#8217;ll certainly make those. And I certainly don&#8217;t want to get ahead of her meetings for her trip, but that&#8217;s all we’ll preview today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Rosiland Jordan.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-HONGKONG"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi, Jalina. Happy Friday. I wanted to get some more information about the advisory to U.S. businesses about doing any business in Hong Kong with any entities based there and the possible risks to their running afoul of U.S. law. Can you give more context on why the U.S. decided to issue this advisory now, and perhaps just as important, to issue sanctions, secondary sanctions against seven people who work in the office that essentially oversees Hong Kong?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Rosiland. I&#8217;ll start off by saying that the United States resolutely stands with the people in Hong Kong. And we&#8217;re promoting accountability with additional sanctions on officials connected with the undermining of Hong Kong&#8217;s autonomy as well as their democratic institutions and freedoms. And we&#8217;re also promoting transparency with a business advisory outlining some of the increased risks of doing business in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>And just to your specific question on sanctions, of course, yes, seven officials were sanctioned today for their actions threatening the peace, security, and stability and autonomy of Hong Kong. Anything beyond that will be issued in our statement online.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Endale Getahun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yes, Jalina, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you. Thank you so much for taking my call from KETO.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-ETHIOPIA"></a> I just wanted to follow up on your statement earlier regarding the COVID assistance to Africa. I just wanted to just get to the hotspot in Ethiopia. I know Ethiopian Government is using a – whatever in Tigray region. So how are you going to be verifying this assistance will be a benefit to Tigray region, for the COVID assistance?</p>
<p>And also, I have another follow-up, maybe if you can just touch up – do you have any statements from your embassy in Addis Ababa or the others for the Tigrayans (inaudible) in Addis Ababa and some of them have been detained and incarcerated in an undisclosed area with the Ethiopian Government, and at the same time there – another region, also there is a conflict (inaudible). So what’s your statements on the current situation in Ethiopia? Thank you for taking my call.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you for your questions. So the United States, of course, is gravely concerned by reports of ongoing hostilities in Tigray, and evidence of escalating military confluence – conflict in Tigray’s western and southern zones. There is, of course, significant risk that such conflict may expand outside of that region. All parties need to end the hostilities and pursue a negotiated ceasefire immediately. Escalating fire will only undermine critical ongoing efforts to deliver much-needed humanitarian relief to the famine-affected populations in Tigray.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Rich Edson.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hey, thanks, Jalina. I’m just wondering if I can get a response from you on the WHO’s director general saying that there needs to be more access within China to discover the origins of COVID and whether the U.S. views this as sort of the international community – an additional sense of it – pushing more pressure on the Chinese Government.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks for your question, Rich. I don’t have anything for you on that today, but happy to get back to you with any updates forthcoming.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Guita Aryan.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-IRAN"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi, Jalina. My question is about Iran. Demonstrations have snowballed, and starting from demonstrations against past-due salaries and wages to shortage of electricity and now shortage of water. Do you have any comment on that?</p>
<p>And then my second question is about the Vienna talks. At the end of the sixth round it was reported that the Iranians want guarantee from the U.S. that future administrations will not leave the JCPOA should they come to an agreement now. And now I’m seeing reports that they specifically want the agreement – should any future administration want to leave the agreement, that it should be taken up at the UN Security Council. Can you comment on that as well, please? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you. I won’t – I certainly won’t project or comment on any future administrations, but I’ll talk about the one for the time being. Of course, we haven’t gotten to the seventh round of talks yet, but as Secretary Blinken has noted, we are certainly committed to seeking a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA by both the United States and Iran. And if we succeed in doing so, we intend to build on that as a part of a comprehensive approach using a variety of policy tools to address nuclear and other issues of concern.</p>
<p>Now, your question on – to your first question, we’ve certainly seen the reports of Iran shortages and resulting protests, and we continue to urge the Iranian Government to support the Iranian people as they exercise their universal rights to freedom of expression as well as freedom of peaceful assembly.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Doug Byun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi. Can you hear?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hi, yes. I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Hi. Thanks for taking my question. I was just wondering if you have any updates on U.S. overtures to North Korea? I mean, has there been any direct or meaningful response from North Korea since Special Envoy Sung Kim reached out to them saying the United States is ready to meet with them anytime, anywhere? And I also have a short follow-up about the deputy secretary’s trip.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So I don’t have any updates to your first question, so while I still have you on the line, let’s take your second one, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sure. I was just wondering if Special Envoy Sung Kim would be joining the deputy secretary in Tokyo or Seoul since her trip is going to be somewhat focused on North Korea as well.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> I don’t have any updates to make about her trip. For anything further or for any other specific details, I would have to guide you to her announcement with those details.</p>
<p>Let’s take our final question from Owen Churchill.</p>
<p><a id="post-260304-HONGKONG2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, yeah. Thanks so much for taking my question, Jalina. Going back to Hong Kong, a couple of questions on that. First of all, what would be your – what would be the State Department’s measure of success with these new sanctions and the business advisory? Are you anticipating any kind of change in Beijing’s behavior as a result of the actions?</p>
<p>And then secondly, we also understand that there were some calls on the administration from advocacy groups to roll out immigration measures to support those fleeing Hong Kong, like either offering asylum or relaxing immigration processes for those people. Can you give us an update on any – on the deliberations on that front, whether there will be any kind of executive action in that department? Thanks a lot.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So to answer both of your questions, I’ll just say that we stand with Hong Kongers against the PRC’s egregious policies and their actions as well. PRC and Hong Kong authorities wield the national security law and other legislation to make politically motivated arrests as well as prosecution of journalists, opposition politicians, activists, and peaceful protesters. These authorities have created an atmosphere of fear and censorship among the general populace.</p>
<p>So our measures today are in response to these and other actions by the PRC and Hong Kong authorities to undermine protected rights and freedoms as well as democratic institutions and the high degree of autonomy promised to Hong Kong. We will deliver all options to respond to the PRC’s further undermining of protected freedoms and Hong Kong’s high degree of autonomy. The United States supports the aspirations of people in Hong Kong to sustain the protected freedoms and rights that were promised to them in the Sino-British Joint Declaration, a binding international agreement.</p>
<p>That concludes today’s department briefing. Thank you so much for joining us today and have a great weekend ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:25 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Kenyan Cabinet Secretary for Foreign Affairs Ambassador Raychelle Omamo Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-kenyan-cabinet-secretary-for-foreign-affairs-ambassador-raychelle-omamo-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 21:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260297</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon.  It is a real pleasure to receive Foreign Minister Omamo here at the White House – excuse me, at the State Department.  We’ll head to the White House later.  We had the wonderful opportunity to do a virtual visit that you hosted a few months ago, but there’s nothing like the real thing, so I’m really grateful to have you here.</p>
<p>We have a very important strategic partnership with Kenya.  We are working together across the continent and beyond, indeed, when you were on the UN Security Council working on global issues, working on regional issues.  We have a lot to talk about.  And of course, we’re very pleased to have been able to help with COVID and vaccines.  There are 1.7 million vaccines that are en route soon to Kenya.  But especially we are grateful for the strategic partnership that we have.  Much work to be done on the continent, on beyond, and I’m looking forward to getting down to work with you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER OMAMO:</strong>  Yes, thank you very much.  Could I just express my gratitude and honor to be able to be visiting you today in person and in your office.  This is my first visit to the State Department as the minister of foreign affairs, and it gives us an opportunity really to reaffirm the deep and longstanding friendship we have between our two countries.</p>
<p>We work together on a variety of issues both nationally and regionally and globally.  We both believe in the same principles, the same values of democracy and the idea that there is hope in every person and that we can surmount our challenges through solidarity, through working together, and through moving forward, especially in the aftermath of COVID-19.</p>
<p>We thank you for the vaccine donation.  We thank you for standing with us throughout this difficult period and for emphasizing that there is still hope and that all countries can build back better.  We can build back better on our continent, and we can do so in partnership with friends.  So thank you so much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Great to have you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, has there been an agreement on the Kabul airport (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’re working on everything.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER OMAMO:</strong>  Thank you very much.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon.  It is a real pleasure to receive Foreign Minister Omamo here at the White House – excuse me, at the State Department.  We’ll head to the White House later.  We had the wonderful opportunity to do a virtual visit that you hosted a few months ago, but there’s nothing like the real thing, so I’m really grateful to have you here.</p>
<p>We have a very important strategic partnership with Kenya.  We are working together across the continent and beyond, indeed, when you were on the UN Security Council working on global issues, working on regional issues.  We have a lot to talk about.  And of course, we’re very pleased to have been able to help with COVID and vaccines.  There are 1.7 million vaccines that are en route soon to Kenya.  But especially we are grateful for the strategic partnership that we have.  Much work to be done on the continent, on beyond, and I’m looking forward to getting down to work with you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER OMAMO:</strong>  Yes, thank you very much.  Could I just express my gratitude and honor to be able to be visiting you today in person and in your office.  This is my first visit to the State Department as the minister of foreign affairs, and it gives us an opportunity really to reaffirm the deep and longstanding friendship we have between our two countries.</p>
<p>We work together on a variety of issues both nationally and regionally and globally.  We both believe in the same principles, the same values of democracy and the idea that there is hope in every person and that we can surmount our challenges through solidarity, through working together, and through moving forward, especially in the aftermath of COVID-19.</p>
<p>We thank you for the vaccine donation.  We thank you for standing with us throughout this difficult period and for emphasizing that there is still hope and that all countries can build back better.  We can build back better on our continent, and we can do so in partnership with friends.  So thank you so much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Great to have you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, has there been an agreement on the Kabul airport (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’re working on everything.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER OMAMO:</strong>  Thank you very much.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Chilean Foreign Minister Allamand</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-chilean-foreign-minister-allamand/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 21:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260279</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Chilean Foreign Minister Andres Allamand in Washington, D.C.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Allamand discussed ongoing collaboration between the United States and Chile to combat COVID-19, advance economic ties, and expand environmental cooperation, noting Chile’s impressive track record as a strong advocate of environmental justice and climate action.</p>
<p>The Secretary and the Foreign Minister also stressed that bilateral and regional cooperation is essential to addressing the Hemisphere&#8217;s shared challenges and promoting democracy in the region.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Chilean Foreign Minister Andres Allamand in Washington, D.C.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Allamand discussed ongoing collaboration between the United States and Chile to combat COVID-19, advance economic ties, and expand environmental cooperation, noting Chile’s impressive track record as a strong advocate of environmental justice and climate action.</p>
<p>The Secretary and the Foreign Minister also stressed that bilateral and regional cooperation is essential to addressing the Hemisphere&#8217;s shared challenges and promoting democracy in the region.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with New Zealand Secretary Chris Seed</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-new-zealand-secretary-chris-seed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 19:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260201</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with New Zealand Chief Executive and Secretary of Foreign Affairs and Trade Chris Seed today.  The Deputy Secretary and Secretary Seed affirmed our strong partnership is rooted in our shared democratic values.  The Deputy Secretary congratulated Secretary Seed on a successful Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum hosted by New Zealand under difficult circumstances, and the leaders discussed the APEC Informal Leaders’ Retreat on July 16 hosted by New Zealand Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern with President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. participating.  The leaders promised close cooperation to fight climate change, recover from COVID-19, strengthen multilateral organizations and the international rules-based order, support Pacific Island countries, and promote human rights, the rule of law, and regional stability.  Together the United States and New Zealand will continue to tackle the greatest challenges confronting our world in order to ensure a free, open, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with New Zealand Chief Executive and Secretary of Foreign Affairs and Trade Chris Seed today.  The Deputy Secretary and Secretary Seed affirmed our strong partnership is rooted in our shared democratic values.  The Deputy Secretary congratulated Secretary Seed on a successful Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum hosted by New Zealand under difficult circumstances, and the leaders discussed the APEC Informal Leaders’ Retreat on July 16 hosted by New Zealand Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern with President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. participating.  The leaders promised close cooperation to fight climate change, recover from COVID-19, strengthen multilateral organizations and the international rules-based order, support Pacific Island countries, and promote human rights, the rule of law, and regional stability.  Together the United States and New Zealand will continue to tackle the greatest challenges confronting our world in order to ensure a free, open, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Chilean Foreign Minister Andres Allamand Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-chilean-foreign-minister-andres-allamand-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 18:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260177</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Good afternoon.  It is a real pleasure to have Foreign Minister Allamand here.  Andres and I have had the opportunity to speak, but now we have the opportunity to spend some time together face-to-face with our teams.  And for the United States and for me, this is especially welcome because Chile is such an important partner for the United States.</p>
<p>We are working together across virtually all of the major issues of our time that are having a real impact on the lives of our citizens: of course, COVID-19, where Chile has done, I think, remarkable work; climate change, where Chile has been a leader; and of course, our shared commitment to democracy and human rights in our region and beyond.  So there’s a lot to talk about, a strong agenda that we have, and I am very, very pleased to have you here.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER ALLAMAND:</strong>  Thank you.  I want to thank you very much.  I want to thank Secretary Blinken for this opportunity to strengthen the very deep, profound, and complete bilateral relations between Chile and the U.S.  As he said, we have very strong and shared commitments towards democracy, human rights.  For instance, all the issues facing how to tackle climate change, that is an issue we share with the administration.</p>
<p>And of course, it’s also a great opportunity to take a look at the state of democracy and human rights in the region, see together how we’re going to all be able to work in cooperation in terms of the recovery, the economic recovery post-COVID-19.  That, of course, is something very, very important.</p>
<p>And I will have the opportunity, of course, to show Secretary Blinken some of the advances that Chile is doing, for instance, in a very important field as green hydrogen.  So we have a fantastic opportunity to have this conversation.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you all very much.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Good afternoon.  It is a real pleasure to have Foreign Minister Allamand here.  Andres and I have had the opportunity to speak, but now we have the opportunity to spend some time together face-to-face with our teams.  And for the United States and for me, this is especially welcome because Chile is such an important partner for the United States.</p>
<p>We are working together across virtually all of the major issues of our time that are having a real impact on the lives of our citizens: of course, COVID-19, where Chile has done, I think, remarkable work; climate change, where Chile has been a leader; and of course, our shared commitment to democracy and human rights in our region and beyond.  So there’s a lot to talk about, a strong agenda that we have, and I am very, very pleased to have you here.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER ALLAMAND:</strong>  Thank you.  I want to thank you very much.  I want to thank Secretary Blinken for this opportunity to strengthen the very deep, profound, and complete bilateral relations between Chile and the U.S.  As he said, we have very strong and shared commitments towards democracy, human rights.  For instance, all the issues facing how to tackle climate change, that is an issue we share with the administration.</p>
<p>And of course, it’s also a great opportunity to take a look at the state of democracy and human rights in the region, see together how we’re going to all be able to work in cooperation in terms of the recovery, the economic recovery post-COVID-19.  That, of course, is something very, very important.</p>
<p>And I will have the opportunity, of course, to show Secretary Blinken some of the advances that Chile is doing, for instance, in a very important field as green hydrogen.  So we have a fantastic opportunity to have this conversation.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you all very much.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry Meetings in Moscow, Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-presidential-envoy-for-climate-john-kerry-meetings-in-moscow-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 18:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260118</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry traveled to Moscow, Russia, July 12-15, 2021.  While in Moscow, he met with Russian Foreign Minister Lavrov, Special Presidential Representative on Climate Issues Edelgeriyev, Special Presidential Representative for Relations with International Organizations Chubais, Deputy Prime Minister Chernyshenko, Russian State Duma Deputy Fetisov, and business representatives to discuss the urgency and seriousness of the climate crisis and efforts to increase ambition, especially in the next decade and on the road to Glasgow and beyond.  Special Presidential Envoy Kerry also had a phone call with Russian President Putin and issued a Joint Statement on the Climate Challenge with Special Presidential Representative on Climate Issues Edelgeriyev.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry traveled to Moscow, Russia, July 12-15, 2021.  While in Moscow, he met with Russian Foreign Minister Lavrov, Special Presidential Representative on Climate Issues Edelgeriyev, Special Presidential Representative for Relations with International Organizations Chubais, Deputy Prime Minister Chernyshenko, Russian State Duma Deputy Fetisov, and business representatives to discuss the urgency and seriousness of the climate crisis and efforts to increase ambition, especially in the next decade and on the road to Glasgow and beyond.  Special Presidential Envoy Kerry also had a phone call with Russian President Putin and issued a Joint Statement on the Climate Challenge with Special Presidential Representative on Climate Issues Edelgeriyev.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement of the C5+1 on the International Conference “Central and South Asia: Regional Connectivity. Challenges and Opportunities”</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-of-the-c51-on-the-international-conference-central-and-south-asia-regional-connectivity-challenges-and-opportunities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 16:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=259967</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was adopted by the Governments of the Republic of Kazakhstan, the Kyrgyz Republic, the Republic of Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, the Republic of Uzbekistan, and the United States of America, on the occasion of the International Conference, “Central and South Asia: Regional Connectivity. Challenges and Opportunities,” held in Tashkent, Uzbekistan July 15-16, 2021.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Begin Text:</p>
<p>Delegations of the C5+1 – the Republic of Kazakhstan, the Kyrgyz Republic, the Republic of Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, the Republic of Uzbekistan, and the United States of America – participated in the July 15-16, 2021 International Conference on “Central and South Asia: Regional Connectivity. Challenges and Opportunities” in Tashkent.</p>
<p>The C5+1 countries affirm their commitment to enhancing engagement through our regional diplomatic platform and seeking opportunities to strengthen connectivity between the Central and South Asian regions via trade, transport, and energy links. The C5+1 recognizes that increased connectivity supports its shared goal of a prosperous and secure Central Asia. Visionary ideas for Central Asia’s economic growth and closer ties to the economies of South Asia also reinforce the C5+1’s commitment to strengthening the region’s security and stability, including through Afghan peace negotiations.</p>
<p>The C5+1 endeavors to build upon the collaborative progress it has made on connectivity, including to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Modernize infrastructure and transit potential in Central Asia, including through the implementation of investment projects;</li>
<li>Promote increased regional cooperation in support of transboundary business-to-business connections and people-to-people exchanges;</li>
<li>Improve energy sector connectivity and performance, including to expand and effectively integrate renewables;</li>
<li>Meet and strengthen goals on climate adaptation, air quality, and water cooperation and protect those most vulnerable to the impacts of climate change;</li>
<li>Uphold human rights and freedoms, further strengthen the rule of law and good governance, based on universal human values and the historical, cultural, civilizational, and spiritual identity of the people of South and Central Asia, restore cultural and humanitarian ties, and promote the inclusion of all people, across all efforts, to support the region’s sustainable economic development<em>;</em></li>
<li>Ease trade, transport, and communication between South and Central Asia, including through Afghanistan;</li>
<li>Create stable and prosperous conditions favorable to the Afghan peace process, including reaffirming to all parties: the urgency of substantive negotiations on a political settlement; that the only path to a just and durable peace is through a negotiated political settlement that results in an inclusive political system and respects the fundamental rights of all Afghans; that there is no support for the imposition by force of a new government in Afghanistan; and that terrorists and third party forces must never be allowed to use Afghan territory to threaten or attack the C5+1 countries or any other country;</li>
<li>Advance cooperation with Afghanistan across security, energy, economic, trade, cultural, and other lines of effort; and,</li>
<li>Cooperate to address challenges and threats to regional security, prosperity, and stability.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was adopted by the Governments of the Republic of Kazakhstan, the Kyrgyz Republic, the Republic of Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, the Republic of Uzbekistan, and the United States of America, on the occasion of the International Conference, “Central and South Asia: Regional Connectivity. Challenges and Opportunities,” held in Tashkent, Uzbekistan July 15-16, 2021.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Begin Text:</p>
<p>Delegations of the C5+1 – the Republic of Kazakhstan, the Kyrgyz Republic, the Republic of Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, the Republic of Uzbekistan, and the United States of America – participated in the July 15-16, 2021 International Conference on “Central and South Asia: Regional Connectivity. Challenges and Opportunities” in Tashkent.</p>
<p>The C5+1 countries affirm their commitment to enhancing engagement through our regional diplomatic platform and seeking opportunities to strengthen connectivity between the Central and South Asian regions via trade, transport, and energy links. The C5+1 recognizes that increased connectivity supports its shared goal of a prosperous and secure Central Asia. Visionary ideas for Central Asia’s economic growth and closer ties to the economies of South Asia also reinforce the C5+1’s commitment to strengthening the region’s security and stability, including through Afghan peace negotiations.</p>
<p>The C5+1 endeavors to build upon the collaborative progress it has made on connectivity, including to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Modernize infrastructure and transit potential in Central Asia, including through the implementation of investment projects;</li>
<li>Promote increased regional cooperation in support of transboundary business-to-business connections and people-to-people exchanges;</li>
<li>Improve energy sector connectivity and performance, including to expand and effectively integrate renewables;</li>
<li>Meet and strengthen goals on climate adaptation, air quality, and water cooperation and protect those most vulnerable to the impacts of climate change;</li>
<li>Uphold human rights and freedoms, further strengthen the rule of law and good governance, based on universal human values and the historical, cultural, civilizational, and spiritual identity of the people of South and Central Asia, restore cultural and humanitarian ties, and promote the inclusion of all people, across all efforts, to support the region’s sustainable economic development<em>;</em></li>
<li>Ease trade, transport, and communication between South and Central Asia, including through Afghanistan;</li>
<li>Create stable and prosperous conditions favorable to the Afghan peace process, including reaffirming to all parties: the urgency of substantive negotiations on a political settlement; that the only path to a just and durable peace is through a negotiated political settlement that results in an inclusive political system and respects the fundamental rights of all Afghans; that there is no support for the imposition by force of a new government in Afghanistan; and that terrorists and third party forces must never be allowed to use Afghan territory to threaten or attack the C5+1 countries or any other country;</li>
<li>Advance cooperation with Afghanistan across security, energy, economic, trade, cultural, and other lines of effort; and,</li>
<li>Cooperate to address challenges and threats to regional security, prosperity, and stability.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issuance of a Hong Kong Business Advisory</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/issuance-of-a-hong-kong-business-advisory/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 15:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=259950</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On July 16, the U.S. Department of State, along with the U.S. Department of the Treasury, the U.S. Department of Commerce, and the U.S. Department of Homeland Security, issued a <a href="https://www.state.gov/risks-and-considerations-for-businesses-operating-in-hong-kong/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MTYuNDMzMDY1MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3Yvcmlza3MtYW5kLWNvbnNpZGVyYXRpb25zLWZvci1idXNpbmVzc2VzLW9wZXJhdGluZy1pbi1ob25nLWtvbmcvIn0.fD8__wQf4hPE5ZH7G7eBgr7NQDdcBBkJUEPXKQgT9DQ/s/1039202793/br/109441528434-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1626536328855000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFMIs2XUnCWxtMSC0IOVu6FJ9YVog">business advisory</a> to caution U.S. businesses about emerging risks to their operations and activities in Hong Kong. Many of these risks stem from the implementation of the Law of the People&#8217;s Republic of China (PRC) on Safeguarding National Security in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, also known as the National Security Law (NSL), and other recent legislative changes.</p>
<p>Developments over the last year in Hong Kong present clear operational, financial, legal, and reputational risks for multinational firms. This business advisory provides companies with information that can assist them in making informed business decisions and properly assessing risk.</p>
<p>The policies which the PRC government and the Government of Hong Kong have implemented undermine the legal and regulatory environment that is critical for individuals and businesses to operate freely and with legal certainty in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Businesses should be aware that the risks faced in mainland China are now increasingly present in Hong Kong. The National Security Law and actions taken by PRC and Hong Kong authorities may negatively affect their staff, finances, legal compliance, reputation, and operations.</p>
<p>The advisory highlights the following:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Businesses operating in Hong Kong, as well as individuals and businesses conducting business on their behalf, are subject to the laws of Hong Kong, including the National Security Law. Foreign nationals, including one U.S. citizen, have been arrested under the NSL.</em></li>
<li><em>Businesses face risks associated with electronic surveillance without warrants and the surrender of corporate and customer data to authorities.</em></li>
<li><em>Businesses that rely on a free and open press may face restricted access to information.</em></li>
<li><em>Individuals and entities should be aware of potential consequences of certain types of engagement with sanctioned individuals or entities.</em></li>
<li><em>Businesses operating in Hong Kong may face heightened risks and uncertainty related to PRC retaliation against companies that comply with sanctions imposed by the United States and other countries, including through enforcement of the PRC’s Countering Foreign Sanctions Law.</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Businesses with potential exposure should be aware of the potential reputational, economic, and legal risks of maintaining a presence or staff in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>In order to mitigate reputational and other risks, businesses should apply industry due diligence policies and procedures to address applicable and identified risks.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On July 16, the U.S. Department of State, along with the U.S. Department of the Treasury, the U.S. Department of Commerce, and the U.S. Department of Homeland Security, issued a <a href="https://www.state.gov/risks-and-considerations-for-businesses-operating-in-hong-kong/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MTYuNDMzMDY1MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3Yvcmlza3MtYW5kLWNvbnNpZGVyYXRpb25zLWZvci1idXNpbmVzc2VzLW9wZXJhdGluZy1pbi1ob25nLWtvbmcvIn0.fD8__wQf4hPE5ZH7G7eBgr7NQDdcBBkJUEPXKQgT9DQ/s/1039202793/br/109441528434-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1626536328855000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFMIs2XUnCWxtMSC0IOVu6FJ9YVog">business advisory</a> to caution U.S. businesses about emerging risks to their operations and activities in Hong Kong. Many of these risks stem from the implementation of the Law of the People&#8217;s Republic of China (PRC) on Safeguarding National Security in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, also known as the National Security Law (NSL), and other recent legislative changes.</p>
<p>Developments over the last year in Hong Kong present clear operational, financial, legal, and reputational risks for multinational firms. This business advisory provides companies with information that can assist them in making informed business decisions and properly assessing risk.</p>
<p>The policies which the PRC government and the Government of Hong Kong have implemented undermine the legal and regulatory environment that is critical for individuals and businesses to operate freely and with legal certainty in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Businesses should be aware that the risks faced in mainland China are now increasingly present in Hong Kong. The National Security Law and actions taken by PRC and Hong Kong authorities may negatively affect their staff, finances, legal compliance, reputation, and operations.</p>
<p>The advisory highlights the following:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Businesses operating in Hong Kong, as well as individuals and businesses conducting business on their behalf, are subject to the laws of Hong Kong, including the National Security Law. Foreign nationals, including one U.S. citizen, have been arrested under the NSL.</em></li>
<li><em>Businesses face risks associated with electronic surveillance without warrants and the surrender of corporate and customer data to authorities.</em></li>
<li><em>Businesses that rely on a free and open press may face restricted access to information.</em></li>
<li><em>Individuals and entities should be aware of potential consequences of certain types of engagement with sanctioned individuals or entities.</em></li>
<li><em>Businesses operating in Hong Kong may face heightened risks and uncertainty related to PRC retaliation against companies that comply with sanctions imposed by the United States and other countries, including through enforcement of the PRC’s Countering Foreign Sanctions Law.</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Businesses with potential exposure should be aware of the potential reputational, economic, and legal risks of maintaining a presence or staff in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>In order to mitigate reputational and other risks, businesses should apply industry due diligence policies and procedures to address applicable and identified risks.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marking One Year of Hong Kong’s National Security Law</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/marking-one-year-of-hong-kongs-national-security-law/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 15:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=259820</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Over the past year, People’s Republic of China (PRC) and Hong Kong officials have systematically undermined Hong Kong’s democratic <wbr />institutions, delayed elections, disqualified elected lawmakers from office, and forced officials to take loyalty oaths to keep their jobs.  Since protests began in 2019, local authorities have arrested thousands for speaking out against government policies with which they disagreed, including for their social media posts and for attending vigils.  Journalists have been arrested simply for doing their jobs in reporting on the government’s activities and repressive efforts against protesters.  Hong Kong authorities have mounted a persistent and politically motivated campaign against the free press, imprisoned <em>Apple Daily</em> founder Jimmy Lai, and forced the closure of that publication – a bastion of independent reporting.  Beijing has chipped away at Hong Kong’s reputation of <wbr />accountable, transparent governance and respect for individual freedoms, and <wbr />has broken its promise to leave Hong Kong’s high degree of autonomy unchanged for 50 years.</p>
<p>We will continue to stand up for the rights and freedoms guaranteed to people in Hong Kong by the Sino-British Joint Declaration and the Basic Law.  In the face of Beijing’s decisions over the past year that have stifled the democratic aspirations of people in Hong Kong, we are taking action.  Today we send a clear message that the United States resolutely stands with Hong Kongers.</p>
<p><strong>Promoting Accountability:  </strong>The Department of State has designated Chen Dong, Yang Jianping, Qiu Hong, Lu Xinning, Tan Tieniu, He Jing, and Yin Zonghua, who are Deputy Directors of the Liaison Office of the Central People’s Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (LOCPG).  The LOCPG is the PRC’s main platform for projecting its influence in Hong Kong and has repeatedly undermined the high degree of autonomy promised for Hong Kong in the Sino – British Joint declaration. The seven officials are being designated under Executive Order 13936.</p>
<p><strong>Transparency:  </strong>Hong Kong’s business environment has deteriorated in the past year.  The many legal, financial, operational, and reputational risks long present in mainland China are now increasingly prevalent in Hong Kong.  A healthy business and investment climate requires a transparent regulatory framework and adherence to the rule of law.  Today, the Department of State, together with the Department of Commerce, the Department of Homeland Security, and the Department of the Treasury, released a <a href="https://www.state.gov/risks-and-considerations-for-businesses-operating-in-hong-kong/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MTYuNDMzMDU2MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3Yvcmlza3MtYW5kLWNvbnNpZGVyYXRpb25zLWZvci1idXNpbmVzc2VzLW9wZXJhdGluZy1pbi1ob25nLWtvbmcvIn0.WMzMcPnWSjxXqKMU3F9ypPhhJK-B_12EK7tP3Kcr-38/s/1039202793/br/109440623462-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1626535512298000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEw_vwTjBH_9urEqCFSNvwrw2ytVA">Business Advisory </a>warning of increased risks for businesses in Hong Kong.  These risks include those introduced by the National Security Law and other new legislation, potential electronic surveillance and lack of data privacy, reduced access to information, and potential retaliation <wbr />against companies for their compliance with U.S. sanctions.  The business advisory outlines these emerging risks to inform U.S. individuals and businesses and recommends increased awareness and due diligence.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Over the past year, People’s Republic of China (PRC) and Hong Kong officials have systematically undermined Hong Kong’s democratic <wbr />institutions, delayed elections, disqualified elected lawmakers from office, and forced officials to take loyalty oaths to keep their jobs.  Since protests began in 2019, local authorities have arrested thousands for speaking out against government policies with which they disagreed, including for their social media posts and for attending vigils.  Journalists have been arrested simply for doing their jobs in reporting on the government’s activities and repressive efforts against protesters.  Hong Kong authorities have mounted a persistent and politically motivated campaign against the free press, imprisoned <em>Apple Daily</em> founder Jimmy Lai, and forced the closure of that publication – a bastion of independent reporting.  Beijing has chipped away at Hong Kong’s reputation of <wbr />accountable, transparent governance and respect for individual freedoms, and <wbr />has broken its promise to leave Hong Kong’s high degree of autonomy unchanged for 50 years.</p>
<p>We will continue to stand up for the rights and freedoms guaranteed to people in Hong Kong by the Sino-British Joint Declaration and the Basic Law.  In the face of Beijing’s decisions over the past year that have stifled the democratic aspirations of people in Hong Kong, we are taking action.  Today we send a clear message that the United States resolutely stands with Hong Kongers.</p>
<p><strong>Promoting Accountability:  </strong>The Department of State has designated Chen Dong, Yang Jianping, Qiu Hong, Lu Xinning, Tan Tieniu, He Jing, and Yin Zonghua, who are Deputy Directors of the Liaison Office of the Central People’s Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (LOCPG).  The LOCPG is the PRC’s main platform for projecting its influence in Hong Kong and has repeatedly undermined the high degree of autonomy promised for Hong Kong in the Sino – British Joint declaration. The seven officials are being designated under Executive Order 13936.</p>
<p><strong>Transparency:  </strong>Hong Kong’s business environment has deteriorated in the past year.  The many legal, financial, operational, and reputational risks long present in mainland China are now increasingly prevalent in Hong Kong.  A healthy business and investment climate requires a transparent regulatory framework and adherence to the rule of law.  Today, the Department of State, together with the Department of Commerce, the Department of Homeland Security, and the Department of the Treasury, released a <a href="https://www.state.gov/risks-and-considerations-for-businesses-operating-in-hong-kong/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MTYuNDMzMDU2MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3Yvcmlza3MtYW5kLWNvbnNpZGVyYXRpb25zLWZvci1idXNpbmVzc2VzLW9wZXJhdGluZy1pbi1ob25nLWtvbmcvIn0.WMzMcPnWSjxXqKMU3F9ypPhhJK-B_12EK7tP3Kcr-38/s/1039202793/br/109440623462-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1626535512298000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEw_vwTjBH_9urEqCFSNvwrw2ytVA">Business Advisory </a>warning of increased risks for businesses in Hong Kong.  These risks include those introduced by the National Security Law and other new legislation, potential electronic surveillance and lack of data privacy, reduced access to information, and potential retaliation <wbr />against companies for their compliance with U.S. sanctions.  The business advisory outlines these emerging risks to inform U.S. individuals and businesses and recommends increased awareness and due diligence.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
