<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 23:32:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>U.S.-EU Consultations Underscore Shared Commitment to Human Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-eu-consultations-underscore-shared-commitment-to-human-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 23:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=328953</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, Acting Assistant Secretary for Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor Lisa Peterson hosted the 2022 U.S.-EU Human Rights Consultations in Washington, D.C.  EU Special Representative for Human Rights Eamon Gilmore led the European Union delegation for this series of meetings.</p>
<p>The United States and the European Union reaffirmed their strong commitment to the transatlantic partnership and discussed challenges to democracy and human rights around the world, emphasizing the need to hold the Russian Federation accountable for its war of aggression in Ukraine and the importance of cooperation in effectively promoting respect for human rights, democracy, and the rule of law.</p>
<p>Throughout the day, State Department and EU officials covered a range of human rights issues present in Europe, Asia, Africa, and Latin America.  Discussions also focused on U.S.-EU cooperation in multilateral fora and on issues pertaining to technology and human rights, business and human rights, disability rights, and protection of underrepresented communities – including historical racially and ethnically marginalized communities, LGBTQI+ persons, and women and girls.  Participants also discussed efforts to defend against authoritarianism, promote respect for human rights, and fight corruption in the Summit for Democracy’s Year of Action.</p>
<p>Against the backdrop of Putin’s unprovoked and unjust war of choice against Ukraine, the discussions demonstrated that the transatlantic alliance is strong and continues to address human rights challenges at home and abroad.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:%20DRL-Press@state.gov">DRL-Press@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, Acting Assistant Secretary for Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor Lisa Peterson hosted the 2022 U.S.-EU Human Rights Consultations in Washington, D.C.  EU Special Representative for Human Rights Eamon Gilmore led the European Union delegation for this series of meetings.</p>
<p>The United States and the European Union reaffirmed their strong commitment to the transatlantic partnership and discussed challenges to democracy and human rights around the world, emphasizing the need to hold the Russian Federation accountable for its war of aggression in Ukraine and the importance of cooperation in effectively promoting respect for human rights, democracy, and the rule of law.</p>
<p>Throughout the day, State Department and EU officials covered a range of human rights issues present in Europe, Asia, Africa, and Latin America.  Discussions also focused on U.S.-EU cooperation in multilateral fora and on issues pertaining to technology and human rights, business and human rights, disability rights, and protection of underrepresented communities – including historical racially and ethnically marginalized communities, LGBTQI+ persons, and women and girls.  Participants also discussed efforts to defend against authoritarianism, promote respect for human rights, and fight corruption in the Summit for Democracy’s Year of Action.</p>
<p>Against the backdrop of Putin’s unprovoked and unjust war of choice against Ukraine, the discussions demonstrated that the transatlantic alliance is strong and continues to address human rights challenges at home and abroad.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:%20DRL-Press@state.gov">DRL-Press@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Briefing with Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brian P. McKeon, U.S. Agency for International Development Deputy Administrator for Management and Resources Paloma Adams-Allen, and Experts On the Administration’s Budget Request for the Department of State and USAID for Fiscal Year 2023</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-with-deputy-secretary-of-state-for-management-and-resources-brian-p-mckeon-u-s-agency-for-international-development-deputy-administrator-for-management-and-resources-paloma-adams-allen-an/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 23:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=328950</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:  </strong>Thank you, Operator.  Here just now, I’d like to thank everyone for joining us today for this briefing on the President’s Fiscal Year 2023 Budget Request for both the U.S. Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development.  As a quick reminder here at the top, we are on the record today, but the contents of this briefing are embargoed until the conclusion of the call.</p>
<p>As Secretary Blinken stated earlier today, President Biden believes deeply in the ability of U.S. global leadership to solve challenges.  And the administration recognizes that diplomacy and development are vital tools for advancing the interests and values of the United States.</p>
<p>With that in mind, it is my pleasure to let you know that we are joined today by Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brian McKeon; and USAID Deputy Administrator for Management and Resources Paloma Adams-Allen.  We are also joined by the director of the Department of State’s Bureau of Budget and Planning, Douglas Pitkin; the director of the Department’s Office of Foreign Assistance, Dr. Dafna Rand; and the department – excuse me – and the deputy assistant administrator for USAID’s Bureau of Policy, Planning and Learning, Nikole Burroughs.  So goes without saying that we certainly have the subject matter experts with us today.</p>
<p>I would note that we just had President Biden address the nation from the White House, and there is a briefing taking place at the White House as well where they’re speaking to the developments of the day, so I would ask that we focus on the Budget Request in this discussion.</p>
<p>To kick us off, we will hear remarks from Deputy Secretary McKeon and Deputy Administrator Adams-Allen, then we’ll take a few of your questions.  And with that, let me turn it over to Deputy Secretary McKeon.  Sir.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:  </strong>Thank you very much, JT, for that introduction, and thanks Paloma Adams-Allen for joining us today as we present the highlights of the Fiscal Year 2023 Budget Request for the State Department and USAID.  The President’s FY23 budget requests 60.4 billion – with a B – for the State Department and USAID.  I don’t need to tell any of us here that we face many ongoing challenges, from Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked invasion of Ukraine to the continuing COVID-19 pandemic and the climate crisis, to unprecedented humanitarian needs.  The State Department and USAID stand at the front lines of these challenges.  U.S. diplomacy and development efforts are more essential than ever to ensure American security and prosperity, solve global challenges, and uphold universal values.  Our Budget Request invests in the tools to do so.</p>
<p>First, this Budget Request builds on Congress’s recent supplemental funding to continue to increase both military and humanitarian support for Ukraine.  It also provides additional support to our allies and partners in the region and addresses the effects the conflict is having on issues such as food security around the world.  Globally, this Budget Request renews longstanding commitments to our closest partners, advances peace and security in Europe and the Indo-Pacific, reaffirms U.S. leadership in the international organizations where our competitors seek to expand their influence, and positions us to compete from a position of strength with Russia and the People’s Republic of China.</p>
<p>Second, this Budget Request equips us to address global challenges that are directly and profoundly impacting Americans’ lives and livelihoods, including the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic and the climate crisis, which is already driving extreme weather events and disrupting entire industries and communities across the United States.  This request will enable U.S. leadership in global health security to prevent, prepare for, and respond to future infectious disease outbreaks and pandemics.  It positions us to meet the climate crisis head-on by scaling up international climate programs and accelerating the global energy transition to net-zero by 2050; helping developing countries enhance resilience to climate shocks and transition to renewable energy sources; and by modeling renewable energy, climate adaptation, and sustainability principles in our own domestic and overseas facilities.</p>
<p>As part of these efforts, funding will also support mainstreaming climate considerations into all development programs to deliver climate co-benefits in sectors such as agriculture and food security, water and sanitation, and global health.  This Budget Request also supports the administration’s work to counter authoritarianism and disinformation, to advance human rights and racial and gender equity, and to support underserved communities, including by funding deliverables from the President’s Summit for Democracy.  It will enable us to work to advance gender equity and equality to build on President Biden’s historic National Strategy on Gender Equity and Equality by providing $2.6 billion to advance these issues across a broad range of sectors.  It reaffirms U.S. humanitarian leadership in the face of unprecedented challenges, including in Ukraine.  This request also seeks funding to provide the resources necessary to continue to rebuild a refugee admissions program and to support up to 125,000 admissions and provide refugee benefits to 10,000 Special Immigrant Visa beneficiaries.</p>
<p>In support of Secretary Blinken’s modernization agenda, this budget requests the resources we need to equip the State Department and USAID for the challenges of the 21st century.  It invests in our technology, training, and professional development – and diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility efforts – to ensure our workforce draws on the full breadth of America’s talent.  And it funds the central effort to keep our people in our facilities safe, including through new efforts to track and respond to the risk of anomalous health incidents.</p>
<p>This budget also supports and is reinforced by the new State Department and USAID Joint Strategic Plan for 2022 to 2026.  That plan is also being released today.  It is the primary State and USAID strategy that directs the priorities in implementing U.S. foreign policy and development assistance for both organizations for the coming years.</p>
<p>In closing, the President’s Budget Request for Fiscal ’23 enables the State Department and USAID and our country to address many global challenges ahead of us.</p>
<p>Now I’ve asked Paloma Adams-Allen to address the key elements of the USAID budget request.</p>
<p><strong>MS ADAMS-ALLEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you.  Thank you, JT.  Good afternoon, everyone.  I’m pleased to join Deputy Secretary McKeon today to discuss the Biden-Harris administration’s FY23 Budget Request.  In addition to being the largest in USAID’s history, this request reinforces the administration’s deeply held belief that the United States diplomacy and development efforts abroad are complementary and interdependent.  It calls for funding commensurate with our need to respond to a growing number of global crises while also advancing longer-term objectives – like making development more responsive to and inclusive of local actors, rooting out corruption that undermines democracy, and promoting greater investment from the private sector.</p>
<p>I want to highlight a few of the top lines and critical funding areas that we at USAID are focused on, and then I’d be happy to take questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Thank you to Deputy Secretary McKeon – I’m sorry.  Sorry, ma’am.  I pre-empted you.  Sorry, my apologies.</p>
<p><strong>MS ADAMS-ALLEN:</strong>  The FY23 Budget Request includes 29.4 billion for the U.S. Agency for International Development’s fully and partially managed accounts, an increase of 1.7 billion – 6 percent of last year’s request.   This number reflects the nature and complexity of the challenges we’re confronting around the world.  It also reflects President Biden’s commitment to reasserting the United States role as a leader in global development and humanitarian assistance.  We appreciate the support of Congress to provide us with supplemental funding to begin to address the crisis in Ukraine, and we look forward to working with them to receive the necessary funding to address the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>Chief among the challenges we face is the threat posed by the rise of authoritarians undermining the rule of law and democratic norms.  USAID’s democracy programming, for which State and USAID are requesting 2.6 billion, confronts authoritarianism and combats corruption and disinformation through partnerships with government reformers and civil society actors seeking to hold illiberal regimes accountable.  This amount includes 100 million to support the USAID-led anti-corruption initiative, a holistic set of programs to connect, empower, and protect anti-corruption champions and reformers in countries where we work.</p>
<p>On top of combating corruption, USAID responds to more than 75 crises in 70 countries on an annual basis.  As the world’s largest donor for global humanitarian assistance, a critical part of these resources is our ability to leverage funds to get our allies and partners to do more.  The Budget Request includes 6.4 billion in USAID-administered humanitarian assistance to address record-high needs stemming from new and protracted conflicts, increasingly frequent and more severe natural disasters, and the lingering effects of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>We know that when countries and populations face humanitarian crises or confront development challenges, it is often women and girls who shoulder the heaviest burden.  And I’m proud to say that this budget reflects a new era in USAID’s gender programming.  In a clear statement that the United States values women’s equity, equality, and empowerment, we’re asking for a historic 2.6 billion in joint State and USAID resources – more than doubling our current gender investment.  These resources will fund programming to promote the political, economic, and social empowerment of women and girls; advance efforts to prevent and respond to gender-based violence; and address gender discrimination and systemic inequities blocking the full participation of women and girls, men and boys, and individuals of other gender identities.</p>
<p>This budget also places the climate crisis at the forefront of our national security and foreign policy with a request of $2.3 billion for climate programs.</p>
<p>If approved, this funding will more than double the number of USAID-implemented climate programs.</p>
<p>In South and Central America, the United States remains committed to addressing the root causes of irregular migration.</p>
<p>To deliver on the President’s long term objectives for our allies and partners in the region, the Budget Request includes $987 million to address economic insecurity; combat corruption and strengthen governance; promote human rights; and combat gender-based violence; and finally, to support pathways to legal immigration.</p>
<p>In a concerted effort to deliver sustainable results for the communities we serve, this Budget Request also supports the structural changes needed for USAID to transform the way we deliver assistance, scaling up the proportion of funding that we give directly to local partners.  It supports efforts to decrease the barriers in our procurement processes, provide support to local partner capacity building, and prepares our staff to authentically engage with the communities we support.</p>
<p>With this Budget Request, we are seeking additional resources to strengthen USAID’s ability to partner with new, non-traditional, and local actors – a key priority of Administrator Power’s – including a $47 million request in support of our Centroamerica Local Initiative.</p>
<p>This initiative serves as a blueprint for our broader efforts to engage more community-based, civil society, and other local organizations in the design and implementation of locally led approaches to development and humanitarian approaches – challenges.</p>
<p>In the global health space, a $3.9 billion dollar request for Global Health funds will enable USAID to continue to play a leadership role in responding to health crises around the world.</p>
<p>The request includes $745 million for Global Health Security programs which will contribute to the prevention of future epidemics and pandemics by building country capacity and resilience.</p>
<p>Finally, none of the work we do in the world is possible without the expertise and commitment of our people.  For the agency to engage more deeply with the communities we support, build strong partnerships across public and private sectors, respond to the growing number of crises around the world, and embody the rich diversity of our country, we need to make strategic investments in our workforce.</p>
<p>With a request of $1.7 billion in operational expenses, USAID is prioritizing building a workforce that is equipped to challenge – to tackle the challenges of the 21st century.</p>
<p>In conclusion, upon examination, this budget proposal is a reflection of the critical importance of development and humanitarian assistance in advancing our interests and upholding our values.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE: </strong>  Thank you, ma’am.  Okay.  And with that, we’ll be happy to take a few of your questions.  Operator, would you please go ahead and give the instructions for getting into the question queue one more time, please?</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong>  For those of you who wish to ask a question, you may signal by pressing 1 then 0 on your phone.  Press 1 then 0 only once to signal that you wish to ask a question.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE: </strong>  Okay.  And with that, let’s please go to the line of Michael Igoe at Devex.  Michael?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Yes, thanks.  This is Michael Igoe with Devex.  Thanks for doing the call.  I appreciate it.  I have two questions really quickly, if possible.  I was wondering if you could say any more about the request of $6.5 billion in mandatory funding for State and USAID to make transformative investments in pandemic and biological threat preparedness.  I’m just wondering if that’s tied to a particular initiative or the implementation of a particular strategy.</p>
<p>And then the second question, really quickly, Administrator Power said in November that USAID will seek to increase its career workforce over the next four years.  I’m wondering if there’s a specific number of career officials you’re planning to hire and if that’s tied somehow to this funding request and those that will follow in subsequent years.  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON: </strong>  On the first one, we’re going to defer to OMB colleagues that are going to be putting out more detail in the next day or two, we understand.  Paloma can answer the second.</p>
<p><strong>MS ADAMS-ALLEN: </strong>  Thanks.  Yeah.  On the second, this request includes an increase of a hundred Foreign Service positions and a hundred Civil Service positions, which, if approved, would bring the total full-time permanent positions at USAID to 3,720 positions requested.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE: </strong>  And let’s go to the line of Rachel Oswald.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  My question is about humanitarian funding.  In the budget document shared by OMB, they referenced a $10 billion request for humanitarian funding.  And then I understand that USAID is seeking $6.4 billion in related humanitarian funding.  How did you arrive at those numbers?  When I tabulated the two principal humanitarian accounts, the MRA Fund in the State Department and the IDA Fund in USAID, I got a number closer to, I think, like $8.5 billion.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  So looking at a summary document that gives the total $10.5 billion:  Title II Food for Peace is 1.7 billion; the IDA Account, International Disaster Assistance, 4.7 billion; Migration Refugee Assistance Account, 3.9 billion; and for the Emergency Refugee and Migration Assistance Account, we’re asking for 100 million.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Very well, let’s please go to the line of Sarah (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  So I have a question about the breakdown of the request for climate funds.  You all are saying it will amount to 2.3 billion, but I believe the Office of Management and Budget says it was rated 5.3 billion.  And I’m wondering how that math adds up and comes together.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  So I’m not sure what document you’re looking at.  I mean, our accounts between the department and USAID is 2.3 billion.  They may be including the DFC or MCC.  I’m not – I’m sorry, I don’t have the document you may be looking at.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Okay, let’s go to the line of Ted Moon (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Yes, we can hear you, Ted.  Go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, I just – thanks for doing this.  I just wonder if there is a budget that can be used to improve the humanitarian situation in North Korea.  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Yes.  Operator, would you allow Ted to come back on and ask his question again, please?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Oh, hello, yes.  Yeah, this is the question about North Korea.  So I just wonder if there is a budget for using to improve the humanitarian situation in North Korea.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  Yeah.  The humanitarian assistance accounts are not allocated in advance by country.  It’s a needs-based response that we undertake in response either to global appeals or situations we see on the ground.  We don’t make political decisions.  We respond with our assistance as – on a needs-based approach.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Operator, if you would, please, go ahead and give our instructions one more time for getting into the question queue.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  For those of you who wish to ask a question, please press 1 then 0.  No one has signaled that they wish to speak.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Let’s just give it just a moment, Operator.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  I believe we have a follow-up question.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Okay, let’s go to the line of Michael, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And I’m just jumping in if no one else is going to.  But I didn’t see in the Budget Request any mention of the Global VAX Initiative, and I know that that was – the sort of scale-up of that was pretty closely tied to the Emergency Supplemental.  But can you just sort of speak to the status of that initiative, where it stands both in the sort of – sort of future thinking and FY 2023 and how that fits in with this request?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  So that’s in the COVID Supplemental we requested for Fiscal ‘22, which is still pending with the Congress.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Let’s go to the line of Michele Kelemen.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, thanks.  I just wanted to ask a question that was raised on the plane today with Secretary Blinken, whether or not there’s any money in the budget for either the consulate in Jerusalem or the consulate in Western Sahara.</p>
<p>And then secondly if you can talk a little bit more about how you plan to ramp up to accept all these refugees from Ukraine and the continued need for Afghanistan refugees.  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  On the first, I don’t really have anything to announce on the issue or question of the consulates at this time.</p>
<p>On Afghanistan – I’ll come back to Ukraine – we have a continuing effort and commitment to try to relocate people from Afghanistan who assisted us over the last 20 years and that work continues under the leadership of Ambassador Beth Jones here in the department.  And we have funding and resources on hand already, although it’s – there’s some money in the budget to continue that operation that she leads.</p>
<p>On Ukraine, I’d point you to the fact sheet the White House listed – issued last week, excuse me – during the President’s trip.  The 100,000 number is a combination of things: some people coming through the normal refugee program, some people coming through family reunification visas, and I think some other ideas that DHS is working on to provide temporary safe haven to people.  And when I say temporary, it’s because what we see and assess is a lot of the Ukrainians who have left the country want to stay.  They want to go back when the war ends.  Many of them want to stay in Europe close to Ukraine because they’ve left family members there and they hope to go back quickly.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Let’s please go to the line of (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  Let me go back to Michele.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Yes.  (Inaudible) hold just a second, please.  Go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  And then Michele, you asked a broader question about rebuilding the refugee program, which we continue to do.  The previous administration, it’s fair to say, was not a fan of the program and decimated the organization in terms of the refugee resettlement agencies here in the United States but also the capabilities in this department and in the Department of Homeland Security, so since President Biden came to office, we’ve been working to rebuild all of those elements.</p>
<p>It’s still a work in progress, but you saw in the course of the fall and the winter 75,000 Afghans who were evacuated from Afghanistan and brought to the United States have now been resettled in communities around the United States.  So we have provided refuge to those 75,000 Afghans and are using some of the lessons learned from that effort to continue to rebuild the broader refugee assistance program.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  (Inaudible) thank you for your patience.  Go ahead, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you for taking my question.  I’d like to ask a follow-up question on the budget for the alliances and the partnerships in the Indo-Pacific.  I’m wondering specifically for those countries located in East Asia like China, Russia, and North Korea, is there anything specific for their nuclear threats and their cyber threats?</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  So the assistance that we provide to allies and partners in the region is to confront a range of issues and security challenges – our traditional Foreign Military Financing program, some cyber assistance, as you referenced.  We have a special fund that Congress has given us called the Countering Chinese Influence Fund.  So it’s a broad range of security and economic assistance to both treaty allies but also other partners across the Asia Pacific.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  And I think we have time for one last question.  Let’s go back to Rachel Oswald, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  My question relates to the funding to address the root causes of migration from Central America and South America.  Can you talk a little bit about that pot of $980-something million and that $470 million?  Are those distinct pots of money or are they in the same pot?  And is that a lot of development assistance or what?</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  So this is the second year of trying to implement the President’s pledge to do four years, $4 billion in assistance to Central America.  This is the second year of the implementation of our Root Causes Strategy and Collaborative Migration Management Strategy.  It is building the capacity of local governments, local actors; helping them create the conditions in their own economies for opportunity and prosperity and security within their countries, including by combating corruption and impunity.</p>
<p>The point is we want people to stay there.  We realize that they are exceedingly desperate when they pick up and make a very dangerous trek north, which we are discouraging them to do.  But the reason they’re doing it is life is not sustainable for them where they live, so we’re trying to help the local governments improve their governance, improve their security, improve – reduce corruption, and provide economic opportunity so people don’t make that dangerous decision to depart and go north.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Okay, and with that, we are out of time this afternoon.  I would like to take this opportunity to thank Deputy Secretary of State McKeon and Deputy Administrator Adams-Allen for joining us today, as well as our other subject matter experts.  I also thank everyone who dialed in today.  And with that, the briefing is ended and the embargo is lifted.  Have a good afternoon.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:  </strong>Thank you, Operator.  Here just now, I’d like to thank everyone for joining us today for this briefing on the President’s Fiscal Year 2023 Budget Request for both the U.S. Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development.  As a quick reminder here at the top, we are on the record today, but the contents of this briefing are embargoed until the conclusion of the call.</p>
<p>As Secretary Blinken stated earlier today, President Biden believes deeply in the ability of U.S. global leadership to solve challenges.  And the administration recognizes that diplomacy and development are vital tools for advancing the interests and values of the United States.</p>
<p>With that in mind, it is my pleasure to let you know that we are joined today by Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brian McKeon; and USAID Deputy Administrator for Management and Resources Paloma Adams-Allen.  We are also joined by the director of the Department of State’s Bureau of Budget and Planning, Douglas Pitkin; the director of the Department’s Office of Foreign Assistance, Dr. Dafna Rand; and the department – excuse me – and the deputy assistant administrator for USAID’s Bureau of Policy, Planning and Learning, Nikole Burroughs.  So goes without saying that we certainly have the subject matter experts with us today.</p>
<p>I would note that we just had President Biden address the nation from the White House, and there is a briefing taking place at the White House as well where they’re speaking to the developments of the day, so I would ask that we focus on the Budget Request in this discussion.</p>
<p>To kick us off, we will hear remarks from Deputy Secretary McKeon and Deputy Administrator Adams-Allen, then we’ll take a few of your questions.  And with that, let me turn it over to Deputy Secretary McKeon.  Sir.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:  </strong>Thank you very much, JT, for that introduction, and thanks Paloma Adams-Allen for joining us today as we present the highlights of the Fiscal Year 2023 Budget Request for the State Department and USAID.  The President’s FY23 budget requests 60.4 billion – with a B – for the State Department and USAID.  I don’t need to tell any of us here that we face many ongoing challenges, from Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked invasion of Ukraine to the continuing COVID-19 pandemic and the climate crisis, to unprecedented humanitarian needs.  The State Department and USAID stand at the front lines of these challenges.  U.S. diplomacy and development efforts are more essential than ever to ensure American security and prosperity, solve global challenges, and uphold universal values.  Our Budget Request invests in the tools to do so.</p>
<p>First, this Budget Request builds on Congress’s recent supplemental funding to continue to increase both military and humanitarian support for Ukraine.  It also provides additional support to our allies and partners in the region and addresses the effects the conflict is having on issues such as food security around the world.  Globally, this Budget Request renews longstanding commitments to our closest partners, advances peace and security in Europe and the Indo-Pacific, reaffirms U.S. leadership in the international organizations where our competitors seek to expand their influence, and positions us to compete from a position of strength with Russia and the People’s Republic of China.</p>
<p>Second, this Budget Request equips us to address global challenges that are directly and profoundly impacting Americans’ lives and livelihoods, including the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic and the climate crisis, which is already driving extreme weather events and disrupting entire industries and communities across the United States.  This request will enable U.S. leadership in global health security to prevent, prepare for, and respond to future infectious disease outbreaks and pandemics.  It positions us to meet the climate crisis head-on by scaling up international climate programs and accelerating the global energy transition to net-zero by 2050; helping developing countries enhance resilience to climate shocks and transition to renewable energy sources; and by modeling renewable energy, climate adaptation, and sustainability principles in our own domestic and overseas facilities.</p>
<p>As part of these efforts, funding will also support mainstreaming climate considerations into all development programs to deliver climate co-benefits in sectors such as agriculture and food security, water and sanitation, and global health.  This Budget Request also supports the administration’s work to counter authoritarianism and disinformation, to advance human rights and racial and gender equity, and to support underserved communities, including by funding deliverables from the President’s Summit for Democracy.  It will enable us to work to advance gender equity and equality to build on President Biden’s historic National Strategy on Gender Equity and Equality by providing $2.6 billion to advance these issues across a broad range of sectors.  It reaffirms U.S. humanitarian leadership in the face of unprecedented challenges, including in Ukraine.  This request also seeks funding to provide the resources necessary to continue to rebuild a refugee admissions program and to support up to 125,000 admissions and provide refugee benefits to 10,000 Special Immigrant Visa beneficiaries.</p>
<p>In support of Secretary Blinken’s modernization agenda, this budget requests the resources we need to equip the State Department and USAID for the challenges of the 21st century.  It invests in our technology, training, and professional development – and diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility efforts – to ensure our workforce draws on the full breadth of America’s talent.  And it funds the central effort to keep our people in our facilities safe, including through new efforts to track and respond to the risk of anomalous health incidents.</p>
<p>This budget also supports and is reinforced by the new State Department and USAID Joint Strategic Plan for 2022 to 2026.  That plan is also being released today.  It is the primary State and USAID strategy that directs the priorities in implementing U.S. foreign policy and development assistance for both organizations for the coming years.</p>
<p>In closing, the President’s Budget Request for Fiscal ’23 enables the State Department and USAID and our country to address many global challenges ahead of us.</p>
<p>Now I’ve asked Paloma Adams-Allen to address the key elements of the USAID budget request.</p>
<p><strong>MS ADAMS-ALLEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you.  Thank you, JT.  Good afternoon, everyone.  I’m pleased to join Deputy Secretary McKeon today to discuss the Biden-Harris administration’s FY23 Budget Request.  In addition to being the largest in USAID’s history, this request reinforces the administration’s deeply held belief that the United States diplomacy and development efforts abroad are complementary and interdependent.  It calls for funding commensurate with our need to respond to a growing number of global crises while also advancing longer-term objectives – like making development more responsive to and inclusive of local actors, rooting out corruption that undermines democracy, and promoting greater investment from the private sector.</p>
<p>I want to highlight a few of the top lines and critical funding areas that we at USAID are focused on, and then I’d be happy to take questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Thank you to Deputy Secretary McKeon – I’m sorry.  Sorry, ma’am.  I pre-empted you.  Sorry, my apologies.</p>
<p><strong>MS ADAMS-ALLEN:</strong>  The FY23 Budget Request includes 29.4 billion for the U.S. Agency for International Development’s fully and partially managed accounts, an increase of 1.7 billion – 6 percent of last year’s request.   This number reflects the nature and complexity of the challenges we’re confronting around the world.  It also reflects President Biden’s commitment to reasserting the United States role as a leader in global development and humanitarian assistance.  We appreciate the support of Congress to provide us with supplemental funding to begin to address the crisis in Ukraine, and we look forward to working with them to receive the necessary funding to address the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>Chief among the challenges we face is the threat posed by the rise of authoritarians undermining the rule of law and democratic norms.  USAID’s democracy programming, for which State and USAID are requesting 2.6 billion, confronts authoritarianism and combats corruption and disinformation through partnerships with government reformers and civil society actors seeking to hold illiberal regimes accountable.  This amount includes 100 million to support the USAID-led anti-corruption initiative, a holistic set of programs to connect, empower, and protect anti-corruption champions and reformers in countries where we work.</p>
<p>On top of combating corruption, USAID responds to more than 75 crises in 70 countries on an annual basis.  As the world’s largest donor for global humanitarian assistance, a critical part of these resources is our ability to leverage funds to get our allies and partners to do more.  The Budget Request includes 6.4 billion in USAID-administered humanitarian assistance to address record-high needs stemming from new and protracted conflicts, increasingly frequent and more severe natural disasters, and the lingering effects of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>We know that when countries and populations face humanitarian crises or confront development challenges, it is often women and girls who shoulder the heaviest burden.  And I’m proud to say that this budget reflects a new era in USAID’s gender programming.  In a clear statement that the United States values women’s equity, equality, and empowerment, we’re asking for a historic 2.6 billion in joint State and USAID resources – more than doubling our current gender investment.  These resources will fund programming to promote the political, economic, and social empowerment of women and girls; advance efforts to prevent and respond to gender-based violence; and address gender discrimination and systemic inequities blocking the full participation of women and girls, men and boys, and individuals of other gender identities.</p>
<p>This budget also places the climate crisis at the forefront of our national security and foreign policy with a request of $2.3 billion for climate programs.</p>
<p>If approved, this funding will more than double the number of USAID-implemented climate programs.</p>
<p>In South and Central America, the United States remains committed to addressing the root causes of irregular migration.</p>
<p>To deliver on the President’s long term objectives for our allies and partners in the region, the Budget Request includes $987 million to address economic insecurity; combat corruption and strengthen governance; promote human rights; and combat gender-based violence; and finally, to support pathways to legal immigration.</p>
<p>In a concerted effort to deliver sustainable results for the communities we serve, this Budget Request also supports the structural changes needed for USAID to transform the way we deliver assistance, scaling up the proportion of funding that we give directly to local partners.  It supports efforts to decrease the barriers in our procurement processes, provide support to local partner capacity building, and prepares our staff to authentically engage with the communities we support.</p>
<p>With this Budget Request, we are seeking additional resources to strengthen USAID’s ability to partner with new, non-traditional, and local actors – a key priority of Administrator Power’s – including a $47 million request in support of our Centroamerica Local Initiative.</p>
<p>This initiative serves as a blueprint for our broader efforts to engage more community-based, civil society, and other local organizations in the design and implementation of locally led approaches to development and humanitarian approaches – challenges.</p>
<p>In the global health space, a $3.9 billion dollar request for Global Health funds will enable USAID to continue to play a leadership role in responding to health crises around the world.</p>
<p>The request includes $745 million for Global Health Security programs which will contribute to the prevention of future epidemics and pandemics by building country capacity and resilience.</p>
<p>Finally, none of the work we do in the world is possible without the expertise and commitment of our people.  For the agency to engage more deeply with the communities we support, build strong partnerships across public and private sectors, respond to the growing number of crises around the world, and embody the rich diversity of our country, we need to make strategic investments in our workforce.</p>
<p>With a request of $1.7 billion in operational expenses, USAID is prioritizing building a workforce that is equipped to challenge – to tackle the challenges of the 21st century.</p>
<p>In conclusion, upon examination, this budget proposal is a reflection of the critical importance of development and humanitarian assistance in advancing our interests and upholding our values.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE: </strong>  Thank you, ma’am.  Okay.  And with that, we’ll be happy to take a few of your questions.  Operator, would you please go ahead and give the instructions for getting into the question queue one more time, please?</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong>  For those of you who wish to ask a question, you may signal by pressing 1 then 0 on your phone.  Press 1 then 0 only once to signal that you wish to ask a question.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE: </strong>  Okay.  And with that, let’s please go to the line of Michael Igoe at Devex.  Michael?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Yes, thanks.  This is Michael Igoe with Devex.  Thanks for doing the call.  I appreciate it.  I have two questions really quickly, if possible.  I was wondering if you could say any more about the request of $6.5 billion in mandatory funding for State and USAID to make transformative investments in pandemic and biological threat preparedness.  I’m just wondering if that’s tied to a particular initiative or the implementation of a particular strategy.</p>
<p>And then the second question, really quickly, Administrator Power said in November that USAID will seek to increase its career workforce over the next four years.  I’m wondering if there’s a specific number of career officials you’re planning to hire and if that’s tied somehow to this funding request and those that will follow in subsequent years.  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON: </strong>  On the first one, we’re going to defer to OMB colleagues that are going to be putting out more detail in the next day or two, we understand.  Paloma can answer the second.</p>
<p><strong>MS ADAMS-ALLEN: </strong>  Thanks.  Yeah.  On the second, this request includes an increase of a hundred Foreign Service positions and a hundred Civil Service positions, which, if approved, would bring the total full-time permanent positions at USAID to 3,720 positions requested.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE: </strong>  And let’s go to the line of Rachel Oswald.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  My question is about humanitarian funding.  In the budget document shared by OMB, they referenced a $10 billion request for humanitarian funding.  And then I understand that USAID is seeking $6.4 billion in related humanitarian funding.  How did you arrive at those numbers?  When I tabulated the two principal humanitarian accounts, the MRA Fund in the State Department and the IDA Fund in USAID, I got a number closer to, I think, like $8.5 billion.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  So looking at a summary document that gives the total $10.5 billion:  Title II Food for Peace is 1.7 billion; the IDA Account, International Disaster Assistance, 4.7 billion; Migration Refugee Assistance Account, 3.9 billion; and for the Emergency Refugee and Migration Assistance Account, we’re asking for 100 million.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Very well, let’s please go to the line of Sarah (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  So I have a question about the breakdown of the request for climate funds.  You all are saying it will amount to 2.3 billion, but I believe the Office of Management and Budget says it was rated 5.3 billion.  And I’m wondering how that math adds up and comes together.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  So I’m not sure what document you’re looking at.  I mean, our accounts between the department and USAID is 2.3 billion.  They may be including the DFC or MCC.  I’m not – I’m sorry, I don’t have the document you may be looking at.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Okay, let’s go to the line of Ted Moon (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Yes, we can hear you, Ted.  Go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, I just – thanks for doing this.  I just wonder if there is a budget that can be used to improve the humanitarian situation in North Korea.  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Yes.  Operator, would you allow Ted to come back on and ask his question again, please?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Oh, hello, yes.  Yeah, this is the question about North Korea.  So I just wonder if there is a budget for using to improve the humanitarian situation in North Korea.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  Yeah.  The humanitarian assistance accounts are not allocated in advance by country.  It’s a needs-based response that we undertake in response either to global appeals or situations we see on the ground.  We don’t make political decisions.  We respond with our assistance as – on a needs-based approach.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Operator, if you would, please, go ahead and give our instructions one more time for getting into the question queue.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  For those of you who wish to ask a question, please press 1 then 0.  No one has signaled that they wish to speak.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Let’s just give it just a moment, Operator.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  I believe we have a follow-up question.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Okay, let’s go to the line of Michael, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And I’m just jumping in if no one else is going to.  But I didn’t see in the Budget Request any mention of the Global VAX Initiative, and I know that that was – the sort of scale-up of that was pretty closely tied to the Emergency Supplemental.  But can you just sort of speak to the status of that initiative, where it stands both in the sort of – sort of future thinking and FY 2023 and how that fits in with this request?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  So that’s in the COVID Supplemental we requested for Fiscal ‘22, which is still pending with the Congress.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Let’s go to the line of Michele Kelemen.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, thanks.  I just wanted to ask a question that was raised on the plane today with Secretary Blinken, whether or not there’s any money in the budget for either the consulate in Jerusalem or the consulate in Western Sahara.</p>
<p>And then secondly if you can talk a little bit more about how you plan to ramp up to accept all these refugees from Ukraine and the continued need for Afghanistan refugees.  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  On the first, I don’t really have anything to announce on the issue or question of the consulates at this time.</p>
<p>On Afghanistan – I’ll come back to Ukraine – we have a continuing effort and commitment to try to relocate people from Afghanistan who assisted us over the last 20 years and that work continues under the leadership of Ambassador Beth Jones here in the department.  And we have funding and resources on hand already, although it’s – there’s some money in the budget to continue that operation that she leads.</p>
<p>On Ukraine, I’d point you to the fact sheet the White House listed – issued last week, excuse me – during the President’s trip.  The 100,000 number is a combination of things: some people coming through the normal refugee program, some people coming through family reunification visas, and I think some other ideas that DHS is working on to provide temporary safe haven to people.  And when I say temporary, it’s because what we see and assess is a lot of the Ukrainians who have left the country want to stay.  They want to go back when the war ends.  Many of them want to stay in Europe close to Ukraine because they’ve left family members there and they hope to go back quickly.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Let’s please go to the line of (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  Let me go back to Michele.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Yes.  (Inaudible) hold just a second, please.  Go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  And then Michele, you asked a broader question about rebuilding the refugee program, which we continue to do.  The previous administration, it’s fair to say, was not a fan of the program and decimated the organization in terms of the refugee resettlement agencies here in the United States but also the capabilities in this department and in the Department of Homeland Security, so since President Biden came to office, we’ve been working to rebuild all of those elements.</p>
<p>It’s still a work in progress, but you saw in the course of the fall and the winter 75,000 Afghans who were evacuated from Afghanistan and brought to the United States have now been resettled in communities around the United States.  So we have provided refuge to those 75,000 Afghans and are using some of the lessons learned from that effort to continue to rebuild the broader refugee assistance program.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  (Inaudible) thank you for your patience.  Go ahead, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you for taking my question.  I’d like to ask a follow-up question on the budget for the alliances and the partnerships in the Indo-Pacific.  I’m wondering specifically for those countries located in East Asia like China, Russia, and North Korea, is there anything specific for their nuclear threats and their cyber threats?</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  So the assistance that we provide to allies and partners in the region is to confront a range of issues and security challenges – our traditional Foreign Military Financing program, some cyber assistance, as you referenced.  We have a special fund that Congress has given us called the Countering Chinese Influence Fund.  So it’s a broad range of security and economic assistance to both treaty allies but also other partners across the Asia Pacific.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  And I think we have time for one last question.  Let’s go back to Rachel Oswald, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  My question relates to the funding to address the root causes of migration from Central America and South America.  Can you talk a little bit about that pot of $980-something million and that $470 million?  Are those distinct pots of money or are they in the same pot?  And is that a lot of development assistance or what?</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY SECRETARY MCKEON:</strong>  So this is the second year of trying to implement the President’s pledge to do four years, $4 billion in assistance to Central America.  This is the second year of the implementation of our Root Causes Strategy and Collaborative Migration Management Strategy.  It is building the capacity of local governments, local actors; helping them create the conditions in their own economies for opportunity and prosperity and security within their countries, including by combating corruption and impunity.</p>
<p>The point is we want people to stay there.  We realize that they are exceedingly desperate when they pick up and make a very dangerous trek north, which we are discouraging them to do.  But the reason they’re doing it is life is not sustainable for them where they live, so we’re trying to help the local governments improve their governance, improve their security, improve – reduce corruption, and provide economic opportunity so people don’t make that dangerous decision to depart and go north.</p>
<p><strong>MR ICE:</strong>  Okay, and with that, we are out of time this afternoon.  I would like to take this opportunity to thank Deputy Secretary of State McKeon and Deputy Administrator Adams-Allen for joining us today, as well as our other subject matter experts.  I also thank everyone who dialed in today.  And with that, the briefing is ended and the embargo is lifted.  Have a good afternoon.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Counselor Chollet’s Travel to the Philippines, Vietnam, and Japan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/counselor-chollets-travel-to-the-philippines-vietnam-and-japan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 19:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=328881</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Counselor Derek Chollet will travel to the Philippines, Vietnam, and Japan from March 28 to April 2. Counselor Chollet will reaffirm the U.S. commitment to our Indo-Pacific allies and partners, and engage with key stakeholders on bilateral and regional issues, including efforts to seek a peaceful return to democracy in Burma. He will also discuss the impact of Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>In the Philippines, Counselor Chollet will consult with officials on our joint efforts to support the rule of law and ensure freedom of navigation in the South China Sea. The Counselor’s visit will reaffirm our unwavering commitment to the U.S.-Philippines Alliance as evident in the Joint Vision for a 21st-Century United States-Philippines Partnership. While in Manila, he will engage counterparts on democracy and human rights. He will also discuss U.S.-ASEAN relations and regional issues, including the crisis in Burma.</p>
<p>In Vietnam, Counselor Chollet will meet with senior government officials to affirm the United States-Vietnam Comprehensive Partnership and the U.S. commitment to ASEAN centrality, while also discussing the ongoing crisis in Burma. The Counselor and his Vietnamese counterparts will also discuss opportunities to further security and economic cooperation. The Counselor will also underscore the importance of respect for human rights. Finally, the Counselor will stop in Japan to meet with senior government officials to discuss Burma, Ukraine, and other issues.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Counselor Derek Chollet will travel to the Philippines, Vietnam, and Japan from March 28 to April 2. Counselor Chollet will reaffirm the U.S. commitment to our Indo-Pacific allies and partners, and engage with key stakeholders on bilateral and regional issues, including efforts to seek a peaceful return to democracy in Burma. He will also discuss the impact of Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>In the Philippines, Counselor Chollet will consult with officials on our joint efforts to support the rule of law and ensure freedom of navigation in the South China Sea. The Counselor’s visit will reaffirm our unwavering commitment to the U.S.-Philippines Alliance as evident in the Joint Vision for a 21st-Century United States-Philippines Partnership. While in Manila, he will engage counterparts on democracy and human rights. He will also discuss U.S.-ASEAN relations and regional issues, including the crisis in Burma.</p>
<p>In Vietnam, Counselor Chollet will meet with senior government officials to affirm the United States-Vietnam Comprehensive Partnership and the U.S. commitment to ASEAN centrality, while also discussing the ongoing crisis in Burma. The Counselor and his Vietnamese counterparts will also discuss opportunities to further security and economic cooperation. The Counselor will also underscore the importance of respect for human rights. Finally, the Counselor will stop in Japan to meet with senior government officials to discuss Burma, Ukraine, and other issues.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Joint Press Statements at the Conclusion of the Negev Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-joint-press-statements-at-the-conclusion-of-the-negev-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 18:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=328858</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Sde Boker</p>
<p>Kedma Hotel</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Good afternoon, Excellencies, ladies and gentlemen.  We are starting now the last chapter of the Negev Summit, which are the press statements by all six foreign ministers.  First to address us is our host, Foreign Minister of the State of Israel His Excellency Yair Lapid.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LAPID:  </b>Thank you, my friend Secretary of State Tony Blinken, Foreign Minister Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed, Foreign Minister Abdullatif Al Zayani, Foreign Minister Sameh Shoukry, and Foreign Minister Nasser Bourita.</p>
<p>Last night, for the second time in a week, terror struck in the heart of Israel – at the heart of Israel in two senses: in the heart of the country in a crowded city, and also in the heart of every Israeli citizen.  This was murder for the sake of murder, terror for the sake of terror.  These terrorists fired in every direction with one goal: to kill as many innocent people as possible, to shed as much blood as possible.  I send my condolences to the families of the murdered and my wishes for the full and speedy recovery of the wounded.  Our thoughts and prayers are with them today.</p>
<p>Shortly after the attack, Islamic Jihad and Hamas praised it.  They declared that it was a response to the Negev Summit we are holding here.  The terrorists’ goal is to intimidate us, to make us afraid to meet and to build relationships and the agreements between us.  They will not succeed; we will not let them.  We have no intention of rewarding terrorists.  We have no intention of letting them dictate our lives or our policies.  Israel is a strong and a proud country and will never surrender to terror.  We will continue on our path, the path of peace.</p>
<p>I am not alone in this.  Everyone here shares this sentiment.  Last night, all the foreign ministers participating in the summit condemned with one strong voice the horrific terror attack.  On behalf of the people of Israel, I thank you for this.</p>
<p>My friends, Israel’s founding father, David Ben Gurion, who is buried two minutes away from here, once said history is isn’t written, history is made.  What we are doing here is making history, building a new regional architecture based on progress, technology, religious tolerance, security, and intelligence cooperation.  This new architecture, the shared capabilities we are building, intimidates and deters our common enemies, first and foremost Iran and its proxies. They certainly have something to fear.  What will stop them is not hesitation or being conciliatory, but rather determination and strength.</p>
<p>Friends, we are standing here in the Negev where our common father went after signing the original Abraham Accords between him and the Lord.  In the book of Genesis, it is written:  Then Abram set out and continued towards the Negev.  He came here to build a better future for his people and his family, and we are here for the same reason.</p>
<p>The history of the Middle East is the story of smart and tough people who made the desert bloom.  Our peoples are those who stopped right here and said, in this place, in this desert, we will make life flourish.  From this desert will spring forth palaces and temples, schools and hospitals, inspirational art and literature, and groundbreaking technology.  This meeting is the first of its kind, but not the last.</p>
<p>Last night, we decided to make the Negev Summit into a permanent forum.  Together with our  closest friend and ally, the United States, we are today opening a door before all the peoples of the region, including the Palestinians, and offering them to replace the way of terror and destruction with shared future of progress and success.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Thank you, Minister Lapid.  Next to address us, Secretary of State of the United States Antony Blinken.  Please, sir.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.  Let me begin by joining Yair and all of my colleagues in condemning the horrific terrorist attack last night in Hadera, which killed two border police officers, both just 19 years old.  On behalf of President Biden, the American people, we extend our heartfelt condolences to the loved ones of the victims, Yazan Fallah and Shirel Aboukaret.  No family should have to experience such loss, and we stand in absolute solidarity with our friends and partners against terrorism and these horrific acts of violence.  And indeed, Yair, as you said, what we are doing here is the exact counterpoint to this senseless destruction and violence.</p>
<p>It’s an honor to be here with you, with Minister Bourita, with Minister Al Zayani, Minister Zayed, Minister Shoukry – the foreign ministers of Israel, Morocco, Bahrain, the United Arab Emirates, and Egypt – standing together in Israel.  Just a few years ago, this gathering would have been impossible to imagine.</p>
<p>You mentioned the original Abraham.  He had a dialogue with God.  He had the temerity sometimes to ask why.  We have the temerity, you have the temerity, to ask, why not?  That’s what this is about.  Since September 15<sup>th</sup>, 2020, when leaders from Israel, Bahrain, and the United Arab Emirates signed the Abraham Accords, and Morocco and Israel signed a normalization agreement soon after, once-impossible things have become possible.</p>
<p>We’ve seen democracy<a id="post-328858-footnote-ref-1" href="#post-328858-footnote-1"></a> flourish, with Morocco and Israel agreeing to open embassies in Rabat and Tel Aviv; Prime Minister Bennett becoming the first Israeli prime minister to visit Bahrain and the United Arab Emirates; and last week, the leaders of the United Arab Emirates, Israel, and Egypt meeting to launch new areas of cooperation.  We’ve seen growing economic ties, with Bahrain and Israel signing more than a dozen agreements, including on aviation, on banking, on technology; government and business leaders from Morocco and Israel meeting last week to promote tourism across both countries; a solar energy deal that will accelerate the green energy transition already underway in the region.</p>
<p>At the heart of these interactions are people, people eager to learn about and from one another.  Student exchanges are flourishing between Rabat and Tal Aviv.  A Holocaust memorial exhibition is now opened in Dubai.  Hospitals in Bahrain and Israel are teaming up on cancer research.  Tomorrow, soccer players from – or football players from your countries will play in the Abraham Accords festival and games at the Dubai Expo, where there’s also an Israel pavilion.</p>
<p>The Abraham Accords are making the lives of people across your countries more peaceful, more prosperous, more vibrant, more integrated.  They’re allowing governments to focus their energies and attentions on the issues that are actually affecting the lives of our citizens and making them better.  The United States has and will continue to strongly support a process that is transforming this region and beyond.  We’ll help to strengthen the bonds between Israel and its circle of friends, both those with which it has normalization agreements and those with which it has longstanding peace treaties, like Egypt and Jordan.</p>
<p>To name one example, later today officials from the United States, the UAE, and Israel will launch the Religious Coexistence Working Group to counter intolerance and promote understanding.  And we’ll help widen the circle of friendship to include other countries interested in securing greater peace and prosperity for their own people.  As we do, we have to be clear that these regional peace agreements are not a substitute for progress between Palestinians and Israelis.</p>
<p>One of the issues we discussed today was how countries involved in the Abraham Accords and normalization, as well as those that have longstanding diplomatic relationships with Israel, can support the Palestinian Authority and the Palestinian people in concrete ways and have a positive impact on the daily lives of Palestinians in the West Bank and Gaza.  This is a conversation we’ll carry forward so that we can work toward our goal of Palestinians and Israelis enjoying equal measures of freedom, security, opportunity, and dignity, and create the conditions for a negotiated two-state solution.  Finally, as neighbors, and in the case of the United States, as friends, we will also work together to confront common security challenges and threats, including those from Iran and its proxies.</p>
<p>Almost exactly 43 years ago, Israel and Egypt concluded the Camp David Accords.  At that time, standing between President Sadat and President<a id="post-328858-footnote-ref-2" href="#post-328858-footnote-2"></a> Begin, President Carter said this:  “We are privileged to witness…a significant achievement in the cause of peace, an achievement  none thought possible  a year ago.”  Well, those were different times.  Israel and its neighbors had just fought a war.  But that sentiment – that what was believed unchangeable was suddenly transformed, creating a new reality – this is also true today.  And as happens whenever you break down barriers that have long kept people from interacting, exchanging ideas, working together, it’s impossible to anticipate all the new directions that this can take us.  This is a new dawn.  The only limits are the ones we can imagine.</p>
<p>So I commend the courage of those willing to break down barriers, political leaders but also people across our societies, individual citizens who are forging new relationships as a result of this historic opening.  I am excited to see all that you and we can imagine and create together for one another, for the region, for the world.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Thank you, Mr. Secretary.  Now I invite His Excellency Abdullatif bin Rashid Al Zayani, minister of foreign affairs of the Kingdom of Bahrain, to address us.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER AL ZAYANI:  </b>Thank you.  Your Highness, Your Excellencies, ladies and gentlemen, it has been my great pleasure to participate in this distinguished gathering.  And I want to start by thanking Foreign Minister Lapid for the invitation. and indeed for the hospitality.</p>
<p>I would like to start by condemning the terrorist attack which took place last night, claiming the lives of two border policemen.  And I would like to convey our condolences to the bereaved families and reaffirm our firm stance against terrorism in all its forms.</p>
<p>I join you here on behalf of the Kingdom of Bahrain, a nation which has always been convinced in the importance of peace, dialogue, coexistence, and mutual respect, principles which are fully reflected and embodied in the vision of His Majesty King Hamad bin Isa Al Khalifa and the policies implemented by the government led by His Royal Highness Prince Salman bin Hamad Al Khalifa.</p>
<p>This is an important and timely meeting, and an opportunity to build on the historic 2020 Abraham Accords with a huge scope for growing the region’s prosperity, safeguarding its security, and realizing the aspirations of all its peoples.  The need to do so is made more urgent by recent developments such as the Houthi terrorist militia’s continued attacks on civilian energy infrastructure, the ongoing threat from terrorist organizations such as Hizballah and other proxy groups, and the need to resolve the Iranian nuclear file.</p>
<p>So we need to put into practice the principles behind the accords, namely those of dialogue, cooperation, and mutual respect.  We need to establish genuine, sustainable coexistence and interdependence between participants, building genuine networks of cooperation and trust to advance our common security and prosperity.  By doing so, we will demonstrate to the whole region what can be achieved by working together and show how, collectively, we can overcome shared regional challenges and seize opportunities in a way that would not – possible individually.  Of course, part of this process will be renewed efforts to resolve the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, and Bahrain continues to urge both parties to come together and negotiate a resolution that establishes a viable state for the Palestinians and protects the security and interests of all parties.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, in the Kingdom of Bahrain, we have moved quickly to build on the Abraham Accords and to rapidly expand our relationship with the state of Israel.  We see great potential for cooperation across all fields.  And over the past 18 months, we have already seen how this potential can be realized.  This forum is therefore an important step in deepening and strengthening these bilateral ties, but also in expanding multilateral cooperation and interdependence among all countries.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken, in this context, I would like to thank the United States of America for their support to the Abraham Accords and for their continued commitment to the security of the region.  And once again, thank you, Minister Lapid, for hosting this gathering and for these warm and constructive discussions.  And I very much look forward to our next meeting and to building further on what we have achieved today.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you very much, Excellency.  I now invite His Excellency Sameh Shoukry, minister of foreign affairs of Egypt, to address us.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER SHOUKRY:</b>  Minister Lapid, colleagues, ladies and gentlemen, let me first of all convey our appreciation to Minister Lapid for having convened these consultations.  They are – I think can be characterized by having been constructive and in-depth, and do address the various challenges that our region faces, turbulence related to regional and international conditions.  And we do so, the day before yesterday, having commemorated, as Secretary Blinken has referred to, the 43rd anniversary of the peace between Egypt and Israel, and we see constructive development in the normalization of relations and believe that the path that we set upon 43 years ago is coming to greater fruition and recognition of the importance and the viability of comprehensive peace and security for our region.</p>
<p>This round of discussions has given us an opportunity to highlight views related to how we can further progress in achieving our common objectives, and it certainly did during these discussions.  We did highlight the importance of the Israeli-Palestinian peace process, the importance of maintaining the credibility and the viability of the two-state solution that – for Israel and a Palestinian state to live side by side in peace with recognized borders for a Palestinian state in accordance with the ’67 lines with East Jerusalem as its capital.</p>
<p>This is an important issue, and Egypt has been striving over the years to facilitate and to assist both Israel and the Palestinians to reach the necessary accommodation and compromise that can facilitate an end of the conflict, and thereby open broader doors of regional cooperation, integration, and the benefits for the peoples of the region.  And of course, we do so in collaboration and with the assistance of our partner, the United States of America, and we value very much the coordination that exists and the common understanding related to the path and the way forward.</p>
<p>We certainly also consider and have on every occasion condemned all resort to violence, to terrorism, to incitement, and believe that it is our role as members of the international community but also as Arab states, states where there is a Muslim majority, as President al-Sisi has always declared, that we need to address the religious narrative and to confront extremism and terrorism and thereby provide peace and security for our region.  Also, the importance of addressing the issue of extra-regional intervention and the negative impact on the security and stability of our region.  We believe that we have the resources and the ability to meet those challenges with the help of our partners in the United States, and we’ll continue to seek areas of cooperation that provide for our protection of our national security interests within a peaceful and cooperative framework.</p>
<p>On all of these fronts, I think we have demonstrated our predictability, the dependence, the longevity of our peace with Israel, and that we are partners that can be depended on, and thereby we seek to enhance the areas of cooperation and interaction that can bring benefit to the region and to international peace and security.  For all of these reasons, we look forward to continuing this dialogue and to reaching a understanding and a consensus of how best to deal with the very many issues.  And here again, I think it is going to be incumbent and important on the short term to deal with the pressures that might arise and the importance of restricting any unilateral activity that might agitate the current situation and have an impact on the tranquility during a very sensitive and important time where we hope we can all direct our attention towards a higher cause rather than having to deal with crisis management.</p>
<p>I thank you again for the opportunity and I welcome this dialogue.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you very much, Your Excellency.  I now have the pleasure of inviting His Excellency Mr. Nasser Bourita, Minister of Foreign Affairs, African Cooperation and Moroccan Expatriates of the Kingdom of Morocco.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER BOURITA:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Please, sir.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER BOURITA:</b>  I would like to start by reiterating Morocco’s strong condemnation of the terrorist attacks of yesterday in Hadera and present our sincere condolences to the victims and our wish of recovery to all the injured.  Our presence today is, I think, the best response to such attacks.</p>
<p>I’m very delighted to be here in Negev in this very historic and timely Negev Summit, or, I should say, first Negev Summit.  And I would like to thank you, Yair, for the invitation, for choosing this very nice venue, and for the hospitality.</p>
<p>I would like also to thank you, Tony, for the presence, for the involvement, for the commitment.  The United States has been a reliable partner in promoting peace, and your personal commitment to this endeavor is very important to us.</p>
<p>Morocco’s presence here under instructions of His Majesty King Mohammed VI is meant to send two messages.  The first one is to our host and to the people of Israel.  As His Majesty King Mohammed VI said when we established the relations, this is not an opportunistic move.  It’s a move of conviction.  It’s a natural decision based on these longstanding relations between Morocco, Israel, and the kings of Morocco, and the Moroccan-Jewish community.</p>
<p>You are saying here that maybe every Israeli has in his family someone with Moroccan blood.  It’s not only a joke; it’s a reality.  I learned that two of the mayors of the main cities in the Negev, in Dimona and in Yeruham, are from Moroccan origin.  And this shows this very close ties between the kingdom and the population here.</p>
<p>Since the signing of the trilateral declaration in December, I think we have achieved a lot: visits, direct flights, agreements, and connecting people, which is also very important.  Very soon there will be a formal bilateral visit in which I think we will strengthen more our relations, including the diplomatic presence of Morocco here in Israel.</p>
<p>The second message is to the region, and I think we are here today because we genuinely, sincerely, and deeply believe in peace – not that kind of passive peace where we turn our backs to each other and peacefully ignore each other, but rather we believe in a thorough, fruitful, paradigm-shaping, and value-creating peace, the only kind of peace that is a battle worth waging.  And I think our presence is a message to that, a message to our people and a message to the people of the region.</p>
<p>We are here to create and to strengthen a positive dynamic, to create a different narrative about the relations between our people.  And I’m coming from a country with a longstanding coexistence between people from different faiths.  And if that’s more than has been successful in Morocco for centuries, it can also be possibly here in this region.</p>
<p>This dynamic is not just diplomatic; it should be tangible.  It should be felt by the people, and it should go into concrete, positive action which improve the lives of the people and open new horizons for the youth in our region.  And that’s why we are here.</p>
<p>We are here also to be a force of peace, and first to show that for the Israeli-Palestinian conflict a solution is possible, and for His Majesty King Mohammed VI, the position is constant.  We are for a two-state solution, living side by side with a Palestinian state in the borders of ’67 with East Jerusalem as capital, and a solution which will preserve the security and the interests of Israel.</p>
<p>I think a message to the region – a positive one, but also a message to those who are enemies of this positive dynamic – here in your region, also in North Africa, acting directly or through their proxies, our message should be that we are here to defend our values, to defend our interests, and that we are creating a shield to protect this positive dynamic.</p>
<p>I think there should be a spirit of Negev, a spirit which is coexistence, which is tangible results, and which is building for peace and challenging positively those who are the enemies of this peace.</p>
<p>I hope we will meet very soon in a different desert, but with the same spirit.  I thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you very much, Your Excellency.  I know have the honor to present His Highness Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed Al Nahyan, minister of foreign affairs and international cooperation of the United Arab Emirates, to address us.  His Highness, please.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER ABDULLAH BIN ZAYED:</b>  Let me start by thanking our host.  And Yair, you are not only a partner; you are a friend.  And we are so grateful for your kind hospitality, words, but also let me thank everyone here.  It just tells us all how much of a historic moment this is for everyone on the stage, but everyone in this room and beyond.</p>
<p>Forty-three years ago, when Egypt and Israel made peace, unfortunately we lost those 43 years of knowing each other better, of working together, and of changing the narrative that many generations of Israelis and Arabs have been living.  I think what we are trying to achieve here today is changing the narrative, creating a different future, and building on better hope for us and for our kids and grandkids.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s new for, I think, Abdullatif and Nasser and myself to be in Israel.  This is our first time.  So if we are curious sometimes and we want to know things and learn, it’s because although Israel has been part of this region for a very long time and – we’ve not known each other.  So it’s time to catch up, to build on a stronger relationship.  When I see 300,000 Israelis visiting the UAE in the last year and a half, but at the same time I see 2 million visitors visiting the Israeli pavilion in Expo in only the last six months, it says how curious and how much we want to know each other.</p>
<p>And this is what I think goes against what happened yesterday.  It’s by our standing together, it’s by our people-to-people relationship, it’s by creating a better environment for our businesses to work with each other – that’s the way we can go after the narrative of hate, of incitement, of terror.  We will prevail, no doubt.  It’s going to cost us, but it matters.  It matters to us, and we can do better on so many areas that either were mentioned in this gathering or mentioned today or yesterday.  It’s clear to me that there is a huge potential and everyone is excited about it.</p>
<p>And some – Egypt showed us leadership 43 years ago.  Thank you for that.  We are just trying to follow your footsteps.  And Tony, your presence here means a great deal, the United States not only being here but encouraging us to do more and building for a better, stable, and prosperous future for all.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you, Your Highness.  Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the first Negev Summit.  I would like to thank all of our guest, excellencies, and their delegations for coming here to Israel, to the Negev – and hoping for many more Negev summits.  Thank you.  <i>Toda raba</i>.  <i>Shukran</i>.  (Applause.)</p>
<div>
<hr />
<div>
<p><a href="#post-328858-footnote-ref-1"></a><a id="post-328858-footnote-1"></a> We’ve seen diplomacy flourish, with Morocco and Israel agreeing to open embassies in Rabat and Tel Aviv…</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a href="#post-328858-footnote-ref-2"></a><a id="post-328858-footnote-2"></a> Prime Minister Begin</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Sde Boker</p>
<p>Kedma Hotel</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Good afternoon, Excellencies, ladies and gentlemen.  We are starting now the last chapter of the Negev Summit, which are the press statements by all six foreign ministers.  First to address us is our host, Foreign Minister of the State of Israel His Excellency Yair Lapid.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER LAPID:  </b>Thank you, my friend Secretary of State Tony Blinken, Foreign Minister Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed, Foreign Minister Abdullatif Al Zayani, Foreign Minister Sameh Shoukry, and Foreign Minister Nasser Bourita.</p>
<p>Last night, for the second time in a week, terror struck in the heart of Israel – at the heart of Israel in two senses: in the heart of the country in a crowded city, and also in the heart of every Israeli citizen.  This was murder for the sake of murder, terror for the sake of terror.  These terrorists fired in every direction with one goal: to kill as many innocent people as possible, to shed as much blood as possible.  I send my condolences to the families of the murdered and my wishes for the full and speedy recovery of the wounded.  Our thoughts and prayers are with them today.</p>
<p>Shortly after the attack, Islamic Jihad and Hamas praised it.  They declared that it was a response to the Negev Summit we are holding here.  The terrorists’ goal is to intimidate us, to make us afraid to meet and to build relationships and the agreements between us.  They will not succeed; we will not let them.  We have no intention of rewarding terrorists.  We have no intention of letting them dictate our lives or our policies.  Israel is a strong and a proud country and will never surrender to terror.  We will continue on our path, the path of peace.</p>
<p>I am not alone in this.  Everyone here shares this sentiment.  Last night, all the foreign ministers participating in the summit condemned with one strong voice the horrific terror attack.  On behalf of the people of Israel, I thank you for this.</p>
<p>My friends, Israel’s founding father, David Ben Gurion, who is buried two minutes away from here, once said history is isn’t written, history is made.  What we are doing here is making history, building a new regional architecture based on progress, technology, religious tolerance, security, and intelligence cooperation.  This new architecture, the shared capabilities we are building, intimidates and deters our common enemies, first and foremost Iran and its proxies. They certainly have something to fear.  What will stop them is not hesitation or being conciliatory, but rather determination and strength.</p>
<p>Friends, we are standing here in the Negev where our common father went after signing the original Abraham Accords between him and the Lord.  In the book of Genesis, it is written:  Then Abram set out and continued towards the Negev.  He came here to build a better future for his people and his family, and we are here for the same reason.</p>
<p>The history of the Middle East is the story of smart and tough people who made the desert bloom.  Our peoples are those who stopped right here and said, in this place, in this desert, we will make life flourish.  From this desert will spring forth palaces and temples, schools and hospitals, inspirational art and literature, and groundbreaking technology.  This meeting is the first of its kind, but not the last.</p>
<p>Last night, we decided to make the Negev Summit into a permanent forum.  Together with our  closest friend and ally, the United States, we are today opening a door before all the peoples of the region, including the Palestinians, and offering them to replace the way of terror and destruction with shared future of progress and success.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Thank you, Minister Lapid.  Next to address us, Secretary of State of the United States Antony Blinken.  Please, sir.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.  Let me begin by joining Yair and all of my colleagues in condemning the horrific terrorist attack last night in Hadera, which killed two border police officers, both just 19 years old.  On behalf of President Biden, the American people, we extend our heartfelt condolences to the loved ones of the victims, Yazan Fallah and Shirel Aboukaret.  No family should have to experience such loss, and we stand in absolute solidarity with our friends and partners against terrorism and these horrific acts of violence.  And indeed, Yair, as you said, what we are doing here is the exact counterpoint to this senseless destruction and violence.</p>
<p>It’s an honor to be here with you, with Minister Bourita, with Minister Al Zayani, Minister Zayed, Minister Shoukry – the foreign ministers of Israel, Morocco, Bahrain, the United Arab Emirates, and Egypt – standing together in Israel.  Just a few years ago, this gathering would have been impossible to imagine.</p>
<p>You mentioned the original Abraham.  He had a dialogue with God.  He had the temerity sometimes to ask why.  We have the temerity, you have the temerity, to ask, why not?  That’s what this is about.  Since September 15<sup>th</sup>, 2020, when leaders from Israel, Bahrain, and the United Arab Emirates signed the Abraham Accords, and Morocco and Israel signed a normalization agreement soon after, once-impossible things have become possible.</p>
<p>We’ve seen democracy<a id="post-328858-footnote-ref-1" href="#post-328858-footnote-1"></a> flourish, with Morocco and Israel agreeing to open embassies in Rabat and Tel Aviv; Prime Minister Bennett becoming the first Israeli prime minister to visit Bahrain and the United Arab Emirates; and last week, the leaders of the United Arab Emirates, Israel, and Egypt meeting to launch new areas of cooperation.  We’ve seen growing economic ties, with Bahrain and Israel signing more than a dozen agreements, including on aviation, on banking, on technology; government and business leaders from Morocco and Israel meeting last week to promote tourism across both countries; a solar energy deal that will accelerate the green energy transition already underway in the region.</p>
<p>At the heart of these interactions are people, people eager to learn about and from one another.  Student exchanges are flourishing between Rabat and Tal Aviv.  A Holocaust memorial exhibition is now opened in Dubai.  Hospitals in Bahrain and Israel are teaming up on cancer research.  Tomorrow, soccer players from – or football players from your countries will play in the Abraham Accords festival and games at the Dubai Expo, where there’s also an Israel pavilion.</p>
<p>The Abraham Accords are making the lives of people across your countries more peaceful, more prosperous, more vibrant, more integrated.  They’re allowing governments to focus their energies and attentions on the issues that are actually affecting the lives of our citizens and making them better.  The United States has and will continue to strongly support a process that is transforming this region and beyond.  We’ll help to strengthen the bonds between Israel and its circle of friends, both those with which it has normalization agreements and those with which it has longstanding peace treaties, like Egypt and Jordan.</p>
<p>To name one example, later today officials from the United States, the UAE, and Israel will launch the Religious Coexistence Working Group to counter intolerance and promote understanding.  And we’ll help widen the circle of friendship to include other countries interested in securing greater peace and prosperity for their own people.  As we do, we have to be clear that these regional peace agreements are not a substitute for progress between Palestinians and Israelis.</p>
<p>One of the issues we discussed today was how countries involved in the Abraham Accords and normalization, as well as those that have longstanding diplomatic relationships with Israel, can support the Palestinian Authority and the Palestinian people in concrete ways and have a positive impact on the daily lives of Palestinians in the West Bank and Gaza.  This is a conversation we’ll carry forward so that we can work toward our goal of Palestinians and Israelis enjoying equal measures of freedom, security, opportunity, and dignity, and create the conditions for a negotiated two-state solution.  Finally, as neighbors, and in the case of the United States, as friends, we will also work together to confront common security challenges and threats, including those from Iran and its proxies.</p>
<p>Almost exactly 43 years ago, Israel and Egypt concluded the Camp David Accords.  At that time, standing between President Sadat and President<a id="post-328858-footnote-ref-2" href="#post-328858-footnote-2"></a> Begin, President Carter said this:  “We are privileged to witness…a significant achievement in the cause of peace, an achievement  none thought possible  a year ago.”  Well, those were different times.  Israel and its neighbors had just fought a war.  But that sentiment – that what was believed unchangeable was suddenly transformed, creating a new reality – this is also true today.  And as happens whenever you break down barriers that have long kept people from interacting, exchanging ideas, working together, it’s impossible to anticipate all the new directions that this can take us.  This is a new dawn.  The only limits are the ones we can imagine.</p>
<p>So I commend the courage of those willing to break down barriers, political leaders but also people across our societies, individual citizens who are forging new relationships as a result of this historic opening.  I am excited to see all that you and we can imagine and create together for one another, for the region, for the world.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Thank you, Mr. Secretary.  Now I invite His Excellency Abdullatif bin Rashid Al Zayani, minister of foreign affairs of the Kingdom of Bahrain, to address us.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER AL ZAYANI:  </b>Thank you.  Your Highness, Your Excellencies, ladies and gentlemen, it has been my great pleasure to participate in this distinguished gathering.  And I want to start by thanking Foreign Minister Lapid for the invitation. and indeed for the hospitality.</p>
<p>I would like to start by condemning the terrorist attack which took place last night, claiming the lives of two border policemen.  And I would like to convey our condolences to the bereaved families and reaffirm our firm stance against terrorism in all its forms.</p>
<p>I join you here on behalf of the Kingdom of Bahrain, a nation which has always been convinced in the importance of peace, dialogue, coexistence, and mutual respect, principles which are fully reflected and embodied in the vision of His Majesty King Hamad bin Isa Al Khalifa and the policies implemented by the government led by His Royal Highness Prince Salman bin Hamad Al Khalifa.</p>
<p>This is an important and timely meeting, and an opportunity to build on the historic 2020 Abraham Accords with a huge scope for growing the region’s prosperity, safeguarding its security, and realizing the aspirations of all its peoples.  The need to do so is made more urgent by recent developments such as the Houthi terrorist militia’s continued attacks on civilian energy infrastructure, the ongoing threat from terrorist organizations such as Hizballah and other proxy groups, and the need to resolve the Iranian nuclear file.</p>
<p>So we need to put into practice the principles behind the accords, namely those of dialogue, cooperation, and mutual respect.  We need to establish genuine, sustainable coexistence and interdependence between participants, building genuine networks of cooperation and trust to advance our common security and prosperity.  By doing so, we will demonstrate to the whole region what can be achieved by working together and show how, collectively, we can overcome shared regional challenges and seize opportunities in a way that would not – possible individually.  Of course, part of this process will be renewed efforts to resolve the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, and Bahrain continues to urge both parties to come together and negotiate a resolution that establishes a viable state for the Palestinians and protects the security and interests of all parties.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, in the Kingdom of Bahrain, we have moved quickly to build on the Abraham Accords and to rapidly expand our relationship with the state of Israel.  We see great potential for cooperation across all fields.  And over the past 18 months, we have already seen how this potential can be realized.  This forum is therefore an important step in deepening and strengthening these bilateral ties, but also in expanding multilateral cooperation and interdependence among all countries.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken, in this context, I would like to thank the United States of America for their support to the Abraham Accords and for their continued commitment to the security of the region.  And once again, thank you, Minister Lapid, for hosting this gathering and for these warm and constructive discussions.  And I very much look forward to our next meeting and to building further on what we have achieved today.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you very much, Excellency.  I now invite His Excellency Sameh Shoukry, minister of foreign affairs of Egypt, to address us.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER SHOUKRY:</b>  Minister Lapid, colleagues, ladies and gentlemen, let me first of all convey our appreciation to Minister Lapid for having convened these consultations.  They are – I think can be characterized by having been constructive and in-depth, and do address the various challenges that our region faces, turbulence related to regional and international conditions.  And we do so, the day before yesterday, having commemorated, as Secretary Blinken has referred to, the 43rd anniversary of the peace between Egypt and Israel, and we see constructive development in the normalization of relations and believe that the path that we set upon 43 years ago is coming to greater fruition and recognition of the importance and the viability of comprehensive peace and security for our region.</p>
<p>This round of discussions has given us an opportunity to highlight views related to how we can further progress in achieving our common objectives, and it certainly did during these discussions.  We did highlight the importance of the Israeli-Palestinian peace process, the importance of maintaining the credibility and the viability of the two-state solution that – for Israel and a Palestinian state to live side by side in peace with recognized borders for a Palestinian state in accordance with the ’67 lines with East Jerusalem as its capital.</p>
<p>This is an important issue, and Egypt has been striving over the years to facilitate and to assist both Israel and the Palestinians to reach the necessary accommodation and compromise that can facilitate an end of the conflict, and thereby open broader doors of regional cooperation, integration, and the benefits for the peoples of the region.  And of course, we do so in collaboration and with the assistance of our partner, the United States of America, and we value very much the coordination that exists and the common understanding related to the path and the way forward.</p>
<p>We certainly also consider and have on every occasion condemned all resort to violence, to terrorism, to incitement, and believe that it is our role as members of the international community but also as Arab states, states where there is a Muslim majority, as President al-Sisi has always declared, that we need to address the religious narrative and to confront extremism and terrorism and thereby provide peace and security for our region.  Also, the importance of addressing the issue of extra-regional intervention and the negative impact on the security and stability of our region.  We believe that we have the resources and the ability to meet those challenges with the help of our partners in the United States, and we’ll continue to seek areas of cooperation that provide for our protection of our national security interests within a peaceful and cooperative framework.</p>
<p>On all of these fronts, I think we have demonstrated our predictability, the dependence, the longevity of our peace with Israel, and that we are partners that can be depended on, and thereby we seek to enhance the areas of cooperation and interaction that can bring benefit to the region and to international peace and security.  For all of these reasons, we look forward to continuing this dialogue and to reaching a understanding and a consensus of how best to deal with the very many issues.  And here again, I think it is going to be incumbent and important on the short term to deal with the pressures that might arise and the importance of restricting any unilateral activity that might agitate the current situation and have an impact on the tranquility during a very sensitive and important time where we hope we can all direct our attention towards a higher cause rather than having to deal with crisis management.</p>
<p>I thank you again for the opportunity and I welcome this dialogue.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you very much, Your Excellency.  I now have the pleasure of inviting His Excellency Mr. Nasser Bourita, Minister of Foreign Affairs, African Cooperation and Moroccan Expatriates of the Kingdom of Morocco.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER BOURITA:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Please, sir.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER BOURITA:</b>  I would like to start by reiterating Morocco’s strong condemnation of the terrorist attacks of yesterday in Hadera and present our sincere condolences to the victims and our wish of recovery to all the injured.  Our presence today is, I think, the best response to such attacks.</p>
<p>I’m very delighted to be here in Negev in this very historic and timely Negev Summit, or, I should say, first Negev Summit.  And I would like to thank you, Yair, for the invitation, for choosing this very nice venue, and for the hospitality.</p>
<p>I would like also to thank you, Tony, for the presence, for the involvement, for the commitment.  The United States has been a reliable partner in promoting peace, and your personal commitment to this endeavor is very important to us.</p>
<p>Morocco’s presence here under instructions of His Majesty King Mohammed VI is meant to send two messages.  The first one is to our host and to the people of Israel.  As His Majesty King Mohammed VI said when we established the relations, this is not an opportunistic move.  It’s a move of conviction.  It’s a natural decision based on these longstanding relations between Morocco, Israel, and the kings of Morocco, and the Moroccan-Jewish community.</p>
<p>You are saying here that maybe every Israeli has in his family someone with Moroccan blood.  It’s not only a joke; it’s a reality.  I learned that two of the mayors of the main cities in the Negev, in Dimona and in Yeruham, are from Moroccan origin.  And this shows this very close ties between the kingdom and the population here.</p>
<p>Since the signing of the trilateral declaration in December, I think we have achieved a lot: visits, direct flights, agreements, and connecting people, which is also very important.  Very soon there will be a formal bilateral visit in which I think we will strengthen more our relations, including the diplomatic presence of Morocco here in Israel.</p>
<p>The second message is to the region, and I think we are here today because we genuinely, sincerely, and deeply believe in peace – not that kind of passive peace where we turn our backs to each other and peacefully ignore each other, but rather we believe in a thorough, fruitful, paradigm-shaping, and value-creating peace, the only kind of peace that is a battle worth waging.  And I think our presence is a message to that, a message to our people and a message to the people of the region.</p>
<p>We are here to create and to strengthen a positive dynamic, to create a different narrative about the relations between our people.  And I’m coming from a country with a longstanding coexistence between people from different faiths.  And if that’s more than has been successful in Morocco for centuries, it can also be possibly here in this region.</p>
<p>This dynamic is not just diplomatic; it should be tangible.  It should be felt by the people, and it should go into concrete, positive action which improve the lives of the people and open new horizons for the youth in our region.  And that’s why we are here.</p>
<p>We are here also to be a force of peace, and first to show that for the Israeli-Palestinian conflict a solution is possible, and for His Majesty King Mohammed VI, the position is constant.  We are for a two-state solution, living side by side with a Palestinian state in the borders of ’67 with East Jerusalem as capital, and a solution which will preserve the security and the interests of Israel.</p>
<p>I think a message to the region – a positive one, but also a message to those who are enemies of this positive dynamic – here in your region, also in North Africa, acting directly or through their proxies, our message should be that we are here to defend our values, to defend our interests, and that we are creating a shield to protect this positive dynamic.</p>
<p>I think there should be a spirit of Negev, a spirit which is coexistence, which is tangible results, and which is building for peace and challenging positively those who are the enemies of this peace.</p>
<p>I hope we will meet very soon in a different desert, but with the same spirit.  I thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you very much, Your Excellency.  I know have the honor to present His Highness Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed Al Nahyan, minister of foreign affairs and international cooperation of the United Arab Emirates, to address us.  His Highness, please.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER ABDULLAH BIN ZAYED:</b>  Let me start by thanking our host.  And Yair, you are not only a partner; you are a friend.  And we are so grateful for your kind hospitality, words, but also let me thank everyone here.  It just tells us all how much of a historic moment this is for everyone on the stage, but everyone in this room and beyond.</p>
<p>Forty-three years ago, when Egypt and Israel made peace, unfortunately we lost those 43 years of knowing each other better, of working together, and of changing the narrative that many generations of Israelis and Arabs have been living.  I think what we are trying to achieve here today is changing the narrative, creating a different future, and building on better hope for us and for our kids and grandkids.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s new for, I think, Abdullatif and Nasser and myself to be in Israel.  This is our first time.  So if we are curious sometimes and we want to know things and learn, it’s because although Israel has been part of this region for a very long time and – we’ve not known each other.  So it’s time to catch up, to build on a stronger relationship.  When I see 300,000 Israelis visiting the UAE in the last year and a half, but at the same time I see 2 million visitors visiting the Israeli pavilion in Expo in only the last six months, it says how curious and how much we want to know each other.</p>
<p>And this is what I think goes against what happened yesterday.  It’s by our standing together, it’s by our people-to-people relationship, it’s by creating a better environment for our businesses to work with each other – that’s the way we can go after the narrative of hate, of incitement, of terror.  We will prevail, no doubt.  It’s going to cost us, but it matters.  It matters to us, and we can do better on so many areas that either were mentioned in this gathering or mentioned today or yesterday.  It’s clear to me that there is a huge potential and everyone is excited about it.</p>
<p>And some – Egypt showed us leadership 43 years ago.  Thank you for that.  We are just trying to follow your footsteps.  And Tony, your presence here means a great deal, the United States not only being here but encouraging us to do more and building for a better, stable, and prosperous future for all.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you, Your Highness.  Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the first Negev Summit.  I would like to thank all of our guest, excellencies, and their delegations for coming here to Israel, to the Negev – and hoping for many more Negev summits.  Thank you.  <i>Toda raba</i>.  <i>Shukran</i>.  (Applause.)</p>
<div>
<hr />
<div>
<p><a href="#post-328858-footnote-ref-1"></a><a id="post-328858-footnote-1"></a> We’ve seen diplomacy flourish, with Morocco and Israel agreeing to open embassies in Rabat and Tel Aviv…</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a href="#post-328858-footnote-ref-2"></a><a id="post-328858-footnote-2"></a> Prime Minister Begin</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Saudi Foreign Minister Prince Faisal bin Farhan Al Saud</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-saudi-foreign-minister-prince-faisal-bin-farhan-al-saud-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 18:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=328857</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with the Foreign Minister of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, Prince Faisal bin Farhan Al Saud.  The Secretary again condemned the recent Houthi terrorist attacks against the Kingdom, and they discussed support for the UN’s proposal for a Ramadan truce in Yemen and efforts to launch a new, more inclusive and comprehensive peace process. The Secretary and the Foreign Minister also discussed the challenge posed by Iran’s nuclear program and building strong international support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity while holding President Putin accountable for his unprovoked and unlawful war.</p>
<p>The Secretary reiterated the U.S. commitment to bolstering Saudi Arabia’s defenses against threats in the region and emphasized the importance of protecting civilians in Yemen.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with the Foreign Minister of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, Prince Faisal bin Farhan Al Saud.  The Secretary again condemned the recent Houthi terrorist attacks against the Kingdom, and they discussed support for the UN’s proposal for a Ramadan truce in Yemen and efforts to launch a new, more inclusive and comprehensive peace process. The Secretary and the Foreign Minister also discussed the challenge posed by Iran’s nuclear program and building strong international support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity while holding President Putin accountable for his unprovoked and unlawful war.</p>
<p>The Secretary reiterated the U.S. commitment to bolstering Saudi Arabia’s defenses against threats in the region and emphasized the importance of protecting civilians in Yemen.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Department of State and U.S. Agency for International Development FY 2023 Budget Request </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-department-of-state-and-u-s-agency-for-international-development-fy-2023-budget-request/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 18:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=328831</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The President’s Fiscal Year 2023 Budget Request includes $60.4 billion for the Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), $1.9 billion or 3 percent above the Fiscal Year 2022 Request, and $7.4 billion or 14 percent above FY 2021 enacted levels.  Reflecting the priority that the Biden-Harris Administration places on global leadership, as well as the President’s belief that diplomacy and development are vital tools for advancing U.S. interests at home and abroad, the resources included in this Budget Request will advance the foreign policy agenda of the United States and deliver results for the American people.</p>
<p>At the Department of State and USAID, the Budget would:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Support Ukraine and Our Allies and Partners in the Region</strong>:  The Request includes $1.6 billion to support Ukraine against Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified invasion and assist other countries across Europe and Central Asia threatened by regional insecurity. The Request provides significant assistance to our allies and partners while building their capacity to counter actions from malign actors.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Affirm U.S. Alliances and Renew U.S. International Leadership</strong>: The Request maintains longstanding commitments to key partners; advances peace, prosperity, and security across the Indo-Pacific and Europe; expands diplomatic and development initiatives in Africa and Asia; and positions us to effectively compete with the People’s Republic of China (PRC) and Russia. The Request includes $4 billion to support U.S. commitments to international organizations and affirms U.S. leadership at a moment when our competitors are seeking to expand their influence.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Address the Climate Crisis</strong>: The Request has $2.3 billion to support U.S. leadership in addressing the existential climate crisis through diplomacy; scaled-up international climate programs that accelerate the global energy transition to net zero by 2050; support to developing countries to enhance climate resilience; and the prioritization of climate adaptation and sustainability principles in Department and USAID domestic and overseas facilities. This total includes over $1.6 billion for direct programming for climate mitigation and adaptation and over $650 million for the mainstreaming of climate considerations across development programs. Our goal is to deliver climate co-benefits and outcomes in sectors such as agriculture and food security, water and sanitation, and global health.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Advance American Leadership in Global Health, Including Global Health Security and Infectious Disease Response and Preparedness</strong>: The Budget Request includes $10.6 billion to bolster U.S. leadership in the face of an enduring COVID-19 pandemic and other global health challenges, $525 million above the FY 2022 Request. U.S. leadership is critical to the Global Fund’s seventh replenishment, and we are supporting a $2 billion contribution this year with an intended pledge of $6 billion over three years, to save lives and continue the fight against HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria, and to support the Global Fund’s expanded response to COVID-19 and global health strengthening. This total also includes $1 billion to prevent, prepare for, and respond to infectious disease outbreaks, including the continued expansion of Global Health Security Agenda capacity-building programs and contributions for a multilateral financial intermediary fund for health security and pandemic preparedness.</li>
</ul>
<p>The Budget also invests in the global health workforce and systems to enhance countries’ abilities to provide core health services, improve health systems resiliency, and respond to crises. In addition to Request for $60.4 billion in annual discretionary appropriations, the Budget includes $6.5 billion in mandatory funding for State and USAID over five years to make transformative investments in pandemic and other biological threat preparedness globally in support of U.S. biodefense and pandemic preparedness strategies and plans. The pandemic preparedness funding will strengthen the global health workforce, support pandemic preparedness research and development, advance global research and development capacity, and support health security financing to strengthen global capacity to prevent, detect, and respond to future COVID variants and other infectious disease outbreaks.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Address Food Insecurity and Foster Inclusive and Sustainable Agriculture-led Economic Growth</strong>: The conflict in Ukraine is exacerbating food insecurity around the world. In support of the President’s pledge to alleviate global food insecurity, we are providing over $1 billion in bilateral agriculture and food security programming. These investments are key to increasing access for communities, including those across Latin America, Africa, and Asia, to nutritious food, strengthening their resilience to shocks and stresses, and lifting them from entrenched poverty.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Champion an Open and Secure Digital and Technological Ecosystem</strong>: The Budget invests more than $350 million to expand reliable and affordable internet access through the development and deployment of secure digital and technological infrastructure. The Budget will improve international cybersecurity practices and promote the adoption of policies that support an open, interoperable, secure, and reliable internet. These resources will further develop programming across sectors, in support of the State Department’s new Bureau of Cyberspace and Digital Policy, and USAID’s digital development strategy. State and USAID will also seek to close the digital gender gap in low- and middle-income countries by increasing women and girls’ access to information communication technologies and address online harassment and abuse globally.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reinvigorate U.S. Leadership in International Institutions</strong>: The Budget requests $4 billion, including an increase of nearly $400 million, to reduce peacekeeping arrears, continue the Administration’s efforts to lead through international organizations by meeting commitments to international organizations and pay contributions United Nations peacekeeping missions on time and in full. Strengthening international partnerships is critical to meeting the Sustainable Development Goals, including global education, ending hunger and malnutrition, building more sustainable, equitable, and resilient food systems, and addressing other global challenges.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Defend Democracy Globally</strong>: In response to increasing authoritarianism around the world, the Request has more than $3.2 billion to advance democratization, protect universal human rights, bolster anti-corruption work, and increase programming that builds inclusive, legitimate, and effective governance – consistent with the commitments made during the President’s Summit for Democracy.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Revitalize Alliances and Partnerships in the Indo-Pacific</strong>: To strengthen and modernize America’s alliances and partnerships in a vital global region and affirm U.S. leadership in strategic competition, the Request includes $1.8 billion to implement the Indo-Pacific Strategy to support a free, open, connected, secure, and resilient Indo-Pacific Region, and an additional $400 million for the Countering PRC Malign Influence Fund (CPMIF).</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Continue Collaborative U.S. Leadership in Central America and Haiti</strong>: As part of a comprehensive strategy to advance systemic reform while addressing the root causes of irregular migration from Central America to the United States, the Budget invests $986.8 million in the region towards the President’s commitment to provide $4 billion in assistance for Central America over four years. Also, in response to deteriorating conditions and widespread violence in Haiti, the Budget invests $274.8 million to support Haiti’s recovery from political and economic shocks, such as increasing the capacity of the Haitian National Police, combating corruption, strengthening the capacity of civil society, and supporting services for marginalized populations. These investments will ensure that the U.S. is able to revitalize partnerships that build economic resilience, democratic stability, and citizen security in the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Support America’s Allies in the Middle East</strong>: The Budget fully supports the U.S.-Israel Memorandum of Understanding for $3.3 billion in military assistance, provides up to $1.45 billion in economic and security assistance for Jordan, and includes $1.4 billion to support the U.S. diplomatic and security partnership with Egypt. As part of the Administration’s commitment to advancing security, prosperity, and freedom for both Israelis and Palestinians, the Budget includes $219 million for critical assistance to the Palestinian people in the West Bank and Gaza.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Strengthen African Engagement</strong>: The Budget provides $7.8 billion for sub-Saharan Africa, including more than $250 million in support of the second U.S.-Africa Leaders’ Summit to strengthen ties with African partners based on principles of mutual respect and shared interests and values. These investments will strengthen collaboration, trade and investment, electrification, ecosystems for mutual growth and prosperity, and promote digital transformation in Africa.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Strengthen U.S. Leadership on Refugee and Humanitarian Issues</strong>: The Budget provides $10.45 billion in State and USAID resources to respond to the unprecedented humanitarian need arising from conflict and natural disasters around the world to serve over 70 countries and approximately 240 million people. The Budget continues to rebuild and strengthen the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Advance Equity and Equality Globally</strong>: The Budget provides $2.6 billion to advance gender equity and equality and to support underserved communities across a broad range of sectors. This includes $200 million for the Gender Equity and Equality Action (GEEA) Fund to advance the economic security of women and girls. This total also includes funding to strengthen the participation of women in conflict prevention, resolution, and recovery through the implementation of the Women, Peace, and Security Act. To further implement the President’s Executive Order advancing racial equity and support for underserved communities, the Budget will better integrate equity through more inclusive policies, strategies, and practice including enhancing the ability of potential non-traditional partners to pursue federal opportunities and address the barriers they face in the federal award process, and new efforts to identify spaces to support and advance underserved population appropriate to the country context.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Invest in and Expand the Diplomatic and Development Workforce</strong>: The Budget will revitalize and expand the diplomatic and development workforce by providing $7.6 billion to recruit, retain, and develop the diverse, highly capable workforce needed to support efforts around the world and manage complex national security issues. It advances diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility across both agencies through increasing investment in diversifying the foreign affairs workforce to reflect and draw on the richness and diversity of the United States, including through targeted fellowship programs. It also strengthens the Department’s cybersecurity posture and secure communications capability.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sustain Diplomatic and Embassy Security</strong>: The Budget will sustain Diplomatic and Embassy Security funding at $5.8 billion to keep our people, buildings, and information around the globe safe and secure. This includes funding for Anomalous Health Incident (AHI) monitoring and research, countering the emerging threat of drones to diplomatic facilities, and strengthening our cybersecurity against malign actors.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, please visit <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMjguNTU1NjI2MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi9jaiJ9.mHJhgvso-ngZAXSuAeIeZIh71LjlxGeuZyARWQeUS6k/s/1039202793/br/128747427189-l" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMjguNTU1NjI2MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi9jaiJ9.mHJhgvso-ngZAXSuAeIeZIh71LjlxGeuZyARWQeUS6k/s/1039202793/br/128747427189-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1648576676558000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1XbU_VmBV9agdyAKC_yMbz">www.state.gov/cj</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The President’s Fiscal Year 2023 Budget Request includes $60.4 billion for the Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), $1.9 billion or 3 percent above the Fiscal Year 2022 Request, and $7.4 billion or 14 percent above FY 2021 enacted levels.  Reflecting the priority that the Biden-Harris Administration places on global leadership, as well as the President’s belief that diplomacy and development are vital tools for advancing U.S. interests at home and abroad, the resources included in this Budget Request will advance the foreign policy agenda of the United States and deliver results for the American people.</p>
<p>At the Department of State and USAID, the Budget would:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Support Ukraine and Our Allies and Partners in the Region</strong>:  The Request includes $1.6 billion to support Ukraine against Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified invasion and assist other countries across Europe and Central Asia threatened by regional insecurity. The Request provides significant assistance to our allies and partners while building their capacity to counter actions from malign actors.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Affirm U.S. Alliances and Renew U.S. International Leadership</strong>: The Request maintains longstanding commitments to key partners; advances peace, prosperity, and security across the Indo-Pacific and Europe; expands diplomatic and development initiatives in Africa and Asia; and positions us to effectively compete with the People’s Republic of China (PRC) and Russia. The Request includes $4 billion to support U.S. commitments to international organizations and affirms U.S. leadership at a moment when our competitors are seeking to expand their influence.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Address the Climate Crisis</strong>: The Request has $2.3 billion to support U.S. leadership in addressing the existential climate crisis through diplomacy; scaled-up international climate programs that accelerate the global energy transition to net zero by 2050; support to developing countries to enhance climate resilience; and the prioritization of climate adaptation and sustainability principles in Department and USAID domestic and overseas facilities. This total includes over $1.6 billion for direct programming for climate mitigation and adaptation and over $650 million for the mainstreaming of climate considerations across development programs. Our goal is to deliver climate co-benefits and outcomes in sectors such as agriculture and food security, water and sanitation, and global health.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Advance American Leadership in Global Health, Including Global Health Security and Infectious Disease Response and Preparedness</strong>: The Budget Request includes $10.6 billion to bolster U.S. leadership in the face of an enduring COVID-19 pandemic and other global health challenges, $525 million above the FY 2022 Request. U.S. leadership is critical to the Global Fund’s seventh replenishment, and we are supporting a $2 billion contribution this year with an intended pledge of $6 billion over three years, to save lives and continue the fight against HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria, and to support the Global Fund’s expanded response to COVID-19 and global health strengthening. This total also includes $1 billion to prevent, prepare for, and respond to infectious disease outbreaks, including the continued expansion of Global Health Security Agenda capacity-building programs and contributions for a multilateral financial intermediary fund for health security and pandemic preparedness.</li>
</ul>
<p>The Budget also invests in the global health workforce and systems to enhance countries’ abilities to provide core health services, improve health systems resiliency, and respond to crises. In addition to Request for $60.4 billion in annual discretionary appropriations, the Budget includes $6.5 billion in mandatory funding for State and USAID over five years to make transformative investments in pandemic and other biological threat preparedness globally in support of U.S. biodefense and pandemic preparedness strategies and plans. The pandemic preparedness funding will strengthen the global health workforce, support pandemic preparedness research and development, advance global research and development capacity, and support health security financing to strengthen global capacity to prevent, detect, and respond to future COVID variants and other infectious disease outbreaks.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Address Food Insecurity and Foster Inclusive and Sustainable Agriculture-led Economic Growth</strong>: The conflict in Ukraine is exacerbating food insecurity around the world. In support of the President’s pledge to alleviate global food insecurity, we are providing over $1 billion in bilateral agriculture and food security programming. These investments are key to increasing access for communities, including those across Latin America, Africa, and Asia, to nutritious food, strengthening their resilience to shocks and stresses, and lifting them from entrenched poverty.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Champion an Open and Secure Digital and Technological Ecosystem</strong>: The Budget invests more than $350 million to expand reliable and affordable internet access through the development and deployment of secure digital and technological infrastructure. The Budget will improve international cybersecurity practices and promote the adoption of policies that support an open, interoperable, secure, and reliable internet. These resources will further develop programming across sectors, in support of the State Department’s new Bureau of Cyberspace and Digital Policy, and USAID’s digital development strategy. State and USAID will also seek to close the digital gender gap in low- and middle-income countries by increasing women and girls’ access to information communication technologies and address online harassment and abuse globally.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reinvigorate U.S. Leadership in International Institutions</strong>: The Budget requests $4 billion, including an increase of nearly $400 million, to reduce peacekeeping arrears, continue the Administration’s efforts to lead through international organizations by meeting commitments to international organizations and pay contributions United Nations peacekeeping missions on time and in full. Strengthening international partnerships is critical to meeting the Sustainable Development Goals, including global education, ending hunger and malnutrition, building more sustainable, equitable, and resilient food systems, and addressing other global challenges.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Defend Democracy Globally</strong>: In response to increasing authoritarianism around the world, the Request has more than $3.2 billion to advance democratization, protect universal human rights, bolster anti-corruption work, and increase programming that builds inclusive, legitimate, and effective governance – consistent with the commitments made during the President’s Summit for Democracy.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Revitalize Alliances and Partnerships in the Indo-Pacific</strong>: To strengthen and modernize America’s alliances and partnerships in a vital global region and affirm U.S. leadership in strategic competition, the Request includes $1.8 billion to implement the Indo-Pacific Strategy to support a free, open, connected, secure, and resilient Indo-Pacific Region, and an additional $400 million for the Countering PRC Malign Influence Fund (CPMIF).</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Continue Collaborative U.S. Leadership in Central America and Haiti</strong>: As part of a comprehensive strategy to advance systemic reform while addressing the root causes of irregular migration from Central America to the United States, the Budget invests $986.8 million in the region towards the President’s commitment to provide $4 billion in assistance for Central America over four years. Also, in response to deteriorating conditions and widespread violence in Haiti, the Budget invests $274.8 million to support Haiti’s recovery from political and economic shocks, such as increasing the capacity of the Haitian National Police, combating corruption, strengthening the capacity of civil society, and supporting services for marginalized populations. These investments will ensure that the U.S. is able to revitalize partnerships that build economic resilience, democratic stability, and citizen security in the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Support America’s Allies in the Middle East</strong>: The Budget fully supports the U.S.-Israel Memorandum of Understanding for $3.3 billion in military assistance, provides up to $1.45 billion in economic and security assistance for Jordan, and includes $1.4 billion to support the U.S. diplomatic and security partnership with Egypt. As part of the Administration’s commitment to advancing security, prosperity, and freedom for both Israelis and Palestinians, the Budget includes $219 million for critical assistance to the Palestinian people in the West Bank and Gaza.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Strengthen African Engagement</strong>: The Budget provides $7.8 billion for sub-Saharan Africa, including more than $250 million in support of the second U.S.-Africa Leaders’ Summit to strengthen ties with African partners based on principles of mutual respect and shared interests and values. These investments will strengthen collaboration, trade and investment, electrification, ecosystems for mutual growth and prosperity, and promote digital transformation in Africa.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Strengthen U.S. Leadership on Refugee and Humanitarian Issues</strong>: The Budget provides $10.45 billion in State and USAID resources to respond to the unprecedented humanitarian need arising from conflict and natural disasters around the world to serve over 70 countries and approximately 240 million people. The Budget continues to rebuild and strengthen the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Advance Equity and Equality Globally</strong>: The Budget provides $2.6 billion to advance gender equity and equality and to support underserved communities across a broad range of sectors. This includes $200 million for the Gender Equity and Equality Action (GEEA) Fund to advance the economic security of women and girls. This total also includes funding to strengthen the participation of women in conflict prevention, resolution, and recovery through the implementation of the Women, Peace, and Security Act. To further implement the President’s Executive Order advancing racial equity and support for underserved communities, the Budget will better integrate equity through more inclusive policies, strategies, and practice including enhancing the ability of potential non-traditional partners to pursue federal opportunities and address the barriers they face in the federal award process, and new efforts to identify spaces to support and advance underserved population appropriate to the country context.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Invest in and Expand the Diplomatic and Development Workforce</strong>: The Budget will revitalize and expand the diplomatic and development workforce by providing $7.6 billion to recruit, retain, and develop the diverse, highly capable workforce needed to support efforts around the world and manage complex national security issues. It advances diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility across both agencies through increasing investment in diversifying the foreign affairs workforce to reflect and draw on the richness and diversity of the United States, including through targeted fellowship programs. It also strengthens the Department’s cybersecurity posture and secure communications capability.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sustain Diplomatic and Embassy Security</strong>: The Budget will sustain Diplomatic and Embassy Security funding at $5.8 billion to keep our people, buildings, and information around the globe safe and secure. This includes funding for Anomalous Health Incident (AHI) monitoring and research, countering the emerging threat of drones to diplomatic facilities, and strengthening our cybersecurity against malign actors.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, please visit <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMjguNTU1NjI2MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi9jaiJ9.mHJhgvso-ngZAXSuAeIeZIh71LjlxGeuZyARWQeUS6k/s/1039202793/br/128747427189-l" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMjguNTU1NjI2MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi9jaiJ9.mHJhgvso-ngZAXSuAeIeZIh71LjlxGeuZyARWQeUS6k/s/1039202793/br/128747427189-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1648576676558000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1XbU_VmBV9agdyAKC_yMbz">www.state.gov/cj</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Republic of Singapore Signs the Artemis Accords</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/republic-of-singapore-signs-the-artemis-accords/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 18:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=328816</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>In August 2021, as part of Vice President Kamala Harris’s trip to Singapore, the United States and Singapore agreed on the importance of creating a safe and transparent environment that facilitates space exploration, science, and commercial activities for all of humanity to enjoy. Vice President Harris and Singaporean Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong discussed opportunities to expand bilateral cooperation in the field of space.</p>
<p>Today, as a product of that expanded dialogue and cooperation on space, Minister for Trade and Industry Gan Kim Yong signed the Artemis Accords on behalf of the Republic of Singapore in a ceremony in Washington, DC.  This important statement of commitment to the peaceful and safe exploration of space was welcomed by Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary J.R. Littlejohn and National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) Deputy Administrator Pam Melroy.</p>
<p>Led by the Department of State and NASA, the Artemis Accords are grounded in the Outer Space Treaty of 1967 and promote values-based cooperation and encourage responsible and safe behavior in space.  These principles for space exploration also underpin NASA’s Artemis Program, which seeks to land the first woman and first person of color on the Moon, while preparing to conduct a human mission to Mars.</p>
<p>Singapore is the 18th country to sign the Accords, joining Australia, Bahrain, Brazil, Canada, Israel, Italy, Japan, the Republic of Korea, Luxembourg, Mexico, New Zealand, Poland, Romania, Ukraine, the United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, and the United States.  These nations are leading the world in operationalizing principles for the responsible exploration of space.</p>
<p>For further information on the Artemis Accords, visit <a class="external-link" href="https://www.nasa.gov/specials/artemis-accords/index.html" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://www.nasa.gov/specials/artemis-accords/index.html.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>In August 2021, as part of Vice President Kamala Harris’s trip to Singapore, the United States and Singapore agreed on the importance of creating a safe and transparent environment that facilitates space exploration, science, and commercial activities for all of humanity to enjoy. Vice President Harris and Singaporean Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong discussed opportunities to expand bilateral cooperation in the field of space.</p>
<p>Today, as a product of that expanded dialogue and cooperation on space, Minister for Trade and Industry Gan Kim Yong signed the Artemis Accords on behalf of the Republic of Singapore in a ceremony in Washington, DC.  This important statement of commitment to the peaceful and safe exploration of space was welcomed by Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary J.R. Littlejohn and National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) Deputy Administrator Pam Melroy.</p>
<p>Led by the Department of State and NASA, the Artemis Accords are grounded in the Outer Space Treaty of 1967 and promote values-based cooperation and encourage responsible and safe behavior in space.  These principles for space exploration also underpin NASA’s Artemis Program, which seeks to land the first woman and first person of color on the Moon, while preparing to conduct a human mission to Mars.</p>
<p>Singapore is the 18th country to sign the Accords, joining Australia, Bahrain, Brazil, Canada, Israel, Italy, Japan, the Republic of Korea, Luxembourg, Mexico, New Zealand, Poland, Romania, Ukraine, the United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, and the United States.  These nations are leading the world in operationalizing principles for the responsible exploration of space.</p>
<p>For further information on the Artemis Accords, visit <a class="external-link" href="https://www.nasa.gov/specials/artemis-accords/index.html" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://www.nasa.gov/specials/artemis-accords/index.html.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The President’s Fiscal Year 2023 Budget</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/on-the-presidents-fiscal-year-2023-budget/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 17:57:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=328811</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>President Biden believes deeply in the ability of U.S. global leadership to solve challenges, and the Administration recognizes that diplomacy and development are vital tools for advancing U.S. interests and values. That is why the Fiscal Year 2023 President’s Budget requests $60.4 billion for the Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), $1.9 billion, or 3 percent, above the Fiscal Year 2022 Request, and $7.4 billion, or 14 percent, above FY 2021 enacted levels. With these resources, we can advance our foreign policy agenda and deliver for the American people.</p>
<p>The Budget will fund a range of Department of State and USAID priorities, including:</p>
<p><strong>Support for Ukraine and Our Allies and Partners in the Region</strong>: The Request includes $1.6 billion to support Ukraine against Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified invasion and assist other countries across Europe and Central Asia threatened by regional insecurity. The Request provides significant assistance to our allies and partners while building their capacity to counter actions from malign actors.</p>
<p><strong>Affirming U.S. Alliances and Renewing U.S. International Leadership</strong>: The Request maintains longstanding commitments to key partners; advances peace, prosperity, and security across the Indo-Pacific and Europe; expands diplomatic and development initiatives in Africa and Asia; and positions us to effectively compete with the People’s Republic of China (PRC) and Russia. This Request includes $4 billion to support U.S. commitments to international organizations and affirms U.S. leadership at a moment when our competitors are seeking to expand their influence.</p>
<p><strong>Addressing the Climate Crisis</strong>: The Request has $2.3 billion to support U.S. leadership in addressing the existential climate crisis through diplomacy; scaled-up international climate programs that accelerate the global energy transition to net zero by 2050; support to developing countries to enhance climate resilience; and the prioritization of climate adaptation and sustainability principles in Department and USAID domestic and overseas facilities.</p>
<p><strong>Strengthening Global Health Systems</strong>: The United States is the international leader in advancing global health outcomes that benefit the American people and millions of others around the world. The Budget requests $10.6 billion in Department and USAID funding to continue to collaborate with international partners to invest in cross-cutting health systems to prevent child and maternal deaths, combat infectious diseases, and control HIV/AIDS.</p>
<p><strong>Revitalizing Alliances and Partnerships in the Indo-Pacific</strong>: To strengthen and modernize America’s alliances and partnerships in a vital global region and affirm U.S. leadership in strategic competition, the Request includes $1.8 billion to implement the Indo-Pacific Strategy to support a free, open, connected, secure, and resilient Indo-Pacific Region, and an additional $400 million for the Countering PRC Malign Influence Fund (CPMIF).</p>
<p><strong>Defending Democracy Globally</strong>: In response to increasing authoritarianism around the world, the Request has more than $3.2 billion to advance democratization, protect universal human rights, bolster anti-corruption work, and increase programming that builds inclusive, legitimate, and effective governance – consistent with the commitments made during the President’s Summit for Democracy.</p>
<p><strong>Promoting Gender Equity and Equality Worldwide</strong>: The Request includes $2.6 billion to advance gender equity and equality across a broad range of sectors, more than doubling such funding over the FY 2022 Budget. This entails $200 million for the Gender Equity and Equality Action (GEEA) Fund to advance the economic security of women and girls.</p>
<p><strong>Revitalizing and Expanding the Diplomatic and Development Workforce</strong>: This Request would equip the Department and USAID to continue to recruit, retain, and develop a diverse, dynamic, and highly capable workforce to tackle 21st century challenges. It advances diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility; supports professional development opportunities; and builds capacity in critical new areas such as cyberspace and emerging technology.</p>
<p>The Budget Request makes these smart investments while also reducing deficits and improving our country’s long-term fiscal outlook.</p>
<p>The State Department and USAID are also releasing today the new 2022-2026 Joint Strategic Plan (JSP), a four-year joint plan that serves as the primary State and USAID strategy for advancing our foreign policy and development priorities in both organizations. The JSP is organized around five goals, as reflected in the Request as well: renewing U.S. leadership and mobilizing coalitions to address the global challenges that have the greatest impact on Americans’ security and well-being; promoting global prosperity and shaping an international environment in which the United States can thrive; strengthening democratic institutions, upholding universal values, and promoting human dignity; revitalizing the diplomatic and development workforce and institutions, and serving U.S. citizens around the world and facilitating secure international travel.</p>
<p>Concurrent with the publication of the Joint Strategic Plan and in support of the <em>Foundations for Evidence-Based Policymaking Act of 2018, </em>the Department will release the 2022 Capacity Assessment for Research, Evaluation, Statistics and Other Analysis, and the Annual Evaluation Plan. The Department’s first enterprise–wide Learning Agenda will be released in April. Together these three documents will promote building evidence and learning in pursuit of the objectives detailed in the Joint Strategic Plan.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>President Biden believes deeply in the ability of U.S. global leadership to solve challenges, and the Administration recognizes that diplomacy and development are vital tools for advancing U.S. interests and values. That is why the Fiscal Year 2023 President’s Budget requests $60.4 billion for the Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), $1.9 billion, or 3 percent, above the Fiscal Year 2022 Request, and $7.4 billion, or 14 percent, above FY 2021 enacted levels. With these resources, we can advance our foreign policy agenda and deliver for the American people.</p>
<p>The Budget will fund a range of Department of State and USAID priorities, including:</p>
<p><strong>Support for Ukraine and Our Allies and Partners in the Region</strong>: The Request includes $1.6 billion to support Ukraine against Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified invasion and assist other countries across Europe and Central Asia threatened by regional insecurity. The Request provides significant assistance to our allies and partners while building their capacity to counter actions from malign actors.</p>
<p><strong>Affirming U.S. Alliances and Renewing U.S. International Leadership</strong>: The Request maintains longstanding commitments to key partners; advances peace, prosperity, and security across the Indo-Pacific and Europe; expands diplomatic and development initiatives in Africa and Asia; and positions us to effectively compete with the People’s Republic of China (PRC) and Russia. This Request includes $4 billion to support U.S. commitments to international organizations and affirms U.S. leadership at a moment when our competitors are seeking to expand their influence.</p>
<p><strong>Addressing the Climate Crisis</strong>: The Request has $2.3 billion to support U.S. leadership in addressing the existential climate crisis through diplomacy; scaled-up international climate programs that accelerate the global energy transition to net zero by 2050; support to developing countries to enhance climate resilience; and the prioritization of climate adaptation and sustainability principles in Department and USAID domestic and overseas facilities.</p>
<p><strong>Strengthening Global Health Systems</strong>: The United States is the international leader in advancing global health outcomes that benefit the American people and millions of others around the world. The Budget requests $10.6 billion in Department and USAID funding to continue to collaborate with international partners to invest in cross-cutting health systems to prevent child and maternal deaths, combat infectious diseases, and control HIV/AIDS.</p>
<p><strong>Revitalizing Alliances and Partnerships in the Indo-Pacific</strong>: To strengthen and modernize America’s alliances and partnerships in a vital global region and affirm U.S. leadership in strategic competition, the Request includes $1.8 billion to implement the Indo-Pacific Strategy to support a free, open, connected, secure, and resilient Indo-Pacific Region, and an additional $400 million for the Countering PRC Malign Influence Fund (CPMIF).</p>
<p><strong>Defending Democracy Globally</strong>: In response to increasing authoritarianism around the world, the Request has more than $3.2 billion to advance democratization, protect universal human rights, bolster anti-corruption work, and increase programming that builds inclusive, legitimate, and effective governance – consistent with the commitments made during the President’s Summit for Democracy.</p>
<p><strong>Promoting Gender Equity and Equality Worldwide</strong>: The Request includes $2.6 billion to advance gender equity and equality across a broad range of sectors, more than doubling such funding over the FY 2022 Budget. This entails $200 million for the Gender Equity and Equality Action (GEEA) Fund to advance the economic security of women and girls.</p>
<p><strong>Revitalizing and Expanding the Diplomatic and Development Workforce</strong>: This Request would equip the Department and USAID to continue to recruit, retain, and develop a diverse, dynamic, and highly capable workforce to tackle 21st century challenges. It advances diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility; supports professional development opportunities; and builds capacity in critical new areas such as cyberspace and emerging technology.</p>
<p>The Budget Request makes these smart investments while also reducing deficits and improving our country’s long-term fiscal outlook.</p>
<p>The State Department and USAID are also releasing today the new 2022-2026 Joint Strategic Plan (JSP), a four-year joint plan that serves as the primary State and USAID strategy for advancing our foreign policy and development priorities in both organizations. The JSP is organized around five goals, as reflected in the Request as well: renewing U.S. leadership and mobilizing coalitions to address the global challenges that have the greatest impact on Americans’ security and well-being; promoting global prosperity and shaping an international environment in which the United States can thrive; strengthening democratic institutions, upholding universal values, and promoting human dignity; revitalizing the diplomatic and development workforce and institutions, and serving U.S. citizens around the world and facilitating secure international travel.</p>
<p>Concurrent with the publication of the Joint Strategic Plan and in support of the <em>Foundations for Evidence-Based Policymaking Act of 2018, </em>the Department will release the 2022 Capacity Assessment for Research, Evaluation, Statistics and Other Analysis, and the Annual Evaluation Plan. The Department’s first enterprise–wide Learning Agenda will be released in April. Together these three documents will promote building evidence and learning in pursuit of the objectives detailed in the Joint Strategic Plan.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Overseas Schools Advisory Council Meeting on Thursday, April 7, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/overseas-schools-advisory-council-meeting-on-thursday-april-7-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 12:51:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=328674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Overseas Schools Advisory Council of the Department of State will hold its winter meeting on Thursday, April 7, 2022.  This meeting is open to the public for virtual participation only.  The meeting will focus on the work and support the Overseas Schools Advisory Council provides to U.S.-sponsored overseas schools.  Topics will include the Child Protection Project, and the Social Emotional Learning Project.  In addition, the Regional Education Officers will present on various activities and initiatives in U.S.-sponsored overseas schools.</p>
<p>Members of the public who wish to attend the meeting virtually should contact Mr. Mark E. Ulfers, Executive Secretary of the Overseas Advisory Council of the Department of State at (202) 261-8200, April 3 to receive the virtual platform instructions.  The public may take part in the discussion, time permitting and at the discretion of the chairperson.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact Joyce L Picado via email at <a href="mailto:PicadoJL@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PicadoJL@state.gov</a> or by phone at 202-261-8203.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Overseas Schools Advisory Council of the Department of State will hold its winter meeting on Thursday, April 7, 2022.  This meeting is open to the public for virtual participation only.  The meeting will focus on the work and support the Overseas Schools Advisory Council provides to U.S.-sponsored overseas schools.  Topics will include the Child Protection Project, and the Social Emotional Learning Project.  In addition, the Regional Education Officers will present on various activities and initiatives in U.S.-sponsored overseas schools.</p>
<p>Members of the public who wish to attend the meeting virtually should contact Mr. Mark E. Ulfers, Executive Secretary of the Overseas Advisory Council of the Department of State at (202) 261-8200, April 3 to receive the virtual platform instructions.  The public may take part in the discussion, time permitting and at the discretion of the chairperson.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact Joyce L Picado via email at <a href="mailto:PicadoJL@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PicadoJL@state.gov</a> or by phone at 202-261-8203.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary Zeya’s Visit to Tunisia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-zeyas-visit-to-tunisia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 03:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=328593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary of State for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights Uzra Zeya visited Tunisia on March 23-27, where she underscored the importance of strengthening democracy in Tunisia and implementing an inclusive political and economic reform process, in coordination with political parties, unions, and civil society.</p>
<p>Over the course of her visit, Under Secretary Zeya met with senior government officials, including Prime Minister Najla Bouden, Foreign Minister Othman Jerandi, and Minister of Interior Taoufik Charfeddine.  She also met with representatives of Tunisia’s vibrant civil society, including human rights defenders, anti-corruption activists, and journalists.  In her meetings, the Under Secretary underscored U.S. concern for Tunisia’s democratic trajectory and the importance of an inclusive political and economic reform process that gives civil society a strong voice.  She was heartened by government assurances of inclusivity during implementation of the political roadmap.  Under Secretary Zeya reiterated the need to respect human rights, including freedom of expression and association for all Tunisians, as stipulated in the Constitution and International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights.  She also underscored that an independent judiciary is key to a strong and healthy democracy, and urged the government to cease trying civilians in military courts and prosecution of individuals for peaceful freedom of expression.  The Under Secretary visited Tunisia’s Independent High Authority for Elections, where she stressed U.S. commitment to free and fair elections and support for this key democratic institution to fulfill its constitutionally mandated role to run the upcoming referendum and parliamentary elections.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Zeya discussed with Tunisian officials the dire impact of Russia’s brutal invasion of Ukraine, which put at least a thousand Tunisians there at risk and threatens to disrupt the supply of critical agricultural commodities from the Black Sea region.  She thanked Tunisia for its support for United Nations General Assembly resolutions on the Ukraine humanitarian crisis and condemning Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified aggression, underscoring the need for sustained international solidarity to support the Ukrainian people and mitigate the negative impact of Russia’s invasion on international food security.</p>
<p>In her capacity leading U.S. programs in support of civil society, migrants, and refugees, Under Secretary Zeya visited a shelter supporting female survivors of gender-based violence and human trafficking where the United States works with the International Organization for Migration, the Government of Tunisia, and civil society to provide critically needed assistance and advance a victim-centered approach.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary of State for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights Uzra Zeya visited Tunisia on March 23-27, where she underscored the importance of strengthening democracy in Tunisia and implementing an inclusive political and economic reform process, in coordination with political parties, unions, and civil society.</p>
<p>Over the course of her visit, Under Secretary Zeya met with senior government officials, including Prime Minister Najla Bouden, Foreign Minister Othman Jerandi, and Minister of Interior Taoufik Charfeddine.  She also met with representatives of Tunisia’s vibrant civil society, including human rights defenders, anti-corruption activists, and journalists.  In her meetings, the Under Secretary underscored U.S. concern for Tunisia’s democratic trajectory and the importance of an inclusive political and economic reform process that gives civil society a strong voice.  She was heartened by government assurances of inclusivity during implementation of the political roadmap.  Under Secretary Zeya reiterated the need to respect human rights, including freedom of expression and association for all Tunisians, as stipulated in the Constitution and International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights.  She also underscored that an independent judiciary is key to a strong and healthy democracy, and urged the government to cease trying civilians in military courts and prosecution of individuals for peaceful freedom of expression.  The Under Secretary visited Tunisia’s Independent High Authority for Elections, where she stressed U.S. commitment to free and fair elections and support for this key democratic institution to fulfill its constitutionally mandated role to run the upcoming referendum and parliamentary elections.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Zeya discussed with Tunisian officials the dire impact of Russia’s brutal invasion of Ukraine, which put at least a thousand Tunisians there at risk and threatens to disrupt the supply of critical agricultural commodities from the Black Sea region.  She thanked Tunisia for its support for United Nations General Assembly resolutions on the Ukraine humanitarian crisis and condemning Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified aggression, underscoring the need for sustained international solidarity to support the Ukrainian people and mitigate the negative impact of Russia’s invasion on international food security.</p>
<p>In her capacity leading U.S. programs in support of civil society, migrants, and refugees, Under Secretary Zeya visited a shelter supporting female survivors of gender-based violence and human trafficking where the United States works with the International Organization for Migration, the Government of Tunisia, and civil society to provide critically needed assistance and advance a victim-centered approach.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
