<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:35:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Terrorist Attack in Elad, Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/terrorist-attack-in-elad-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=341429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>We vehemently condemn the terrorist attack in Elad, Israel, which killed at least three and wounded many others. This was a horrific attack targeting innocent men and women, and was particularly heinous coming as Israel celebrated its Independence Day. Our hearts are with the victims and loved ones of those killed, and we wish those injured a speedy recovery. We remain in close contact with our Israeli friends and partners and stand firmly with them in the face of this attack.</p>
<p>May the memory of those who passed be a blessing.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>We vehemently condemn the terrorist attack in Elad, Israel, which killed at least three and wounded many others. This was a horrific attack targeting innocent men and women, and was particularly heinous coming as Israel celebrated its Independence Day. Our hearts are with the victims and loved ones of those killed, and we wish those injured a speedy recovery. We remain in close contact with our Israeli friends and partners and stand firmly with them in the face of this attack.</p>
<p>May the memory of those who passed be a blessing.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Response to the al-Shabab Attack in Somalia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-response-to-the-al-shabab-attack-in-somalia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 22:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=341415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States stands with Burundi in the face of al-Shabab’s May 3 attack on Burundian soldiers serving at the African Union Transition Mission in Somalia (ATMIS) base in Ceel-Baraf, Somalia.  Our heartfelt condolences go out to the families of the fallen, wounded, and missing.  Burundi’s courageous armed forces have for years held the line against transnational terrorism in Somalia.  The United States remains steadfast in support of ATMIS and against the scourge of terrorism.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States stands with Burundi in the face of al-Shabab’s May 3 attack on Burundian soldiers serving at the African Union Transition Mission in Somalia (ATMIS) base in Ceel-Baraf, Somalia.  Our heartfelt condolences go out to the families of the fallen, wounded, and missing.  Burundi’s courageous armed forces have for years held the line against transnational terrorism in Somalia.  The United States remains steadfast in support of ATMIS and against the scourge of terrorism.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing – May 5, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-may-5-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 22:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=341394</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Small but mighty crew today. Good to see.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Small.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-DEPARTMENT"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Just one thing at the top, and then I look forward to taking your questions. This morning, together with the president of the World Food Prize Foundation, we announced the 2022 World Food Prize Laureate. Commonly known as the Nobel Prize for agriculture, the award recognizes the achievements of individuals who have advanced human development by improving the quality, quantity, or availability of food in the world.</p>
<p>This year’s winner is American climate scientist Dr. Cynthia Rosenzweig, who works at the NASA Goddard Institute for Space Studies. Dr. Rosenzweig is being recognized for her four decades of pioneering work improving the world’s understanding of climate change impacts on agriculture. We offer her our congratulations and gratitude for this critical work.</p>
<p>The World Food Prize Foundation’s mission to advance human development by improving the quality, quantity, or availability of food in the world, engaging in cutting-edge global food security issues, and inspiring the next generation to end hunger – it’s a mission that is critical to addressing food security challenges of today and preparing to feed future generations.</p>
<p>Already a critical concern due to the impacts of the climate crisis, the problem of food insecurity is now even more acute, as President Putin’s war in Ukraine has put millions around the globe at risk. And addressing this issue is a top priority for the U.S. Government.</p>
<p>This morning, as you saw, the department announced the appointment of Dr. Cary Fowler, a noted agriculturalist, as U.S. Special Envoy for Global Food Security.</p>
<p>Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield announced the United States will launch a week of action to address food insecurity across the globe later this month, which will include a ministerial-level meeting on May 18th at the UN in New York and an open debate in the UN Security Council about food insecurity and armed conflict the following day, on May 19th.</p>
<p>On March 24th, President Biden announced $1 billion towards additional humanitarian assistance for Ukraine and global food security. These funds will provide food, shelter, clean water, medical supplies, and other forms of assistance to those affected by Russia’s invasion.</p>
<p>President Biden has also committed $11 billion to support long-term food security priorities. Once approved by Congress, these funds will be used at home and abroad to support long-term efforts to bolster food security, enhance supply chain resilience, and provide humanitarian aid, including to those affected by this war.</p>
<p>This is in addition to our ongoing work with allies and partners to combat food insecurity, which has been exacerbated by Russia’s destructive war on Ukraine.</p>
<p>With that, happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. Before I get to policy matters, the Secretary – I presume – maybe, maybe not – you’ve spoken to him? Is he doing okay?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> He is on the phone. He is experiencing only the same mild symptoms. I expect he’ll continue to have phone conversations, speak with staff here, counterparts around the world, members of Congress, and others over the next couple days. And I know he looks forward to returning to the office just as soon as he can.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-SWEDEN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Yesterday, before his positive PCR test, he met with the Swedish foreign minister, who said afterwards in an interview that she had spoken to him about the very real possibility that Sweden would apply for NATO membership, and that the Secretary responded that the U.S. is willing – would be willing to provide security assurances to Sweden in the interim period between application and accession. I’m wondering if you can tell us if – tell us anything more about that, if that is actually correct, and if there were any specifics involved, and what those assurances might be.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, they had a wide-ranging discussion. It was a follow-on discussion to the many conversations, including the in-person meeting that the foreign minister and the Secretary had when the Secretary was in Stockholm for the OSCE meeting late last year. It not only broached Russia’s ongoing war in Ukraine and the attendant issues there, but we cooperate closely with Sweden on a host of bilateral and global issues. That includes food security, advancing democracy, human rights around the world. Sweden has been instrumental in promoting and helping to build upon the ongoing truce in Yemen. We – they discussed areas of cooperation between the U.S. and the EU as Sweden prepares to assume the presidency of the Council of the European Union in 2023.</p>
<p>Of course, they did have an extended discussion on Russia’s actions in Ukraine and the implications of it. As we have said before, every country has a right to choose its own path, every country has a right to determine for itself its foreign policy, its alliances, its partnerships. And when it comes to NATO, that is a decision for the 30 members of the Alliance and the aspirant country, and nobody else.</p>
<p>We have consistently made clear our commitment to NATO’s “Open Door” policy. NATO’s door remains open to aspirant countries when they are ready and able to meet the commitments and obligations of membership and to contribute to security in the Euro-Atlantic area. When it comes to Finland and Sweden, as we’ve said before, both are valued partners of NATO. They’re valued partners of the United States. We remain firmly committed to this “Open Door” policy. Of course, the NATO secretary general has recently noted that Allies would welcome Sweden and Finland, and as the secretary general himself said, I am certain that we will find ways to address concerns they may have regarding the period between the potential application and the final ratification.</p>
<p>The discussion yesterday noted that Sweden has not made any formal public announcement about its intentions to put forward an application for NATO. There was a hypothetical discussion about that and related issues, but as we’ve said, our commitment to NATO’s open door, that is firm. It is an open door that should remain open, must remain open for any country that can meet those stringent application requirements.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, okay, fine, but obviously they haven’t yet applied for it, but it’s pretty much a foregone conclusion. So the idea that it’s a hypothetical question – in the realm of hypothetical questions, it’s less of a hypothetical than, say, I don’t know. I don’t want to insult any country here, but like some very, very tiny country launching a lunar expedition. This is something that is clearly going to happen and that people are preparing for, so what is it that you guys can offer to Sweden and potentially Finland &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I would say, Matt, is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; in that interim period?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I would say is that this will remain a hypothetical until it’s not a hypothetical, and at this stage neither Sweden nor Finland has put forward a firm intention to seek NATO membership. That could change in the coming weeks. We’ll leave it to those countries or any other country to speak for itself.</p>
<p>I will just add this without going too far down the hypothetical rabbit hole. Our countries, our militaries have worked together for years. We are confident that we could, as parallel to what the NATO secretary general said, find ways to address any concerns either country could have about the period of time between a NATO membership application and a country’s potential accession to the NATO Alliance. But again, this remains a hypothetical, and until it is not a hypothetical, it’s best left in those terms.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All right, well, let me just – look, it’s a – it’s right now 2:14 p.m. It’s also a hypothetical that it’s going to be 2:15 p.m., okay? So you obviously are making plans for this very likely eventuality. And so – so you’re just not prepared to discuss what those are? Is that the answer to the question?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You are putting this in terms that are &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> It’s now 2:15, so that hypothetical is no longer a hypothetical.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You are putting this in terms that are more certain than what we’ve heard from our Finnish and Swedish partners, so I will allow our Finnish and Swedish partners to speak for themselves. And if and when they do make that decision or make any other decision, we’ll be prepared to speak to it in more concrete terms.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I follow up there?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Does the United States have any intelligence or assessments or concerns that Russia will launch any kind of attack on Sweden and Finland if they apply?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I do not have – we don’t have any such information, and certainly nothing to speak to. We have made very clear that we are committed to our partners in Europe. Of course, when it comes to NATO Allies, we have an Article 5 commitment. It’s an ironclad commitment that an attack on one is an attack on all, but as we are demonstrating in the context of Ukraine, we have a commitment to partners across Europe. And as I said before, Sweden, Finland, many other countries across the continent that are not members of NATO, they are strong, stalwart partners of the United States. In some cases they are members of the EU, and we’re committed to those partnerships.</p>
<p>Daphne.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, I want to follow up as well. Did the Secretary have detailed discussions yesterday with the foreign minister on what that support would look like during the period of application?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, this goes back to Matt’s hypothetical. I will just say &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> It’s not a hypothetical. You just said that they discussed it. They did.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> They discussed NATO’s “Open Door” policy and they discussed various possibilities in hypothetical terms. I would say it was not a conversation that was deep on the specifics at this point just because it remains a hypothetical.</p>
<p>Yes, Janne.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. I have two questions, China and North &#8212;</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-UKRAINE"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can we stay in Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. We’ll take a couple questions on &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Did the U.S. pledge any financial aid to Ukraine in the Poland conference today?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So we did. As you alluded to, there was a pledging conference, and through the U.S. Agency for International Development we are providing and pledged nearly $387 million in additional humanitarian assistance to Ukraine amid this war. This, of course, is in addition to the more than $1 billion in humanitarian assistance to vulnerable communities in the region since Russia first invaded Ukraine eight years ago, including more than $688 million, almost $700 million this year alone.</p>
<p>You’ve heard us say this before, but the United States has been and is the largest single-country donor of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine. On – in late March, on March 24th, President Biden announced that we would be prepared to provide more than $1 billion in new funding towards humanitarian assistance for those affected by the Kremlin’s war in Ukraine and its severe impacts around the world, including, as I alluded to at the top, a marked rise in food insecurity.</p>
<p>We’ve also put forward for Congress’s consideration a supplemental budget request that has additional funds, not only for security assistance, not only for economic assistance for Ukraine, but also for humanitarian assistance for those displaced by Russia’s war inside Ukraine and those refugees who have been forced to flee Ukraine, who are now in the region and in some cases further beyond.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You said 378?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Three hundred and eighty-seven million dollars. Yeah. Anything else on Russia, Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I have one on Russia.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Following Trevor Reed’s release last week, has there been any contact between the U.S. and Russian teams on the potential release of other detainees, including Paul Whelan and Brittney Griner?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So I will say that prior to Trevor Reed’s release you didn’t hear us speak of our communication, our dialogue with the Kremlin, with the Russian Federation regarding any preparations, any plans, any efforts to do so. And that is chiefly because we have found that in these cases we can be more effective if we are afforded the opportunity to have discussions that are outside of public view, that are not conducted in public but are, rather, private.</p>
<p>What I will say generally is that there have been longstanding efforts to free, in the case of Russia, Paul Whelan. Of course, you heard us yesterday that we now consider Brittney Griner to be a case of wrongful detention. Her case will now be handled and is now handled by Ambassador Roger Carstens, our special presidential envoy for hostage affairs. Those efforts to secure their release are ongoing, just as our efforts to secure the release of Americans who are detained around the world.</p>
<p>Yes, Jenny.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You said we’d be hearing more from the U.S. in the leadup to May 9th. Is that going to be support for Ukraine? Are those punitive measures? What – can you tell us anything?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I suspect you will hear us put forward elements that will allow us to continue our strategy. It is a strategy that has, in the context of Ukraine, had two primary elements. One is significant security assistance, significant support for those brave defenders of Ukraine’s democracy, its freedom, its independence, and its territorial integrity.</p>
<p>To date, we have contributed nearly $4 billion since the start of the invasion to this effort. This is security assistance that has proved to be a key enabler of the success that our Ukrainian partners have been able to demonstrate on the battlefield. And if you just take a step back and think about where we are, we’re now 70 days into Russia’s war on Ukraine. Russia has lost the battle of Kyiv. Russia has been forced to narrow its aims. Its aims have gone from an attempt to take an entire country – to subjugate an entire people, to essentially redraw the map of Europe – to focus its military objectives on the south and the east, continuing its brutal campaign, but with objectives that are far different from what Vladimir Putin by many accounts had in mind when his forces went into Ukraine on February 24th.</p>
<p>We’ll continue with that security assistance. We’ll also continue, on the other side of the ledger, to apply unprecedented amounts of pressure on the Kremlin, and we’ve done that together with dozens of countries around the world, spanning four continents, with financial sanctions, with export control measures, with efforts to reduce and wean dependence on Russian energy that has for too long been a source of revenue for the Kremlin and for, more recently, the Kremlin’s war machine in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Both of these things combined to strengthen Ukraine’s hand on the battlefield and to strengthen Ukraine’s hand at the negotiating table, because our strategy is to see to it that Ukraine emerges from this victorious. Ukraine will do so at the negotiating table. Our goal is to strengthen Ukraine’s position at that negotiating table as we continue to place mounting costs on the Russian Federation.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The Richardson Center has confirmed that the former ambassador to the UN is taking on Brittney Griner’s case. Is this welcome news to the State Department? Can you comment?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Look, we appreciate all of those who are very invested in this case, and Brittney Griner is fortunate to have a network who has supported her from day one. We have worked very closely with that network. When it comes to others, we do often partner with various individuals and organizations on these cases, but it’s not something that we speak to publicly. We welcome all of those efforts that are coordinated closely with us that might help to seek the safe release of any American who’s unjustly detained around the world.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> How concerned are you that Russia has said that any weapons deliveries from the U.S. or other NATO countries would be a legitimate target?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’re not going to respond to Russian bluster, to Russian propaganda. I think you’ve heard from my counterpart at the Department of Defense that we continue to have the unimpeded ability to flow weapons and security assistance into Ukraine. Those deliveries have, whether it’s from the United States or from our allies and partners around the world, been occurring almost daily. The fact that we have been able to announce such large drawdowns – the last two of which have been $800 million, nearly $4 billion since the start of the war, and then to deliver that within oftentimes days of making the announcement – speaks to the fact that we are able to process those drawdowns, to deliver those weapons precisely to our Ukrainian partners, what they need, so they then can take it precisely to where they need it most.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-NORTHKOREA"></a> Yes, Janne.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. On North Korea and China, will additional U.S. sanctions on North Korea be adopted in this month’s UN Security Council resolution? If China and Russia use their veto, then what happen?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, this is something that we are discussing with our allies and partners around the world, and in the first instance we’re having these discussions with our treaty allies in the Indo-Pacific. We’ve talked about our ironclad commitment to the defense of Korea, the Republic of Korea, and to Japan as well. And so in the aftermath of these most recent provocations, including the three ICBM launches and the ballistic missile launches, this week we have continued those conversations with our allies.</p>
<p>But we are also discussing this with a broader set of allies and partners around the world. That includes in New York, where our ambassador there, Ambassador Linda Thomas-Greenfield, and her team have been engaged on the challenge that is posed by North Korea’s ballistic missile and its nuclear weapons program. It is a challenge, it is a threat to international peace and security that the UN Security Council and its members have recognized in the past. The UN Security Council and its members, including all five Permanent Members, in the past have signed on to a string of UN Security Council resolutions. That’s precisely why the ballistic missile launches this week, the ICBM launches in recent weeks have been an affront to multiple UN Security Council resolutions.</p>
<p>So we’re not going to get ahead of any steps that the UN might take or the UN Security Council might take, but we do think that accountability is important. We do think it’s vital that the international community, our allies as well as partners around the world, send a very clear signal to the DPRK that these types of provocations won’t be tolerated, they won’t improve its strategic positioning, and the world will respond accordingly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On China, yesterday Chinese foreign ministry said the U.S. was responsible for North Korea’s continued missile violations. What is your reaction of Chinese blaming the United States?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m not going to react to the Chinese reaction, especially to one like that. What I will say is that the PRC and the DPRK equally know where we stand on this. We have and we harbor no hostile intent towards the DPRK. It is our goal, as it is the goal of other allies and partners in the region and around the world, to see the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. We believe we can effect that through diplomacy and dialogue. That is what we seek to have. We have made very clear to the DPRK, we’ve made very clear publicly to all of you, that we are prepared to engage in that dialogue towards the end of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. In the absence of discussions with the DPRK, we are engaged concertedly with our allies Japan and the Republic of Korea, but also with allies and partners around the world.</p>
<p>Michel.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-SYRIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, on Syria. Austin Tice’s parents have said yesterday that the President has pledged to engage directly with the Syrian regime to free Austin. How will this engagement be? Are you planning to send a U.S. official to Damascus to talk about this issue?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So this goes back to what we were – what I was saying in response to previous questions in the case of Trevor Reed and Brittney Griner. We’ve often found that we can move the ball forward most effectively if we don’t detail everything we’re doing in public, if we do have space to conduct behind-the-scenes discussions.</p>
<p>In the case of Austin Tice, this is an American who has spent nearly a quarter of his life, almost 10 years of his 40 years on this Earth, separated from his family. We have said before that when our special presidential envoy for hostage affairs speaks with other officials, speaks with regimes, speaks with actors around the world, that is distinct from traditional diplomacy in many ways. And Ambassador Carstens can go places, he can talk to people that others in this administration in some cases would not, but I’m just going to leave it there.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That means he will be going to negotiate with the regime, and will he talk with them about U.S.-Syria relations and &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I said nothing of the sort. I said that Ambassador Carstens is in a position as the special presidential envoy for hostage affairs to talk to individuals, to talk to governments, to talk to regimes that others in this department or in this government might not be in a position to do. He has done that before in his role. He has been successful in efforts to free Americans who have been unjustly detained around the world, including in places where we don’t have diplomatic relations. And so we are going to seek to continue that track record of bringing Americans home.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-LEBANON"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And on Lebanon, tomorrow will start the parliamentarian elections. What are your expectations?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the elections aren’t until later this month. I believe they’re May 15th. But we do support free &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> They start tomorrow in the Arab world and on Sunday (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> But we do support free, fair, transparent, and on-time elections in Lebanon that represent the legitimate will of the Lebanese people who are living through crises of historic proportion. We hope these elections will lead to a timely formation of government – of a government that will quickly address the challenges faced by the people of Lebanon.</p>
<p>Yes, Jenny.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-ISRAEL"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> This news is just breaking now, but I was wondering if you have any comment. The Israelis are saying at least three people were killed in a suspected terror attack just today.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I saw initial reports just as I was walking in. If these reports are accurate, and certainly no reason to doubt them, it would be the latest in what has been a string of despicable terrorist attacks that have rocked Israel in recent weeks. We saw them in advance of this holy period, the confluence of Easter, of Passover, of Ramadan. We saw them in advance of the Negev summit. And if this is what it appears to be, it is something that we would condemn in the strongest terms. Our commitment to our Israeli partners, to Israel’s security, that is ironclad, and we’ll provide any and all assistance that may be required in this case.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-BRAZIL"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On the reports that the CIA director told President Bolsonaro to stop casting doubts on the country’s election system last year, did State also communicate a similar message?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Of course, I’m not going to speak to any messages or any travel that the CIA director may have conveyed. What I will say is that we have regularly engaged with our Brazilian partners. Just last month, we had a Strategic Dialogue, and Toria Nuland, our under secretary of state for political affairs, and Jose Fernández, our under secretary of state for economic affairs, were both in Brazil to continue these important conversations.</p>
<p>Our bottom line has been that, like the United States, Brazil is a strong democracy, and we both have a commitment to ensure our democracies deliver for our people. We have high confidence in Brazil’s democratic institutions. Brazil has a strong track record of free and fair elections, with transparency and high levels of voter participation. And it’s important that Brazilians, as they look forward to their elections later this year, have confidence in their electoral systems and that Brazil once again is in a position to demonstrate to the world through these elections the enduring strength of Brazil’s democracy.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-IRAN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. Regarding the JCPOA, you have mentioned yesterday you are preparing for – equally for either scenario. So what is your plan B if the JCPOA doesn’t work anymore?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So you’re referring to the fact that the JCPOA continues, we believe, to be in our national security interests. It continues to be in our national security interests principally because it would once again put in a box Iran’s nuclear program, a program that since 2018 has been in a position to gallop forward in ways that are unacceptable to us, that are unacceptable to many of our allies and partners around the world.</p>
<p>If we are going to be in a position to mutually return to full compliance with the JCPOA, what that would do is to once again impose the most stringent set of – the most stringent verification and monitoring regime ever peacefully negotiated. And importantly, it would prolong what is now a breakout time – that is to say, the time it would take Iran to acquire the fissile material necessary for a nuclear weapon if Iran decided to pursue the path of weaponization. It would prolong that period, a period that, once again, for us is unacceptably short.</p>
<p>So we know the status quo can’t endure for long. And so either we’re going to be in a position to return to compliance with the JCPOA and to see those restrictions once again imposed on Iran’s nuclear program, or we’re going to have to pursue a different path. It has been clear to us since the beginning that a mutual return to compliance was never guaranteed. It was never a certainty. So discussions with our allies and partners regarding an alternative approach – that is not something that we have undertaken only in recent days or even recent weeks. These are discussions that we have had for a number of months now with allies and partners around the world.</p>
<p>President Biden has a commitment that Iran must never be able to acquire a nuclear weapon. The JCPOA, if that is back in force, will be the vehicle to carry that out. But we are engaging with allies and partners around the world to devise a means by which we will be able to make good on President Biden’s commitment whether or not there is a JCPOA.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, sorry, how &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is military option on the table?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m sorry, I didn’t hear the question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is military option still on the table?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We believe that diplomacy and dialogue presents us with the most effective, sustainable, durable means by which to ensure Iran will never acquire a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So on this, do you remember the first time that you actually said that you guys have to prepare for a world in which there is no – potentially there is no JCPOA? I mean, it wasn’t yesterday. How many months ago do you think the &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, as I just said &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; do you think that that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> But Matt, you’re making my point. As I just said, when we &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m not trying to make any point, I’m trying to – well, I’m just surprised that people all of a sudden took yesterday that you said we have to prepare for this like it’s something new.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Ah. I was surprised by that too, yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You’ve been saying this for months, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I was &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you remember what month you first started saying it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t, but as I just alluded to, I’m sure you do and you’ll tell me in just a second.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, no, no, I didn’t. I actually &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Oh, okay. Oh, I see, it was a genuine question. I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All of my questions are genuine, Ned, except when they’re not. (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Except when they’re hypothetical.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I will tell you is that when we started this process in April of 2021 – April more than a year ago now – it was never a certainty. It was never a guarantee that we would get back to a point of mutual return to compliance. We always knew it was an uncertain proposition, so we started preparing for this reality, to your point – to your very valid point – quite some time ago.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, okay, exactly. So, now, in terms of the debate over this assessment or alleged assessment about whether or not it has – the window has already closed and that it no longer makes sense – according to some people that this assessment says that it no longer makes sense to rejoin the JCPOA – is there a situation in which even though you can’t get everything you want in terms of breakout time with the JCPOA, that the administration still believes that it is in the U.S. national security interest to come back into compliance with it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So to the first part of your question, I just want to be clear about this because I know there has been some misinformation, potentially disinformation, out there. There is no “secret assessment,” quote/unquote, that a mutual return to full implementation of the JCPOA is no longer in our national interest.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, so – all right, stop right there and let me just say – so what is Senator Menendez talking about? Not Senator Cruz, Senator Menendez. When he says that he understands from classified or – I don’t know what – but he understands from the administration that the window actually closed in February. So is he just making this up?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I can tell you is that our experts – our experts here, our experts in the Intelligence Community and elsewhere – we are constantly assessing the nonproliferation gains of a potential return to the JCPOA. That is the metric we use. We compare where we are now to the potential nonproliferation gains of a possible return to compliance with the JCPOA. At this stage, such a return would still achieve our most important and most urgent nonproliferation goals and would – at least in the view of the administration – strongly be in our national interest. That is why we continue to pursue, at least for the moment, a mutual return to compliance.</p>
<p>Now, to the point that others have raised, there will come a time when the assessment of the nonproliferation benefits that a return to the JCPOA would bring – when that assessment renders the fact that Iran’s program has advanced too far, that rendering a potential return to the JCPOA is no longer in our interest. But we are not at the point.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> In this situation, are you saying that U.S. – broader national U.S. security interests are entirely dependent on the nonproliferation part of it? Or is there a way in which you would assess that even if you don’t get what you’re looking for in terms of breakout time, that it could still be in the U.S. national interest to go back?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> This is a nonproliferation deal.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And that’s it.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> And we look at it through a nonproliferation lens.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And that’s it. There is no other – there’s no other lens. This is a &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We look at – we – through a nonproliferation lens, comparing a potential return to compliance with the JCPOA to where we are now, it is in our advantage to return to the JCPOA. The famous saying from President Biden – don’t compare us to the Almighty, compare us to the alternative. The JCPOA is the best alternative. It remains the best alternative at the moment. That won’t be the case forever.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Where is Robert Malley at this time and what is he doing?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The last time I saw Rob was a few days ago. He was in Washington, D.C. He is always on the phone. He is talking to our European allies. He’s talking to other stakeholders. And until and unless there is reason for him to return to Vienna, I suspect he will continue to do a lot of that from here.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, my last one on this. Just what do you make, if anything, of this Senate vote yesterday on the – I mean, I know it’s non-binding, but it was a pretty clear shot across the bow of the administration.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So it was a vote on the China bill, and we do look forward to the rapid passage of legislation that President Biden can sign to boost our competitiveness vis-à-vis the PRC &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, I’m talking about the Iran deal.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, it was part of the package.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, I understand that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>But to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>All right. This is like me asking you to describe an elephant and you say, well, elephants are scared of mice.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And a mouse is a little brown animal, whatever, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The problem is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I’m asking you about the Iran part of this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I know, but the problem is that you &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; which Democrats &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>You &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Very – quite a few of them &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>You interrupted me before I could finish my first sentence, and the second clause of my first sentence was going to say &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>All right. Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; we are aware of the nonbinding Iran-related instruction to Senate conferees that was passed yesterday. As I said before, the President’s commitment is that Iran will not obtain a nuclear weapon. He has been clear that at this point, the best way to realize that is through a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA. That is what Rob Malley and his team are seeking to achieve at the moment.</p>
<p>We do share the concern expressed by the Senate about other aspects of Iran’s behavior, including their development of ballistic missiles, support for terrorism through the IRGC and other elements. And that’s why our administration has actually increased sanctions on Iran’s ballistic missile program and on the IRGC over the past year. There is nothing in a potential return to the JCPOA that would in any way diminish our resolve or our ability to continue combating these aspects of Iran’s policies in the region. If this math is still correct, of the 107 sanctions that we have applied on Iran since January 20th of 2021, 86 of those – which, if my math is right, about three quarters of those – have been on the IRGC. We are committed to doing all we can, pulling every lever we can to take on the threat, together with our partners, from the IRGC.</p>
<p>Now, having said all that, we know that all of these problems are even more intractable, even more challenging – and challenging, if Iran also is in a position to have a nuclear program that is unconstrained. That is why we have always been of the mindset that the decision to withdraw from an agreement that was demonstrably working to prevent Iran from obtaining a nuclear weapon has comprehensively failed to protect our national security interests and, in fact, has actually resulted in the opposite. It has resulted in an Iran that is more aggressive, that is more destabilizing, and its proxies could be called the same.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. But it is still the administration’s position that you do not believe that you can get anything outside of the nuclear stuff into a return to the JCPOA? In other words, just as it was in 2015, the missiles, the support for extremists, et cetera – you’re not looking to get that into just – get that into a deal?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The JCPOA is about one thing and one thing only, and that’s Iran’s nuclear program.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, so then is this the end of the longer and stronger thing that you guys have been – had been talking about since February of last year (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>As I said before, we are committed to working with our allies and partners to address these other challenges that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Right, but the JCPOA is not going to be longer and stronger even &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The first step &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Even &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The first step, but &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, no, no, no. But if you, a deal to return, it isn’t going to be longer and stronger for now.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The first step is testing the proposition as to whether we can mutually return to compliance with the JCPOA.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I get that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That’s the first step.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Now, going back to the point about hypotheticals, it’s far from clear that we’ll get there.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, it wasn’t a hypothetical.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, no &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>This is what the administration came into – into office saying not only do we want to return to the JCPOA, but we want to make it longer and stronger, part of one whole thing. And I just want to make sure that what you’re saying now is that you have essentially – given up might be a pejorative here, but you don’t believe that it is – that it is at all possible to include other things that weren’t covered by the original deal in &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We have – we have &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; in a new one.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We have always said that a first step is putting a box back on top of Iran’s nuclear program. That is the first step. It is, to my point a moment ago, a hypothetical as to whether we’ll be able to do that, because it’s far from certain whether a mutual return to the JCPOA will be in the offing or not. Whether we’re able to get there or if we’re not able to get there, we are still going to work with partners and allies and still engage in diplomacy to see to it that we can take on these other challenges that Iran poses to the region and by extension to us. And that includes the IRGC and its ballistic missile program, among other challenges.</p>
<p>Guita.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, you – when you talk about Iran’s advances to a point where the benefits of the JCPOA will not be realized anymore, about that, nuclear experts believe that at a certain point anybody – anybody with nuclear capabilities – can produce crude nuclear bombs, which is one level, obviously, less than the actual, bigger size one. Does the administration differentiate between these two? Because according to David Albright, he – in early April, he estimated that between mid April and end of April Iran would have enough, 60 percent, to manufacture a crude bomb. Does the administration differentiate? Do you – are you waiting until it has – it does 90 percent?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have a commitment that Iran must never be able to acquire a nuclear weapon. And the reason why we have pursued a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA is not only that it would define what Iran can’t do and to impose the most stringent verification and monitoring regime ever negotiated, but it would give the international community – principally through the IAEA – greater transparency into all of the potential pathways that Iran could seek to illicitly acquire a nuclear weapon. So to have an agreement that has these caps, that has a stringent verification and monitoring regime, and as a result that affords much greater levels of transparency to international weapons inspectors, this is why the JCPOA remains – at least for the moment – manifestly in our interest.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, sure. But by now Iran may have enough, 60 percent, to manufacture a smaller explosive. That doesn’t count?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You’re raising something that, again, falls in the category of hypotheticals. We are – we have made clear that we are determined, the President has a commitment, that Iran won’t be able to acquire a nuclear weapon. We want to see to it that we put everything in place in a way that is sustainable, in a way that is durable, in a way that is transparent, so that not only can we prevent this, but if Iran seeks to manufacture a nuclear weapon, if it seeks to manufacture, as you put it, a crude nuclear device, that is something that we would able to detect early on.</p>
<p>All right. Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hold it. I got one more.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Oh, okay. Okay.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-NEPAL"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I just – I’m just wondering if you have an – any kind of an update on this child custody/abduction issue in Nepal.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Not an update since we last talked about it. I think as you know, this is a matter that is before a court in Nepal. Our priority and responsibility is to assist U.S. citizens the most effective way possible. The embassy in Kathmandu, the department are working diligently to assist the family member in this case. Embassy personnel are in regular contact with the father. They’ve informed him of all developments in this case.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But you’re – you do not consider this to be a case of the child being abducted from India into Nepal?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We are not characterizing this case as an international parental child abduction to Nepal.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Gotcha.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But – well, continue, if you have more.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Okay. So I’ll give you the fuller facts.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We understand the facts of the case to be the following: The child’s Indian national mother was – wrongfully retained the U.S.-citizen child in India in 2017. The father, who is a U.S. citizen, immediately secured a court order in Cook County, Illinois, determining he had sole custody of the child while she was still unlawfully retained in India with her mother. In light of the mother’s actions, the department considers the case to be an international parental child abduction case between the U.S. and India, and the U.S. has formally raised it with the Indian Government on several occasions, urging a swift resolution. In April of this year, the father, while visiting the child, departed India with her across the border to Nepal. Both parents are now in Nepal.</p>
<p>Daphne.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh – sorry, Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, I’m done. Thank you. I said “thank you.”</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-CHINA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Do you have any update on Blinken’s China speech? Will it be rescheduled?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It will be rescheduled. I do not have a date to offer at this time, but I can assure you that we will find a date at the earliest opportunity.</p>
<p>Thank you, all.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:52 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Small but mighty crew today. Good to see.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Small.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-DEPARTMENT"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Just one thing at the top, and then I look forward to taking your questions. This morning, together with the president of the World Food Prize Foundation, we announced the 2022 World Food Prize Laureate. Commonly known as the Nobel Prize for agriculture, the award recognizes the achievements of individuals who have advanced human development by improving the quality, quantity, or availability of food in the world.</p>
<p>This year’s winner is American climate scientist Dr. Cynthia Rosenzweig, who works at the NASA Goddard Institute for Space Studies. Dr. Rosenzweig is being recognized for her four decades of pioneering work improving the world’s understanding of climate change impacts on agriculture. We offer her our congratulations and gratitude for this critical work.</p>
<p>The World Food Prize Foundation’s mission to advance human development by improving the quality, quantity, or availability of food in the world, engaging in cutting-edge global food security issues, and inspiring the next generation to end hunger – it’s a mission that is critical to addressing food security challenges of today and preparing to feed future generations.</p>
<p>Already a critical concern due to the impacts of the climate crisis, the problem of food insecurity is now even more acute, as President Putin’s war in Ukraine has put millions around the globe at risk. And addressing this issue is a top priority for the U.S. Government.</p>
<p>This morning, as you saw, the department announced the appointment of Dr. Cary Fowler, a noted agriculturalist, as U.S. Special Envoy for Global Food Security.</p>
<p>Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield announced the United States will launch a week of action to address food insecurity across the globe later this month, which will include a ministerial-level meeting on May 18th at the UN in New York and an open debate in the UN Security Council about food insecurity and armed conflict the following day, on May 19th.</p>
<p>On March 24th, President Biden announced $1 billion towards additional humanitarian assistance for Ukraine and global food security. These funds will provide food, shelter, clean water, medical supplies, and other forms of assistance to those affected by Russia’s invasion.</p>
<p>President Biden has also committed $11 billion to support long-term food security priorities. Once approved by Congress, these funds will be used at home and abroad to support long-term efforts to bolster food security, enhance supply chain resilience, and provide humanitarian aid, including to those affected by this war.</p>
<p>This is in addition to our ongoing work with allies and partners to combat food insecurity, which has been exacerbated by Russia’s destructive war on Ukraine.</p>
<p>With that, happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. Before I get to policy matters, the Secretary – I presume – maybe, maybe not – you’ve spoken to him? Is he doing okay?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> He is on the phone. He is experiencing only the same mild symptoms. I expect he’ll continue to have phone conversations, speak with staff here, counterparts around the world, members of Congress, and others over the next couple days. And I know he looks forward to returning to the office just as soon as he can.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-SWEDEN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Yesterday, before his positive PCR test, he met with the Swedish foreign minister, who said afterwards in an interview that she had spoken to him about the very real possibility that Sweden would apply for NATO membership, and that the Secretary responded that the U.S. is willing – would be willing to provide security assurances to Sweden in the interim period between application and accession. I’m wondering if you can tell us if – tell us anything more about that, if that is actually correct, and if there were any specifics involved, and what those assurances might be.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, they had a wide-ranging discussion. It was a follow-on discussion to the many conversations, including the in-person meeting that the foreign minister and the Secretary had when the Secretary was in Stockholm for the OSCE meeting late last year. It not only broached Russia’s ongoing war in Ukraine and the attendant issues there, but we cooperate closely with Sweden on a host of bilateral and global issues. That includes food security, advancing democracy, human rights around the world. Sweden has been instrumental in promoting and helping to build upon the ongoing truce in Yemen. We – they discussed areas of cooperation between the U.S. and the EU as Sweden prepares to assume the presidency of the Council of the European Union in 2023.</p>
<p>Of course, they did have an extended discussion on Russia’s actions in Ukraine and the implications of it. As we have said before, every country has a right to choose its own path, every country has a right to determine for itself its foreign policy, its alliances, its partnerships. And when it comes to NATO, that is a decision for the 30 members of the Alliance and the aspirant country, and nobody else.</p>
<p>We have consistently made clear our commitment to NATO’s “Open Door” policy. NATO’s door remains open to aspirant countries when they are ready and able to meet the commitments and obligations of membership and to contribute to security in the Euro-Atlantic area. When it comes to Finland and Sweden, as we’ve said before, both are valued partners of NATO. They’re valued partners of the United States. We remain firmly committed to this “Open Door” policy. Of course, the NATO secretary general has recently noted that Allies would welcome Sweden and Finland, and as the secretary general himself said, I am certain that we will find ways to address concerns they may have regarding the period between the potential application and the final ratification.</p>
<p>The discussion yesterday noted that Sweden has not made any formal public announcement about its intentions to put forward an application for NATO. There was a hypothetical discussion about that and related issues, but as we’ve said, our commitment to NATO’s open door, that is firm. It is an open door that should remain open, must remain open for any country that can meet those stringent application requirements.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, okay, fine, but obviously they haven’t yet applied for it, but it’s pretty much a foregone conclusion. So the idea that it’s a hypothetical question – in the realm of hypothetical questions, it’s less of a hypothetical than, say, I don’t know. I don’t want to insult any country here, but like some very, very tiny country launching a lunar expedition. This is something that is clearly going to happen and that people are preparing for, so what is it that you guys can offer to Sweden and potentially Finland &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I would say, Matt, is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; in that interim period?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I would say is that this will remain a hypothetical until it’s not a hypothetical, and at this stage neither Sweden nor Finland has put forward a firm intention to seek NATO membership. That could change in the coming weeks. We’ll leave it to those countries or any other country to speak for itself.</p>
<p>I will just add this without going too far down the hypothetical rabbit hole. Our countries, our militaries have worked together for years. We are confident that we could, as parallel to what the NATO secretary general said, find ways to address any concerns either country could have about the period of time between a NATO membership application and a country’s potential accession to the NATO Alliance. But again, this remains a hypothetical, and until it is not a hypothetical, it’s best left in those terms.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All right, well, let me just – look, it’s a – it’s right now 2:14 p.m. It’s also a hypothetical that it’s going to be 2:15 p.m., okay? So you obviously are making plans for this very likely eventuality. And so – so you’re just not prepared to discuss what those are? Is that the answer to the question?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You are putting this in terms that are &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> It’s now 2:15, so that hypothetical is no longer a hypothetical.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You are putting this in terms that are more certain than what we’ve heard from our Finnish and Swedish partners, so I will allow our Finnish and Swedish partners to speak for themselves. And if and when they do make that decision or make any other decision, we’ll be prepared to speak to it in more concrete terms.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I follow up there?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Does the United States have any intelligence or assessments or concerns that Russia will launch any kind of attack on Sweden and Finland if they apply?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I do not have – we don’t have any such information, and certainly nothing to speak to. We have made very clear that we are committed to our partners in Europe. Of course, when it comes to NATO Allies, we have an Article 5 commitment. It’s an ironclad commitment that an attack on one is an attack on all, but as we are demonstrating in the context of Ukraine, we have a commitment to partners across Europe. And as I said before, Sweden, Finland, many other countries across the continent that are not members of NATO, they are strong, stalwart partners of the United States. In some cases they are members of the EU, and we’re committed to those partnerships.</p>
<p>Daphne.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, I want to follow up as well. Did the Secretary have detailed discussions yesterday with the foreign minister on what that support would look like during the period of application?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, this goes back to Matt’s hypothetical. I will just say &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> It’s not a hypothetical. You just said that they discussed it. They did.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> They discussed NATO’s “Open Door” policy and they discussed various possibilities in hypothetical terms. I would say it was not a conversation that was deep on the specifics at this point just because it remains a hypothetical.</p>
<p>Yes, Janne.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. I have two questions, China and North &#8212;</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-UKRAINE"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can we stay in Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. We’ll take a couple questions on &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Did the U.S. pledge any financial aid to Ukraine in the Poland conference today?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So we did. As you alluded to, there was a pledging conference, and through the U.S. Agency for International Development we are providing and pledged nearly $387 million in additional humanitarian assistance to Ukraine amid this war. This, of course, is in addition to the more than $1 billion in humanitarian assistance to vulnerable communities in the region since Russia first invaded Ukraine eight years ago, including more than $688 million, almost $700 million this year alone.</p>
<p>You’ve heard us say this before, but the United States has been and is the largest single-country donor of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine. On – in late March, on March 24th, President Biden announced that we would be prepared to provide more than $1 billion in new funding towards humanitarian assistance for those affected by the Kremlin’s war in Ukraine and its severe impacts around the world, including, as I alluded to at the top, a marked rise in food insecurity.</p>
<p>We’ve also put forward for Congress’s consideration a supplemental budget request that has additional funds, not only for security assistance, not only for economic assistance for Ukraine, but also for humanitarian assistance for those displaced by Russia’s war inside Ukraine and those refugees who have been forced to flee Ukraine, who are now in the region and in some cases further beyond.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You said 378?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Three hundred and eighty-seven million dollars. Yeah. Anything else on Russia, Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I have one on Russia.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Following Trevor Reed’s release last week, has there been any contact between the U.S. and Russian teams on the potential release of other detainees, including Paul Whelan and Brittney Griner?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So I will say that prior to Trevor Reed’s release you didn’t hear us speak of our communication, our dialogue with the Kremlin, with the Russian Federation regarding any preparations, any plans, any efforts to do so. And that is chiefly because we have found that in these cases we can be more effective if we are afforded the opportunity to have discussions that are outside of public view, that are not conducted in public but are, rather, private.</p>
<p>What I will say generally is that there have been longstanding efforts to free, in the case of Russia, Paul Whelan. Of course, you heard us yesterday that we now consider Brittney Griner to be a case of wrongful detention. Her case will now be handled and is now handled by Ambassador Roger Carstens, our special presidential envoy for hostage affairs. Those efforts to secure their release are ongoing, just as our efforts to secure the release of Americans who are detained around the world.</p>
<p>Yes, Jenny.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You said we’d be hearing more from the U.S. in the leadup to May 9th. Is that going to be support for Ukraine? Are those punitive measures? What – can you tell us anything?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I suspect you will hear us put forward elements that will allow us to continue our strategy. It is a strategy that has, in the context of Ukraine, had two primary elements. One is significant security assistance, significant support for those brave defenders of Ukraine’s democracy, its freedom, its independence, and its territorial integrity.</p>
<p>To date, we have contributed nearly $4 billion since the start of the invasion to this effort. This is security assistance that has proved to be a key enabler of the success that our Ukrainian partners have been able to demonstrate on the battlefield. And if you just take a step back and think about where we are, we’re now 70 days into Russia’s war on Ukraine. Russia has lost the battle of Kyiv. Russia has been forced to narrow its aims. Its aims have gone from an attempt to take an entire country – to subjugate an entire people, to essentially redraw the map of Europe – to focus its military objectives on the south and the east, continuing its brutal campaign, but with objectives that are far different from what Vladimir Putin by many accounts had in mind when his forces went into Ukraine on February 24th.</p>
<p>We’ll continue with that security assistance. We’ll also continue, on the other side of the ledger, to apply unprecedented amounts of pressure on the Kremlin, and we’ve done that together with dozens of countries around the world, spanning four continents, with financial sanctions, with export control measures, with efforts to reduce and wean dependence on Russian energy that has for too long been a source of revenue for the Kremlin and for, more recently, the Kremlin’s war machine in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Both of these things combined to strengthen Ukraine’s hand on the battlefield and to strengthen Ukraine’s hand at the negotiating table, because our strategy is to see to it that Ukraine emerges from this victorious. Ukraine will do so at the negotiating table. Our goal is to strengthen Ukraine’s position at that negotiating table as we continue to place mounting costs on the Russian Federation.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The Richardson Center has confirmed that the former ambassador to the UN is taking on Brittney Griner’s case. Is this welcome news to the State Department? Can you comment?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Look, we appreciate all of those who are very invested in this case, and Brittney Griner is fortunate to have a network who has supported her from day one. We have worked very closely with that network. When it comes to others, we do often partner with various individuals and organizations on these cases, but it’s not something that we speak to publicly. We welcome all of those efforts that are coordinated closely with us that might help to seek the safe release of any American who’s unjustly detained around the world.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> How concerned are you that Russia has said that any weapons deliveries from the U.S. or other NATO countries would be a legitimate target?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’re not going to respond to Russian bluster, to Russian propaganda. I think you’ve heard from my counterpart at the Department of Defense that we continue to have the unimpeded ability to flow weapons and security assistance into Ukraine. Those deliveries have, whether it’s from the United States or from our allies and partners around the world, been occurring almost daily. The fact that we have been able to announce such large drawdowns – the last two of which have been $800 million, nearly $4 billion since the start of the war, and then to deliver that within oftentimes days of making the announcement – speaks to the fact that we are able to process those drawdowns, to deliver those weapons precisely to our Ukrainian partners, what they need, so they then can take it precisely to where they need it most.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-NORTHKOREA"></a> Yes, Janne.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. On North Korea and China, will additional U.S. sanctions on North Korea be adopted in this month’s UN Security Council resolution? If China and Russia use their veto, then what happen?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, this is something that we are discussing with our allies and partners around the world, and in the first instance we’re having these discussions with our treaty allies in the Indo-Pacific. We’ve talked about our ironclad commitment to the defense of Korea, the Republic of Korea, and to Japan as well. And so in the aftermath of these most recent provocations, including the three ICBM launches and the ballistic missile launches, this week we have continued those conversations with our allies.</p>
<p>But we are also discussing this with a broader set of allies and partners around the world. That includes in New York, where our ambassador there, Ambassador Linda Thomas-Greenfield, and her team have been engaged on the challenge that is posed by North Korea’s ballistic missile and its nuclear weapons program. It is a challenge, it is a threat to international peace and security that the UN Security Council and its members have recognized in the past. The UN Security Council and its members, including all five Permanent Members, in the past have signed on to a string of UN Security Council resolutions. That’s precisely why the ballistic missile launches this week, the ICBM launches in recent weeks have been an affront to multiple UN Security Council resolutions.</p>
<p>So we’re not going to get ahead of any steps that the UN might take or the UN Security Council might take, but we do think that accountability is important. We do think it’s vital that the international community, our allies as well as partners around the world, send a very clear signal to the DPRK that these types of provocations won’t be tolerated, they won’t improve its strategic positioning, and the world will respond accordingly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On China, yesterday Chinese foreign ministry said the U.S. was responsible for North Korea’s continued missile violations. What is your reaction of Chinese blaming the United States?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m not going to react to the Chinese reaction, especially to one like that. What I will say is that the PRC and the DPRK equally know where we stand on this. We have and we harbor no hostile intent towards the DPRK. It is our goal, as it is the goal of other allies and partners in the region and around the world, to see the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. We believe we can effect that through diplomacy and dialogue. That is what we seek to have. We have made very clear to the DPRK, we’ve made very clear publicly to all of you, that we are prepared to engage in that dialogue towards the end of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. In the absence of discussions with the DPRK, we are engaged concertedly with our allies Japan and the Republic of Korea, but also with allies and partners around the world.</p>
<p>Michel.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-SYRIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, on Syria. Austin Tice’s parents have said yesterday that the President has pledged to engage directly with the Syrian regime to free Austin. How will this engagement be? Are you planning to send a U.S. official to Damascus to talk about this issue?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So this goes back to what we were – what I was saying in response to previous questions in the case of Trevor Reed and Brittney Griner. We’ve often found that we can move the ball forward most effectively if we don’t detail everything we’re doing in public, if we do have space to conduct behind-the-scenes discussions.</p>
<p>In the case of Austin Tice, this is an American who has spent nearly a quarter of his life, almost 10 years of his 40 years on this Earth, separated from his family. We have said before that when our special presidential envoy for hostage affairs speaks with other officials, speaks with regimes, speaks with actors around the world, that is distinct from traditional diplomacy in many ways. And Ambassador Carstens can go places, he can talk to people that others in this administration in some cases would not, but I’m just going to leave it there.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That means he will be going to negotiate with the regime, and will he talk with them about U.S.-Syria relations and &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I said nothing of the sort. I said that Ambassador Carstens is in a position as the special presidential envoy for hostage affairs to talk to individuals, to talk to governments, to talk to regimes that others in this department or in this government might not be in a position to do. He has done that before in his role. He has been successful in efforts to free Americans who have been unjustly detained around the world, including in places where we don’t have diplomatic relations. And so we are going to seek to continue that track record of bringing Americans home.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-LEBANON"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And on Lebanon, tomorrow will start the parliamentarian elections. What are your expectations?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the elections aren’t until later this month. I believe they’re May 15th. But we do support free &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> They start tomorrow in the Arab world and on Sunday (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> But we do support free, fair, transparent, and on-time elections in Lebanon that represent the legitimate will of the Lebanese people who are living through crises of historic proportion. We hope these elections will lead to a timely formation of government – of a government that will quickly address the challenges faced by the people of Lebanon.</p>
<p>Yes, Jenny.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-ISRAEL"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> This news is just breaking now, but I was wondering if you have any comment. The Israelis are saying at least three people were killed in a suspected terror attack just today.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I saw initial reports just as I was walking in. If these reports are accurate, and certainly no reason to doubt them, it would be the latest in what has been a string of despicable terrorist attacks that have rocked Israel in recent weeks. We saw them in advance of this holy period, the confluence of Easter, of Passover, of Ramadan. We saw them in advance of the Negev summit. And if this is what it appears to be, it is something that we would condemn in the strongest terms. Our commitment to our Israeli partners, to Israel’s security, that is ironclad, and we’ll provide any and all assistance that may be required in this case.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-BRAZIL"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On the reports that the CIA director told President Bolsonaro to stop casting doubts on the country’s election system last year, did State also communicate a similar message?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Of course, I’m not going to speak to any messages or any travel that the CIA director may have conveyed. What I will say is that we have regularly engaged with our Brazilian partners. Just last month, we had a Strategic Dialogue, and Toria Nuland, our under secretary of state for political affairs, and Jose Fernández, our under secretary of state for economic affairs, were both in Brazil to continue these important conversations.</p>
<p>Our bottom line has been that, like the United States, Brazil is a strong democracy, and we both have a commitment to ensure our democracies deliver for our people. We have high confidence in Brazil’s democratic institutions. Brazil has a strong track record of free and fair elections, with transparency and high levels of voter participation. And it’s important that Brazilians, as they look forward to their elections later this year, have confidence in their electoral systems and that Brazil once again is in a position to demonstrate to the world through these elections the enduring strength of Brazil’s democracy.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-IRAN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. Regarding the JCPOA, you have mentioned yesterday you are preparing for – equally for either scenario. So what is your plan B if the JCPOA doesn’t work anymore?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So you’re referring to the fact that the JCPOA continues, we believe, to be in our national security interests. It continues to be in our national security interests principally because it would once again put in a box Iran’s nuclear program, a program that since 2018 has been in a position to gallop forward in ways that are unacceptable to us, that are unacceptable to many of our allies and partners around the world.</p>
<p>If we are going to be in a position to mutually return to full compliance with the JCPOA, what that would do is to once again impose the most stringent set of – the most stringent verification and monitoring regime ever peacefully negotiated. And importantly, it would prolong what is now a breakout time – that is to say, the time it would take Iran to acquire the fissile material necessary for a nuclear weapon if Iran decided to pursue the path of weaponization. It would prolong that period, a period that, once again, for us is unacceptably short.</p>
<p>So we know the status quo can’t endure for long. And so either we’re going to be in a position to return to compliance with the JCPOA and to see those restrictions once again imposed on Iran’s nuclear program, or we’re going to have to pursue a different path. It has been clear to us since the beginning that a mutual return to compliance was never guaranteed. It was never a certainty. So discussions with our allies and partners regarding an alternative approach – that is not something that we have undertaken only in recent days or even recent weeks. These are discussions that we have had for a number of months now with allies and partners around the world.</p>
<p>President Biden has a commitment that Iran must never be able to acquire a nuclear weapon. The JCPOA, if that is back in force, will be the vehicle to carry that out. But we are engaging with allies and partners around the world to devise a means by which we will be able to make good on President Biden’s commitment whether or not there is a JCPOA.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, sorry, how &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is military option on the table?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m sorry, I didn’t hear the question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is military option still on the table?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We believe that diplomacy and dialogue presents us with the most effective, sustainable, durable means by which to ensure Iran will never acquire a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So on this, do you remember the first time that you actually said that you guys have to prepare for a world in which there is no – potentially there is no JCPOA? I mean, it wasn’t yesterday. How many months ago do you think the &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, as I just said &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; do you think that that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> But Matt, you’re making my point. As I just said, when we &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m not trying to make any point, I’m trying to – well, I’m just surprised that people all of a sudden took yesterday that you said we have to prepare for this like it’s something new.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Ah. I was surprised by that too, yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You’ve been saying this for months, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I was &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you remember what month you first started saying it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t, but as I just alluded to, I’m sure you do and you’ll tell me in just a second.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, no, no, I didn’t. I actually &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Oh, okay. Oh, I see, it was a genuine question. I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All of my questions are genuine, Ned, except when they’re not. (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Except when they’re hypothetical.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I will tell you is that when we started this process in April of 2021 – April more than a year ago now – it was never a certainty. It was never a guarantee that we would get back to a point of mutual return to compliance. We always knew it was an uncertain proposition, so we started preparing for this reality, to your point – to your very valid point – quite some time ago.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, okay, exactly. So, now, in terms of the debate over this assessment or alleged assessment about whether or not it has – the window has already closed and that it no longer makes sense – according to some people that this assessment says that it no longer makes sense to rejoin the JCPOA – is there a situation in which even though you can’t get everything you want in terms of breakout time with the JCPOA, that the administration still believes that it is in the U.S. national security interest to come back into compliance with it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So to the first part of your question, I just want to be clear about this because I know there has been some misinformation, potentially disinformation, out there. There is no “secret assessment,” quote/unquote, that a mutual return to full implementation of the JCPOA is no longer in our national interest.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, so – all right, stop right there and let me just say – so what is Senator Menendez talking about? Not Senator Cruz, Senator Menendez. When he says that he understands from classified or – I don’t know what – but he understands from the administration that the window actually closed in February. So is he just making this up?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I can tell you is that our experts – our experts here, our experts in the Intelligence Community and elsewhere – we are constantly assessing the nonproliferation gains of a potential return to the JCPOA. That is the metric we use. We compare where we are now to the potential nonproliferation gains of a possible return to compliance with the JCPOA. At this stage, such a return would still achieve our most important and most urgent nonproliferation goals and would – at least in the view of the administration – strongly be in our national interest. That is why we continue to pursue, at least for the moment, a mutual return to compliance.</p>
<p>Now, to the point that others have raised, there will come a time when the assessment of the nonproliferation benefits that a return to the JCPOA would bring – when that assessment renders the fact that Iran’s program has advanced too far, that rendering a potential return to the JCPOA is no longer in our interest. But we are not at the point.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> In this situation, are you saying that U.S. – broader national U.S. security interests are entirely dependent on the nonproliferation part of it? Or is there a way in which you would assess that even if you don’t get what you’re looking for in terms of breakout time, that it could still be in the U.S. national interest to go back?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> This is a nonproliferation deal.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And that’s it.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> And we look at it through a nonproliferation lens.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And that’s it. There is no other – there’s no other lens. This is a &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We look at – we – through a nonproliferation lens, comparing a potential return to compliance with the JCPOA to where we are now, it is in our advantage to return to the JCPOA. The famous saying from President Biden – don’t compare us to the Almighty, compare us to the alternative. The JCPOA is the best alternative. It remains the best alternative at the moment. That won’t be the case forever.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Where is Robert Malley at this time and what is he doing?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The last time I saw Rob was a few days ago. He was in Washington, D.C. He is always on the phone. He is talking to our European allies. He’s talking to other stakeholders. And until and unless there is reason for him to return to Vienna, I suspect he will continue to do a lot of that from here.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, my last one on this. Just what do you make, if anything, of this Senate vote yesterday on the – I mean, I know it’s non-binding, but it was a pretty clear shot across the bow of the administration.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So it was a vote on the China bill, and we do look forward to the rapid passage of legislation that President Biden can sign to boost our competitiveness vis-à-vis the PRC &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, I’m talking about the Iran deal.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, it was part of the package.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, I understand that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>But to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>All right. This is like me asking you to describe an elephant and you say, well, elephants are scared of mice.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And a mouse is a little brown animal, whatever, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The problem is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I’m asking you about the Iran part of this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I know, but the problem is that you &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; which Democrats &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>You &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Very – quite a few of them &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>You interrupted me before I could finish my first sentence, and the second clause of my first sentence was going to say &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>All right. Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; we are aware of the nonbinding Iran-related instruction to Senate conferees that was passed yesterday. As I said before, the President’s commitment is that Iran will not obtain a nuclear weapon. He has been clear that at this point, the best way to realize that is through a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA. That is what Rob Malley and his team are seeking to achieve at the moment.</p>
<p>We do share the concern expressed by the Senate about other aspects of Iran’s behavior, including their development of ballistic missiles, support for terrorism through the IRGC and other elements. And that’s why our administration has actually increased sanctions on Iran’s ballistic missile program and on the IRGC over the past year. There is nothing in a potential return to the JCPOA that would in any way diminish our resolve or our ability to continue combating these aspects of Iran’s policies in the region. If this math is still correct, of the 107 sanctions that we have applied on Iran since January 20th of 2021, 86 of those – which, if my math is right, about three quarters of those – have been on the IRGC. We are committed to doing all we can, pulling every lever we can to take on the threat, together with our partners, from the IRGC.</p>
<p>Now, having said all that, we know that all of these problems are even more intractable, even more challenging – and challenging, if Iran also is in a position to have a nuclear program that is unconstrained. That is why we have always been of the mindset that the decision to withdraw from an agreement that was demonstrably working to prevent Iran from obtaining a nuclear weapon has comprehensively failed to protect our national security interests and, in fact, has actually resulted in the opposite. It has resulted in an Iran that is more aggressive, that is more destabilizing, and its proxies could be called the same.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. But it is still the administration’s position that you do not believe that you can get anything outside of the nuclear stuff into a return to the JCPOA? In other words, just as it was in 2015, the missiles, the support for extremists, et cetera – you’re not looking to get that into just – get that into a deal?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The JCPOA is about one thing and one thing only, and that’s Iran’s nuclear program.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, so then is this the end of the longer and stronger thing that you guys have been – had been talking about since February of last year (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>As I said before, we are committed to working with our allies and partners to address these other challenges that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Right, but the JCPOA is not going to be longer and stronger even &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The first step &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Even &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The first step, but &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, no, no, no. But if you, a deal to return, it isn’t going to be longer and stronger for now.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The first step is testing the proposition as to whether we can mutually return to compliance with the JCPOA.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I get that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That’s the first step.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Now, going back to the point about hypotheticals, it’s far from clear that we’ll get there.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, it wasn’t a hypothetical.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, no &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>This is what the administration came into – into office saying not only do we want to return to the JCPOA, but we want to make it longer and stronger, part of one whole thing. And I just want to make sure that what you’re saying now is that you have essentially – given up might be a pejorative here, but you don’t believe that it is – that it is at all possible to include other things that weren’t covered by the original deal in &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We have – we have &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; in a new one.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We have always said that a first step is putting a box back on top of Iran’s nuclear program. That is the first step. It is, to my point a moment ago, a hypothetical as to whether we’ll be able to do that, because it’s far from certain whether a mutual return to the JCPOA will be in the offing or not. Whether we’re able to get there or if we’re not able to get there, we are still going to work with partners and allies and still engage in diplomacy to see to it that we can take on these other challenges that Iran poses to the region and by extension to us. And that includes the IRGC and its ballistic missile program, among other challenges.</p>
<p>Guita.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, you – when you talk about Iran’s advances to a point where the benefits of the JCPOA will not be realized anymore, about that, nuclear experts believe that at a certain point anybody – anybody with nuclear capabilities – can produce crude nuclear bombs, which is one level, obviously, less than the actual, bigger size one. Does the administration differentiate between these two? Because according to David Albright, he – in early April, he estimated that between mid April and end of April Iran would have enough, 60 percent, to manufacture a crude bomb. Does the administration differentiate? Do you – are you waiting until it has – it does 90 percent?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have a commitment that Iran must never be able to acquire a nuclear weapon. And the reason why we have pursued a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA is not only that it would define what Iran can’t do and to impose the most stringent verification and monitoring regime ever negotiated, but it would give the international community – principally through the IAEA – greater transparency into all of the potential pathways that Iran could seek to illicitly acquire a nuclear weapon. So to have an agreement that has these caps, that has a stringent verification and monitoring regime, and as a result that affords much greater levels of transparency to international weapons inspectors, this is why the JCPOA remains – at least for the moment – manifestly in our interest.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, sure. But by now Iran may have enough, 60 percent, to manufacture a smaller explosive. That doesn’t count?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You’re raising something that, again, falls in the category of hypotheticals. We are – we have made clear that we are determined, the President has a commitment, that Iran won’t be able to acquire a nuclear weapon. We want to see to it that we put everything in place in a way that is sustainable, in a way that is durable, in a way that is transparent, so that not only can we prevent this, but if Iran seeks to manufacture a nuclear weapon, if it seeks to manufacture, as you put it, a crude nuclear device, that is something that we would able to detect early on.</p>
<p>All right. Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hold it. I got one more.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Oh, okay. Okay.</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-NEPAL"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I just – I’m just wondering if you have an – any kind of an update on this child custody/abduction issue in Nepal.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Not an update since we last talked about it. I think as you know, this is a matter that is before a court in Nepal. Our priority and responsibility is to assist U.S. citizens the most effective way possible. The embassy in Kathmandu, the department are working diligently to assist the family member in this case. Embassy personnel are in regular contact with the father. They’ve informed him of all developments in this case.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But you’re – you do not consider this to be a case of the child being abducted from India into Nepal?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We are not characterizing this case as an international parental child abduction to Nepal.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Gotcha.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But – well, continue, if you have more.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Okay. So I’ll give you the fuller facts.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We understand the facts of the case to be the following: The child’s Indian national mother was – wrongfully retained the U.S.-citizen child in India in 2017. The father, who is a U.S. citizen, immediately secured a court order in Cook County, Illinois, determining he had sole custody of the child while she was still unlawfully retained in India with her mother. In light of the mother’s actions, the department considers the case to be an international parental child abduction case between the U.S. and India, and the U.S. has formally raised it with the Indian Government on several occasions, urging a swift resolution. In April of this year, the father, while visiting the child, departed India with her across the border to Nepal. Both parents are now in Nepal.</p>
<p>Daphne.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh – sorry, Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, I’m done. Thank you. I said “thank you.”</p>
<p><a id="post-341394-CHINA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Do you have any update on Blinken’s China speech? Will it be rescheduled?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It will be rescheduled. I do not have a date to offer at this time, but I can assure you that we will find a date at the earliest opportunity.</p>
<p>Thank you, all.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:52 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Angolan Minister of State Chief Furtado</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-angolan-minister-of-state-chief-furtado/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 21:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=341390</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with Angolan Minister of State Chief Francisco Furtado in Luanda. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Angolan Minister of State Chief Furtado discussed the growing bilateral security relationship between the United States and Angola, as well as opportunities to deepen regional and multilateral cooperation.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with Angolan Minister of State Chief Francisco Furtado in Luanda. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Angolan Minister of State Chief Furtado discussed the growing bilateral security relationship between the United States and Angola, as well as opportunities to deepen regional and multilateral cooperation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The U.S. Government and AIR – Alliance for Innovative Regulation Announce First TechSprint to Combat Global Corruption</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-u-s-government-and-air-alliance-for-innovative-regulation-announce-first-techsprint-to-combat-global-corruption/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 21:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=341376</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The Department of State’s Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs (INL) and Department of the Treasury’s Office of Terrorist Financing and Financial Crimes are partnering with the AIR to support an inaugural <i>Anti-Corruption Solutions through Emerging Technologies (ASET) Global Anti-Corruption TechSprint</i> to combat global corruption.</p>
<p align="left">Corruption undermines democracy and respect for human rights, impedes investment, stifles economic growth, hampers government services, and allows criminality to flourish.  Responding to this transnational threat, President Biden established fighting corruption as a core U.S. national security interest, releasing the first-ever U.S. Strategy on Countering Corruption, and elevating the fight against corruption as a pillar of the Summit for Democracy. The TechSprint allows for a collaboration with other governments, the private sector, civil society, and the responsible use of technology in the fight against corruption, which are core elements of both effective implementation of the strategy, and the Summit for Democracy’s Year of Action.</p>
<p align="left">The development and implementation of effective anti-corruption mechanisms consistent with international standards – and the ability to meet evolving corruption challenges – is vital to peace and prosperity and is a key Department of State commitment for the Summit for Democracy.  INL’s ASET program advances the Administration’s anti-corruption strategy by supporting efforts to accelerate technological solutions to combat corruption worldwide. This multi-day virtual competition will bring together anti-corruption stakeholders from across government, civil society, and the private sector, to spur new ideas and relationships around anti-corruption measures, with a particular emphasis on financial solutions. The TechSprint prototypes may be further developed, tested, and adapted for global use by the teams that develop them.</p>
<p align="left">INL works to keep Americans safe by countering crime, illegal drugs, and instability abroad.  The bureau is working around the world to, among other measures, build the capacity of foreign justice sector partners to investigate and prosecute complex corruption cases.</p>
<p align="left">For more information about the sprint, please visit <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA1MDUuNTc0ODM4MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5hbnRpY29ycnVwdGlvbnRlY2hzcHJpbnQub3JnLyJ9.9sskJyABwFpJJkL-HYrS16AGVPwACwcsMPJV8kQ4X7A/s/1248191874/br/130892471240-l" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA1MDUuNTc0ODM4MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5hbnRpY29ycnVwdGlvbnRlY2hzcHJpbnQub3JnLyJ9.9sskJyABwFpJJkL-HYrS16AGVPwACwcsMPJV8kQ4X7A/s/1248191874/br/130892471240-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1651870771367000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1C-q9zDGRX-v3lna2i6tiu">https://www.<wbr />anticorruptiontechsprint.org/</a> <wbr />or contact INL-PAPD@state.gov.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The Department of State’s Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs (INL) and Department of the Treasury’s Office of Terrorist Financing and Financial Crimes are partnering with the AIR to support an inaugural <i>Anti-Corruption Solutions through Emerging Technologies (ASET) Global Anti-Corruption TechSprint</i> to combat global corruption.</p>
<p align="left">Corruption undermines democracy and respect for human rights, impedes investment, stifles economic growth, hampers government services, and allows criminality to flourish.  Responding to this transnational threat, President Biden established fighting corruption as a core U.S. national security interest, releasing the first-ever U.S. Strategy on Countering Corruption, and elevating the fight against corruption as a pillar of the Summit for Democracy. The TechSprint allows for a collaboration with other governments, the private sector, civil society, and the responsible use of technology in the fight against corruption, which are core elements of both effective implementation of the strategy, and the Summit for Democracy’s Year of Action.</p>
<p align="left">The development and implementation of effective anti-corruption mechanisms consistent with international standards – and the ability to meet evolving corruption challenges – is vital to peace and prosperity and is a key Department of State commitment for the Summit for Democracy.  INL’s ASET program advances the Administration’s anti-corruption strategy by supporting efforts to accelerate technological solutions to combat corruption worldwide. This multi-day virtual competition will bring together anti-corruption stakeholders from across government, civil society, and the private sector, to spur new ideas and relationships around anti-corruption measures, with a particular emphasis on financial solutions. The TechSprint prototypes may be further developed, tested, and adapted for global use by the teams that develop them.</p>
<p align="left">INL works to keep Americans safe by countering crime, illegal drugs, and instability abroad.  The bureau is working around the world to, among other measures, build the capacity of foreign justice sector partners to investigate and prosecute complex corruption cases.</p>
<p align="left">For more information about the sprint, please visit <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA1MDUuNTc0ODM4MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5hbnRpY29ycnVwdGlvbnRlY2hzcHJpbnQub3JnLyJ9.9sskJyABwFpJJkL-HYrS16AGVPwACwcsMPJV8kQ4X7A/s/1248191874/br/130892471240-l" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA1MDUuNTc0ODM4MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5hbnRpY29ycnVwdGlvbnRlY2hzcHJpbnQub3JnLyJ9.9sskJyABwFpJJkL-HYrS16AGVPwACwcsMPJV8kQ4X7A/s/1248191874/br/130892471240-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1651870771367000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1C-q9zDGRX-v3lna2i6tiu">https://www.<wbr />anticorruptiontechsprint.org/</a> <wbr />or contact INL-PAPD@state.gov.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary of State for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment Jose W. Fernandez At the 2022 World Food Prize Laureate Announcement Ceremony</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-of-state-for-economic-growth-energy-and-the-environment-jose-w-fernandez-at-the-2022-world-food-prize-laureate-announcement-ceremony/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jose W. Fernandez, Under Secretary for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 17:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=341324</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jose W. Fernandez, Under Secretary for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</b>  Good morning, everyone.  Welcome to the State Department.  Like to welcome Under Secretary Fernandez, President Stinson, honored guests, ladies and gentlemen.  Good morning and welcome to the 2022 World Food Prize Laureate announcement ceremony.  I know some of you are joining us virtually, but I’m happy to have the chance to see so many people here in person today.</p>
<p>We’re delighted to have you join us both in this historic room and online.</p>
<p>For more than 30 years, the World Food Prize has recognized and celebrated individuals who advance the cause of food security and nutrition around the world.  It’s the U.S. Department of State’s honor to host this event in person this year after two years of fully virtual events.</p>
<p>We’re glad to be joined by Special Envoy for Global Food Security Dr. Cary Fowler.  I’d also like to thank Secretary of Agriculture Tom Vilsack for participating in this event.  While he’s unable to join us in person, we’re grateful for his pre-recorded remarks for today’s ceremony.</p>
<p>At the State Department and particularly in the bureau I’m responsible for, the Bureau for Economic and Business Affairs, we greatly value our longstanding relationship with the World Food Prize Foundation.  Our mutual focus on promoting innovation and science-based solutions, much like the prize’s namesake, Dr. Norman Borlaug, are needed more than ever to address the complex food security challenges facing the world.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, those challenges are being exacerbated at this very moment by Vladimir Putin’s unjustified, unprovoked war against Ukraine, which has put millions more around the globe at risk of food insecurity.</p>
<p>Russia and Ukraine are two of the world’s most significant exporters of agricultural commodities and fertilizer.  And by conducting his war of aggression against Ukraine, Putin has guaranteed that the costs of his reckless campaign will be felt beyond Ukraine by the world’s most vulnerable citizens for years – and for years to come.</p>
<p>The work of the World Food Prize Foundation is more important now than ever as we face both the consequences of this war and other challenges, like climate change and the lingering effects of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>And now to announce this year’s World Food Prize laureate, I welcome to the stage World Food Prize Foundation President Barbara Stinson.<b>  </b>(Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MS STINSON:</b>  Thank you.  Thank you so much.  Thank you, Assistant Secretary Toloui – thank you to Secretary Blinken; our thoughts are with you; thank you for inviting us in – Under Secretary Fernandez and Dr. Fowler, and the U.S. State Department for hosting the announcement in the beautiful Benjamin Franklin Room.</p>
<p>We are so pleased to be back in person after two years.  We appreciate 20 years of incredible partnership with the State Department, and I’d also like to thank Secretary Tom Vilsack.  We appreciate your partnership over these many years, working with us to announce the 2022 laureate, and I’m also happy to welcome Jennifer Moffitt, Chavonda Jacobs-Young, also here with us today.</p>
<p>Other friends are also here from USDA, and truly, our partners from around the world, everyone here in the room – we thank you.  Special guest, his honor – His Excellency Hailemariam Desalegn, welcome – from Ethiopia.  Thank you.</p>
<p>At the World Food Prize Foundation, our mission is to elevate innovations and inspire action to sustainably increase the quality, quantity, and availability of food for all.  Today we recognize an individual who epitomizes this mission.</p>
<p>Let me also thank Paul Schickler, who’s here with us as chair of our board of directors, and the council of advisors.  We have representatives of the council of advisors – they’d give us sage advice throughout the year – and we have both Dr. Jacobs-Young with us today, Mort Neufville, and Ismail Serageldin.  Thank you for coming.</p>
<p>Dr. Norman Borlaug was the father of the Green Revolution, and it’s said to have saved over a billion lives through his agricultural innovations.  He envisioned an annual prize honoring significant and measurable achievements in improving the world’s food supply, and he inspired others to action.  Dr. Gebisa Ejeta is one of those, 2009 World Food Prize laureate and the chair of our independent group of experts who support the selection committee of the World Food Prize.  Thank you to Gebisa.</p>
<p>Today I announce the 2022 World Food Prize laureate, who will join 51 others who advanced human development through their innovations in food and agriculture, but also for nutrition, aquatic foods, soil health, food technology and infrastructure, economics, and humanitarian leadership.</p>
<p>I am pleased to have one of our laureates here today, David Beckmann.  He received the 2010 World Food Prize.</p>
<p>We are faced with unprecedented challenges in global food security, with the war in Ukraine, escalating food prizes, food availability and access challenges, and the ongoing impacts of COVID-19 and climate change.  This triple threat impacts our world’s hungry, poor, and vulnerable the most.</p>
<p>Today we recognize and elevate the work of our 52nd laureate, who’s making seminal global contributions to climate change modeling for transforming food systems.  She has spent four decades cultivating our understanding of biophysical and socioeconomic impacts that climate change and food systems have on each other, improving the methods that we use to predict these trends.  Her collaborative research provides the scientific evidence used by thousands of decision makers in more than 90 countries that are striving to both mitigate the impacts of and adapt to climate change.  Our laureate’s work shows that data-driven strategies curb climate change impacts and enhance sustainable food production at the same time.</p>
<p>An agronomist and a climatologist, she has been a leader in the field of food and climate since the early 1980s when she carried out some of the first studies on how climate change would impact food production in North America.  She quickly escalated this work and elevated to global studies, incorporating economics, social research, using agricultural science and climate modeling to better understand and predict trends.  She was one of the first to document the impacts of climate change on our food supply.</p>
<p>Her work as lead and co-lead author on international assessments contributed to our scientific foundation of the UN Framework Convention for* Climate Change.  Her research directly supports work in more than 20 countries to develop national adaptation plans and to determine their contributions.  She founded the Agricultural Model Intercomparison and Improvement Program<a href="#footnote1"></a>, AgMIP.  It’s a global transdisciplinary network of more than a thousand leading researchers from around the world.  AgMIP sets the gold standard for climate and food systems modeling.  Our laureate led the development of protocols to improve model performance in diverse conditions, and coordinated assessments across many different disciplines and scales.</p>
<p>As a farmer herself, our laureate understands the importance of centering farmers in agricultural research, as both the most important beneficiaries of the research and custodians of practical indigenous knowledge.  AgMIP helps us understand climate risks in various scenarios, and assures that both public policy and our investments are going to serve farmers of all types equitably.</p>
<p>For her energy and insight this brilliant trailblazer brings to addressing climate change and transforming food systems, I am so pleased to announce that the 2022 World Food Prize laureate is Dr. Cynthia Rosenzweig of the United States.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>Dr. Rosenzweig is a senior research scientist and head of the Climate Impacts group at NASA’s Goddard Institute for Space Studies.  I am pleased to have Administrator of NASA Bill Nelson here with us today.  Thank you for coming.  To learn more about Dr. Rosenzweig, see her story. It’s going to be passed out as you leave the room.  It’s available on our website right away, now, and – (laughter) – boom – and it’s also going to be an opportunity to learn more about her at Live with the Laureate, which is a webcast that we’ll present on Thursday, May 26th.</p>
<p>And it will be my honor to present the World Food Prize at the Iowa State Capitol in Des Moines on Thursday, October 20th, so please plan to join us.  The 2022 International Borlaug Dialogue will take place in Des Moines.  It will be in person and virtually.  As always, we will be addressing the theme of feeding a fragile world – to address the nexus of agriculture, climate change, and food and nutrition security.</p>
<p>Thank you all for coming today.  Thank you for celebrating.  I’m going to turn it back to you, Assistant Secretary Toloui.  I hope to see all of you in Des Moines, where you can meet the 2022 World Food Prize laureate, Dr. Cynthia Rosenzweig.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:  </b>Thank you, President Stinson, for those remarks.  And congratulations to the New World Food Prize laureate, Dr. Cynthia Rosenzweig.  I’m very proud that my home state of Iowa is going to be hosting the ceremony.</p>
<p>I’d now like to turn to Under Secretary for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment Jose Fernandez, who will offer congratulations and remarks of his own.</p>
<p><b>UNDER SECRETARY FERNANDEZ:</b>  Thank you and good morning.  And thank you, Ramin.  My talking points say, “Thank you for that warm introduction,” but I’ll cut the warm for – (laughter).  Thank you so much.  And thank you really for the work that you and your team are doing, the good work that you’re doing to strengthen food security worldwide, especially in the face of Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine.  And Barbara , I – as someone who went to Iowa when I was assistant secretary three times, it’s a real show.  It’s a lot of fun, and it’s a real celebration.  So hopefully – hopefully I can get back there.</p>
<p>Thank you again, Barbara, to you and to everyone at the World Food Prize Foundation for your outstanding work in fighting world hunger and supporting extraordinary individuals like this year’s laureate, Cynthia – Dr. Cynthia Rosenzweig.</p>
<p>I don’t need to tell you this: this is a critical moment for food security.  In 2021, more than 160 million people worldwide experienced acute food insecurity, a 19 percent jump – a 19 percent jump – from the year before.  Millions more are poised to fall into food insecurity due to the Russian Government’s war in Ukraine.  As many of you know, Ukraine supplies a significant amount of the world’s wheat and corn, but this can’t happen when farmers have been forced to fight or have had to flee invading troops, and when they don’t have the diesel fuel to operate tractors and other equipment.  Russian troops have destroyed port facilities, they’ve blocked food shipments in the Black Sea that get food to the rest of the world, and as a result, it’s not only displaced Ukrainians who are going hungry, but it’s also created hunger around the world for people who depend on these crops.</p>
<p>The issue of food security has grown even more urgent, and the effects of food insecurity are widespread and are devastating.  When there is food insecurity, farmers lose their livelihoods.  Parents spend hours every day trying to secure their family’s next meal.  Hungry children struggle to learn, and they suffer irreversible health consequences.  Already vulnerable populations are always, always hit hardest, and food insecurity also holds back broader economic growth and increases the risk of violent conflict and civil unrest.</p>
<p>This is a humanitarian crisis; it’s a health crisis.  It’s an economic and national security issue. And simply put, it’s a moral issue.  No child – no child on Earth should have to go hungry.  That’s why the U.S. – and a lot of this is through Ramin’s good work – is committed to the global fight against food insecurity both by addressing the root causes of hunger, and also by meeting the immediate needs of those suffering worldwide.</p>
<p>One of those root causes is the climate crisis.  Climate change has already had a significant and negative impact on global agricultural production, and its impact is only going to get worse.  We’re seeing rice fields drown in floods; we’re seeing other crops wither in drought.  We’ve seen shellfish die in more acidic oceans, and crop diseases are spreading to new regions.  We likely would not understand all of these problems as well as we do today without the work of Dr. Cynthia Rosenzweig, this year’s World Food Prize laureate.</p>
<p>As you’ve heard, Dr. Rosenzweig was one of the first scientists to document how climate change affects food production.  Thanks to her research, we can better predict how rising temperatures, extreme weather, and carbon dioxide will affect food production and quality.  And the work she’s done for NASA, for the United Nations, and the U.S. Congress has empowered lawmakers and also policymakers to make smarter decisions to protect agriculture against the changing climate.</p>
<p>For example, the U.S. recently launched an initiative with the UAE, with the United Arab Emirates, called the Agricultural Innovation Mission for Climate, or AIM for C.  Together, we’re investing $4 billion in climate-smart agriculture to develop crops that are more resilient to threats like pests and extreme weather.  And this will build upon Dr. Rosenzweig’s foundational research.  We’re grateful for her pioneering work, and we’re proud to be an ally in this fight, and we’re proud to be an ally with the World Food Prize Foundation.</p>
<p>The State Department has created an action plan.  It’s created an action plan to bring partners together to address food security that’s been caused by Putin’s war.  And this plan has five components.</p>
<p>First, we’re tackling immediate disruptions to the global food supply and mobilizing resources to meet urgent humanitarian needs.  President Biden announced recently that the U.S. is prepared to provide one billion dollars to this effort.</p>
<p>The second component is that we’re stepping efforts – stepping up our work to mitigate the global fertilizer shortage by collaborating with other countries to increase production.</p>
<p>Third, we continue to boost agricultural capacity and resilience through Feed the Future, which is the U.S. Government’s global hunger and food security initiative.  Feed the Future provides support to countries in order to improve local nutrition and make their agricultural systems more resilient.</p>
<p>Fourth, we’re working with our partners, including the International Monetary Fund, the World Bank, and many other multilateral organizations and development banks, to cushion the impact of rising food prices on poor people.  This includes strengthening social safety nets and scaling up cash transfers to the most vulnerable.</p>
<p>Finally, and fifth, we are pursuing all of these efforts with intensive diplomacy in our bilateral relationships and in international forums.  For example, in a couple of weeks, in two weeks, Secretary Blinken will host a ministerial in New York at the United Nations, a ministerial that we’re calling a global food security call to action.  This is going to bring together those countries most affected by food insecurity together with those best positioned to help.  And Secretary Blinken will chair a meeting of the UN Security Council that’s going to be focused on the current hunger crisis.</p>
<p>As we continue this work, we will be joined by a new member of our team, who I’d like to introduce right now, Dr. Cary Fowler.  Dr. Fowler has a resume that we can all dream of.  He’s our new Special Envoy for Global Food Security and he brings decades – decades – of experience to the State Department.  Dr. Fowler is a renowned agriculturalist and he’s going to be indispensable in our work and in our fight against global hunger.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s people like Dr. Rosenzweig, like Dr. Fowler, and each of you here today who make progress against food insecurity possible.  Thank you.  Thank you all for your dedication to this worthy fight.  And congratulations again to Dr. Rosenzweig for this well-deserved recognition.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</b>  Thank you, Under Secretary Fernandez, Jose, for your remarks.  I’ll have to warm up those introductions next year.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Now I’d like to turn everyone’s attention to the video screens.  Secretary Tom Vilsack from USDA was unable to attend today, but he’s provided prerecorded remarks for this event.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY VILSACK:</b> (Via video remarks) It’s my honor to join guests from all around the world in celebrating the 2022 World Food Prize laureate, Dr. Cynthia Rosenzweig.  Dr. Rosenzweig embodies the leadership, innovation, and experience necessary to face the intersecting challenges of global hunger and the climate crisis and to empower agriculture to be a meaningful solution to address these challenges.</p>
<p>A farmer first, her early influences in agricultural came from working the land and cultivating a love for food on the farm.  Through work that thus far has spanned four decades, she set out to discover what will happen to our food with the climate changing so rapidly and has been at the cutting edge of using modeling to predict outcomes.</p>
<p>She completed the first transdisciplinary model projections of the effects of climate change on food production in North America in 1985, becoming one of the first scientists to document that climate change was already impacting the cultivation of our food supply.  She started the Agricultural Model Intercomparison and Improvement Project to significantly improve agricultural models and scientific and technological capabilities for assessing the impacts of climate variability and change, as well as other driving forces on agriculture, food security, and poverty from local to global scales.  This type of interdisciplinary work has and will continue to aid USDA in making investments in programmatic decisions, particularly as we develop climate-smart agricultural approaches, build on a greater understanding of the impacts of climate change on our food systems.</p>
<p>In addition, her work on Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change demonstrated a way forward on food and agricultural systems.  Among the key findings in the 2019 report she coauthored, we find optimism through the recognition that healthy and sustainable foods present major opportunities for reducing greenhouse gas emissions and improving health outcomes.</p>
<p>She also shines a bright light on the importance of agricultural training programs that inspire the next generation of climate, agriculture, and food leaders.</p>
<p>Training and retraining will become even more pertinent with ongoing climate challenges.  Changing crops, pests, rainfall amounts, and seasonal patterns means ag systems will need even greater and more innovative training and information-delivery models for farmers.</p>
<p>At USDA, we’re proud to partner with the World Food Prize Foundation on the Wallace-Carver Fellowship, which offers college students a valuable opportunity to learn firsthand from scientists and policymakers at research centers and field offices.</p>
<p>Just as Dr. Rosenzweig’s on-the-job experience, training, and education propelled her forward in her career, we are training and inspiring the next generation of leaders who will follow in her footsteps.  At the same time, we’ll continue to pursue climate-smart agricultural methods and innovative solutions to drive transformation in climate action, in no small part thanks to her groundbreaking work.</p>
<p>Congratulations to her on this incredible, successful career, which is culminated in this noble and well-deserved honor.  This generation and future generations thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</b>  I’d like to thank Secretary Vilsack for those remarks, and to all of our USDA colleagues who’ve – who joined in sharing that video today.  We’re – we work very closely with USDA here at the State Department on these global food security challenges.</p>
<p>And with that, let me welcome Dr. Cary Fowler, the Department of State’s new special envoy for global food security, to the podium.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>DR FOWLER:</b>  Good morning.  It is a good morning, isn’t it?  Under Secretary Fernandez, President Stinson, Assistant Secretary Toloui, honored guests, it’s my honor to be with you today.  I’m particularly thrilled as today’s laureate announcement ceremony marks the first official public engagement in my new role as special envoy for global food security.  I very much appreciate the trust shown to me by President Biden and Secretary Blinken.</p>
<p>Agriculture is facing an historically unprecedented combination of challenges: the task of producing more food with less land, with less water, in the context of escalating conflict, and in the face of a rapidly changing climate.  Is agriculture ready for this?  Are our crops adapted?  Are our farming systems and institutions prepared?</p>
<p>Everyone looks to World Food Prize laureates both for hope and for solutions.  However, there is no quick fix or easy answer.  The recipients of this award have labored long and brought innovation and creativity to bear to answer these questions.  The World Food Prize recognizes and celebrates the grand masters of global food security.  These are men and women who are not only brilliant in their specific fields, but, like the best chess players, they are superb strategists.  They have recognized big problems, usually intractable and often invisible to others, and they’ve navigated past all the obstacles on the board to solve them.  Most laureates labor quietly and with little notice or fanfare until their names are read out in this building.  The announcement here at the State Department recognizes the importance of their work and their personal sacrifices, and it signals our nation’s profound gratitude.</p>
<p>Most importantly, though, I hope that this inspires the next generation of budding scientists and researchers to follow in their footsteps in striving for a world where food is truly available to all.  Congratulations to Dr. Rosenzweig and thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</b>  Dr. Fowler, thank you.  It’s a delight to have you in the building at this important time.</p>
<p>As we conclude today’s ceremony – and I’d like to thank José, Under Secretary Fernandez, President Stinson, Secretary Vilsack for their involvement today.  It should be clear to everyone who is here in person and participating virtually how seriously the United States Government takes this issue.  Through pioneering initiatives like the Agriculture Innovation Mission for Climate, we’re working with governments, companies, researchers, and philanthropies around the world to drive investment toward our most pressing agriculture innovation priorities, and I’d encourage you all to join us in “AIMing for Climate,” and we’re grateful to the contributions you’re already making to these goals.</p>
<p>I also want to thank President Barbara Stinson and the entire World Food Prize Foundation for their tireless efforts to strengthen global food security and food systems and advance human development.  The State Department and our government partners look forward to participating in the October Borlaug Dialogue events in Des Moines and to continuing our efforts throughout the year to advance our common objectives to build sustainable, equitable, and resilient food systems.</p>
<p>Thank you again for everyone – to everyone for joining us today, and once more, congratulations to our 2022 World Food Prize Laureate Dr. Cynthia Rosenzweig.  (Applause.)</p>
<div>
<hr />
<div>
<p><a id="footnote1"></a> Agricultural Model Intercomparison and Improvement Project</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jose W. Fernandez, Under Secretary for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</b>  Good morning, everyone.  Welcome to the State Department.  Like to welcome Under Secretary Fernandez, President Stinson, honored guests, ladies and gentlemen.  Good morning and welcome to the 2022 World Food Prize Laureate announcement ceremony.  I know some of you are joining us virtually, but I’m happy to have the chance to see so many people here in person today.</p>
<p>We’re delighted to have you join us both in this historic room and online.</p>
<p>For more than 30 years, the World Food Prize has recognized and celebrated individuals who advance the cause of food security and nutrition around the world.  It’s the U.S. Department of State’s honor to host this event in person this year after two years of fully virtual events.</p>
<p>We’re glad to be joined by Special Envoy for Global Food Security Dr. Cary Fowler.  I’d also like to thank Secretary of Agriculture Tom Vilsack for participating in this event.  While he’s unable to join us in person, we’re grateful for his pre-recorded remarks for today’s ceremony.</p>
<p>At the State Department and particularly in the bureau I’m responsible for, the Bureau for Economic and Business Affairs, we greatly value our longstanding relationship with the World Food Prize Foundation.  Our mutual focus on promoting innovation and science-based solutions, much like the prize’s namesake, Dr. Norman Borlaug, are needed more than ever to address the complex food security challenges facing the world.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, those challenges are being exacerbated at this very moment by Vladimir Putin’s unjustified, unprovoked war against Ukraine, which has put millions more around the globe at risk of food insecurity.</p>
<p>Russia and Ukraine are two of the world’s most significant exporters of agricultural commodities and fertilizer.  And by conducting his war of aggression against Ukraine, Putin has guaranteed that the costs of his reckless campaign will be felt beyond Ukraine by the world’s most vulnerable citizens for years – and for years to come.</p>
<p>The work of the World Food Prize Foundation is more important now than ever as we face both the consequences of this war and other challenges, like climate change and the lingering effects of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>And now to announce this year’s World Food Prize laureate, I welcome to the stage World Food Prize Foundation President Barbara Stinson.<b>  </b>(Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MS STINSON:</b>  Thank you.  Thank you so much.  Thank you, Assistant Secretary Toloui – thank you to Secretary Blinken; our thoughts are with you; thank you for inviting us in – Under Secretary Fernandez and Dr. Fowler, and the U.S. State Department for hosting the announcement in the beautiful Benjamin Franklin Room.</p>
<p>We are so pleased to be back in person after two years.  We appreciate 20 years of incredible partnership with the State Department, and I’d also like to thank Secretary Tom Vilsack.  We appreciate your partnership over these many years, working with us to announce the 2022 laureate, and I’m also happy to welcome Jennifer Moffitt, Chavonda Jacobs-Young, also here with us today.</p>
<p>Other friends are also here from USDA, and truly, our partners from around the world, everyone here in the room – we thank you.  Special guest, his honor – His Excellency Hailemariam Desalegn, welcome – from Ethiopia.  Thank you.</p>
<p>At the World Food Prize Foundation, our mission is to elevate innovations and inspire action to sustainably increase the quality, quantity, and availability of food for all.  Today we recognize an individual who epitomizes this mission.</p>
<p>Let me also thank Paul Schickler, who’s here with us as chair of our board of directors, and the council of advisors.  We have representatives of the council of advisors – they’d give us sage advice throughout the year – and we have both Dr. Jacobs-Young with us today, Mort Neufville, and Ismail Serageldin.  Thank you for coming.</p>
<p>Dr. Norman Borlaug was the father of the Green Revolution, and it’s said to have saved over a billion lives through his agricultural innovations.  He envisioned an annual prize honoring significant and measurable achievements in improving the world’s food supply, and he inspired others to action.  Dr. Gebisa Ejeta is one of those, 2009 World Food Prize laureate and the chair of our independent group of experts who support the selection committee of the World Food Prize.  Thank you to Gebisa.</p>
<p>Today I announce the 2022 World Food Prize laureate, who will join 51 others who advanced human development through their innovations in food and agriculture, but also for nutrition, aquatic foods, soil health, food technology and infrastructure, economics, and humanitarian leadership.</p>
<p>I am pleased to have one of our laureates here today, David Beckmann.  He received the 2010 World Food Prize.</p>
<p>We are faced with unprecedented challenges in global food security, with the war in Ukraine, escalating food prizes, food availability and access challenges, and the ongoing impacts of COVID-19 and climate change.  This triple threat impacts our world’s hungry, poor, and vulnerable the most.</p>
<p>Today we recognize and elevate the work of our 52nd laureate, who’s making seminal global contributions to climate change modeling for transforming food systems.  She has spent four decades cultivating our understanding of biophysical and socioeconomic impacts that climate change and food systems have on each other, improving the methods that we use to predict these trends.  Her collaborative research provides the scientific evidence used by thousands of decision makers in more than 90 countries that are striving to both mitigate the impacts of and adapt to climate change.  Our laureate’s work shows that data-driven strategies curb climate change impacts and enhance sustainable food production at the same time.</p>
<p>An agronomist and a climatologist, she has been a leader in the field of food and climate since the early 1980s when she carried out some of the first studies on how climate change would impact food production in North America.  She quickly escalated this work and elevated to global studies, incorporating economics, social research, using agricultural science and climate modeling to better understand and predict trends.  She was one of the first to document the impacts of climate change on our food supply.</p>
<p>Her work as lead and co-lead author on international assessments contributed to our scientific foundation of the UN Framework Convention for* Climate Change.  Her research directly supports work in more than 20 countries to develop national adaptation plans and to determine their contributions.  She founded the Agricultural Model Intercomparison and Improvement Program<a href="#footnote1"></a>, AgMIP.  It’s a global transdisciplinary network of more than a thousand leading researchers from around the world.  AgMIP sets the gold standard for climate and food systems modeling.  Our laureate led the development of protocols to improve model performance in diverse conditions, and coordinated assessments across many different disciplines and scales.</p>
<p>As a farmer herself, our laureate understands the importance of centering farmers in agricultural research, as both the most important beneficiaries of the research and custodians of practical indigenous knowledge.  AgMIP helps us understand climate risks in various scenarios, and assures that both public policy and our investments are going to serve farmers of all types equitably.</p>
<p>For her energy and insight this brilliant trailblazer brings to addressing climate change and transforming food systems, I am so pleased to announce that the 2022 World Food Prize laureate is Dr. Cynthia Rosenzweig of the United States.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>Dr. Rosenzweig is a senior research scientist and head of the Climate Impacts group at NASA’s Goddard Institute for Space Studies.  I am pleased to have Administrator of NASA Bill Nelson here with us today.  Thank you for coming.  To learn more about Dr. Rosenzweig, see her story. It’s going to be passed out as you leave the room.  It’s available on our website right away, now, and – (laughter) – boom – and it’s also going to be an opportunity to learn more about her at Live with the Laureate, which is a webcast that we’ll present on Thursday, May 26th.</p>
<p>And it will be my honor to present the World Food Prize at the Iowa State Capitol in Des Moines on Thursday, October 20th, so please plan to join us.  The 2022 International Borlaug Dialogue will take place in Des Moines.  It will be in person and virtually.  As always, we will be addressing the theme of feeding a fragile world – to address the nexus of agriculture, climate change, and food and nutrition security.</p>
<p>Thank you all for coming today.  Thank you for celebrating.  I’m going to turn it back to you, Assistant Secretary Toloui.  I hope to see all of you in Des Moines, where you can meet the 2022 World Food Prize laureate, Dr. Cynthia Rosenzweig.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:  </b>Thank you, President Stinson, for those remarks.  And congratulations to the New World Food Prize laureate, Dr. Cynthia Rosenzweig.  I’m very proud that my home state of Iowa is going to be hosting the ceremony.</p>
<p>I’d now like to turn to Under Secretary for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment Jose Fernandez, who will offer congratulations and remarks of his own.</p>
<p><b>UNDER SECRETARY FERNANDEZ:</b>  Thank you and good morning.  And thank you, Ramin.  My talking points say, “Thank you for that warm introduction,” but I’ll cut the warm for – (laughter).  Thank you so much.  And thank you really for the work that you and your team are doing, the good work that you’re doing to strengthen food security worldwide, especially in the face of Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine.  And Barbara , I – as someone who went to Iowa when I was assistant secretary three times, it’s a real show.  It’s a lot of fun, and it’s a real celebration.  So hopefully – hopefully I can get back there.</p>
<p>Thank you again, Barbara, to you and to everyone at the World Food Prize Foundation for your outstanding work in fighting world hunger and supporting extraordinary individuals like this year’s laureate, Cynthia – Dr. Cynthia Rosenzweig.</p>
<p>I don’t need to tell you this: this is a critical moment for food security.  In 2021, more than 160 million people worldwide experienced acute food insecurity, a 19 percent jump – a 19 percent jump – from the year before.  Millions more are poised to fall into food insecurity due to the Russian Government’s war in Ukraine.  As many of you know, Ukraine supplies a significant amount of the world’s wheat and corn, but this can’t happen when farmers have been forced to fight or have had to flee invading troops, and when they don’t have the diesel fuel to operate tractors and other equipment.  Russian troops have destroyed port facilities, they’ve blocked food shipments in the Black Sea that get food to the rest of the world, and as a result, it’s not only displaced Ukrainians who are going hungry, but it’s also created hunger around the world for people who depend on these crops.</p>
<p>The issue of food security has grown even more urgent, and the effects of food insecurity are widespread and are devastating.  When there is food insecurity, farmers lose their livelihoods.  Parents spend hours every day trying to secure their family’s next meal.  Hungry children struggle to learn, and they suffer irreversible health consequences.  Already vulnerable populations are always, always hit hardest, and food insecurity also holds back broader economic growth and increases the risk of violent conflict and civil unrest.</p>
<p>This is a humanitarian crisis; it’s a health crisis.  It’s an economic and national security issue. And simply put, it’s a moral issue.  No child – no child on Earth should have to go hungry.  That’s why the U.S. – and a lot of this is through Ramin’s good work – is committed to the global fight against food insecurity both by addressing the root causes of hunger, and also by meeting the immediate needs of those suffering worldwide.</p>
<p>One of those root causes is the climate crisis.  Climate change has already had a significant and negative impact on global agricultural production, and its impact is only going to get worse.  We’re seeing rice fields drown in floods; we’re seeing other crops wither in drought.  We’ve seen shellfish die in more acidic oceans, and crop diseases are spreading to new regions.  We likely would not understand all of these problems as well as we do today without the work of Dr. Cynthia Rosenzweig, this year’s World Food Prize laureate.</p>
<p>As you’ve heard, Dr. Rosenzweig was one of the first scientists to document how climate change affects food production.  Thanks to her research, we can better predict how rising temperatures, extreme weather, and carbon dioxide will affect food production and quality.  And the work she’s done for NASA, for the United Nations, and the U.S. Congress has empowered lawmakers and also policymakers to make smarter decisions to protect agriculture against the changing climate.</p>
<p>For example, the U.S. recently launched an initiative with the UAE, with the United Arab Emirates, called the Agricultural Innovation Mission for Climate, or AIM for C.  Together, we’re investing $4 billion in climate-smart agriculture to develop crops that are more resilient to threats like pests and extreme weather.  And this will build upon Dr. Rosenzweig’s foundational research.  We’re grateful for her pioneering work, and we’re proud to be an ally in this fight, and we’re proud to be an ally with the World Food Prize Foundation.</p>
<p>The State Department has created an action plan.  It’s created an action plan to bring partners together to address food security that’s been caused by Putin’s war.  And this plan has five components.</p>
<p>First, we’re tackling immediate disruptions to the global food supply and mobilizing resources to meet urgent humanitarian needs.  President Biden announced recently that the U.S. is prepared to provide one billion dollars to this effort.</p>
<p>The second component is that we’re stepping efforts – stepping up our work to mitigate the global fertilizer shortage by collaborating with other countries to increase production.</p>
<p>Third, we continue to boost agricultural capacity and resilience through Feed the Future, which is the U.S. Government’s global hunger and food security initiative.  Feed the Future provides support to countries in order to improve local nutrition and make their agricultural systems more resilient.</p>
<p>Fourth, we’re working with our partners, including the International Monetary Fund, the World Bank, and many other multilateral organizations and development banks, to cushion the impact of rising food prices on poor people.  This includes strengthening social safety nets and scaling up cash transfers to the most vulnerable.</p>
<p>Finally, and fifth, we are pursuing all of these efforts with intensive diplomacy in our bilateral relationships and in international forums.  For example, in a couple of weeks, in two weeks, Secretary Blinken will host a ministerial in New York at the United Nations, a ministerial that we’re calling a global food security call to action.  This is going to bring together those countries most affected by food insecurity together with those best positioned to help.  And Secretary Blinken will chair a meeting of the UN Security Council that’s going to be focused on the current hunger crisis.</p>
<p>As we continue this work, we will be joined by a new member of our team, who I’d like to introduce right now, Dr. Cary Fowler.  Dr. Fowler has a resume that we can all dream of.  He’s our new Special Envoy for Global Food Security and he brings decades – decades – of experience to the State Department.  Dr. Fowler is a renowned agriculturalist and he’s going to be indispensable in our work and in our fight against global hunger.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s people like Dr. Rosenzweig, like Dr. Fowler, and each of you here today who make progress against food insecurity possible.  Thank you.  Thank you all for your dedication to this worthy fight.  And congratulations again to Dr. Rosenzweig for this well-deserved recognition.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</b>  Thank you, Under Secretary Fernandez, Jose, for your remarks.  I’ll have to warm up those introductions next year.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Now I’d like to turn everyone’s attention to the video screens.  Secretary Tom Vilsack from USDA was unable to attend today, but he’s provided prerecorded remarks for this event.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY VILSACK:</b> (Via video remarks) It’s my honor to join guests from all around the world in celebrating the 2022 World Food Prize laureate, Dr. Cynthia Rosenzweig.  Dr. Rosenzweig embodies the leadership, innovation, and experience necessary to face the intersecting challenges of global hunger and the climate crisis and to empower agriculture to be a meaningful solution to address these challenges.</p>
<p>A farmer first, her early influences in agricultural came from working the land and cultivating a love for food on the farm.  Through work that thus far has spanned four decades, she set out to discover what will happen to our food with the climate changing so rapidly and has been at the cutting edge of using modeling to predict outcomes.</p>
<p>She completed the first transdisciplinary model projections of the effects of climate change on food production in North America in 1985, becoming one of the first scientists to document that climate change was already impacting the cultivation of our food supply.  She started the Agricultural Model Intercomparison and Improvement Project to significantly improve agricultural models and scientific and technological capabilities for assessing the impacts of climate variability and change, as well as other driving forces on agriculture, food security, and poverty from local to global scales.  This type of interdisciplinary work has and will continue to aid USDA in making investments in programmatic decisions, particularly as we develop climate-smart agricultural approaches, build on a greater understanding of the impacts of climate change on our food systems.</p>
<p>In addition, her work on Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change demonstrated a way forward on food and agricultural systems.  Among the key findings in the 2019 report she coauthored, we find optimism through the recognition that healthy and sustainable foods present major opportunities for reducing greenhouse gas emissions and improving health outcomes.</p>
<p>She also shines a bright light on the importance of agricultural training programs that inspire the next generation of climate, agriculture, and food leaders.</p>
<p>Training and retraining will become even more pertinent with ongoing climate challenges.  Changing crops, pests, rainfall amounts, and seasonal patterns means ag systems will need even greater and more innovative training and information-delivery models for farmers.</p>
<p>At USDA, we’re proud to partner with the World Food Prize Foundation on the Wallace-Carver Fellowship, which offers college students a valuable opportunity to learn firsthand from scientists and policymakers at research centers and field offices.</p>
<p>Just as Dr. Rosenzweig’s on-the-job experience, training, and education propelled her forward in her career, we are training and inspiring the next generation of leaders who will follow in her footsteps.  At the same time, we’ll continue to pursue climate-smart agricultural methods and innovative solutions to drive transformation in climate action, in no small part thanks to her groundbreaking work.</p>
<p>Congratulations to her on this incredible, successful career, which is culminated in this noble and well-deserved honor.  This generation and future generations thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</b>  I’d like to thank Secretary Vilsack for those remarks, and to all of our USDA colleagues who’ve – who joined in sharing that video today.  We’re – we work very closely with USDA here at the State Department on these global food security challenges.</p>
<p>And with that, let me welcome Dr. Cary Fowler, the Department of State’s new special envoy for global food security, to the podium.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>DR FOWLER:</b>  Good morning.  It is a good morning, isn’t it?  Under Secretary Fernandez, President Stinson, Assistant Secretary Toloui, honored guests, it’s my honor to be with you today.  I’m particularly thrilled as today’s laureate announcement ceremony marks the first official public engagement in my new role as special envoy for global food security.  I very much appreciate the trust shown to me by President Biden and Secretary Blinken.</p>
<p>Agriculture is facing an historically unprecedented combination of challenges: the task of producing more food with less land, with less water, in the context of escalating conflict, and in the face of a rapidly changing climate.  Is agriculture ready for this?  Are our crops adapted?  Are our farming systems and institutions prepared?</p>
<p>Everyone looks to World Food Prize laureates both for hope and for solutions.  However, there is no quick fix or easy answer.  The recipients of this award have labored long and brought innovation and creativity to bear to answer these questions.  The World Food Prize recognizes and celebrates the grand masters of global food security.  These are men and women who are not only brilliant in their specific fields, but, like the best chess players, they are superb strategists.  They have recognized big problems, usually intractable and often invisible to others, and they’ve navigated past all the obstacles on the board to solve them.  Most laureates labor quietly and with little notice or fanfare until their names are read out in this building.  The announcement here at the State Department recognizes the importance of their work and their personal sacrifices, and it signals our nation’s profound gratitude.</p>
<p>Most importantly, though, I hope that this inspires the next generation of budding scientists and researchers to follow in their footsteps in striving for a world where food is truly available to all.  Congratulations to Dr. Rosenzweig and thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</b>  Dr. Fowler, thank you.  It’s a delight to have you in the building at this important time.</p>
<p>As we conclude today’s ceremony – and I’d like to thank José, Under Secretary Fernandez, President Stinson, Secretary Vilsack for their involvement today.  It should be clear to everyone who is here in person and participating virtually how seriously the United States Government takes this issue.  Through pioneering initiatives like the Agriculture Innovation Mission for Climate, we’re working with governments, companies, researchers, and philanthropies around the world to drive investment toward our most pressing agriculture innovation priorities, and I’d encourage you all to join us in “AIMing for Climate,” and we’re grateful to the contributions you’re already making to these goals.</p>
<p>I also want to thank President Barbara Stinson and the entire World Food Prize Foundation for their tireless efforts to strengthen global food security and food systems and advance human development.  The State Department and our government partners look forward to participating in the October Borlaug Dialogue events in Des Moines and to continuing our efforts throughout the year to advance our common objectives to build sustainable, equitable, and resilient food systems.</p>
<p>Thank you again for everyone – to everyone for joining us today, and once more, congratulations to our 2022 World Food Prize Laureate Dr. Cynthia Rosenzweig.  (Applause.)</p>
<div>
<hr />
<div>
<p><a id="footnote1"></a> Agricultural Model Intercomparison and Improvement Project</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Angolan Foreign Minister Antonio</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-angolan-foreign-minister-antonio/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 16:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=341277</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with Angolan Foreign Minister Tete Antonio in Luanda.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Antonio discussed the strong and deepening partnership between the United States and Angola.  They discussed areas of shared interest, including strengthening people-to-people ties, and also addressed issues of regional and global security.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with Angolan Foreign Minister Tete Antonio in Luanda.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Antonio discussed the strong and deepening partnership between the United States and Angola.  They discussed areas of shared interest, including strengthening people-to-people ties, and also addressed issues of regional and global security.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Angolan President Lourenço</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-angolan-president-lourenco/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 14:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=341254</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with Angolan President João Lourenço in Luanda.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and President Lourenço discussed deepening our strong bilateral relationship and the importance of bolstering trade and U.S. private investment and promoting progress on economic reforms and anti-corruption initiatives.  They addressed our work together to confront the COVID-19 pandemic and address the climate crisis.  The Deputy Secretary and President also discussed opportunities for expanded cooperation on regional security and cooperation among Atlantic nations on shared maritime challenges and opportunities in the Atlantic Basin.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with Angolan President João Lourenço in Luanda.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and President Lourenço discussed deepening our strong bilateral relationship and the importance of bolstering trade and U.S. private investment and promoting progress on economic reforms and anti-corruption initiatives.  They addressed our work together to confront the COVID-19 pandemic and address the climate crisis.  The Deputy Secretary and President also discussed opportunities for expanded cooperation on regional security and cooperation among Atlantic nations on shared maritime challenges and opportunities in the Atlantic Basin.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcoming Dr. Cary Fowler as Special Envoy for Global Food Security</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/welcoming-dr-cary-fowler-as-special-envoy-for-global-food-security/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 12:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=341193</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Dr. Cary Fowler, a noted agriculturalist, has joined the Department of State as U.S. Special Envoy for Global Food Security. Best known as the &#8220;father&#8221; of the Svalbard Global Seed Vault, Dr. Fowler brings decades of commitment and a depth of experience leading multilateral efforts, including at United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) and the Global Crop Diversity Trust.  He arrives at a time of unprecedented stress on global food systems, driven in part by climate change, the impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic, and conflict, most notably Russia’s brutal and unjustified attack on Ukraine and the resulting disruptions to global grain supplies.</p>
<p>The mission of the Special Envoy for Global Food Security is to advance U.S. food security, global hunger, and nutrition objectives, through diplomatic engagement with allies and partners in bilateral, regional and multilateral fora.  As such, Dr. Fowler will be critical to the Department’s efforts to respond to the current global food security challenges guided by the Administration’s Global Food Security Strategy 2022-2026 and Global Nutrition Coordination Plan 2021-2026. He will also serve as Deputy Coordinator for Diplomacy under the U.S. Agency for International Development’s Feed the Future initiative. He will consult widely with our partners nationally and internationally, including, partner governments, the private sector, academia, researchers, international organizations, civil society, and Congress.</p>
<p>I will count on Dr. Fowler’s strategic vision and advice as we advance efforts with the international community to address the many challenges to global food security, nutrition, and food systems.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Dr. Cary Fowler, a noted agriculturalist, has joined the Department of State as U.S. Special Envoy for Global Food Security. Best known as the &#8220;father&#8221; of the Svalbard Global Seed Vault, Dr. Fowler brings decades of commitment and a depth of experience leading multilateral efforts, including at United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) and the Global Crop Diversity Trust.  He arrives at a time of unprecedented stress on global food systems, driven in part by climate change, the impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic, and conflict, most notably Russia’s brutal and unjustified attack on Ukraine and the resulting disruptions to global grain supplies.</p>
<p>The mission of the Special Envoy for Global Food Security is to advance U.S. food security, global hunger, and nutrition objectives, through diplomatic engagement with allies and partners in bilateral, regional and multilateral fora.  As such, Dr. Fowler will be critical to the Department’s efforts to respond to the current global food security challenges guided by the Administration’s Global Food Security Strategy 2022-2026 and Global Nutrition Coordination Plan 2021-2026. He will also serve as Deputy Coordinator for Diplomacy under the U.S. Agency for International Development’s Feed the Future initiative. He will consult widely with our partners nationally and internationally, including, partner governments, the private sector, academia, researchers, international organizations, civil society, and Congress.</p>
<p>I will count on Dr. Fowler’s strategic vision and advice as we advance efforts with the international community to address the many challenges to global food security, nutrition, and food systems.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing – May 4, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-may-4-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 01:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=341143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-dept1"></a>Good afternoon, everyone. Maybe I should say good evening. I am very sorry for the delay. I assume you all have seen a statement that is just hitting your inboxes regarding the fact that Secretary Blinken has tested positive for COVID. The good news is that he is fully vaccinated; he is boosted. He is experiencing only mild symptoms. He will quarantine at home; he will follow CDC guidelines. I know he very much look forwards to returning to the office, returning to his full schedule, and returning to the road just as soon as he is able to do so.</p>
<p>So with that, happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is the China speech still on – tomorrow &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The Secretary looks forward to delivering the address that was scheduled for tomorrow. Unfortunately, it will not talk place tomorrow, but we’ll find an alternative date just as soon as we can.</p>
<p>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. On North Korea and South Korea, China: North Korea fired an ICBM yesterday. How will the United States respond to Kim Jong-un’s repeated missile provocations? And I have one other one next.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-NorthKorea"></a>Well, I am not sure if I heard you perfectly, but it was a ballistic missile that the North Koreans launched. We condemn that launch. Like the DPRK’s recent tests of at least three intercontinental ballistic missiles, this launch is a clear violation of multiple United Nations Security Council resolutions. It demonstrates the fact that North Korea’s ballistic missile program, its nuclear weapons program, it pose – they pose a threat to the DPRK’s neighbors. They pose a threat to the region. They pose a threat to peace and stability throughout the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>When it comes to the United States – and we have said this before; we’ve said this in the aftermath of other recent provocations – our commitment to the defense of our treaty allies, the Republic of Korea and Japan, that commitment is ironclad. We have been and will – we will continue to be in close touch, in close coordination with our treaty allies, the ROK and Japan. And together, we will respond to the provocations that we have seen emanate from the DPRK. This is also something that we will address with our allies and partners in New York. That is work that is ongoing.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But the – when North Korea launched the missile yesterday, Chinese ambassador to Korean Peninsula, Liu Xiaoming, (inaudible) China has never criticized North Korea.  How can you say about this, that China has never criticized North Korea, so they always say that you better – people are talking – is better way is that they both need to dialogue, but they never have?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I would refer to what I said earlier, and that is the fact that each of these provocations has been a violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions. The PRC, of course, is a permanent member of the UN Security Council. The fact that there are multiple UN Security Council resolutions, the fact that there are multiple statements that have emanated from the UN Security Council chamber itself is a testament to the fact that countries around the world – including the PRC – recognize that the DPRK’s ballistic missile, its nuclear program is a source of instability, it is a source of insecurity, and that it is a threat to the broader region.</p>
<p>We will continue to work very closely with Japan and the ROK on this challenge. But of course, we will work with allies as well as partners around the world. And we, as we’ve recently said, have had recent engagements with our PRC counterparts on the danger that is posed by the DPRK’s ballistic missile and nuclear weapons program. Our special envoy, , has had recent engagements; Secretary Blinken has had an opportunity in recent months to engage Wang Yi on this issue as well. It is a challenge that we, on every occasion, also do address with our PRC counterparts.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Lastly, as you know, China is ignoring North Korea’s continued missile provocation. There is no reason why South Korea should get approval from China to deploy THAAD for its own defense – THAAD missile. If South Koreans’ incoming government wants to deploy additional THAAD, will the United States consider it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Every country has the inherent right to self-defense. As I said before, our commitment to the defense of our treaty allies, the ROK in this case, it is ironclad. These will be discussions that we will have as allies regarding how best we can see to it that our commitment to the defense of the ROK remains ironclad.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Follow-up on that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yep.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So is it your assessment that this was a ballistic missile but not an ICBM?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>It is our assessment that it is a ballistic missile. We’re not in a position to provide any additional detail at this time.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>News out of Iran today said that the Iranian Swedish detainee will be – his sentence is going to be carried out towards the end of this month. He is charged with spying for Israel and is to be executed. Today, apparently, also, the Iranian foreign minister spoke with – and that announcement out of Tehran, news out of Tehran is no coincidence. But yesterday Iran – I mean, the trial of a former officer at the – Tehran’s prosecution office, his trial ended in Stockholm, Sweden for having a hand in the execution of political prisoners in 1988. Given that the U.S. has more experience than other countries with its citizens being held hostage for different reasons and getting different sentences, do other countries reach out to the U.S. to see how to handle situations like this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, let me first say <a id="post-341143-Iran"></a>something about this particular case. It’s one that we’re watching very closely, and we’re watching it very closely because it is especially egregious. It is an egregious case of arbitrary detention of this Swedish Iranian doctor, Ahmad Reza Jalali. He has been held by Iranian authorities. Both this department, the State Department, along with the UN special rapporteur on human rights in Iran, have highlighted Jalali’s case and human reports on human rights conditions in Iran. It was a case that was featured in our Human Rights Report.</p>
<p>We know that, as you alluded to, Iran does have a long history of unjust imprisonment of foreign nationals for use as political leverage. It continues to engage in a range of human rights abuses, which include large-scale arbitrary or unlawful detention of individuals, some of whom have faced torture or worse, in some cases execution, after a failure to receive due process and enduring unjust trials.</p>
<p>These practices are outrageous; we continuously document them. We, to your question, do often consult with our allies and partners. As you know, this is an issue that is quite personal for us as a country. Americans remain detained wrongfully, unjustly in Iran. They have been separated from their families for far too long. But it is not only Americans who suffer this treatment, and of course, countless Iranians do as well, dual nationals do as well. So yes, it is something that we routinely discuss with our closest partners to determine how best we can address this shameful practice of wrongful detention, how best we can work together to seek to affect the safe release of our nationals, and importantly, to work together to seek to create and to underscore a norm against this outrageous practice.</p>
<p>This is something that Secretary Blinken has been quite focused on. Our Canadian counterparts have put forward a series of very constructive, very useful proposals that will help to establish this norm by which countries around the world will work together not only to condemn this egregious practice, but to seek to put an end to it by holding accountable, collectively, those countries that are most responsible for this practice. And of course, Iran, unfortunately, is one of those countries.</p>
<p>Yes. Courtney.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Can we stay on Iran?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just a – do you have a status update on JCPOA compliance negotiations? You’ve spoken before and we’ve talked many times about the window closing, the runway being short. Where are we now?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Happy to provide an update. You will find that the update is not all that dissimilar from what you heard when this was last asked, I think it was day before yesterday. The fact is, as everyone in this room knows, that we had achieved significant progress in the P5+1 context in Vienna in recent months, but of course we have not been able to close an agreement and it remains uncertain and unclear if we will be able to. We remain engaged with our European partners and we have spoken of the role of Enrique Mora, the helpful role that he has played conveying messages back and forth between the United States and, in this case, Iran.</p>
<p>We remain committed to testing the proposition as to whether we can achieve a mutual return to compliance with the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action for one reason, and for one reason only: a mutual return to compliance – that is to say, if Iran were to once again submit itself to the permanent, to the verifiable limits and checks imposed on its nuclear program – that would be manifestly in our national interest. Yes, this process has dragged on for much longer than we would like, for far too long, but the fact is that a mutual return to compliance – if Iran were to re‑enter the JCPOA, if we in turn were to re-enter the JCPOA – the result would work to our national security benefit.</p>
<p>That is because ever since 2018, when the last administration left the deal that was working, a deal with which Iran was in compliance, Iran’s nuclear program has advanced in ways that are unacceptable to us. And the net result of those advancements is the fact that Iran has gone from a breakout time – that is to say, the time that it would take Iran to acquire the fissile material necessary for a nuclear weapon should it make the decision to weaponize – has gone from a highwater mark of about a year at the outset of the deal to something that is best now measured in weeks.</p>
<p>And to us, that is unacceptable. And I say that we remain engaged on trying to determine whether a mutual return to compliance is in the offing because a mutual return to compliance would change that dynamic. It would significantly prolong the breakout time. It would change the dynamic. It would reimpose the most stringent verification and monitoring program ever peacefully negotiated on a nuclear program that has not been subject to it for several years now.</p>
<p>So &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are you not yet at the point of diminishing returns? I’m sorry to cut you off, but we – I mean, we’ve talked about the time running short. We’ve now blown past what seem to be several kind of guideposts for timing on negotiating a (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There seems to be an impression that there was always a dated fixed on the calendar for us, and I’ve seen this reported, but I would just note that it flies in the face of what I have consistently said. We don’t think of this – and I’m sorry to go back to this; I’m sure you’re all sick of hearing it – as a temporal clock. This is a technical clock, and it is a technical clock for one simple reason: what we’re looking at is the technical assessment of the point at which a mutual return to compliance – that is to say, the point at which re-entering the deal would not convey benefits, nonproliferation benefits that outweigh the advancements and the implications of the advancements that Iran has been able to achieve while these nuclear shackles has been off – have been off.</p>
<p>So we are still at a point where, if we were able to negotiate a mutual return to compliance, that breakout time would be prolonged from where it is now. We would have greater transparency. There would be those permanent, verifiable limits reimposed on Iran. That would be in our national security interest.</p>
<p>Now, to your point, it is true that there will come a time when, on the basis of those technical assessments, a mutual return to compliance and the nonproliferation benefits it would convey would not, in fact, outweigh the implications of the advancements that Iran has been able to achieve in its nuclear program.</p>
<p>So we are constantly taking a close look at the state of Iran’s nuclear program, of what it is doing, the implications of those actions, and comparing that to the deal that may still be in the offing. But I should add that because the JCPOA, a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA, is very much an uncertain proposition, we are now preparing equally for either scenario – a scenario in which we have a mutual return to compliance, in which that breakout time is elongated and a point at which this – what has the potential to devolve further into a nuclear crisis is put back into a box.</p>
<p>We are also preparing with our allies and partners for a scenario in which there is not a JCPOA and we will have to turn to other tactics and other approaches to fulfill what is for us a requirement, a commitment that President Biden has made that Iran, whether there is a JCPAO or whether there is not a JCPAO, must never, never, never be allowed to acquire a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, can you just say – you keep saying there will come a time when it won’t be worthwhile anymore. But you can say definitively right now today that that time has not – there has not been a judgement made that that time has come and gone?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That time has not come and gone.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, moving on?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Axios has reported today that when the Israeli national security advisor was here and spoke with Jake Sullivan that they – it was agreed that they increase pressure on Iran to finalize this deal and prepare, if it doesn’t happen, for later to push Iran towards this. Can you say anything?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong><a id="post-341143-Israel"></a>What I can say is that we regularly have occasion to consult with our Israeli partners on this. I know that Secretary Blinken has recently met with Foreign Minister Lapid. He’s met with him several times in recent months. He’s been on the phone with him several times in recent months. When there were active negotiations in Vienna, we would routinely brief our Israeli partners before each round, during each round, after each round. Secretary Blinken has done that himself to Foreign Minister Lapid. Secretary Blinken has done that himself with Prime Minister Bennett and his predecessor as well. So I’m not going to detail those consultations, but it is regularly a topic of discussion with our Israeli partners.</p>
<p>Shaun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Can we go to Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The Russians have said that they’re going to again have a ceasefire for three days at the steel plant in Mariupol. Do you see this as – do you see anything positive in this? Do you – are you hopeful that this could actually come to fruition?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong><a id="post-341143-RussiaUkraine1"></a>Well, every time an individual is able to take advantage of a humanitarian corridor, a humanitarian pause to reach safety, that is a good thing. What we want to see happen, however, is a prolonged humanitarian corridor, prolonged humanitarian access. What we have consistently seen, and we’ve seen this even in recent days, is the tendency on the part of the Russian Federation to embrace a so‑called humanitarian pause to cloak itself in the guise of an actor that has humanitarian concerns only to quickly and promptly resume shelling and violence, including against civilians who are trapped in besieged areas, including in Mariupol.</p>
<p>Our concern is – and what we want to see happen – is that this humanitarian access be motivated by genuine humanitarian concern and not the desire on the part of the Russian Federation to achieve a PR victory, to claim it has humanitarian concerns when its only concerns is propaganda.</p>
<p>Now, in recent days, there have been over a hundred individuals who have been able to reach safety as far as Zaporizhzhia in recent days. There are still hundreds of people who are trapped in the steel plant. There are still thousands of people who are in the besieged city of Mariupol who have been once again subject to shelling, to violence. People need to be let out. Humanitarian aid needs to be let in. That dynamic needs to last. That’s what we care about.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, just a follow up on that. There have been reports in Ukraine that the Russians are planning a, quote/unquote, “victory parade” in Mariupol for Monday to mark their Victory Day against Nazi Germany. I mean, first of all, is there anything the United States know about that? But is – how would that be seen? What do you think the message would be if that were to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, I know there’s lots of speculation about what the Russians may or may not do on May 9th, but I can tell you that May 8th and May 9th, it’s not only a day of significance for the Russians. It is a significant day for all of Europe and for the United States too, the anniversary of the defeat of the advance of Nazi Germany at the end of World War II. So this is not a day that any single country owns.</p>
<p>But what I can tell you is that on May 8th, on May 9th, our strategy and our approach is going to be the same strategy and the same effective approach that we have employed since February 24th, since the Russian invasion began. That is to support in many different ways our Ukrainian partners, to hold the Kremlin and the Russian Federation to account, and to do that with allies and partners around the world – dozens of allies around the world across four continents.</p>
<p>So I don’t have anything to preview for what they might do, but again, to claim as a victory, to parade through the streets of a city that not all that long ago was filled with hundreds of thousands of civilians, of people who were doing nothing but seeking livelihoods, pursuing their lives – I think that says a lot in the aftermath of a brutalization by Russian bombs, by Russian shells, by Russian artillery. And if that is the focus of any Victory Day parade, any Victory Day celebration, I think that speaks volumes about the nature of the Kremlin and the nature of what they’re doing to the people of Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. President of the European Council Charles Michel said today that the European Union will provide additional military equipment to Moldova to strengthen its resilience. I wonder if the U.S. considers additional military assistance to Moldova and Georgia, and I wonder if you see any imminent threat of new Russian aggression in the region against these countries.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-georgiamoldova"></a>Both Georgia and Moldova, our – are important partners of the United States. We are committed to their sovereignty, to their independence, to their territorial integrity. We have demonstrated that commitment in a number of ways. When it comes to Moldova, we spoke about this, I believe, on Tuesday. We recently restarted a strategic dialogue with our Moldovan counterparts. Secretary Blinken was recently in Chișinău, where he met with the Moldovan leadership; had an opportunity to meet with Moldovan leadership once again here for that strategic dialogue.</p>
<p>It is a partnership that spans many different elements. We have provided significant amount – a significant amount of humanitarian assistance to our Moldovan partners. Our militaries have an effective partnership. They have served together side by side as far away as Kosovo, and our commitment, as I said before, to the sovereignty, to the independence, to the territorial integrity of Moldova and to Georgia, which we have demonstrated in our own right as well – that is something that we will continue to support.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And any negotiations planned with Georgian side about the latest developments in the region and Russian aggression?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’re always in touch through our embassy, through the department here with our partners in the region. That certainly includes with our counterparts in Tbilisi. Those discussions are ongoing. Again, to your previous question, we know that Vladimir Putin may harbor aspirations to wage aggression against other countries in the region. I think we are demonstrating in response to how we are providing our Ukrainian partners with what they need to be effective against this instance, this egregious instance of Russian aggression – we are demonstrating that the United States and our allies and partners won’t stand for that type of activity.</p>
<p>Yes, sir.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Inaudible) news network, Pakistan. Sir, last week there was a suicide bomb blast in Pakistan. Due to situation in Afghanistan, we have seen rising terrorism in Pakistan. The security assistance was suspended by previous U.S. administration. It is still suspended. Is there any reviews going on?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-pakistan"></a>Well, at the time, we strongly condemned the terrorist attack against Karachi University, a university in Pakistan. We reiterate that condemnation today. A terrorist attack anywhere is an affront to humanity everywhere, but for a terrorist attack to take place at a university, or at a religious site, or at some of the locations we’ve seen recently – that is a true affront to mankind.</p>
<p>When it comes to your question, what I’ll say is that we value our bilateral relationship. We want to continue to work together in areas where we do have mutual interests with our Pakistani partners. That includes counterterrorism. That includes border security as well.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you so much. Jahanzaib Ali from ARY News TV Pakistan. Sir, the U.S. Commission on Religious Freedom recommended to include India into their blacklist, like for the religious freedom violations. So what would be the – expecting to see in regards to, like, second time in a row a U.S. commission recommended India to be included into the CPC countries?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-religion"></a>Well, USCIRF is an independent commission. It’s not a governmental entity. It does provide recommendations and guidance to the U.S. Government. It is something that we look at closely as we evaluate conditions of religious freedom or lack thereof around the world. I have no doubt that our experts in our Office of International Religious Freedom will take a close look at the report that USCIRF has submitted as they prepare for our determinations and our findings when it comes to religious freedom around the world.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And on China, can you give a preview of the China strategy speech?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong><a id="post-341143-china"></a>I was going to deflect that question and to duck it, pointing to the fact that there would be a speech tomorrow. Unfortunately, there won’t be a speech tomorrow, but there will be a speech at some point in the not too distant future. So I will then duck that question pointing to that date in the not too distant future.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And about Secretary Blinken, did he take an antigen test or a PCR test? It said about taking – took one on Tuesday and also this morning.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong><a id="post-341143-dept2"></a>He tested positive earlier this afternoon via PCR test. He had tested negative as recently as earlier this morning, and again yesterday with antigen tests.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, well, let’s just stay on that – and I don’t know how much you covered at the beginning before I was here.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think I answered everyone’s questions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, on this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I’m kidding.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>On the COVID? So you say that he’s not considered a close contact with the President.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That’s right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Certainly he’s – correct me if I’m wrong – a close contact with the Swedish foreign minister, who was &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That’s right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; here this afternoon, and potentially with the Mexican foreign secretary who was here yesterday and everyone who was at that luncheon. So have they all been informed? And then why, if he tested negative this morning with an antigen test, did he get a PCR test this afternoon? Was it because he was feeling symptomatic (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So we are in the process and we have notified those individuals with whom he has been in close contact following CDC guidance. So in most cases, if not all cases, we’ve been in a position to notify them. The Secretary, as you know, he has young kids in the house. As you know, he was around a number of people this weekend. So as a matter of precaution, he does regularly test. He reported symptoms this afternoon. He received a PCR test shortly thereafter.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So in other words, he didn’t get the PCR test this afternoon because he was – he was feeling symptoms. He got it just because &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>He reported symptoms this afternoon and thereafter received a PCR test.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So that’s why he took the PCR test?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Correct. Correct.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I mean, it wasn’t something that was required since he had been – he had tested negative this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That’s right. That’s right. That’s right. Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, and then – so can you say approximately how many people have been notified that they are close contacts of the Secretary? I mean, does it go back to Saturday night’s dinner? Does it go to whatever events, parties that he went to on Sunday?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>What I will say is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>How far back &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; that he is he is working closely with the department physician, his physician here at the department. They are working together to follow CDC guidance, to reconstruct close contacts in the appropriate period. And those people either have been notified or are in the process of being notified.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, well, can you just explain to me – according – I guess it’s CDC guidance, but also – and I’ve had personal experience with this as well with a State Department physician. But can you say that the Swedish foreign minister is a close contact? I mean, we saw them standing next to each other &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; but I don’t know if that qualifies for the 15 minutes and – you know.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I will – I don’t want to divulge &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I know you don’t want to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; divulge anyone’s health information. What I will say is that he had a bilateral meeting &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Fair enough, but &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; with the Swedish foreign minister, and the press aspect of that was only one element of it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Right.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So suffice it to say that we are notifying everyone who is considered a close contact per that CDC guidance.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The Secretary spoke at the Foreign Press Centers yesterday. You were along with the Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Have you tested negative? And also any update on informing reporters and Foreign Press Centers staffers?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So if – I believe you were there at the at the Foreign Press Center. The Secretary was not within six feet of reporters. There are CDC guidelines regarding close contacts. As I was explaining to Matt, we are and have notified those individuals who would qualify as close contacts. I was tested just about an hour ago and tested negative.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>A couple questions on Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So hang on a second, so you were identified as a close contact? I mean, I would hope you were since you’re his spokesman, but &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>What I will say is that I was tested about an hour ago and tested negative.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>On Ukraine, a couple of questions. Let me start with Hungary, which is pushing back against oil – Russian oil ban. I know you’re not involved in this, but the U.S. did not impose sanctions on Russian oil, but rather decided to go with its own purchase decision. Will Hungary’s pushback, first, affect your relationship with Hungary? Secondly, will maybe cause the U.S. to reconsider its decision on Russian oil ban moving towards the sanctions, which will make Hungary an enabler if they continue to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong><a id="post-341143-russia"></a>When it comes to the proposed oil ban, it is something we welcome on the part of the EU. I would need to refer you to the European Union for any details. Obviously this is a question that they continue to discuss within their own bloc, within their member states.</p>
<p>There is, however, broad support among our allies and partners for cutting off what is undeniably the strength of President Putin’s economy and his war machine, and that is energy. We are united as a NATO Alliance. We are united with our European allies, including with the EU, on the imperative on cutting back and choking off this important source of revenue for our – for the Russian Federation. We are in regular conversation with our partners and allies about the most effective way to decrease their dependence on Russian energy.</p>
<p>The position the United States is in is different from the position that any member of the EU is in; it is different from the position that any other country around the world is in. The United States, as we have discussed, is in a fortunate position in that we were never reliant on Russian energy, and in fact, we have infrastructure and we have energy supplies in this country that has enabled us to do things earlier that other countries, that other blocs are considering now. And shortly after the start of the invasion, on March 8th, President Biden signed an executive order that banned the import of key sources of Russian energy.</p>
<p>Now, of course, the EU – there are certain countries in the EU who have a higher dependence on Russian energy. Our goal is to see to it that we do everything to choke off these strategic assets, to make it as painful for the Kremlin and to make it as painless for the United States and our partners and allies around the world. But these are conversations that are ongoing within the EU, so I wouldn’t want to get ahead of those.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> One more question on the EU – EU unity, actually – Secretary Blinken and French Foreign Minister Le Drian, last week they had their call, and the readout says that they also discussed intensifying support for both North Macedonia and Albania on their EU accession bids. So can you tell me more in detail what exactly this intensified support means that was mentioned in the readout and how this support is given? Do you have some back-and-forth diplomatic channels with Bulgaria? Did you contact the EU leaders to convince Bulgaria and even put pressure on it to lift its veto for these countries to finally start the negotiation talks with the EU, North Macedonia, and Albania?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-EU"></a>Well, the United States has long been a strong supporter of North Macedonia and Albania’s integration into the EU. We believe the future of the Western Balkans is squarely with the EU. The enlargement process promotes long-term peace, stability, prosperity throughout the region, and the EU’s March 2020 decision to open accession negotiations with North Macedonia and Albania we think was a positive step. These two countries have laid the groundwork, and the time, we believe, is now to move forward together to the next phase in the long and challenging accession process.</p>
<p>The historic Prespa Agreement demonstrated that countries in the Western Balkans are capable of doing difficult things, making compromises, and finding solutions, and we’re confident that Bulgaria and North Macedonia will do the same by negotiating their bilateral disputes. We do continue on a bilateral basis to urge both of them, Bulgaria and North Macedonia, to resolve those disputes quickly, but obviously we’re not going to detail those conversations.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> To go back to Iran. The families of some of the imprisoned Americans joined in a demonstration today outside the White House. Can you give us an update on the status of the indirect talks over the detainees? Are they still happening despite the holdup in the nuclear talks? And will the State Department help facilitate a meeting between the families and President Biden, as they called for today?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-Iran2"></a>So in terms of the Americans who are detained – wrongfully detained – in Iran, we have made the point that we have no higher priority than the safe return of Americans who are wrongfully or unjustly detained anywhere, and that includes the four Americans who are detained in Iran.</p>
<p>We’ve also made the point that even as there had been a process in Vienna to discuss nuclear issues, that we were not going to conflate these two areas of discussion. And we weren’t going to do those for one simple reason, and I think that simple reason has become even more evident given where we are now in terms of the talks regarding Iran’s nuclear program. The JCPOA has always been an uncertain proposition. It is very uncertain now, the potential of a mutual return to compliance with it.</p>
<p>We want to see to it that the return of these Americans is a certain proposition. So it does not do us, it certainly does not do these Americans or their families any good to tie their fates to something that may or may not happen. At the same time, we have conveyed in no uncertain terms to the Iranians the priority we attach to seeing the safe release of these Americans. It is something that our team here as worked on constantly. It’s something that we worked on even before the formal process in Vienna began in the spring of 2021.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>To follow up on the families.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just – I just want to make sure you get a chance to respond to these families are out there. They gave – were out there this morning, gave a press conference where there was a lot of – obviously a lot of criticism of the administration for, as they see it, not doing enough to get their family members home. Specifically, Alexandra Forseth is the daughter and niece of two of the guys who were part of the CITGO-6 in Venezuela. She says, talking to the other families, they all see this pattern of indecision from the administration in terms of trying to get family members home, talked about running into roadblocks within the administration as they tried to – try to get more action from you guys that would help to get these family members home. Now, how do you respond to these people’s emotional pleas and criticisms like that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong><a id="post-341143-VZ"></a>I wouldn’t want to respond directly only because I am not going to be in a position to understand their full anguish and the emotion that is of course attached to having a loved one held unjustly in a faraway place for, in all cases, far too long and, for most of those cases, years at a time. I will never be able to understand that. There are many people in this building who don’t – won’t be able to understand that on a personal level. But what I can say is that we are doing everything we can, almost all of it unseen, almost all of it unsaid in public, to do everything we can to advance the commitment that President Biden has to see these Americans who are wrongfully or unjustly detained around the world or in some cases held hostage around the world brought home.</p>
<p>The President has made a commitment to do that. We have been able to make good on that commitment in a number of cases, including as you alluded to in Venezuela, including in Burma, including in Afghanistan, including in Haiti, including most recently in Russia with the return of Trevor Reed. In all of those cases, we did not detail contemporaneously what it was that we were doing, but we were doing it and we were executing on the President’s commitment. We are executing on the priority that the President attaches to this, that Secretary Blinken attaches to this.</p>
<p>And our special presidential envoy for hostage affairs and his office, Roger Carstens and his office. They have traveled the world, they are ready and willing to go anywhere, to talk to anyone as in some cases – as in many cases they have – in an effort to see these Americans returned to their homes. That is a commitment we have. We will keep executing on that commitment until every single last American is reunited with her or his family.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Can you talk some more about the State Department’s process for determining that Brittney Griner is being wrongfully detained in Russia? And why did that take the amount of time that it did?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong><a id="post-341143-Russia2"></a>What I can say is that – and as you heard from us yesterday, we have – we have determined that the Russian Federation has wrongfully detained U.S. citizen Brittney Griner. There is – there will be no change, of course, to the fact that we are going to do everything we can to provide appropriate support to Ms. Griner, to her family. There’s only so much I can say about the process for determining whether an American is wrongfully detained. It is a deliberative process.</p>
<p>But what I can say is that we weigh the totality of circumstances in every case: whether it’s the case of Brittney Griner, whether it’s the case of Paul Whelan, whether it&#8217;s the case of Americans in Iran. There are going to be unique factors in each and every one of those cases. But I would say that the Robert Levinson Act, section 302 of that act, does spell out a number of criteria – 11 criteria that are among the factors that we look at in determining whether an American who is detained overseas is held wrongfully or unjustly.</p>
<p>And you can see for yourself many of those criteria: if there is, for example, an indication of innocence; if the detention is based on being a U.S. national; if it is in violation of the laws of the detaining country; if due process has been sufficiently denied or impaired, and you can go on through that list.</p>
<p>But each case of an American detained overseas is going to be unique, and in each case, we look at the totality of circumstances in that case when it comes to arriving at such a determination.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just to follow up on their call for White House meetings, the Tices met with President Biden this week. Will the other families have a chance to?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I can say – I can only speak for the Department of State, but I can say that Secretary Blinken has frequently had an opportunity to meet and to speak with the families of Americans who are wrongfully detained around the world. As recently within the past couple days he’s had an opportunity to meet face to face with the family of one such American and to speak to the family over the phone of another such American.</p>
<p>We often don’t publicize these, again, because our efforts – we want to see to it that our efforts have the best prospects of being effective. And we’ve found that when we undertake these activities, these discussions quietly, that they are bestowed typically with more effectiveness.</p>
<p>Now, of course, President Biden, Jake Sullivan, others at the White House have also routinely met with the families of hostages. It is important for us to hear their perspective, to hear their inputs. After all, it’s these families who know the details, who know the intricacies of these cases better than anyone. And there was a process put forward in 2015 with a new PPD that called for a more streamlined, more effective process for engaging with the families. That is a commitment that the department and I know this entire administration takes very seriously, knowing that, again, these families are going to be the best advocates, these families are going to be the best experts when it comes to the unique and the totality of circumstances behind each individual case.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, two questions on conflicts, and let me start with Ukraine again. President Zelenskyy said today that we will not go to a frozen conflict. I wonder if it reflects Washington’s viewpoint as well. Can Ukraine rely on State Department’s or Washington’s support when it comes to frozen conflict (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m sorry. I missed part of your question. Can Ukraine rely on the United States &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. The president said that he will not accept frozen – another frozen – we have been there, done that, so that’s not a solution. Does that reflect general sentiment here as well as a potential playout of this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-RussiaUkraine2"></a>The general sentiment here – in fact, the only sentiment here – is that it is up to our Ukrainian partners to determine the endpoint that they want to achieve. It is up to them to determine what they seek to achieve in their discussions with the Russians. It is up to them to determine what it is that is the will of their people. And it is our role to support them in carrying that out. It is our role to support them on the battlefield by providing security assistance. It is our role to support them at the negotiating table by strengthening their hand, including by providing them security assistance, but also holding the Russian Federation to account.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> To another conflict as well, chief OSCE monitor Andrzej Kasprzyk was at the State Department this morning. I believe he met with Assistant Secretary Donfried. Have they discussed the Nagorno-Karabaakh issue and/or is the U.S. – the state of U.S. involvement at this point? I know that there are some efforts between Europeans and Washington and probably the – if I’m not mistaken, there have been other meetings this week or next week with Europeans. Am I right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sorry, I missed the last part of your question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That there have been other meetings between Europeans and Washington either this week or next week, if I’m not mistaken &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t know if they agreed to an additional meeting or if that was discussed, but we’ll let you know if we have more details to share from that meeting.</p>
<p>We’ll take a couple final questions, yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. I have a question on Saudi Arabia on behalf of a colleague, Michele, who had to leave. But <em>The Wall Street Journal</em> says that – has reported that CIA Director Bill Burns traveled to Saudi Arabia in mid-April, and according to this article, one American official has called – has described the trip as better than prior engagements. What’s the status of relations between the U.S. and Saudi Arabia? Has it gotten worse? Is it the Russia crisis – the crisis that Russia has created? And what will it take to bring back Saudi Arabia in this way and not – and not let it go towards Russia and China?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-Saudi"></a>Well, I think I would dispute the premise of the second part of your question. Of course, Saudi Arabia has been a longstanding partner of the United States. In many ways that’s a partnership that dates back to 1945, when FDR met with King Abdul Aziz. But fast-forwarding, more recently, you’ve heard from senior American and Saudi officials about the critical importance of the strategic ties between the United States and Saudi Arabia, and importantly, how we can use that strategic partnership and those strategic ties to deliver for our own people.</p>
<p>For our part, we have pursued the many mutual interests that we have with our Saudi partners. We’ve pursued the many interests that we have within the Gulf region and beyond with Saudi Arabia, just as we have sought to elevate human rights and to put them at the center of our foreign policy, including at the center of our bilateral relationships. And we have – not unrelated to that – engaged in vigorous diplomacy, including with our Saudi partners, to seek to bring an end to the war in Yemen. And I think across the board you have seen the way we have managed this relationship and the way we have – the way we have engaged with this partner deliver results for the United States, for our Saudi partners as well.</p>
<p>Most recently, we supported UN efforts to secure a nationwide two-month truce in Yemen. We – it is something that we were – have been quite encouraged by. It is a testament to the work of the UN special envoy but also to our own Special Envoy Tim Lenderking, who has spent quite a good bit of time in Riyadh and other parts of Saudi Arabia and in other parts of the Gulf to arrive at this two-month truce that, of course, we want to see built upon.</p>
<p>We’re also encouraged by Saudi Arabia’s return of its ambassador to Lebanon at an important moment. And we remain committed to building a partnership with Saudi Arabia that is durable and that is, importantly, sustainable that accounts for the broad range of shared interests that our countries have, whether that is helping Saudi Arabia defend its territory and the 70-some-odd thousand Americans who are resident within the kingdom; whether it is helping to educate tens of thousands of young Saudis who will help to craft and to drive their country’s future; whether it’s partnering on clean energy and renewables; whether it’s addressing human rights or, as I said before, helping to end the war in Yemen.</p>
<p>Our approach to this partnership has been designed to advance the ball on each and every one of those, and the way we measure this partnership is in terms of that effectiveness: what have we been able to achieve? And we’ve been able to achieve a great deal, including in recent weeks.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> There is no point of contention, no differences?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Every relationship is unique, and of course there is no country around the world with whom we share identical perspectives on every single issue. What is important for us is that we manage our relationship in a way that delivers results for our two countries, and I think in the case of Saudi Arabia you’ve been able to see many of those results in recent weeks.</p>
<p>One final question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are there any plans to help the Ukrainian refugees that traveled to Mexico and are now in this limbo state because the U.S. is no longer accepting them?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-Ukraine"></a>Well, what I can say is that we have put in place a process so that Ukrainians need not make the journey to Mexico or to any other third country in the region because we do have a pipeline now, a program we are calling Uniting for Ukraine under which Ukrainians can be sponsored directly and under which they can be paroled directly into the United States for two years.</p>
<p>Now, the President has made a commitment to bring to this country 100,000 Ukrainians and others affected by this war. That includes Ukrainians who are internally displaced within their home country, Ukrainians who are now refugees in Europe, but in some cases there will be Ukrainians who are refugees in places closer to the United States. We’re going to adjudicate each of those cases, but again, there is now a program through which Ukrainians have much readier, much easier access to the United States through this sponsorship program. Of course, that’s not the only pathway for arrival here in the United States – the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program, including the Lautenberg Program under those auspices, and then the additional resources we have committed to visa processing – visa processing in the region for Ukrainians seeking to travel to the United States.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 4:42 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-dept1"></a>Good afternoon, everyone. Maybe I should say good evening. I am very sorry for the delay. I assume you all have seen a statement that is just hitting your inboxes regarding the fact that Secretary Blinken has tested positive for COVID. The good news is that he is fully vaccinated; he is boosted. He is experiencing only mild symptoms. He will quarantine at home; he will follow CDC guidelines. I know he very much look forwards to returning to the office, returning to his full schedule, and returning to the road just as soon as he is able to do so.</p>
<p>So with that, happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is the China speech still on – tomorrow &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The Secretary looks forward to delivering the address that was scheduled for tomorrow. Unfortunately, it will not talk place tomorrow, but we’ll find an alternative date just as soon as we can.</p>
<p>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. On North Korea and South Korea, China: North Korea fired an ICBM yesterday. How will the United States respond to Kim Jong-un’s repeated missile provocations? And I have one other one next.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-NorthKorea"></a>Well, I am not sure if I heard you perfectly, but it was a ballistic missile that the North Koreans launched. We condemn that launch. Like the DPRK’s recent tests of at least three intercontinental ballistic missiles, this launch is a clear violation of multiple United Nations Security Council resolutions. It demonstrates the fact that North Korea’s ballistic missile program, its nuclear weapons program, it pose – they pose a threat to the DPRK’s neighbors. They pose a threat to the region. They pose a threat to peace and stability throughout the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>When it comes to the United States – and we have said this before; we’ve said this in the aftermath of other recent provocations – our commitment to the defense of our treaty allies, the Republic of Korea and Japan, that commitment is ironclad. We have been and will – we will continue to be in close touch, in close coordination with our treaty allies, the ROK and Japan. And together, we will respond to the provocations that we have seen emanate from the DPRK. This is also something that we will address with our allies and partners in New York. That is work that is ongoing.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But the – when North Korea launched the missile yesterday, Chinese ambassador to Korean Peninsula, Liu Xiaoming, (inaudible) China has never criticized North Korea.  How can you say about this, that China has never criticized North Korea, so they always say that you better – people are talking – is better way is that they both need to dialogue, but they never have?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I would refer to what I said earlier, and that is the fact that each of these provocations has been a violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions. The PRC, of course, is a permanent member of the UN Security Council. The fact that there are multiple UN Security Council resolutions, the fact that there are multiple statements that have emanated from the UN Security Council chamber itself is a testament to the fact that countries around the world – including the PRC – recognize that the DPRK’s ballistic missile, its nuclear program is a source of instability, it is a source of insecurity, and that it is a threat to the broader region.</p>
<p>We will continue to work very closely with Japan and the ROK on this challenge. But of course, we will work with allies as well as partners around the world. And we, as we’ve recently said, have had recent engagements with our PRC counterparts on the danger that is posed by the DPRK’s ballistic missile and nuclear weapons program. Our special envoy, , has had recent engagements; Secretary Blinken has had an opportunity in recent months to engage Wang Yi on this issue as well. It is a challenge that we, on every occasion, also do address with our PRC counterparts.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Lastly, as you know, China is ignoring North Korea’s continued missile provocation. There is no reason why South Korea should get approval from China to deploy THAAD for its own defense – THAAD missile. If South Koreans’ incoming government wants to deploy additional THAAD, will the United States consider it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Every country has the inherent right to self-defense. As I said before, our commitment to the defense of our treaty allies, the ROK in this case, it is ironclad. These will be discussions that we will have as allies regarding how best we can see to it that our commitment to the defense of the ROK remains ironclad.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Follow-up on that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yep.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So is it your assessment that this was a ballistic missile but not an ICBM?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>It is our assessment that it is a ballistic missile. We’re not in a position to provide any additional detail at this time.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>News out of Iran today said that the Iranian Swedish detainee will be – his sentence is going to be carried out towards the end of this month. He is charged with spying for Israel and is to be executed. Today, apparently, also, the Iranian foreign minister spoke with – and that announcement out of Tehran, news out of Tehran is no coincidence. But yesterday Iran – I mean, the trial of a former officer at the – Tehran’s prosecution office, his trial ended in Stockholm, Sweden for having a hand in the execution of political prisoners in 1988. Given that the U.S. has more experience than other countries with its citizens being held hostage for different reasons and getting different sentences, do other countries reach out to the U.S. to see how to handle situations like this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, let me first say <a id="post-341143-Iran"></a>something about this particular case. It’s one that we’re watching very closely, and we’re watching it very closely because it is especially egregious. It is an egregious case of arbitrary detention of this Swedish Iranian doctor, Ahmad Reza Jalali. He has been held by Iranian authorities. Both this department, the State Department, along with the UN special rapporteur on human rights in Iran, have highlighted Jalali’s case and human reports on human rights conditions in Iran. It was a case that was featured in our Human Rights Report.</p>
<p>We know that, as you alluded to, Iran does have a long history of unjust imprisonment of foreign nationals for use as political leverage. It continues to engage in a range of human rights abuses, which include large-scale arbitrary or unlawful detention of individuals, some of whom have faced torture or worse, in some cases execution, after a failure to receive due process and enduring unjust trials.</p>
<p>These practices are outrageous; we continuously document them. We, to your question, do often consult with our allies and partners. As you know, this is an issue that is quite personal for us as a country. Americans remain detained wrongfully, unjustly in Iran. They have been separated from their families for far too long. But it is not only Americans who suffer this treatment, and of course, countless Iranians do as well, dual nationals do as well. So yes, it is something that we routinely discuss with our closest partners to determine how best we can address this shameful practice of wrongful detention, how best we can work together to seek to affect the safe release of our nationals, and importantly, to work together to seek to create and to underscore a norm against this outrageous practice.</p>
<p>This is something that Secretary Blinken has been quite focused on. Our Canadian counterparts have put forward a series of very constructive, very useful proposals that will help to establish this norm by which countries around the world will work together not only to condemn this egregious practice, but to seek to put an end to it by holding accountable, collectively, those countries that are most responsible for this practice. And of course, Iran, unfortunately, is one of those countries.</p>
<p>Yes. Courtney.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Can we stay on Iran?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just a – do you have a status update on JCPOA compliance negotiations? You’ve spoken before and we’ve talked many times about the window closing, the runway being short. Where are we now?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Happy to provide an update. You will find that the update is not all that dissimilar from what you heard when this was last asked, I think it was day before yesterday. The fact is, as everyone in this room knows, that we had achieved significant progress in the P5+1 context in Vienna in recent months, but of course we have not been able to close an agreement and it remains uncertain and unclear if we will be able to. We remain engaged with our European partners and we have spoken of the role of Enrique Mora, the helpful role that he has played conveying messages back and forth between the United States and, in this case, Iran.</p>
<p>We remain committed to testing the proposition as to whether we can achieve a mutual return to compliance with the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action for one reason, and for one reason only: a mutual return to compliance – that is to say, if Iran were to once again submit itself to the permanent, to the verifiable limits and checks imposed on its nuclear program – that would be manifestly in our national interest. Yes, this process has dragged on for much longer than we would like, for far too long, but the fact is that a mutual return to compliance – if Iran were to re‑enter the JCPOA, if we in turn were to re-enter the JCPOA – the result would work to our national security benefit.</p>
<p>That is because ever since 2018, when the last administration left the deal that was working, a deal with which Iran was in compliance, Iran’s nuclear program has advanced in ways that are unacceptable to us. And the net result of those advancements is the fact that Iran has gone from a breakout time – that is to say, the time that it would take Iran to acquire the fissile material necessary for a nuclear weapon should it make the decision to weaponize – has gone from a highwater mark of about a year at the outset of the deal to something that is best now measured in weeks.</p>
<p>And to us, that is unacceptable. And I say that we remain engaged on trying to determine whether a mutual return to compliance is in the offing because a mutual return to compliance would change that dynamic. It would significantly prolong the breakout time. It would change the dynamic. It would reimpose the most stringent verification and monitoring program ever peacefully negotiated on a nuclear program that has not been subject to it for several years now.</p>
<p>So &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are you not yet at the point of diminishing returns? I’m sorry to cut you off, but we – I mean, we’ve talked about the time running short. We’ve now blown past what seem to be several kind of guideposts for timing on negotiating a (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There seems to be an impression that there was always a dated fixed on the calendar for us, and I’ve seen this reported, but I would just note that it flies in the face of what I have consistently said. We don’t think of this – and I’m sorry to go back to this; I’m sure you’re all sick of hearing it – as a temporal clock. This is a technical clock, and it is a technical clock for one simple reason: what we’re looking at is the technical assessment of the point at which a mutual return to compliance – that is to say, the point at which re-entering the deal would not convey benefits, nonproliferation benefits that outweigh the advancements and the implications of the advancements that Iran has been able to achieve while these nuclear shackles has been off – have been off.</p>
<p>So we are still at a point where, if we were able to negotiate a mutual return to compliance, that breakout time would be prolonged from where it is now. We would have greater transparency. There would be those permanent, verifiable limits reimposed on Iran. That would be in our national security interest.</p>
<p>Now, to your point, it is true that there will come a time when, on the basis of those technical assessments, a mutual return to compliance and the nonproliferation benefits it would convey would not, in fact, outweigh the implications of the advancements that Iran has been able to achieve in its nuclear program.</p>
<p>So we are constantly taking a close look at the state of Iran’s nuclear program, of what it is doing, the implications of those actions, and comparing that to the deal that may still be in the offing. But I should add that because the JCPOA, a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA, is very much an uncertain proposition, we are now preparing equally for either scenario – a scenario in which we have a mutual return to compliance, in which that breakout time is elongated and a point at which this – what has the potential to devolve further into a nuclear crisis is put back into a box.</p>
<p>We are also preparing with our allies and partners for a scenario in which there is not a JCPOA and we will have to turn to other tactics and other approaches to fulfill what is for us a requirement, a commitment that President Biden has made that Iran, whether there is a JCPAO or whether there is not a JCPAO, must never, never, never be allowed to acquire a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, can you just say – you keep saying there will come a time when it won’t be worthwhile anymore. But you can say definitively right now today that that time has not – there has not been a judgement made that that time has come and gone?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That time has not come and gone.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, moving on?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Axios has reported today that when the Israeli national security advisor was here and spoke with Jake Sullivan that they – it was agreed that they increase pressure on Iran to finalize this deal and prepare, if it doesn’t happen, for later to push Iran towards this. Can you say anything?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong><a id="post-341143-Israel"></a>What I can say is that we regularly have occasion to consult with our Israeli partners on this. I know that Secretary Blinken has recently met with Foreign Minister Lapid. He’s met with him several times in recent months. He’s been on the phone with him several times in recent months. When there were active negotiations in Vienna, we would routinely brief our Israeli partners before each round, during each round, after each round. Secretary Blinken has done that himself to Foreign Minister Lapid. Secretary Blinken has done that himself with Prime Minister Bennett and his predecessor as well. So I’m not going to detail those consultations, but it is regularly a topic of discussion with our Israeli partners.</p>
<p>Shaun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Can we go to Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The Russians have said that they’re going to again have a ceasefire for three days at the steel plant in Mariupol. Do you see this as – do you see anything positive in this? Do you – are you hopeful that this could actually come to fruition?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong><a id="post-341143-RussiaUkraine1"></a>Well, every time an individual is able to take advantage of a humanitarian corridor, a humanitarian pause to reach safety, that is a good thing. What we want to see happen, however, is a prolonged humanitarian corridor, prolonged humanitarian access. What we have consistently seen, and we’ve seen this even in recent days, is the tendency on the part of the Russian Federation to embrace a so‑called humanitarian pause to cloak itself in the guise of an actor that has humanitarian concerns only to quickly and promptly resume shelling and violence, including against civilians who are trapped in besieged areas, including in Mariupol.</p>
<p>Our concern is – and what we want to see happen – is that this humanitarian access be motivated by genuine humanitarian concern and not the desire on the part of the Russian Federation to achieve a PR victory, to claim it has humanitarian concerns when its only concerns is propaganda.</p>
<p>Now, in recent days, there have been over a hundred individuals who have been able to reach safety as far as Zaporizhzhia in recent days. There are still hundreds of people who are trapped in the steel plant. There are still thousands of people who are in the besieged city of Mariupol who have been once again subject to shelling, to violence. People need to be let out. Humanitarian aid needs to be let in. That dynamic needs to last. That’s what we care about.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, just a follow up on that. There have been reports in Ukraine that the Russians are planning a, quote/unquote, “victory parade” in Mariupol for Monday to mark their Victory Day against Nazi Germany. I mean, first of all, is there anything the United States know about that? But is – how would that be seen? What do you think the message would be if that were to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, I know there’s lots of speculation about what the Russians may or may not do on May 9th, but I can tell you that May 8th and May 9th, it’s not only a day of significance for the Russians. It is a significant day for all of Europe and for the United States too, the anniversary of the defeat of the advance of Nazi Germany at the end of World War II. So this is not a day that any single country owns.</p>
<p>But what I can tell you is that on May 8th, on May 9th, our strategy and our approach is going to be the same strategy and the same effective approach that we have employed since February 24th, since the Russian invasion began. That is to support in many different ways our Ukrainian partners, to hold the Kremlin and the Russian Federation to account, and to do that with allies and partners around the world – dozens of allies around the world across four continents.</p>
<p>So I don’t have anything to preview for what they might do, but again, to claim as a victory, to parade through the streets of a city that not all that long ago was filled with hundreds of thousands of civilians, of people who were doing nothing but seeking livelihoods, pursuing their lives – I think that says a lot in the aftermath of a brutalization by Russian bombs, by Russian shells, by Russian artillery. And if that is the focus of any Victory Day parade, any Victory Day celebration, I think that speaks volumes about the nature of the Kremlin and the nature of what they’re doing to the people of Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. President of the European Council Charles Michel said today that the European Union will provide additional military equipment to Moldova to strengthen its resilience. I wonder if the U.S. considers additional military assistance to Moldova and Georgia, and I wonder if you see any imminent threat of new Russian aggression in the region against these countries.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-georgiamoldova"></a>Both Georgia and Moldova, our – are important partners of the United States. We are committed to their sovereignty, to their independence, to their territorial integrity. We have demonstrated that commitment in a number of ways. When it comes to Moldova, we spoke about this, I believe, on Tuesday. We recently restarted a strategic dialogue with our Moldovan counterparts. Secretary Blinken was recently in Chișinău, where he met with the Moldovan leadership; had an opportunity to meet with Moldovan leadership once again here for that strategic dialogue.</p>
<p>It is a partnership that spans many different elements. We have provided significant amount – a significant amount of humanitarian assistance to our Moldovan partners. Our militaries have an effective partnership. They have served together side by side as far away as Kosovo, and our commitment, as I said before, to the sovereignty, to the independence, to the territorial integrity of Moldova and to Georgia, which we have demonstrated in our own right as well – that is something that we will continue to support.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And any negotiations planned with Georgian side about the latest developments in the region and Russian aggression?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’re always in touch through our embassy, through the department here with our partners in the region. That certainly includes with our counterparts in Tbilisi. Those discussions are ongoing. Again, to your previous question, we know that Vladimir Putin may harbor aspirations to wage aggression against other countries in the region. I think we are demonstrating in response to how we are providing our Ukrainian partners with what they need to be effective against this instance, this egregious instance of Russian aggression – we are demonstrating that the United States and our allies and partners won’t stand for that type of activity.</p>
<p>Yes, sir.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Inaudible) news network, Pakistan. Sir, last week there was a suicide bomb blast in Pakistan. Due to situation in Afghanistan, we have seen rising terrorism in Pakistan. The security assistance was suspended by previous U.S. administration. It is still suspended. Is there any reviews going on?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-pakistan"></a>Well, at the time, we strongly condemned the terrorist attack against Karachi University, a university in Pakistan. We reiterate that condemnation today. A terrorist attack anywhere is an affront to humanity everywhere, but for a terrorist attack to take place at a university, or at a religious site, or at some of the locations we’ve seen recently – that is a true affront to mankind.</p>
<p>When it comes to your question, what I’ll say is that we value our bilateral relationship. We want to continue to work together in areas where we do have mutual interests with our Pakistani partners. That includes counterterrorism. That includes border security as well.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you so much. Jahanzaib Ali from ARY News TV Pakistan. Sir, the U.S. Commission on Religious Freedom recommended to include India into their blacklist, like for the religious freedom violations. So what would be the – expecting to see in regards to, like, second time in a row a U.S. commission recommended India to be included into the CPC countries?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-religion"></a>Well, USCIRF is an independent commission. It’s not a governmental entity. It does provide recommendations and guidance to the U.S. Government. It is something that we look at closely as we evaluate conditions of religious freedom or lack thereof around the world. I have no doubt that our experts in our Office of International Religious Freedom will take a close look at the report that USCIRF has submitted as they prepare for our determinations and our findings when it comes to religious freedom around the world.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And on China, can you give a preview of the China strategy speech?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong><a id="post-341143-china"></a>I was going to deflect that question and to duck it, pointing to the fact that there would be a speech tomorrow. Unfortunately, there won’t be a speech tomorrow, but there will be a speech at some point in the not too distant future. So I will then duck that question pointing to that date in the not too distant future.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And about Secretary Blinken, did he take an antigen test or a PCR test? It said about taking – took one on Tuesday and also this morning.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong><a id="post-341143-dept2"></a>He tested positive earlier this afternoon via PCR test. He had tested negative as recently as earlier this morning, and again yesterday with antigen tests.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, well, let’s just stay on that – and I don’t know how much you covered at the beginning before I was here.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think I answered everyone’s questions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, on this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I’m kidding.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>On the COVID? So you say that he’s not considered a close contact with the President.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That’s right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Certainly he’s – correct me if I’m wrong – a close contact with the Swedish foreign minister, who was &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That’s right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; here this afternoon, and potentially with the Mexican foreign secretary who was here yesterday and everyone who was at that luncheon. So have they all been informed? And then why, if he tested negative this morning with an antigen test, did he get a PCR test this afternoon? Was it because he was feeling symptomatic (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So we are in the process and we have notified those individuals with whom he has been in close contact following CDC guidance. So in most cases, if not all cases, we’ve been in a position to notify them. The Secretary, as you know, he has young kids in the house. As you know, he was around a number of people this weekend. So as a matter of precaution, he does regularly test. He reported symptoms this afternoon. He received a PCR test shortly thereafter.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So in other words, he didn’t get the PCR test this afternoon because he was – he was feeling symptoms. He got it just because &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>He reported symptoms this afternoon and thereafter received a PCR test.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So that’s why he took the PCR test?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Correct. Correct.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I mean, it wasn’t something that was required since he had been – he had tested negative this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That’s right. That’s right. That’s right. Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, and then – so can you say approximately how many people have been notified that they are close contacts of the Secretary? I mean, does it go back to Saturday night’s dinner? Does it go to whatever events, parties that he went to on Sunday?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>What I will say is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>How far back &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; that he is he is working closely with the department physician, his physician here at the department. They are working together to follow CDC guidance, to reconstruct close contacts in the appropriate period. And those people either have been notified or are in the process of being notified.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, well, can you just explain to me – according – I guess it’s CDC guidance, but also – and I’ve had personal experience with this as well with a State Department physician. But can you say that the Swedish foreign minister is a close contact? I mean, we saw them standing next to each other &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; but I don’t know if that qualifies for the 15 minutes and – you know.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I will – I don’t want to divulge &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I know you don’t want to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; divulge anyone’s health information. What I will say is that he had a bilateral meeting &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Fair enough, but &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; with the Swedish foreign minister, and the press aspect of that was only one element of it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Right.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So suffice it to say that we are notifying everyone who is considered a close contact per that CDC guidance.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The Secretary spoke at the Foreign Press Centers yesterday. You were along with the Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Have you tested negative? And also any update on informing reporters and Foreign Press Centers staffers?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So if – I believe you were there at the at the Foreign Press Center. The Secretary was not within six feet of reporters. There are CDC guidelines regarding close contacts. As I was explaining to Matt, we are and have notified those individuals who would qualify as close contacts. I was tested just about an hour ago and tested negative.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>A couple questions on Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So hang on a second, so you were identified as a close contact? I mean, I would hope you were since you’re his spokesman, but &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>What I will say is that I was tested about an hour ago and tested negative.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>On Ukraine, a couple of questions. Let me start with Hungary, which is pushing back against oil – Russian oil ban. I know you’re not involved in this, but the U.S. did not impose sanctions on Russian oil, but rather decided to go with its own purchase decision. Will Hungary’s pushback, first, affect your relationship with Hungary? Secondly, will maybe cause the U.S. to reconsider its decision on Russian oil ban moving towards the sanctions, which will make Hungary an enabler if they continue to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong><a id="post-341143-russia"></a>When it comes to the proposed oil ban, it is something we welcome on the part of the EU. I would need to refer you to the European Union for any details. Obviously this is a question that they continue to discuss within their own bloc, within their member states.</p>
<p>There is, however, broad support among our allies and partners for cutting off what is undeniably the strength of President Putin’s economy and his war machine, and that is energy. We are united as a NATO Alliance. We are united with our European allies, including with the EU, on the imperative on cutting back and choking off this important source of revenue for our – for the Russian Federation. We are in regular conversation with our partners and allies about the most effective way to decrease their dependence on Russian energy.</p>
<p>The position the United States is in is different from the position that any member of the EU is in; it is different from the position that any other country around the world is in. The United States, as we have discussed, is in a fortunate position in that we were never reliant on Russian energy, and in fact, we have infrastructure and we have energy supplies in this country that has enabled us to do things earlier that other countries, that other blocs are considering now. And shortly after the start of the invasion, on March 8th, President Biden signed an executive order that banned the import of key sources of Russian energy.</p>
<p>Now, of course, the EU – there are certain countries in the EU who have a higher dependence on Russian energy. Our goal is to see to it that we do everything to choke off these strategic assets, to make it as painful for the Kremlin and to make it as painless for the United States and our partners and allies around the world. But these are conversations that are ongoing within the EU, so I wouldn’t want to get ahead of those.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> One more question on the EU – EU unity, actually – Secretary Blinken and French Foreign Minister Le Drian, last week they had their call, and the readout says that they also discussed intensifying support for both North Macedonia and Albania on their EU accession bids. So can you tell me more in detail what exactly this intensified support means that was mentioned in the readout and how this support is given? Do you have some back-and-forth diplomatic channels with Bulgaria? Did you contact the EU leaders to convince Bulgaria and even put pressure on it to lift its veto for these countries to finally start the negotiation talks with the EU, North Macedonia, and Albania?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-EU"></a>Well, the United States has long been a strong supporter of North Macedonia and Albania’s integration into the EU. We believe the future of the Western Balkans is squarely with the EU. The enlargement process promotes long-term peace, stability, prosperity throughout the region, and the EU’s March 2020 decision to open accession negotiations with North Macedonia and Albania we think was a positive step. These two countries have laid the groundwork, and the time, we believe, is now to move forward together to the next phase in the long and challenging accession process.</p>
<p>The historic Prespa Agreement demonstrated that countries in the Western Balkans are capable of doing difficult things, making compromises, and finding solutions, and we’re confident that Bulgaria and North Macedonia will do the same by negotiating their bilateral disputes. We do continue on a bilateral basis to urge both of them, Bulgaria and North Macedonia, to resolve those disputes quickly, but obviously we’re not going to detail those conversations.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> To go back to Iran. The families of some of the imprisoned Americans joined in a demonstration today outside the White House. Can you give us an update on the status of the indirect talks over the detainees? Are they still happening despite the holdup in the nuclear talks? And will the State Department help facilitate a meeting between the families and President Biden, as they called for today?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-Iran2"></a>So in terms of the Americans who are detained – wrongfully detained – in Iran, we have made the point that we have no higher priority than the safe return of Americans who are wrongfully or unjustly detained anywhere, and that includes the four Americans who are detained in Iran.</p>
<p>We’ve also made the point that even as there had been a process in Vienna to discuss nuclear issues, that we were not going to conflate these two areas of discussion. And we weren’t going to do those for one simple reason, and I think that simple reason has become even more evident given where we are now in terms of the talks regarding Iran’s nuclear program. The JCPOA has always been an uncertain proposition. It is very uncertain now, the potential of a mutual return to compliance with it.</p>
<p>We want to see to it that the return of these Americans is a certain proposition. So it does not do us, it certainly does not do these Americans or their families any good to tie their fates to something that may or may not happen. At the same time, we have conveyed in no uncertain terms to the Iranians the priority we attach to seeing the safe release of these Americans. It is something that our team here as worked on constantly. It’s something that we worked on even before the formal process in Vienna began in the spring of 2021.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>To follow up on the families.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just – I just want to make sure you get a chance to respond to these families are out there. They gave – were out there this morning, gave a press conference where there was a lot of – obviously a lot of criticism of the administration for, as they see it, not doing enough to get their family members home. Specifically, Alexandra Forseth is the daughter and niece of two of the guys who were part of the CITGO-6 in Venezuela. She says, talking to the other families, they all see this pattern of indecision from the administration in terms of trying to get family members home, talked about running into roadblocks within the administration as they tried to – try to get more action from you guys that would help to get these family members home. Now, how do you respond to these people’s emotional pleas and criticisms like that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong><a id="post-341143-VZ"></a>I wouldn’t want to respond directly only because I am not going to be in a position to understand their full anguish and the emotion that is of course attached to having a loved one held unjustly in a faraway place for, in all cases, far too long and, for most of those cases, years at a time. I will never be able to understand that. There are many people in this building who don’t – won’t be able to understand that on a personal level. But what I can say is that we are doing everything we can, almost all of it unseen, almost all of it unsaid in public, to do everything we can to advance the commitment that President Biden has to see these Americans who are wrongfully or unjustly detained around the world or in some cases held hostage around the world brought home.</p>
<p>The President has made a commitment to do that. We have been able to make good on that commitment in a number of cases, including as you alluded to in Venezuela, including in Burma, including in Afghanistan, including in Haiti, including most recently in Russia with the return of Trevor Reed. In all of those cases, we did not detail contemporaneously what it was that we were doing, but we were doing it and we were executing on the President’s commitment. We are executing on the priority that the President attaches to this, that Secretary Blinken attaches to this.</p>
<p>And our special presidential envoy for hostage affairs and his office, Roger Carstens and his office. They have traveled the world, they are ready and willing to go anywhere, to talk to anyone as in some cases – as in many cases they have – in an effort to see these Americans returned to their homes. That is a commitment we have. We will keep executing on that commitment until every single last American is reunited with her or his family.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Can you talk some more about the State Department’s process for determining that Brittney Griner is being wrongfully detained in Russia? And why did that take the amount of time that it did?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong><a id="post-341143-Russia2"></a>What I can say is that – and as you heard from us yesterday, we have – we have determined that the Russian Federation has wrongfully detained U.S. citizen Brittney Griner. There is – there will be no change, of course, to the fact that we are going to do everything we can to provide appropriate support to Ms. Griner, to her family. There’s only so much I can say about the process for determining whether an American is wrongfully detained. It is a deliberative process.</p>
<p>But what I can say is that we weigh the totality of circumstances in every case: whether it’s the case of Brittney Griner, whether it’s the case of Paul Whelan, whether it&#8217;s the case of Americans in Iran. There are going to be unique factors in each and every one of those cases. But I would say that the Robert Levinson Act, section 302 of that act, does spell out a number of criteria – 11 criteria that are among the factors that we look at in determining whether an American who is detained overseas is held wrongfully or unjustly.</p>
<p>And you can see for yourself many of those criteria: if there is, for example, an indication of innocence; if the detention is based on being a U.S. national; if it is in violation of the laws of the detaining country; if due process has been sufficiently denied or impaired, and you can go on through that list.</p>
<p>But each case of an American detained overseas is going to be unique, and in each case, we look at the totality of circumstances in that case when it comes to arriving at such a determination.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just to follow up on their call for White House meetings, the Tices met with President Biden this week. Will the other families have a chance to?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I can say – I can only speak for the Department of State, but I can say that Secretary Blinken has frequently had an opportunity to meet and to speak with the families of Americans who are wrongfully detained around the world. As recently within the past couple days he’s had an opportunity to meet face to face with the family of one such American and to speak to the family over the phone of another such American.</p>
<p>We often don’t publicize these, again, because our efforts – we want to see to it that our efforts have the best prospects of being effective. And we’ve found that when we undertake these activities, these discussions quietly, that they are bestowed typically with more effectiveness.</p>
<p>Now, of course, President Biden, Jake Sullivan, others at the White House have also routinely met with the families of hostages. It is important for us to hear their perspective, to hear their inputs. After all, it’s these families who know the details, who know the intricacies of these cases better than anyone. And there was a process put forward in 2015 with a new PPD that called for a more streamlined, more effective process for engaging with the families. That is a commitment that the department and I know this entire administration takes very seriously, knowing that, again, these families are going to be the best advocates, these families are going to be the best experts when it comes to the unique and the totality of circumstances behind each individual case.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, two questions on conflicts, and let me start with Ukraine again. President Zelenskyy said today that we will not go to a frozen conflict. I wonder if it reflects Washington’s viewpoint as well. Can Ukraine rely on State Department’s or Washington’s support when it comes to frozen conflict (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m sorry. I missed part of your question. Can Ukraine rely on the United States &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. The president said that he will not accept frozen – another frozen – we have been there, done that, so that’s not a solution. Does that reflect general sentiment here as well as a potential playout of this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-RussiaUkraine2"></a>The general sentiment here – in fact, the only sentiment here – is that it is up to our Ukrainian partners to determine the endpoint that they want to achieve. It is up to them to determine what they seek to achieve in their discussions with the Russians. It is up to them to determine what it is that is the will of their people. And it is our role to support them in carrying that out. It is our role to support them on the battlefield by providing security assistance. It is our role to support them at the negotiating table by strengthening their hand, including by providing them security assistance, but also holding the Russian Federation to account.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> To another conflict as well, chief OSCE monitor Andrzej Kasprzyk was at the State Department this morning. I believe he met with Assistant Secretary Donfried. Have they discussed the Nagorno-Karabaakh issue and/or is the U.S. – the state of U.S. involvement at this point? I know that there are some efforts between Europeans and Washington and probably the – if I’m not mistaken, there have been other meetings this week or next week with Europeans. Am I right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sorry, I missed the last part of your question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That there have been other meetings between Europeans and Washington either this week or next week, if I’m not mistaken &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t know if they agreed to an additional meeting or if that was discussed, but we’ll let you know if we have more details to share from that meeting.</p>
<p>We’ll take a couple final questions, yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. I have a question on Saudi Arabia on behalf of a colleague, Michele, who had to leave. But <em>The Wall Street Journal</em> says that – has reported that CIA Director Bill Burns traveled to Saudi Arabia in mid-April, and according to this article, one American official has called – has described the trip as better than prior engagements. What’s the status of relations between the U.S. and Saudi Arabia? Has it gotten worse? Is it the Russia crisis – the crisis that Russia has created? And what will it take to bring back Saudi Arabia in this way and not – and not let it go towards Russia and China?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-Saudi"></a>Well, I think I would dispute the premise of the second part of your question. Of course, Saudi Arabia has been a longstanding partner of the United States. In many ways that’s a partnership that dates back to 1945, when FDR met with King Abdul Aziz. But fast-forwarding, more recently, you’ve heard from senior American and Saudi officials about the critical importance of the strategic ties between the United States and Saudi Arabia, and importantly, how we can use that strategic partnership and those strategic ties to deliver for our own people.</p>
<p>For our part, we have pursued the many mutual interests that we have with our Saudi partners. We’ve pursued the many interests that we have within the Gulf region and beyond with Saudi Arabia, just as we have sought to elevate human rights and to put them at the center of our foreign policy, including at the center of our bilateral relationships. And we have – not unrelated to that – engaged in vigorous diplomacy, including with our Saudi partners, to seek to bring an end to the war in Yemen. And I think across the board you have seen the way we have managed this relationship and the way we have – the way we have engaged with this partner deliver results for the United States, for our Saudi partners as well.</p>
<p>Most recently, we supported UN efforts to secure a nationwide two-month truce in Yemen. We – it is something that we were – have been quite encouraged by. It is a testament to the work of the UN special envoy but also to our own Special Envoy Tim Lenderking, who has spent quite a good bit of time in Riyadh and other parts of Saudi Arabia and in other parts of the Gulf to arrive at this two-month truce that, of course, we want to see built upon.</p>
<p>We’re also encouraged by Saudi Arabia’s return of its ambassador to Lebanon at an important moment. And we remain committed to building a partnership with Saudi Arabia that is durable and that is, importantly, sustainable that accounts for the broad range of shared interests that our countries have, whether that is helping Saudi Arabia defend its territory and the 70-some-odd thousand Americans who are resident within the kingdom; whether it is helping to educate tens of thousands of young Saudis who will help to craft and to drive their country’s future; whether it’s partnering on clean energy and renewables; whether it’s addressing human rights or, as I said before, helping to end the war in Yemen.</p>
<p>Our approach to this partnership has been designed to advance the ball on each and every one of those, and the way we measure this partnership is in terms of that effectiveness: what have we been able to achieve? And we’ve been able to achieve a great deal, including in recent weeks.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> There is no point of contention, no differences?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Every relationship is unique, and of course there is no country around the world with whom we share identical perspectives on every single issue. What is important for us is that we manage our relationship in a way that delivers results for our two countries, and I think in the case of Saudi Arabia you’ve been able to see many of those results in recent weeks.</p>
<p>One final question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are there any plans to help the Ukrainian refugees that traveled to Mexico and are now in this limbo state because the U.S. is no longer accepting them?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-341143-Ukraine"></a>Well, what I can say is that we have put in place a process so that Ukrainians need not make the journey to Mexico or to any other third country in the region because we do have a pipeline now, a program we are calling Uniting for Ukraine under which Ukrainians can be sponsored directly and under which they can be paroled directly into the United States for two years.</p>
<p>Now, the President has made a commitment to bring to this country 100,000 Ukrainians and others affected by this war. That includes Ukrainians who are internally displaced within their home country, Ukrainians who are now refugees in Europe, but in some cases there will be Ukrainians who are refugees in places closer to the United States. We’re going to adjudicate each of those cases, but again, there is now a program through which Ukrainians have much readier, much easier access to the United States through this sponsorship program. Of course, that’s not the only pathway for arrival here in the United States – the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program, including the Lautenberg Program under those auspices, and then the additional resources we have committed to visa processing – visa processing in the region for Ukrainians seeking to travel to the United States.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 4:42 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
