<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 15:13:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary Noyes’ Travel to Uganda and Geneva</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-noyes-travel-to-uganda-and-geneva/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 15:13:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=358315</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM) Julieta Valls Noyes travels to Uganda July 9-15 and Geneva July 16-19.</p>
<p>While in Uganda, Assistant Secretary Noyes will meet with international organization partners and with Ugandan government officials to discuss the recent refugee influx from the Democratic Republic of the Congo and to coordinate on humanitarian priorities for the over 1.5 million refugees hosted in Uganda.  She will also visit refugee settlements to hear directly from refugees about the health, livelihood, education, and protection needs while hosted in Uganda.</p>
<p>While in Geneva, Assistant Secretary Noyes will meet with humanitarian international organizations, NGOs, and other donor governments to discuss humanitarian issues affecting the most vulnerable populations across the globe.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM) Julieta Valls Noyes travels to Uganda July 9-15 and Geneva July 16-19.</p>
<p>While in Uganda, Assistant Secretary Noyes will meet with international organization partners and with Ugandan government officials to discuss the recent refugee influx from the Democratic Republic of the Congo and to coordinate on humanitarian priorities for the over 1.5 million refugees hosted in Uganda.  She will also visit refugee settlements to hear directly from refugees about the health, livelihood, education, and protection needs while hosted in Uganda.</p>
<p>While in Geneva, Assistant Secretary Noyes will meet with humanitarian international organizations, NGOs, and other donor governments to discuss humanitarian issues affecting the most vulnerable populations across the globe.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken At a Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-press-availability-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 13:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=358300</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Bangkok, Thailand</p>
<p>Anantara Siam Hotel</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone.  It is wonderful to be back in Thailand.  We had a trip that was planned a few months ago that was delayed because of COVID, so I’m finally glad to make it here.  And I was reflecting, in conversation with the Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don that the first time I was here was actually in 1980, so 42 years ago.</p>
<p>As I said at the signing that we had earlier today of the Memorandum of Understanding with the Deputy Prime Minister, the strength of the relationship between our countries lies in how we are constantly evolving to try to meet the needs of our people and to try and address the challenges we face.</p>
<p>We’re working together to revitalize our economies, a central topic in my meetings with the Prime Minister and with the Deputy Prime Minister.  We share the same goal of not just driving growth, but trying to ensure that it creates opportunities for all our people.</p>
<p>We’re doing this together, bilaterally.  The United States is Thailand’s largest export market and third largest investor, and through new efforts like the ones we launched today to shore up our supply chains, we’re going to be making our economies even more secure.</p>
<p>We’re doing it regionally, through the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.  As a founding partner, Thailand is taking a leading role in shaping that framework to position our workers, our businesses, our governments to lead in areas that are critical to our shared prosperity, like clean energy, like the digital trade.  And we very much appreciate Thailand’s leadership of APEC this year; we look forward to building on that success when the United States takes over as host next year.</p>
<p>We also had candid discussions today on democracy and human rights – core values that we share.  One of democracy’s unique strengths is the ability to acknowledge our flaws and work to address them.  This spirit is reflected in the Communiqué on Strategic Alliance and Partnership that we signed today, which reaffirms our commitment to helping one another live up to the principles of free and open societies, such as an independent civil society and free and fair elections.</p>
<p>We’re also deepening what has been decades-long cooperation in public health.  Thailand is a crucial partner in the COVID-19 Global Action Plan that we established to try to end the acute phase of this pandemic and leave the world better prepared to prevent, detect, and respond to future emergencies.</p>
<p>We’ve donated more than 2.5 million doses of safe, effective COVID-19 vaccines to Thailand – free of charge, no political strings attached – while USAID has provided significant assistance to communities that are facing the highest risks.</p>
<p>Our two countries partner in responding to regional challenges and regional crises.  The United States is working with Thailand, and all of ASEAN, to push Burma’s regime to fulfill the five-point consensus, end its brutal violence, and put Burma back on the path to democracy.</p>
<p>This morning I actually had an opportunity to meet with some young leaders from Burma, who are committed as ever to building a democratic future.  More than 91,000 displaced people from Burma are currently in Thailand, part of the nation’s proud tradition of welcoming refugees.</p>
<p>For decades the United States has provided support for those efforts here in Thailand, including $45 million in humanitarian assistance this year alone.</p>
<p>Finally, we’re deepening the bonds, the connections between our peoples.</p>
<p>Today I met with some Thai alumni from the Fulbright Program, the International Visitor Leadership Program, and the Young Southeast Asian Leaders Initiative.  More than 5,000 Thais have participated in these programs over the years.  They’ve been enriched by their interaction with Americans, just as Americans have benefited from their engagement with Thai students, scholars, innovators, and leaders.</p>
<p>Few people in history have done more to foster these ties than the great diplomat, Thanat Khoman.  Among his many contributions, he pushed for Thailand to become one of the first countries to host Peace Corps volunteers from the United States.  And when he was asked why, he said, “It is well that governments should come into contact with one another, but it is even more important for people to come into contact with one another, to have first-hand knowledge, first-hand experience, and also first-hand ideas about what we should do in this world to keep peace and develop friendly relations.”</p>
<p>So I’m grateful that, all these years later, that we continue to find new ways to bring our governments together but, more important even, to bring our people together to the benefit of all of us.</p>
<p>So I want to thank the government and people of Thailand for hosting us so warmly today, on a Sunday.  And with that, I’m happy to take some questions.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll start with Shaun Tandon of the AFP.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Shaun?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah.  Thanks, Mr. Secretary.  Could I follow up on the comments you made about Burma/Myanmar?  You talked about the five-point consensus, but of course it’s been over a year since ASEAN put that forward.  It’s been over a year since the United States has been putting sanctions on the junta.  Are you still confident that this approach is working?  What else can be done?  What else can the United States do to restore democracy, to help restore democracy in Burma?</p>
<p>Can I follow up on a couple points on that?  The Chinese foreign minister, Wang Yi, was also recently – besides being in Bali, was also recently in Myanmar.  Do you see his efforts and China’s efforts helping or hindering the diplomacy that ASEAN and the United States are doing on Burma?</p>
<p>And on that, some have called for the U.S. to formally recognize the NUG as a legitimate government of Myanmar.  Is that something in the cards, including a representative office in Washington?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Look, as a bottom line, I think it’s unfortunately safe to say that we’ve seen no positive movement.  And on the contrary, we continue to see the repression of the Burmese people.  We continue to see violence perpetrated on them by the regime.  We continue to see virtually the entire opposition in jail or in exile.  And we continue to see a terrible humanitarian situation, exacerbated by the fact that the regime is not delivering what’s necessary for the people.  And that’s also putting real pressure on Thailand as people flee from the violence, from the repression, in Burma.</p>
<p>On that note, I should say that we very much appreciate what Thailand has done to try to facilitate cross-border assistance, to try to expand cooperation on, for example, getting COVID-19 vaccines to people in Burma and to those displaced.  I think there’s even more that we can do to make sure that humanitarian organizations have access to people along the border to make sure they’re getting the assistance they need.</p>
<p>But look, at this point I think a few things.  One, all countries have to continue to speak clearly about what the regime is doing in its ongoing repression and brutality.  We have an obligation to the people of Burma to hold the regime accountable.  Regional support for the regime’s adherence to the five-point consensus developed by ASEAN is also critical.  That has not happened, and I think all the ASEAN countries need to hold the regime accountable for that, to continue to demand an immediate cessation of violence, the release of political prisoners, and a restoration of Burma’s democratic path.</p>
<p>But to date, we have not seen positive movement in that direction.  We will continue to look for ways that we can – and other countries can effectively put pressure on the regime to move back to the democratic path, and we’re doing that on a regular basis.  That was part of the conversation that we had today.</p>
<p>I can’t speak directly to what China is or isn’t doing in Burma, but I think it’s also incumbent upon China, and in China’s interests, to see Burma move back to the path that it was on and it was so violently disrupted from by the coup.</p>
<p>I think this is something that we’re deeply focused on, even as we’re spending, of course, a lot of time on Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.  We haven’t lost sight of Burma, we haven’t lost sight of its people.  I had an opportunity today to sit down with some remarkable young people from Burma to talk about what they see as its democratic future, and we are working with young people, we’re working with the National Unity Government, we’re working with other genuine representatives of the Burmese people, and we’ll continue to do that, including supporting the work of the NUG.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  I will turn to Mr. Chanchai Pratheepwattanawong.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Recently China just confirmed that President Xi Jinping will attend the APEC meeting in November.  Any update from U.S. Government if President Biden will attend, as well?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, we very much look forward to participating in the APEC Summit and, as I mentioned, we’ll also be taking the APEC baton next year.  So we are – we spent some time talking to our friends here in Thailand about their leadership of APEC, what lessons we can learn as we take the baton.  I can’t speak yet to who will be participating, but the United States will very much be present.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Nike Ching, VOA.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong> Thank you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  On Sri Lanka, can you comment on the crisis there, as the country is facing the worst economic crisis since its independence, and its president is going to resign next week?  Would you attribute the crisis to the food and energy prices hike linked to Russia’s invasion in Ukraine, and if it would cause similar instability in other parts of the world?</p>
<p>And separately, if I may on China, to follow up the previous question, is there any progress on firming up next interaction between President Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping, and if there is a prospect of first face-to-face meeting between them at G20 Summit?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, Nike.  With regard to Sri Lanka more broadly, this is something that we’re closely following.  We’re looking at the political developments.  We’ve seen now thousands of people of all backgrounds taking to the streets, looking for accountability, looking for transparency, looking for a better future.</p>
<p>I would note that the prime minister announced that he will step down when all parties agree to form a new government.  We’ve also seen reports from the Sri Lankan parliament, the speaker, who said the president intends to step down on July 13th.  We’re tracking all of that.</p>
<p>By the way, we would urge the Sri Lankan parliament to approach this with a commitment to the betterment of the country, not any one political party.</p>
<p>And then it’s incumbent on the government, whether it’s a new, constitutionally-selected government, the existing government, to work quickly to try to identify and implement solutions that will bring back the prospect of long-term economic stability, address the Sri Lankan people’s discontent, which is so powerful and palpable, over the worsening economic conditions, including power, including food – and I’ll come back to that in a minute – including fuel shortages.</p>
<p>At the same time, as we’re seeing this unfold, we condemn any violence against peaceful protestors and journalists.  The Sri Lankan people have a right to peacefully raise their voices.  At the same time, we call for a full investigation, arrest, prosecution of anyone involved in any protest-related violence and incidents of violence.</p>
<p>You asked about the impact of the Russian aggression in Ukraine on food insecurity and the impact, potentially, on Sir Lanka.  Well, I think we are seeing that impact around the world, and it may be one of the contributing factors to what’s happened in Sri Lanka, although I think there were, as I’ve just said, many others that have come together.</p>
<p>But what we are seeing around the world is growing food insecurity that has been significantly exacerbated by the Russian aggression against Ukraine.  And as we’ve had opportunity to discuss in recent days, there are more than 20 million tons of grain that are sitting in silos in Ukraine that can’t get out, can’t get out to feed people around the world because Russia is blockading Ukraine’s ports in Odessa, the Black Sea.</p>
<p>We have a fertilizer crisis that is having a real impact here in Thailand, a fertilizer shortage, prices that have gone sky-high.  That is very significant, especially in a farming country, a vibrant farming country like Thailand, because in the absence of fertilizer, we know that means that next year yields will go down, prices potentially will go up.  That’s one of the reasons that President Biden dedicated half a billion dollars a few weeks ago to incentivizing more production of fertilizer in the United States that we can share with the world.</p>
<p>So we’re seeing the impact of this Russian aggression play out everywhere.  It, again, may have contributed to the situation in Sri Lanka.  We’re concerned about the implications that it has around the world.  We’re working very hard to address those implications, including by putting significant resources into addressing humanitarian needs from food insecurity right now, as well as investing in longer-term production and sustainability, so that countries have the wherewithal to produce the food that they need over time.</p>
<p>And then, with regard to President Xi and President Biden, our expectation is that they will have an opportunity to speak in the weeks ahead, and I can’t talk to what may happen in the fall.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll take a final question from Mr. Jompol Daosukho.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong> Hello.  Could you make it clear that – about the U.S. Government role in Asia-Pacific, as called Indo-Pacific?  Because some Thais are growing too concerned about your role.  Some say that the U.S. Government will build the new version of NATO in our region.  Could you make it clear that it is or not?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  We have a commitment to and a vision of – that I think is shared with many other countries – of this region and its future, one that is free, one that is open, one that is secure.  And that means, among other things, that people, products, investment can move about freely and go where it’s needed.  It means that countries can make their own decisions about their own futures, their own policies, free from coercion by anyone else.  It means that people in those countries can live freely, speak freely, and aspire to an even better life in the future.  That is the future that we’re trying to build.</p>
<p>And we’re doing that in a variety of ways.  We’re doing that by working, for example, very closely with ASEAN as well as within APEC.  We’re doing that through some new initiatives that we’ve launched, including the so-called Quad that involves India, that involves Japan, that involves Australia, where, among other things, we’ve come together to be able to produce and distribute many, many vaccines to deal with COVID-19.  We’re doing that through the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework that tries to address the most important factors of the 21st century economy in ways that affect the lives of citizens in all of our countries; the digital economy, which is increasingly important; secure supply chains; the rules that surround the use of technology, to make sure that technology is used in a way that protects privacy and advances freedom, not uses a tool of repression; to make sure that governance is effective and devoid of corruption.  All of those things are part of our vision.</p>
<p>And the last thing I’ll say is that this is not about demanding or insisting that countries choose; it’s about giving them a choice.  And that’s what we’re focused on.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR: </strong>  Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Bangkok, Thailand</p>
<p>Anantara Siam Hotel</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone.  It is wonderful to be back in Thailand.  We had a trip that was planned a few months ago that was delayed because of COVID, so I’m finally glad to make it here.  And I was reflecting, in conversation with the Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don that the first time I was here was actually in 1980, so 42 years ago.</p>
<p>As I said at the signing that we had earlier today of the Memorandum of Understanding with the Deputy Prime Minister, the strength of the relationship between our countries lies in how we are constantly evolving to try to meet the needs of our people and to try and address the challenges we face.</p>
<p>We’re working together to revitalize our economies, a central topic in my meetings with the Prime Minister and with the Deputy Prime Minister.  We share the same goal of not just driving growth, but trying to ensure that it creates opportunities for all our people.</p>
<p>We’re doing this together, bilaterally.  The United States is Thailand’s largest export market and third largest investor, and through new efforts like the ones we launched today to shore up our supply chains, we’re going to be making our economies even more secure.</p>
<p>We’re doing it regionally, through the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.  As a founding partner, Thailand is taking a leading role in shaping that framework to position our workers, our businesses, our governments to lead in areas that are critical to our shared prosperity, like clean energy, like the digital trade.  And we very much appreciate Thailand’s leadership of APEC this year; we look forward to building on that success when the United States takes over as host next year.</p>
<p>We also had candid discussions today on democracy and human rights – core values that we share.  One of democracy’s unique strengths is the ability to acknowledge our flaws and work to address them.  This spirit is reflected in the Communiqué on Strategic Alliance and Partnership that we signed today, which reaffirms our commitment to helping one another live up to the principles of free and open societies, such as an independent civil society and free and fair elections.</p>
<p>We’re also deepening what has been decades-long cooperation in public health.  Thailand is a crucial partner in the COVID-19 Global Action Plan that we established to try to end the acute phase of this pandemic and leave the world better prepared to prevent, detect, and respond to future emergencies.</p>
<p>We’ve donated more than 2.5 million doses of safe, effective COVID-19 vaccines to Thailand – free of charge, no political strings attached – while USAID has provided significant assistance to communities that are facing the highest risks.</p>
<p>Our two countries partner in responding to regional challenges and regional crises.  The United States is working with Thailand, and all of ASEAN, to push Burma’s regime to fulfill the five-point consensus, end its brutal violence, and put Burma back on the path to democracy.</p>
<p>This morning I actually had an opportunity to meet with some young leaders from Burma, who are committed as ever to building a democratic future.  More than 91,000 displaced people from Burma are currently in Thailand, part of the nation’s proud tradition of welcoming refugees.</p>
<p>For decades the United States has provided support for those efforts here in Thailand, including $45 million in humanitarian assistance this year alone.</p>
<p>Finally, we’re deepening the bonds, the connections between our peoples.</p>
<p>Today I met with some Thai alumni from the Fulbright Program, the International Visitor Leadership Program, and the Young Southeast Asian Leaders Initiative.  More than 5,000 Thais have participated in these programs over the years.  They’ve been enriched by their interaction with Americans, just as Americans have benefited from their engagement with Thai students, scholars, innovators, and leaders.</p>
<p>Few people in history have done more to foster these ties than the great diplomat, Thanat Khoman.  Among his many contributions, he pushed for Thailand to become one of the first countries to host Peace Corps volunteers from the United States.  And when he was asked why, he said, “It is well that governments should come into contact with one another, but it is even more important for people to come into contact with one another, to have first-hand knowledge, first-hand experience, and also first-hand ideas about what we should do in this world to keep peace and develop friendly relations.”</p>
<p>So I’m grateful that, all these years later, that we continue to find new ways to bring our governments together but, more important even, to bring our people together to the benefit of all of us.</p>
<p>So I want to thank the government and people of Thailand for hosting us so warmly today, on a Sunday.  And with that, I’m happy to take some questions.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll start with Shaun Tandon of the AFP.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Shaun?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah.  Thanks, Mr. Secretary.  Could I follow up on the comments you made about Burma/Myanmar?  You talked about the five-point consensus, but of course it’s been over a year since ASEAN put that forward.  It’s been over a year since the United States has been putting sanctions on the junta.  Are you still confident that this approach is working?  What else can be done?  What else can the United States do to restore democracy, to help restore democracy in Burma?</p>
<p>Can I follow up on a couple points on that?  The Chinese foreign minister, Wang Yi, was also recently – besides being in Bali, was also recently in Myanmar.  Do you see his efforts and China’s efforts helping or hindering the diplomacy that ASEAN and the United States are doing on Burma?</p>
<p>And on that, some have called for the U.S. to formally recognize the NUG as a legitimate government of Myanmar.  Is that something in the cards, including a representative office in Washington?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Look, as a bottom line, I think it’s unfortunately safe to say that we’ve seen no positive movement.  And on the contrary, we continue to see the repression of the Burmese people.  We continue to see violence perpetrated on them by the regime.  We continue to see virtually the entire opposition in jail or in exile.  And we continue to see a terrible humanitarian situation, exacerbated by the fact that the regime is not delivering what’s necessary for the people.  And that’s also putting real pressure on Thailand as people flee from the violence, from the repression, in Burma.</p>
<p>On that note, I should say that we very much appreciate what Thailand has done to try to facilitate cross-border assistance, to try to expand cooperation on, for example, getting COVID-19 vaccines to people in Burma and to those displaced.  I think there’s even more that we can do to make sure that humanitarian organizations have access to people along the border to make sure they’re getting the assistance they need.</p>
<p>But look, at this point I think a few things.  One, all countries have to continue to speak clearly about what the regime is doing in its ongoing repression and brutality.  We have an obligation to the people of Burma to hold the regime accountable.  Regional support for the regime’s adherence to the five-point consensus developed by ASEAN is also critical.  That has not happened, and I think all the ASEAN countries need to hold the regime accountable for that, to continue to demand an immediate cessation of violence, the release of political prisoners, and a restoration of Burma’s democratic path.</p>
<p>But to date, we have not seen positive movement in that direction.  We will continue to look for ways that we can – and other countries can effectively put pressure on the regime to move back to the democratic path, and we’re doing that on a regular basis.  That was part of the conversation that we had today.</p>
<p>I can’t speak directly to what China is or isn’t doing in Burma, but I think it’s also incumbent upon China, and in China’s interests, to see Burma move back to the path that it was on and it was so violently disrupted from by the coup.</p>
<p>I think this is something that we’re deeply focused on, even as we’re spending, of course, a lot of time on Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.  We haven’t lost sight of Burma, we haven’t lost sight of its people.  I had an opportunity today to sit down with some remarkable young people from Burma to talk about what they see as its democratic future, and we are working with young people, we’re working with the National Unity Government, we’re working with other genuine representatives of the Burmese people, and we’ll continue to do that, including supporting the work of the NUG.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  I will turn to Mr. Chanchai Pratheepwattanawong.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Recently China just confirmed that President Xi Jinping will attend the APEC meeting in November.  Any update from U.S. Government if President Biden will attend, as well?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, we very much look forward to participating in the APEC Summit and, as I mentioned, we’ll also be taking the APEC baton next year.  So we are – we spent some time talking to our friends here in Thailand about their leadership of APEC, what lessons we can learn as we take the baton.  I can’t speak yet to who will be participating, but the United States will very much be present.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Nike Ching, VOA.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong> Thank you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  On Sri Lanka, can you comment on the crisis there, as the country is facing the worst economic crisis since its independence, and its president is going to resign next week?  Would you attribute the crisis to the food and energy prices hike linked to Russia’s invasion in Ukraine, and if it would cause similar instability in other parts of the world?</p>
<p>And separately, if I may on China, to follow up the previous question, is there any progress on firming up next interaction between President Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping, and if there is a prospect of first face-to-face meeting between them at G20 Summit?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, Nike.  With regard to Sri Lanka more broadly, this is something that we’re closely following.  We’re looking at the political developments.  We’ve seen now thousands of people of all backgrounds taking to the streets, looking for accountability, looking for transparency, looking for a better future.</p>
<p>I would note that the prime minister announced that he will step down when all parties agree to form a new government.  We’ve also seen reports from the Sri Lankan parliament, the speaker, who said the president intends to step down on July 13th.  We’re tracking all of that.</p>
<p>By the way, we would urge the Sri Lankan parliament to approach this with a commitment to the betterment of the country, not any one political party.</p>
<p>And then it’s incumbent on the government, whether it’s a new, constitutionally-selected government, the existing government, to work quickly to try to identify and implement solutions that will bring back the prospect of long-term economic stability, address the Sri Lankan people’s discontent, which is so powerful and palpable, over the worsening economic conditions, including power, including food – and I’ll come back to that in a minute – including fuel shortages.</p>
<p>At the same time, as we’re seeing this unfold, we condemn any violence against peaceful protestors and journalists.  The Sri Lankan people have a right to peacefully raise their voices.  At the same time, we call for a full investigation, arrest, prosecution of anyone involved in any protest-related violence and incidents of violence.</p>
<p>You asked about the impact of the Russian aggression in Ukraine on food insecurity and the impact, potentially, on Sir Lanka.  Well, I think we are seeing that impact around the world, and it may be one of the contributing factors to what’s happened in Sri Lanka, although I think there were, as I’ve just said, many others that have come together.</p>
<p>But what we are seeing around the world is growing food insecurity that has been significantly exacerbated by the Russian aggression against Ukraine.  And as we’ve had opportunity to discuss in recent days, there are more than 20 million tons of grain that are sitting in silos in Ukraine that can’t get out, can’t get out to feed people around the world because Russia is blockading Ukraine’s ports in Odessa, the Black Sea.</p>
<p>We have a fertilizer crisis that is having a real impact here in Thailand, a fertilizer shortage, prices that have gone sky-high.  That is very significant, especially in a farming country, a vibrant farming country like Thailand, because in the absence of fertilizer, we know that means that next year yields will go down, prices potentially will go up.  That’s one of the reasons that President Biden dedicated half a billion dollars a few weeks ago to incentivizing more production of fertilizer in the United States that we can share with the world.</p>
<p>So we’re seeing the impact of this Russian aggression play out everywhere.  It, again, may have contributed to the situation in Sri Lanka.  We’re concerned about the implications that it has around the world.  We’re working very hard to address those implications, including by putting significant resources into addressing humanitarian needs from food insecurity right now, as well as investing in longer-term production and sustainability, so that countries have the wherewithal to produce the food that they need over time.</p>
<p>And then, with regard to President Xi and President Biden, our expectation is that they will have an opportunity to speak in the weeks ahead, and I can’t talk to what may happen in the fall.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We’ll take a final question from Mr. Jompol Daosukho.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong> Hello.  Could you make it clear that – about the U.S. Government role in Asia-Pacific, as called Indo-Pacific?  Because some Thais are growing too concerned about your role.  Some say that the U.S. Government will build the new version of NATO in our region.  Could you make it clear that it is or not?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  We have a commitment to and a vision of – that I think is shared with many other countries – of this region and its future, one that is free, one that is open, one that is secure.  And that means, among other things, that people, products, investment can move about freely and go where it’s needed.  It means that countries can make their own decisions about their own futures, their own policies, free from coercion by anyone else.  It means that people in those countries can live freely, speak freely, and aspire to an even better life in the future.  That is the future that we’re trying to build.</p>
<p>And we’re doing that in a variety of ways.  We’re doing that by working, for example, very closely with ASEAN as well as within APEC.  We’re doing that through some new initiatives that we’ve launched, including the so-called Quad that involves India, that involves Japan, that involves Australia, where, among other things, we’ve come together to be able to produce and distribute many, many vaccines to deal with COVID-19.  We’re doing that through the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework that tries to address the most important factors of the 21st century economy in ways that affect the lives of citizens in all of our countries; the digital economy, which is increasingly important; secure supply chains; the rules that surround the use of technology, to make sure that technology is used in a way that protects privacy and advances freedom, not uses a tool of repression; to make sure that governance is effective and devoid of corruption.  All of those things are part of our vision.</p>
<p>And the last thing I’ll say is that this is not about demanding or insisting that countries choose; it’s about giving them a choice.  And that’s what we’re focused on.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR: </strong>  Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States-Thailand Communiqué on Strategic Alliance and Partnership</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-thailand-communique-on-strategic-alliance-and-partnership/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 12:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=358295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following statement was signed by Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken of the United States and Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don Pramudwinai of the Kingdom of Thailand in Bangkok, Thailand on July 10, 2022.</em></p>
<p><em> </em><em>Begin text:</em><em> </em></p>
<p><strong>Recognizing Our History and Building Our Future</strong><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<ol>
<li>As the United States and Thailand celebrate our 190<sup>th</sup> anniversary of diplomatic relations in 2023, we recognize two centuries of special trust and collaboration built through the 1833 Treaty of Amity and Commerce, our treaty alliance established through the 1954 Manila Pact, the 1962 Thanat-Rusk Communiqué, and the 1966 Treaty of Amity and Economic Relations. Forged by shared history and common values, and anchored by our collective commitment to build resilient, inclusive democracies and advance human rights, our two countries reaffirm our commitment to our strategic alliance as sovereign equals, with steadfast commitment to the principles of mutual trust, mutual respect, and mutual interest.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="2">
<li>We are committed to reinforcing and enhancing our strategic alliance and partnership. This encompasses economic revitalization; defense, security, and intelligence cooperation; public health advancement; people-to-people collaboration; and innovative environmental and sustainable solutions to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and adapt to the impacts of climate change.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Our Pledge to Pursue Joint Strategic Goals</strong></p>
<ol start="3">
<li>The long-term goals of the United States and Thailand are to expand and strengthen our strategic partnership to prevent conflict, preserve a peaceful security environment, promote free expression and civil and political rights, and achieve inclusive, sustainable, and balanced economic prosperity. We pursue these goals as equals, for the benefit of the American and Thai people, as well as for the rest of the Indo-Pacific populations and the wider world. We seek to work together to ensure the resilience of critical supply chains, so that both our nations have access to the goods and resources required to preserve our safety, security, and prosperity. We intend to continue to promote international cooperation to combat criminal threats, leveraging our 1986 Treaty on Mutual Assistance in Criminal Matters and 1983 Treaty relating to Extradition as we strive to make our nations, the region, and the world safer from criminal networks.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="4">
<li>As we face new challenges, we engage shoulder-to-shoulder a broadening set of cooperation. We seek to strengthen our collaboration to advance global health security, respond to future public health crises, and enhance, regional and global health, including emphasizing transparency and access to information about emerging disease threats. We will be deepening our cooperation on energy, developing the resources of tomorrow as we promote innovation and expand the use and generation of renewable power. We plan to reinvigorate our bilateral dialogues on science, technology, and space while developing new mechanisms to promote innovation and the safe and responsible use of emerging technologies.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>High-Level Strategic Dialogue</strong></p>
<ol start="5">
<li>In addition to frequent, high-level engagement, we intend to anchor our consultations and review progress with an annual senior-level United States-Thailand Strategic and Defense Dialogue. Bringing together multiple agencies from across our respective governments, the Strategic and Defense Dialogue will include a broad array of themes, including trade and investment cooperation, defense and security cooperation, democracy and human rights, humanitarian assistance, regional stability, climate action, supply chain resiliency, infrastructure and communication connectivity, and education and cultural exchanges.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Our Shared Commitment to Strategic Cooperation to Advance the Peace, Sustainability, and Prosperity of our Two Countries and the Indo-Pacific Region</strong><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p>As part of our strategic alliance and partnership, the United States and Thailand seek to promote closer cooperation in the following areas:</p>
<ol start="6">
<li><strong>Adhere to Core Principles:</strong> Promoting democratic development in an open and transparent way is essential to implementing our shared vision of an Indo-Pacific that is free, open, inclusive and sustainable. Strong democratic institutions, independent civil society, and free and fair elections are central to this vision, allowing our respective societies to reach their full potential. We intend to strengthen our shared values and ideals, including the rule of law; protecting human rights and human security; adhering to humanitarian principles, including non-refoulement; promoting sustainable development; and upholding resilient democracies. We share common aspirations in promoting open and inclusive societies in all aspects, especially among vulnerable and marginalized groups such as women, children, people with disabilities, LGBTQI+ persons, and various groups of migrants, among others, as well as in combating all forms of human trafficking. This includes cooperation on human capital development to promote inclusive, balanced, and sustainable growth. We also reaffirm our commitment to working together to promote and protect the rights of vulnerable groups in line with our relevant international obligations.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="7">
<li><strong>Revitalize Our Economies:</strong> The United States and Thailand seek to build back from the impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic via increased commercial and economic cooperation to advance inclusive, sustainable, and balanced growth, including through the concepts outlined in the Bio-Circular-Green Economy Model and the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework. By strengthening our mutual supply chains, promoting a business-conducive ecosystem, and exploring capacity-building via innovative technology transfer on voluntary and mutually agreed terms, we will increase competitiveness and opportunities for jobs and sustainable growth in both countries. We also seek to advance our cooperation on sustainable and smart agriculture, increasing capacities of farmers, as well as strengthening global food security. We plan to work together to enhance supply chain resilience, particularly for critical goods, and coordinate to avoid disruptions of trade in critically important products. The United States and Thailand also plan to collaborate on digital economy to support digital transformation and promote innovation for economic recovery and advancement, including in developing secure and stable digital infrastructure, enhancing the digital skills of our workforces, and the digitization of our enterprises and start-ups, developing smart cities and policies promoting digital trade. The recognition and protection of intellectual property rights (IPR) and cooperation on IPR enforcement are vital elements for enhanced trade. Beyond our borders, our two nations intend to continue to explore opportunities to promote high-quality, sustainable and resilient transport, energy and digital infrastructure and connectivity in the Mekong sub-region and the broader Indo-Pacific, through mechanisms including joint financing, private sector collaboration, and cooperation with third countries.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="8">
<li><strong>Address the Threat of Climate Change:</strong> Recognizing the global risks posed by climate change, the United States and Thailand are committed to continuing to play leading roles in addressing environmental challenges as we raise our climate ambitions and strive to advance toward net-zero targets. We plan to work together to reduce emissions, enhance climate adaptation and resilience, and climate-related goals. Utilizing climate-friendly policies to drive economic growth and accelerate energy transition, we intend to leverage new technologies that harness clean and renewable energy, including solar power; carbon capture, utilization, and storage (CCUS); climate smart agriculture; e-mobility, including electric vehicle (EV) technology; smart grids; and efficient power storage. We plan to cooperate to make Thailand a center for innovation and climate change leadership in the region. We also plan to work together to promote environmental protection and to strengthen water security and climate resilience across the Mekong River basin. Our two countries seek to collaborate on catalyzing investment in green technology, facilitating private sector partnership and increasing Thailand’s capacity in critical energy supply chains, to support its Nationally Determined Contribution (NDC) as well as its goal of achieving carbon neutrality by 2050.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="9">
<li><strong>Advance Our Treaty Alliance:</strong> We reaffirm the foundations of the U.S.-Thai treaty alliance and our commitment to address 21st Century security challenges, as enunciated in the 2020 Joint Vision Statement for the U.S.-Thai Defense Alliance. We seek to facilitate a free, open, and inclusive Indo-Pacific region through enhanced security and defense cooperation and capabilities, based on mutual respect, shared democratic values, and common interests. We recognize the important role of the United States and Thailand cooperation in promoting regional peace and security. Our sustained security cooperation, including human capital development, education and training, capacity-building, interoperability, and modernization of defense and security institutions serves the interest of each of our countries and the wider region. The United States reaffirms its strong commitment to security cooperation with Thailand and its support for long-term modernization, education and training, maritime security, cyber and space domain initiatives, and humanitarian and disaster relief capabilities.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="10">
<li><strong>Expand and Reinforce Law Enforcement Cooperation:</strong> As part of our strategic alliance, we are committed to expanding our bilateral, sub-regional, and regional cooperation in law enforcement, including strengthening border security; fighting transnational crime, including drug smuggling and wildlife and timber trafficking; and combatting terrorism and money laundering. The United States and Thailand commit to expanding our cooperation against human trafficking and the exploitation of children, by increasing our joint efforts to investigate and prosecute traffickers, including the officials who protect them, as well as to strengthen protections for migrant workers. The two sides commit to making full use of the International Law Enforcement Academy (ILEA) in Bangkok to forge networks and enhance coordination among law enforcement officials in the region.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="11">
<li><strong>Deepen Cybersecurity and Technology Collaboration:</strong> We plan to expand our existing cooperation on cybersecurity to ensure that our networks are secure, criminals are prosecuted, and Critical Information Infrastructure (CII) is protected. The United States is committed to continuing to support Thailand in developing its National Cyber Incident Response Plan, National Computer Emergency Response Team (National CERT), National Coordination Center, and information-sharing capability with critical infrastructure sectors. We intend to further strengthen our engagement to promote the cooperation of law enforcement and civilian authorities in preventing and prosecuting cybercrimes and plan to work together and with partner countries in the sub-region, region, and beyond to investigate and bring cyber criminals to justice.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="12">
<li><strong>Promote Regional Cooperation:</strong> The United States and Thailand recognize the significance of Southeast Asia to the security architecture and sustainable development of the entire region and beyond. We underscore our unwavering commitment to ensure a peaceful and stable regional environment that will contribute to socio-economic recovery, balanced growth and sustainable development in the sub-region and Southeast Asian region. Together, we intend to strengthen our collaboration to better respond to regional and global challenges. We intend to collaborate to address humanitarian crises confronting the region. We reaffirm our support for Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) centrality and the vital role that ASEAN plays in addressing traditional and non-traditional security challenges through ASEAN-led mechanisms, including the ASEAN Defense Ministers’ Meeting Plus (ADMM-Plus) and the ASEAN Regional Forum (ARF), guided by the ASEAN Outlook on the Indo-Pacific (AOIP). We also highlight the implementation of the Plan of Action of the Mekong-U.S. Partnership in which the United States and Thailand are members and the Ayeyawady-Chao Phraya-Mekong Economic Cooperation Strategy (ACMECS) Master Plan of which Thailand is a founding member and the United States is a development partner. We also plan to continue to cooperate in regional economic fora such as the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC), where we seek to leverage our 2022 and 2023 leadership roles to promote free, fair, and open trade and investment while advancing inclusive and sustainable economic growth.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="13">
<li><strong>Advance Global Health:</strong> The United States and Thailand plan to continue our close and long-standing public health cooperation to mitigate emerging health challenges and promote commercial and investment engagement. For over 60 years, we have worked together to address critical issues affecting public health through medical research, vaccine and therapeutic development, and public health cooperation led by the U.S. Centers for Disease Control Prevention, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), the Armed Forces Research Institute of Medical Sciences (AFRIMS), the Ministry of Public Health of Thailand, and other relevant health agencies in both countries. The innovations we have achieved by working together have had global reach, and we plan to continue our cooperation to advance sub-regional and regional health security and improve health outcomes for people around the world. With the continued emergence of new variants of the virus that causes COVID-19, we seek to enhance our close collaboration on pandemic preparedness and response to reinforce a resilient global health recovery.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="14">
<li><strong>Promote People-to-People Ties:</strong> Our close and extensive people-to-people exchanges have long provided a strong foundation in our countries’ relations. Through American Spaces in Thailand and Thailand’s outreach across the United States, we plan to work together to help ensure that people in our respective countries understand one another and are positioned to carry our partnership into its third century. We seek to bring together our students, entrepreneurs, professionals, and people from all walks of life to strengthen people-to-people ties through the exchanges and educational and professional development programs, including those in the English language and Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics (STEM), undertaken jointly in the United States and Thailand, as well as promoting the Thai studies programs in the United States. The newly established Thailand-United States Alumni Association will bring together exchange alumni from across Thailand to promote our shared values and goals.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="15">
<li><strong>Increase Our Diplomatic Capabilities:</strong> In recognition of our expanding relationship, the United States and Thailand are committed to further strengthening the alliance and partnership through enhanced coordination and regular exchange of official visits. We intend to renew and enhance our mutual support for our respective diplomatic missions to reflect our expanded relationship.</li>
</ol>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following statement was signed by Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken of the United States and Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don Pramudwinai of the Kingdom of Thailand in Bangkok, Thailand on July 10, 2022.</em></p>
<p><em> </em><em>Begin text:</em><em> </em></p>
<p><strong>Recognizing Our History and Building Our Future</strong><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<ol>
<li>As the United States and Thailand celebrate our 190<sup>th</sup> anniversary of diplomatic relations in 2023, we recognize two centuries of special trust and collaboration built through the 1833 Treaty of Amity and Commerce, our treaty alliance established through the 1954 Manila Pact, the 1962 Thanat-Rusk Communiqué, and the 1966 Treaty of Amity and Economic Relations. Forged by shared history and common values, and anchored by our collective commitment to build resilient, inclusive democracies and advance human rights, our two countries reaffirm our commitment to our strategic alliance as sovereign equals, with steadfast commitment to the principles of mutual trust, mutual respect, and mutual interest.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="2">
<li>We are committed to reinforcing and enhancing our strategic alliance and partnership. This encompasses economic revitalization; defense, security, and intelligence cooperation; public health advancement; people-to-people collaboration; and innovative environmental and sustainable solutions to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and adapt to the impacts of climate change.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Our Pledge to Pursue Joint Strategic Goals</strong></p>
<ol start="3">
<li>The long-term goals of the United States and Thailand are to expand and strengthen our strategic partnership to prevent conflict, preserve a peaceful security environment, promote free expression and civil and political rights, and achieve inclusive, sustainable, and balanced economic prosperity. We pursue these goals as equals, for the benefit of the American and Thai people, as well as for the rest of the Indo-Pacific populations and the wider world. We seek to work together to ensure the resilience of critical supply chains, so that both our nations have access to the goods and resources required to preserve our safety, security, and prosperity. We intend to continue to promote international cooperation to combat criminal threats, leveraging our 1986 Treaty on Mutual Assistance in Criminal Matters and 1983 Treaty relating to Extradition as we strive to make our nations, the region, and the world safer from criminal networks.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="4">
<li>As we face new challenges, we engage shoulder-to-shoulder a broadening set of cooperation. We seek to strengthen our collaboration to advance global health security, respond to future public health crises, and enhance, regional and global health, including emphasizing transparency and access to information about emerging disease threats. We will be deepening our cooperation on energy, developing the resources of tomorrow as we promote innovation and expand the use and generation of renewable power. We plan to reinvigorate our bilateral dialogues on science, technology, and space while developing new mechanisms to promote innovation and the safe and responsible use of emerging technologies.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>High-Level Strategic Dialogue</strong></p>
<ol start="5">
<li>In addition to frequent, high-level engagement, we intend to anchor our consultations and review progress with an annual senior-level United States-Thailand Strategic and Defense Dialogue. Bringing together multiple agencies from across our respective governments, the Strategic and Defense Dialogue will include a broad array of themes, including trade and investment cooperation, defense and security cooperation, democracy and human rights, humanitarian assistance, regional stability, climate action, supply chain resiliency, infrastructure and communication connectivity, and education and cultural exchanges.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Our Shared Commitment to Strategic Cooperation to Advance the Peace, Sustainability, and Prosperity of our Two Countries and the Indo-Pacific Region</strong><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p>As part of our strategic alliance and partnership, the United States and Thailand seek to promote closer cooperation in the following areas:</p>
<ol start="6">
<li><strong>Adhere to Core Principles:</strong> Promoting democratic development in an open and transparent way is essential to implementing our shared vision of an Indo-Pacific that is free, open, inclusive and sustainable. Strong democratic institutions, independent civil society, and free and fair elections are central to this vision, allowing our respective societies to reach their full potential. We intend to strengthen our shared values and ideals, including the rule of law; protecting human rights and human security; adhering to humanitarian principles, including non-refoulement; promoting sustainable development; and upholding resilient democracies. We share common aspirations in promoting open and inclusive societies in all aspects, especially among vulnerable and marginalized groups such as women, children, people with disabilities, LGBTQI+ persons, and various groups of migrants, among others, as well as in combating all forms of human trafficking. This includes cooperation on human capital development to promote inclusive, balanced, and sustainable growth. We also reaffirm our commitment to working together to promote and protect the rights of vulnerable groups in line with our relevant international obligations.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="7">
<li><strong>Revitalize Our Economies:</strong> The United States and Thailand seek to build back from the impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic via increased commercial and economic cooperation to advance inclusive, sustainable, and balanced growth, including through the concepts outlined in the Bio-Circular-Green Economy Model and the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework. By strengthening our mutual supply chains, promoting a business-conducive ecosystem, and exploring capacity-building via innovative technology transfer on voluntary and mutually agreed terms, we will increase competitiveness and opportunities for jobs and sustainable growth in both countries. We also seek to advance our cooperation on sustainable and smart agriculture, increasing capacities of farmers, as well as strengthening global food security. We plan to work together to enhance supply chain resilience, particularly for critical goods, and coordinate to avoid disruptions of trade in critically important products. The United States and Thailand also plan to collaborate on digital economy to support digital transformation and promote innovation for economic recovery and advancement, including in developing secure and stable digital infrastructure, enhancing the digital skills of our workforces, and the digitization of our enterprises and start-ups, developing smart cities and policies promoting digital trade. The recognition and protection of intellectual property rights (IPR) and cooperation on IPR enforcement are vital elements for enhanced trade. Beyond our borders, our two nations intend to continue to explore opportunities to promote high-quality, sustainable and resilient transport, energy and digital infrastructure and connectivity in the Mekong sub-region and the broader Indo-Pacific, through mechanisms including joint financing, private sector collaboration, and cooperation with third countries.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="8">
<li><strong>Address the Threat of Climate Change:</strong> Recognizing the global risks posed by climate change, the United States and Thailand are committed to continuing to play leading roles in addressing environmental challenges as we raise our climate ambitions and strive to advance toward net-zero targets. We plan to work together to reduce emissions, enhance climate adaptation and resilience, and climate-related goals. Utilizing climate-friendly policies to drive economic growth and accelerate energy transition, we intend to leverage new technologies that harness clean and renewable energy, including solar power; carbon capture, utilization, and storage (CCUS); climate smart agriculture; e-mobility, including electric vehicle (EV) technology; smart grids; and efficient power storage. We plan to cooperate to make Thailand a center for innovation and climate change leadership in the region. We also plan to work together to promote environmental protection and to strengthen water security and climate resilience across the Mekong River basin. Our two countries seek to collaborate on catalyzing investment in green technology, facilitating private sector partnership and increasing Thailand’s capacity in critical energy supply chains, to support its Nationally Determined Contribution (NDC) as well as its goal of achieving carbon neutrality by 2050.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="9">
<li><strong>Advance Our Treaty Alliance:</strong> We reaffirm the foundations of the U.S.-Thai treaty alliance and our commitment to address 21st Century security challenges, as enunciated in the 2020 Joint Vision Statement for the U.S.-Thai Defense Alliance. We seek to facilitate a free, open, and inclusive Indo-Pacific region through enhanced security and defense cooperation and capabilities, based on mutual respect, shared democratic values, and common interests. We recognize the important role of the United States and Thailand cooperation in promoting regional peace and security. Our sustained security cooperation, including human capital development, education and training, capacity-building, interoperability, and modernization of defense and security institutions serves the interest of each of our countries and the wider region. The United States reaffirms its strong commitment to security cooperation with Thailand and its support for long-term modernization, education and training, maritime security, cyber and space domain initiatives, and humanitarian and disaster relief capabilities.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="10">
<li><strong>Expand and Reinforce Law Enforcement Cooperation:</strong> As part of our strategic alliance, we are committed to expanding our bilateral, sub-regional, and regional cooperation in law enforcement, including strengthening border security; fighting transnational crime, including drug smuggling and wildlife and timber trafficking; and combatting terrorism and money laundering. The United States and Thailand commit to expanding our cooperation against human trafficking and the exploitation of children, by increasing our joint efforts to investigate and prosecute traffickers, including the officials who protect them, as well as to strengthen protections for migrant workers. The two sides commit to making full use of the International Law Enforcement Academy (ILEA) in Bangkok to forge networks and enhance coordination among law enforcement officials in the region.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="11">
<li><strong>Deepen Cybersecurity and Technology Collaboration:</strong> We plan to expand our existing cooperation on cybersecurity to ensure that our networks are secure, criminals are prosecuted, and Critical Information Infrastructure (CII) is protected. The United States is committed to continuing to support Thailand in developing its National Cyber Incident Response Plan, National Computer Emergency Response Team (National CERT), National Coordination Center, and information-sharing capability with critical infrastructure sectors. We intend to further strengthen our engagement to promote the cooperation of law enforcement and civilian authorities in preventing and prosecuting cybercrimes and plan to work together and with partner countries in the sub-region, region, and beyond to investigate and bring cyber criminals to justice.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="12">
<li><strong>Promote Regional Cooperation:</strong> The United States and Thailand recognize the significance of Southeast Asia to the security architecture and sustainable development of the entire region and beyond. We underscore our unwavering commitment to ensure a peaceful and stable regional environment that will contribute to socio-economic recovery, balanced growth and sustainable development in the sub-region and Southeast Asian region. Together, we intend to strengthen our collaboration to better respond to regional and global challenges. We intend to collaborate to address humanitarian crises confronting the region. We reaffirm our support for Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) centrality and the vital role that ASEAN plays in addressing traditional and non-traditional security challenges through ASEAN-led mechanisms, including the ASEAN Defense Ministers’ Meeting Plus (ADMM-Plus) and the ASEAN Regional Forum (ARF), guided by the ASEAN Outlook on the Indo-Pacific (AOIP). We also highlight the implementation of the Plan of Action of the Mekong-U.S. Partnership in which the United States and Thailand are members and the Ayeyawady-Chao Phraya-Mekong Economic Cooperation Strategy (ACMECS) Master Plan of which Thailand is a founding member and the United States is a development partner. We also plan to continue to cooperate in regional economic fora such as the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC), where we seek to leverage our 2022 and 2023 leadership roles to promote free, fair, and open trade and investment while advancing inclusive and sustainable economic growth.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="13">
<li><strong>Advance Global Health:</strong> The United States and Thailand plan to continue our close and long-standing public health cooperation to mitigate emerging health challenges and promote commercial and investment engagement. For over 60 years, we have worked together to address critical issues affecting public health through medical research, vaccine and therapeutic development, and public health cooperation led by the U.S. Centers for Disease Control Prevention, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), the Armed Forces Research Institute of Medical Sciences (AFRIMS), the Ministry of Public Health of Thailand, and other relevant health agencies in both countries. The innovations we have achieved by working together have had global reach, and we plan to continue our cooperation to advance sub-regional and regional health security and improve health outcomes for people around the world. With the continued emergence of new variants of the virus that causes COVID-19, we seek to enhance our close collaboration on pandemic preparedness and response to reinforce a resilient global health recovery.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="14">
<li><strong>Promote People-to-People Ties:</strong> Our close and extensive people-to-people exchanges have long provided a strong foundation in our countries’ relations. Through American Spaces in Thailand and Thailand’s outreach across the United States, we plan to work together to help ensure that people in our respective countries understand one another and are positioned to carry our partnership into its third century. We seek to bring together our students, entrepreneurs, professionals, and people from all walks of life to strengthen people-to-people ties through the exchanges and educational and professional development programs, including those in the English language and Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics (STEM), undertaken jointly in the United States and Thailand, as well as promoting the Thai studies programs in the United States. The newly established Thailand-United States Alumni Association will bring together exchange alumni from across Thailand to promote our shared values and goals.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="15">
<li><strong>Increase Our Diplomatic Capabilities:</strong> In recognition of our expanding relationship, the United States and Thailand are committed to further strengthening the alliance and partnership through enhanced coordination and regular exchange of official visits. We intend to renew and enhance our mutual support for our respective diplomatic missions to reflect our expanded relationship.</li>
</ol>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Bahamas Independence Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-bahamas-independence-day-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 12:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=358186</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the Commonwealth of The Bahamas as you celebrate your independence.</p>
<p>The United States and The Bahamas have long enjoyed a mutually beneficial partnership.  The ties between our nations have never been stronger.  The United States is committed to maintaining and strengthening that relationship.</p>
<p>Our nations face challenging times as we grapple with the COVID-19 pandemic and the effects of the brutal Russian invasion of Ukraine, which has produced chaos in global food and energy markets.  We will manage these crises and do so in a fashion that adheres to our shared commitment to support freedom, respect national sovereignty, and protect human rights.</p>
<p>We will continue to work in partnership to address the climate crisis and fight illicit trafficking in narcotics and firearms.  We look to do even more to promote security and prosperity throughout the Caribbean through the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative and the U.S. – Caribbean Partnership to Address the Climate Crisis 2030.  These initiatives confirm the United States has been and will always remain a steadfast friend to the people and government of The Bahamas.</p>
<p>On the occasion of your 49th year as an independent nation, the United States and its people wish the people of the Commonwealth of The Bahamas every success over the year to come.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the Commonwealth of The Bahamas as you celebrate your independence.</p>
<p>The United States and The Bahamas have long enjoyed a mutually beneficial partnership.  The ties between our nations have never been stronger.  The United States is committed to maintaining and strengthening that relationship.</p>
<p>Our nations face challenging times as we grapple with the COVID-19 pandemic and the effects of the brutal Russian invasion of Ukraine, which has produced chaos in global food and energy markets.  We will manage these crises and do so in a fashion that adheres to our shared commitment to support freedom, respect national sovereignty, and protect human rights.</p>
<p>We will continue to work in partnership to address the climate crisis and fight illicit trafficking in narcotics and firearms.  We look to do even more to promote security and prosperity throughout the Caribbean through the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative and the U.S. – Caribbean Partnership to Address the Climate Crisis 2030.  These initiatives confirm the United States has been and will always remain a steadfast friend to the people and government of The Bahamas.</p>
<p>On the occasion of your 49th year as an independent nation, the United States and its people wish the people of the Commonwealth of The Bahamas every success over the year to come.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Travel to Bali, Bangkok, and Tokyo</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-bali-bangkok-and-tokyo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 02:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=358257</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to the Bali, Indonesia, Bangkok, Thailand, and Tokyo, Japan, July 6-11, 2022.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken will first travel to Bali, Indonesia, to attend the G20 Foreign Ministers’ Meeting, where he will reinforce our commitment to working with international partners to confront global challenges, including food and energy insecurity and the threat Russia’s continued war against Ukraine presents to the international order. In addition to attending G20-related engagements, the Secretary will hold a bilateral meeting with Indonesian Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi.  Among other bilateral engagements, Secretary Blinken will also meet with the People’s Republic of China (PRC) State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi on the margins of the G20.</p>
<p>In Bangkok, Thailand, Secretary Blinken will meet with Prime Minister Prayut Chan-o-cha and Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don Pramudwinai. He looks forward to discussing a range of issues, including building on the successes of Thailand’s APEC 2022 agenda during our 2023 APEC host year, expanding health and climate cooperation, and addressing the crisis in Burma.  He will also meet with alumni of U.S. exchange programs.  The U.S-Thai Alliance is essential for advancing the President’s Indo-Pacific Strategy for a free and open, connected, prosperous, secure, and resilient region.</p>
<p>Finally, Secretary Blinken will travel to Tokyo, Japan, to offer condolences to the Japanese people on the death of former Prime Minister Abe Shinzo and to meet with senior Japanese officials.  The U.S.-Japan Alliance is the cornerstone of peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific and has never been stronger.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to the Bali, Indonesia, Bangkok, Thailand, and Tokyo, Japan, July 6-11, 2022.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken will first travel to Bali, Indonesia, to attend the G20 Foreign Ministers’ Meeting, where he will reinforce our commitment to working with international partners to confront global challenges, including food and energy insecurity and the threat Russia’s continued war against Ukraine presents to the international order. In addition to attending G20-related engagements, the Secretary will hold a bilateral meeting with Indonesian Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi.  Among other bilateral engagements, Secretary Blinken will also meet with the People’s Republic of China (PRC) State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi on the margins of the G20.</p>
<p>In Bangkok, Thailand, Secretary Blinken will meet with Prime Minister Prayut Chan-o-cha and Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don Pramudwinai. He looks forward to discussing a range of issues, including building on the successes of Thailand’s APEC 2022 agenda during our 2023 APEC host year, expanding health and climate cooperation, and addressing the crisis in Burma.  He will also meet with alumni of U.S. exchange programs.  The U.S-Thai Alliance is essential for advancing the President’s Indo-Pacific Strategy for a free and open, connected, prosperous, secure, and resilient region.</p>
<p>Finally, Secretary Blinken will travel to Tokyo, Japan, to offer condolences to the Japanese people on the death of former Prime Minister Abe Shinzo and to meet with senior Japanese officials.  The U.S.-Japan Alliance is the cornerstone of peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific and has never been stronger.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>$400 million in New U.S. Military Assistance for Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/400-million-in-new-u-s-military-assistance-for-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 15:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=358215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The Ukrainian people continue to courageously defend their nation in the face of Russia’s unlawful and unprovoked invasion. The United States salutes their bravery, and we will stand by them as long as it takes.</p>
<p>Pursuant to a delegation of authority from the President, I am authorizing our fifteenth drawdown of arms and equipment from U.S. Department of Defense inventories for Ukraine’s self-defense since August 2021 of up to $400 million. This authorization will bring total U.S. military assistance to Ukraine to more than $7.32 billion since Russia launched its brutal, unprovoked, full-scale invasion of Ukraine on February 24 – including $2.2 billion over the last several weeks as we have expedited assistance to help Ukraine defend itself.</p>
<p>Our commitment to the people of Ukraine will not waver, and we will continue to stand united with Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The Ukrainian people continue to courageously defend their nation in the face of Russia’s unlawful and unprovoked invasion. The United States salutes their bravery, and we will stand by them as long as it takes.</p>
<p>Pursuant to a delegation of authority from the President, I am authorizing our fifteenth drawdown of arms and equipment from U.S. Department of Defense inventories for Ukraine’s self-defense since August 2021 of up to $400 million. This authorization will bring total U.S. military assistance to Ukraine to more than $7.32 billion since Russia launched its brutal, unprovoked, full-scale invasion of Ukraine on February 24 – including $2.2 billion over the last several weeks as we have expedited assistance to help Ukraine defend itself.</p>
<p>Our commitment to the people of Ukraine will not waver, and we will continue to stand united with Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Philippine Secretary of Foreign Affairs Manalo</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-philippine-secretary-of-foreign-affairs-manalo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 14:33:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=358210</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Philippine Secretary of Foreign Affairs Enrique A. Manalo.  Secretary Blinken congratulated Secretary Manalo on his recent appointment and highlighted the increasing significance of the U.S.-Philippine bilateral alliance to security and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region and around the world.  The Secretary also emphasized the importance of respect for human rights and the rule of law.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Philippine Secretary of Foreign Affairs Enrique A. Manalo.  Secretary Blinken congratulated Secretary Manalo on his recent appointment and highlighted the increasing significance of the U.S.-Philippine bilateral alliance to security and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region and around the world.  The Secretary also emphasized the importance of respect for human rights and the rule of law.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States-Thailand Relationship</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-thailand-relationship/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 14:28:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=358207</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Bangkok, Thailand where he will meet with Thai Prime Minister Prayut Chan-o-cha and Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don Pramudwinai to reaffirm the U.S.-Thai alliance and the U.S. commitment to the Indo-Pacific region.  They will also discuss the economic and security ties that bind our enduring partnership with Thailand.  Secretary Blinken will visit a shelter for victims of human trafficking to demonstrate shared commitment to eliminating trafficking.  The Secretary will meet with U.S. exchange alumni to gain perspective on priority issues for young Thai leaders.  Throughout his visit, Secretary Blinken will push to end the violence in Burma and expand humanitarian assistance for vulnerable populations.</p>
<p><strong>The United States and Thailand are Close Partners and Allies</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States looks forward to strengthening the excellent cooperation between our two countries, as allies and friends. Next year marks 190 years of diplomatic relations.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Our relationship is deep and enduring.  The United States formalized diplomatic relations with Thailand in 1833 with a Treaty of Amity and Commerce and reaffirmed relations with the 1954 Manila Pact of the former Southeast Asia Treaty Organization. In 2003, the United States designated Thailand a major non-NATO Ally.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Thailand and the United States share a commitment to the same values – democracy, human rights, labor rights, the rule of law, security, and prosperity.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>We welcome Thailand’s focus on tackling the climate crisis and fostering a sustainable and inclusive economic recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic, including through its 2022 Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) host year and partnership in the Association of Southeast Asian Nations. We look forward to advancing Thailand’s leadership on these topics during the U.S. 2023 APEC host year.<strong> </strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Security Cooperation Strengthens Our Partnership and Benefits the Region</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Thailand is a treaty ally, a leader and guarantor of security in the international community, and a reliable partner.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Thailand is a key regional law enforcement partner and leader. The United States and Thailand jointly operate the International Law Enforcement Academy (ILEA) in Bangkok, which since 1998 has provided training to more than 22,000 criminal justice sector officials from across Southeast Asia on topics such as anticorruption, cybercrime, and trafficking in narcotics, wildlife, and persons.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Thailand and the United States co-host Cobra Gold, the region’s largest and longest-running annual multinational military exercise. Since 1950, Thailand has received U.S. military equipment, essential supplies, training, and other assistance in the construction and improvement of facilities.  We have $2.85 billion in ongoing Foreign Military Sales and an annual slate of more than 400 joint military exercises and engagements.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States supports Thailand’s leadership in the Mekong region through the Mekong-U.S. Partnership (MUSP), as a development partner of the Mekong River Commission, and as a development partner of the Ayeyawady-Chao Phraya-Mekong Economic Cooperation Strategy (ACMECS), a partnership between the five Mekong–region countries to coordinate infrastructure development. Through the MUSP, the United States collaborates with Thailand and other Lower Mekong countries to strengthen transboundary economic connections and address emerging challenges, such as resource management, transnational crime, transparency and good governance, and human resource development.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Americans and Thais Benefit from Our Close Economic, Environment, Health, and Educational Ties</strong><strong> </strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States is Thailand’s largest export market, purchasing more than $47 billion of goods from Thailand 2021. In 2021, our total two-way trade amounted to $63.7 billion.  Our relationship, which ranges from trade in consumer goods and agricultural products to cooperation in the defense industries, has spurred collaboration in fields outside the economic realm, including security and space technology.  The United States contributed $17.5 billion of foreign direct investment (FDI) to Thailand in 2020, making it Thailand’s third-largest foreign investor.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>For more than 60 years, U.S. agencies, such as the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Armed Forces Research Institute of Medical Sciences, and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), have partnered with Thai counterparts to safeguard the health of U.S., Thai, and international communities through medical research and innovation and public health initiatives.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>USAID environment programs promote sustainable resource management; conserve biodiversity; expand the use of data to inform policy decisions on issues including air quality; combat wildlife trafficking; and increase access to clean, safe, affordable, reliable, and modern sources of energy. USAID and the Thailand International Cooperation Agency (TICA) are also deepening cooperation through a Strategic Partnership to jointly provide development assistance to other countries in Southeast Asia.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States supports exchange programs that connect Thai youth, students, educators, artists, athletes, and rising leaders to their counterparts in the United States and the ASEAN region, engaging them on strategic priorities ranging from civic engagement to economic sustainability. Our exchange programs are robust, with more than 5,000 Thai alumni of the Fulbright program, International Visitor Leadership Program (IVLP), and Young Southeast Asian Leaders Initiative (YSEALI).  The newly established Thailand-United States Alumni Association brings together alumni from across the country to work together on projects that support our mutual goals.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>S. Peace Corps Volunteers, active in Thailand since 1962, focus on English teacher training in primary schools and youth life skills development.</li>
</ul>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Bangkok, Thailand where he will meet with Thai Prime Minister Prayut Chan-o-cha and Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don Pramudwinai to reaffirm the U.S.-Thai alliance and the U.S. commitment to the Indo-Pacific region.  They will also discuss the economic and security ties that bind our enduring partnership with Thailand.  Secretary Blinken will visit a shelter for victims of human trafficking to demonstrate shared commitment to eliminating trafficking.  The Secretary will meet with U.S. exchange alumni to gain perspective on priority issues for young Thai leaders.  Throughout his visit, Secretary Blinken will push to end the violence in Burma and expand humanitarian assistance for vulnerable populations.</p>
<p><strong>The United States and Thailand are Close Partners and Allies</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States looks forward to strengthening the excellent cooperation between our two countries, as allies and friends. Next year marks 190 years of diplomatic relations.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Our relationship is deep and enduring.  The United States formalized diplomatic relations with Thailand in 1833 with a Treaty of Amity and Commerce and reaffirmed relations with the 1954 Manila Pact of the former Southeast Asia Treaty Organization. In 2003, the United States designated Thailand a major non-NATO Ally.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Thailand and the United States share a commitment to the same values – democracy, human rights, labor rights, the rule of law, security, and prosperity.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>We welcome Thailand’s focus on tackling the climate crisis and fostering a sustainable and inclusive economic recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic, including through its 2022 Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) host year and partnership in the Association of Southeast Asian Nations. We look forward to advancing Thailand’s leadership on these topics during the U.S. 2023 APEC host year.<strong> </strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Security Cooperation Strengthens Our Partnership and Benefits the Region</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Thailand is a treaty ally, a leader and guarantor of security in the international community, and a reliable partner.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Thailand is a key regional law enforcement partner and leader. The United States and Thailand jointly operate the International Law Enforcement Academy (ILEA) in Bangkok, which since 1998 has provided training to more than 22,000 criminal justice sector officials from across Southeast Asia on topics such as anticorruption, cybercrime, and trafficking in narcotics, wildlife, and persons.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Thailand and the United States co-host Cobra Gold, the region’s largest and longest-running annual multinational military exercise. Since 1950, Thailand has received U.S. military equipment, essential supplies, training, and other assistance in the construction and improvement of facilities.  We have $2.85 billion in ongoing Foreign Military Sales and an annual slate of more than 400 joint military exercises and engagements.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States supports Thailand’s leadership in the Mekong region through the Mekong-U.S. Partnership (MUSP), as a development partner of the Mekong River Commission, and as a development partner of the Ayeyawady-Chao Phraya-Mekong Economic Cooperation Strategy (ACMECS), a partnership between the five Mekong–region countries to coordinate infrastructure development. Through the MUSP, the United States collaborates with Thailand and other Lower Mekong countries to strengthen transboundary economic connections and address emerging challenges, such as resource management, transnational crime, transparency and good governance, and human resource development.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Americans and Thais Benefit from Our Close Economic, Environment, Health, and Educational Ties</strong><strong> </strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States is Thailand’s largest export market, purchasing more than $47 billion of goods from Thailand 2021. In 2021, our total two-way trade amounted to $63.7 billion.  Our relationship, which ranges from trade in consumer goods and agricultural products to cooperation in the defense industries, has spurred collaboration in fields outside the economic realm, including security and space technology.  The United States contributed $17.5 billion of foreign direct investment (FDI) to Thailand in 2020, making it Thailand’s third-largest foreign investor.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>For more than 60 years, U.S. agencies, such as the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Armed Forces Research Institute of Medical Sciences, and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), have partnered with Thai counterparts to safeguard the health of U.S., Thai, and international communities through medical research and innovation and public health initiatives.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>USAID environment programs promote sustainable resource management; conserve biodiversity; expand the use of data to inform policy decisions on issues including air quality; combat wildlife trafficking; and increase access to clean, safe, affordable, reliable, and modern sources of energy. USAID and the Thailand International Cooperation Agency (TICA) are also deepening cooperation through a Strategic Partnership to jointly provide development assistance to other countries in Southeast Asia.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States supports exchange programs that connect Thai youth, students, educators, artists, athletes, and rising leaders to their counterparts in the United States and the ASEAN region, engaging them on strategic priorities ranging from civic engagement to economic sustainability. Our exchange programs are robust, with more than 5,000 Thai alumni of the Fulbright program, International Visitor Leadership Program (IVLP), and Young Southeast Asian Leaders Initiative (YSEALI).  The newly established Thailand-United States Alumni Association brings together alumni from across the country to work together on projects that support our mutual goals.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>S. Peace Corps Volunteers, active in Thailand since 1962, focus on English teacher training in primary schools and youth life skills development.</li>
</ul>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ninth Session of the Intergovernmental Science-Policy Platform on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services (IPBES) Approves the Thematic Assessment of the Sustainable Use of Wild Species</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/ninth-session-of-the-intergovernmental-science-policy-platform-on-biodiversity-and-ecosystem-services-ipbes-approves-the-thematic-assessment-of-the-sustainable-use-of-wild-species/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 14:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=358194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On Thursday, July 7, the Ninth Session of the Intergovernmental Science-Policy Platform on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services (IPBES) approved the Thematic Assessment of the Sustainable Use of Wild Species, which underscores the fundamental link between people and nature and reaffirms that people are dependent on nature.</p>
<p>The assessment makes clear that billions of people in all regions of the world rely on and benefit from the use of wild species for food, medicine, energy, income, and many other purposes; that the sustainable use of wild species is central to the identity and existence of many indigenous peoples and local communities; and, that ensuring sustainability of the use of wild species is critical to reversing the global trend in biodiversity decline.</p>
<p>Just as the 2019 IPBES Report on the Global Assessment on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services set out the grim reality that a million species are at risk of extinction due to unsustainable human activities, the IPBES Thematic Assessment on the Sustainable Use of Wild Species will be important to advancing our efforts to conserve at least 30 percent of land and water and 30 percent of the global ocean.  The IPBES assessment spotlights the importance of recognizing, respecting, and incorporating indigenous and local knowledge and knowledge systems into policy decisions.</p>
<p>The United States was instrumental in establishing IPBES in 2012 and remains a strong supporter of IPBES today.  We are celebrating IPBES’ 10-year anniversary by reaffirming our commitment to advancing science and the role of science in decision-making.  The United States has also worked in IPBES to advance the inclusion of indigenous peoples and local communities and incorporation, with their consent, of indigenous and local knowledge into the IPBES assessments.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On Thursday, July 7, the Ninth Session of the Intergovernmental Science-Policy Platform on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services (IPBES) approved the Thematic Assessment of the Sustainable Use of Wild Species, which underscores the fundamental link between people and nature and reaffirms that people are dependent on nature.</p>
<p>The assessment makes clear that billions of people in all regions of the world rely on and benefit from the use of wild species for food, medicine, energy, income, and many other purposes; that the sustainable use of wild species is central to the identity and existence of many indigenous peoples and local communities; and, that ensuring sustainability of the use of wild species is critical to reversing the global trend in biodiversity decline.</p>
<p>Just as the 2019 IPBES Report on the Global Assessment on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services set out the grim reality that a million species are at risk of extinction due to unsustainable human activities, the IPBES Thematic Assessment on the Sustainable Use of Wild Species will be important to advancing our efforts to conserve at least 30 percent of land and water and 30 percent of the global ocean.  The IPBES assessment spotlights the importance of recognizing, respecting, and incorporating indigenous and local knowledge and knowledge systems into policy decisions.</p>
<p>The United States was instrumental in establishing IPBES in 2012 and remains a strong supporter of IPBES today.  We are celebrating IPBES’ 10-year anniversary by reaffirming our commitment to advancing science and the role of science in decision-making.  The United States has also worked in IPBES to advance the inclusion of indigenous peoples and local communities and incorporation, with their consent, of indigenous and local knowledge into the IPBES assessments.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on Support for North Macedonia Opening EU Accession Negotiations</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-support-for-north-macedonia-opening-eu-accession-negotiations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 14:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=358190</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by United States Secretary of State Antony Blinken and High Representative/Vice-President of the European Commission Josep Borrell to express support for North Macedonia opening EU accession negotiations.</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>At this critical moment in European history, marked by the unjustifiable aggression carried out by Russia against Ukraine, advancing Albania and North Macedonia’s EU path is key to strengthening the cohesion and resilience of the entire European continent.  Guided by common values and EU standards and benchmarks, both countries are ready to take the next step toward EU membership.</p>
<p>We welcome a compromise proposal which takes into account the interests and concerns of both North Macedonia and Bulgaria based on mutual respect, trust, and understanding. The sovereign decision of the Parliament of North Macedonia will be important to move forward. This spirit of constructive compromise on which European integration is built should continue to inspire all those involved in this historic process.</p>
<p>The European Union and the United States are committed to closer cooperation in the Western Balkans.  Ensuring stability and prosperity and making their European and Euro-Atlantic future a reality remains our common goal.</p>
<p><i>End text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by United States Secretary of State Antony Blinken and High Representative/Vice-President of the European Commission Josep Borrell to express support for North Macedonia opening EU accession negotiations.</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>At this critical moment in European history, marked by the unjustifiable aggression carried out by Russia against Ukraine, advancing Albania and North Macedonia’s EU path is key to strengthening the cohesion and resilience of the entire European continent.  Guided by common values and EU standards and benchmarks, both countries are ready to take the next step toward EU membership.</p>
<p>We welcome a compromise proposal which takes into account the interests and concerns of both North Macedonia and Bulgaria based on mutual respect, trust, and understanding. The sovereign decision of the Parliament of North Macedonia will be important to move forward. This spirit of constructive compromise on which European integration is built should continue to inspire all those involved in this historic process.</p>
<p>The European Union and the United States are committed to closer cooperation in the Western Balkans.  Ensuring stability and prosperity and making their European and Euro-Atlantic future a reality remains our common goal.</p>
<p><i>End text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
