<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 16:51:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with French, German, Italian, and UK Counterparts</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-french-german-italian-and-uk-counterparts-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 16:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312823</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with French MFA Secretary General Francois Delattre, German MFA State Secretary Andreas Michaelis, Italian MFA Political Director Pasquale Ferrara, and UK Minister of State for Middle East, North Africa, and North America James Cleverly.  Deputy Secretary Sherman reaffirmed the United States’ readiness, together with Allies and partners, to impose swift, severe costs on Russia in response to any further military aggression by Russia against Ukraine. Participants discussed our ongoing, coordinated diplomatic outreach to Russia, our continued military support for NATO Allies on the Eastern flank, and the importance of Russia taking concrete steps to de-escalate.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with French MFA Secretary General Francois Delattre, German MFA State Secretary Andreas Michaelis, Italian MFA Political Director Pasquale Ferrara, and UK Minister of State for Middle East, North Africa, and North America James Cleverly.  Deputy Secretary Sherman reaffirmed the United States’ readiness, together with Allies and partners, to impose swift, severe costs on Russia in response to any further military aggression by Russia against Ukraine. Participants discussed our ongoing, coordinated diplomatic outreach to Russia, our continued military support for NATO Allies on the Eastern flank, and the importance of Russia taking concrete steps to de-escalate.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Designation of Under Secretary for Management John R. Bass as Chief Sustainability Officer</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/designation-of-under-secretary-for-management-john-r-bass-as-chief-sustainability-officer/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 15:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>With a footprint in nearly every country, the Department of State has seen firsthand the impacts of a changing climate on our operations.  From drought to worsening air quality, the climate crisis has not only had  implications for our personnel and their families, but also our host country partners around the world.  The years ahead will be critical to slowing the pace of global temperature rise and  preventing the worst impacts of climate change.  The Department of State is mobilizing on all fronts to tackle the climate crisis, including changing the way we operate at home and abroad to curb emissions, improve sustainability, and adapt to climate hazards.</p>
<p>There has never been a more urgent moment.  That is why I have designated Under Secretary for Management John R. Bass as the Department’s Chief Sustainability Officer.  In this role, he will lead the Department’s efforts to advance the rigorous federal climate and sustainability ambitions and priorities set by the Administration under Executive Orders 14008 and 14057.  Under Secretary Bass will set the vision for and  oversee implementation of the Department’s sustainability, adaptation, and resilience goals.</p>
<p>He will be supported by the Deputy Chief Sustainability Officer who leads the Greening Diplomacy Initiative within the Office of Management Strategy and Solutions, as well as the Climate and Sustainability Working Group comprising multiple Department bureaus and offices.</p>
<p>The Department is building on more than a decade of climate actions that have curbed emissions, enhanced climate adaptation, and made our operations more sustainable.  We are proud to be the premier federal agency in terms of harnessing renewable energy in our domestic operations and are working to electrify our fleet at home and abroad.  Our embassies and consulates are built to be U.S. Green Building Council Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (LEED) Silver certified or better, so we can ensure our facilities are resilient and highlight innovative U.S. technologies.  We are also advancing sustainability and resilience in our overseas operations through actions like installing rainwater harvesting systems in drought-stricken areas and installing on-site renewable energy.</p>
<p>There is a lot more to be done, however.  I have full confidence that Under Secretary Bass will take our efforts to the next level and demonstrate the Department’s full commitment to leading by example in tackling the climate crisis.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>With a footprint in nearly every country, the Department of State has seen firsthand the impacts of a changing climate on our operations.  From drought to worsening air quality, the climate crisis has not only had  implications for our personnel and their families, but also our host country partners around the world.  The years ahead will be critical to slowing the pace of global temperature rise and  preventing the worst impacts of climate change.  The Department of State is mobilizing on all fronts to tackle the climate crisis, including changing the way we operate at home and abroad to curb emissions, improve sustainability, and adapt to climate hazards.</p>
<p>There has never been a more urgent moment.  That is why I have designated Under Secretary for Management John R. Bass as the Department’s Chief Sustainability Officer.  In this role, he will lead the Department’s efforts to advance the rigorous federal climate and sustainability ambitions and priorities set by the Administration under Executive Orders 14008 and 14057.  Under Secretary Bass will set the vision for and  oversee implementation of the Department’s sustainability, adaptation, and resilience goals.</p>
<p>He will be supported by the Deputy Chief Sustainability Officer who leads the Greening Diplomacy Initiative within the Office of Management Strategy and Solutions, as well as the Climate and Sustainability Working Group comprising multiple Department bureaus and offices.</p>
<p>The Department is building on more than a decade of climate actions that have curbed emissions, enhanced climate adaptation, and made our operations more sustainable.  We are proud to be the premier federal agency in terms of harnessing renewable energy in our domestic operations and are working to electrify our fleet at home and abroad.  Our embassies and consulates are built to be U.S. Green Building Council Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (LEED) Silver certified or better, so we can ensure our facilities are resilient and highlight innovative U.S. technologies.  We are also advancing sustainability and resilience in our overseas operations through actions like installing rainwater harvesting systems in drought-stricken areas and installing on-site renewable energy.</p>
<p>There is a lot more to be done, however.  I have full confidence that Under Secretary Bass will take our efforts to the next level and demonstrate the Department’s full commitment to leading by example in tackling the climate crisis.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Remarks to the Press En Route Melbourne, Australia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-remarks-to-the-press-en-route-melbourne-australia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 04:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312648</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Very good.  First of all, this is an important moment because it’s the final leg of our four-leg trip, so I know you’re all feeling good about that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  All right.  In all seriousness, look, there is obviously a tremendous amount of focus on what’s happening in Europe, in particular Russia’s ongoing buildup of forces near Ukraine.  And that remains front and center in what we’re doing and indeed what I continue to do even as we’re heading to Australia.</p>
<p>I’ve been on the phone during a chunk of this trip talking to various counterparts with some focus on Russia-Ukraine.  I spent some time talking to the National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan as well.  And this is part of, as we’ve tabulated, with foreign counterparts something like 200-plus engagements just in recent weeks – phone calls, video conferences, in-person meetings, where we have been working to coordinate all of our partners in standing up to this Russian aggression directed toward Ukraine.</p>
<p>And as you all know, we have been engaged in a two-track strategy where we have, on the one hand, been pursuing diplomacy, by far the preferable course, the responsible course, but at the same time building up strong deterrence to dissuade Russia from taking aggressive action.</p>
<p>Having said that, the world is a big place.  Our interests are global, and you all know very well the focus that we have put on the Asia-Pacific and Indo-Pacific region.  And we ended last year with a trip that some of you were on, and we have a sustained focus on this, and that’s why we’re heading to Australia.</p>
<p>We’ll be first and foremost meeting with the Quad countries – Australia, Japan, India, the United States – following up on the leader level summit, the first ever that the President had, and pursuing the work that I think is vital to the interests of Americans but also people throughout the region and around the world.  The Quad is becoming a powerful mechanism for delivering, helping to vaccinate a big part of the world and getting a lot of vaccines out there, strengthening maritime security to push back against aggression and coercion in the Indo-Pacific region, working together on emerging technologies and making sure that they can be used in positive ways not negative ways, and an increasingly broad and deep agenda.</p>
<p>At the same time, it’s an opportunity to meet with our Australian partners, meetings as well with Japanese and Indian counterparts – all critical partners both in terms of the Quad but also individually.</p>
<p>And one of the other reasons I want to emphasize the work that we’re doing with the Quad is it’s very representative of what we’re doing in different ways around the world, which is building, energizing, driving different coalitions of countries focused on sometimes overlapping issues.  We’re doing that with established institutions like NATO or in Asia like ASEAN with our traditional alliances, but also with new groupings and coalitions of countries that can focus the strengths of different partners on issues that really, really matter, whether it’s climate, whether it’s COVID, whether it’s emerging technologies.  The Quad’s one of the best examples of that.</p>
<p>I’ll also have a chance in Australia to spend some time with some incredible technologists at the University of Melbourne, students as well.  Parenthetically, my late stepfather went to the University of Melbourne, so this will be a little bit of a homecoming in that sense, too.</p>
<p>And then after Australia we’re off, as you know, to Fiji.  This is, I am told, the first time in nearly 40 years that a secretary of state has visited Fiji.  There’s a very good reason for that:  we’re a Pacific nation.  The Pacific part of the Indo-Pacific Strategy is vitally important, and in the category of 90 percent of life is showing up or showing up; but more than showing up, I think you’ll see some very concrete things come out of the visit to Fiji.  I’m not going to get ahead of myself, but we’ll have a few things to talk about when we get there.  So I’m very much looking forward to that.</p>
<p>And then finally, of course, we end up in Hawaii, and there Japanese and Korean counterparts will come together.  We’ve been spending a lot of time – Deputy Secretary Sherman and myself – on trilateral collaboration among the United States, Japan, and Republic of Korea.  This is another opportunity to drive that forward.  There is a very broad common agenda that we have, of course, starting with challenges posed by the DPRK but going well beyond that.  This is an important moment to keep driving that forward.</p>
<p>We’ll also have a chance to spend time with our INDOPACOM commander, Admiral Aquilino, to talk about the work that we’re doing throughout the Indo-Pacific to advance stability, to advance security.</p>
<p>So we’re covering quite literally as well as figuratively a lot of territory.  I’m looking forward also to seeing some of our State Department colleagues who have a hardship assignment in Honolulu when we end the trip.  So that’s what we’re doing.  There’s a lot that’s going to be said at each stop.  We’ll have a chance to talk about specific issues that we’re focused on.</p>
<p>Meanwhile – the last thing I’ll say – even as we’re doing this we will be on the phones, on the video conference with other countries and counterparts, back in Washington, given everything that’s going on in Europe.  And I expect, for example, to be speaking to French, Germans, British colleagues in the coming days, among many others.  So I wanted to leave it at that.<input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Very good.  First of all, this is an important moment because it’s the final leg of our four-leg trip, so I know you’re all feeling good about that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  All right.  In all seriousness, look, there is obviously a tremendous amount of focus on what’s happening in Europe, in particular Russia’s ongoing buildup of forces near Ukraine.  And that remains front and center in what we’re doing and indeed what I continue to do even as we’re heading to Australia.</p>
<p>I’ve been on the phone during a chunk of this trip talking to various counterparts with some focus on Russia-Ukraine.  I spent some time talking to the National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan as well.  And this is part of, as we’ve tabulated, with foreign counterparts something like 200-plus engagements just in recent weeks – phone calls, video conferences, in-person meetings, where we have been working to coordinate all of our partners in standing up to this Russian aggression directed toward Ukraine.</p>
<p>And as you all know, we have been engaged in a two-track strategy where we have, on the one hand, been pursuing diplomacy, by far the preferable course, the responsible course, but at the same time building up strong deterrence to dissuade Russia from taking aggressive action.</p>
<p>Having said that, the world is a big place.  Our interests are global, and you all know very well the focus that we have put on the Asia-Pacific and Indo-Pacific region.  And we ended last year with a trip that some of you were on, and we have a sustained focus on this, and that’s why we’re heading to Australia.</p>
<p>We’ll be first and foremost meeting with the Quad countries – Australia, Japan, India, the United States – following up on the leader level summit, the first ever that the President had, and pursuing the work that I think is vital to the interests of Americans but also people throughout the region and around the world.  The Quad is becoming a powerful mechanism for delivering, helping to vaccinate a big part of the world and getting a lot of vaccines out there, strengthening maritime security to push back against aggression and coercion in the Indo-Pacific region, working together on emerging technologies and making sure that they can be used in positive ways not negative ways, and an increasingly broad and deep agenda.</p>
<p>At the same time, it’s an opportunity to meet with our Australian partners, meetings as well with Japanese and Indian counterparts – all critical partners both in terms of the Quad but also individually.</p>
<p>And one of the other reasons I want to emphasize the work that we’re doing with the Quad is it’s very representative of what we’re doing in different ways around the world, which is building, energizing, driving different coalitions of countries focused on sometimes overlapping issues.  We’re doing that with established institutions like NATO or in Asia like ASEAN with our traditional alliances, but also with new groupings and coalitions of countries that can focus the strengths of different partners on issues that really, really matter, whether it’s climate, whether it’s COVID, whether it’s emerging technologies.  The Quad’s one of the best examples of that.</p>
<p>I’ll also have a chance in Australia to spend some time with some incredible technologists at the University of Melbourne, students as well.  Parenthetically, my late stepfather went to the University of Melbourne, so this will be a little bit of a homecoming in that sense, too.</p>
<p>And then after Australia we’re off, as you know, to Fiji.  This is, I am told, the first time in nearly 40 years that a secretary of state has visited Fiji.  There’s a very good reason for that:  we’re a Pacific nation.  The Pacific part of the Indo-Pacific Strategy is vitally important, and in the category of 90 percent of life is showing up or showing up; but more than showing up, I think you’ll see some very concrete things come out of the visit to Fiji.  I’m not going to get ahead of myself, but we’ll have a few things to talk about when we get there.  So I’m very much looking forward to that.</p>
<p>And then finally, of course, we end up in Hawaii, and there Japanese and Korean counterparts will come together.  We’ve been spending a lot of time – Deputy Secretary Sherman and myself – on trilateral collaboration among the United States, Japan, and Republic of Korea.  This is another opportunity to drive that forward.  There is a very broad common agenda that we have, of course, starting with challenges posed by the DPRK but going well beyond that.  This is an important moment to keep driving that forward.</p>
<p>We’ll also have a chance to spend time with our INDOPACOM commander, Admiral Aquilino, to talk about the work that we’re doing throughout the Indo-Pacific to advance stability, to advance security.</p>
<p>So we’re covering quite literally as well as figuratively a lot of territory.  I’m looking forward also to seeing some of our State Department colleagues who have a hardship assignment in Honolulu when we end the trip.  So that’s what we’re doing.  There’s a lot that’s going to be said at each stop.  We’ll have a chance to talk about specific issues that we’re focused on.</p>
<p>Meanwhile – the last thing I’ll say – even as we’re doing this we will be on the phones, on the video conference with other countries and counterparts, back in Washington, given everything that’s going on in Europe.  And I expect, for example, to be speaking to French, Germans, British colleagues in the coming days, among many others.  So I wanted to leave it at that.<input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States and Australia: A Vital Partnership for the Indo-Pacific Region and the World</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-and-australia-a-vital-partnership-for-the-indo-pacific-region-and-the-world/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 23:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312563</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>As democratic anchors in the Indo-Pacific, the United States and Australia share an unshakeable commitment to defending freedom and democracy, championing opportunity, upholding human rights, respecting the rule of law, and countering state-sponsored disinformation.</p>
<p>Australia and the United States have a proud history of working together in times of crisis for more than 100 years.  Australia and the United States have stood shoulder to shoulder in every major conflict since World War 1.  Last year marked the 70th anniversary of the signing of the Australia, New Zealand, United States (ANZUS) Treaty—a keystone of our relationship with Australia and an enduring force for stability in the wider region.  The only time the collective defense article of the ANZUS Treaty was formally invoked was after September 11, 2001.</p>
<p><strong>The United States and Australia: Securing a Safe and Prosperous Indo-Pacific</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The Quad – the United States, Australia, India, and Japan – is making tangible progress on the Indo-Pacific region’s most important challenges. The Quad Vaccine Partnership is committed to expanding local production of safe and effective doses of COVID-19 vaccines, having already collectively provided over 484 million safe and effective vaccine doses as of February 1, 2022.  Australia will focus on vaccine procurement and last-mile delivery support to the region.  Quad Partners are joining forces to expand safe, affordable, and effective vaccine production and equitable access to speed economic recovery and benefit global health.  At the same time, Quad partners are working with countries around the region to strengthen the region’s maritime security, counter-terrorism, counter-disinformation, and cybersecurity, and humanitarian and disaster relief response, including cooperatively supporting Tonga following the recent volcanic eruptions, ashfall, and tsunami.  The Quad will continue to meet regularly to deliver as a force for good for the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States is committed to deeper and more intensive engagement in the Indo-Pacific for generations to come. AUKUS, the enhanced trilateral security partnership between Australia, the United Kingdom, and the United States, demonstrates the U.S. commitment to revitalizing our partnerships and strengthening them to take on the challenges of the 21st century.  This partnership is especially important given the changing strategic environment in the region.  AUKUS will bring together our service members, our scientists, and our industries to maintain and expand our edge in military capabilities and critical technologies.  The partnership is about connecting existing U.S. allies and partners in new ways and amplifying our ability to collaborate.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>In the wake of the recent Hunga Tonga-Hunga Ha’apai volcanic eruptions, ashfall, and tsunami, the United States and Australia are coordinating closely, together with other international partners, to provide immediate help and support on assistance to Tonga. The USS Sampson (DDG 102) supported not only disaster relief efforts but also the Australian Defence Force-led response.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>The United States and Australia: A Vital Partnership for the World</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Australia and U.S. biotech company Moderna have agreed to build an mRNA vaccine manufacturing and finishing facility in Melbourne, Australia, that will produce as many as 100 million mRNA vaccines a year – increasing the health security of Australia and the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Australia is an essential partner in developing emerging technologies, including quantum information sciences, artificial intelligence, advanced manufacturing, and clean energy technologies. Our bilateral collaboration promotes innovative research, enhances economic productivity, and upholds the highest standards for these novel technologies.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>We welcome Australia’s work with us and likeminded partners to strengthen the resilience, security, and diversity of key supply chains, including critical minerals needed to fuel the clean energy transition, of which Australia has world-leading reserves. The United States and Australia are working to build robust, responsible supply chains for clean energy minerals and metals through the Energy Resource Governance Initiative (ERGI) and will continue to expand our cooperation bilaterally through the Quad Climate Working Group and other relevant multilateral initiatives.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States and Australia share a robust and growing economic relationship. The United States is proud to be the top foreign investor in Australia by far and to be the top destination for Australia’s foreign investment.  Deep people-to-people ties also reinforce our shared beliefs and common interests.  Tens of thousands of Australian and American students have participated in academic exchange programs.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>As democratic anchors in the Indo-Pacific, the United States and Australia share an unshakeable commitment to defending freedom and democracy, championing opportunity, upholding human rights, respecting the rule of law, and countering state-sponsored disinformation.</p>
<p>Australia and the United States have a proud history of working together in times of crisis for more than 100 years.  Australia and the United States have stood shoulder to shoulder in every major conflict since World War 1.  Last year marked the 70th anniversary of the signing of the Australia, New Zealand, United States (ANZUS) Treaty—a keystone of our relationship with Australia and an enduring force for stability in the wider region.  The only time the collective defense article of the ANZUS Treaty was formally invoked was after September 11, 2001.</p>
<p><strong>The United States and Australia: Securing a Safe and Prosperous Indo-Pacific</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The Quad – the United States, Australia, India, and Japan – is making tangible progress on the Indo-Pacific region’s most important challenges. The Quad Vaccine Partnership is committed to expanding local production of safe and effective doses of COVID-19 vaccines, having already collectively provided over 484 million safe and effective vaccine doses as of February 1, 2022.  Australia will focus on vaccine procurement and last-mile delivery support to the region.  Quad Partners are joining forces to expand safe, affordable, and effective vaccine production and equitable access to speed economic recovery and benefit global health.  At the same time, Quad partners are working with countries around the region to strengthen the region’s maritime security, counter-terrorism, counter-disinformation, and cybersecurity, and humanitarian and disaster relief response, including cooperatively supporting Tonga following the recent volcanic eruptions, ashfall, and tsunami.  The Quad will continue to meet regularly to deliver as a force for good for the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States is committed to deeper and more intensive engagement in the Indo-Pacific for generations to come. AUKUS, the enhanced trilateral security partnership between Australia, the United Kingdom, and the United States, demonstrates the U.S. commitment to revitalizing our partnerships and strengthening them to take on the challenges of the 21st century.  This partnership is especially important given the changing strategic environment in the region.  AUKUS will bring together our service members, our scientists, and our industries to maintain and expand our edge in military capabilities and critical technologies.  The partnership is about connecting existing U.S. allies and partners in new ways and amplifying our ability to collaborate.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>In the wake of the recent Hunga Tonga-Hunga Ha’apai volcanic eruptions, ashfall, and tsunami, the United States and Australia are coordinating closely, together with other international partners, to provide immediate help and support on assistance to Tonga. The USS Sampson (DDG 102) supported not only disaster relief efforts but also the Australian Defence Force-led response.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>The United States and Australia: A Vital Partnership for the World</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Australia and U.S. biotech company Moderna have agreed to build an mRNA vaccine manufacturing and finishing facility in Melbourne, Australia, that will produce as many as 100 million mRNA vaccines a year – increasing the health security of Australia and the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Australia is an essential partner in developing emerging technologies, including quantum information sciences, artificial intelligence, advanced manufacturing, and clean energy technologies. Our bilateral collaboration promotes innovative research, enhances economic productivity, and upholds the highest standards for these novel technologies.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>We welcome Australia’s work with us and likeminded partners to strengthen the resilience, security, and diversity of key supply chains, including critical minerals needed to fuel the clean energy transition, of which Australia has world-leading reserves. The United States and Australia are working to build robust, responsible supply chains for clean energy minerals and metals through the Energy Resource Governance Initiative (ERGI) and will continue to expand our cooperation bilaterally through the Quad Climate Working Group and other relevant multilateral initiatives.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States and Australia share a robust and growing economic relationship. The United States is proud to be the top foreign investor in Australia by far and to be the top destination for Australia’s foreign investment.  Deep people-to-people ties also reinforce our shared beliefs and common interests.  Tens of thousands of Australian and American students have participated in academic exchange programs.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing – February 8, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-february-8-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 22:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=312524</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Good afternoon, and thank you all for joining today’s press briefing. I don’t have any elements at the top, but I’ll give it a few extra minutes to have some more reporters filter in the queue before I start taking your questions.</p>
<p>So, let’s start off with the line of Cindy Spang, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, hello. Good afternoon. I have a question about Jamshid Sharmahd, a German Iranian dissident and longtime California resident who was abducted by Iran and went on trial Sunday and could face the death penalty. Would you have any comment or reaction to that, please? And thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-GermanyIran"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Cindy. We’re certainly aware of the reports regarding Jamshid Sharmahd’s detention, but we’re going to have to refer you to the Government of Germany for any further inquiries.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to Janne Pak.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hello.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hello.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you, Janne. Great to hear from you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, because very hard to – this signal here. So, I have two questions for you. And it is an important time for the U.S. and ROK-Japan trilateral alliance to respond to North Korea’s successive provocations. Will there be any discussion about the South Korea’s ascension to the Quad at the three-party foreign ministers meeting in Hawaii?</p>
<p>Second question: It is reported that the North Korea is operating on ICBM bases on the border between North Korea and China. My question is: Do you have any specific information about this? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Quad"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Janne. I’ll start with your first question first. And just broadly speaking, I’d like to say that the Quad is an essential multilateral grouping that convenes four like-minded democracies. Of course, that’s the U.S., Australia, Japan, and India. And the purpose, of course, is to make tangible progress on pressing challenges within the Indo Pacific. It’s also based on our shared values and capability. Each Quad member shares collective commitments to democracy, peace, security, and prosperity in the region.</p>
<p>To answer your questions about South Korea’s ascension into the Quad, I certainly don’t have any details to share other than what we issued in our readout – that was our travel announcement, excuse me, that was issued last Friday.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-NorthKorea"></a> But what I would say is that we continue to consult closely with the Republic of Korea, Japan, as well as other allies and partners on how to best engage the DPRK. The United States condemned the DPRK’s missile launches, and of course the DPRK wants to normalize illicit weapons testing, but we’re taking a calibrated approach, as we’ve said previously, to these provocations based on the degree of threat to the United States as well as to our allies.</p>
<p>Of course, as it can’t be understated, a number times, that our goal remains the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and that we have no hostile intent towards the DPRK and remain open to meeting the DPRK without preconditions. Of course, however, we also have an obligation to address the DPRK’s recent provocations and enforce UNSCRs that are already in place.</p>
<p>To your second question, on the ICBM base on the border with China, I would say that our goal remains the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. The DPRK constitutes a threat to international peace and security and the global nonproliferation regime. It’s – the United States has a vital interest in deterring the DPRK. That includes defending against its provocations or uses of force, limiting the reach of its most dangerous weapons programs, and above all keeping the American people, our deployed forces, and our allies safe.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to the line of Daphne Psaledakis, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for doing this. How has the resumption of Iran talks in Vienna gone today? Has any progress been made? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Iran"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks for your question, Daphne. Special Envoy Malley has actually just recently returned to Vienna. He returned yesterday for the eighth round of talks that resumed today. I don’t have anything to read out from there. Of course, he continues to meet on the sidelines with our partners in Vienna. He also continues to brief Congress virtually, but outside of that I don’t have anything else to say, and I certainly wouldn’t want to get ahead of the talks. Of course, if we do have updates, we’ll be certain to share them with you as soon as we have them.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Michel Ghandour, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for the call. I have a question on Iran talks, but since you have no update, I will ask you about Lebanon and Senior Advisor Hochstein who’s in Beirut today. Is he bringing any U.S. plan or offer to solve the maritime dispute between Lebanon and Israel? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-LebanonIsrael"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Michel. So, what I would say at the top is that the maritime boundary is a decision for both Israel and Lebanon to make. And of course, the U.S. stands ready to facilitate negotiations on the maritime boundary between both Lebanon and Israel, and we support efforts to reach a mutually beneficial agreement.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Conor Finnegan, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hi. Yes, Conor, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey. Hey, Jalina. Two questions for you. On Ukraine first, any response to the talks between Presidents Macron and Putin, now that we’ve heard a bit more about them from both sides? Macron specifically said today that Putin told him Russia wouldn’t initiate an escalation. I’m wondering if you believe that’s true.</p>
<p>And then a second question on Honduras. The information that was declassified and publicized last night that former President Hernández was included on the list of corrupt and undemocratic actors – why was this information declassified now, and does it send the wrong message that heads of government would only face repercussions like this once they leave power? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-UkraineFranceRussia"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So, Conor, I will start with your first question. On Macron, I would just say that we are engaged in intensive diplomacy with our allies and partners, but I’m – I just can’t get into detail about private meetings. But one of the messages that we’ve tried to send very clearly to Russia is that the West is united, and the fact is that there’s still more than 100,000 Russian troops surrounding Ukraine. Russia continues to surge troops and equipment to the borders of Ukraine, and we believe that they are in a position where they can invade at any time.</p>
<p>Of course, we just can’t control what Russia will do next, but what we can do is make clear with our allies and partners that there will be massive consequences to Russia should Putin choose to further invade Ukraine. And if Russia does invade, it will end up in a weaker position over time, and the NATO Alliance will be stronger and more united.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Honduras"></a> To your second question on Honduras, we’re declassifying and publicizing the inclusion of former Honduran President Juan Orlando Hernández in the Corrupt Undemocratic Actors List under Section 353 of the United States-Northern Triangle Enhancement Engagement Act. The department included Hernández on this list effective July 1st on – in 2021.</p>
<p>According to multiple credible media outlets, Juan Orlando Hernández has engaged in significant corruption by committing or facilitating acts of corruption and narcotrafficking and using proceeds of illicit activity to facilitate political campaigns.</p>
<p>I would say in addition Hernández was identified by name in a sworn witness testimony in a U.S. Federal criminal proceeding as having received narcotrafficking proceeds as a part of his campaign funding. And pursuant to Section 353 of the United States-Northern Triangle Enhancement Engagement Act, individuals identified through this list are generally ineligible for visas to travel to the United States.</p>
<p>I would also add that the United States encourages the fight against corruption as a core national security priority. And of course, we’re engaged in a careful, thorough effort to combat corruption in Honduras as well as across the region and as well as around the world.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to the line of Matt Lee.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hey Matt, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, I have two brief ones on Iran. I realize you don’t have a readout from Vienna, but I’m just wondering: Can you say if Rob Malley and the team has at least begun to have meetings – the indirect meetings – with the Europeans, or are they just kind of waiting for – to have – to begin those contacts tomorrow or later today?</p>
<p>And then secondly, you guys have made the case that the sanctions waivers that were signed on Friday by the Secretary do not invoke or do not require the provisions of INARA to be followed because it’s not a quid pro quo or part of a – part of an agreement. But you probably will have seen a letter that has been sent by, I think, 33 Republican senators that says that it does actually, and, also, more – perhaps more importantly that they will block or move to block any kind of an agreement that you do – that you may reach with Iran if it is not submitted to Congress first.</p>
<p>And so, part – and so without getting into congressional correspondence, I’m just wondering if you can assure members of Congress now that you will be submitting any agreement that you get in Vienna to Congress for its approval. And then also very briefly, just to remind you of the first one, have the actual meetings with the U.S. team begun? Thanks.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Iran2"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hey Matt, I think I want to go back to your first question. I thought you asked initially had meetings with Special Envoy Malley started with the Europeans yet. And if that’s correct, I don’t have anything to share or read out at the moment.</p>
<p>But to your second question on Congress, I’d reiterate at the top what I shared on the – with one of the questions of your colleagues, which is that Special Envoy Malley continues to brief members of Congress even remotely. But what I’ll say more specifically is that the administration will carefully consider the facts as well as the circumstances of any U.S. return to the JCPOA to determine the legal implications, which would include under INARA. We’re committed to ensuring the requirements of INARA are satisfied.</p>
<p>And the President believes that a bipartisan approach to Iran is the strongest way to safeguard U.S. interests for the long term. And the administration officials have reached out at all levels to members of Congress as well as their staff to discuss our approach to Iran. Special Envoy Malley remains deeply committed to continued close engagement with Congress in a bipartisan manner as Iran policy continues to develop.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to the line of Luis Rojas.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. I have only one question today. Do you have any update on the possible retabulation of remittance to Cuba or on the sending of diplomatic personnel to the United States Embassy in Havana, please?</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Cuba"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Luis. To your second question, I don’t have any announcements or any updates to make about personnel issues, but I’d just reiterate what we have shared in the past to your first question, which was: following the July 2021 protest the administration created a remittance working group to explore options to facilitate remittances to Cuba that would go to maximally benefit the Cuban people, and that would also include by allowing Cuban families to support each other and also minimize or eliminate benefits to the Cuban regime and its military.</p>
<p>Also, in August of 2021, the remittance working group shared its analysis that includes potential options with other members of the administration, and the administration continues to consider these options and explore innovative solutions such as digital payment. Outside of that, we don’t have any specific timetables for a decision or any other updates to share, at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to the line of Will Mauldin.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks so much, Jalina. I just wanted to follow up on Conor’s question about the French diplomacy in Russia and Ukraine, and was wondering if Secretary Blinken – I know he’s traveling, but he has a pretty good telephone set on board – or any of the other senior members of the department, Under Secretary Nuland or Deputy Secretary Sherman, had been in touch with the French or were expected to, or other people in the administration. And if they – and what was the general view on that? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-UkraineFranceRussia2"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Will. I don’t have anything much else to add from what I shared with Conor in that we are – we continue to be in close consultation and coordination with our allies and partners, and we continue to be in alliance with them as well.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Jiha Ham, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, good afternoon. I have two questions for you today. Yesterday, VOA reported that a North Korean defector, who is a military officer, who is also known as a cryptocurrency expert, was arrested by Russia and now imprisoned in a North Korean consulate in Vladivostok. Some expect that he will be sent back to North Korea. Do you have any concerns that this may be another forced repatriation case that we have seen in China many times? Some human rights experts suggest that the State Department should ask Russia to free this person. So, what’s your position on this?</p>
<p>And my second question is about China’s remark yesterday at the Security Council. The Chinese ambassador said that there have been serious humanitarian consequences in North Korea and the import of humanitarian livelihood goods have been severely restricted because of the sanctions on North Korea. But in fact, there are many aid groups who have received sanctions exemptions, and quite many of them are ready to send those important items, but the problem is North Korea’s border closure. So, do you have any response or comment on this? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-HumanitarianSanctionsNorthKorea"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Jiha. I’ll start with your second question. The United States has led efforts to streamline the process for humanitarian sanctions exemptions at the UN and it has also committed to reviewing such applications as quickly as possible. We’ve also maintained broad exemptions and authorizations across many of the sanctions programs, including the DPRK program, aimed at ensuring that U.S. sanctions don’t hamper the transfer and delivery of humanitarian aid.</p>
<p>And to your first question, I would have to refer you to colleagues at the Department of Homeland Security.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Albert Hong, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>One more North Korean issue. North Korea’s Foreign Ministry said it had never committed a cyber crime. North Korea also accused the United States for cyber crime. What is the State Department&#8217;s position of that?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks for your question. While I haven&#8217;t seen those reports before your question, I would just say that U.S. diplomats work with countries around the world to promote the stability in cyberspace and also reduce the risk of conflict. They coordinate with partners and allies to call out and impose consequences on states that use cyber capabilities irresponsibly. They also implement programs to enhance the capacity of partner countries to implement effective cyber policies, respond to cyber threats, which would include cyber crime, and also participate in international conversations on cyber issues.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s take a final question from Anas Elsabbar.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yes, thank you, Jalina. My question regarding the designation of Houthis as a terrorist group. I don&#8217;t know if you have any update on this. And also, there were news about designating some Houthis’ top leaders and sanctioning them in the near future. I don&#8217;t know if you have any update on that as well.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you, Anas. I, actually, don&#8217;t have any updates on either to share at this time, but certainly happy to share them as soon as we do.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Afghanistan"></a> Now, before I close today’s briefing I just – I thought this might have come up, but since it didn&#8217;t, I just wanted to take a moment to address something very specific that has been in our news cycle. Following the Secretary’s hearing in Congress last week on Afghanistan, there has been renewed reflection on events from last year as well as interest in our Afghan relocation efforts.</p>
<p>There was a media report today recounting internal discussions and deliberations from a Department of Defense internal report related to the end of the U.S. war in Afghanistan from last summer. Cherry-picked comments do not reflect the months of work that were already underway or the whole picture of what the U.S. diplomats undertook to facilitate the evacuation and relocation of U.S. citizens, lawful permanent residents, and allies – Afghan allies from Afghanistan. Some of the claims allegedly included in the report regarding State Department personnel and plans are outright false and shamefully so.</p>
<p>I also want to take a moment to acknowledge the career Foreign Service officers who were in Afghanistan, who demonstrated immense bravery, professionalism, and dedication to doing the mission during extraordinarily difficult circumstances. They put their lives at risk, standing shoulder to shoulder with our armed forces at gates to the airport, and in the end helping 124,000 Americans, foreigners, Afghan allies and their families leave Kabul.</p>
<p>Of course, this mission continues today. Many of these courageous colleagues have volunteered to be part of the team at State Department leading our ongoing Afghan relocation efforts. And this Department is proud of their service and their sacrifice, and I am personally honored to serve with them.</p>
<p>That ends today’s press briefing. I hope you have a wonderful day, and we’ll see you back here tomorrow.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:29 p.m.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Good afternoon, and thank you all for joining today’s press briefing. I don’t have any elements at the top, but I’ll give it a few extra minutes to have some more reporters filter in the queue before I start taking your questions.</p>
<p>So, let’s start off with the line of Cindy Spang, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, hello. Good afternoon. I have a question about Jamshid Sharmahd, a German Iranian dissident and longtime California resident who was abducted by Iran and went on trial Sunday and could face the death penalty. Would you have any comment or reaction to that, please? And thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-GermanyIran"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Cindy. We’re certainly aware of the reports regarding Jamshid Sharmahd’s detention, but we’re going to have to refer you to the Government of Germany for any further inquiries.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to Janne Pak.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hello.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hello.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you, Janne. Great to hear from you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, because very hard to – this signal here. So, I have two questions for you. And it is an important time for the U.S. and ROK-Japan trilateral alliance to respond to North Korea’s successive provocations. Will there be any discussion about the South Korea’s ascension to the Quad at the three-party foreign ministers meeting in Hawaii?</p>
<p>Second question: It is reported that the North Korea is operating on ICBM bases on the border between North Korea and China. My question is: Do you have any specific information about this? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Quad"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Janne. I’ll start with your first question first. And just broadly speaking, I’d like to say that the Quad is an essential multilateral grouping that convenes four like-minded democracies. Of course, that’s the U.S., Australia, Japan, and India. And the purpose, of course, is to make tangible progress on pressing challenges within the Indo Pacific. It’s also based on our shared values and capability. Each Quad member shares collective commitments to democracy, peace, security, and prosperity in the region.</p>
<p>To answer your questions about South Korea’s ascension into the Quad, I certainly don’t have any details to share other than what we issued in our readout – that was our travel announcement, excuse me, that was issued last Friday.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-NorthKorea"></a> But what I would say is that we continue to consult closely with the Republic of Korea, Japan, as well as other allies and partners on how to best engage the DPRK. The United States condemned the DPRK’s missile launches, and of course the DPRK wants to normalize illicit weapons testing, but we’re taking a calibrated approach, as we’ve said previously, to these provocations based on the degree of threat to the United States as well as to our allies.</p>
<p>Of course, as it can’t be understated, a number times, that our goal remains the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and that we have no hostile intent towards the DPRK and remain open to meeting the DPRK without preconditions. Of course, however, we also have an obligation to address the DPRK’s recent provocations and enforce UNSCRs that are already in place.</p>
<p>To your second question, on the ICBM base on the border with China, I would say that our goal remains the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. The DPRK constitutes a threat to international peace and security and the global nonproliferation regime. It’s – the United States has a vital interest in deterring the DPRK. That includes defending against its provocations or uses of force, limiting the reach of its most dangerous weapons programs, and above all keeping the American people, our deployed forces, and our allies safe.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to the line of Daphne Psaledakis, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for doing this. How has the resumption of Iran talks in Vienna gone today? Has any progress been made? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Iran"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks for your question, Daphne. Special Envoy Malley has actually just recently returned to Vienna. He returned yesterday for the eighth round of talks that resumed today. I don’t have anything to read out from there. Of course, he continues to meet on the sidelines with our partners in Vienna. He also continues to brief Congress virtually, but outside of that I don’t have anything else to say, and I certainly wouldn’t want to get ahead of the talks. Of course, if we do have updates, we’ll be certain to share them with you as soon as we have them.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Michel Ghandour, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for the call. I have a question on Iran talks, but since you have no update, I will ask you about Lebanon and Senior Advisor Hochstein who’s in Beirut today. Is he bringing any U.S. plan or offer to solve the maritime dispute between Lebanon and Israel? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-LebanonIsrael"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Michel. So, what I would say at the top is that the maritime boundary is a decision for both Israel and Lebanon to make. And of course, the U.S. stands ready to facilitate negotiations on the maritime boundary between both Lebanon and Israel, and we support efforts to reach a mutually beneficial agreement.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Conor Finnegan, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hi. Yes, Conor, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey. Hey, Jalina. Two questions for you. On Ukraine first, any response to the talks between Presidents Macron and Putin, now that we’ve heard a bit more about them from both sides? Macron specifically said today that Putin told him Russia wouldn’t initiate an escalation. I’m wondering if you believe that’s true.</p>
<p>And then a second question on Honduras. The information that was declassified and publicized last night that former President Hernández was included on the list of corrupt and undemocratic actors – why was this information declassified now, and does it send the wrong message that heads of government would only face repercussions like this once they leave power? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-UkraineFranceRussia"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So, Conor, I will start with your first question. On Macron, I would just say that we are engaged in intensive diplomacy with our allies and partners, but I’m – I just can’t get into detail about private meetings. But one of the messages that we’ve tried to send very clearly to Russia is that the West is united, and the fact is that there’s still more than 100,000 Russian troops surrounding Ukraine. Russia continues to surge troops and equipment to the borders of Ukraine, and we believe that they are in a position where they can invade at any time.</p>
<p>Of course, we just can’t control what Russia will do next, but what we can do is make clear with our allies and partners that there will be massive consequences to Russia should Putin choose to further invade Ukraine. And if Russia does invade, it will end up in a weaker position over time, and the NATO Alliance will be stronger and more united.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Honduras"></a> To your second question on Honduras, we’re declassifying and publicizing the inclusion of former Honduran President Juan Orlando Hernández in the Corrupt Undemocratic Actors List under Section 353 of the United States-Northern Triangle Enhancement Engagement Act. The department included Hernández on this list effective July 1st on – in 2021.</p>
<p>According to multiple credible media outlets, Juan Orlando Hernández has engaged in significant corruption by committing or facilitating acts of corruption and narcotrafficking and using proceeds of illicit activity to facilitate political campaigns.</p>
<p>I would say in addition Hernández was identified by name in a sworn witness testimony in a U.S. Federal criminal proceeding as having received narcotrafficking proceeds as a part of his campaign funding. And pursuant to Section 353 of the United States-Northern Triangle Enhancement Engagement Act, individuals identified through this list are generally ineligible for visas to travel to the United States.</p>
<p>I would also add that the United States encourages the fight against corruption as a core national security priority. And of course, we’re engaged in a careful, thorough effort to combat corruption in Honduras as well as across the region and as well as around the world.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to the line of Matt Lee.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hey Matt, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, I have two brief ones on Iran. I realize you don’t have a readout from Vienna, but I’m just wondering: Can you say if Rob Malley and the team has at least begun to have meetings – the indirect meetings – with the Europeans, or are they just kind of waiting for – to have – to begin those contacts tomorrow or later today?</p>
<p>And then secondly, you guys have made the case that the sanctions waivers that were signed on Friday by the Secretary do not invoke or do not require the provisions of INARA to be followed because it’s not a quid pro quo or part of a – part of an agreement. But you probably will have seen a letter that has been sent by, I think, 33 Republican senators that says that it does actually, and, also, more – perhaps more importantly that they will block or move to block any kind of an agreement that you do – that you may reach with Iran if it is not submitted to Congress first.</p>
<p>And so, part – and so without getting into congressional correspondence, I’m just wondering if you can assure members of Congress now that you will be submitting any agreement that you get in Vienna to Congress for its approval. And then also very briefly, just to remind you of the first one, have the actual meetings with the U.S. team begun? Thanks.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Iran2"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hey Matt, I think I want to go back to your first question. I thought you asked initially had meetings with Special Envoy Malley started with the Europeans yet. And if that’s correct, I don’t have anything to share or read out at the moment.</p>
<p>But to your second question on Congress, I’d reiterate at the top what I shared on the – with one of the questions of your colleagues, which is that Special Envoy Malley continues to brief members of Congress even remotely. But what I’ll say more specifically is that the administration will carefully consider the facts as well as the circumstances of any U.S. return to the JCPOA to determine the legal implications, which would include under INARA. We’re committed to ensuring the requirements of INARA are satisfied.</p>
<p>And the President believes that a bipartisan approach to Iran is the strongest way to safeguard U.S. interests for the long term. And the administration officials have reached out at all levels to members of Congress as well as their staff to discuss our approach to Iran. Special Envoy Malley remains deeply committed to continued close engagement with Congress in a bipartisan manner as Iran policy continues to develop.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to the line of Luis Rojas.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. I have only one question today. Do you have any update on the possible retabulation of remittance to Cuba or on the sending of diplomatic personnel to the United States Embassy in Havana, please?</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Cuba"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Luis. To your second question, I don’t have any announcements or any updates to make about personnel issues, but I’d just reiterate what we have shared in the past to your first question, which was: following the July 2021 protest the administration created a remittance working group to explore options to facilitate remittances to Cuba that would go to maximally benefit the Cuban people, and that would also include by allowing Cuban families to support each other and also minimize or eliminate benefits to the Cuban regime and its military.</p>
<p>Also, in August of 2021, the remittance working group shared its analysis that includes potential options with other members of the administration, and the administration continues to consider these options and explore innovative solutions such as digital payment. Outside of that, we don’t have any specific timetables for a decision or any other updates to share, at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to the line of Will Mauldin.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks so much, Jalina. I just wanted to follow up on Conor’s question about the French diplomacy in Russia and Ukraine, and was wondering if Secretary Blinken – I know he’s traveling, but he has a pretty good telephone set on board – or any of the other senior members of the department, Under Secretary Nuland or Deputy Secretary Sherman, had been in touch with the French or were expected to, or other people in the administration. And if they – and what was the general view on that? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-UkraineFranceRussia2"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Will. I don’t have anything much else to add from what I shared with Conor in that we are – we continue to be in close consultation and coordination with our allies and partners, and we continue to be in alliance with them as well.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Jiha Ham, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, good afternoon. I have two questions for you today. Yesterday, VOA reported that a North Korean defector, who is a military officer, who is also known as a cryptocurrency expert, was arrested by Russia and now imprisoned in a North Korean consulate in Vladivostok. Some expect that he will be sent back to North Korea. Do you have any concerns that this may be another forced repatriation case that we have seen in China many times? Some human rights experts suggest that the State Department should ask Russia to free this person. So, what’s your position on this?</p>
<p>And my second question is about China’s remark yesterday at the Security Council. The Chinese ambassador said that there have been serious humanitarian consequences in North Korea and the import of humanitarian livelihood goods have been severely restricted because of the sanctions on North Korea. But in fact, there are many aid groups who have received sanctions exemptions, and quite many of them are ready to send those important items, but the problem is North Korea’s border closure. So, do you have any response or comment on this? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-HumanitarianSanctionsNorthKorea"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Jiha. I’ll start with your second question. The United States has led efforts to streamline the process for humanitarian sanctions exemptions at the UN and it has also committed to reviewing such applications as quickly as possible. We’ve also maintained broad exemptions and authorizations across many of the sanctions programs, including the DPRK program, aimed at ensuring that U.S. sanctions don’t hamper the transfer and delivery of humanitarian aid.</p>
<p>And to your first question, I would have to refer you to colleagues at the Department of Homeland Security.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Albert Hong, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>One more North Korean issue. North Korea’s Foreign Ministry said it had never committed a cyber crime. North Korea also accused the United States for cyber crime. What is the State Department&#8217;s position of that?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks for your question. While I haven&#8217;t seen those reports before your question, I would just say that U.S. diplomats work with countries around the world to promote the stability in cyberspace and also reduce the risk of conflict. They coordinate with partners and allies to call out and impose consequences on states that use cyber capabilities irresponsibly. They also implement programs to enhance the capacity of partner countries to implement effective cyber policies, respond to cyber threats, which would include cyber crime, and also participate in international conversations on cyber issues.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s take a final question from Anas Elsabbar.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yes, thank you, Jalina. My question regarding the designation of Houthis as a terrorist group. I don&#8217;t know if you have any update on this. And also, there were news about designating some Houthis’ top leaders and sanctioning them in the near future. I don&#8217;t know if you have any update on that as well.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you, Anas. I, actually, don&#8217;t have any updates on either to share at this time, but certainly happy to share them as soon as we do.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Afghanistan"></a> Now, before I close today’s briefing I just – I thought this might have come up, but since it didn&#8217;t, I just wanted to take a moment to address something very specific that has been in our news cycle. Following the Secretary’s hearing in Congress last week on Afghanistan, there has been renewed reflection on events from last year as well as interest in our Afghan relocation efforts.</p>
<p>There was a media report today recounting internal discussions and deliberations from a Department of Defense internal report related to the end of the U.S. war in Afghanistan from last summer. Cherry-picked comments do not reflect the months of work that were already underway or the whole picture of what the U.S. diplomats undertook to facilitate the evacuation and relocation of U.S. citizens, lawful permanent residents, and allies – Afghan allies from Afghanistan. Some of the claims allegedly included in the report regarding State Department personnel and plans are outright false and shamefully so.</p>
<p>I also want to take a moment to acknowledge the career Foreign Service officers who were in Afghanistan, who demonstrated immense bravery, professionalism, and dedication to doing the mission during extraordinarily difficult circumstances. They put their lives at risk, standing shoulder to shoulder with our armed forces at gates to the airport, and in the end helping 124,000 Americans, foreigners, Afghan allies and their families leave Kabul.</p>
<p>Of course, this mission continues today. Many of these courageous colleagues have volunteered to be part of the team at State Department leading our ongoing Afghan relocation efforts. And this Department is proud of their service and their sacrifice, and I am personally honored to serve with them.</p>
<p>That ends today’s press briefing. I hope you have a wonderful day, and we’ll see you back here tomorrow.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:29 p.m.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Promoting Sustainable Peace and Responsive Governance in Somalia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/promoting-sustainable-peace-and-responsive-governance-in-somalia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 21:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The best path toward sustainable peace in Somalia is through the rapid conclusion of credible elections. The United States has repeatedly expressed concern over the delays and procedural irregularities in Somalia’s electoral process and the broader implications of those irregularities for the country’s democracy and stability.</p>
<p>Today, on the one-year anniversary of the expiration of the Somali president’s term in office, I am announcing the implementation of a policy under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act that restricts the issuance of visas to current or former Somali officials or other individuals who are believed to be responsible for, or complicit in, undermining the democratic process in Somalia, including through violence against protestors, unjust arrests or intimidation of journalists and opposition members, and manipulation of the electoral process. Immediate family members of such persons may also be subject to these restrictions.</p>
<p>This policy will apply to individuals who have played a role in procedural irregularities that have undermined the electoral process, who have failed to follow through with their obligations to implement timely and transparent elections, and who have targeted journalists and opposition party members with harassment, intimidation, arrest, and violence.</p>
<p>Somalia’s national and federal member state leaders must follow through on their commitments to complete the parliamentary process in a credible and transparent manner by February 25, which will further lay the groundwork for responsive governance in Somalia. The United States strongly supports the Somali people, and we are committed to working together to advance democracy and mutual prosperity for both of our countries.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The best path toward sustainable peace in Somalia is through the rapid conclusion of credible elections. The United States has repeatedly expressed concern over the delays and procedural irregularities in Somalia’s electoral process and the broader implications of those irregularities for the country’s democracy and stability.</p>
<p>Today, on the one-year anniversary of the expiration of the Somali president’s term in office, I am announcing the implementation of a policy under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act that restricts the issuance of visas to current or former Somali officials or other individuals who are believed to be responsible for, or complicit in, undermining the democratic process in Somalia, including through violence against protestors, unjust arrests or intimidation of journalists and opposition members, and manipulation of the electoral process. Immediate family members of such persons may also be subject to these restrictions.</p>
<p>This policy will apply to individuals who have played a role in procedural irregularities that have undermined the electoral process, who have failed to follow through with their obligations to implement timely and transparent elections, and who have targeted journalists and opposition party members with harassment, intimidation, arrest, and violence.</p>
<p>Somalia’s national and federal member state leaders must follow through on their commitments to complete the parliamentary process in a credible and transparent manner by February 25, which will further lay the groundwork for responsive governance in Somalia. The United States strongly supports the Somali people, and we are committed to working together to advance democracy and mutual prosperity for both of our countries.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States Releases Updated List of Critical and Emerging Technologies</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-releases-updated-list-of-critical-and-emerging-technologies/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 20:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312490</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The White House has released an updated list of Critical and Emerging Technologies (“CET List”), which will serve to inform a forthcoming strategy on U.S. technological competitiveness and national security.</p>
<p>Critical and emerging technologies (CETs) are a subset of advanced technologies that are potentially significant to U.S. national security. The 2021 Interim National Security Strategic Guidance defines three national security objectives: protect the security of the American people, expand economic prosperity and opportunity, and realize and defend democratic values. This list identifies CETs with the potential to further these objectives and builds on the October 2020 National Strategy for Critical and Emerging Technologies, which contains an initial list of priority CETs.</p>
<p>The U.S. Government, the private sector, and allies and partners must understand and remain focused on developing and deploying the technologies that are most critical to our national security, economic prosperity, and to realizing and defending our democratic values. In addition, our joint leadership in CETs faces growing challenges from strategic competitors and adversaries who recognize the benefits of CET and are organizing human and capital resources on a national scale to challenge our lead in areas with long-term consequences.</p>
<p>In response to these challenges, the United States remains unwaveringly committed to advancing technology leadership with our allies and partners to protect our shared security interests, economic prosperity, and democratic values.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The White House has released an updated list of Critical and Emerging Technologies (“CET List”), which will serve to inform a forthcoming strategy on U.S. technological competitiveness and national security.</p>
<p>Critical and emerging technologies (CETs) are a subset of advanced technologies that are potentially significant to U.S. national security. The 2021 Interim National Security Strategic Guidance defines three national security objectives: protect the security of the American people, expand economic prosperity and opportunity, and realize and defend democratic values. This list identifies CETs with the potential to further these objectives and builds on the October 2020 National Strategy for Critical and Emerging Technologies, which contains an initial list of priority CETs.</p>
<p>The U.S. Government, the private sector, and allies and partners must understand and remain focused on developing and deploying the technologies that are most critical to our national security, economic prosperity, and to realizing and defending our democratic values. In addition, our joint leadership in CETs faces growing challenges from strategic competitors and adversaries who recognize the benefits of CET and are organizing human and capital resources on a national scale to challenge our lead in areas with long-term consequences.</p>
<p>In response to these challenges, the United States remains unwaveringly committed to advancing technology leadership with our allies and partners to protect our shared security interests, economic prosperity, and democratic values.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Turkish Foreign Minister Cavusoglu</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-turkish-foreign-minister-cavusoglu-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 18:21:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312409</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Turkish Foreign Minister Mevlut Cavusoglu. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Cavusoglu discussed ways to further coordination and NATO unity regarding the threat of further Russian escalation and aggression against Ukraine. The Secretary emphasized our shared commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and noted President Erdogan’s engagement in support of a diplomatic resolution. The leaders discussed Turkey-Armenia normalization and additional steps the United States could take to support these efforts. They also reviewed opportunities to maintain a robust U.S.-Turkey bilateral relationship.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Turkish Foreign Minister Mevlut Cavusoglu. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Cavusoglu discussed ways to further coordination and NATO unity regarding the threat of further Russian escalation and aggression against Ukraine. The Secretary emphasized our shared commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and noted President Erdogan’s engagement in support of a diplomatic resolution. The leaders discussed Turkey-Armenia normalization and additional steps the United States could take to support these efforts. They also reviewed opportunities to maintain a robust U.S.-Turkey bilateral relationship.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with African Union Commission Chairperson Faki</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-african-union-commission-chairperson-faki-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 17:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312387</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with African Union Commission Chairperson Moussa Faki Mahamat. They discussed possible ways forward on political and security matters in Africa, including Sudan, Mali, and Burkina Faso and the need to bolster democracy on the continent. Secretary Blinken reaffirmed U.S. prioritization of our important partnership with the AU, particularly in initiatives to strengthen democratic institutions in furtherance of peace and security resulting from the recent 2022 AU Heads of State Summit on February 5-6.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with African Union Commission Chairperson Moussa Faki Mahamat. They discussed possible ways forward on political and security matters in Africa, including Sudan, Mali, and Burkina Faso and the need to bolster democracy on the continent. Secretary Blinken reaffirmed U.S. prioritization of our important partnership with the AU, particularly in initiatives to strengthen democratic institutions in furtherance of peace and security resulting from the recent 2022 AU Heads of State Summit on February 5-6.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Media Freedom Coalition Statement on Closure of Media Outlets in Hong Kong</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/media-freedom-coalition-statement-on-closure-of-media-outlets-in-hong-kong/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 17:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312384</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The undersigned members of the Media Freedom Coalition express their deep concern at the Hong Kong and mainland Chinese authorities’ attacks on freedom of the press and their suppression of independent local media in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Recent developments include the raid of Stand News offices, the arrests of its staff, and the subsequent self-closure of Citizen News, stemming from concern over the safety of its staff. Since the enactment of the National Security Law in June 2020, authorities have targeted and suppressed independent media in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. This has eroded the protected rights and freedoms set out in the Basic Law and undermines China’s obligations under the Sino-British Joint Declaration. This has also caused the near-complete disappearance of local independent media outlets in Hong Kong. These ongoing actions further undermine confidence in Hong Kong’s international reputation through the suppression of human rights, freedom of speech and free flow and exchange of opinions and information.</p>
<p>A stable and prosperous Hong Kong in which human rights and fundamental freedoms are protected should be in everybody’s interest. We urge Hong Kong and mainland Chinese authorities to respect freedom of the press and freedom of speech in Hong Kong, in line with the Basic Law and China’s obligations under the Sino-British Joint Declaration.</p>
<p><em>Signed by the Governments of Australia, Austria, Canada, Czech Republic, Estonia, Finland, Germany, Iceland, Ireland, Italy, Japan, Latvia, Lithuania, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, New Zealand, Slovakia, Slovenia, Switzerland, the United Kingdom, the United States.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The undersigned members of the Media Freedom Coalition express their deep concern at the Hong Kong and mainland Chinese authorities’ attacks on freedom of the press and their suppression of independent local media in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Recent developments include the raid of Stand News offices, the arrests of its staff, and the subsequent self-closure of Citizen News, stemming from concern over the safety of its staff. Since the enactment of the National Security Law in June 2020, authorities have targeted and suppressed independent media in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. This has eroded the protected rights and freedoms set out in the Basic Law and undermines China’s obligations under the Sino-British Joint Declaration. This has also caused the near-complete disappearance of local independent media outlets in Hong Kong. These ongoing actions further undermine confidence in Hong Kong’s international reputation through the suppression of human rights, freedom of speech and free flow and exchange of opinions and information.</p>
<p>A stable and prosperous Hong Kong in which human rights and fundamental freedoms are protected should be in everybody’s interest. We urge Hong Kong and mainland Chinese authorities to respect freedom of the press and freedom of speech in Hong Kong, in line with the Basic Law and China’s obligations under the Sino-British Joint Declaration.</p>
<p><em>Signed by the Governments of Australia, Austria, Canada, Czech Republic, Estonia, Finland, Germany, Iceland, Ireland, Italy, Japan, Latvia, Lithuania, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, New Zealand, Slovakia, Slovenia, Switzerland, the United Kingdom, the United States.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
