<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 21:46:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken At a Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-press-availability-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 21:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319908</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Press Briefing Room</p>
<p align="left"><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon.</p>
<p>Today is the seventh day of President Putin’s full-scale war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>The assault continues by land, by air, by sea.</p>
<p>And as I noted in my remarks to the UN Human Rights Council just yesterday, Russian strikes are hitting schools, hospitals, residences.</p>
<p>They’re destroying critical infrastructure which supplies millions of people across Ukraine with drinking water, with electricity, with gas to keep from freezing to death.</p>
<p>Buses, cars, ambulances being shelled.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Russian strikes in Kyiv struck the capital’s main television and radio tower and destroyed part of the Babin Yar Holocaust Memorial.</p>
<p>Apartment buildings outside of Kyiv were hit, partially collapsed.</p>
<p>A huge explosion occurred in the main square of Kharkiv, Ukraine’s second-largest city.</p>
<p>These aren’t military targets; they are places where civilians work and families live.</p>
<p>Kharkiv is one of the largest Russian-speaking cities in Europe.</p>
<p>It’s fewer than 50 miles from Belgorod, its sister city in Russia.</p>
<p>And Belgorod is where the missiles against Kharkiv were likely fired.</p>
<p>President Putin, among the many false justifications he’s given for invading Ukraine, has cited the need to protect against an imaginary threat to Russian ethnic and Russian-speaking peoples.</p>
<p>How is assaulting and bombing the population of Kharkiv – again, one of the largest Russian-speaking cities in Europe – advancing that purported goal?</p>
<p>As President Zelenskyy said after the assault, there was never a border between Kharkiv and its Russian sister city.  The two cities are joined in the hearts of the Ukrainian and the Russian people living on either side.</p>
<p>Among the great damage we see from war, we’re seeing that in Kharkiv.  We’ve also seen that the International Court of Justice has announced that it will hold hearings on Russia’s actions.</p>
<p>Already, the human costs of the Kremlin’s unwarranted, unprovoked, and unjustified war on Ukraine are staggering.</p>
<p>Hundreds, if not thousands, of civilians have been killed and wounded.</p>
<p>There are now more than 174,000 refugees who have sought safety in nearby countries.</p>
<p>Millions of Ukrainians still in Ukraine are sheltering wherever they can – including children receiving cancer treatment who are now living in the basements of Ukraine’s children’s hospitals, with doctors and nurses doing their best to care for them as explosions boom overhead.</p>
<p>This is shameful.</p>
<p>The numbers of civilians killed and wounded, the humanitarian consequences, will only grow in the days ahead.</p>
<p>In the face of this violence, the courage of the Ukrainian people is inspiring the world.</p>
<p>As President Biden said in his State of the Union address last night, the response to Russia’s war has been unity – unity among world leaders, unity in Europe, unity among people gathering around the world to protest President Putin’s war of choice, including thousands of people in Russia and Belarus coming out to protest peacefully even though they know what they risk in so doing.</p>
<p>Because the Biden administration dedicated its first year to repairing and rebuilding our alliances and partnerships in Europe and around the world, and because we spent the better part of the past several months raising alarms about looming Russian aggression, declassifying and sharing our intelligence nearly in real time, and relentlessly exposing President Putin’s lies, we were ready.</p>
<p>In fact, one reason why we’re seeing the unified response now is because we made the decision late last year to publicize to the world what we knew was underway and the playbook we were convinced Russia would follow.</p>
<p>I went to the UN Security Council two weeks ago to walk through, step by step, the pretexts for war that we were sure President Putin would invent and the subsequent military invasion that he’d planned to order.</p>
<p>And that’s precisely what he did – while Russian officials continued to deny it right until the invasion began.</p>
<p>Seeing that duplicity and premeditated aggression play out exactly as we predicted has generated outrage and solidarity across Europe and around the world.</p>
<p>And that’s turned into unprecedented action.</p>
<p>We said that if the Kremlin ordered an invasion, we would help Ukraine defend itself while imposing costs on Russia.</p>
<p>Last week, the President approved $350 million in military assistance to Ukraine to help with the armored, airborne, and other significant threats it now faces.</p>
<p>That brings our total security assistance to Ukraine in the past year to more than $1 billion – more than in any previous year.</p>
<p>Over the past several days, I authorized the expedited transfer of U.S.-origin defensive equipment from allies to Ukraine, and we are coordinating efforts to get this equipment – including anti-tank and anti-aircraft weaponry, as well as small arms and munitions – into the hands of Ukrainian fighters, who are defending their country with skill and determination.</p>
<p>We’re sending humanitarian assistance to the people of Ukraine as well.</p>
<p>Three days ago, we announced nearly $54 million in additional support, on top of the more than $300 million we’ve provided in recent years.</p>
<p>USAID has deployed a Disaster Assistance Response Team, our top international emergency responders, to lead the U.S. humanitarian response in coordination with European allies, partners, and international organizations.  And USAID Director Samantha Power was, as you know, just in Poland along the border with Ukraine a few days ago, along with other senior officials from the State Department.</p>
<p>And we’re working to support the frontline countries – including Poland, Moldova, Romania, Hungary, and Slovakia – that have welcomed hundreds of thousands of refugees, including many children, elderly people, people with disabilities, all of whom are fleeing Ukraine to escape Russia’s violence and facing harrowing journeys to reach safety.</p>
<p>We and our allies and partners will work to keep people safe, manage the flow of refugees, keep border crossings open, and provide critical supplies.</p>
<p>At the same time, we’re holding Russia accountable, including Russia’s economy.</p>
<p>Back on December 1st, I said that Russia would face massive consequences for attacking Ukraine, including severe and lasting economic costs.</p>
<p>The United States and more than 30 allies and partners, representing more than half the world’s economy, have made good on that commitment with powerful sanctions and export controls on Russia, including additional actions just today.</p>
<p>We’ve now sanctioned most of Russia’s largest financial institutions and its sovereign wealth fund.</p>
<p>The European Union removed key sanctioned Russian banks from the SWIFT international payments network.</p>
<p>We’ve restricted Russia’s ability to seek funding beyond its borders.</p>
<p>Thirteen of the most critical Russian state-owned enterprises, including Gazprom, are now extremely limited in raising money through the U.S. market.</p>
<p>We’ve imposed sanctions on individuals, including President Putin, other members of Russia’s security council, and elites and their family members.</p>
<p>And we and our allies and partners are launching a task force to identify, track down, and freeze the assets of sanctioned Russian companies and oligarchs.</p>
<p>We will freeze and seize their yachts, their private jets, their opulent estates in world capitals.</p>
<p>Today, we’re also imposing sweeping sanctions on Russia’s defense sector.</p>
<p>In total, 22 Russian defense-related entities will be designated, including companies that make combat aircraft, infantry fighting vehicles, missiles, unmanned aerial vehicles, electronic warfare systems – the very systems now being used to assault the Ukrainian people, abuse human rights, violate international humanitarian law.</p>
<p>We’re also imposing export controls on Belarus to hold the Lukashenka regime accountable for being a co-belligerent in President Putin’s war of choice.</p>
<p>We will choke off Belarus’s ability to import key technologies.</p>
<p>And if Lukashenka’s support for the war continues, the consequences for his regime will escalate.</p>
<p>All told, these sanctions and restrictions have had a powerful effect on Russia’s economy.</p>
<p>The value of the ruble has plummeted; the Russian stock market closed at – as fear of capital flight rose; interest rates more than doubled; Russia’s credit rating has been cut to junk status.</p>
<p>The value of President Putin’s “war fund” has vanished.</p>
<p>And by choking Russia’s access to technology, we’re delivering a blow to its economy and military that will be felt not just now, but for years to come.</p>
<p>President Putin may have assumed that the United States and our allies were bluffing when we warned of massive, unprecedented consequences.</p>
<p>But – as President Biden likes to say – big nations can’t bluff.</p>
<p>The United States doesn’t bluff.</p>
<p>And President Putin has gravely miscalculated.</p>
<p>As President Biden made clear last night, this is President Putin’s war.</p>
<p>This isn’t the Russian people’s war.</p>
<p>It’s becoming clearer by the day that the Russian people oppose it.</p>
<p>Members of the Russian military oppose it and had no idea what they were being sent to do.</p>
<p>And now the Russian people will suffer the consequences of their leaders’ choices.</p>
<p>So my message to the people of Russia – if they’re even able to hear it, as the Kremlin cracks down even harder on media outlets reporting the truth – my message is that we know many of you want no part of this war.</p>
<p>You, like Ukrainians, like Americans, like people everywhere, want the same basic things – good jobs, clean air and water, the chance to raise your kids in safe neighborhoods, to send them to good schools, to give them better lives than you had.</p>
<p>How in the world does President Putin’s unprovoked aggression against Ukraine help you achieve any of these things?</p>
<p>How is it going to make your lives better?</p>
<p>The economic costs that we’ve been forced to impose on Russia are not aimed at you – they are aimed at compelling your government to stop its actions, to stop its aggression.</p>
<p>And just as millions of us around the world stand together against Moscow’s aggression, we also stand together with you as you demand that your leaders end this war.</p>
<p>If President Putin wants to demonstrate leadership, he should allow Russian soldiers to go home to their families.</p>
<p>Finally, the United States is continuing our diplomatic efforts.</p>
<p>We’re keeping the door open to a diplomatic way forward.  That’s going to be very hard to happen without military de-escalation.  It’s much more difficult for diplomacy to succeed when guns are firing, tanks are rolling, planes are flying.  But if Russia pulls back and pursues diplomacy, we stand ready to do the same thing.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, our intensive diplomacy with allies and partners continues.  I’ve been in virtually daily contact with my friend and counterpart, Ukraine’s Foreign Minister Kuleba, and I’ve made clear that we’ll support any diplomatic efforts by the Ukrainian Government to reach a ceasefire and withdrawal of Russian forces.  If there are diplomatic steps that we can take that the Ukrainian Government believes would be helpful, we’re prepared to take them – even as we continue to support Ukraine’s ability to defend itself.</p>
<p>Tomorrow, I’ll travel to Brussels, where I’ll meet with our NATO, European Union, and G7 allies and partners to continue our coordination; to commend them on the unprecedented steps that they’ve taken to support Ukraine and hold Russia to account; and to reaffirm our Article 5 commitment that an attack on any NATO member is an attack on all.  From there, I’ll travel to Poland, which is already hosting hundreds of thousands of Ukrainian refugees, with tens of thousands arriving by the day; and then to Moldova, which is also hosting Ukrainian refugees, and where Russian troops have been occupying territory against the will of the people for years.</p>
<p>And then I’ll go on to the Baltic countries – to Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia – which are facing a renewed threat from Russia themselves, as President Putin seeks to reassert Russia’s dominance over former Soviet republics.  Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia are our NATO Allies, and as President Biden has said, we will defend every inch of NATO territory against any aggression from Russia or otherwise.</p>
<p>Finally, I want to note the consequential and historic vote that just took place in the United Nations.  A hundred and forty-one member states voted in favor of a resolution reaffirming Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and condemning Russia’s invasion of another member state.  As this vote revealed, the overwhelming majority of the international community stands in strong support of the core principles of the United Nations and upholding the UN Charter – and stands against Russia’s reckless attempts to change the borders of another sovereign country by force, to replace its will for the will of the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p>As 141 member states of the United Nations know, more is at stake, even, than the conflict in Ukraine itself and the freedom and security of Ukraine and its people.  This is a threat to stability in Europe, and to the entire rules-based order, which has been the foundation of security and prosperity for people around the world for nearly 80 years.</p>
<p>In this time of uncertainty, we have a clear way forward: help Ukraine defend itself.  Support the Ukrainian people.  Hold Russia accountable.  And persist with diplomacy.</p>
<p>President Putin is more isolated from the world than ever before.  As President Biden predicted last night, when the history of this era is written, Russia’s war on Ukraine will have left Russia weaker and the rest of the world stronger.  And in the days ahead, we will continue to draw inspiration from the iron will of the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p>With that, happy to take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Humeyra.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello, Mr. Secretary.  Thanks for being here.  I just want to ask you, what is the U.S. assessment on Putin’s state of mind?  You said that he’s more isolated than before.  Do you worry that this isolation might prompt him to lash out and do something even more dramatic than we’ve so far seen on the ground?</p>
<p>And I also want to ask you:  I’m sure you’ve seen that there are Americans who have expressed their desire to go and join the fight in Ukraine.  What is your message to them?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks.  I can’t put myself in President Putin’s mind or state of mind.  All that we can focus on are the actions that he’s taking and our response to those actions.  I’ve said before, one of the Achilles’ heels of autocracies is the inability to speak truth to power.  I don’t know who said what to President Putin before he launched this aggression.  I don’t know who’s saying what to him now.  But again, all of that is speculation.  We can’t put ourselves in his mindset.  All we can do is what we’re doing, which is to be very clear in how we’ll respond to the actions that he takes; to continue to work in unity with allies and partners in support of Ukraine, in defense of Ukraine; to help its people; to help those who have been forced to flee; and if there are any diplomatic opportunities to pursue, to pursue those.  But we’re focused less on what President Putin thinks or may think and more on what he does.</p>
<p>And with regard to the second part of your question, look, we’ve been very clear for some time, of course, in calling on Americans who may be – may have been resident in Ukraine to leave, and making clear to Americans who may be thinking of traveling there not to go.  For those who want to help Ukraine and help its people, there are many ways to do that, including by supporting and helping the many NGOs that are working to provide humanitarian assistance; providing resources themselves to groups that are trying to help Ukraine by being advocates for Ukraine and for peaceful resolution to this crisis that was created by Russia.  Those are the most effective ways that people who want to help can do so.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, you just quoted the President as saying big nations don’t bluff.  Do you think that President Putin is bluffing by putting his nuclear forces on alert?  And I have another question, if you don’t mind.</p>
<p>Are you surprised that we have not seen more – we’ve seen some denial of services, but are you surprised that we have not seen a more massive cyber attack against Ukraine or against other of the NATO nations or against us?  Do you think that the legislation that just passed improves our ability to defend against such attacks?</p>
<p>And if I could impose on you one more question.  I talked today to Daria Kaleniuk, who was part of the President and your democracy summit this year, and you know how passionate she is.  Perhaps you saw her questioning.  And she says that despite everything that has been done, and I would – I would say it’s an extraordinary amount of coordination and agreement with the allies, it’s not going to get there in time.  That convoy is sitting outside Kyiv and poised to encircle Kyiv, and they’re not going to get those supplies.  What more can be done to help those people?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Andrea, thank you.  Let me take them in not quite reverse order.  First, just on the cyber piece, two things.  First, yes, the legislation that you referred is extremely helpful.  But beyond that, and before that, we have been very focused on the potential for cyber attacks not only against Ukraine but against us, against allies and partners.  We’ve been working for months first with Ukraine and also among ourselves to harden, to sharpen defenses.  All of that work is very much underway, including with the private sector.  And so I think we have to be very much on guard about that possibility.  We are.</p>
<p>With regard to assistance to Ukraine, here’s what I can – here’s what I can tell you.  We are very actively working every day, every hour, to provide that assistance and to make sure that, to the best of our ability, it gets to where it needs to go.  And this is not just us; this is many countries in Europe.  We’re coordinating a lot of efforts to do that.  And my own assessment right now is that the vitally needed assistance is getting to where it needs to go.</p>
<p>With regard to President Putin’s statements on Russia’s nuclear posture, first, as you know, Russia and the United States have long agreed that the actual use of nuclear weapons would be devastating and have devastating consequences for the entire world.  And as we’ve stated many times, including earlier this year following the meeting between President Biden and President Putin in Geneva, both of our countries have stated that a nuclear war cannot be won and must never be fought.  That was a key reaffirmation coming out of the meeting between President Biden and President Putin back in June.</p>
<p>Provocative rhetoric about nuclear weapons is the height of irresponsibility.  It’s dangerous.  It adds to the risk of miscalculation.  It needs to be avoided.  We’ve assessed President Putin’s directive and his statements, and at this time we see no reason to change our own alert levels.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, thank you.  You mentioned the vote in the UN, which was by – it was overwhelming, as you said.  And the countries that voted against, the five countries who voted against, no surprise: Belarus, Eritrea, North Korea, Syria, and Russia.  But I’m wondering if you have any thoughts about the abstentions, particularly from Latin America: Cuba, Nicaragua, Venezuela, who stayed out.  These are countries that are no stranger to larger powers, who might – shall go unnamed, getting involved in their internal politics.  And I’m wondering if that says anything to you.</p>
<p>And then secondly, on the prospects for diplomacy with Russia, which you said you’re keeping the door open to, I mean, really, what are the prospects for – what are the chances of that happening?  And are – and is there – if there is an open door, is it just for Ukraine and potentially the Iran talks in Vienna?  Or are you open to the whole gamut of things – arms control, climate, all – any number of other things?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Matt, first of all, to put the vote in the UN in perspective, it is both overwhelming and, I would even say, historic.  Go back to 2014, when the General Assembly pronounced itself on Russia’s initial aggression against Ukraine.  The votes in favor of that resolution were 100.  Then go to the horrific actions that the Assad regime took in Aleppo.  The vote there was 120 in favor of a resolution condemning the actions of the Assad regime.  Today 141 votes.  That speaks powerfully and eloquently about the overwhelming majority of the world and its views about what Russia is doing in Ukraine.</p>
<p>I’m not going to parse the individual votes.  I think in some cases an abstention actually speaks loudly itself as opposed to a no vote, so I think you have to look at some of the individual countries, assess their relationship with Russia, and look at how they voted in that context.  For the small number that voted against – Belarus, the DPRK, Eritrea, Syria, as well as, of course, Russia – as Groucho Marx once sort of said, this is not very much a club that I would want to be a member of.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Olga Koshelenko.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Oh, wait, sorry, on the prospects for diplomacy.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Oh, I’m sorry, yes.  Look, as I said a moment ago, with regard to Ukraine itself, we of course remain open to pursuing any reasonable path, but it’s very hard to see any path when the bombs are dropping, the planes are flying, the tanks are rolling.  So de-escalation, pulling back forces – that would open a path to diplomacy, and we I think demonstrated very clearly in the months leading up to Russia’s aggression that we were prepared to engage Russia diplomatically on any legitimate security concerns on a reciprocal basis that remains.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, tragically, horrifically, I think we’ve seen – and you don’t have to take my word for it; just listen to President Putin’s own words – that virtually everything the Russian Government professed to be concerned about was not really what was at issue – for example, Ukraine joining NATO.  What President Putin has said loudly and clearly and has now demonstrated by the actions that Russia has taken is that what this is about for him is Ukraine being absorbed in one fashion or another into Russia.  He sees Ukraine as having no independent existence.  He wants to reincorporate it into an empire; short of that, to make it part of a renewed sphere of influence or maybe, at the very least, to make it totally neutral.  So this is about way more than the issues that we were prepared to engage Russia on.</p>
<p>So two quick pieces on the diplomacy now.  One, with regard to Ukraine itself, first and foremost, the question is if Ukraine thinks there is a path that would help advance its interests, protect it, end the war, and we can be helpful in that, of course.  We’re fully prepared to do that.  But we really look to the Ukrainian Government to see what, if anything, might make sense.  They’re engaged in talks with Russia.  They had one round.  There may be another one; we’ll see.  But, of course, the demands that Russia put on the table were beyond excessive.  They were, of course, non-starters, and what we’ve seen repeatedly is that Russia goes through the pretense of diplomacy to distract and continue on its aggressive path.</p>
<p>More broadly, even as we’ve imposed and continue to impose massive costs on Russia for its aggression and actions in Ukraine, if we determine that there are areas that it’s in our interest to continue to pursue and that in one fashion or another may involve some engagement from Russia, we’ll continue to pursue that.  We’re not going to let Russia dictate in any way what’s in our interests and how to pursue them.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Time for a final question from Olga Koshelenko.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Inaudible) Media, Ukraine.  Just a few days ago European Union proposed to donate their fighter jets to Ukraine to protect our sky, but as far as I know, for now this deal has fallen apart.  I know that you were on a phone call with Foreign Minister Kuleba today discussing this topic as well.  Could one expect that after your travel to Europe, something could change and Ukraine will get access to those jets?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  I can’t comment in detail on my conversations with Foreign Minister Kuleba.  We talked about a lot of things, including the ongoing provision of security assistance to Ukraine, and that is something that I will be talking to European allies and partners about in a couple of days in Brussels.  Again, I can tell you, as I mentioned in response to Andrea’s question, that when it comes to vital defensive military equipment that Ukraine needs, we are very actively coordinating its provision, and that assistance is getting there.  But we’ll probably have more to say in the next couple of days.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Can I follow up?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, everyone.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you very much.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Just one very quick one.  Sir, do you think that Russia is deliberately targeting civilians?  You said they’re hitting schools and hospitals.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Mm-hmm.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  They’re – are they doing it deliberately?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We have certainly seen in the past that one of Russia’s methods of war is to be absolutely brutal in trying to cow the citizenry of a given country, and that includes at the very least indiscriminate targeting and potentially deliberate targeting as well.  We’re looking very closely at what’s happening in Ukraine right now, including what’s happening to civilians.  We’re taking account of it.  We’re documenting it.  And we want to ensure, among other things, that there’s accountability for it.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you all.  Thank you all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Press Briefing Room</p>
<p align="left"><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon.</p>
<p>Today is the seventh day of President Putin’s full-scale war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>The assault continues by land, by air, by sea.</p>
<p>And as I noted in my remarks to the UN Human Rights Council just yesterday, Russian strikes are hitting schools, hospitals, residences.</p>
<p>They’re destroying critical infrastructure which supplies millions of people across Ukraine with drinking water, with electricity, with gas to keep from freezing to death.</p>
<p>Buses, cars, ambulances being shelled.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Russian strikes in Kyiv struck the capital’s main television and radio tower and destroyed part of the Babin Yar Holocaust Memorial.</p>
<p>Apartment buildings outside of Kyiv were hit, partially collapsed.</p>
<p>A huge explosion occurred in the main square of Kharkiv, Ukraine’s second-largest city.</p>
<p>These aren’t military targets; they are places where civilians work and families live.</p>
<p>Kharkiv is one of the largest Russian-speaking cities in Europe.</p>
<p>It’s fewer than 50 miles from Belgorod, its sister city in Russia.</p>
<p>And Belgorod is where the missiles against Kharkiv were likely fired.</p>
<p>President Putin, among the many false justifications he’s given for invading Ukraine, has cited the need to protect against an imaginary threat to Russian ethnic and Russian-speaking peoples.</p>
<p>How is assaulting and bombing the population of Kharkiv – again, one of the largest Russian-speaking cities in Europe – advancing that purported goal?</p>
<p>As President Zelenskyy said after the assault, there was never a border between Kharkiv and its Russian sister city.  The two cities are joined in the hearts of the Ukrainian and the Russian people living on either side.</p>
<p>Among the great damage we see from war, we’re seeing that in Kharkiv.  We’ve also seen that the International Court of Justice has announced that it will hold hearings on Russia’s actions.</p>
<p>Already, the human costs of the Kremlin’s unwarranted, unprovoked, and unjustified war on Ukraine are staggering.</p>
<p>Hundreds, if not thousands, of civilians have been killed and wounded.</p>
<p>There are now more than 174,000 refugees who have sought safety in nearby countries.</p>
<p>Millions of Ukrainians still in Ukraine are sheltering wherever they can – including children receiving cancer treatment who are now living in the basements of Ukraine’s children’s hospitals, with doctors and nurses doing their best to care for them as explosions boom overhead.</p>
<p>This is shameful.</p>
<p>The numbers of civilians killed and wounded, the humanitarian consequences, will only grow in the days ahead.</p>
<p>In the face of this violence, the courage of the Ukrainian people is inspiring the world.</p>
<p>As President Biden said in his State of the Union address last night, the response to Russia’s war has been unity – unity among world leaders, unity in Europe, unity among people gathering around the world to protest President Putin’s war of choice, including thousands of people in Russia and Belarus coming out to protest peacefully even though they know what they risk in so doing.</p>
<p>Because the Biden administration dedicated its first year to repairing and rebuilding our alliances and partnerships in Europe and around the world, and because we spent the better part of the past several months raising alarms about looming Russian aggression, declassifying and sharing our intelligence nearly in real time, and relentlessly exposing President Putin’s lies, we were ready.</p>
<p>In fact, one reason why we’re seeing the unified response now is because we made the decision late last year to publicize to the world what we knew was underway and the playbook we were convinced Russia would follow.</p>
<p>I went to the UN Security Council two weeks ago to walk through, step by step, the pretexts for war that we were sure President Putin would invent and the subsequent military invasion that he’d planned to order.</p>
<p>And that’s precisely what he did – while Russian officials continued to deny it right until the invasion began.</p>
<p>Seeing that duplicity and premeditated aggression play out exactly as we predicted has generated outrage and solidarity across Europe and around the world.</p>
<p>And that’s turned into unprecedented action.</p>
<p>We said that if the Kremlin ordered an invasion, we would help Ukraine defend itself while imposing costs on Russia.</p>
<p>Last week, the President approved $350 million in military assistance to Ukraine to help with the armored, airborne, and other significant threats it now faces.</p>
<p>That brings our total security assistance to Ukraine in the past year to more than $1 billion – more than in any previous year.</p>
<p>Over the past several days, I authorized the expedited transfer of U.S.-origin defensive equipment from allies to Ukraine, and we are coordinating efforts to get this equipment – including anti-tank and anti-aircraft weaponry, as well as small arms and munitions – into the hands of Ukrainian fighters, who are defending their country with skill and determination.</p>
<p>We’re sending humanitarian assistance to the people of Ukraine as well.</p>
<p>Three days ago, we announced nearly $54 million in additional support, on top of the more than $300 million we’ve provided in recent years.</p>
<p>USAID has deployed a Disaster Assistance Response Team, our top international emergency responders, to lead the U.S. humanitarian response in coordination with European allies, partners, and international organizations.  And USAID Director Samantha Power was, as you know, just in Poland along the border with Ukraine a few days ago, along with other senior officials from the State Department.</p>
<p>And we’re working to support the frontline countries – including Poland, Moldova, Romania, Hungary, and Slovakia – that have welcomed hundreds of thousands of refugees, including many children, elderly people, people with disabilities, all of whom are fleeing Ukraine to escape Russia’s violence and facing harrowing journeys to reach safety.</p>
<p>We and our allies and partners will work to keep people safe, manage the flow of refugees, keep border crossings open, and provide critical supplies.</p>
<p>At the same time, we’re holding Russia accountable, including Russia’s economy.</p>
<p>Back on December 1st, I said that Russia would face massive consequences for attacking Ukraine, including severe and lasting economic costs.</p>
<p>The United States and more than 30 allies and partners, representing more than half the world’s economy, have made good on that commitment with powerful sanctions and export controls on Russia, including additional actions just today.</p>
<p>We’ve now sanctioned most of Russia’s largest financial institutions and its sovereign wealth fund.</p>
<p>The European Union removed key sanctioned Russian banks from the SWIFT international payments network.</p>
<p>We’ve restricted Russia’s ability to seek funding beyond its borders.</p>
<p>Thirteen of the most critical Russian state-owned enterprises, including Gazprom, are now extremely limited in raising money through the U.S. market.</p>
<p>We’ve imposed sanctions on individuals, including President Putin, other members of Russia’s security council, and elites and their family members.</p>
<p>And we and our allies and partners are launching a task force to identify, track down, and freeze the assets of sanctioned Russian companies and oligarchs.</p>
<p>We will freeze and seize their yachts, their private jets, their opulent estates in world capitals.</p>
<p>Today, we’re also imposing sweeping sanctions on Russia’s defense sector.</p>
<p>In total, 22 Russian defense-related entities will be designated, including companies that make combat aircraft, infantry fighting vehicles, missiles, unmanned aerial vehicles, electronic warfare systems – the very systems now being used to assault the Ukrainian people, abuse human rights, violate international humanitarian law.</p>
<p>We’re also imposing export controls on Belarus to hold the Lukashenka regime accountable for being a co-belligerent in President Putin’s war of choice.</p>
<p>We will choke off Belarus’s ability to import key technologies.</p>
<p>And if Lukashenka’s support for the war continues, the consequences for his regime will escalate.</p>
<p>All told, these sanctions and restrictions have had a powerful effect on Russia’s economy.</p>
<p>The value of the ruble has plummeted; the Russian stock market closed at – as fear of capital flight rose; interest rates more than doubled; Russia’s credit rating has been cut to junk status.</p>
<p>The value of President Putin’s “war fund” has vanished.</p>
<p>And by choking Russia’s access to technology, we’re delivering a blow to its economy and military that will be felt not just now, but for years to come.</p>
<p>President Putin may have assumed that the United States and our allies were bluffing when we warned of massive, unprecedented consequences.</p>
<p>But – as President Biden likes to say – big nations can’t bluff.</p>
<p>The United States doesn’t bluff.</p>
<p>And President Putin has gravely miscalculated.</p>
<p>As President Biden made clear last night, this is President Putin’s war.</p>
<p>This isn’t the Russian people’s war.</p>
<p>It’s becoming clearer by the day that the Russian people oppose it.</p>
<p>Members of the Russian military oppose it and had no idea what they were being sent to do.</p>
<p>And now the Russian people will suffer the consequences of their leaders’ choices.</p>
<p>So my message to the people of Russia – if they’re even able to hear it, as the Kremlin cracks down even harder on media outlets reporting the truth – my message is that we know many of you want no part of this war.</p>
<p>You, like Ukrainians, like Americans, like people everywhere, want the same basic things – good jobs, clean air and water, the chance to raise your kids in safe neighborhoods, to send them to good schools, to give them better lives than you had.</p>
<p>How in the world does President Putin’s unprovoked aggression against Ukraine help you achieve any of these things?</p>
<p>How is it going to make your lives better?</p>
<p>The economic costs that we’ve been forced to impose on Russia are not aimed at you – they are aimed at compelling your government to stop its actions, to stop its aggression.</p>
<p>And just as millions of us around the world stand together against Moscow’s aggression, we also stand together with you as you demand that your leaders end this war.</p>
<p>If President Putin wants to demonstrate leadership, he should allow Russian soldiers to go home to their families.</p>
<p>Finally, the United States is continuing our diplomatic efforts.</p>
<p>We’re keeping the door open to a diplomatic way forward.  That’s going to be very hard to happen without military de-escalation.  It’s much more difficult for diplomacy to succeed when guns are firing, tanks are rolling, planes are flying.  But if Russia pulls back and pursues diplomacy, we stand ready to do the same thing.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, our intensive diplomacy with allies and partners continues.  I’ve been in virtually daily contact with my friend and counterpart, Ukraine’s Foreign Minister Kuleba, and I’ve made clear that we’ll support any diplomatic efforts by the Ukrainian Government to reach a ceasefire and withdrawal of Russian forces.  If there are diplomatic steps that we can take that the Ukrainian Government believes would be helpful, we’re prepared to take them – even as we continue to support Ukraine’s ability to defend itself.</p>
<p>Tomorrow, I’ll travel to Brussels, where I’ll meet with our NATO, European Union, and G7 allies and partners to continue our coordination; to commend them on the unprecedented steps that they’ve taken to support Ukraine and hold Russia to account; and to reaffirm our Article 5 commitment that an attack on any NATO member is an attack on all.  From there, I’ll travel to Poland, which is already hosting hundreds of thousands of Ukrainian refugees, with tens of thousands arriving by the day; and then to Moldova, which is also hosting Ukrainian refugees, and where Russian troops have been occupying territory against the will of the people for years.</p>
<p>And then I’ll go on to the Baltic countries – to Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia – which are facing a renewed threat from Russia themselves, as President Putin seeks to reassert Russia’s dominance over former Soviet republics.  Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia are our NATO Allies, and as President Biden has said, we will defend every inch of NATO territory against any aggression from Russia or otherwise.</p>
<p>Finally, I want to note the consequential and historic vote that just took place in the United Nations.  A hundred and forty-one member states voted in favor of a resolution reaffirming Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and condemning Russia’s invasion of another member state.  As this vote revealed, the overwhelming majority of the international community stands in strong support of the core principles of the United Nations and upholding the UN Charter – and stands against Russia’s reckless attempts to change the borders of another sovereign country by force, to replace its will for the will of the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p>As 141 member states of the United Nations know, more is at stake, even, than the conflict in Ukraine itself and the freedom and security of Ukraine and its people.  This is a threat to stability in Europe, and to the entire rules-based order, which has been the foundation of security and prosperity for people around the world for nearly 80 years.</p>
<p>In this time of uncertainty, we have a clear way forward: help Ukraine defend itself.  Support the Ukrainian people.  Hold Russia accountable.  And persist with diplomacy.</p>
<p>President Putin is more isolated from the world than ever before.  As President Biden predicted last night, when the history of this era is written, Russia’s war on Ukraine will have left Russia weaker and the rest of the world stronger.  And in the days ahead, we will continue to draw inspiration from the iron will of the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p>With that, happy to take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Humeyra.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello, Mr. Secretary.  Thanks for being here.  I just want to ask you, what is the U.S. assessment on Putin’s state of mind?  You said that he’s more isolated than before.  Do you worry that this isolation might prompt him to lash out and do something even more dramatic than we’ve so far seen on the ground?</p>
<p>And I also want to ask you:  I’m sure you’ve seen that there are Americans who have expressed their desire to go and join the fight in Ukraine.  What is your message to them?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks.  I can’t put myself in President Putin’s mind or state of mind.  All that we can focus on are the actions that he’s taking and our response to those actions.  I’ve said before, one of the Achilles’ heels of autocracies is the inability to speak truth to power.  I don’t know who said what to President Putin before he launched this aggression.  I don’t know who’s saying what to him now.  But again, all of that is speculation.  We can’t put ourselves in his mindset.  All we can do is what we’re doing, which is to be very clear in how we’ll respond to the actions that he takes; to continue to work in unity with allies and partners in support of Ukraine, in defense of Ukraine; to help its people; to help those who have been forced to flee; and if there are any diplomatic opportunities to pursue, to pursue those.  But we’re focused less on what President Putin thinks or may think and more on what he does.</p>
<p>And with regard to the second part of your question, look, we’ve been very clear for some time, of course, in calling on Americans who may be – may have been resident in Ukraine to leave, and making clear to Americans who may be thinking of traveling there not to go.  For those who want to help Ukraine and help its people, there are many ways to do that, including by supporting and helping the many NGOs that are working to provide humanitarian assistance; providing resources themselves to groups that are trying to help Ukraine by being advocates for Ukraine and for peaceful resolution to this crisis that was created by Russia.  Those are the most effective ways that people who want to help can do so.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, you just quoted the President as saying big nations don’t bluff.  Do you think that President Putin is bluffing by putting his nuclear forces on alert?  And I have another question, if you don’t mind.</p>
<p>Are you surprised that we have not seen more – we’ve seen some denial of services, but are you surprised that we have not seen a more massive cyber attack against Ukraine or against other of the NATO nations or against us?  Do you think that the legislation that just passed improves our ability to defend against such attacks?</p>
<p>And if I could impose on you one more question.  I talked today to Daria Kaleniuk, who was part of the President and your democracy summit this year, and you know how passionate she is.  Perhaps you saw her questioning.  And she says that despite everything that has been done, and I would – I would say it’s an extraordinary amount of coordination and agreement with the allies, it’s not going to get there in time.  That convoy is sitting outside Kyiv and poised to encircle Kyiv, and they’re not going to get those supplies.  What more can be done to help those people?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Andrea, thank you.  Let me take them in not quite reverse order.  First, just on the cyber piece, two things.  First, yes, the legislation that you referred is extremely helpful.  But beyond that, and before that, we have been very focused on the potential for cyber attacks not only against Ukraine but against us, against allies and partners.  We’ve been working for months first with Ukraine and also among ourselves to harden, to sharpen defenses.  All of that work is very much underway, including with the private sector.  And so I think we have to be very much on guard about that possibility.  We are.</p>
<p>With regard to assistance to Ukraine, here’s what I can – here’s what I can tell you.  We are very actively working every day, every hour, to provide that assistance and to make sure that, to the best of our ability, it gets to where it needs to go.  And this is not just us; this is many countries in Europe.  We’re coordinating a lot of efforts to do that.  And my own assessment right now is that the vitally needed assistance is getting to where it needs to go.</p>
<p>With regard to President Putin’s statements on Russia’s nuclear posture, first, as you know, Russia and the United States have long agreed that the actual use of nuclear weapons would be devastating and have devastating consequences for the entire world.  And as we’ve stated many times, including earlier this year following the meeting between President Biden and President Putin in Geneva, both of our countries have stated that a nuclear war cannot be won and must never be fought.  That was a key reaffirmation coming out of the meeting between President Biden and President Putin back in June.</p>
<p>Provocative rhetoric about nuclear weapons is the height of irresponsibility.  It’s dangerous.  It adds to the risk of miscalculation.  It needs to be avoided.  We’ve assessed President Putin’s directive and his statements, and at this time we see no reason to change our own alert levels.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, thank you.  You mentioned the vote in the UN, which was by – it was overwhelming, as you said.  And the countries that voted against, the five countries who voted against, no surprise: Belarus, Eritrea, North Korea, Syria, and Russia.  But I’m wondering if you have any thoughts about the abstentions, particularly from Latin America: Cuba, Nicaragua, Venezuela, who stayed out.  These are countries that are no stranger to larger powers, who might – shall go unnamed, getting involved in their internal politics.  And I’m wondering if that says anything to you.</p>
<p>And then secondly, on the prospects for diplomacy with Russia, which you said you’re keeping the door open to, I mean, really, what are the prospects for – what are the chances of that happening?  And are – and is there – if there is an open door, is it just for Ukraine and potentially the Iran talks in Vienna?  Or are you open to the whole gamut of things – arms control, climate, all – any number of other things?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Matt, first of all, to put the vote in the UN in perspective, it is both overwhelming and, I would even say, historic.  Go back to 2014, when the General Assembly pronounced itself on Russia’s initial aggression against Ukraine.  The votes in favor of that resolution were 100.  Then go to the horrific actions that the Assad regime took in Aleppo.  The vote there was 120 in favor of a resolution condemning the actions of the Assad regime.  Today 141 votes.  That speaks powerfully and eloquently about the overwhelming majority of the world and its views about what Russia is doing in Ukraine.</p>
<p>I’m not going to parse the individual votes.  I think in some cases an abstention actually speaks loudly itself as opposed to a no vote, so I think you have to look at some of the individual countries, assess their relationship with Russia, and look at how they voted in that context.  For the small number that voted against – Belarus, the DPRK, Eritrea, Syria, as well as, of course, Russia – as Groucho Marx once sort of said, this is not very much a club that I would want to be a member of.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Olga Koshelenko.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Oh, wait, sorry, on the prospects for diplomacy.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Oh, I’m sorry, yes.  Look, as I said a moment ago, with regard to Ukraine itself, we of course remain open to pursuing any reasonable path, but it’s very hard to see any path when the bombs are dropping, the planes are flying, the tanks are rolling.  So de-escalation, pulling back forces – that would open a path to diplomacy, and we I think demonstrated very clearly in the months leading up to Russia’s aggression that we were prepared to engage Russia diplomatically on any legitimate security concerns on a reciprocal basis that remains.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, tragically, horrifically, I think we’ve seen – and you don’t have to take my word for it; just listen to President Putin’s own words – that virtually everything the Russian Government professed to be concerned about was not really what was at issue – for example, Ukraine joining NATO.  What President Putin has said loudly and clearly and has now demonstrated by the actions that Russia has taken is that what this is about for him is Ukraine being absorbed in one fashion or another into Russia.  He sees Ukraine as having no independent existence.  He wants to reincorporate it into an empire; short of that, to make it part of a renewed sphere of influence or maybe, at the very least, to make it totally neutral.  So this is about way more than the issues that we were prepared to engage Russia on.</p>
<p>So two quick pieces on the diplomacy now.  One, with regard to Ukraine itself, first and foremost, the question is if Ukraine thinks there is a path that would help advance its interests, protect it, end the war, and we can be helpful in that, of course.  We’re fully prepared to do that.  But we really look to the Ukrainian Government to see what, if anything, might make sense.  They’re engaged in talks with Russia.  They had one round.  There may be another one; we’ll see.  But, of course, the demands that Russia put on the table were beyond excessive.  They were, of course, non-starters, and what we’ve seen repeatedly is that Russia goes through the pretense of diplomacy to distract and continue on its aggressive path.</p>
<p>More broadly, even as we’ve imposed and continue to impose massive costs on Russia for its aggression and actions in Ukraine, if we determine that there are areas that it’s in our interest to continue to pursue and that in one fashion or another may involve some engagement from Russia, we’ll continue to pursue that.  We’re not going to let Russia dictate in any way what’s in our interests and how to pursue them.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Time for a final question from Olga Koshelenko.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Inaudible) Media, Ukraine.  Just a few days ago European Union proposed to donate their fighter jets to Ukraine to protect our sky, but as far as I know, for now this deal has fallen apart.  I know that you were on a phone call with Foreign Minister Kuleba today discussing this topic as well.  Could one expect that after your travel to Europe, something could change and Ukraine will get access to those jets?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  I can’t comment in detail on my conversations with Foreign Minister Kuleba.  We talked about a lot of things, including the ongoing provision of security assistance to Ukraine, and that is something that I will be talking to European allies and partners about in a couple of days in Brussels.  Again, I can tell you, as I mentioned in response to Andrea’s question, that when it comes to vital defensive military equipment that Ukraine needs, we are very actively coordinating its provision, and that assistance is getting there.  But we’ll probably have more to say in the next couple of days.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Can I follow up?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, everyone.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you very much.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Just one very quick one.  Sir, do you think that Russia is deliberately targeting civilians?  You said they’re hitting schools and hospitals.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Mm-hmm.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  They’re – are they doing it deliberately?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We have certainly seen in the past that one of Russia’s methods of war is to be absolutely brutal in trying to cow the citizenry of a given country, and that includes at the very least indiscriminate targeting and potentially deliberate targeting as well.  We’re looking very closely at what’s happening in Ukraine right now, including what’s happening to civilians.  We’re taking account of it.  We’re documenting it.  And we want to ensure, among other things, that there’s accountability for it.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you all.  Thank you all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-Djibouti Bi-National Forum</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-djibouti-bi-national-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 21:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319877</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for African Affairs Molly Phee and Djiboutian Foreign Minister Mahmoud Ali Youssouf concluded the 6th annual U.S.-Djibouti Bi-National Forum today.  In these high-level discussions launched by Secretary of State Anthony Blinken on February 4, Assistant Secretary Phee and Foreign Minister Youssouf reviewed the longstanding bilateral partnership between the United States and Djibouti and the broad range of security, economic, and development cooperation that encompasses the U.S.-Djibouti bilateral relationship.  They also discussed areas of collaboration to further regional peace, stability, and prosperity in the Horn of Africa.</p>
<div id="mail_footer"></div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for African Affairs Molly Phee and Djiboutian Foreign Minister Mahmoud Ali Youssouf concluded the 6th annual U.S.-Djibouti Bi-National Forum today.  In these high-level discussions launched by Secretary of State Anthony Blinken on February 4, Assistant Secretary Phee and Foreign Minister Youssouf reviewed the longstanding bilateral partnership between the United States and Djibouti and the broad range of security, economic, and development cooperation that encompasses the U.S.-Djibouti bilateral relationship.  They also discussed areas of collaboration to further regional peace, stability, and prosperity in the Horn of Africa.</p>
<div id="mail_footer"></div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friends of Sudan Statement on Publication of UNITAMS Summary Report</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/friends-of-sudan-statement-on-publication-of-unitams-summary-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 20:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319866</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Kuwait, the Netherlands, Norway, Saudi Arabia, Spain, Sweden, United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, the United States of America, and the European Union, as members of the Friends of Sudan, welcome the publication by the UN Integrated Transition Assistance Mission in Sudan (UNITAMS) of its summary report on consultations with Sudanese stakeholders, against the backdrop of Sudan’s ongoing political crisis.</p>
<p>The active engagement of a wide range of Sudanese stakeholders in the consultations, including those representing women, youth, and other groups and regions is a strong and encouraging sign of the actors’ unwavering commitment to resolving the political crisis and to paving the way for a democratic and peaceful Sudan. The report reflects their views and demonstrates strong consensus on a number of key issues and principles, including: installation of a transitional cabinet of civilian technocrats; reduction in the size and powers of the transitional Sovereign Council; establishment of a transitional Legislative Assembly composed of civilians; the equitable participation of women in the transitional institutions; the importance of transitional justice and accountability; and the need to establish new electoral laws and bodies which can deliver free and fair elections.</p>
<p>The areas of consensus provide an important basis for further efforts by all Sudanese parties to find a common understanding on the way forward, by agreeing on a new constitutional and legal basis and governance arrangements for the remaining transitional period, pending credible elections. These efforts must remain Sudanese-owned and –led, and we welcome the commitment of UNITAMS, the African Union, and the Inter-Governmental Authority on Development, as well as the EU, the League of Arab States, and Friends of Sudan, to work together to support the process.</p>
<p>The UNITAMS report also notes overwhelming consensus on the need to build a conducive environment for a political process, by stopping violence and killings in the context of protests, lifting the State of Emergency, ending unjust detentions, ceasing attacks on hospitals, and respecting rights to free expression and peaceful assembly.</p>
<p>The Friends of Sudan call on all relevant Sudanese stakeholders to engage in the next phase of a political process to resolve the political crisis in Sudan. We remain committed to supporting the aspirations of the Sudanese people for a free, democratic, peaceful, and prosperous Sudan.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Kuwait, the Netherlands, Norway, Saudi Arabia, Spain, Sweden, United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, the United States of America, and the European Union, as members of the Friends of Sudan, welcome the publication by the UN Integrated Transition Assistance Mission in Sudan (UNITAMS) of its summary report on consultations with Sudanese stakeholders, against the backdrop of Sudan’s ongoing political crisis.</p>
<p>The active engagement of a wide range of Sudanese stakeholders in the consultations, including those representing women, youth, and other groups and regions is a strong and encouraging sign of the actors’ unwavering commitment to resolving the political crisis and to paving the way for a democratic and peaceful Sudan. The report reflects their views and demonstrates strong consensus on a number of key issues and principles, including: installation of a transitional cabinet of civilian technocrats; reduction in the size and powers of the transitional Sovereign Council; establishment of a transitional Legislative Assembly composed of civilians; the equitable participation of women in the transitional institutions; the importance of transitional justice and accountability; and the need to establish new electoral laws and bodies which can deliver free and fair elections.</p>
<p>The areas of consensus provide an important basis for further efforts by all Sudanese parties to find a common understanding on the way forward, by agreeing on a new constitutional and legal basis and governance arrangements for the remaining transitional period, pending credible elections. These efforts must remain Sudanese-owned and –led, and we welcome the commitment of UNITAMS, the African Union, and the Inter-Governmental Authority on Development, as well as the EU, the League of Arab States, and Friends of Sudan, to work together to support the process.</p>
<p>The UNITAMS report also notes overwhelming consensus on the need to build a conducive environment for a political process, by stopping violence and killings in the context of protests, lifting the State of Emergency, ending unjust detentions, ceasing attacks on hospitals, and respecting rights to free expression and peaceful assembly.</p>
<p>The Friends of Sudan call on all relevant Sudanese stakeholders to engage in the next phase of a political process to resolve the political crisis in Sudan. We remain committed to supporting the aspirations of the Sudanese people for a free, democratic, peaceful, and prosperous Sudan.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Travel to Belgium, Poland, Moldova, Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-belgium-poland-moldova-latvia-lithuania-and-estonia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 19:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319768</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Belgium, Poland, Moldova, Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia from March 3 to 8, 2022.  The trip continues extensive consultations and coordination with our NATO Allies and European partners about the Russian Federation’s continued premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken will begin his trip in Brussels, Belgium where he will participate in a NATO Foreign Ministerial, meet with EU counterparts, participate in a G7 Ministerial Meeting, and hold additional meetings with partners to discuss the global response to Russia’s invasion, including Allies’ and partners’ continued coordination on imposing massive consequences and severe economic costs on Russia.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Poland on March 5, where he will meet with Polish leaders, including Foreign Minister Zbigniew Rau, to discuss further security assistance in the face of Russia’s continued aggression and unprovoked attack on Ukraine.  He will also thank Poland for generously welcoming hundreds of thousands of displaced persons from Ukraine and discuss how the United States can augment humanitarian assistance efforts for those fleeing Putin’s war.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Chisinau, Moldova to meet with President Maia Sandu, Prime Minister Natalia Gavrilita, and Foreign Minister Nicu Popescu.  During his stop, the Secretary will discuss support for Moldova’s efforts to receive and assist refugees fleeing Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, as well as U.S. support for Moldova’s democracy, sovereignty, and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Vilnius, Lithuania on March 6 to meet with President Gitanas Nauseda, Prime Minister Ingrida Simonyte, and Foreign Minister Gabrielius Landsbergis. On March 7, the Secretary will travel to Riga, Latvia, to meet with President Egils Levits, Prime Minister Krisjanis Karins, and Foreign Minister Edgars Rinkevics. He will travel to Tallinn, Estonia, on March 8 to meet with President Alar Karis, Prime Minister Kaja Kallas, and Foreign Minister Eva-Maria Liimets. During all three stops, he will discuss joint efforts to support Ukraine, strengthen NATO’s deterrence and defense, promote democracy and human rights, and pursue deeper economic and energy cooperation with our Baltic Allies.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Belgium, Poland, Moldova, Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia from March 3 to 8, 2022.  The trip continues extensive consultations and coordination with our NATO Allies and European partners about the Russian Federation’s continued premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken will begin his trip in Brussels, Belgium where he will participate in a NATO Foreign Ministerial, meet with EU counterparts, participate in a G7 Ministerial Meeting, and hold additional meetings with partners to discuss the global response to Russia’s invasion, including Allies’ and partners’ continued coordination on imposing massive consequences and severe economic costs on Russia.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Poland on March 5, where he will meet with Polish leaders, including Foreign Minister Zbigniew Rau, to discuss further security assistance in the face of Russia’s continued aggression and unprovoked attack on Ukraine.  He will also thank Poland for generously welcoming hundreds of thousands of displaced persons from Ukraine and discuss how the United States can augment humanitarian assistance efforts for those fleeing Putin’s war.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Chisinau, Moldova to meet with President Maia Sandu, Prime Minister Natalia Gavrilita, and Foreign Minister Nicu Popescu.  During his stop, the Secretary will discuss support for Moldova’s efforts to receive and assist refugees fleeing Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, as well as U.S. support for Moldova’s democracy, sovereignty, and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Vilnius, Lithuania on March 6 to meet with President Gitanas Nauseda, Prime Minister Ingrida Simonyte, and Foreign Minister Gabrielius Landsbergis. On March 7, the Secretary will travel to Riga, Latvia, to meet with President Egils Levits, Prime Minister Krisjanis Karins, and Foreign Minister Edgars Rinkevics. He will travel to Tallinn, Estonia, on March 8 to meet with President Alar Karis, Prime Minister Kaja Kallas, and Foreign Minister Eva-Maria Liimets. During all three stops, he will discuss joint efforts to support Ukraine, strengthen NATO’s deterrence and defense, promote democracy and human rights, and pursue deeper economic and energy cooperation with our Baltic Allies.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Saudi Foreign Minister Prince Faisal bin Farhan Al Saud</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-saudi-foreign-minister-prince-faisal-bin-farhan-al-saud-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 17:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with the Foreign Minister of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, Prince Faisal bin Farhan Al Saud, about Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified attack against Ukraine, the importance of respecting the UN Charter’s principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity of states, and coordinating a strong international response in support of Ukrainian sovereignty.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with the Foreign Minister of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, Prince Faisal bin Farhan Al Saud, about Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified attack against Ukraine, the importance of respecting the UN Charter’s principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity of states, and coordinating a strong international response in support of Ukrainian sovereignty.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-Turkmenistan Annual Bilateral Consultations</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-turkmenistan-annual-bilateral-consultations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 17:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319608</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, virtual United States-Turkmenistan Annual Bilateral Consultations (ABCs) concluded after two days of productive discussions.  A senior U.S. delegation, led by Assistant Secretary of State Donald Lu, hosted Foreign Minister Rashid Meredov and the senior Turkmen delegation.</p>
<p>The ABCs began in 2009 so that our governments could discuss important policy issues. They continue to serve that important role, even as the global and regional situation have evolved.</p>
<p>During the consultations, the U.S. delegation reinforced support for the independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity of Turkmenistan and reiterated our shared commitment to peace, prosperity, and security in Central Asia through the C5+1 diplomatic platform.  The U.S. delegation reiterated the importance of condemning Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine and of maintaining solidarity with the people of Ukraine.  The delegations discussed a wide range of bilateral and regional issues including cooperation on strengthening border security, counternarcotics, and counterterrorism, as well as the need for progress on human rights, including freedom of religion or belief, labor issues, and education opportunities.  Both delegations also discussed their growing engagement on climate action, trade and business, women’s economic empowerment, and regional connectivity of energy resources.</p>
<p>The United States looks forward to strengthening our efforts with Turkmenistan in all of these important areas and deepening the friendship between our peoples.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, virtual United States-Turkmenistan Annual Bilateral Consultations (ABCs) concluded after two days of productive discussions.  A senior U.S. delegation, led by Assistant Secretary of State Donald Lu, hosted Foreign Minister Rashid Meredov and the senior Turkmen delegation.</p>
<p>The ABCs began in 2009 so that our governments could discuss important policy issues. They continue to serve that important role, even as the global and regional situation have evolved.</p>
<p>During the consultations, the U.S. delegation reinforced support for the independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity of Turkmenistan and reiterated our shared commitment to peace, prosperity, and security in Central Asia through the C5+1 diplomatic platform.  The U.S. delegation reiterated the importance of condemning Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine and of maintaining solidarity with the people of Ukraine.  The delegations discussed a wide range of bilateral and regional issues including cooperation on strengthening border security, counternarcotics, and counterterrorism, as well as the need for progress on human rights, including freedom of religion or belief, labor issues, and education opportunities.  Both delegations also discussed their growing engagement on climate action, trade and business, women’s economic empowerment, and regional connectivity of energy resources.</p>
<p>The United States looks forward to strengthening our efforts with Turkmenistan in all of these important areas and deepening the friendship between our peoples.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with Indonesian Foreign Minister Marsudi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-indonesian-foreign-minister-marsudi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 14:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319433</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Indonesian Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi.  The Deputy Secretary condemned Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine and thanked the Government of Indonesia for cosponsoring the UN General Assembly resolution on Ukraine.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Marsudi also emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Indonesia Strategic Partnership and discussed ways to ensure the success of the upcoming U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Indonesian Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi.  The Deputy Secretary condemned Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine and thanked the Government of Indonesia for cosponsoring the UN General Assembly resolution on Ukraine.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Marsudi also emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Indonesia Strategic Partnership and discussed ways to ensure the success of the upcoming U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Mexican Foreign Secretary Ebrard</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-mexican-foreign-secretary-ebrard-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 01:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Mexican Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard. Secretary Blinken noted Mexico’s strong statements in support of Ukraine and in defense of the UN Charter in its Security Council and General Assembly remarks and as a part of the OAS Joint Declaration in the wake of Russia’s premeditated and unprovoked invasion. The Secretary and Foreign Secretary reaffirmed both countries’ condemnation of Russia’s actions and called for Russia to cease all hostilities. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Ebrard also spoke about the renewed and vibrant U.S.-Mexico partnership and the advances in cooperation over the past year led by President Biden and President Lopez Obrador. Secretary Blinken reiterated his sincere appreciation for our strong partnership with Mexico as we work to advance democracy, economic prosperity, and security in North America and around the world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Mexican Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard. Secretary Blinken noted Mexico’s strong statements in support of Ukraine and in defense of the UN Charter in its Security Council and General Assembly remarks and as a part of the OAS Joint Declaration in the wake of Russia’s premeditated and unprovoked invasion. The Secretary and Foreign Secretary reaffirmed both countries’ condemnation of Russia’s actions and called for Russia to cease all hostilities. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Ebrard also spoke about the renewed and vibrant U.S.-Mexico partnership and the advances in cooperation over the past year led by President Biden and President Lopez Obrador. Secretary Blinken reiterated his sincere appreciation for our strong partnership with Mexico as we work to advance democracy, economic prosperity, and security in North America and around the world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ukraine’s Filing Against Russia at the International Court of Justice</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/ukraines-filing-against-russia-at-the-international-court-of-justice/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319299</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>On February 26, 2022, Ukraine filed an application at the International Court of Justice (ICJ) to initiate proceedings against the Russian Federation under the Convention on the Prevention and Punishment of the Crime of Genocide. Ukraine seeks to address Russia’s groundless claims that genocide has occurred in the Luhansk and Donetsk oblasts of Ukraine and establish that Russia has no lawful basis to take military action on the basis of those false claims. Ukraine has also requested the ICJ exercise its authority to indicate provisional measures to preserve Ukraine’s rights and limit the ongoing and irreparable harm to the Ukrainian people as well as Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity within its internationally recognized borders.</p>
<p>As the principal judicial organ of the United Nations, the ICJ has a vital role to play in the peaceful settlement of disputes. Ukraine also requested the Court call upon Russia to halt immediately all military actions in Ukraine pending the Court’s review. Today, in response to that request, the Court called on the Russian Federation to act in a manner that would allow any provisional measures ordered by the Court to have an actual impact. This is another clear indication that Russia must cease its military activities in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Considering the gravity of the crisis in Ukraine that has resulted from Russia’s unprovoked invasion, we trust the Court is taking into consideration the dire circumstances and rapidly unfolding events and hope that it will act with utmost urgency on Ukraine’s request for provisional measures.</p>
<p>Each day that Russia is unconstrained in its aggression is a day that brings more violence, suffering, death, and destruction in Ukraine. The United States stands with the people of Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>On February 26, 2022, Ukraine filed an application at the International Court of Justice (ICJ) to initiate proceedings against the Russian Federation under the Convention on the Prevention and Punishment of the Crime of Genocide. Ukraine seeks to address Russia’s groundless claims that genocide has occurred in the Luhansk and Donetsk oblasts of Ukraine and establish that Russia has no lawful basis to take military action on the basis of those false claims. Ukraine has also requested the ICJ exercise its authority to indicate provisional measures to preserve Ukraine’s rights and limit the ongoing and irreparable harm to the Ukrainian people as well as Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity within its internationally recognized borders.</p>
<p>As the principal judicial organ of the United Nations, the ICJ has a vital role to play in the peaceful settlement of disputes. Ukraine also requested the Court call upon Russia to halt immediately all military actions in Ukraine pending the Court’s review. Today, in response to that request, the Court called on the Russian Federation to act in a manner that would allow any provisional measures ordered by the Court to have an actual impact. This is another clear indication that Russia must cease its military activities in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Considering the gravity of the crisis in Ukraine that has resulted from Russia’s unprovoked invasion, we trust the Court is taking into consideration the dire circumstances and rapidly unfolding events and hope that it will act with utmost urgency on Ukraine’s request for provisional measures.</p>
<p>Each day that Russia is unconstrained in its aggression is a day that brings more violence, suffering, death, and destruction in Ukraine. The United States stands with the people of Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with Peruvian Foreign Minister Landa</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-peruvian-foreign-minister-landa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 23:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319290</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Peruvian Foreign Minister César Landa about our shared democratic values and opposition to Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. In addition to discussing opportunities to further strengthen Peru-U.S. relations, Deputy Secretary Sherman commended the Peruvian government for its leadership in condemning Russia’s actions, including its support of the February 25 Organization of American States’ joint declaration on Russia’s aggression. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Landa also discussed how Russia’s violation of international law and the territorial integrity and sovereignty of Ukraine undermines global stability and contradicts the values that bind our hemisphere. The Deputy Secretary congratulated the Foreign Minister on Peru’s designation as the host of APEC 2024 and welcomed the OECD council’s approval to open accession discussions for Peru.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Peruvian Foreign Minister César Landa about our shared democratic values and opposition to Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. In addition to discussing opportunities to further strengthen Peru-U.S. relations, Deputy Secretary Sherman commended the Peruvian government for its leadership in condemning Russia’s actions, including its support of the February 25 Organization of American States’ joint declaration on Russia’s aggression. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Landa also discussed how Russia’s violation of international law and the territorial integrity and sovereignty of Ukraine undermines global stability and contradicts the values that bind our hemisphere. The Deputy Secretary congratulated the Foreign Minister on Peru’s designation as the host of APEC 2024 and welcomed the OECD council’s approval to open accession discussions for Peru.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
