<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:06:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Briefing with Gayle Smith, State Department Coordinator for Global COVID-19 Response and Health Security On the Biden-Harris Administration’s Plans for Global Vaccine Sharing</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-with-gayle-smith-state-department-coordinator-for-global-covid-19-response-and-health-security-on-the-biden-harris-administrations-plans-for-global-vaccine-sharing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gayle Smith, State Department Coordinator for Global COVID-19 Response and Health Security]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=249540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Gayle Smith, State Department Coordinator for Global COVID-19 Response and Health Security</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Good afternoon, everyone, and thanks for joining us and especially thanks for joining us on a Friday afternoon. We are really pleased to have with us today Gayle Smith, the State Department Coordinator for Global COVID-19 Response and Health Security. Gayle will be able to chat with us a bit about yesterday’s announcement and offer some context around it, and then she will be happy to take your questions. As a reminder, this is on the record, but the contents of this briefing are embargoed until the end of the call. So with that, I will turn over to Coordinator Smith.</p>
<p><strong>MS SMITH: </strong>Thank you, Ned. And thank you so much, everybody, for joining us. I’m just going to run through a little bit of the why, how, and who and a little bit on what comes next, and then happy to take your questions.</p>
<p>I mean, as for why we’re doing this, I think the President has articulated a very urgent need, which is ending the global pandemic, and as part of that tackling the problem that is that we’ve got a real challenge on the supply of vaccines against demand. It’s in our interest to do this. Our own health security is at risk, but it has – as has been said, I think thousands of times since this pandemic started, none of us is safe until all of us are safe.</p>
<p>I think another reason is that U.S. leadership matters. We’ve been in consultation with a number of countries around the world, and I think it makes a big difference when the U.S. steps up and leads and organizes other countries to join forces. One of the reasons we’re not doing this is to curry any political favor. Our goal is to end the pandemic and maximize the supply as quickly as we can.</p>
<p>As to how we’ve thought through this first tranche of 25 million doses – and I would remind you that this is part of an initial 80 million dose commitment announced by the President – first, we wanted to make sure that we could maximize global coverage in this first round given the breadth of the need and the requirements.</p>
<p>The second is to be able to address both surges and what I would call pre-surges. There are a number of countries that may have been doing well, but with the rise of variants or other problems, they’re seeing sudden upticks – some of the things we’ve seen here in the United States – and there is the great urgency to move.</p>
<p>And third, we wanted to be very responsive to the very large number of countries who have come to us about their needs for vaccines and also to our neighbors.</p>
<p>In terms of the allocation of the vaccines, we will do at least 75 percent through COVAX. COVAX is the largest vaccine delivery platform in the world. We know it well. They’re an important partner. It’s built on something called Gavi, the Global Vaccine Alliance, which the United States has supported for many, many years to be the primary delivery mechanism for childhood vaccines.</p>
<p>We have identified the countries we want these vaccines to go to, and we’ll work with COVAX to have them delivered. That’s roughly just over 6 million across Latin America including Caribbean, 7 million South and Southeast Asia, 5 million across Africa. The balance of 25 percent, we are likely to do bilaterally. It gives us greater flexibility. And again, as we’ve seen, there are a lot of pop-ups and flairs in this pandemic, and we want to be able to move vaccines on an urgent basis if needed.</p>
<p>What comes next – we will continue this three-part strategy to maximize supply, again, by doing this dose sharing – and again, we anticipate it will increase over the coming months; by working with and encouraging U.S. manufacturers to increase production, including by the last quarter if not earlier of this year and well into next year; and to also work on global vaccine production. The international architecture for vaccine production was built for a much smaller number of doses than the world demands now, and so we want to increase production in its capacity and in fact decentralize it so there are more places in the world manufacturing and able to distribute vaccines.</p>
<p>Finally, I’d remind you that this dose-sharing operation is nested in a much broader response by the United States Government which includes vaccine readiness and working with countries to make sure that their health systems can provide the services that are needed both to deal with the spread of the virus but also to deliver vaccines. Many of the humanitarian impacts of the pandemic, which have been acute all across the world, the systemic economic impacts – so we’re working on all of those fronts as well.</p>
<p>And we will be working very hard in the coming days as we are soon going into the G7 Summit. And we’ve been having very, very productive discussions with our partners there about our collective efforts to do as much as we possibly can to get global vaccine coverage and to bring this pandemic to an end.</p>
<p>So let me stop there, and happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Excellent. Operator, do you mind just repeating the instructions to ask a question?</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Sure. If you would like to ask a question on today’s call, please press 1 then 0. That command, again, 1 then 0.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Great. Let’s go to the line of David Brunnstrom.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, hi. Thank you very much for this. You mentioned just there the G7. New Zealand is hosting APEC, and I think that’s actually later on today. It’s been pushing APEC countries to remove tariffs on vaccines and products in the vaccine supply chain. I’m just wondering if the U.S. supports that.</p>
<p>And I also wondered if you could – when you talk about the decentralizing production capacity – and we know that the United States is going to be relaxing restrictions on export of raw materials – if you allow the export of raw materials to other countries, is that fully* the understanding that those countries will be producing for export rather than for their own domestic consumption? Many thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS SMITH:</strong> Those are really good questions, and I think two things. I mean, look, we need greater vaccine productive capacity even without a pandemic, so I think that’s quite important. I think our – certainly our hope would be that countries will produce – certainly they’re going to produce for themselves, but also to be able to export, because again, that’s been a real obstacle that has come up.</p>
<p>I have to confess I am not familiar with but will immediately look into New Zealand’s latest moves and can come back to you on our position on that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll go to the line of Josh Wingrove.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you so much for doing this. Can you offer a little insight into the reiteration yesterday of the 80 million pledge? Should that be interpreted as confidence that the AstraZeneca doses will become available this month, or is the plan to make up the – what is quoted, a 55 million balance due, for lack of a better phrase, with those other authorized vaccines?</p>
<p><strong>MS SMITH:</strong> Yeah, good question. Our expectation and certainly hope is that we will get a clearance from the FDA. Given that that is a regulatory public health agency, we are not going to prejudice that at all and let them come forth with their determination. And then we’ll act on the basis of that. But I think what you heard from the President, the commitment to 80 million vaccines, our current expectation is that the balance after these 25 million will come from the AstraZeneca doses.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll go to the line of Nicole Gaouette.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you for doing this. Two questions. I’m wondering if you could talk us through how you arrived at that distribution – those numbers between Latin America, South and Southeast Asia, and Africa.</p>
<p>And the second part of my question is: When those remaining 55 million doses will be made available whether you have a sense whether they’ll all go to COVAX or whether you’ll also be holding some of those back to distribute bilaterally.</p>
<p><strong>MS SMITH:</strong> Good questions. The way we looked at the numbers (inaudible) – obviously, given the demand, this is a bit challenging. Obviously, we want to give a certain focus to our own hemisphere, and so on the Latin American side that made a big difference – Latin America and the Caribbean. But I think if you look at – we’ve got three regions covered and focused on, because as I said at the top, we want to start laying the ground for global coverage so that when we do the next tranche of shared vaccines, we will be adding another layer of global coverage and so on and so forth. So that’s number one.</p>
<p>Number two is there are a number of places where there are either surge conditions or pre-surge conditions. We’ve seen a spike – many of the countries that have been affected by the extraordinary surge in India, for example. And there are a number of cases there where if we move quickly – you want to make sure healthcare workers are covered and other things. And again, we are trying to be responsive, including to our neighbors. The important thing I’d note on the actual allocation is that, again, this is the first round. This is just the beginning. So as we share more doses, we anticipate having greater coverage.</p>
<p>As to the allocation of the next round, we will likely – I can’t say for certain – follow a similar model to this one, but we can come back to you, absolutely, on that when we’re ready to move on the next tranche. But this seems to be an effective and workable formula.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll go to the line of Patsy Widakuswara.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, yes. Thank you for taking my call and thank you for doing this briefing. Can you speak a little bit about – the administration has been saying that this is not going to be currying political favors, but can you speak a little bit about the branding of these vaccines? We saw some of the shipment that was going out to South Korea had American flags on them. Would there be similar kind of branding even for the shipment that’s going to COVAX?</p>
<p>And my second question is on vaccine patent waiver. We saw that the EU pushed a counterproposal saying that they don’t want to support the TRIPS waiver. Do you think the administration will be pushing for this at the G7? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS SMITH: </strong>Yeah, good question. I think on the branding side I think there’s a real difference between trying to curry political favor and letting countries know that assistance we may be providing is from the American people. I think those are two very different things. So I think people will know. The vaccines will convey that they are from the American people, and I think when vaccines start arriving in country our ambassadors and other staff will be there to greet them. So that’s – yes, that these come from the United States. That’s an important fact and I think people will be well aware of that.</p>
<p>On the EU position, our current position is as it has been, that we support the TRIPS waiver. As you know, the next step on that is very arduous text negotiations by a consensus-based organization which are being led by our U.S. Trade Representative. I suspect that these issues will come up at the G7, but I’m not able to tell you any more specifically on that. I expect, frankly – quite focused on the response to the pandemic in the main.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll go to the line of Carmen Paun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you so much for taking my question. I was wondering if you could say from the 25 million first tranche how many of those are Moderna doses, how many are J&amp;J, and how many are Pfizer, and if you already have a timeline of when they are going to start being shipped out to countries. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS SMITH:</strong> Sure. So what these are – that’s a really good question. What these are is it’s a combination of vaccines from our own stocks. There will be multiple types of vaccines available. And what we will do is there’s a process of sort of matching vaccines to the vaccination program. In some countries they may have some amount of an initial vaccine. J&amp;J may be easier than a two-dose. So we will be working that through with COVAX and with partner countries.</p>
<p>In terms of the timing, we intend to move as quickly as possible. Delivering vaccines and donating vaccines isn’t quite as simple as putting them on plane and dropping them off. There are regulatory and legal procedures that have to be in true. Transporting vaccines, as we’ve seen in the United States, they are important and somewhat delicate medicaments we need to do very carefully. So we’ve got teams set up to do all of that, work through that as quickly as possible and kick off deliveries as soon as we can and to establish a regular cadence. But again, and importantly, there are steps that have to be gone through before we can start moving them, but we’ve already started the work on that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll take a final question from the line of Doug Byun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thanks for doing this. I wanted to ask a question about the shipment to South Korea. President Biden said in his joint press conference with President Jae-in that he would help – the United States would help inoculate 550,000 troops, South Korean troops, and apparently referring to active service members. But – and as a result, the United States sent 1.some million doses of J&amp;J vaccine to South Korea which arrived earlier today. But the thing is the South Korean FDA does not allow people under the age of 30 be inoculated with J&amp;J vaccine, so I was wondering if the United States knew about this South Korean FDA’s regulation regarding J&amp;J vaccine when he made the decision to provide J&amp;J instead of the other two types that you have here.</p>
<p><strong>MS SMITH:</strong> Yes, my understanding – and we may need to do a follow-up with you on this – on this question is that the way this has worked and the way these future deliveries will work is among the first initial steps are to understand what countries have approved which vaccines and then proceed from there through a number of regulatory and legal steps. I would be happy to work with my colleagues to get a more specific answer back to you on that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, Gayle, thank you very much. Thank you very much, everyone, for tuning in and hope everyone has a wonderful weekend.</p>
<p><strong>MS SMITH:</strong> Thanks so much, everybody.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gayle Smith, State Department Coordinator for Global COVID-19 Response and Health Security</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Good afternoon, everyone, and thanks for joining us and especially thanks for joining us on a Friday afternoon. We are really pleased to have with us today Gayle Smith, the State Department Coordinator for Global COVID-19 Response and Health Security. Gayle will be able to chat with us a bit about yesterday’s announcement and offer some context around it, and then she will be happy to take your questions. As a reminder, this is on the record, but the contents of this briefing are embargoed until the end of the call. So with that, I will turn over to Coordinator Smith.</p>
<p><strong>MS SMITH: </strong>Thank you, Ned. And thank you so much, everybody, for joining us. I’m just going to run through a little bit of the why, how, and who and a little bit on what comes next, and then happy to take your questions.</p>
<p>I mean, as for why we’re doing this, I think the President has articulated a very urgent need, which is ending the global pandemic, and as part of that tackling the problem that is that we’ve got a real challenge on the supply of vaccines against demand. It’s in our interest to do this. Our own health security is at risk, but it has – as has been said, I think thousands of times since this pandemic started, none of us is safe until all of us are safe.</p>
<p>I think another reason is that U.S. leadership matters. We’ve been in consultation with a number of countries around the world, and I think it makes a big difference when the U.S. steps up and leads and organizes other countries to join forces. One of the reasons we’re not doing this is to curry any political favor. Our goal is to end the pandemic and maximize the supply as quickly as we can.</p>
<p>As to how we’ve thought through this first tranche of 25 million doses – and I would remind you that this is part of an initial 80 million dose commitment announced by the President – first, we wanted to make sure that we could maximize global coverage in this first round given the breadth of the need and the requirements.</p>
<p>The second is to be able to address both surges and what I would call pre-surges. There are a number of countries that may have been doing well, but with the rise of variants or other problems, they’re seeing sudden upticks – some of the things we’ve seen here in the United States – and there is the great urgency to move.</p>
<p>And third, we wanted to be very responsive to the very large number of countries who have come to us about their needs for vaccines and also to our neighbors.</p>
<p>In terms of the allocation of the vaccines, we will do at least 75 percent through COVAX. COVAX is the largest vaccine delivery platform in the world. We know it well. They’re an important partner. It’s built on something called Gavi, the Global Vaccine Alliance, which the United States has supported for many, many years to be the primary delivery mechanism for childhood vaccines.</p>
<p>We have identified the countries we want these vaccines to go to, and we’ll work with COVAX to have them delivered. That’s roughly just over 6 million across Latin America including Caribbean, 7 million South and Southeast Asia, 5 million across Africa. The balance of 25 percent, we are likely to do bilaterally. It gives us greater flexibility. And again, as we’ve seen, there are a lot of pop-ups and flairs in this pandemic, and we want to be able to move vaccines on an urgent basis if needed.</p>
<p>What comes next – we will continue this three-part strategy to maximize supply, again, by doing this dose sharing – and again, we anticipate it will increase over the coming months; by working with and encouraging U.S. manufacturers to increase production, including by the last quarter if not earlier of this year and well into next year; and to also work on global vaccine production. The international architecture for vaccine production was built for a much smaller number of doses than the world demands now, and so we want to increase production in its capacity and in fact decentralize it so there are more places in the world manufacturing and able to distribute vaccines.</p>
<p>Finally, I’d remind you that this dose-sharing operation is nested in a much broader response by the United States Government which includes vaccine readiness and working with countries to make sure that their health systems can provide the services that are needed both to deal with the spread of the virus but also to deliver vaccines. Many of the humanitarian impacts of the pandemic, which have been acute all across the world, the systemic economic impacts – so we’re working on all of those fronts as well.</p>
<p>And we will be working very hard in the coming days as we are soon going into the G7 Summit. And we’ve been having very, very productive discussions with our partners there about our collective efforts to do as much as we possibly can to get global vaccine coverage and to bring this pandemic to an end.</p>
<p>So let me stop there, and happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Excellent. Operator, do you mind just repeating the instructions to ask a question?</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Sure. If you would like to ask a question on today’s call, please press 1 then 0. That command, again, 1 then 0.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Great. Let’s go to the line of David Brunnstrom.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, hi. Thank you very much for this. You mentioned just there the G7. New Zealand is hosting APEC, and I think that’s actually later on today. It’s been pushing APEC countries to remove tariffs on vaccines and products in the vaccine supply chain. I’m just wondering if the U.S. supports that.</p>
<p>And I also wondered if you could – when you talk about the decentralizing production capacity – and we know that the United States is going to be relaxing restrictions on export of raw materials – if you allow the export of raw materials to other countries, is that fully* the understanding that those countries will be producing for export rather than for their own domestic consumption? Many thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS SMITH:</strong> Those are really good questions, and I think two things. I mean, look, we need greater vaccine productive capacity even without a pandemic, so I think that’s quite important. I think our – certainly our hope would be that countries will produce – certainly they’re going to produce for themselves, but also to be able to export, because again, that’s been a real obstacle that has come up.</p>
<p>I have to confess I am not familiar with but will immediately look into New Zealand’s latest moves and can come back to you on our position on that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll go to the line of Josh Wingrove.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you so much for doing this. Can you offer a little insight into the reiteration yesterday of the 80 million pledge? Should that be interpreted as confidence that the AstraZeneca doses will become available this month, or is the plan to make up the – what is quoted, a 55 million balance due, for lack of a better phrase, with those other authorized vaccines?</p>
<p><strong>MS SMITH:</strong> Yeah, good question. Our expectation and certainly hope is that we will get a clearance from the FDA. Given that that is a regulatory public health agency, we are not going to prejudice that at all and let them come forth with their determination. And then we’ll act on the basis of that. But I think what you heard from the President, the commitment to 80 million vaccines, our current expectation is that the balance after these 25 million will come from the AstraZeneca doses.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll go to the line of Nicole Gaouette.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you for doing this. Two questions. I’m wondering if you could talk us through how you arrived at that distribution – those numbers between Latin America, South and Southeast Asia, and Africa.</p>
<p>And the second part of my question is: When those remaining 55 million doses will be made available whether you have a sense whether they’ll all go to COVAX or whether you’ll also be holding some of those back to distribute bilaterally.</p>
<p><strong>MS SMITH:</strong> Good questions. The way we looked at the numbers (inaudible) – obviously, given the demand, this is a bit challenging. Obviously, we want to give a certain focus to our own hemisphere, and so on the Latin American side that made a big difference – Latin America and the Caribbean. But I think if you look at – we’ve got three regions covered and focused on, because as I said at the top, we want to start laying the ground for global coverage so that when we do the next tranche of shared vaccines, we will be adding another layer of global coverage and so on and so forth. So that’s number one.</p>
<p>Number two is there are a number of places where there are either surge conditions or pre-surge conditions. We’ve seen a spike – many of the countries that have been affected by the extraordinary surge in India, for example. And there are a number of cases there where if we move quickly – you want to make sure healthcare workers are covered and other things. And again, we are trying to be responsive, including to our neighbors. The important thing I’d note on the actual allocation is that, again, this is the first round. This is just the beginning. So as we share more doses, we anticipate having greater coverage.</p>
<p>As to the allocation of the next round, we will likely – I can’t say for certain – follow a similar model to this one, but we can come back to you, absolutely, on that when we’re ready to move on the next tranche. But this seems to be an effective and workable formula.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll go to the line of Patsy Widakuswara.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, yes. Thank you for taking my call and thank you for doing this briefing. Can you speak a little bit about – the administration has been saying that this is not going to be currying political favors, but can you speak a little bit about the branding of these vaccines? We saw some of the shipment that was going out to South Korea had American flags on them. Would there be similar kind of branding even for the shipment that’s going to COVAX?</p>
<p>And my second question is on vaccine patent waiver. We saw that the EU pushed a counterproposal saying that they don’t want to support the TRIPS waiver. Do you think the administration will be pushing for this at the G7? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS SMITH: </strong>Yeah, good question. I think on the branding side I think there’s a real difference between trying to curry political favor and letting countries know that assistance we may be providing is from the American people. I think those are two very different things. So I think people will know. The vaccines will convey that they are from the American people, and I think when vaccines start arriving in country our ambassadors and other staff will be there to greet them. So that’s – yes, that these come from the United States. That’s an important fact and I think people will be well aware of that.</p>
<p>On the EU position, our current position is as it has been, that we support the TRIPS waiver. As you know, the next step on that is very arduous text negotiations by a consensus-based organization which are being led by our U.S. Trade Representative. I suspect that these issues will come up at the G7, but I’m not able to tell you any more specifically on that. I expect, frankly – quite focused on the response to the pandemic in the main.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll go to the line of Carmen Paun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you so much for taking my question. I was wondering if you could say from the 25 million first tranche how many of those are Moderna doses, how many are J&amp;J, and how many are Pfizer, and if you already have a timeline of when they are going to start being shipped out to countries. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS SMITH:</strong> Sure. So what these are – that’s a really good question. What these are is it’s a combination of vaccines from our own stocks. There will be multiple types of vaccines available. And what we will do is there’s a process of sort of matching vaccines to the vaccination program. In some countries they may have some amount of an initial vaccine. J&amp;J may be easier than a two-dose. So we will be working that through with COVAX and with partner countries.</p>
<p>In terms of the timing, we intend to move as quickly as possible. Delivering vaccines and donating vaccines isn’t quite as simple as putting them on plane and dropping them off. There are regulatory and legal procedures that have to be in true. Transporting vaccines, as we’ve seen in the United States, they are important and somewhat delicate medicaments we need to do very carefully. So we’ve got teams set up to do all of that, work through that as quickly as possible and kick off deliveries as soon as we can and to establish a regular cadence. But again, and importantly, there are steps that have to be gone through before we can start moving them, but we’ve already started the work on that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll take a final question from the line of Doug Byun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thanks for doing this. I wanted to ask a question about the shipment to South Korea. President Biden said in his joint press conference with President Jae-in that he would help – the United States would help inoculate 550,000 troops, South Korean troops, and apparently referring to active service members. But – and as a result, the United States sent 1.some million doses of J&amp;J vaccine to South Korea which arrived earlier today. But the thing is the South Korean FDA does not allow people under the age of 30 be inoculated with J&amp;J vaccine, so I was wondering if the United States knew about this South Korean FDA’s regulation regarding J&amp;J vaccine when he made the decision to provide J&amp;J instead of the other two types that you have here.</p>
<p><strong>MS SMITH:</strong> Yes, my understanding – and we may need to do a follow-up with you on this – on this question is that the way this has worked and the way these future deliveries will work is among the first initial steps are to understand what countries have approved which vaccines and then proceed from there through a number of regulatory and legal steps. I would be happy to work with my colleagues to get a more specific answer back to you on that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, Gayle, thank you very much. Thank you very much, everyone, for tuning in and hope everyone has a wonderful weekend.</p>
<p><strong>MS SMITH:</strong> Thanks so much, everybody.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Acting Assistant Secretary Reeker’s Travel to Georgia, Azerbaijan, and Armenia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/acting-assistant-secretary-reekers-travel-to-georgia-azerbaijan-and-armenia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 21:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=249516</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Acting Assistant Secretary for European and Eurasian Affairs Philip T. Reeker will travel to Tbilisi, Georgia; Baku, Azerbaijan; and Yerevan, Armenia June 6-13 to advance bilateral and regional priorities and to express U.S. support for democratic and economic development across the region.</p>
<p>Acting Assistant Secretary Reeker will meet in Georgia with government, opposition, and civil society leaders to discuss full implementation of the April 19 agreement among Georgian political parties as well as Russia’s ongoing aggression against and occupation of Georgia.</p>
<p>In Armenia and Azerbaijan, Acting Assistant Secretary Reeker will meet with government, civil society, and business leaders to discuss bilateral priorities and issues related to the Nagorno-Karabakh conflict.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:EUR-Press-DL@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EUR-Press-DL@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Acting Assistant Secretary for European and Eurasian Affairs Philip T. Reeker will travel to Tbilisi, Georgia; Baku, Azerbaijan; and Yerevan, Armenia June 6-13 to advance bilateral and regional priorities and to express U.S. support for democratic and economic development across the region.</p>
<p>Acting Assistant Secretary Reeker will meet in Georgia with government, opposition, and civil society leaders to discuss full implementation of the April 19 agreement among Georgian political parties as well as Russia’s ongoing aggression against and occupation of Georgia.</p>
<p>In Armenia and Azerbaijan, Acting Assistant Secretary Reeker will meet with government, civil society, and business leaders to discuss bilateral priorities and issues related to the Nagorno-Karabakh conflict.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:EUR-Press-DL@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EUR-Press-DL@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing – June 4, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-june-4-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 20:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=249509</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:06 p.m. EST</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Good afternoon and thank you so much for joining today’s briefing. I just have one announcement at the top, and then we will resume taking questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-249509-AFGHANISTAN"></a> As a part of our continued U.S. support for the people of Afghanistan, Secretary Blinken announced today that the United States is providing more than $266 million in new humanitarian assistance, bringing the total U.S. humanitarian aid for Afghanistan to nearly $3.9 billion since 2002.</p>
<p>For many years, the United States has prioritized support for Afghan returnees, refugees, displaced persons, and other vulnerable populations. This assistance from the American people will allow our partners to provide lifesaving protection, shelter, livelihood opportunities, health care, emergency food aid, water, sanitation, and hygiene services.<a id="post-249509-_Hlk73693778"></a></p>
<p>As the United States withdraws forces from Afghanistan, we will continue to support the peaceful, stable future of – the Afghan people want and deserve, and using our full diplomatic, economic, and assistance toolkit.</p>
<p>We urge the Taliban and Afghan leaders to accelerate progress toward negotiated political settlement and permanent and comprehensive ceasefire to bring an end to more than 40 years of conflict and create the conditions that will allow refugees to return to their homes safely.</p>
<p>And we’ll start taking your questions in just one minute.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Cindy Saine.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, hello. Thank you so much. My Afghan service colleagues are asking whether this new assistance is brand new or whether it was part of the previously announced $300 million. Thank you so much.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Cindy. This – again, to reiterate the announcement at the top, this is new funding, and this funding, to just be a little bit more specific, includes $157.5 million from USAID and also $109 million from the State Department. So that will bring our total from Fiscal Year 2020 and 2021 humanitarian assistance to more than 534 – I’m sorry, $543 million. And again, this totals $3.9 billion since 2002.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Simon Lewis.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> And your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi. Thanks, Jalina. I have a question on Iran. We’re reporting that the U.S., Britain, France, and Germany are not going to seek a resolution – a Board of Governors’ resolution at the IAEA Board of Governors next week over Iran’s failure to explain uranium traces at three sites. Can you confirm that and tell us why?</p>
<p>And if the Iranians fail to explain these – the Iranians fail to explain these uranium traces, why should you trust them to adhere to the terms of a renewed JCPOA agreement, assuming you can get one? And are you going easy on them over this in hopes of securing a new deal? Thanks.</p>
<p><a id="post-249509-IRAN"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Simon. So for your first question, I’m not able to comment on that from here and would have to refer you back to the IAEA. But again, as you know, these talks are ongoing, and again, we’ll continue to underscore that to enable a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA commitments, we’d like to build on the meaningful process that we’ve achieved and keep on doing that moving forward. Other than that, I don’t have anything else to announce.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Said Arikat.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina, for taking my question. Very quickly, Jalina, Secretary of State Antony Blinken met today with Palestinian Americans. Can you share with us the topics he discussed with them and what kind of commitment he may have made or reiterated a U.S. commitment to help the Palestinians?</p>
<p>And second, I also wanted to ask about the ongoing sort of horrible situation in Gaza in terms of medicines, in terms of the people leaving or being allowed to leave the strip. Thank you very kindly.</p>
<p><a id="post-249509-MEP"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> I think if I still have you, number one, I’ll answer your first question quickly. I can confirm the meeting, but I don’t have any other details to preview on the details of the meeting. But if I still have you, Said, can you repeat your first – your second question? Excuse me.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> My second question, the situation has not – and despite there has been a ceasefire for the past, whatever, almost two weeks or close to that, two weeks, yes, in terms of patients who are in need of desperate health care and so on being allowed through the crossings into Israel, and to the West Bank, and to Egypt, and so on. So what is the administration doing in terms of either pressuring Egypt and Israel to allow the Gaza patients in and out? Thank you.</p>
<p>Hello?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, thank you for holding. So what I would say to that is that we’re certainly not going to get ahead of the process that’s underway. And any other details we have to preview, we’ll be able to share those at a later time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jiha Ham.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> And their line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. So the U.S. is sharing 25 million vaccine doses worldwide, but the administration has no plans to share vaccines with the DPRK. I’m wondering if it is because simply there is no such request from North Korea, or it is just because there is a political decision you have made not to share the vaccines with countries like North Korea.</p>
<p>And my second question, if I may, the South Korean Government reiterated its commitment or willingness to resume its tourism project with North Korea. Could you tell us how you view on this? Is tourism between the two Koreas subject to U.S. or international sanctions? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-249509-DPRK"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Jiha. So to your – to answer your first question, no specific comment on any asks from the DPRK. But what I will say is that the United States and this administration has been priding itself as being a leader in vaccine diplomacy.</p>
<p>To your second question, we certainly have no comment from here on that either.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Rosiland Jordan.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> And their line is open. And Rosiland Jordan, if you’re on mute &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, we can hear you now.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, sorry about that. I see that the Secretary is scheduled to appear before the House Foreign Affairs Committee and the Senate Foreign Relations Committee next week to testify about the proposed coming fiscal year budget. Are there particular items in the budget that the Secretary is really going to defend, especially since there is a pronounced anti-foreign aid component among congressional Republicans? And if so, how is he going to make the best case for defending that funding?</p>
<p><a id="post-249509-DEPT"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you for the question, Rosiland. So, of course, we can confirm that the Secretary will be testifying on the Hill next week, but we certainly won’t be able to get ahead of his testimony or preview anything from here today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Hiba Nasr.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you, Jalina, for taking my question. I want to ask a question about Lebanon. The start of the trial of the Ayyash case at a special tribunal for Lebanon has been cancelled due to insufficient funding. And the tribunal itself will have to close if it is unable to solve the funding problem. Do you have any comment on that, especially that the U.S. offered $10 million for information on Ayyash?</p>
<p>And I have one more question on Iran: Do we expect anything or a significant announcement before the Iranian election?</p>
<p><a id="post-249509-IRANLEBANON"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>So to your question on Iran, we don’t have any announcements to make at this time. And to your question on Lebanon, we’re going to have to take that one back for you today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to (inaudible). My apologies if I pronounced your name incorrectly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You did great. Thank you so much, pronouncing (inaudible). Thank you so much for taking my call. I am just going to – regarding – I’m going to ask you regarding the current situation – as you know that Ethiopia – the Ethiopian Government just put out a statement this past weekend – I mean a week ago – for the situation that they going to have a second case for military movements or military action in Tigray. So what’s your assessment of the current situation? Are you still waiting for the Eritreans also to withdraw from Tigray region? And what’s the current situation in term of the overall on your assessment? Thank you so much.</p>
<p><a id="post-249509-ETHIOPIA"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>So thank you for your question. So what I can say at a broad level is that of course the United States has concerns about the crisis in the Tigray region, of course, as well as other threats to both the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ethiopia. The people in Tigray continue to suffer human rights violations, various abuses, atrocities, and urgently need humanitarian relief that is being blocked by the Ethiopian and Eritrean militaries as well as other armed actors. And, of course, the parties – despite any significant diplomatic engagement, we call on the parties to the conflict in Tigray that have no meaningful steps or – to end the hostility, to pursue a peaceful resolution to the political crisis.</p>
<p>Let’s take our last question from Pearl Matibe.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hello, Jalina, and thank you so much for taking my question. Happy Friday. I’m wondering now that we are almost exactly 30 days or a month away from July 4th, the United States celebrates its independence. And given your foreign policy, looking at your domestic policy that determines your foreign policy, where do you think you are at now this number of days into President Biden’s administration? How can you – how are you assessing – what are the indicators that you are succeeding in this new foreign policy approach? Maybe if you can share something about that.</p>
<p><a id="post-249509-DEPT2"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you for your question, Pearl. So as you noted, we are 30 days away from July 4th, but at the same time President Biden has also already previewed all the accomplishments that our administration has made within the first 100 days, so I would have to guide you back to his remarks that he made to the public that day and any other remarks on the administration at a wider level to the White House.</p>
<p>That concludes today’s briefing. Thank you all so much for joining, and I hope you have a great weekend ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:25 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:06 p.m. EST</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Good afternoon and thank you so much for joining today’s briefing. I just have one announcement at the top, and then we will resume taking questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-249509-AFGHANISTAN"></a> As a part of our continued U.S. support for the people of Afghanistan, Secretary Blinken announced today that the United States is providing more than $266 million in new humanitarian assistance, bringing the total U.S. humanitarian aid for Afghanistan to nearly $3.9 billion since 2002.</p>
<p>For many years, the United States has prioritized support for Afghan returnees, refugees, displaced persons, and other vulnerable populations. This assistance from the American people will allow our partners to provide lifesaving protection, shelter, livelihood opportunities, health care, emergency food aid, water, sanitation, and hygiene services.<a id="post-249509-_Hlk73693778"></a></p>
<p>As the United States withdraws forces from Afghanistan, we will continue to support the peaceful, stable future of – the Afghan people want and deserve, and using our full diplomatic, economic, and assistance toolkit.</p>
<p>We urge the Taliban and Afghan leaders to accelerate progress toward negotiated political settlement and permanent and comprehensive ceasefire to bring an end to more than 40 years of conflict and create the conditions that will allow refugees to return to their homes safely.</p>
<p>And we’ll start taking your questions in just one minute.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Cindy Saine.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, hello. Thank you so much. My Afghan service colleagues are asking whether this new assistance is brand new or whether it was part of the previously announced $300 million. Thank you so much.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Cindy. This – again, to reiterate the announcement at the top, this is new funding, and this funding, to just be a little bit more specific, includes $157.5 million from USAID and also $109 million from the State Department. So that will bring our total from Fiscal Year 2020 and 2021 humanitarian assistance to more than 534 – I’m sorry, $543 million. And again, this totals $3.9 billion since 2002.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Simon Lewis.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> And your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi. Thanks, Jalina. I have a question on Iran. We’re reporting that the U.S., Britain, France, and Germany are not going to seek a resolution – a Board of Governors’ resolution at the IAEA Board of Governors next week over Iran’s failure to explain uranium traces at three sites. Can you confirm that and tell us why?</p>
<p>And if the Iranians fail to explain these – the Iranians fail to explain these uranium traces, why should you trust them to adhere to the terms of a renewed JCPOA agreement, assuming you can get one? And are you going easy on them over this in hopes of securing a new deal? Thanks.</p>
<p><a id="post-249509-IRAN"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Simon. So for your first question, I’m not able to comment on that from here and would have to refer you back to the IAEA. But again, as you know, these talks are ongoing, and again, we’ll continue to underscore that to enable a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA commitments, we’d like to build on the meaningful process that we’ve achieved and keep on doing that moving forward. Other than that, I don’t have anything else to announce.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Said Arikat.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina, for taking my question. Very quickly, Jalina, Secretary of State Antony Blinken met today with Palestinian Americans. Can you share with us the topics he discussed with them and what kind of commitment he may have made or reiterated a U.S. commitment to help the Palestinians?</p>
<p>And second, I also wanted to ask about the ongoing sort of horrible situation in Gaza in terms of medicines, in terms of the people leaving or being allowed to leave the strip. Thank you very kindly.</p>
<p><a id="post-249509-MEP"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> I think if I still have you, number one, I’ll answer your first question quickly. I can confirm the meeting, but I don’t have any other details to preview on the details of the meeting. But if I still have you, Said, can you repeat your first – your second question? Excuse me.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> My second question, the situation has not – and despite there has been a ceasefire for the past, whatever, almost two weeks or close to that, two weeks, yes, in terms of patients who are in need of desperate health care and so on being allowed through the crossings into Israel, and to the West Bank, and to Egypt, and so on. So what is the administration doing in terms of either pressuring Egypt and Israel to allow the Gaza patients in and out? Thank you.</p>
<p>Hello?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, thank you for holding. So what I would say to that is that we’re certainly not going to get ahead of the process that’s underway. And any other details we have to preview, we’ll be able to share those at a later time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jiha Ham.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> And their line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. So the U.S. is sharing 25 million vaccine doses worldwide, but the administration has no plans to share vaccines with the DPRK. I’m wondering if it is because simply there is no such request from North Korea, or it is just because there is a political decision you have made not to share the vaccines with countries like North Korea.</p>
<p>And my second question, if I may, the South Korean Government reiterated its commitment or willingness to resume its tourism project with North Korea. Could you tell us how you view on this? Is tourism between the two Koreas subject to U.S. or international sanctions? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-249509-DPRK"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Jiha. So to your – to answer your first question, no specific comment on any asks from the DPRK. But what I will say is that the United States and this administration has been priding itself as being a leader in vaccine diplomacy.</p>
<p>To your second question, we certainly have no comment from here on that either.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Rosiland Jordan.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> And their line is open. And Rosiland Jordan, if you’re on mute &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, we can hear you now.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, sorry about that. I see that the Secretary is scheduled to appear before the House Foreign Affairs Committee and the Senate Foreign Relations Committee next week to testify about the proposed coming fiscal year budget. Are there particular items in the budget that the Secretary is really going to defend, especially since there is a pronounced anti-foreign aid component among congressional Republicans? And if so, how is he going to make the best case for defending that funding?</p>
<p><a id="post-249509-DEPT"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you for the question, Rosiland. So, of course, we can confirm that the Secretary will be testifying on the Hill next week, but we certainly won’t be able to get ahead of his testimony or preview anything from here today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Hiba Nasr.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you, Jalina, for taking my question. I want to ask a question about Lebanon. The start of the trial of the Ayyash case at a special tribunal for Lebanon has been cancelled due to insufficient funding. And the tribunal itself will have to close if it is unable to solve the funding problem. Do you have any comment on that, especially that the U.S. offered $10 million for information on Ayyash?</p>
<p>And I have one more question on Iran: Do we expect anything or a significant announcement before the Iranian election?</p>
<p><a id="post-249509-IRANLEBANON"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>So to your question on Iran, we don’t have any announcements to make at this time. And to your question on Lebanon, we’re going to have to take that one back for you today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to (inaudible). My apologies if I pronounced your name incorrectly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You did great. Thank you so much, pronouncing (inaudible). Thank you so much for taking my call. I am just going to – regarding – I’m going to ask you regarding the current situation – as you know that Ethiopia – the Ethiopian Government just put out a statement this past weekend – I mean a week ago – for the situation that they going to have a second case for military movements or military action in Tigray. So what’s your assessment of the current situation? Are you still waiting for the Eritreans also to withdraw from Tigray region? And what’s the current situation in term of the overall on your assessment? Thank you so much.</p>
<p><a id="post-249509-ETHIOPIA"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>So thank you for your question. So what I can say at a broad level is that of course the United States has concerns about the crisis in the Tigray region, of course, as well as other threats to both the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ethiopia. The people in Tigray continue to suffer human rights violations, various abuses, atrocities, and urgently need humanitarian relief that is being blocked by the Ethiopian and Eritrean militaries as well as other armed actors. And, of course, the parties – despite any significant diplomatic engagement, we call on the parties to the conflict in Tigray that have no meaningful steps or – to end the hostility, to pursue a peaceful resolution to the political crisis.</p>
<p>Let’s take our last question from Pearl Matibe.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hello, Jalina, and thank you so much for taking my question. Happy Friday. I’m wondering now that we are almost exactly 30 days or a month away from July 4th, the United States celebrates its independence. And given your foreign policy, looking at your domestic policy that determines your foreign policy, where do you think you are at now this number of days into President Biden’s administration? How can you – how are you assessing – what are the indicators that you are succeeding in this new foreign policy approach? Maybe if you can share something about that.</p>
<p><a id="post-249509-DEPT2"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you for your question, Pearl. So as you noted, we are 30 days away from July 4th, but at the same time President Biden has also already previewed all the accomplishments that our administration has made within the first 100 days, so I would have to guide you back to his remarks that he made to the public that day and any other remarks on the administration at a wider level to the White House.</p>
<p>That concludes today’s briefing. Thank you all so much for joining, and I hope you have a great weekend ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:25 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Guatemalan Foreign Minister Brolo</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-guatemalan-foreign-minister-brolo-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 19:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=249476</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Guatemalan Foreign Minister Pedro Brolo today.  Secretary Blinken noted that the United States values our partnership with Guatemala and we are closely following the recent challenges to anti-corruption efforts in Guatemala.  The U.S. government continues to work closely with the Public Ministry and the Special Prosecutor’s Office Against Impunity (FECI) to support anti-corruption efforts.  The Secretary expressed deep concern about any efforts to abolish anti-corruption offices, such as FECI, and relayed that the preservation of independent institutions that fight corruption and impunity is fundamental to addressing challenges to security, prosperity, and governance in Guatemala.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Guatemalan Foreign Minister Pedro Brolo today.  Secretary Blinken noted that the United States values our partnership with Guatemala and we are closely following the recent challenges to anti-corruption efforts in Guatemala.  The U.S. government continues to work closely with the Public Ministry and the Special Prosecutor’s Office Against Impunity (FECI) to support anti-corruption efforts.  The Secretary expressed deep concern about any efforts to abolish anti-corruption offices, such as FECI, and relayed that the preservation of independent institutions that fight corruption and impunity is fundamental to addressing challenges to security, prosperity, and governance in Guatemala.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Department of State Debars Seven Persons for Violating or Conspiring to Violate   the Arms Export Control Act   </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-department-of-state-debars-seven-persons-for-violating-or-conspiring-to-violate-the-arms-export-control-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 19:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=249439</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On June 4, 2021, the U.S. Department of State published a Federal Register notice of seven persons statutorily debarred for having been convicted of violating, or conspiring to violate, the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2751, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">et seq.</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">).  This action, pursuant to section 127.7(b) of the International Traffic in Arms Regulations (ITAR) (22 CFR parts 120-130), highlights the Department’s responsibility to protect the integrity of U.S. defense trade.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This notice is provided for purposes of making the public aware that these statutorily debarred persons are prohibited from participating directly or indirectly in activities regulated by the ITAR.  This includes any brokering activities and any export from or temporary import into the United States of defense articles, related technical data, or defense services in any situation covered by the ITAR.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Department’s Office of Defense Trade Controls Compliance in the Bureau of Political-Military Affairs, working in collaboration with the Department of Justice, Homeland Security Investigations, and the Federal Bureau of Investigation, identified the persons subject to statutory debarment based on their criminal conviction by a court of the United States.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Under the terms of the statutory debarment, these individuals and entities are prohibited from participating directly or indirectly in any activities that are subject to the ITAR.  Each individual and entity on this list will remain debarred until the Department approves an application request for reinstatement.  All persons engaged in activities subject to the ITAR should be vigilant in their compliance with all export control regulations and ensure that their activities do not involve debarred persons. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The notice of statutory debarment listing the names of the debarred individuals and entities was published in the </span><a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA2MDQuNDE1MDgyOTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5mZWRlcmFscmVnaXN0ZXIuZ292L2RvY3VtZW50cy8yMDIxLzA2LzA0LzIwMjEtMTE3MzcvYnVyZWF1LW9mLXBvbGl0aWNhbC1taWxpdGFyeS1hZmZhaXJzLXN0YXR1dG9yeS1kZWJhcm1lbnQtdW5kZXItdGhlLWFybXMtZXhwb3J0LWNvbnRyb2wtYWN0LWFuZC10aGUifQ.utSqrIz6IiP8_95cLXLSk_4cV5uWXtT0omyV-2y7gMo/s/1250718950/br/107484762778-l"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Federal Register</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on June 4, 2021.  A </span><a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA2MDQuNDE1MDgyOTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5wbWRkdGMuc3RhdGUuZ292L2RkdGNfcHVibGljP2lkPWRkdGNfa2JfYXJ0aWNsZV9wYWdlJnN5c19pZD03MTg4ZGFjNmRiM2NkMzAwNDRmOWZmNjIxZjk2MTkxNCJ9.OAk7VZsn7J2ua0m-8tUVdB44YTM_VdK1r5H8kdV2xgM/s/1250718950/br/107484762778-l"><span style="font-weight: 400;">full list of all persons subject to statutory debarment</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is available on the website of the PM Bureau’s Directorate of Defense Trade Controls (DDTC).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For additional information, please contact the Bureau of Political-Military Affairs’ Office of Congressional and Public Affairs at PM-CPA@state.gov.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On June 4, 2021, the U.S. Department of State published a Federal Register notice of seven persons statutorily debarred for having been convicted of violating, or conspiring to violate, the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2751, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">et seq.</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">).  This action, pursuant to section 127.7(b) of the International Traffic in Arms Regulations (ITAR) (22 CFR parts 120-130), highlights the Department’s responsibility to protect the integrity of U.S. defense trade.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This notice is provided for purposes of making the public aware that these statutorily debarred persons are prohibited from participating directly or indirectly in activities regulated by the ITAR.  This includes any brokering activities and any export from or temporary import into the United States of defense articles, related technical data, or defense services in any situation covered by the ITAR.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Department’s Office of Defense Trade Controls Compliance in the Bureau of Political-Military Affairs, working in collaboration with the Department of Justice, Homeland Security Investigations, and the Federal Bureau of Investigation, identified the persons subject to statutory debarment based on their criminal conviction by a court of the United States.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Under the terms of the statutory debarment, these individuals and entities are prohibited from participating directly or indirectly in any activities that are subject to the ITAR.  Each individual and entity on this list will remain debarred until the Department approves an application request for reinstatement.  All persons engaged in activities subject to the ITAR should be vigilant in their compliance with all export control regulations and ensure that their activities do not involve debarred persons. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The notice of statutory debarment listing the names of the debarred individuals and entities was published in the </span><a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA2MDQuNDE1MDgyOTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5mZWRlcmFscmVnaXN0ZXIuZ292L2RvY3VtZW50cy8yMDIxLzA2LzA0LzIwMjEtMTE3MzcvYnVyZWF1LW9mLXBvbGl0aWNhbC1taWxpdGFyeS1hZmZhaXJzLXN0YXR1dG9yeS1kZWJhcm1lbnQtdW5kZXItdGhlLWFybXMtZXhwb3J0LWNvbnRyb2wtYWN0LWFuZC10aGUifQ.utSqrIz6IiP8_95cLXLSk_4cV5uWXtT0omyV-2y7gMo/s/1250718950/br/107484762778-l"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Federal Register</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on June 4, 2021.  A </span><a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA2MDQuNDE1MDgyOTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5wbWRkdGMuc3RhdGUuZ292L2RkdGNfcHVibGljP2lkPWRkdGNfa2JfYXJ0aWNsZV9wYWdlJnN5c19pZD03MTg4ZGFjNmRiM2NkMzAwNDRmOWZmNjIxZjk2MTkxNCJ9.OAk7VZsn7J2ua0m-8tUVdB44YTM_VdK1r5H8kdV2xgM/s/1250718950/br/107484762778-l"><span style="font-weight: 400;">full list of all persons subject to statutory debarment</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is available on the website of the PM Bureau’s Directorate of Defense Trade Controls (DDTC).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For additional information, please contact the Bureau of Political-Military Affairs’ Office of Congressional and Public Affairs at PM-CPA@state.gov.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Ortega Regime Should Immediately Release Opposition Leader Cristiana Chamorro  </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-ortega-regime-should-immediately-release-opposition-leader-cristiana-chamorro/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 18:55:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=249431</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States calls on the Nicaraguan government to immediately release opposition leader Cristiana Chamorro and her two colleagues from the recently shuttered Violeta Barrios de Chamorro Foundation for Reconciliation and Democracy.  Their detention on trumped up charges is an abuse of their rights, and it represents an assault on democratic values as well as a clear attempt to thwart free and fair elections. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ms. Chamorro’s arrest comes amid unrelenting attacks on pro-democracy presidential candidates and independent media.  The Ortega regime has pledged to bar Ms. Chamorro from participating in November elections and, in May, baselessly canceled the legal status of two opposition political parties.  Rather than implement electoral reforms by the May deadline established by the Organization of American States, President Ortega instead instituted further restrictions and reduced electoral transparency.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The current conditions of repression and exclusion are not consistent with credible elections.  The region and the international community must stand together with the Nicaraguan people in support of their right to freely choose their government. </span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States calls on the Nicaraguan government to immediately release opposition leader Cristiana Chamorro and her two colleagues from the recently shuttered Violeta Barrios de Chamorro Foundation for Reconciliation and Democracy.  Their detention on trumped up charges is an abuse of their rights, and it represents an assault on democratic values as well as a clear attempt to thwart free and fair elections. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ms. Chamorro’s arrest comes amid unrelenting attacks on pro-democracy presidential candidates and independent media.  The Ortega regime has pledged to bar Ms. Chamorro from participating in November elections and, in May, baselessly canceled the legal status of two opposition political parties.  Rather than implement electoral reforms by the May deadline established by the Organization of American States, President Ortega instead instituted further restrictions and reduced electoral transparency.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The current conditions of repression and exclusion are not consistent with credible elections.  The region and the international community must stand together with the Nicaraguan people in support of their right to freely choose their government. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Continued U.S. Support for a Peaceful, Stable Afghanistan Through New Humanitarian Assistance</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/continued-u-s-support-for-a-peaceful-stable-afghanistan-through-new-humanitarian-assistance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 16:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=249369</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>As part of our commitment to the people of Afghanistan, the United States is providing more than $266 million in new humanitarian assistance, bringing total U.S. humanitarian aid for Afghanistan to nearly $3.9 billion since 2002.</p>
<p>This assistance from the American people will help our international humanitarian partners provide support to some of the estimated 18 million people in need in Afghanistan, including more than 4.8 million Afghans internally displaced.  This year alone, more than 115,000 persons have been displaced by conflict inside Afghanistan, and nearly 500,000 have returned to Afghanistan in need of assistance.  This funding will allow our partners to provide lifesaving protection, shelter, livelihoods opportunities, essential health care, emergency food aid, water, sanitation, and hygiene services to respond to the needs generated by the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic.  Furthermore, this assistance helps to address protection needs for the most vulnerable Afghans.  This includes women and girls facing particular risks, including gender-based violence, as a result of the pandemic and decades of conflict.</p>
<p>We welcome the contributions of other donors toward this international response and urge others to generously support Afghanistan’s immediate humanitarian needs.  Afghanistan’s neighbors have hosted one of the largest, most-protracted refugee populations in the world.  We thank host countries for their ongoing commitment to the Afghan people and urge them to keep their borders open to Afghans seeking international protection and are working with our partners to assist host countries in their efforts.</p>
<p>For many years, the United States has prioritized support for Afghan returnees, refugees, and displaced persons.  As the United States withdraws military forces from Afghanistan, our enduring commitment is clear.  We remain engaged through our full diplomatic, economic, and assistance toolkit to support the peaceful, stable future the Afghan people want and deserve.  We urge Afghan leaders and the Taliban to accelerate progress toward a negotiated political settlement and permanent and comprehensive ceasefire to bring an end to over forty years of conflict and create the conditions that will allow refugees to return to their homes safely.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>As part of our commitment to the people of Afghanistan, the United States is providing more than $266 million in new humanitarian assistance, bringing total U.S. humanitarian aid for Afghanistan to nearly $3.9 billion since 2002.</p>
<p>This assistance from the American people will help our international humanitarian partners provide support to some of the estimated 18 million people in need in Afghanistan, including more than 4.8 million Afghans internally displaced.  This year alone, more than 115,000 persons have been displaced by conflict inside Afghanistan, and nearly 500,000 have returned to Afghanistan in need of assistance.  This funding will allow our partners to provide lifesaving protection, shelter, livelihoods opportunities, essential health care, emergency food aid, water, sanitation, and hygiene services to respond to the needs generated by the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic.  Furthermore, this assistance helps to address protection needs for the most vulnerable Afghans.  This includes women and girls facing particular risks, including gender-based violence, as a result of the pandemic and decades of conflict.</p>
<p>We welcome the contributions of other donors toward this international response and urge others to generously support Afghanistan’s immediate humanitarian needs.  Afghanistan’s neighbors have hosted one of the largest, most-protracted refugee populations in the world.  We thank host countries for their ongoing commitment to the Afghan people and urge them to keep their borders open to Afghans seeking international protection and are working with our partners to assist host countries in their efforts.</p>
<p>For many years, the United States has prioritized support for Afghan returnees, refugees, and displaced persons.  As the United States withdraws military forces from Afghanistan, our enduring commitment is clear.  We remain engaged through our full diplomatic, economic, and assistance toolkit to support the peaceful, stable future the Afghan people want and deserve.  We urge Afghan leaders and the Taliban to accelerate progress toward a negotiated political settlement and permanent and comprehensive ceasefire to bring an end to over forty years of conflict and create the conditions that will allow refugees to return to their homes safely.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Omani Foreign Minister Al Busaidi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-omani-foreign-minister-al-busaidi-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 15:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=249361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Omani Foreign Minister Sayyid Badr Al Busaidi.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed efforts to reduce risks of further conflict between Israel, Hamas, and other parties in Gaza.  Secretary Blinken also affirmed the United States’ commitment to a two-state solution and underscored that Palestinians and Israelis equally deserve to live in safety and security and with dignity.  In addition, the Secretary and Foreign Minister noted the importance of an immediate, comprehensive ceasefire to help bring the war in Yemen and the humanitarian suffering of the Yemeni people to an end.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Omani Foreign Minister Sayyid Badr Al Busaidi.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed efforts to reduce risks of further conflict between Israel, Hamas, and other parties in Gaza.  Secretary Blinken also affirmed the United States’ commitment to a two-state solution and underscored that Palestinians and Israelis equally deserve to live in safety and security and with dignity.  In addition, the Secretary and Foreign Minister noted the importance of an immediate, comprehensive ceasefire to help bring the war in Yemen and the humanitarian suffering of the Yemeni people to an end.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Lenderking Returns from Travel to Saudi Arabia, Oman, the UAE, and Jordan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-special-envoy-for-yemen-lenderking-returns-from-travel-to-saudi-arabia-oman-the-uae-and-jordan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 11:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=249214</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking returned on June 3 from travel to Saudi Arabia, Oman, the UAE, and Jordan.  During his trip, Special Envoy Lenderking met with senior government officials, international partners, and Yemenis to discuss the humanitarian and economic crisis in Yemen and the urgent need for a comprehensive ceasefire to bring relief to Yemenis.  The Special Envoy coordinated closely with UN Special Envoy Martin Griffiths during his trip and welcomed Griffiths’ latest trip to Sana’a.  While there are numerous problematic actors inside of Yemen, the Houthis bear major responsibility for refusing to engage meaningfully on a ceasefire and to take steps to resolve a nearly seven-year conflict that has brought unimaginable suffering to the Yemeni people.  Instead, the Houthis continue a devastating offensive on Marib that is condemned by the international community and leaves the Houthis increasingly isolated.  During his meetings with Yemenis, Lenderking also discussed the need to strengthen inclusive processes that enable the country&#8217;s citizens to discuss the future of their country and amplify voices for peace.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For any questions, please contact Vanessa Vidal at </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEA-Press@state.gov</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">and follow us on Twitter </span><a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA2MDQuNDE0Nzk1NjEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3R3aXR0ZXIuY29tL1N0YXRlRGVwdF9ORUEjX2JsYW5rIn0.vHGWmYG3fsaFoD8QZEKHpWGyU26XHOmtwhIK4RzGD7s/s/1248191874/br/107454774662-l"><span style="font-weight: 400;">@StateDept_NEA</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking returned on June 3 from travel to Saudi Arabia, Oman, the UAE, and Jordan.  During his trip, Special Envoy Lenderking met with senior government officials, international partners, and Yemenis to discuss the humanitarian and economic crisis in Yemen and the urgent need for a comprehensive ceasefire to bring relief to Yemenis.  The Special Envoy coordinated closely with UN Special Envoy Martin Griffiths during his trip and welcomed Griffiths’ latest trip to Sana’a.  While there are numerous problematic actors inside of Yemen, the Houthis bear major responsibility for refusing to engage meaningfully on a ceasefire and to take steps to resolve a nearly seven-year conflict that has brought unimaginable suffering to the Yemeni people.  Instead, the Houthis continue a devastating offensive on Marib that is condemned by the international community and leaves the Houthis increasingly isolated.  During his meetings with Yemenis, Lenderking also discussed the need to strengthen inclusive processes that enable the country&#8217;s citizens to discuss the future of their country and amplify voices for peace.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For any questions, please contact Vanessa Vidal at </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEA-Press@state.gov</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">and follow us on Twitter </span><a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA2MDQuNDE0Nzk1NjEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3R3aXR0ZXIuY29tL1N0YXRlRGVwdF9ORUEjX2JsYW5rIn0.vHGWmYG3fsaFoD8QZEKHpWGyU26XHOmtwhIK4RzGD7s/s/1248191874/br/107454774662-l"><span style="font-weight: 400;">@StateDept_NEA</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On the 32nd Anniversary of Tiananmen Square</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/on-the-32nd-anniversary-of-tiananmen-square/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 23:12:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=249123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p align="left">Tomorrow marks the 32nd anniversary of the Tiananmen Square massacre.  Named after the nearby Gate of Heavenly Peace, the square is instead synonymous with the brutal actions by the Government of the People’s Republic of China (PRC) in 1989 to silence tens of thousands of individuals advocating to have a say in their government and exercise their human rights and fundamental freedoms.</p>
<p align="left">These individuals had a noble and simple request: Recognize and respect our human rights, which are enshrined in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.  Instead of meeting this request with dignity and open debate, PRC authorities responded with violence.  The courage of the brave individuals who stood shoulder-to-shoulder on June 4 reminds us that we must never stop seeking transparency on the events of that day, including a full accounting of all those killed, detained, or missing. The Tiananmen demonstrations are echoed in the struggle for democracy and freedom in Hong Kong, where a planned vigil to commemorate the massacre in Tiananmen Square was banned by local authorities.</p>
<p align="left">The United States will continue to stand with the people of China as they demand that their government respect universal human rights.  We honor the sacrifices of those killed 32 years ago, and the brave activists who carry on their efforts today in the face of ongoing government repression.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p align="left">Tomorrow marks the 32nd anniversary of the Tiananmen Square massacre.  Named after the nearby Gate of Heavenly Peace, the square is instead synonymous with the brutal actions by the Government of the People’s Republic of China (PRC) in 1989 to silence tens of thousands of individuals advocating to have a say in their government and exercise their human rights and fundamental freedoms.</p>
<p align="left">These individuals had a noble and simple request: Recognize and respect our human rights, which are enshrined in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.  Instead of meeting this request with dignity and open debate, PRC authorities responded with violence.  The courage of the brave individuals who stood shoulder-to-shoulder on June 4 reminds us that we must never stop seeking transparency on the events of that day, including a full accounting of all those killed, detained, or missing. The Tiananmen demonstrations are echoed in the struggle for democracy and freedom in Hong Kong, where a planned vigil to commemorate the massacre in Tiananmen Square was banned by local authorities.</p>
<p align="left">The United States will continue to stand with the people of China as they demand that their government respect universal human rights.  We honor the sacrifices of those killed 32 years ago, and the brave activists who carry on their efforts today in the face of ongoing government repression.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
