<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:41:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Domestic Renewal as a Foreign Policy Priority</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/domestic-renewal-as-a-foreign-policy-priority/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 23:14:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=269116</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>College Park, MD</p>
<p>University of Maryland A. James Clark School of Engineering </p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.</p>
<p>It is wonderful to be here at the University of Maryland, College Park, one of our country’s outstanding public research universities, to be joined by some of the students, university leaders, and public servants who help make this community such a dynamic place to learn, to teach, and to create.</p>
<p>Mr. President, I especially want to thank you, both for your kind words, for hosting us today, and for your leadership of this institution.  Leader Hoyer, it’s always an honor and a pleasure to be with you.  I know you’re a very proud alum of this university.  Thank you so much for taking the time to join us, as well as to my colleagues and friends, Senator Cardin, Senator Van Hollen.  Now, I’m flattered to think that I had something to do with you being out here this afternoon, but I know that’s not the case.  It’s this university, the University of Maryland.  I know your strong support across the board for this extraordinary institution and I’m glad to be able to share in that with you today.</p>
<p>And Sarah, a special thanks to you for a wonderful introduction.  Look, in the unlikely event that engineering somehow doesn’t work out, diplomacy, think about it.  We may want to bring you in.  Thank you so much.</p>
<p>The best part of today for me is getting to spend time with some of the extraordinary young people here at College Park.</p>
<p>As Secretary, I’m often focused on events that are taking place thousands of miles away.  The last lab that I actually toured was at the University of Copenhagen, so across an ocean.  But I wanted to come here today to the University of Maryland – 10 miles from the State Department – because, as has been noted, the innovation happening here and at thousands of colleges and universities across America is a huge source of our strength.</p>
<p>And whether America protects and invests in our strength at home is going to determine whether we remain strong in the world and deliver results for the American people.</p>
<p>I’ve got to tell you that maybe more than at any other time in my career – maybe in my lifetime – old distinctions between domestic and foreign policy have simply fallen away.  Our domestic renewal and our strength in the world are completely entwined.</p>
<p>And that’s why I’m here today, because there’s nothing we can do that will enhance our global standing and influence more than what our domestic renewal can deliver, particularly when it comes to the strength of our workforce, our economic dynamism, the quality of opportunity we offer our people, the resilience of our infrastructure, and the power of our innovation.</p>
<p>And I’m here to tell you that we could be doing better.  That is the hard truth.</p>
<p>We’re falling behind where we once were in the world.  And our rivals, slowly but surely, are pulling close behind us.  In some areas, they’re already ahead of us.</p>
<p>And this matters.</p>
<p>It matters because if these trends continue, we’ll be less competitive in a more competitive world.</p>
<p>The weight of our diplomacy and our ability to advance the interests and values of the American people will suffer.</p>
<p>And the democratic model and way of life will be less able to withstand a fierce challenge from authoritarian governments.</p>
<p>Most of all, investing in our domestic renewal now will make our future more secure, more prosperous, more free.</p>
<p>So what I’d like to do today is talk about the foreign policy, the national security case for public investment at home, because it’s vital that we act.</p>
<p>And let’s start by stepping back for just a minute.</p>
<p>I think you all know this very, very well:  For a long time, America made big investments in ourselves.</p>
<p>We established universal elementary school.  We made investments in public secondary education.  Between 1910 and 1940, the percentage of American teens in high school went from 18 percent to 70 percent.  President Lincoln signed into law land-grant colleges, like the University of Maryland, so that more people could get higher education.  President Roosevelt signed the GI Bill so more service members and veterans could go to college and get job training, and more than 50 percent of its beneficiaries went on to start a business.</p>
<p>These and other programs weren’t perfect.  We know that.  They weren’t equitable.  Many people were left out because of their race or gender.  We’re still working to close those gaps today.  But these investments helped America’s economy leap ahead and made the United States workforce the wealthiest and best educated in the entire world.</p>
<p>Through the decades, we also invested in roads, in railways, in highways, in ports, airports, power grids, water systems – a vast public infrastructure that was the foundation for us becoming the strongest economy in the world, with a workforce and standard of living that set us apart.</p>
<p>But in recent decades, our public investment as a share of the economy has fallen more than 40 percent.  We’re still relying heavily on those earlier achievements – schools, roads, and innovations created a long time ago.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, other countries have doubled down.  For example, China is spending three times as much on infrastructure as we do every year.  And it’s not just China.  The United States now ranks 13th in the world in the total quality of our infrastructure, and if we don’t make major investments soon, it’ll be more than just 12 countries ahead of us.</p>
<p>We’re falling behind on innovation.  Thirty years ago, we ranked number one in the world in terms of how much we invested as a share of our economy in research and development.  It’s how we won the space race, mapped the human genome, built the internet.  Now we’re number nine.  China used to be number eight.  Now they’re number two.</p>
<p>Here at the Clark School, students are learning advanced manufacturing technologies, like this hyperloop pod for mag-lev high-speed train travel, created by the award-winning UMD Loop team, made up entirely of undergraduates.  I just got a tour of the Advanced Fabrication Lab and saw some of what you’re creating here with 3D printing.  We as a country should be doing much more to support this kind of work.  The bipartisan U.S. Innovation and Competition Act, for example, which the Senate has approved, would boost federal funding for U.S.-based semiconductor manufacturing and provide $52 billion over five years for research initiatives.  Because research in fields like robotics, artificial intelligence, nanotech, and solar cells is racing ahead – and too often, we are not the ones out in front.  We’re missing out on the chance to build and lead the industries of the future.</p>
<p>Now, there’s no question that the free market can do a lot to spur investment.  The creativity, ingenuity, and dynamism of the American private sector is unmatched in the world.  It’s our greatest competitive advantage.  But there are some things that even the most vibrant private sector can’t do on its own.  Public investment is still vital.</p>
<p>Moreover, America’s entrepreneurs are able to do their pathbreaking work in part because of the foundation provided by public investment.  The work of the most brilliant scientists is rooted in publicly funded basic research.  Companies run on public utilities.  Public schools helped educate their workforce.</p>
<p>So public and private investment are both essential.  It’s not either/or.  It’s both/and.</p>
<p>Now, make no mistake – we are still the most powerful country and economy in the world.  We’re resilient and entrepreneurial; there’s a reason the world’s most successful companies are born here.  Our network of alliances and partnership with other countries is unmatched; our military is the most powerful fighting force on the planet.  And the American workforce is outstanding, and that includes all the people from other countries who move to the United States every year to work hard and build better lives for themselves, because this is still the place where the world’s strivers and dreamers want to be.</p>
<p>As President Biden says, it’s never a good bet to bet against America – never has been, never will be.</p>
<p>But we became the United States of America because past generations of Americans reinvented, renewed, and reinvested in our core sources of strength.  They used American ingenuity and determination to do it – and they didn’t just to prepare for the future, they created it.  They shaped it.</p>
<p>Now it’s our job to take up the baton and carry it forward for future generations.</p>
<p>I believe our domestic renewal is the most important thing we can do to advance our foreign policy for three reasons.</p>
<p>First, this is about our global competitiveness.</p>
<p>We’re competing for jobs.  We want the high-skilled, high-paying careers of the future to be created here, not somewhere else.</p>
<p>We’re competing for investment.  We want the investors, the companies, the countries to look at the United States and say, “That’s where we want to be.”  And they’re much more likely to say that when they know that everything about operating in America is top of the line, from the reliability of our broadband to the efficiency of our ports to how well-trained our workers are.</p>
<p>We’re competing for trade.  For too long, we thought we could trade more with the world while investing less here at home.  That didn’t work out for our economy, for our workers, or for our communities.  President Biden has made it clear that before making more trade deals, we must first make a generational investment in our own competitiveness.  Our domestic renewal comes first.  If we do that, we will compete in the 21st-century global economy from a position of strength.  We will keep faith with American workers; shape the terms of global trade; ensure that labor, environmental, and intellectual property standards are protected; and stand with our allies and partners when others seek to take advantage of them.</p>
<p>We’re also competing for the best and the brightest.  One of the most powerful, I say even magical things about the United States is that we have long been a destination for talented, driven people from everywhere on Earth.  No other country has that kind of pull on people’s imaginations and ambitions.  And that also goes for our universities.  There are thousands of top international students here at College Park getting a world-class education; we’re lucky they chose us.  We want always to be the place that represents opportunity, possibility, achievement.  Investing in our domestic renewal now means that we can continue to be that beacon to the world.</p>
<p>Second, our domestic renewal is a foreign policy priority because it empowers our diplomacy.  Take it from me, when you’re sitting at the table with foreign leaders, trying to persuade them to align with your point of view or join your coalition or stop doing something that you disagree with, it makes all the difference in the world to be operating from a position of national strength.  And that goes far beyond military might.  If your economy is growing, if your people are healthy, if the cultural life of your country is thriving, if your country is known to give people from all backgrounds access to opportunity, it all adds up to greater diplomatic strength.</p>
<p>Countries pay attention to these things.  And they pay attention if you aren’t strong in those ways, too.</p>
<p>This is particularly important now, because it’s no secret to any of us that the Chinese and Russian governments, among others, are making the argument in public and in private that the United States is in decline – so it’s better to cast your lot with their authoritarian visions for the world than with our democratic one.</p>
<p>We can and we do remind them that we continue to be an abundantly strong country by measure after measure.  When we met with Chinese officials in Anchorage in March, our first topic of discussion was what we’re achieving here at home – a robust economic recovery, a massive national program to fight COVID.  We wanted them to know that we will emerge from the pandemic stronger than before and better able to rally our friends and partners in the world to stand up against aggression, abuse, and coercion.</p>
<p>Nothing would put to rest faster their specious argument about America’s best days being behind us than if the United States made serious investments in our domestic renewal right now.  It’s a lot harder to say a country is in decline when you’re watching it become stronger, more effective, more united before your very eyes.</p>
<p>I can tell you, too, that from my own experience so far as Secretary of State, when I tell countries that America is back, they believe it because they’re seeing how much effort we’re putting into building our alliances and partnerships, and showing up again in the rooms where decisions are made and democratic principles are defended.  But they will believe it even more when we make major investments in our own renewal here at home.  And that will make my job of advancing our interests and values around the world easier because there’ll be no question that America is back.</p>
<p>I can also tell you that our friends around the world are also hoping that we’ll make these investments.  They want badly for us to succeed because they know that when we’re strong, they benefit too.</p>
<p>Third, our domestic renewal is about standing up for democracy<strong>, </strong>and that is a foreign policy imperative.</p>
<p>Democracy is under threat around the world right now.  Authoritarianism and nationalism are on the rise.  And the United States is out there every day fighting the good fight for political freedom and human rights.  We’re making the argument that our system – the democratic system – is the better one.  But it’s one thing to say it; it’s another to show it.  By investing in our strength at home, we can show the world that democracies can do hard things and that we can do them without jailing dissidents, letting corruption run rampant, or violating fundamental freedoms.</p>
<p>The more we and all democracies can show the world that we can deliver – for our people, for each other – the more we can refute the lie that authoritarian countries love to tell – that our system is hopelessly polarized and paralyzed and that theirs is the better way to meet people’s fundamental needs and hopes.</p>
<p>Now, I’ve said the word “China” a few times today, and it’s true that when we talk about competitors, we often talk about China.  They’re a rising power.  And they’re full speed ahead when it comes to investing in infrastructure, growth, innovation.</p>
<p>But I’m not only talking about China here today.  Many countries are making major investments in their own domestic renewal right now.  For the United States to continue to lead and to successfully bring countries together in common cause for the good of all our people, we have to do the same.</p>
<p>Plus, ultimately, this isn’t really about anyone else.  This is about us and what we can do to make our lives and our future even brighter.</p>
<p>When President Biden gave me the honor of taking on the role of America’s chief diplomat, he made it crystal clear that I had one job above all others: to help deliver for the American people, to make your lives more secure, create opportunity for you and your families, and tackle the global crises that are increasingly shaping your lives.  My ability to do that – and the ability for everyone who holds this job after me to do that – will depend on the choices we make as a country now and in the months and years to come.</p>
<p>At our best, the American people share a spirit of boundless optimism and possibility.  People around the world are inspired by it; I hear that everywhere I go.  We need to bring that spirit to bear in this endeavor to renew our sources of domestic strength and invest in our future greatness.  That’s how we’ll lead the world in the industries of tomorrow and that’s how we’ll carry forward the eternal work of making the United States a more perfect union.</p>
<p>Thank so much for listening.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>College Park, MD</p>
<p>University of Maryland A. James Clark School of Engineering </p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.</p>
<p>It is wonderful to be here at the University of Maryland, College Park, one of our country’s outstanding public research universities, to be joined by some of the students, university leaders, and public servants who help make this community such a dynamic place to learn, to teach, and to create.</p>
<p>Mr. President, I especially want to thank you, both for your kind words, for hosting us today, and for your leadership of this institution.  Leader Hoyer, it’s always an honor and a pleasure to be with you.  I know you’re a very proud alum of this university.  Thank you so much for taking the time to join us, as well as to my colleagues and friends, Senator Cardin, Senator Van Hollen.  Now, I’m flattered to think that I had something to do with you being out here this afternoon, but I know that’s not the case.  It’s this university, the University of Maryland.  I know your strong support across the board for this extraordinary institution and I’m glad to be able to share in that with you today.</p>
<p>And Sarah, a special thanks to you for a wonderful introduction.  Look, in the unlikely event that engineering somehow doesn’t work out, diplomacy, think about it.  We may want to bring you in.  Thank you so much.</p>
<p>The best part of today for me is getting to spend time with some of the extraordinary young people here at College Park.</p>
<p>As Secretary, I’m often focused on events that are taking place thousands of miles away.  The last lab that I actually toured was at the University of Copenhagen, so across an ocean.  But I wanted to come here today to the University of Maryland – 10 miles from the State Department – because, as has been noted, the innovation happening here and at thousands of colleges and universities across America is a huge source of our strength.</p>
<p>And whether America protects and invests in our strength at home is going to determine whether we remain strong in the world and deliver results for the American people.</p>
<p>I’ve got to tell you that maybe more than at any other time in my career – maybe in my lifetime – old distinctions between domestic and foreign policy have simply fallen away.  Our domestic renewal and our strength in the world are completely entwined.</p>
<p>And that’s why I’m here today, because there’s nothing we can do that will enhance our global standing and influence more than what our domestic renewal can deliver, particularly when it comes to the strength of our workforce, our economic dynamism, the quality of opportunity we offer our people, the resilience of our infrastructure, and the power of our innovation.</p>
<p>And I’m here to tell you that we could be doing better.  That is the hard truth.</p>
<p>We’re falling behind where we once were in the world.  And our rivals, slowly but surely, are pulling close behind us.  In some areas, they’re already ahead of us.</p>
<p>And this matters.</p>
<p>It matters because if these trends continue, we’ll be less competitive in a more competitive world.</p>
<p>The weight of our diplomacy and our ability to advance the interests and values of the American people will suffer.</p>
<p>And the democratic model and way of life will be less able to withstand a fierce challenge from authoritarian governments.</p>
<p>Most of all, investing in our domestic renewal now will make our future more secure, more prosperous, more free.</p>
<p>So what I’d like to do today is talk about the foreign policy, the national security case for public investment at home, because it’s vital that we act.</p>
<p>And let’s start by stepping back for just a minute.</p>
<p>I think you all know this very, very well:  For a long time, America made big investments in ourselves.</p>
<p>We established universal elementary school.  We made investments in public secondary education.  Between 1910 and 1940, the percentage of American teens in high school went from 18 percent to 70 percent.  President Lincoln signed into law land-grant colleges, like the University of Maryland, so that more people could get higher education.  President Roosevelt signed the GI Bill so more service members and veterans could go to college and get job training, and more than 50 percent of its beneficiaries went on to start a business.</p>
<p>These and other programs weren’t perfect.  We know that.  They weren’t equitable.  Many people were left out because of their race or gender.  We’re still working to close those gaps today.  But these investments helped America’s economy leap ahead and made the United States workforce the wealthiest and best educated in the entire world.</p>
<p>Through the decades, we also invested in roads, in railways, in highways, in ports, airports, power grids, water systems – a vast public infrastructure that was the foundation for us becoming the strongest economy in the world, with a workforce and standard of living that set us apart.</p>
<p>But in recent decades, our public investment as a share of the economy has fallen more than 40 percent.  We’re still relying heavily on those earlier achievements – schools, roads, and innovations created a long time ago.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, other countries have doubled down.  For example, China is spending three times as much on infrastructure as we do every year.  And it’s not just China.  The United States now ranks 13th in the world in the total quality of our infrastructure, and if we don’t make major investments soon, it’ll be more than just 12 countries ahead of us.</p>
<p>We’re falling behind on innovation.  Thirty years ago, we ranked number one in the world in terms of how much we invested as a share of our economy in research and development.  It’s how we won the space race, mapped the human genome, built the internet.  Now we’re number nine.  China used to be number eight.  Now they’re number two.</p>
<p>Here at the Clark School, students are learning advanced manufacturing technologies, like this hyperloop pod for mag-lev high-speed train travel, created by the award-winning UMD Loop team, made up entirely of undergraduates.  I just got a tour of the Advanced Fabrication Lab and saw some of what you’re creating here with 3D printing.  We as a country should be doing much more to support this kind of work.  The bipartisan U.S. Innovation and Competition Act, for example, which the Senate has approved, would boost federal funding for U.S.-based semiconductor manufacturing and provide $52 billion over five years for research initiatives.  Because research in fields like robotics, artificial intelligence, nanotech, and solar cells is racing ahead – and too often, we are not the ones out in front.  We’re missing out on the chance to build and lead the industries of the future.</p>
<p>Now, there’s no question that the free market can do a lot to spur investment.  The creativity, ingenuity, and dynamism of the American private sector is unmatched in the world.  It’s our greatest competitive advantage.  But there are some things that even the most vibrant private sector can’t do on its own.  Public investment is still vital.</p>
<p>Moreover, America’s entrepreneurs are able to do their pathbreaking work in part because of the foundation provided by public investment.  The work of the most brilliant scientists is rooted in publicly funded basic research.  Companies run on public utilities.  Public schools helped educate their workforce.</p>
<p>So public and private investment are both essential.  It’s not either/or.  It’s both/and.</p>
<p>Now, make no mistake – we are still the most powerful country and economy in the world.  We’re resilient and entrepreneurial; there’s a reason the world’s most successful companies are born here.  Our network of alliances and partnership with other countries is unmatched; our military is the most powerful fighting force on the planet.  And the American workforce is outstanding, and that includes all the people from other countries who move to the United States every year to work hard and build better lives for themselves, because this is still the place where the world’s strivers and dreamers want to be.</p>
<p>As President Biden says, it’s never a good bet to bet against America – never has been, never will be.</p>
<p>But we became the United States of America because past generations of Americans reinvented, renewed, and reinvested in our core sources of strength.  They used American ingenuity and determination to do it – and they didn’t just to prepare for the future, they created it.  They shaped it.</p>
<p>Now it’s our job to take up the baton and carry it forward for future generations.</p>
<p>I believe our domestic renewal is the most important thing we can do to advance our foreign policy for three reasons.</p>
<p>First, this is about our global competitiveness.</p>
<p>We’re competing for jobs.  We want the high-skilled, high-paying careers of the future to be created here, not somewhere else.</p>
<p>We’re competing for investment.  We want the investors, the companies, the countries to look at the United States and say, “That’s where we want to be.”  And they’re much more likely to say that when they know that everything about operating in America is top of the line, from the reliability of our broadband to the efficiency of our ports to how well-trained our workers are.</p>
<p>We’re competing for trade.  For too long, we thought we could trade more with the world while investing less here at home.  That didn’t work out for our economy, for our workers, or for our communities.  President Biden has made it clear that before making more trade deals, we must first make a generational investment in our own competitiveness.  Our domestic renewal comes first.  If we do that, we will compete in the 21st-century global economy from a position of strength.  We will keep faith with American workers; shape the terms of global trade; ensure that labor, environmental, and intellectual property standards are protected; and stand with our allies and partners when others seek to take advantage of them.</p>
<p>We’re also competing for the best and the brightest.  One of the most powerful, I say even magical things about the United States is that we have long been a destination for talented, driven people from everywhere on Earth.  No other country has that kind of pull on people’s imaginations and ambitions.  And that also goes for our universities.  There are thousands of top international students here at College Park getting a world-class education; we’re lucky they chose us.  We want always to be the place that represents opportunity, possibility, achievement.  Investing in our domestic renewal now means that we can continue to be that beacon to the world.</p>
<p>Second, our domestic renewal is a foreign policy priority because it empowers our diplomacy.  Take it from me, when you’re sitting at the table with foreign leaders, trying to persuade them to align with your point of view or join your coalition or stop doing something that you disagree with, it makes all the difference in the world to be operating from a position of national strength.  And that goes far beyond military might.  If your economy is growing, if your people are healthy, if the cultural life of your country is thriving, if your country is known to give people from all backgrounds access to opportunity, it all adds up to greater diplomatic strength.</p>
<p>Countries pay attention to these things.  And they pay attention if you aren’t strong in those ways, too.</p>
<p>This is particularly important now, because it’s no secret to any of us that the Chinese and Russian governments, among others, are making the argument in public and in private that the United States is in decline – so it’s better to cast your lot with their authoritarian visions for the world than with our democratic one.</p>
<p>We can and we do remind them that we continue to be an abundantly strong country by measure after measure.  When we met with Chinese officials in Anchorage in March, our first topic of discussion was what we’re achieving here at home – a robust economic recovery, a massive national program to fight COVID.  We wanted them to know that we will emerge from the pandemic stronger than before and better able to rally our friends and partners in the world to stand up against aggression, abuse, and coercion.</p>
<p>Nothing would put to rest faster their specious argument about America’s best days being behind us than if the United States made serious investments in our domestic renewal right now.  It’s a lot harder to say a country is in decline when you’re watching it become stronger, more effective, more united before your very eyes.</p>
<p>I can tell you, too, that from my own experience so far as Secretary of State, when I tell countries that America is back, they believe it because they’re seeing how much effort we’re putting into building our alliances and partnerships, and showing up again in the rooms where decisions are made and democratic principles are defended.  But they will believe it even more when we make major investments in our own renewal here at home.  And that will make my job of advancing our interests and values around the world easier because there’ll be no question that America is back.</p>
<p>I can also tell you that our friends around the world are also hoping that we’ll make these investments.  They want badly for us to succeed because they know that when we’re strong, they benefit too.</p>
<p>Third, our domestic renewal is about standing up for democracy<strong>, </strong>and that is a foreign policy imperative.</p>
<p>Democracy is under threat around the world right now.  Authoritarianism and nationalism are on the rise.  And the United States is out there every day fighting the good fight for political freedom and human rights.  We’re making the argument that our system – the democratic system – is the better one.  But it’s one thing to say it; it’s another to show it.  By investing in our strength at home, we can show the world that democracies can do hard things and that we can do them without jailing dissidents, letting corruption run rampant, or violating fundamental freedoms.</p>
<p>The more we and all democracies can show the world that we can deliver – for our people, for each other – the more we can refute the lie that authoritarian countries love to tell – that our system is hopelessly polarized and paralyzed and that theirs is the better way to meet people’s fundamental needs and hopes.</p>
<p>Now, I’ve said the word “China” a few times today, and it’s true that when we talk about competitors, we often talk about China.  They’re a rising power.  And they’re full speed ahead when it comes to investing in infrastructure, growth, innovation.</p>
<p>But I’m not only talking about China here today.  Many countries are making major investments in their own domestic renewal right now.  For the United States to continue to lead and to successfully bring countries together in common cause for the good of all our people, we have to do the same.</p>
<p>Plus, ultimately, this isn’t really about anyone else.  This is about us and what we can do to make our lives and our future even brighter.</p>
<p>When President Biden gave me the honor of taking on the role of America’s chief diplomat, he made it crystal clear that I had one job above all others: to help deliver for the American people, to make your lives more secure, create opportunity for you and your families, and tackle the global crises that are increasingly shaping your lives.  My ability to do that – and the ability for everyone who holds this job after me to do that – will depend on the choices we make as a country now and in the months and years to come.</p>
<p>At our best, the American people share a spirit of boundless optimism and possibility.  People around the world are inspired by it; I hear that everywhere I go.  We need to bring that spirit to bear in this endeavor to renew our sources of domestic strength and invest in our future greatness.  That’s how we’ll lead the world in the industries of tomorrow and that’s how we’ll carry forward the eternal work of making the United States a more perfect union.</p>
<p>Thank so much for listening.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Japanese National Security Advisor Akiba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-japanese-national-security-advisor-akiba/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 21:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=269025</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Japanese National Security Advisor Akiba Takeo in Washington, D.C. Secretary Blinken and National Security Advisor Akiba emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Japan Alliance to maintaining an inclusive, free, and open Indo-Pacific.  The Secretary and the National Security Advisor reiterated their shared opposition to any unilateral attempts to change the status quo in the East China Sea and activities that undermine, destabilize, or threaten the rules-based international order. They pledged to maintain peace and stability, lawful unimpeded commerce, and respect for international law, including freedom of navigation and overflight and other lawful uses of the sea in the South China Sea and beyond.  They also stressed the importance of preserving peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait.  The Secretary and the National Security Advisor also noted the importance of trilateral U.S.-Japan-Republic of Korea cooperation to address the pressing challenges of the 21st century, including the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Japanese National Security Advisor Akiba Takeo in Washington, D.C. Secretary Blinken and National Security Advisor Akiba emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Japan Alliance to maintaining an inclusive, free, and open Indo-Pacific.  The Secretary and the National Security Advisor reiterated their shared opposition to any unilateral attempts to change the status quo in the East China Sea and activities that undermine, destabilize, or threaten the rules-based international order. They pledged to maintain peace and stability, lawful unimpeded commerce, and respect for international law, including freedom of navigation and overflight and other lawful uses of the sea in the South China Sea and beyond.  They also stressed the importance of preserving peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait.  The Secretary and the National Security Advisor also noted the importance of trilateral U.S.-Japan-Republic of Korea cooperation to address the pressing challenges of the 21st century, including the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken At the United Nations Security Council Meeting on Maintenance of International Peace and Security: Maritime Security</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-the-united-nations-security-council-meeting-on-maintenance-of-international-peace-and-security-maritime-security/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 19:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=269028</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Virtual Participation</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, thank you very much, Foreign Minister Jaishankar.  It’s wonderful to be with you and please convey our thanks to Prime Minister Modi for bringing us together for this critically important discussion and for India’s leadership on these issues, especially in championing a free and open Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p class="p1">When I last had the chance to address the Council back in May, it was to underscore the importance of defending, upholding, and revitalizing the rules-based international order grounded in the United Nations Charter.  Few issues are more crucial to that endeavor than the future of our ocean.  The ocean not only covers 70 percent of Earth and accounts for 97 percent of its water, but it is crucial to the livelihood of our people and the sustainability of our planet.  Maritime safety and security are enduring interests of all nations and are vital natural (inaudible).</p>
<p class="p1">(Interruption.)</p>
<p class="p1">Thank you.  Freedom of navigation and overflight and the unimpeded flow of lawful maritime commerce are also critical to the security and prosperity of nations and to global stability.  The international community has long benefited from a rules-based maritime order where international law, as reflected in the 1982 United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea, sets out the legal framework for all activities in the ocean and seas.</p>
<p class="p1">But despite having a clear body of international law that we’ve all committed to abide by and uphold, despite all the ways that freedom of the seas, open waterways, and the unimpeded flow of lawful maritime commerce have delivered for nations and people around the world, and despite the indispensable role this maritime order has played in fostering economic activity, security cooperation, scientific innovation, environmental sustainability – despite all of that, the order is under serious threat.</p>
<p class="p1">That’s why I’m grateful for India’s leadership in bringing us together today and calling on all nations to recommit to defending and strengthening the maritime rules and principles that we forged together and committed to uphold.</p>
<p class="p1">Let me just speak, if I could, specifically to some of the critical areas where we see maritime rules and principles under threat.</p>
<p class="p1">In the South China Sea, we have seen dangerous encounters between vessels at sea and provocative actions to advance unlawful maritime claims.  The United States has made clear its concerns regarding actions that intimidate and bully other states from lawfully accessing their maritime resources.  And we and other countries, including South China Sea claimants, have protested such behavior and unlawful maritime claims in the South China Sea.</p>
<p class="p1">Five years ago, an arbitral tribunal constituted under the 1982 Law of the Sea Convention delivered a unanimous and legally binding decision to the parties before it firmly rejecting unlawful, expansive South China Sea maritime claims as being inconsistent with international law.  The United States has consistently called for all countries to conform their maritime claims to the International Law of the Sea as reflected in the 1982 convention.</p>
<p class="p1">This is in keeping with the peaceful resolution of disputes and the sovereign equality of member-states, which are core principles enshrined in the United Nations Charter.  Efforts to resolve maritime disputes through threat or use of force flout these principles.</p>
<p class="p1">Some may assert that resolving the dispute in the South China Sea is not the business of the United States or any other country that is not a claimant to the islands and waters.  But it is the business and, even more, the responsibility of every member-state to defend the rules that we’ve all agreed to follow and peacefully resolve maritime disputes.  Conflict in the South China Sea or in any ocean would have serious global consequences for security and for commerce.  What’s more, when a state faces no consequences for ignoring these rules, it fuels greater impunity and instability everywhere.</p>
<p class="p1">States are also provocatively and unlawfully advancing their interests in the Persian Gulf and the Black Sea.  On July 29th, the <i>Mercer Street</i>, a commercial ship that was peacefully transiting international waters in the North Arabian Sea, was attacked using explosive unmanned aerial vehicles, resulting in the death of two people.  Upon review of the available information, we are confident that Iran conducted this unjustified attack, which is part of a pattern of attacks and other provocative behavior.  These actions threaten freedom of navigation through this crucial waterway, international shipping and commerce, and the lives of people on the vessels involved.</p>
<p class="p1">On behalf of the United States, I reiterate my condolences to the families of the victims and to the United Kingdom and Romania.  It is on all of our nations to hold accountable those responsible.  Failing to do so will only fuel their sense of impunity and embolden others inclined to disregard the maritime order.</p>
<p class="p1">In the Black Sea, the Kerch Strait, the Sea of Azov, we see continued aggressive actions against Ukraine with dangerous incursions on the sea and in the air and the harassment of vessels, which are disrupting commerce and energy access.  We reaffirm our support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity within its internationally recognized borders, extending to its territorial waters.  Crimea is Ukraine.</p>
<p class="p1">When nations ignore or purport to redraw the borders of other nations, whether by land or by sea, they undermine the sovereign equality of member-states, a guiding principle of the United Nations.</p>
<p class="p1">Non-state actors also pose serious risk to maritime safety and security, from pirates and illicit maritime traffickers in the Gulf of Aden and the Indian Ocean, to pirates and armed robbers in the Gulf of Guinea, to drug traffickers in the Caribbean Sea and the Eastern Pacific.  Yet our collective response to these actors shows how effective we can be when we work together to defend maritime order and hold those accountable who violate it.</p>
<p class="p1">We see that in the Africa-led Yaounde Architecture for Maritime Safety and Security, which was supported by Friends of the Gulf of Guinea, and in the Nigerian-led Deep Blue Project and Maritime Collaborative Forum.  We see it in India’s Maritime Fusion Center, which has enhanced cooperation among Indian Ocean partners, and in the widespread ratification by countries of the Caribbean Basin of the Treaty of San Jose.</p>
<p class="p1">We see it in the Contact Group on Piracy off the Coast of Somalia, which has demonstrated significant success in building an effective regional response, most notably in law enforcement.  The United States led the creation of this group and we remain active in its work and in coordinating naval operations to prevent a resurgence of piracy in the area.  We’re grateful to fellow Security Council members for supporting annual resolutions to help coordinate and strengthen these efforts.</p>
<p class="p1">We must bring the same coordinated and comprehensive responses to other threats to maritime safety and security.  This includes illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing, which undermines the sustainability of fish stocks, circumvents agreed conservation and management measures, and violate the sovereign rights of coastal states, and often goes hand in hand with the use of forced labor and other illicit activities.  And it also includes responding to environmental disasters, like the cooperation between Sri Lanka, the United States, and other countries to mitigate the impact of the <i>MV X-Press Pearl</i> catastrophe.</p>
<p class="p1">All of these activities require that we share information and coordinate our responses, that we help build the capacity of our maritime partners, that we engage with affected communities, industry, nongovernmental organizations, which are critically important allies in this effort.</p>
<p class="p1">Together, our nations have spent decades building this maritime order and the broader rules-based international system that it is a part of.  We’ve done so out of a shared recognition that it benefits all our nations and all our people when governments accept certain constraints on their actions rather than living in a world where the strong do what they can and where those who are less powerful feel coerced and threatened.</p>
<p class="p1">That’s never been more true than it is today, and that makes the collective effort to defend, to strengthen, and build upon this order more urgent than ever.  Thanks very much.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Virtual Participation</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, thank you very much, Foreign Minister Jaishankar.  It’s wonderful to be with you and please convey our thanks to Prime Minister Modi for bringing us together for this critically important discussion and for India’s leadership on these issues, especially in championing a free and open Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p class="p1">When I last had the chance to address the Council back in May, it was to underscore the importance of defending, upholding, and revitalizing the rules-based international order grounded in the United Nations Charter.  Few issues are more crucial to that endeavor than the future of our ocean.  The ocean not only covers 70 percent of Earth and accounts for 97 percent of its water, but it is crucial to the livelihood of our people and the sustainability of our planet.  Maritime safety and security are enduring interests of all nations and are vital natural (inaudible).</p>
<p class="p1">(Interruption.)</p>
<p class="p1">Thank you.  Freedom of navigation and overflight and the unimpeded flow of lawful maritime commerce are also critical to the security and prosperity of nations and to global stability.  The international community has long benefited from a rules-based maritime order where international law, as reflected in the 1982 United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea, sets out the legal framework for all activities in the ocean and seas.</p>
<p class="p1">But despite having a clear body of international law that we’ve all committed to abide by and uphold, despite all the ways that freedom of the seas, open waterways, and the unimpeded flow of lawful maritime commerce have delivered for nations and people around the world, and despite the indispensable role this maritime order has played in fostering economic activity, security cooperation, scientific innovation, environmental sustainability – despite all of that, the order is under serious threat.</p>
<p class="p1">That’s why I’m grateful for India’s leadership in bringing us together today and calling on all nations to recommit to defending and strengthening the maritime rules and principles that we forged together and committed to uphold.</p>
<p class="p1">Let me just speak, if I could, specifically to some of the critical areas where we see maritime rules and principles under threat.</p>
<p class="p1">In the South China Sea, we have seen dangerous encounters between vessels at sea and provocative actions to advance unlawful maritime claims.  The United States has made clear its concerns regarding actions that intimidate and bully other states from lawfully accessing their maritime resources.  And we and other countries, including South China Sea claimants, have protested such behavior and unlawful maritime claims in the South China Sea.</p>
<p class="p1">Five years ago, an arbitral tribunal constituted under the 1982 Law of the Sea Convention delivered a unanimous and legally binding decision to the parties before it firmly rejecting unlawful, expansive South China Sea maritime claims as being inconsistent with international law.  The United States has consistently called for all countries to conform their maritime claims to the International Law of the Sea as reflected in the 1982 convention.</p>
<p class="p1">This is in keeping with the peaceful resolution of disputes and the sovereign equality of member-states, which are core principles enshrined in the United Nations Charter.  Efforts to resolve maritime disputes through threat or use of force flout these principles.</p>
<p class="p1">Some may assert that resolving the dispute in the South China Sea is not the business of the United States or any other country that is not a claimant to the islands and waters.  But it is the business and, even more, the responsibility of every member-state to defend the rules that we’ve all agreed to follow and peacefully resolve maritime disputes.  Conflict in the South China Sea or in any ocean would have serious global consequences for security and for commerce.  What’s more, when a state faces no consequences for ignoring these rules, it fuels greater impunity and instability everywhere.</p>
<p class="p1">States are also provocatively and unlawfully advancing their interests in the Persian Gulf and the Black Sea.  On July 29th, the <i>Mercer Street</i>, a commercial ship that was peacefully transiting international waters in the North Arabian Sea, was attacked using explosive unmanned aerial vehicles, resulting in the death of two people.  Upon review of the available information, we are confident that Iran conducted this unjustified attack, which is part of a pattern of attacks and other provocative behavior.  These actions threaten freedom of navigation through this crucial waterway, international shipping and commerce, and the lives of people on the vessels involved.</p>
<p class="p1">On behalf of the United States, I reiterate my condolences to the families of the victims and to the United Kingdom and Romania.  It is on all of our nations to hold accountable those responsible.  Failing to do so will only fuel their sense of impunity and embolden others inclined to disregard the maritime order.</p>
<p class="p1">In the Black Sea, the Kerch Strait, the Sea of Azov, we see continued aggressive actions against Ukraine with dangerous incursions on the sea and in the air and the harassment of vessels, which are disrupting commerce and energy access.  We reaffirm our support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity within its internationally recognized borders, extending to its territorial waters.  Crimea is Ukraine.</p>
<p class="p1">When nations ignore or purport to redraw the borders of other nations, whether by land or by sea, they undermine the sovereign equality of member-states, a guiding principle of the United Nations.</p>
<p class="p1">Non-state actors also pose serious risk to maritime safety and security, from pirates and illicit maritime traffickers in the Gulf of Aden and the Indian Ocean, to pirates and armed robbers in the Gulf of Guinea, to drug traffickers in the Caribbean Sea and the Eastern Pacific.  Yet our collective response to these actors shows how effective we can be when we work together to defend maritime order and hold those accountable who violate it.</p>
<p class="p1">We see that in the Africa-led Yaounde Architecture for Maritime Safety and Security, which was supported by Friends of the Gulf of Guinea, and in the Nigerian-led Deep Blue Project and Maritime Collaborative Forum.  We see it in India’s Maritime Fusion Center, which has enhanced cooperation among Indian Ocean partners, and in the widespread ratification by countries of the Caribbean Basin of the Treaty of San Jose.</p>
<p class="p1">We see it in the Contact Group on Piracy off the Coast of Somalia, which has demonstrated significant success in building an effective regional response, most notably in law enforcement.  The United States led the creation of this group and we remain active in its work and in coordinating naval operations to prevent a resurgence of piracy in the area.  We’re grateful to fellow Security Council members for supporting annual resolutions to help coordinate and strengthen these efforts.</p>
<p class="p1">We must bring the same coordinated and comprehensive responses to other threats to maritime safety and security.  This includes illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing, which undermines the sustainability of fish stocks, circumvents agreed conservation and management measures, and violate the sovereign rights of coastal states, and often goes hand in hand with the use of forced labor and other illicit activities.  And it also includes responding to environmental disasters, like the cooperation between Sri Lanka, the United States, and other countries to mitigate the impact of the <i>MV X-Press Pearl</i> catastrophe.</p>
<p class="p1">All of these activities require that we share information and coordinate our responses, that we help build the capacity of our maritime partners, that we engage with affected communities, industry, nongovernmental organizations, which are critically important allies in this effort.</p>
<p class="p1">Together, our nations have spent decades building this maritime order and the broader rules-based international system that it is a part of.  We’ve done so out of a shared recognition that it benefits all our nations and all our people when governments accept certain constraints on their actions rather than living in a world where the strong do what they can and where those who are less powerful feel coerced and threatened.</p>
<p class="p1">That’s never been more true than it is today, and that makes the collective effort to defend, to strengthen, and build upon this order more urgent than ever.  Thanks very much.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holding the Lukashenka Regime to Account on the Anniversary of the Fraudulent Presidential Belarusian Election</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/holding-the-lukashenka-regime-to-account-on-the-anniversary-of-the-fraudulent-presidential-belarusian-election/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 15:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268947</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p class="p1">On the one-year anniversary of Belarus’s fraudulent presidential election, the United States government has taken decisive action against forty-four individuals and entities in order to hold <span class="s1">Alyaksandr</span> Lukashenka and his regime to account for its continued, violent repression of Belarusians inside and outside the country.  These steps are a further consequence to the Belarusian authorities’ continued flagrant disregard for human rights and Belarus’s failure to comply with its obligations under international human rights law.</p>
<p class="p2">Pursuant to a new Executive Order the President signed today, the U.S. Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) designated forty-four individuals and entities. These sanctions are the latest in a series of efforts demonstrating our determination to take action in the face of the increased repression and sharply deteriorating human rights situation in Belarus.  <span class="s2">OFAC targeted, among others, entities and individuals, including state-owned enterprises, government officials, and others, who support the regime, facilitate its violent repression of the Belarusian people, and violate the rule of law.  </span></p>
<p class="p1">Democratic countries are stronger when they stand together. Alongside these U.S. actions, we welcome the steps taken today by the United Kingdom and Canada against the regime and those announced by the European Union on June 24. The United States further commends the ongoing close coordination with Lithuania and Poland as a demonstration of the steadfast international resolve in supporting the Belarusian people’s democratic aspirations.</p>
<p class="p2">One year ago, the people of Belarus turned out in record numbers to give voice to their democratic aspirations and desire for change.  Instead of honoring their votes, the regime fraudulently declared victory and embarked on a campaign of violence and repression.  Since that time, Lukashenka has sought to cement his hold on power at the expense of the Belarusian people.  Over 600 political prisoners are unjustly detained.  Independent media outlets have been raided and shuttered, and Belarusian authorities are attempting to silence NGOs and vital members of civil society.  Moreover, this repression does not occur solely within Belarus’s borders, as Belarusians abroad also face intimidation.  This repression features blatant disregard of international norms, as displayed by the brazen forced diversion of Ryanair flight 4978 for the purpose of arresting a Belarusian journalist, the dangerous attempt to intimidate the EU – in particular, our Ally Lithuania – by orchestrating irregular migrant flows on Belarus’s border, and most recently the attempted forced repatriation of Belarusian Olympian Krystsyna Tsimanouskaya, who has been offered a humanitarian visa by Poland.  These acts of transnational repression cannot be tolerated and must stop.  The United States stands in solidarity with our Allies and partners in responding to these threats.</p>
<p class="p1">The United States once again calls on the Belarusian authorities to end the crackdown on members of civil society, the media, athletes, students, legal professionals and other citizens, immediately release all political prisoners, engage in a genuine dialogue with the democratic opposition and civil society, as called for in the OSCE Expert Mission report, and hold free and fair elections under international observation.  We will continue working with the international community to hold to account those responsible for human rights violations and abuses in Belarus.</p>
<p class="p2">We stand with the people of Belarus in support of their human rights and fundamental freedoms.</p>
<p class="p1">To learn more about today’s actions and Executive Order, visit <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0315"><span class="s3">https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0315</span></a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p class="p1">On the one-year anniversary of Belarus’s fraudulent presidential election, the United States government has taken decisive action against forty-four individuals and entities in order to hold <span class="s1">Alyaksandr</span> Lukashenka and his regime to account for its continued, violent repression of Belarusians inside and outside the country.  These steps are a further consequence to the Belarusian authorities’ continued flagrant disregard for human rights and Belarus’s failure to comply with its obligations under international human rights law.</p>
<p class="p2">Pursuant to a new Executive Order the President signed today, the U.S. Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) designated forty-four individuals and entities. These sanctions are the latest in a series of efforts demonstrating our determination to take action in the face of the increased repression and sharply deteriorating human rights situation in Belarus.  <span class="s2">OFAC targeted, among others, entities and individuals, including state-owned enterprises, government officials, and others, who support the regime, facilitate its violent repression of the Belarusian people, and violate the rule of law.  </span></p>
<p class="p1">Democratic countries are stronger when they stand together. Alongside these U.S. actions, we welcome the steps taken today by the United Kingdom and Canada against the regime and those announced by the European Union on June 24. The United States further commends the ongoing close coordination with Lithuania and Poland as a demonstration of the steadfast international resolve in supporting the Belarusian people’s democratic aspirations.</p>
<p class="p2">One year ago, the people of Belarus turned out in record numbers to give voice to their democratic aspirations and desire for change.  Instead of honoring their votes, the regime fraudulently declared victory and embarked on a campaign of violence and repression.  Since that time, Lukashenka has sought to cement his hold on power at the expense of the Belarusian people.  Over 600 political prisoners are unjustly detained.  Independent media outlets have been raided and shuttered, and Belarusian authorities are attempting to silence NGOs and vital members of civil society.  Moreover, this repression does not occur solely within Belarus’s borders, as Belarusians abroad also face intimidation.  This repression features blatant disregard of international norms, as displayed by the brazen forced diversion of Ryanair flight 4978 for the purpose of arresting a Belarusian journalist, the dangerous attempt to intimidate the EU – in particular, our Ally Lithuania – by orchestrating irregular migrant flows on Belarus’s border, and most recently the attempted forced repatriation of Belarusian Olympian Krystsyna Tsimanouskaya, who has been offered a humanitarian visa by Poland.  These acts of transnational repression cannot be tolerated and must stop.  The United States stands in solidarity with our Allies and partners in responding to these threats.</p>
<p class="p1">The United States once again calls on the Belarusian authorities to end the crackdown on members of civil society, the media, athletes, students, legal professionals and other citizens, immediately release all political prisoners, engage in a genuine dialogue with the democratic opposition and civil society, as called for in the OSCE Expert Mission report, and hold free and fair elections under international observation.  We will continue working with the international community to hold to account those responsible for human rights violations and abuses in Belarus.</p>
<p class="p2">We stand with the people of Belarus in support of their human rights and fundamental freedoms.</p>
<p class="p1">To learn more about today’s actions and Executive Order, visit <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0315"><span class="s3">https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0315</span></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Department of State Concludes $6.6 Million Settlement of Alleged Export Violations by Keysight Technologies, Inc.</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-department-of-state-concludes-6-6-million-settlement-of-alleged-export-violations-by-keysight-technologies-inc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 13:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268910</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1">The Department of State has concluded an administrative settlement with Keysight Technologies, Inc. (Keysight) of Santa Rosa, California, to resolve alleged violations of the Arms Export Control Act (AECA), 22 U.S.C. § 2751 <i>et seq</i>., and the International Traffic in Arms Regulations (ITAR), 22 C.F.R. Parts 120-130.  The Department of State and Keysight have reached this settlement following an extensive compliance review by the Office of Defense Trade Controls Compliance in the Department’s Bureau of Political-Military Affairs.</p>
<p class="p1">The Department of State and Keysight have reached an agreement pursuant to ITAR § 128.11 to address alleged <span class="s1">unauthorized exports of </span>technical data, and in this case, software used for testing radar equipment on fixed or mobile platforms.  The settlement demonstrates the Department’s role in strengthening U.S. industry by protecting technical data from unauthorized exports.  The settlement also highlights the importance of obtaining appropriate authorization from the Department for exporting software as well as determining proper export jurisdiction.</p>
<p class="p1">Under the terms of the 36-month Consent Agreement, Keysight will pay a civil penalty of $6,600,000.  The Department has agreed to suspend $2,500,000 of this amount on the condition that the funds will be used for Department-approved Consent Agreement remedial compliance measures.  Also, Keysight must hire an outside Special Compliance Officer for a term of two years and conduct an external audit to assess and improve its compliance program during the Consent Agreement term.</p>
<p class="p1">Keysight disclosed to the Department the alleged AECA and ITAR violations.  However, the Department first alerted Keysight of misclassification concerns and advised Keysight to obtain proper classification for the software through a Commodity Jurisdiction request, which led to the discovery of the violations.  Keysight cooperated with the Department’s review, including submitting one disclosure that acknowledged the charged conduct, implemented remedial compliance measures, and signed a statute of limitations agreement tolling the statutory period.  For these reasons, the Department has determined that it is not appropriate to administratively debar Keysight at this time.</p>
<p class="p1">The Consent Agreement and related documents will be available for public inspection in the <a href="https://foia.state.gov/Search/Search.aspx"><span class="s2">Public Reading Room of the Department of State</span></a> and on <a href="https://www.pmddtc.state.gov/ddtc_public?id=ddtc_kb_article_page&amp;sys_id=384b968adb3cd30044f9ff621f961941"><span class="s2">Penalties and Oversights Agreements</span></a> section of the Directorate of Defense Trade Controls’ website.  For additional information, please contact the Bureau of Political-Military Affairs’ Office of Congressional and Public Affairs at <a href="mailto:pm-cpa@state.gov"><span class="s2">pm-cpa@state.gov</span></a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1">The Department of State has concluded an administrative settlement with Keysight Technologies, Inc. (Keysight) of Santa Rosa, California, to resolve alleged violations of the Arms Export Control Act (AECA), 22 U.S.C. § 2751 <i>et seq</i>., and the International Traffic in Arms Regulations (ITAR), 22 C.F.R. Parts 120-130.  The Department of State and Keysight have reached this settlement following an extensive compliance review by the Office of Defense Trade Controls Compliance in the Department’s Bureau of Political-Military Affairs.</p>
<p class="p1">The Department of State and Keysight have reached an agreement pursuant to ITAR § 128.11 to address alleged <span class="s1">unauthorized exports of </span>technical data, and in this case, software used for testing radar equipment on fixed or mobile platforms.  The settlement demonstrates the Department’s role in strengthening U.S. industry by protecting technical data from unauthorized exports.  The settlement also highlights the importance of obtaining appropriate authorization from the Department for exporting software as well as determining proper export jurisdiction.</p>
<p class="p1">Under the terms of the 36-month Consent Agreement, Keysight will pay a civil penalty of $6,600,000.  The Department has agreed to suspend $2,500,000 of this amount on the condition that the funds will be used for Department-approved Consent Agreement remedial compliance measures.  Also, Keysight must hire an outside Special Compliance Officer for a term of two years and conduct an external audit to assess and improve its compliance program during the Consent Agreement term.</p>
<p class="p1">Keysight disclosed to the Department the alleged AECA and ITAR violations.  However, the Department first alerted Keysight of misclassification concerns and advised Keysight to obtain proper classification for the software through a Commodity Jurisdiction request, which led to the discovery of the violations.  Keysight cooperated with the Department’s review, including submitting one disclosure that acknowledged the charged conduct, implemented remedial compliance measures, and signed a statute of limitations agreement tolling the statutory period.  For these reasons, the Department has determined that it is not appropriate to administratively debar Keysight at this time.</p>
<p class="p1">The Consent Agreement and related documents will be available for public inspection in the <a href="https://foia.state.gov/Search/Search.aspx"><span class="s2">Public Reading Room of the Department of State</span></a> and on <a href="https://www.pmddtc.state.gov/ddtc_public?id=ddtc_kb_article_page&amp;sys_id=384b968adb3cd30044f9ff621f961941"><span class="s2">Penalties and Oversights Agreements</span></a> section of the Directorate of Defense Trade Controls’ website.  For additional information, please contact the Bureau of Political-Military Affairs’ Office of Congressional and Public Affairs at <a href="mailto:pm-cpa@state.gov"><span class="s2">pm-cpa@state.gov</span></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change Working Group I Contribution to the Sixth Assessment Report</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/intergovernmental-panel-on-climate-change-working-group-i-contribution-to-the-sixth-assessment-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 12:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268884</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change’s (IPCC) newest report makes it clear – climate change is already a crisis.   </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Today, the United States joined nearly 200 IPCC member governments in approving the Working Group I contribution to the IPCC’s Sixth Assessment Report.  This is the first volume in a series of four reports that the IPCC will release for the Sixth Assessment.  This report evaluates the physical science of climate change – looking at the past, present, and future climate and revealing how human-caused emissions are altering our planet and what that means for our collective future.   </span></p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">The report highlights that our climate is rapidly changing due to human influence and is already altering our planet in drastic ways <i>– </i>Arctic sea ice is at its lowest level in more than 150 years; sea levels are rising faster than at any time in at least the last 3,000 years; and glaciers are declining at a rate unprecedented in at least 2,000 years.  Weather and climate events – such as extreme heat, heavy rainfall, fire conditions, and droughts – are becoming more severe and frequent because of clima</span><span class="s2">te change.  We are seeing the detrimental impacts of these events on the lives and livelihoods of people around the world.     </span><span class="s1"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Most importantly, the report finds we are already edging closer to a 1.5 degrees Celsius warmer world, and every day emissions rise the prospects for averting the worst impacts of climate change become dimmer.  This is why it is essential that all countries </span><span class="s3">–</span><span class="s1"> in particular the major economies </span><span class="s3">–</span><span class="s1"> do their part during this critical decade of the 2020s to put the world on a trajectory to keep a 1.5 degrees Celsius limit on warming within reach.  This is why the United States has committed to a 50-52 percent reduction in emissions from 2005 levels in 2030 and is marshaling the entire federal government to tackle the climate crisis.  We cannot delay ambitious climate action any longer.   </span><span class="s3"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">As countries prepare for the 26th UN Climate Change Conference (COP26) in Glasgow, this report is a stark reminder that we must let science drive us to action.  This moment requires world leaders, the private sector, and individuals to act together with urgency and do everything it takes to protect our planet and our future in this decade and beyond.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change’s (IPCC) newest report makes it clear – climate change is already a crisis.   </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Today, the United States joined nearly 200 IPCC member governments in approving the Working Group I contribution to the IPCC’s Sixth Assessment Report.  This is the first volume in a series of four reports that the IPCC will release for the Sixth Assessment.  This report evaluates the physical science of climate change – looking at the past, present, and future climate and revealing how human-caused emissions are altering our planet and what that means for our collective future.   </span></p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">The report highlights that our climate is rapidly changing due to human influence and is already altering our planet in drastic ways <i>– </i>Arctic sea ice is at its lowest level in more than 150 years; sea levels are rising faster than at any time in at least the last 3,000 years; and glaciers are declining at a rate unprecedented in at least 2,000 years.  Weather and climate events – such as extreme heat, heavy rainfall, fire conditions, and droughts – are becoming more severe and frequent because of clima</span><span class="s2">te change.  We are seeing the detrimental impacts of these events on the lives and livelihoods of people around the world.     </span><span class="s1"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Most importantly, the report finds we are already edging closer to a 1.5 degrees Celsius warmer world, and every day emissions rise the prospects for averting the worst impacts of climate change become dimmer.  This is why it is essential that all countries </span><span class="s3">–</span><span class="s1"> in particular the major economies </span><span class="s3">–</span><span class="s1"> do their part during this critical decade of the 2020s to put the world on a trajectory to keep a 1.5 degrees Celsius limit on warming within reach.  This is why the United States has committed to a 50-52 percent reduction in emissions from 2005 levels in 2030 and is marshaling the entire federal government to tackle the climate crisis.  We cannot delay ambitious climate action any longer.   </span><span class="s3"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">As countries prepare for the 26th UN Climate Change Conference (COP26) in Glasgow, this report is a stark reminder that we must let science drive us to action.  This moment requires world leaders, the private sector, and individuals to act together with urgency and do everything it takes to protect our planet and our future in this decade and beyond.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Lack of Prospects for Free and Fair Election in Nicaragua</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-lack-of-prospects-for-free-and-fair-election-in-nicaragua/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 22:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268848</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>President Daniel Ortega and Vice President Rosario Murillo&#8217;s decision on August 6 to ban the last genuine opposition party from participating in the November elections underscores their desire to remain in power at all costs.   This autocratic maneuver follows the detention of seven presidential candidates and 24 other opposition figures, human rights activists, business leaders, students, and NGO workers over the last two months.  The United States views the regime’s latest undemocratic, authoritarian actions—driven by Ortega’s fear of an electoral loss—as the final blow against Nicaragua’s prospects for a free and fair election later this year.  That electoral process, including its eventual results, has lost all credibility.</p>
<p>The Ortega-Murillo regime has undermined its  international commitments, including those under the Inter-American Democratic Charter, as well as the rights of the Nicaraguan people to freely choose their own leaders.  We will continue to work closely with other democracies to respond diplomatically and economically to these dire developments, which only further deprive the Nicaraguan people of their desire for a representative government and economic prosperity.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>President Daniel Ortega and Vice President Rosario Murillo&#8217;s decision on August 6 to ban the last genuine opposition party from participating in the November elections underscores their desire to remain in power at all costs.   This autocratic maneuver follows the detention of seven presidential candidates and 24 other opposition figures, human rights activists, business leaders, students, and NGO workers over the last two months.  The United States views the regime’s latest undemocratic, authoritarian actions—driven by Ortega’s fear of an electoral loss—as the final blow against Nicaragua’s prospects for a free and fair election later this year.  That electoral process, including its eventual results, has lost all credibility.</p>
<p>The Ortega-Murillo regime has undermined its  international commitments, including those under the Inter-American Democratic Charter, as well as the rights of the Nicaraguan people to freely choose their own leaders.  We will continue to work closely with other democracies to respond diplomatically and economically to these dire developments, which only further deprive the Nicaraguan people of their desire for a representative government and economic prosperity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Côte d’Ivoire National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/cote-divoire-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 04:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268500</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I join the people of Côte d’Ivoire as they celebrate their Independence Day.</p>
<p>The United States values our strong, cooperative relationship with Côte d’Ivoire.  This year, we will work together to end the COVID-19 pandemic, strengthen democracy, and promote economic opportunities and success for all Ivoirians.  We support Côte d’Ivoire’s cooperation with its neighbors to address the climate crisis and to ensure regional security.  The United States will remain a steadfast and reliable partner as we work together to advance these shared priorities.</p>
<p>The United States and the American people wish the people of Côte d’Ivoire prosperity and happiness on the occasion of your 61st year as an independent nation over the years to come.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I join the people of Côte d’Ivoire as they celebrate their Independence Day.</p>
<p>The United States values our strong, cooperative relationship with Côte d’Ivoire.  This year, we will work together to end the COVID-19 pandemic, strengthen democracy, and promote economic opportunities and success for all Ivoirians.  We support Côte d’Ivoire’s cooperation with its neighbors to address the climate crisis and to ensure regional security.  The United States will remain a steadfast and reliable partner as we work together to advance these shared priorities.</p>
<p>The United States and the American people wish the people of Côte d’Ivoire prosperity and happiness on the occasion of your 61st year as an independent nation over the years to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Designations of ISIS-Mozambique, JNIM, and al-Shabaab Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/designations-of-isis-mozambique-jnim-and-al-shabaab-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268812</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>I am announcing the designation of five terrorist leaders in Africa. Bonomade Machude Omar, Sidan ag Hitta, Salem ould Breihmatt, Ali Mohamed Rage, and Abdikadir Mohamed Abdikadir are designated as Specially Designated Global Terrorists (SDGTs) under Executive Order 13224, as amended.</p>
<ul>
<li>Bonomade Machude Omar, also known as Abu Sulayfa Muhammad and Ibn Omar, leads the Military and External Affairs Departments for ISIS-Mozambique and serves as the senior commander and lead coordinator for all attacks conducted by the group in northern Mozambique, as well as the lead facilitator and communications conduit for the group.  During the March 2021 attack on Palma, Omar led one group of fighters while Abu Yasir Hassan, the leader of ISIS-Mozambique, led another group of fighters, and Omar also led the attack on the Amarula Hotel in Palma.  Omar has been responsible for attacks in Cabo Delgado Province, Mozambique, and Mtwara Region, Tanzania.</li>
<li>Sidanag Hitta, also known as Abu Qarwaniand Abu Abdelhakim al-Kidali, is a senior leader and commander responsible for the Kidal Region in Mali within Jama’at Nasr al-Islam wal Muslimin (JNIM). Hitta was among the group responsible for the January 20, 2019, attack on the MINUSMA base in Aguelhoc, Kidal Region, Mali.  He was also responsible for hostages in the Kidal Region.</li>
<li>Salem ould Breihmatt, also known as Abu Hamza al-Shanqitiand Hamza al-Mauritani, is a JNIM senior leader and emir of Arbinda and Serma in the Mopti Region of Mali. He is also charged with the oversight of JNIM in Burkina Faso and is an explosives expert and instructor.</li>
<li>Ali Mohamed Rage, also known as Ali Dheere, is al-Shabaab’s spokesman and a senior leader of the group.  He replaced Sheikh Mukhtar Robowas al-Shabaab’s top spokesman in May 2009.  Rage has been involved in attack planning that has targeted areas in Kenya and Somalia.</li>
<li>Abdikadir Mohamed Abdikadir, also known as Ikrima, is a facilitator and operational planner.  As of November 2019, Abdikadir was an al-Shabaab senior leader and served as the Head of Operations and Logistics.  Abdikadir had also directed previous attack planning for al-Shabaab.</li>
</ul>
<p>As a result of our actions today, among other consequences, all property and interests in property of these individuals must be blocked and reported to the Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC). In addition, persons that engage in certain transactions with the persons designated today may themselves be exposed to designation.  Furthermore, any foreign financial institution that knowingly facilitates a significant financial transaction or provides significant financial services for the persons designated today could be subject to U.S. correspondent account or payable-through account sanctions.</p>
<p>The United States is committed to disrupting the financing methods of ISIS-Mozambique, JNIM, and al-Shabaab &#8212; all of which are designated Foreign Terrorist Organizations and SDGTs &#8212; limiting their abilities to conduct further attacks against civilians and supporting our partners in efforts to disrupt terrorism finance.  Addressing the terrorist threat across the continent will require working closely with our partners to degrade the capacity and operations of these terrorist groups, combatting their control and influence in West, East, and Southern Africa.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>I am announcing the designation of five terrorist leaders in Africa. Bonomade Machude Omar, Sidan ag Hitta, Salem ould Breihmatt, Ali Mohamed Rage, and Abdikadir Mohamed Abdikadir are designated as Specially Designated Global Terrorists (SDGTs) under Executive Order 13224, as amended.</p>
<ul>
<li>Bonomade Machude Omar, also known as Abu Sulayfa Muhammad and Ibn Omar, leads the Military and External Affairs Departments for ISIS-Mozambique and serves as the senior commander and lead coordinator for all attacks conducted by the group in northern Mozambique, as well as the lead facilitator and communications conduit for the group.  During the March 2021 attack on Palma, Omar led one group of fighters while Abu Yasir Hassan, the leader of ISIS-Mozambique, led another group of fighters, and Omar also led the attack on the Amarula Hotel in Palma.  Omar has been responsible for attacks in Cabo Delgado Province, Mozambique, and Mtwara Region, Tanzania.</li>
<li>Sidanag Hitta, also known as Abu Qarwaniand Abu Abdelhakim al-Kidali, is a senior leader and commander responsible for the Kidal Region in Mali within Jama’at Nasr al-Islam wal Muslimin (JNIM). Hitta was among the group responsible for the January 20, 2019, attack on the MINUSMA base in Aguelhoc, Kidal Region, Mali.  He was also responsible for hostages in the Kidal Region.</li>
<li>Salem ould Breihmatt, also known as Abu Hamza al-Shanqitiand Hamza al-Mauritani, is a JNIM senior leader and emir of Arbinda and Serma in the Mopti Region of Mali. He is also charged with the oversight of JNIM in Burkina Faso and is an explosives expert and instructor.</li>
<li>Ali Mohamed Rage, also known as Ali Dheere, is al-Shabaab’s spokesman and a senior leader of the group.  He replaced Sheikh Mukhtar Robowas al-Shabaab’s top spokesman in May 2009.  Rage has been involved in attack planning that has targeted areas in Kenya and Somalia.</li>
<li>Abdikadir Mohamed Abdikadir, also known as Ikrima, is a facilitator and operational planner.  As of November 2019, Abdikadir was an al-Shabaab senior leader and served as the Head of Operations and Logistics.  Abdikadir had also directed previous attack planning for al-Shabaab.</li>
</ul>
<p>As a result of our actions today, among other consequences, all property and interests in property of these individuals must be blocked and reported to the Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC). In addition, persons that engage in certain transactions with the persons designated today may themselves be exposed to designation.  Furthermore, any foreign financial institution that knowingly facilitates a significant financial transaction or provides significant financial services for the persons designated today could be subject to U.S. correspondent account or payable-through account sanctions.</p>
<p>The United States is committed to disrupting the financing methods of ISIS-Mozambique, JNIM, and al-Shabaab &#8212; all of which are designated Foreign Terrorist Organizations and SDGTs &#8212; limiting their abilities to conduct further attacks against civilians and supporting our partners in efforts to disrupt terrorism finance.  Addressing the terrorist threat across the continent will require working closely with our partners to degrade the capacity and operations of these terrorist groups, combatting their control and influence in West, East, and Southern Africa.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hizballah Rocket Attacks into Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/hizballah-rocket-attacks-into-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 22:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=268802</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States condemns in the strongest terms Hizballah’s rocket attacks into Israel. This violence puts Israelis and Lebanese at risk and jeopardizes Lebanon’s stability and sovereignty.  The United States remains engaged with Israeli and Lebanese officials, as well as the Lebanese Armed Forces. We call upon the Lebanese government urgently to prevent such attacks and bring the area under its control.  We also urge the Lebanese government to facilitate full access for UNIFIL peacekeepers in accordance with UNSCR 1701. We strongly encourage all efforts to maintain calm.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States condemns in the strongest terms Hizballah’s rocket attacks into Israel. This violence puts Israelis and Lebanese at risk and jeopardizes Lebanon’s stability and sovereignty.  The United States remains engaged with Israeli and Lebanese officials, as well as the Lebanese Armed Forces. We call upon the Lebanese government urgently to prevent such attacks and bring the area under its control.  We also urge the Lebanese government to facilitate full access for UNIFIL peacekeepers in accordance with UNSCR 1701. We strongly encourage all efforts to maintain calm.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
