<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 16:48:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Opening Remarks by Secretary Antony J. Blinken Before the House Subcommittee on State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/opening-remarks-by-secretary-antony-j-blinken-before-the-house-subcommittee-on-state-foreign-operations-and-related-programs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 16:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=338893</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>HT-2 The Capitol</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much, Chairwoman Lee.  It’s great to see you.  Ranking Member Rogers, Ranking Member Granger, thank you for being here today as well.  It’s very good to be with you, and I’m really grateful for this opportunity to speak to you about the administration’s proposed budget for the State Department.</p>
<p>As you know, I recently returned from Kyiv with Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin, where we sought to demonstrate, by our presence as well as by our actions, the United States commitment to Ukraine and its people.</p>
<p>This brutal war of aggression being committed by Russia against Ukraine has brought into sharp focus the power and purpose of American diplomacy.  Our diplomacy is rallying allies and partners around the world to join us in supporting Ukraine militarily, economically, and with humanitarian assistance to impose massive costs on the Kremlin for its aggression, while strengthening our collective security and defense, and addressing the war’s mounting global consequences, including the refugee and food crises that you’ve alluded to.</p>
<p>We have to continue to drive that diplomacy forward to also seize the strategic opportunities and address the risks presented by Russia’s overreach, as countries are reconsidering their policies, their priorities, and their relationships.</p>
<p>The budget request that you have before you actually predates the crisis, but fully funding it is critical to ensuring that Russia’s war in Ukraine is a strategic failure for the Kremlin and also serves as a powerful lesson for those who might consider following the same path.</p>
<p>As we’re focused on this urgent crisis, the State Department continues to carry out the missions traditionally associated with diplomacy, particularly responsibly managing great power competition with China, also facilitating a halt to fighting in places like Yemen and Ethiopia, pushing back against the rising tide of authoritarianism and the threat that it poses to democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>We also face evolving challenges that require us to develop new capabilities: the emergence and re-emergence of infectious disease, an accelerated climate crisis, and a digital revolution that holds both enormous promise but also peril if not managed correctly.</p>
<p>A few months ago, in the fall, I had a chance to set out a modernization agenda for the State Department and for U.S. diplomacy to respond to all of these demands and all of these needs.</p>
<p>And in no small part thanks to the significant FY22 budget that was approved by Congress, we’ve been able to make real progress on this agenda, but much remains to be done.</p>
<p>Just to give you a few quick examples, we’ve strengthened our capacity to shape the ongoing technological revolution so that it protects our interests, it boosts our competitiveness, it upholds our values.  With bipartisan congressional support and encouragement, we recently launched a new Bureau for Cyberspace and Digital Policy, with 60 team members to start.  And this is something that was done very much in collaboration with and with the counsel of Congress.</p>
<p>We’re also making headway on ensuring our diplomats reflect America’s remarkable diversity, which is one of our greatest strengths.  As the Chairwoman said, our department’s first ever Chief Diversity and Inclusion Officer, Ambassador Gina Abercrombie-Winstanley, has spearheaded an effort to analyze and address the obstacles that prevent under-represented groups from joining and advancing at the department.  We’ve expanded the Pickering and Rangel fellowship programs, and we have paid internships at State – again, strong congressional input and support for these initiatives.</p>
<p>We recently welcomed a new cohort of 179 exceptional Foreign Service professionals.  That puts us on track for our largest annual intake in a decade.</p>
<p>These first 15 months on the job for me have only strengthened my conviction that these and other reforms are not just worthwhile, they’re essential to delivering for the American people.</p>
<p>Today’s meeting, by our count, marks the 103rd time that I’ve had the opportunity to brief Congress in one way or another – meetings, calls – which is one of the ways that I’ve worked to meet the commitment I made in my confirmation, to ensure that Congress’s role as a partner, both in our foreign policymaking and in modernizing the State Department, is realized.</p>
<p>Ensuring that we can deliver on this agenda requires sustained funding, requires some new authorities – most importantly, it requires our partnership.</p>
<p>If we want to deepen our capability in areas like climate, like public health, like multilateral diplomacy; if we want to expand on Secretary Powell’s vision of a Foreign Service training float; if we want to strengthen global health security to prevent, detect, and respond to future outbreaks – we need these additional resources.</p>
<p>If we want to be able to swiftly stand up new missions, to deploy diplomats when and where they are needed, and make these decisions based on risk management rather than risk aversion – we need to reform the security – the Secure Embassy Construction and Counterterrorism Act and the Accountability Review Board statute.</p>
<p>If we want to rapidly scale up the response to crises like refugee surges and epidemics, while also avoiding costly overhead, we need more flexible domestic hiring authorities.</p>
<p>These are just a few examples, and I just want to stress in closing:  This is not about advancing the goals of any one administration or any one party.  It’s about refocusing our mission and our purpose on the forces that are affecting the lives of all of our fellow citizens – their livelihoods, their security – for decades to come.</p>
<p>So I really appreciate the opportunity to speak today about why this matters, and look forward to working with this committee, the subcommittee, Congress as a whole, as a partner in these efforts.</p>
<p>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>HT-2 The Capitol</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much, Chairwoman Lee.  It’s great to see you.  Ranking Member Rogers, Ranking Member Granger, thank you for being here today as well.  It’s very good to be with you, and I’m really grateful for this opportunity to speak to you about the administration’s proposed budget for the State Department.</p>
<p>As you know, I recently returned from Kyiv with Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin, where we sought to demonstrate, by our presence as well as by our actions, the United States commitment to Ukraine and its people.</p>
<p>This brutal war of aggression being committed by Russia against Ukraine has brought into sharp focus the power and purpose of American diplomacy.  Our diplomacy is rallying allies and partners around the world to join us in supporting Ukraine militarily, economically, and with humanitarian assistance to impose massive costs on the Kremlin for its aggression, while strengthening our collective security and defense, and addressing the war’s mounting global consequences, including the refugee and food crises that you’ve alluded to.</p>
<p>We have to continue to drive that diplomacy forward to also seize the strategic opportunities and address the risks presented by Russia’s overreach, as countries are reconsidering their policies, their priorities, and their relationships.</p>
<p>The budget request that you have before you actually predates the crisis, but fully funding it is critical to ensuring that Russia’s war in Ukraine is a strategic failure for the Kremlin and also serves as a powerful lesson for those who might consider following the same path.</p>
<p>As we’re focused on this urgent crisis, the State Department continues to carry out the missions traditionally associated with diplomacy, particularly responsibly managing great power competition with China, also facilitating a halt to fighting in places like Yemen and Ethiopia, pushing back against the rising tide of authoritarianism and the threat that it poses to democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>We also face evolving challenges that require us to develop new capabilities: the emergence and re-emergence of infectious disease, an accelerated climate crisis, and a digital revolution that holds both enormous promise but also peril if not managed correctly.</p>
<p>A few months ago, in the fall, I had a chance to set out a modernization agenda for the State Department and for U.S. diplomacy to respond to all of these demands and all of these needs.</p>
<p>And in no small part thanks to the significant FY22 budget that was approved by Congress, we’ve been able to make real progress on this agenda, but much remains to be done.</p>
<p>Just to give you a few quick examples, we’ve strengthened our capacity to shape the ongoing technological revolution so that it protects our interests, it boosts our competitiveness, it upholds our values.  With bipartisan congressional support and encouragement, we recently launched a new Bureau for Cyberspace and Digital Policy, with 60 team members to start.  And this is something that was done very much in collaboration with and with the counsel of Congress.</p>
<p>We’re also making headway on ensuring our diplomats reflect America’s remarkable diversity, which is one of our greatest strengths.  As the Chairwoman said, our department’s first ever Chief Diversity and Inclusion Officer, Ambassador Gina Abercrombie-Winstanley, has spearheaded an effort to analyze and address the obstacles that prevent under-represented groups from joining and advancing at the department.  We’ve expanded the Pickering and Rangel fellowship programs, and we have paid internships at State – again, strong congressional input and support for these initiatives.</p>
<p>We recently welcomed a new cohort of 179 exceptional Foreign Service professionals.  That puts us on track for our largest annual intake in a decade.</p>
<p>These first 15 months on the job for me have only strengthened my conviction that these and other reforms are not just worthwhile, they’re essential to delivering for the American people.</p>
<p>Today’s meeting, by our count, marks the 103rd time that I’ve had the opportunity to brief Congress in one way or another – meetings, calls – which is one of the ways that I’ve worked to meet the commitment I made in my confirmation, to ensure that Congress’s role as a partner, both in our foreign policymaking and in modernizing the State Department, is realized.</p>
<p>Ensuring that we can deliver on this agenda requires sustained funding, requires some new authorities – most importantly, it requires our partnership.</p>
<p>If we want to deepen our capability in areas like climate, like public health, like multilateral diplomacy; if we want to expand on Secretary Powell’s vision of a Foreign Service training float; if we want to strengthen global health security to prevent, detect, and respond to future outbreaks – we need these additional resources.</p>
<p>If we want to be able to swiftly stand up new missions, to deploy diplomats when and where they are needed, and make these decisions based on risk management rather than risk aversion – we need to reform the security – the Secure Embassy Construction and Counterterrorism Act and the Accountability Review Board statute.</p>
<p>If we want to rapidly scale up the response to crises like refugee surges and epidemics, while also avoiding costly overhead, we need more flexible domestic hiring authorities.</p>
<p>These are just a few examples, and I just want to stress in closing:  This is not about advancing the goals of any one administration or any one party.  It’s about refocusing our mission and our purpose on the forces that are affecting the lives of all of our fellow citizens – their livelihoods, their security – for decades to come.</p>
<p>So I really appreciate the opportunity to speak today about why this matters, and look forward to working with this committee, the subcommittee, Congress as a whole, as a partner in these efforts.</p>
<p>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Commemorating the Day of Holocaust Remembrance</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/commemorating-the-day-of-holocaust-remembrance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 15:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=338846</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Under the theme “Courage Facing Evil,” today we mark the Day of Holocaust Remembrance and honor the victims and survivors of the Holocaust.</p>
<p>As we remember the horrors of that dark chapter, we are surrounded by descendants of Holocaust survivors who were inspired by their family’s suffering and courage to dedicate themselves to public service. It is a sentiment I share from my own family’s story. They are public servants like U.S. Ambassador Michèle Taylor, whose parents and grandparents managed to escape the Holocaust before the Nazis murdered her extended family. This terrible loss of loved ones and her family’s will to survive were catalysts for the Ambassador’s long career defending and advancing the cause of human rights. Today, she is the U.S. representative to the United Nations Human Rights Council, where she stands up for the freedom, equal rights and dignity of all, and where she is working to rally the world in support of Ukraine against Russia’s brutal war of aggression.</p>
<p>Our charge remains to stand united against tyranny, lies, and hatred in all their forms. We must confront rising antisemitism. We must ensure that current and future generations learn the history and lessons of and from the Holocaust, so they feel a responsibility to stand up to injustice and take action against atrocities wherever they occur. This work is urgent. Fewer and fewer survivors are still with us, while those who deny and distort the history of the Holocaust are finding insidious new ways to spread their lies.</p>
<p>Today we remember all Holocaust survivors, the six million Jewish men, women and children who were murdered, and the millions of others who were killed or suffered persecution and horrific inhumanity, including Roma, persons with disabilities, and LGTBQI+ persons who were targeted in the Nazis’ campaign of dehumanization. Their precious lives and memory teach us why it is important not only to remember, but also to act. Every act of courage in the face of evil gives meaning to our sacred vow “Never Again.”</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Under the theme “Courage Facing Evil,” today we mark the Day of Holocaust Remembrance and honor the victims and survivors of the Holocaust.</p>
<p>As we remember the horrors of that dark chapter, we are surrounded by descendants of Holocaust survivors who were inspired by their family’s suffering and courage to dedicate themselves to public service. It is a sentiment I share from my own family’s story. They are public servants like U.S. Ambassador Michèle Taylor, whose parents and grandparents managed to escape the Holocaust before the Nazis murdered her extended family. This terrible loss of loved ones and her family’s will to survive were catalysts for the Ambassador’s long career defending and advancing the cause of human rights. Today, she is the U.S. representative to the United Nations Human Rights Council, where she stands up for the freedom, equal rights and dignity of all, and where she is working to rally the world in support of Ukraine against Russia’s brutal war of aggression.</p>
<p>Our charge remains to stand united against tyranny, lies, and hatred in all their forms. We must confront rising antisemitism. We must ensure that current and future generations learn the history and lessons of and from the Holocaust, so they feel a responsibility to stand up to injustice and take action against atrocities wherever they occur. This work is urgent. Fewer and fewer survivors are still with us, while those who deny and distort the history of the Holocaust are finding insidious new ways to spread their lies.</p>
<p>Today we remember all Holocaust survivors, the six million Jewish men, women and children who were murdered, and the millions of others who were killed or suffered persecution and horrific inhumanity, including Roma, persons with disabilities, and LGTBQI+ persons who were targeted in the Nazis’ campaign of dehumanization. Their precious lives and memory teach us why it is important not only to remember, but also to act. Every act of courage in the face of evil gives meaning to our sacred vow “Never Again.”</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the United States – Iceland Strategic Dialogue</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-the-united-states-iceland-strategic-dialogue-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 13:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=338764</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is the text of a joint statement by the Governments of the United States of America and Iceland following their strategic dialogue in Reykjavik, Iceland on April 26.</p>
<p><i>Begin text:</i></p>
<p>As close NATO Allies, the United States and Iceland discussed a range of issues pertinent to each country’s national security and to the security of the North Atlantic at the annual strategic dialogue on April 26. The two countries reiterated their condemnation of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustifiable war of aggression, while reaffirming their steadfast support for Ukraine. As part of the dialogue, the Allies reviewed cooperation at NATO and the bilateral security relationship. They also discussed continued cooperation on issues including safeguarding the international rules-based order, People’s Republic of China influence in Europe, the Arctic and measures to address climate change, cybersecurity, and global human rights. The bilateral defense agreement between the United States and Iceland, in place since 1951, continues to contribute to the security of our two democracies.</p>
<p>The United States was represented by the Department of State, the Department of Defense (Office of the Secretary Defense, Joint Staff, and U.S. European Command), the U.S. Coast Guard, the Department of Homeland Security, and the U.S. Embassy in Reykjavik. Iceland was represented by the Ministry for Foreign Affairs, the Prime Minister’s Office, the Icelandic Coast Guard, and the Icelandic Embassy in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><i>End text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is the text of a joint statement by the Governments of the United States of America and Iceland following their strategic dialogue in Reykjavik, Iceland on April 26.</p>
<p><i>Begin text:</i></p>
<p>As close NATO Allies, the United States and Iceland discussed a range of issues pertinent to each country’s national security and to the security of the North Atlantic at the annual strategic dialogue on April 26. The two countries reiterated their condemnation of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustifiable war of aggression, while reaffirming their steadfast support for Ukraine. As part of the dialogue, the Allies reviewed cooperation at NATO and the bilateral security relationship. They also discussed continued cooperation on issues including safeguarding the international rules-based order, People’s Republic of China influence in Europe, the Arctic and measures to address climate change, cybersecurity, and global human rights. The bilateral defense agreement between the United States and Iceland, in place since 1951, continues to contribute to the security of our two democracies.</p>
<p>The United States was represented by the Department of State, the Department of Defense (Office of the Secretary Defense, Joint Staff, and U.S. European Command), the U.S. Coast Guard, the Department of Homeland Security, and the U.S. Embassy in Reykjavik. Iceland was represented by the Ministry for Foreign Affairs, the Prime Minister’s Office, the Icelandic Coast Guard, and the Icelandic Embassy in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><i>End text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Omani Foreign Minister Al-Busaidi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-omani-foreign-minister-al-busaidi-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 13:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=338751</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke yesterday with Omani Foreign Minister Sayyid Badr al-Busaidi. The Secretary thanked Oman for its support on critical regional issues and encouraged further efforts to strengthen the truce in Yemen and translate it into a comprehensive process. Secretary Blinken reiterated the strength and importance of the U.S.-Oman relationship and discussed opportunities to deepen bilateral cooperation.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke yesterday with Omani Foreign Minister Sayyid Badr al-Busaidi. The Secretary thanked Oman for its support on critical regional issues and encouraged further efforts to strengthen the truce in Yemen and translate it into a comprehensive process. Secretary Blinken reiterated the strength and importance of the U.S.-Oman relationship and discussed opportunities to deepen bilateral cooperation.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Release of the First Annual Interagency Report on the Implementation of the Presidential Memorandum on Advancing the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Around the World</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/release-of-the-first-annual-interagency-report-on-the-implementation-of-the-presidential-memorandum-on-advancing-the-human-rights-of-lgbtqi-persons-around-the-world/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 12:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=338703</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p><span>Today we released the first-ever public report on the U.S. government’s implementation of the 2021 Presidential Memorandum on Advancing the Human Rights of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer, and Intersex Persons (LGBTQI+) Around the World.  The report details our efforts to protect and promote the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons globally over the past year.  It is my hope that this historic report inspires other governments around the world to undertake similar actions to advance the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons and to report publicly on those efforts.</span><span></span></p>
<p><span>Promoting and protecting the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons is a foreign policy priority for this Administration.  It remains vitally important that we address the violence and discrimination faced by LGBTQI+ persons while acknowledging the effects of the intersections of race and ethnicity, gender, disability, religion, and national origin, to name a few.  As the report demonstrates, the U.S. government advances these priorities by supporting efforts to end the criminalization of LGBTQI+ status and conduct, seeking to protect vulnerable LGBTQI+ refugees and asylum seekers, providing foreign assistance to protect the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons and advancing  non-discrimination protections, responding to human rights abuses of LGBTQI+ persons abroad, building coalitions of like-minded nations, and engaging international organizations in the fight against LGBTQI+ discrimination.  Our collective efforts drive toward the goal of ending violence and discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, and sex characteristics.  Equality and equity build stronger societies for all.  </span><span></span></p>
<p><span>I recognize the deeply meaningful and noble work that LGBTQI+ human rights defenders and civil society organizations undertake as they seek to advance respect for human rights for all.  They are our partners and allies, as are the like-minded governments and multilateral institutions with which we work closely to catalyze progress. </span></p>
<p><span>The report is available to the public at </span><span><a href="https://www.state.gov/lgbtqi-human-rights/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MjguNTcwOTk1MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvbGdidHFpLWh1bWFuLXJpZ2h0cy8ifQ.9ut53Yrep2aLxiRF-9t7lT8qgWX2S-FFT2g8RJK0ZH0/s/1006560560/br/130498637366-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1651234035169000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3uoUFk5ElTheXzkKKtuBpK">https://www.state.gov/lgbtqi-<wbr />human-rights/</a></span><span>.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p><span>Today we released the first-ever public report on the U.S. government’s implementation of the 2021 Presidential Memorandum on Advancing the Human Rights of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer, and Intersex Persons (LGBTQI+) Around the World.  The report details our efforts to protect and promote the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons globally over the past year.  It is my hope that this historic report inspires other governments around the world to undertake similar actions to advance the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons and to report publicly on those efforts.</span><span></span></p>
<p><span>Promoting and protecting the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons is a foreign policy priority for this Administration.  It remains vitally important that we address the violence and discrimination faced by LGBTQI+ persons while acknowledging the effects of the intersections of race and ethnicity, gender, disability, religion, and national origin, to name a few.  As the report demonstrates, the U.S. government advances these priorities by supporting efforts to end the criminalization of LGBTQI+ status and conduct, seeking to protect vulnerable LGBTQI+ refugees and asylum seekers, providing foreign assistance to protect the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons and advancing  non-discrimination protections, responding to human rights abuses of LGBTQI+ persons abroad, building coalitions of like-minded nations, and engaging international organizations in the fight against LGBTQI+ discrimination.  Our collective efforts drive toward the goal of ending violence and discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, and sex characteristics.  Equality and equity build stronger societies for all.  </span><span></span></p>
<p><span>I recognize the deeply meaningful and noble work that LGBTQI+ human rights defenders and civil society organizations undertake as they seek to advance respect for human rights for all.  They are our partners and allies, as are the like-minded governments and multilateral institutions with which we work closely to catalyze progress. </span></p>
<p><span>The report is available to the public at </span><span><a href="https://www.state.gov/lgbtqi-human-rights/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MjguNTcwOTk1MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvbGdidHFpLWh1bWFuLXJpZ2h0cy8ifQ.9ut53Yrep2aLxiRF-9t7lT8qgWX2S-FFT2g8RJK0ZH0/s/1006560560/br/130498637366-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1651234035169000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3uoUFk5ElTheXzkKKtuBpK">https://www.state.gov/lgbtqi-<wbr />human-rights/</a></span><span>.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Launch of the Declaration for the Future of the Internet</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/launch-of-the-declaration-for-the-future-of-the-internet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 22:32:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=338617</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span>On April 28 at 7:30 a.m. EDT, Assistant to the President and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan will host a virtual minister-level launch of the Declaration for the Future of the Internet at the White House with more than 50 partners from around the world.  The Declaration is a political commitment among partners to advance an affirmative vision for the Internet and digital technologies.  The launch event will be livestreamed to the public on <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MjcuNTcwODU0NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2djYzAyLnNhZmVsaW5rcy5wcm90ZWN0aW9uLm91dGxvb2suY29tLz91cmw9aHR0cCUzQSUyRiUyRnd3dy53aGl0ZWhvdXNlLmdvdiUyRmxpdmUmZGF0YT0wNSU3QzAxJTdDVHJhbk1KJTQwc3RhdGUuZ292JTdDNzA0MDA4NmEwMmE5NDhhMTNhNzcwOGRhMjg5NzAyZWYlN0M2NmNmNTA3NDVhZmU0OGQxYTY5MWExMmIyMTIxZjQ0YiU3QzAlN0MwJTdDNjM3ODY2OTI2MzAxOTg0NDcwJTdDVW5rbm93biU3Q1RXRnBiR1pzYjNkOGV5SldJam9pTUM0d0xqQXdNREFpTENKUUlqb2lWMmx1TXpJaUxDSkJUaUk2SWsxaGFXd2lMQ0pYVkNJNk1uMCUzRCU3QzMwMDAlN0MlN0MlN0Mmc2RhdGE9UTR4ajNOJTJCYm8lMkZNSlIlMkJEQXpzdlhUNzg1TSUyQjczc3dvRE9DbFVnbWFmMVRNJTNEJnJlc2VydmVkPTAifQ.UmniQUi8phRjTJu24FTCDVNo0FTcyT9BjAuWrtRw5v0/s/1248191874/br/130476455920-l" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MjcuNTcwODU0NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2djYzAyLnNhZmVsaW5rcy5wcm90ZWN0aW9uLm91dGxvb2suY29tLz91cmw9aHR0cCUzQSUyRiUyRnd3dy53aGl0ZWhvdXNlLmdvdiUyRmxpdmUmZGF0YT0wNSU3QzAxJTdDVHJhbk1KJTQwc3RhdGUuZ292JTdDNzA0MDA4NmEwMmE5NDhhMTNhNzcwOGRhMjg5NzAyZWYlN0M2NmNmNTA3NDVhZmU0OGQxYTY5MWExMmIyMTIxZjQ0YiU3QzAlN0MwJTdDNjM3ODY2OTI2MzAxOTg0NDcwJTdDVW5rbm93biU3Q1RXRnBiR1pzYjNkOGV5SldJam9pTUM0d0xqQXdNREFpTENKUUlqb2lWMmx1TXpJaUxDSkJUaUk2SWsxaGFXd2lMQ0pYVkNJNk1uMCUzRCU3QzMwMDAlN0MlN0MlN0Mmc2RhdGE9UTR4ajNOJTJCYm8lMkZNSlIlMkJEQXpzdlhUNzg1TSUyQjczc3dvRE9DbFVnbWFmMVRNJTNEJnJlc2VydmVkPTAifQ.UmniQUi8phRjTJu24FTCDVNo0FTcyT9BjAuWrtRw5v0/s/1248191874/br/130476455920-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1651184745687000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3nMrVib44sC3694FC6ArbM">www.whitehouse.gov/live</a><u>.</u> </span></p>
<p><span>Following the launch, the Declaration and additional information will be available on <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MjcuNTcwODU0NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdiJ9.kSAd1etDmb2Vh6kKH7h45Us544bL4P9FZEPY9sYSSlk/s/1248191874/br/130476455920-l" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MjcuNTcwODU0NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdiJ9.kSAd1etDmb2Vh6kKH7h45Us544bL4P9FZEPY9sYSSlk/s/1248191874/br/130476455920-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1651184745687000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3KGaBxfP8bePLQVJW6tFsL">www.state.gov</a>.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span>On April 28 at 7:30 a.m. EDT, Assistant to the President and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan will host a virtual minister-level launch of the Declaration for the Future of the Internet at the White House with more than 50 partners from around the world.  The Declaration is a political commitment among partners to advance an affirmative vision for the Internet and digital technologies.  The launch event will be livestreamed to the public on <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MjcuNTcwODU0NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2djYzAyLnNhZmVsaW5rcy5wcm90ZWN0aW9uLm91dGxvb2suY29tLz91cmw9aHR0cCUzQSUyRiUyRnd3dy53aGl0ZWhvdXNlLmdvdiUyRmxpdmUmZGF0YT0wNSU3QzAxJTdDVHJhbk1KJTQwc3RhdGUuZ292JTdDNzA0MDA4NmEwMmE5NDhhMTNhNzcwOGRhMjg5NzAyZWYlN0M2NmNmNTA3NDVhZmU0OGQxYTY5MWExMmIyMTIxZjQ0YiU3QzAlN0MwJTdDNjM3ODY2OTI2MzAxOTg0NDcwJTdDVW5rbm93biU3Q1RXRnBiR1pzYjNkOGV5SldJam9pTUM0d0xqQXdNREFpTENKUUlqb2lWMmx1TXpJaUxDSkJUaUk2SWsxaGFXd2lMQ0pYVkNJNk1uMCUzRCU3QzMwMDAlN0MlN0MlN0Mmc2RhdGE9UTR4ajNOJTJCYm8lMkZNSlIlMkJEQXpzdlhUNzg1TSUyQjczc3dvRE9DbFVnbWFmMVRNJTNEJnJlc2VydmVkPTAifQ.UmniQUi8phRjTJu24FTCDVNo0FTcyT9BjAuWrtRw5v0/s/1248191874/br/130476455920-l" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MjcuNTcwODU0NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2djYzAyLnNhZmVsaW5rcy5wcm90ZWN0aW9uLm91dGxvb2suY29tLz91cmw9aHR0cCUzQSUyRiUyRnd3dy53aGl0ZWhvdXNlLmdvdiUyRmxpdmUmZGF0YT0wNSU3QzAxJTdDVHJhbk1KJTQwc3RhdGUuZ292JTdDNzA0MDA4NmEwMmE5NDhhMTNhNzcwOGRhMjg5NzAyZWYlN0M2NmNmNTA3NDVhZmU0OGQxYTY5MWExMmIyMTIxZjQ0YiU3QzAlN0MwJTdDNjM3ODY2OTI2MzAxOTg0NDcwJTdDVW5rbm93biU3Q1RXRnBiR1pzYjNkOGV5SldJam9pTUM0d0xqQXdNREFpTENKUUlqb2lWMmx1TXpJaUxDSkJUaUk2SWsxaGFXd2lMQ0pYVkNJNk1uMCUzRCU3QzMwMDAlN0MlN0MlN0Mmc2RhdGE9UTR4ajNOJTJCYm8lMkZNSlIlMkJEQXpzdlhUNzg1TSUyQjczc3dvRE9DbFVnbWFmMVRNJTNEJnJlc2VydmVkPTAifQ.UmniQUi8phRjTJu24FTCDVNo0FTcyT9BjAuWrtRw5v0/s/1248191874/br/130476455920-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1651184745687000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3nMrVib44sC3694FC6ArbM">www.whitehouse.gov/live</a><u>.</u> </span></p>
<p><span>Following the launch, the Declaration and additional information will be available on <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MjcuNTcwODU0NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdiJ9.kSAd1etDmb2Vh6kKH7h45Us544bL4P9FZEPY9sYSSlk/s/1248191874/br/130476455920-l" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MjcuNTcwODU0NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdiJ9.kSAd1etDmb2Vh6kKH7h45Us544bL4P9FZEPY9sYSSlk/s/1248191874/br/130476455920-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1651184745687000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3KGaBxfP8bePLQVJW6tFsL">www.state.gov</a>.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New U.S. APEC Business Advisory Council Member Appointment</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/new-u-s-apec-business-advisory-council-member-appointment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 19:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=338575</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the appointment of Dominic Ng, Chairman and CEO of East West Bank, to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) Business Advisory Council (ABAC).</p>
<p>Mr. Ng and his ABAC counterparts from the other APEC economies will advise APEC Leaders on issues affecting the continued growth of the region’s economy.  In this role, Mr. Ng will provide recommendations reflecting the perspective of U.S. stakeholders.  ABAC, created in 1995, consists of up to three business representatives from each APEC economy and is a key component of APEC’s multi-stakeholder approach to trade and economic policies.  ABAC meets throughout the year to discuss policy recommendations, undertakes activities to promote trade and investment as well as sustainable and inclusive growth, and reports annually to APEC Leaders.</p>
<p>Mr. Ng leads East West Bank, the largest publicly-listed independent bank headquartered in Southern California.  Since joining the Bank in 1991, Mr. Ng transformed East West from a small savings and loan association with $600 million in assets into a global full-service commercial bank with assets over $62 billion today.  Its 3,200 employees serve more than 600,000 customers worldwide.  Bank Director ranked East West Bank No.1 Performing Bank in 2021 and top bank with the Best Board in 2022.  Mr. Ng serves on the governing boards of Mattel, Inc., the University of Southern California, and the Academy Museum of Motion Pictures.  He is a member of the Council on Foreign Relations and a board member of the 21st Century China Center of the University of California, San Diego.  He is a former Chairman of the Committee of 100.  Mr. Ng’s previous board service also includes the Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco, Los Angeles Branch; PacifiCare Health Systems; Asia Society; and the United Way of Greater Los Angeles.</p>
<p>Among the extensive recognitions for his business achievements and philanthropic impact, Mr. Ng was named one of <i>Forbes</i>’ 25 most notable Chinese Americans; one of <i>Los Angeles Times</i>’100 most influential people in Los Angeles; and Business Person of the Year by the <i>Los Angeles Business Journal</i>. <i>American Banker</i> recognized Mr. Ng as Banker of the Year for successfully executing his vision while maintaining credit discipline and building East West into one of the nation’s most profitable regional banks.</p>
<p>For more than 30 years, APEC has served as the premier economic platform for the United States to engage our regional partners on structural issues to advance an economic and trade architecture that opens markets, promotes high standards, and promotes sustainable and inclusive growth.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact the U.S. APEC Team at <a href="mailto:DOSAPEC@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DOSAPEC@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the appointment of Dominic Ng, Chairman and CEO of East West Bank, to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) Business Advisory Council (ABAC).</p>
<p>Mr. Ng and his ABAC counterparts from the other APEC economies will advise APEC Leaders on issues affecting the continued growth of the region’s economy.  In this role, Mr. Ng will provide recommendations reflecting the perspective of U.S. stakeholders.  ABAC, created in 1995, consists of up to three business representatives from each APEC economy and is a key component of APEC’s multi-stakeholder approach to trade and economic policies.  ABAC meets throughout the year to discuss policy recommendations, undertakes activities to promote trade and investment as well as sustainable and inclusive growth, and reports annually to APEC Leaders.</p>
<p>Mr. Ng leads East West Bank, the largest publicly-listed independent bank headquartered in Southern California.  Since joining the Bank in 1991, Mr. Ng transformed East West from a small savings and loan association with $600 million in assets into a global full-service commercial bank with assets over $62 billion today.  Its 3,200 employees serve more than 600,000 customers worldwide.  Bank Director ranked East West Bank No.1 Performing Bank in 2021 and top bank with the Best Board in 2022.  Mr. Ng serves on the governing boards of Mattel, Inc., the University of Southern California, and the Academy Museum of Motion Pictures.  He is a member of the Council on Foreign Relations and a board member of the 21st Century China Center of the University of California, San Diego.  He is a former Chairman of the Committee of 100.  Mr. Ng’s previous board service also includes the Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco, Los Angeles Branch; PacifiCare Health Systems; Asia Society; and the United Way of Greater Los Angeles.</p>
<p>Among the extensive recognitions for his business achievements and philanthropic impact, Mr. Ng was named one of <i>Forbes</i>’ 25 most notable Chinese Americans; one of <i>Los Angeles Times</i>’100 most influential people in Los Angeles; and Business Person of the Year by the <i>Los Angeles Business Journal</i>. <i>American Banker</i> recognized Mr. Ng as Banker of the Year for successfully executing his vision while maintaining credit discipline and building East West into one of the nation’s most profitable regional banks.</p>
<p>For more than 30 years, APEC has served as the premier economic platform for the United States to engage our regional partners on structural issues to advance an economic and trade architecture that opens markets, promotes high standards, and promotes sustainable and inclusive growth.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact the U.S. APEC Team at <a href="mailto:DOSAPEC@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DOSAPEC@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States Announces Additional Humanitarian Assistance for the Horn of Africa</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-announces-additional-humanitarian-assistance-for-the-horn-of-africa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 18:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=338529</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>In Geneva at the High-Level Roundtable for the Horn of Africa Drought, the United States announced more than $200 million in additional humanitarian assistance for the Horn of Africa region.  This funding will be used to respond to the humanitarian needs from the devastating drought and to address the needs of refugees, internally displaced persons, and people affected by conflict in the region. With this funding, the United States has provided more than $361 million in humanitarian assistance to the region since the beginning of Fiscal Year 2022.</p>
<p>This assistance from the American people will enable our international humanitarian partners to meet the humanitarian needs in the region, including the provision of food and nutrition assistance, health services, access to safe water, sanitation and hygiene, and general livelihood support.</p>
<p>We remain gravely concerned about the worsening humanitarian crisis in the region. Immediate, full, safe, and unhindered access for humanitarian organizations and workers is essential to provide timely, need-based assistance to those affected by the drought and the ongoing conflict, and to save lives.</p>
<p>We welcome the contributions of other donors toward this crisis response and urge others to generously support the immediate humanitarian needs created and exacerbated by this historic drought.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>In Geneva at the High-Level Roundtable for the Horn of Africa Drought, the United States announced more than $200 million in additional humanitarian assistance for the Horn of Africa region.  This funding will be used to respond to the humanitarian needs from the devastating drought and to address the needs of refugees, internally displaced persons, and people affected by conflict in the region. With this funding, the United States has provided more than $361 million in humanitarian assistance to the region since the beginning of Fiscal Year 2022.</p>
<p>This assistance from the American people will enable our international humanitarian partners to meet the humanitarian needs in the region, including the provision of food and nutrition assistance, health services, access to safe water, sanitation and hygiene, and general livelihood support.</p>
<p>We remain gravely concerned about the worsening humanitarian crisis in the region. Immediate, full, safe, and unhindered access for humanitarian organizations and workers is essential to provide timely, need-based assistance to those affected by the drought and the ongoing conflict, and to save lives.</p>
<p>We welcome the contributions of other donors toward this crisis response and urge others to generously support the immediate humanitarian needs created and exacerbated by this historic drought.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The European Democratic Resilience Initiative</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-european-democratic-resilience-initiative/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 18:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=338520</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On March 24, President Biden <a class="external-link" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-announces-new-humanitarian-development-and-democracy-assistance-to-ukraine-and-the-surrounding-region/#:~:text=In%20line%20with%20President%20Biden%27s,human%20rights%20in%20Ukraine%20and" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">announced</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> the launch of the European Democratic Resilience Initiative (EDRI) to bolster democratic resilience, advance anti-corruption efforts, and defend human rights in Ukraine and its neighbors in response Russia’s war of aggression.  Working with Congress, the Biden Administration aims to harness the EDRI to provide up to $320 million in new funding to address immediate and medium-term needs in Europe and Eurasia.  The EDRI will complement the global Presidential Initiative for Democratic Renewal announced by President Biden at the December 2021 Summit for Democracy, as well as efforts to counter Russia’s kleptocracy through the international Russian Elites, Proxies, and Oligarchs (REPO) and the U.S.-interagency law enforcement KleptoCapture task forces.  EDRI-supported programs and projects will be closely coordinated with the EU and other donors.  This Fact Sheet provides information on the EDRI’s initial funding priorities and focus.  Additional information will be released as the U.S. Government continues to address evolving needs in Ukraine and the region.</p>
<p><strong><u>Urgent Needs:</u></strong>  The EDRI will prioritize support for immediate human rights priorities in Ukraine and its surrounding region, including by promoting accountability as a deterrent to further atrocities, and addressing risks to vulnerable and at-risk groups fleeing Ukraine and repression across Eurasia.  Working with Congress, the State Department and USAID anticipate providing an initial $80 million of the overall EDRI funding amount to support the following urgent needs:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Advancing Accountability: </strong>To promote justice and accountability for atrocities committed by Russia’s forces in Ukraine, the EDRI will:
<ul>
<li>Provide expert support and capacity-building for the war crimes units under the Ukrainian Office of the Prosecutor General (OPG), assisting these offices in accomplishing their mandate of investigating and prosecuting war crimes and other serious international crimes.</li>
<li>Support an online platform for the documentation, verification, and dissemination of evidence of Russia’s human rights violations and abuses, war crimes, and other violations of international humanitarian law in the conflict in Ukraine.</li>
<li>Support the UN Human Rights Monitoring Mission in Ukraine (HRMMU) to expand its work in response to Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine.</li>
<li>Support Ukrainian civil society efforts to monitor and document violations of international humanitarian law and human rights violations and abuses; and provide training for legal professionals and monitors on international human rights law; and training and support for media coverage of war crimes and atrocities</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Defending Journalists, Civic Activists and At-Risk Groups: </strong>The EDRI will enhance the safety, security, and operational effectiveness of journalists, and pro-democracy, human rights, and anti-corruption activists inside and outside of Ukraine. The EDRI will specifically support:
<ul>
<li>Logistical and operational support to civil society activists, lawyers, journalists, and human rights defenders who have been forced to flee their home country to help them remain engaged in their relevant work from abroad.</li>
<li>Core funding for Ukrainian national media outlets to maintain operations and continue support for sub-national media.</li>
<li>Digital security and connectivity of Ukrainian civil society activists and organizations, and civil society efforts to address urgent needs of IDPs and vulnerable populations.</li>
<li>Programming to mitigate the impact of disinformation campaigns, including implementation of specific countermeasures.</li>
<li>Grantmaking, convening, and emergency support to a wide range of civil society and media entities throughout Eurasia.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><u>Medium-Term Needs:</u></strong> The State Department and USAID anticipate that, working with Congress<strong>, </strong>the EDRI will maintain its focus on pressing needs, while also expanding its focus to address medium-term needs in Ukraine and the Europe and Eurasia region, including by:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Bolstering Human Rights and Democracy in Europe:</strong> The EDRI will strengthen government institutions and non-governmental capacity and resiliency to support the needs of both local populations and refugees in Europe and Eurasia.</li>
<li><strong>Advancing Anti-Corruption Efforts:</strong> The EDRI will expand rapid response capabilities and technical assistance to build resilience in the face of Kremlin-led and -influenced strategic corruption and kleptocracy.</li>
<li><strong>Sustaining Civil Society and Independent Media:</strong> The EDRI will work to sustain civil society, pro-democracy organizations and movements, and independent media operating throughout the region, including in restrictive operating environments.</li>
</ul>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On March 24, President Biden <a class="external-link" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-announces-new-humanitarian-development-and-democracy-assistance-to-ukraine-and-the-surrounding-region/#:~:text=In%20line%20with%20President%20Biden%27s,human%20rights%20in%20Ukraine%20and" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">announced</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> the launch of the European Democratic Resilience Initiative (EDRI) to bolster democratic resilience, advance anti-corruption efforts, and defend human rights in Ukraine and its neighbors in response Russia’s war of aggression.  Working with Congress, the Biden Administration aims to harness the EDRI to provide up to $320 million in new funding to address immediate and medium-term needs in Europe and Eurasia.  The EDRI will complement the global Presidential Initiative for Democratic Renewal announced by President Biden at the December 2021 Summit for Democracy, as well as efforts to counter Russia’s kleptocracy through the international Russian Elites, Proxies, and Oligarchs (REPO) and the U.S.-interagency law enforcement KleptoCapture task forces.  EDRI-supported programs and projects will be closely coordinated with the EU and other donors.  This Fact Sheet provides information on the EDRI’s initial funding priorities and focus.  Additional information will be released as the U.S. Government continues to address evolving needs in Ukraine and the region.</p>
<p><strong><u>Urgent Needs:</u></strong>  The EDRI will prioritize support for immediate human rights priorities in Ukraine and its surrounding region, including by promoting accountability as a deterrent to further atrocities, and addressing risks to vulnerable and at-risk groups fleeing Ukraine and repression across Eurasia.  Working with Congress, the State Department and USAID anticipate providing an initial $80 million of the overall EDRI funding amount to support the following urgent needs:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Advancing Accountability: </strong>To promote justice and accountability for atrocities committed by Russia’s forces in Ukraine, the EDRI will:
<ul>
<li>Provide expert support and capacity-building for the war crimes units under the Ukrainian Office of the Prosecutor General (OPG), assisting these offices in accomplishing their mandate of investigating and prosecuting war crimes and other serious international crimes.</li>
<li>Support an online platform for the documentation, verification, and dissemination of evidence of Russia’s human rights violations and abuses, war crimes, and other violations of international humanitarian law in the conflict in Ukraine.</li>
<li>Support the UN Human Rights Monitoring Mission in Ukraine (HRMMU) to expand its work in response to Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine.</li>
<li>Support Ukrainian civil society efforts to monitor and document violations of international humanitarian law and human rights violations and abuses; and provide training for legal professionals and monitors on international human rights law; and training and support for media coverage of war crimes and atrocities</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Defending Journalists, Civic Activists and At-Risk Groups: </strong>The EDRI will enhance the safety, security, and operational effectiveness of journalists, and pro-democracy, human rights, and anti-corruption activists inside and outside of Ukraine. The EDRI will specifically support:
<ul>
<li>Logistical and operational support to civil society activists, lawyers, journalists, and human rights defenders who have been forced to flee their home country to help them remain engaged in their relevant work from abroad.</li>
<li>Core funding for Ukrainian national media outlets to maintain operations and continue support for sub-national media.</li>
<li>Digital security and connectivity of Ukrainian civil society activists and organizations, and civil society efforts to address urgent needs of IDPs and vulnerable populations.</li>
<li>Programming to mitigate the impact of disinformation campaigns, including implementation of specific countermeasures.</li>
<li>Grantmaking, convening, and emergency support to a wide range of civil society and media entities throughout Eurasia.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><u>Medium-Term Needs:</u></strong> The State Department and USAID anticipate that, working with Congress<strong>, </strong>the EDRI will maintain its focus on pressing needs, while also expanding its focus to address medium-term needs in Ukraine and the Europe and Eurasia region, including by:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Bolstering Human Rights and Democracy in Europe:</strong> The EDRI will strengthen government institutions and non-governmental capacity and resiliency to support the needs of both local populations and refugees in Europe and Eurasia.</li>
<li><strong>Advancing Anti-Corruption Efforts:</strong> The EDRI will expand rapid response capabilities and technical assistance to build resilience in the face of Kremlin-led and -influenced strategic corruption and kleptocracy.</li>
<li><strong>Sustaining Civil Society and Independent Media:</strong> The EDRI will work to sustain civil society, pro-democracy organizations and movements, and independent media operating throughout the region, including in restrictive operating environments.</li>
</ul>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Senior Administration Officials on the Release of Trevor Reed</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/senior-administration-officials-on-the-release-of-trevor-reed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 15:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=338379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you very much and good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining this call, and especially so on such short notice.  We wanted to convene it promptly given the news that has emerged this morning regarding the release of Trevor Reed from Russian custody.  We’ll do this call on background.  You can refer to what you hear – you can attribute it to senior administration officials.</p>
<p>For your knowledge only and not for reporting, we have two senior administration officials on the line.  We have .  We also have  on the line.  Again, you can refer to both of them as senior administration officials.</p>
<p>With that, the call will be embargoed until its conclusion, and I will turn it over to our first senior administration official to start us off.  Go ahead.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:</b>  Thank you so much, .  I’m grateful to everyone for joining and I am particularly grateful to have good news to share this morning.  Trevor Reed, a U.S. citizen, a former U.S. Marine detained for far too long in Russia, now has his freedom and he is on the way to being reunited with his parents.</p>
<p>It is a big moment and a moment that speaks to President Biden’s commitment to bring home Americans held hostage and wrongfully detained around the world.  Let me put today’s news in some context and say a few words on how we got to this particular moment.</p>
<p>President Biden has been very clear since the beginning of the administration about his commitment to bringing Americans home.  Very early in his tenure, Secretary of State Blinken spoke with a wide range of hostage and detainee families emphasizing the administration’s commitment in this area.</p>
<p>And day in and day out, the President’s National Security Council staff works on resolving these often very hard, always very important matters.  That includes working closely with the remarkable Office of the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs at the State Department.  It also includes working closely with FBI and a wide range of other components of the federal government.</p>
<p>The commitment to resolve these matters goes right to the top – to the President, to the National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, who has heard directly from and spoken directly with hostage and detainee families understandably eager to hear how their government is working to bring home their loved ones.</p>
<p>I would emphasize the President isn’t just committed; he is also delivering on that commitment.  He has brought home Americans from Venezuela, from Afghanistan, from Haiti, from Burma, and now today from Russia.  Trevor’s freedom is the result of months and months of hard, careful work across the U.S. Government.  That includes negotiations on this discrete particular issue set with the Russians that have been going on for a very long time.</p>
<p>Ultimately, those negotiations led the President to have to make a very hard decision.  It was a decision to commute the sentence of Konstantin Yaroshenko, a Russian smuggler convicted of conspiring to import cocaine.  Now I want to emphasize here that this was a commutation of his sentence.  The action in no way undermines or diminishes the import of the finding of his guilt.  I also want to emphasize that Yaroshenko has already paid a steep price in the U.S. justice system for his crime.  In fact, he had already served the majority of his sentence.</p>
<p>That all being said, this is a tough call for a president.  But President Biden made it to bring home an American whose health was a source of an intense concern and to deliver on his commitment to resolve these hard cases and reunite Americans with their loved ones.  And so Trevor Reed is on the way to be reunited with his loving family.</p>
<p>I suspect that when we get to questions, there will be questions about the operational or logistical details of getting this done, and I will offer warning in advance that I just won’t have much to say on that because we don’t comment on such things.  But I can say that we are relieved and frankly delighted to be welcoming Trevor home, which is where he belongs.</p>
<p>I also want to emphasize that our work in this area continues.  Even as we celebrate today’s good news, Paul Whelan is very much on our mind, still detained in Russia.  So are others held in Russia, so are others held hostage and wrongfully detained elsewhere in the world.  We on the President’s team will keep working these issues until they’re home, just as the President has pledged that we’ll do.</p>
<p>And I want to be very clear:  This is a discrete issue on which we were able to make an arrangement with the Russians.  It represents no change, zero, to our approach to the appalling violence in Ukraine.  Let me just emphasize this again because it’s so important:  The discussions with the Russians that led to this exchange were strictly limited to these topics, not a broader diplomatic conversation or even the start of one.</p>
<p>Now let me hand things over to my colleague , who is , an office that has helped to make today’s good news possible.  , over to you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b>  Hey, thank you, .  Hey, everybody this is , as  said.  I’m .</p>
<p>Obviously, as  said, the United States welcomes the release of U.S. citizen Trevor Reed, who has been wrongfully detained in Russia since 2019.  I also want to emphasize what  said, that this was a team effort.  The President and his team over at the White House, the State Department, our office, but also all of you on the line here.  The media coverage, the interest in Trevor Reed’s case and the ongoing case of Paul Whelan has been crucial to ensuring that the other – that the Russians knew our position and the President’s determination to get Trevor back.</p>
<p>So I just want to update that SPEHA Carstens met with Trevor upon his release from detention.  He was in good spirits and he spoke to his family.  While we celebrate the release of Trevor, we still have work to do.  Unfortunately, we have another American citizen to get back.  The President and Secretary Blinken have been clear about the need to see wrongfully detained U.S. citizen Paul Whelan released.  And we won’t stop working on this until every U.S. national is<a id="post-338379-footnote-ref-i" href="#post-338379-footnote-i"></a> detained anywhere in the world.  And I just want to emphasize what  said, that this is a longstanding effort – many, many months of discrete diplomacy, with certain milestones along the way, such as when the Secretary of State raised Trevor and Paul in Reykjavík in May, and then the President again in June, and then the intensive negotiations that followed.</p>
<p>So this is a good day.  Thank you all for the broader team effort here.  I’ll turn it back to  at that point.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Terrific.  Operator, if you wouldn’t mind just repeating the instructions to ask questions.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  If you wish to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 at this time.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Great.  We will start with the line of Jennifer Hansler, please.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you.  Thanks so much for doing the call.  Can you just give us a little more details on the tick-tock of how this went down?  I know you said months and months, , but specifically when did this start to gain real traction?  How frequently was the U.S. meeting with the Russians?  Who was meeting with the Russians to negotiate this?  And how was this specific Russian prisoner and how was Trevor chosen out of the multiple Americans that are held there and the multiple Russians that are detained here?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:</b>  Yeah, thanks for the question, Jennifer.  So as we indicated, this conversation with the Russians on this particular issue, this discrete issue, has been going on for months.  And we’ve acknowledged publicly that everyone from the President down, including the Secretary of State, as my colleague mentioned, have continued to raise at all levels with the Russian Government the importance – to us, to our President, to our government – of bringing home those who are wrongfully detained.</p>
<p>That conversation has, of course, included others whom we regard as wrongfully detained in Russia, and we’ll need to continue to include them so that they come home as well.  Obviously, the conversations on this particular issue have accelerated recently to get us to this point.  And one factor in getting to this point was our growing concern, which you’ve heard from the family publicly and which we share as a government, of what the status of Trevor Reed’s health was while in detention.  That, I think, contributed to really ratcheting up the conversations on this issue, getting to a point where we were able to make this arrangement, getting to a point where we were able to turn to some of the logistics of simply getting it done.  And of course, we are delighted that we have found a way to get it done, and we’ll continue to work on the cases that still need resolution.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  We’ll go to the line of Shaun Tandon.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So I know you said at the beginning that you don’t see this as leading to any greater diplomatic effort with Russia.  Could I expand on that?  In terms of the conversations that were there, did it give you an idea about the Russians being serious about this in particular, about anything broader?  Was – were other countries involved in this, or was it truly a bilateral aspect?</p>
<p>And also, you mentioned that Trevor Reed, he seemed to be in good spirits.  Can you just expand on that in terms of the condition that he’s in?  Do you think that he’s – his state is good at this point?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:</b>  I’ll say a couple words on this, and then I’ll see if Ned wants to add anything as well, or , on the last point there.</p>
<p>I would emphasize, as your question refers back to, that these conversations, these negotiations were on a discrete issue set.  The discussions that led to today’s very good news were strictly limited to these topics, detainee topics.  They were not part of broader diplomatic discussions; they were not the beginnings of discussions on other issues.  We were delighted to see them come to fruition in this way, of course, but they are limited – they were limited and are limited to these particular issues.</p>
<p>, is there anything else you’d like to add on that?</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  I think that’s a key point.  I would just also add that this in no way will change our approach to supporting our Ukrainian partners and to holding the Kremlin accountable for its actions in Ukraine.  But as my colleague has stressed multiple times, these topics weren’t broached.  They were intended to be broached, these broader topics.  This was about one thing and one thing only, and it was securing the release of an American who had been wrongfully detained in Russia for far too long.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b>  Hey, I might just add also on the question about Trevor, he was in good spirits, as I said.  But beyond that, out of respect to the privacy – to Trevor’s privacy and the privacy of his family, we’re going to let him and his family speak for themselves when they’re ready.  It’s a good day, and he’s clearly in good spirits, but you’ll understand he’s had a difficult couple years here.  So – and we ought to respect that as well.  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  We’ll go to the line of Humeyra Pamuk.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  (Inaudible) doing this.  I have a couple of questions.  When do you expect Trevor to be home?  And I understand that this was squarely – these discussions were squarely about him, but can you talk a little bit about the nature or, like, the demeanor of the Russians in these talks?  Was there anything that was positive?  Or what was it like that – was there anything that gave you any hope about a broader diplomatic thing?  Because there are a number of channels all across the world for various reasons, but basically trying to put an end to this war – was there anything in these discussions that you thought could be a positive signal?  And also, can you give us an update on Britney Griner’s case, please?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:  </b>Yeah, thank you for those questions.  I’ll hit them briefly and then see if  wants to embellish.</p>
<p>So on the first one, Trevor is on his way home, on his way to the United States now.  I’ll stay away from kind of particular operational details, but he is on his way now, which we’re obviously delighted about.</p>
<p>In terms of the conversations with the Russians on these issues, look, we have been saying for the past couple months, few months that where we can on issues of mutual interest, on issues of importance to us, we will try to find ways to continue conversations and, ideally, to get things done.  And I think this represents one of those categories – inaction, so to speak.  It was an issue that we had been discussing.  As I have indicated before, many months ago, we were able to keep discussing and obviously able to get to a result about which we’re very happy with respect to Trevor Reed and about which more work needs to be done for other Americans.</p>
<p>But I think being able to get to this point is consistent with what we’ve been saying about trying to find areas where we still can have a constructive conversation without in any way – as  and I have both emphasized – without in any way representing through this any change in our approach to just appalling violence that we continue to see in Ukraine.</p>
<p>And then I’ll just say briefly on the last question that we are very aware that there are other Americans held in Russia with Whelan, Griner, and others very much in our minds today, even as we are so happy for the news about Trevor Reed.  And we will continue to work on and attempt to find ways to address other cases as best we can.</p>
<p>, do you want to add anything to that?</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>The only thing I would add – and I would also invite my colleague to add on here – is that there is a key word in Roger Carstens’ title.  He’s the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs.  And so when Roger Carstens, when his team are having discussions with foreign governments, they’re discussing one thing and one thing only.  They’re discussing hostages and Americans who are detained against their will unjustly overseas.  These discussions didn’t give us any additional pessimism about Russia’s course in Ukraine, neither did it give us any additional optimism, precisely because there wasn’t a discussion of anything beyond this very discrete, this very particular issue.  And that was the successful release – successful as of today – of Trevor Reed.</p>
<p>, do you want to add anything?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:  </b>Thanks, .  You covered it right there.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>We’ll take a final question here.  We’ll go to Missy Ryan.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>What – I’m not sure what the limits of what you’re able to talk about in terms of the particulars of the transfers and all of that, but is the – Mr. Yaroshenko, is he now in Russian Government custody?  Can you say whether this whole arrangement and negotiation involved any senior U.S. Government travel to Moscow?  And also, could you just, if possible, clarify for us how many Americans are being held by the Russian Government?  Obviously, you mentioned two individuals, but are there additional people that we should know about?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:  </b>Thanks, Missy.  So as you anticipated, I’ll stay a bit general here, but I will say that Mr. Yaroshenko is in Russian custody at this point, and that we were able to make this arrangement without additional senior-level travel to Moscow or to Russia.  And I think I’ll probably leave it at that.  , anything you want to add?</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Nope.  I think you covered it.</p>
<p>, barring anything additional from you, we will bring this call to an end.  Again, a reminder:  This call was on background, attributable to senior administration officials, and the embargo is now lifted.  Thanks, everyone, for dialing in.  Thanks to fellow speakers.</p>
<div>
<hr />
<div>
<p><a href="#post-338379-footnote-ref-i"></a><a id="post-338379-footnote-i"></a>‘…<i>until every U.S. national unlawfully detained anywhere in the world is free.’</i></p>
</div>
</div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you very much and good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining this call, and especially so on such short notice.  We wanted to convene it promptly given the news that has emerged this morning regarding the release of Trevor Reed from Russian custody.  We’ll do this call on background.  You can refer to what you hear – you can attribute it to senior administration officials.</p>
<p>For your knowledge only and not for reporting, we have two senior administration officials on the line.  We have .  We also have  on the line.  Again, you can refer to both of them as senior administration officials.</p>
<p>With that, the call will be embargoed until its conclusion, and I will turn it over to our first senior administration official to start us off.  Go ahead.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:</b>  Thank you so much, .  I’m grateful to everyone for joining and I am particularly grateful to have good news to share this morning.  Trevor Reed, a U.S. citizen, a former U.S. Marine detained for far too long in Russia, now has his freedom and he is on the way to being reunited with his parents.</p>
<p>It is a big moment and a moment that speaks to President Biden’s commitment to bring home Americans held hostage and wrongfully detained around the world.  Let me put today’s news in some context and say a few words on how we got to this particular moment.</p>
<p>President Biden has been very clear since the beginning of the administration about his commitment to bringing Americans home.  Very early in his tenure, Secretary of State Blinken spoke with a wide range of hostage and detainee families emphasizing the administration’s commitment in this area.</p>
<p>And day in and day out, the President’s National Security Council staff works on resolving these often very hard, always very important matters.  That includes working closely with the remarkable Office of the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs at the State Department.  It also includes working closely with FBI and a wide range of other components of the federal government.</p>
<p>The commitment to resolve these matters goes right to the top – to the President, to the National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, who has heard directly from and spoken directly with hostage and detainee families understandably eager to hear how their government is working to bring home their loved ones.</p>
<p>I would emphasize the President isn’t just committed; he is also delivering on that commitment.  He has brought home Americans from Venezuela, from Afghanistan, from Haiti, from Burma, and now today from Russia.  Trevor’s freedom is the result of months and months of hard, careful work across the U.S. Government.  That includes negotiations on this discrete particular issue set with the Russians that have been going on for a very long time.</p>
<p>Ultimately, those negotiations led the President to have to make a very hard decision.  It was a decision to commute the sentence of Konstantin Yaroshenko, a Russian smuggler convicted of conspiring to import cocaine.  Now I want to emphasize here that this was a commutation of his sentence.  The action in no way undermines or diminishes the import of the finding of his guilt.  I also want to emphasize that Yaroshenko has already paid a steep price in the U.S. justice system for his crime.  In fact, he had already served the majority of his sentence.</p>
<p>That all being said, this is a tough call for a president.  But President Biden made it to bring home an American whose health was a source of an intense concern and to deliver on his commitment to resolve these hard cases and reunite Americans with their loved ones.  And so Trevor Reed is on the way to be reunited with his loving family.</p>
<p>I suspect that when we get to questions, there will be questions about the operational or logistical details of getting this done, and I will offer warning in advance that I just won’t have much to say on that because we don’t comment on such things.  But I can say that we are relieved and frankly delighted to be welcoming Trevor home, which is where he belongs.</p>
<p>I also want to emphasize that our work in this area continues.  Even as we celebrate today’s good news, Paul Whelan is very much on our mind, still detained in Russia.  So are others held in Russia, so are others held hostage and wrongfully detained elsewhere in the world.  We on the President’s team will keep working these issues until they’re home, just as the President has pledged that we’ll do.</p>
<p>And I want to be very clear:  This is a discrete issue on which we were able to make an arrangement with the Russians.  It represents no change, zero, to our approach to the appalling violence in Ukraine.  Let me just emphasize this again because it’s so important:  The discussions with the Russians that led to this exchange were strictly limited to these topics, not a broader diplomatic conversation or even the start of one.</p>
<p>Now let me hand things over to my colleague , who is , an office that has helped to make today’s good news possible.  , over to you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b>  Hey, thank you, .  Hey, everybody this is , as  said.  I’m .</p>
<p>Obviously, as  said, the United States welcomes the release of U.S. citizen Trevor Reed, who has been wrongfully detained in Russia since 2019.  I also want to emphasize what  said, that this was a team effort.  The President and his team over at the White House, the State Department, our office, but also all of you on the line here.  The media coverage, the interest in Trevor Reed’s case and the ongoing case of Paul Whelan has been crucial to ensuring that the other – that the Russians knew our position and the President’s determination to get Trevor back.</p>
<p>So I just want to update that SPEHA Carstens met with Trevor upon his release from detention.  He was in good spirits and he spoke to his family.  While we celebrate the release of Trevor, we still have work to do.  Unfortunately, we have another American citizen to get back.  The President and Secretary Blinken have been clear about the need to see wrongfully detained U.S. citizen Paul Whelan released.  And we won’t stop working on this until every U.S. national is<a id="post-338379-footnote-ref-i" href="#post-338379-footnote-i"></a> detained anywhere in the world.  And I just want to emphasize what  said, that this is a longstanding effort – many, many months of discrete diplomacy, with certain milestones along the way, such as when the Secretary of State raised Trevor and Paul in Reykjavík in May, and then the President again in June, and then the intensive negotiations that followed.</p>
<p>So this is a good day.  Thank you all for the broader team effort here.  I’ll turn it back to  at that point.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Terrific.  Operator, if you wouldn’t mind just repeating the instructions to ask questions.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  If you wish to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 at this time.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Great.  We will start with the line of Jennifer Hansler, please.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you.  Thanks so much for doing the call.  Can you just give us a little more details on the tick-tock of how this went down?  I know you said months and months, , but specifically when did this start to gain real traction?  How frequently was the U.S. meeting with the Russians?  Who was meeting with the Russians to negotiate this?  And how was this specific Russian prisoner and how was Trevor chosen out of the multiple Americans that are held there and the multiple Russians that are detained here?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:</b>  Yeah, thanks for the question, Jennifer.  So as we indicated, this conversation with the Russians on this particular issue, this discrete issue, has been going on for months.  And we’ve acknowledged publicly that everyone from the President down, including the Secretary of State, as my colleague mentioned, have continued to raise at all levels with the Russian Government the importance – to us, to our President, to our government – of bringing home those who are wrongfully detained.</p>
<p>That conversation has, of course, included others whom we regard as wrongfully detained in Russia, and we’ll need to continue to include them so that they come home as well.  Obviously, the conversations on this particular issue have accelerated recently to get us to this point.  And one factor in getting to this point was our growing concern, which you’ve heard from the family publicly and which we share as a government, of what the status of Trevor Reed’s health was while in detention.  That, I think, contributed to really ratcheting up the conversations on this issue, getting to a point where we were able to make this arrangement, getting to a point where we were able to turn to some of the logistics of simply getting it done.  And of course, we are delighted that we have found a way to get it done, and we’ll continue to work on the cases that still need resolution.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  We’ll go to the line of Shaun Tandon.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So I know you said at the beginning that you don’t see this as leading to any greater diplomatic effort with Russia.  Could I expand on that?  In terms of the conversations that were there, did it give you an idea about the Russians being serious about this in particular, about anything broader?  Was – were other countries involved in this, or was it truly a bilateral aspect?</p>
<p>And also, you mentioned that Trevor Reed, he seemed to be in good spirits.  Can you just expand on that in terms of the condition that he’s in?  Do you think that he’s – his state is good at this point?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:</b>  I’ll say a couple words on this, and then I’ll see if Ned wants to add anything as well, or , on the last point there.</p>
<p>I would emphasize, as your question refers back to, that these conversations, these negotiations were on a discrete issue set.  The discussions that led to today’s very good news were strictly limited to these topics, detainee topics.  They were not part of broader diplomatic discussions; they were not the beginnings of discussions on other issues.  We were delighted to see them come to fruition in this way, of course, but they are limited – they were limited and are limited to these particular issues.</p>
<p>, is there anything else you’d like to add on that?</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  I think that’s a key point.  I would just also add that this in no way will change our approach to supporting our Ukrainian partners and to holding the Kremlin accountable for its actions in Ukraine.  But as my colleague has stressed multiple times, these topics weren’t broached.  They were intended to be broached, these broader topics.  This was about one thing and one thing only, and it was securing the release of an American who had been wrongfully detained in Russia for far too long.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b>  Hey, I might just add also on the question about Trevor, he was in good spirits, as I said.  But beyond that, out of respect to the privacy – to Trevor’s privacy and the privacy of his family, we’re going to let him and his family speak for themselves when they’re ready.  It’s a good day, and he’s clearly in good spirits, but you’ll understand he’s had a difficult couple years here.  So – and we ought to respect that as well.  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  We’ll go to the line of Humeyra Pamuk.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  (Inaudible) doing this.  I have a couple of questions.  When do you expect Trevor to be home?  And I understand that this was squarely – these discussions were squarely about him, but can you talk a little bit about the nature or, like, the demeanor of the Russians in these talks?  Was there anything that was positive?  Or what was it like that – was there anything that gave you any hope about a broader diplomatic thing?  Because there are a number of channels all across the world for various reasons, but basically trying to put an end to this war – was there anything in these discussions that you thought could be a positive signal?  And also, can you give us an update on Britney Griner’s case, please?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:  </b>Yeah, thank you for those questions.  I’ll hit them briefly and then see if  wants to embellish.</p>
<p>So on the first one, Trevor is on his way home, on his way to the United States now.  I’ll stay away from kind of particular operational details, but he is on his way now, which we’re obviously delighted about.</p>
<p>In terms of the conversations with the Russians on these issues, look, we have been saying for the past couple months, few months that where we can on issues of mutual interest, on issues of importance to us, we will try to find ways to continue conversations and, ideally, to get things done.  And I think this represents one of those categories – inaction, so to speak.  It was an issue that we had been discussing.  As I have indicated before, many months ago, we were able to keep discussing and obviously able to get to a result about which we’re very happy with respect to Trevor Reed and about which more work needs to be done for other Americans.</p>
<p>But I think being able to get to this point is consistent with what we’ve been saying about trying to find areas where we still can have a constructive conversation without in any way – as  and I have both emphasized – without in any way representing through this any change in our approach to just appalling violence that we continue to see in Ukraine.</p>
<p>And then I’ll just say briefly on the last question that we are very aware that there are other Americans held in Russia with Whelan, Griner, and others very much in our minds today, even as we are so happy for the news about Trevor Reed.  And we will continue to work on and attempt to find ways to address other cases as best we can.</p>
<p>, do you want to add anything to that?</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>The only thing I would add – and I would also invite my colleague to add on here – is that there is a key word in Roger Carstens’ title.  He’s the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs.  And so when Roger Carstens, when his team are having discussions with foreign governments, they’re discussing one thing and one thing only.  They’re discussing hostages and Americans who are detained against their will unjustly overseas.  These discussions didn’t give us any additional pessimism about Russia’s course in Ukraine, neither did it give us any additional optimism, precisely because there wasn’t a discussion of anything beyond this very discrete, this very particular issue.  And that was the successful release – successful as of today – of Trevor Reed.</p>
<p>, do you want to add anything?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:  </b>Thanks, .  You covered it right there.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>We’ll take a final question here.  We’ll go to Missy Ryan.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>What – I’m not sure what the limits of what you’re able to talk about in terms of the particulars of the transfers and all of that, but is the – Mr. Yaroshenko, is he now in Russian Government custody?  Can you say whether this whole arrangement and negotiation involved any senior U.S. Government travel to Moscow?  And also, could you just, if possible, clarify for us how many Americans are being held by the Russian Government?  Obviously, you mentioned two individuals, but are there additional people that we should know about?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:  </b>Thanks, Missy.  So as you anticipated, I’ll stay a bit general here, but I will say that Mr. Yaroshenko is in Russian custody at this point, and that we were able to make this arrangement without additional senior-level travel to Moscow or to Russia.  And I think I’ll probably leave it at that.  , anything you want to add?</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Nope.  I think you covered it.</p>
<p>, barring anything additional from you, we will bring this call to an end.  Again, a reminder:  This call was on background, attributable to senior administration officials, and the embargo is now lifted.  Thanks, everyone, for dialing in.  Thanks to fellow speakers.</p>
<div>
<hr />
<div>
<p><a href="#post-338379-footnote-ref-i"></a><a id="post-338379-footnote-i"></a>‘…<i>until every U.S. national unlawfully detained anywhere in the world is free.’</i></p>
</div>
</div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
