<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 11:43:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Moldovan Foreign Minister Natalia Gavrilita Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-moldovan-foreign-minister-natalia-gavrilita-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 11:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321175</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Chisinau, Moldova</p>
<p>Government House</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER GAVRILITA:</strong>  Dear Secretary of State Blinken, welcome to Chisinau.  I’m sure we would have all loved to have met under different circumstances and for your visit to have occurred on a more positive occasion.  Yet precisely because our region has been plunged into war, it is even of more importance that your visit comes as a sign of strong support not only for our effort to deal with the large influx of refugees and to help the people of Ukraine, but also to support our aspiration to be part of the free world.</p>
<p>We strongly condemn the act of war on Ukraine and fully support the independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders.  We stand united with the people of Ukraine and our call is for restoration of peace as soon as possible, first and foremost through diplomatic efforts.</p>
<p>We are firmly committed to help those who are fleeing from Ukraine.  The government has put in place the most comprehensive humanitarian operation in the history of the Republic of Moldova.  As of this morning, we had more than 230,000 people who have crossed the border from Ukraine and 120,000 stayed in Moldova; 96,000 of them are Ukrainian citizens.  For a small country like Moldova, proportionately this is a very large number and managing such an influx has only been possible because of the extraordinary solidarity shown by every person, every company, every nongovernmental organization.  Everybody has come together to host, to provide shelter, to provide food, to provide assistance to those who are fleeing the war.</p>
<p>But we will need assistance to deal with this influx, and we need this quickly and through flexible instruments.  Unfortunately, this humanitarian crisis comes on top of the developmental challenges that Moldova already had, and it was dealing with global challenges like the pandemic and energy crisis and inflation.  So we were already in double-digit inflation.  This war will also not only cost us in terms of the humanitarian cost, but economically, trade with Ukraine has been a very important element of our economy and we see disruptions of transportation routes and we see a global impact economically of this war.</p>
<p>So we count on your quick and comprehensive support as we have always had, and we are very grateful for the support that the U.S. Government has provided for the development of Moldova and to ensure the well-being of its citizens.</p>
<p>And finally, I just want to mention that we’ve – while we are facing these unprecedented circumstances, we are firmly committed to our path for European integration.  We believe that this is an agenda to transform Moldova into a modern, prosperous European state based on the fundamental values of human rights and the rule of law.  And we are committed to steer towards membership in the European Union.  We have submitted our application on the 3rd of March.  And as we embark on this journey, we know that we can count on the friendship and the strong support with the United States.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Prime Minister, thank you very, very much.  And indeed, you can count on that support across the board.</p>
<p>Let me first say, as you noted so well, this terrible, unprovoked war of choice is having, of course, profound consequences for the Ukrainian people, who are suffering terribly as a result while showing extraordinary resilience, but it’s also having consequences beyond Ukraine’s borders, including here in Moldova.  We admire the generosity, the hospitality, the willingness to be such good friends to people who are in distress, and indeed, we want to do everything we can to help you deal with the burden that this is imposing.  But we’re grateful for it.</p>
<p>As you also noted, at a time when all of us have so many things that we need to do to make the lives of our citizens better – dealing with what’s left of COVID-19, advancing the economic recovery that touches everyone, meeting the challenge of climate change and transforming our economies to account for that, so many things that we need to do for our societies, for our people – the last thing anyone needed or anyone wanted was a war, especially one that was totally unnecessary, totally unprovoked and, I’m afraid, premeditated.  And so the consequences, as you point out, go beyond Ukraine.  They go beyond even Ukraine’s neighbors.  They are in fact global because this is having an impact on everything that we actually need to be doing and should be doing.  And like you, we want to see it brought to the swiftest possible conclusion.</p>
<p>But meanwhile, we’re prepared to do everything we can in support of the Ukrainian people, in support of Ukraine’s neighbors who are standing up for the Ukrainian people and helping those in distress, those fleeing, and, of course, continuing to put pressure on President Putin and his government to change course.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, though, we’re also very, very pleased to be working closely with you.  I am in effect back to Moldova because this is my second visit here.  I was here in 2016.  It’s wonderful to be back.  And it’s especially wonderful to be back because your story is such a powerful one and positive one at a time that we need powerful and positive stories.  It’s a story of democracy emerging and strengthening and taking root, and it’s something that I think is inspiring to the world because it’s coming at a moment when over some years, democracies have been moving backward, not forward.  You’re the example of the opposite.  You’re showing us and you’re showing the world how democracies can grow, strengthen, and we are and will be your partner in that.  So thank you for having us.</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER GAVRILITA:</strong>  Thank you. <input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Chisinau, Moldova</p>
<p>Government House</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER GAVRILITA:</strong>  Dear Secretary of State Blinken, welcome to Chisinau.  I’m sure we would have all loved to have met under different circumstances and for your visit to have occurred on a more positive occasion.  Yet precisely because our region has been plunged into war, it is even of more importance that your visit comes as a sign of strong support not only for our effort to deal with the large influx of refugees and to help the people of Ukraine, but also to support our aspiration to be part of the free world.</p>
<p>We strongly condemn the act of war on Ukraine and fully support the independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders.  We stand united with the people of Ukraine and our call is for restoration of peace as soon as possible, first and foremost through diplomatic efforts.</p>
<p>We are firmly committed to help those who are fleeing from Ukraine.  The government has put in place the most comprehensive humanitarian operation in the history of the Republic of Moldova.  As of this morning, we had more than 230,000 people who have crossed the border from Ukraine and 120,000 stayed in Moldova; 96,000 of them are Ukrainian citizens.  For a small country like Moldova, proportionately this is a very large number and managing such an influx has only been possible because of the extraordinary solidarity shown by every person, every company, every nongovernmental organization.  Everybody has come together to host, to provide shelter, to provide food, to provide assistance to those who are fleeing the war.</p>
<p>But we will need assistance to deal with this influx, and we need this quickly and through flexible instruments.  Unfortunately, this humanitarian crisis comes on top of the developmental challenges that Moldova already had, and it was dealing with global challenges like the pandemic and energy crisis and inflation.  So we were already in double-digit inflation.  This war will also not only cost us in terms of the humanitarian cost, but economically, trade with Ukraine has been a very important element of our economy and we see disruptions of transportation routes and we see a global impact economically of this war.</p>
<p>So we count on your quick and comprehensive support as we have always had, and we are very grateful for the support that the U.S. Government has provided for the development of Moldova and to ensure the well-being of its citizens.</p>
<p>And finally, I just want to mention that we’ve – while we are facing these unprecedented circumstances, we are firmly committed to our path for European integration.  We believe that this is an agenda to transform Moldova into a modern, prosperous European state based on the fundamental values of human rights and the rule of law.  And we are committed to steer towards membership in the European Union.  We have submitted our application on the 3rd of March.  And as we embark on this journey, we know that we can count on the friendship and the strong support with the United States.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Prime Minister, thank you very, very much.  And indeed, you can count on that support across the board.</p>
<p>Let me first say, as you noted so well, this terrible, unprovoked war of choice is having, of course, profound consequences for the Ukrainian people, who are suffering terribly as a result while showing extraordinary resilience, but it’s also having consequences beyond Ukraine’s borders, including here in Moldova.  We admire the generosity, the hospitality, the willingness to be such good friends to people who are in distress, and indeed, we want to do everything we can to help you deal with the burden that this is imposing.  But we’re grateful for it.</p>
<p>As you also noted, at a time when all of us have so many things that we need to do to make the lives of our citizens better – dealing with what’s left of COVID-19, advancing the economic recovery that touches everyone, meeting the challenge of climate change and transforming our economies to account for that, so many things that we need to do for our societies, for our people – the last thing anyone needed or anyone wanted was a war, especially one that was totally unnecessary, totally unprovoked and, I’m afraid, premeditated.  And so the consequences, as you point out, go beyond Ukraine.  They go beyond even Ukraine’s neighbors.  They are in fact global because this is having an impact on everything that we actually need to be doing and should be doing.  And like you, we want to see it brought to the swiftest possible conclusion.</p>
<p>But meanwhile, we’re prepared to do everything we can in support of the Ukrainian people, in support of Ukraine’s neighbors who are standing up for the Ukrainian people and helping those in distress, those fleeing, and, of course, continuing to put pressure on President Putin and his government to change course.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, though, we’re also very, very pleased to be working closely with you.  I am in effect back to Moldova because this is my second visit here.  I was here in 2016.  It’s wonderful to be back.  And it’s especially wonderful to be back because your story is such a powerful one and positive one at a time that we need powerful and positive stories.  It’s a story of democracy emerging and strengthening and taking root, and it’s something that I think is inspiring to the world because it’s coming at a moment when over some years, democracies have been moving backward, not forward.  You’re the example of the opposite.  You’re showing us and you’re showing the world how democracies can grow, strengthen, and we are and will be your partner in that.  So thank you for having us.</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER GAVRILITA:</strong>  Thank you. <input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Piotr Krasko of TVN</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-piotr-krasko-of-tvn/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 22:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321128</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rzeszow, Poland</p>
<p>Hotel Bristol</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Mr. Secretary, we really appreciate your presence.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>It’s a great honor for us.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>It’s very good to be with you tonight.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Mr. Secretary, you are one of more than 10,000 American citizens now in Poland. A lot of them are in this region – we are in Rzeszow now – most of them are soldiers.  We really, really appreciate your presence here, you and American soldiers.  You’ve had a lot of many different meetings today, including our prime minister, minister of foreign affairs.  Can you tell us about the results of these meetings?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, first, let me say this:  I am overwhelmed by the generosity of Poland and the Polish people.  I visited the welcome center for Ukrainians and others who are coming out of Ukraine because of the horrific aggression being committed by Vladimir Putin and Russia.  And to see the hospitality, to see the generosity of our Polish friends is very, very moving in and of itself.  And I think it speaks to a larger solidarity that exists and that we’re seeing between the United States and Poland, but also so much of the international community, in support of Ukraine and in opposition to a war of choice being committed by Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p>The strength of our own partnership, I think, has never been better, and that was very evident to me in the meetings that I had today with the prime minister, with my friend Zbigniew Rau – we’ve worked together very closely on a very regular basis.  And we’re united in this effort; that’s what’s so important.  That unity in support of Ukraine, in opposition to this aggression by Russia, is what will carry the day.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Half an hour ago, we’ve heard about your meeting with minister of foreign affairs of Ukraine, the Minister Kuleba.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Yes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>As far as I understand, you were in Ukraine – correct me if I&#8217;m wrong – you crossed the border.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>That’s correct.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>And can you tell us more about this conversation?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>First, Dmytro Kuleba is a remarkable colleague, a remarkable friend.  And he, like President Zelenskyy and others in the government, have been the face of the Ukrainian people in confronting this aggression.  But we’re on the phone regularly.  He’s somewhere in Ukraine.  I couldn’t say were for security reasons.  But I thought it was important when we met – symbolically – to cross the border and to have us stand together in Ukraine, because we’re standing together for Ukraine.  And we work very closely, and for me, it’s making sure that I understand as best possible what our Ukrainian friends and partners need, what we can do to continue to support them as well as to put the pressure on Russia.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Sir, in 1940, Churchill delivered his famous speech in British Parliament:  We’ll fight “in the streets,” “in the fields,” “on the landing grounds” until America, “with all its power and might,” would come to rescue us.  I would never imagine that they will say these words, but we have a war just next to us.  Would you be ready again to come with all your power and might to defend your European allies &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Yes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>&#8212; this time, including Poland in NATO?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Yes.  Yes, that’s the – it’s as simple as that. President Biden said this to the entire country.  He gave his State of the Union speech – this is the speech that a president gives where he talks to every American in their living rooms – just last week.  And what he said there – and he’s said repeatedly in recent weeks – is we will defend every inch of NATO territory.  That commitment, so-called Article 5 of the NATO Treaty, is sacrosanct for him and for the United States.  So no one should have any doubt about that, certainly not our allies and certainly not Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Putin expected NATO to withdraw its forces, to remove military installations from the territory of new members.  The result is the opposite, with more American troops.  But what may come in the future – would you be ready to send even more troops?</p>
<p>Well, we had already – before this aggression committed by Russia, we had about 5,000 American forces in Poland as part of the NATO mission.  It’s now double that.  We’ve sent another 5,000 from the 82nd Airborne Division who are here now.   And what’s so striking about what President Putin has done, over many years now, is he has precipitated everything he says he wants to prevent.  What’s happened in recent years as a result of Russian aggression starting back in 2014?  Ukraine, Ukrainian people have turned against Russia.  Whereas before 2014 there were favorable views in Ukraine of Russia, now 90 percent of the country honestly hate Russia and certainly hate Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p>At the same time, the NATO Alliance has come together as strongly as I’ve ever seen it, and the very forces of NATO that – a defensive alliance that has no aggressive intent against Russia, is here for our common defense.  That alliance has grown stronger, and it’s stronger closer to Russia as a result of Putin’s aggression.  So everything he’s done has been to create what he says he doesn’t want to see happen.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Vladimir Putin said today that Western sanctions on Russia are akin to declaration of war, which is a big lie, because even if Russian Central Bank lost billions of dollars &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>That’s right.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>&#8212; or some oligarchs lost your yachts and villas, it’s not a war.  War is killing Ukrainian kids.  What’s your assumption, sir?  Are these sanctions getting us closer to stop Putin?  Are they working?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>The sanctions are having a very, very powerful impact.  And I think the impact is, is far greater than most people would have imagined a month ago or six weeks ago.  That’s because so many countries are taking part and doing it together, and it’s because the sanctions themselves – going after the major financial institutions in Russia, denying Russia the technology it needs to modernize its most important industries, going directly at the oligarchs and their families – all of this is already having a big, powerful demonstrative effect.  The ruble has gone through the floor.  The ability of Russia to use the reserves that it’s built up to support its currency, we’ve taken that away by going right at the Central Bank of Russia.  In their daily lives – and it’s deeply unfortunate that the Russian people are suffering as a consequence, but this is what Putin has brought to them.</p>
<p>I have a list five pages long from yesterday – it’s probably longer even today – of all of the companies and businesses that have left Russia in the last week, the most important brands in the world that people know and – in their daily lives.  So the Russian people are feeling this in their bank accounts, in the value of the ruble.  They’re feeling this in the business that’s gone away.  And elites are feeling it and their inability to travel.  We’re now in the business for the oligarchs of seizing their yachts, their sports cars, their apartments.  So this is having a big impact already, and it will have an even bigger impact over time as Russia is unable to make the investments it wants in its future.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Mr. Secretary, one last question.  Millions of people are hoping and praying that the war would be over tonight.  But even if that’s the case, we all feel that the world has changed deeply, probably for a very long time.  What’s your assessment?  How much the world has changed since – in 10 days since the beginning of the invasion?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>I think you’re right, the world has changed, but it’s very possible that it ultimately changes in a positive way.  Here’s what I mean by that.  In the last couple of decades, democracies in one way or another, including our own, have in some ways moved backwards, or they’ve been on their heels, not on their toes.  What we’ve seen now is the most powerful response to an autocracy – Russia, under Putin, saying: oh, we’re going to do whatever we want, and we know democracies won’t respond.  We have responded; we are responding.  We’re standing with Ukraine; we’re standing against this aggression.  And it’s too early to say, because we have to see how this comes out, but this could be a positive inflection point where the world’s democracies say: there’s a line; enough is enough; we will act; we will come together.</p>
<p>And when we come together, when we’re united as we are at NATO, as we are with the European Union, as we are at the – even at the United Nations, 141 countries coming together and saying we condemn this aggression, we stand for Ukraine – that could be a moment of positive change, but only if we sustain this, if we see this through, if we make sure that Ukraine prevails, which I’m convinced it will because the Ukrainian people will insist on it, and that Russia does not succeed in what it’s doing.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Sir, thank you so much.  We really appreciate your time and thank you for this optimistic part – we all need it.  Thank you so much.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.  Great to be with you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rzeszow, Poland</p>
<p>Hotel Bristol</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Mr. Secretary, we really appreciate your presence.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>It’s a great honor for us.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>It’s very good to be with you tonight.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Mr. Secretary, you are one of more than 10,000 American citizens now in Poland. A lot of them are in this region – we are in Rzeszow now – most of them are soldiers.  We really, really appreciate your presence here, you and American soldiers.  You’ve had a lot of many different meetings today, including our prime minister, minister of foreign affairs.  Can you tell us about the results of these meetings?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, first, let me say this:  I am overwhelmed by the generosity of Poland and the Polish people.  I visited the welcome center for Ukrainians and others who are coming out of Ukraine because of the horrific aggression being committed by Vladimir Putin and Russia.  And to see the hospitality, to see the generosity of our Polish friends is very, very moving in and of itself.  And I think it speaks to a larger solidarity that exists and that we’re seeing between the United States and Poland, but also so much of the international community, in support of Ukraine and in opposition to a war of choice being committed by Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p>The strength of our own partnership, I think, has never been better, and that was very evident to me in the meetings that I had today with the prime minister, with my friend Zbigniew Rau – we’ve worked together very closely on a very regular basis.  And we’re united in this effort; that’s what’s so important.  That unity in support of Ukraine, in opposition to this aggression by Russia, is what will carry the day.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Half an hour ago, we’ve heard about your meeting with minister of foreign affairs of Ukraine, the Minister Kuleba.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Yes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>As far as I understand, you were in Ukraine – correct me if I&#8217;m wrong – you crossed the border.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>That’s correct.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>And can you tell us more about this conversation?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>First, Dmytro Kuleba is a remarkable colleague, a remarkable friend.  And he, like President Zelenskyy and others in the government, have been the face of the Ukrainian people in confronting this aggression.  But we’re on the phone regularly.  He’s somewhere in Ukraine.  I couldn’t say were for security reasons.  But I thought it was important when we met – symbolically – to cross the border and to have us stand together in Ukraine, because we’re standing together for Ukraine.  And we work very closely, and for me, it’s making sure that I understand as best possible what our Ukrainian friends and partners need, what we can do to continue to support them as well as to put the pressure on Russia.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Sir, in 1940, Churchill delivered his famous speech in British Parliament:  We’ll fight “in the streets,” “in the fields,” “on the landing grounds” until America, “with all its power and might,” would come to rescue us.  I would never imagine that they will say these words, but we have a war just next to us.  Would you be ready again to come with all your power and might to defend your European allies &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Yes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>&#8212; this time, including Poland in NATO?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Yes.  Yes, that’s the – it’s as simple as that. President Biden said this to the entire country.  He gave his State of the Union speech – this is the speech that a president gives where he talks to every American in their living rooms – just last week.  And what he said there – and he’s said repeatedly in recent weeks – is we will defend every inch of NATO territory.  That commitment, so-called Article 5 of the NATO Treaty, is sacrosanct for him and for the United States.  So no one should have any doubt about that, certainly not our allies and certainly not Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Putin expected NATO to withdraw its forces, to remove military installations from the territory of new members.  The result is the opposite, with more American troops.  But what may come in the future – would you be ready to send even more troops?</p>
<p>Well, we had already – before this aggression committed by Russia, we had about 5,000 American forces in Poland as part of the NATO mission.  It’s now double that.  We’ve sent another 5,000 from the 82nd Airborne Division who are here now.   And what’s so striking about what President Putin has done, over many years now, is he has precipitated everything he says he wants to prevent.  What’s happened in recent years as a result of Russian aggression starting back in 2014?  Ukraine, Ukrainian people have turned against Russia.  Whereas before 2014 there were favorable views in Ukraine of Russia, now 90 percent of the country honestly hate Russia and certainly hate Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p>At the same time, the NATO Alliance has come together as strongly as I’ve ever seen it, and the very forces of NATO that – a defensive alliance that has no aggressive intent against Russia, is here for our common defense.  That alliance has grown stronger, and it’s stronger closer to Russia as a result of Putin’s aggression.  So everything he’s done has been to create what he says he doesn’t want to see happen.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Vladimir Putin said today that Western sanctions on Russia are akin to declaration of war, which is a big lie, because even if Russian Central Bank lost billions of dollars &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>That’s right.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>&#8212; or some oligarchs lost your yachts and villas, it’s not a war.  War is killing Ukrainian kids.  What’s your assumption, sir?  Are these sanctions getting us closer to stop Putin?  Are they working?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>The sanctions are having a very, very powerful impact.  And I think the impact is, is far greater than most people would have imagined a month ago or six weeks ago.  That’s because so many countries are taking part and doing it together, and it’s because the sanctions themselves – going after the major financial institutions in Russia, denying Russia the technology it needs to modernize its most important industries, going directly at the oligarchs and their families – all of this is already having a big, powerful demonstrative effect.  The ruble has gone through the floor.  The ability of Russia to use the reserves that it’s built up to support its currency, we’ve taken that away by going right at the Central Bank of Russia.  In their daily lives – and it’s deeply unfortunate that the Russian people are suffering as a consequence, but this is what Putin has brought to them.</p>
<p>I have a list five pages long from yesterday – it’s probably longer even today – of all of the companies and businesses that have left Russia in the last week, the most important brands in the world that people know and – in their daily lives.  So the Russian people are feeling this in their bank accounts, in the value of the ruble.  They’re feeling this in the business that’s gone away.  And elites are feeling it and their inability to travel.  We’re now in the business for the oligarchs of seizing their yachts, their sports cars, their apartments.  So this is having a big impact already, and it will have an even bigger impact over time as Russia is unable to make the investments it wants in its future.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Mr. Secretary, one last question.  Millions of people are hoping and praying that the war would be over tonight.  But even if that’s the case, we all feel that the world has changed deeply, probably for a very long time.  What’s your assessment?  How much the world has changed since – in 10 days since the beginning of the invasion?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>I think you’re right, the world has changed, but it’s very possible that it ultimately changes in a positive way.  Here’s what I mean by that.  In the last couple of decades, democracies in one way or another, including our own, have in some ways moved backwards, or they’ve been on their heels, not on their toes.  What we’ve seen now is the most powerful response to an autocracy – Russia, under Putin, saying: oh, we’re going to do whatever we want, and we know democracies won’t respond.  We have responded; we are responding.  We’re standing with Ukraine; we’re standing against this aggression.  And it’s too early to say, because we have to see how this comes out, but this could be a positive inflection point where the world’s democracies say: there’s a line; enough is enough; we will act; we will come together.</p>
<p>And when we come together, when we’re united as we are at NATO, as we are with the European Union, as we are at the – even at the United Nations, 141 countries coming together and saying we condemn this aggression, we stand for Ukraine – that could be a moment of positive change, but only if we sustain this, if we see this through, if we make sure that Ukraine prevails, which I’m convinced it will because the Ukrainian people will insist on it, and that Russia does not succeed in what it’s doing.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Sir, thank you so much.  We really appreciate your time and thank you for this optimistic part – we all need it.  Thank you so much.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.  Great to be with you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meetings with Turkish Deputy Foreign Minister Onal</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meetings-with-turkish-deputy-foreign-minister-onal-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 21:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321115</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today in Ankara with Turkish Deputy Foreign Minister Sedat Onal to discuss Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine. Deputy Secretary Sherman thanked Turkey for its strong and vocal support in defense of Ukraine and expressed appreciation for the solidarity among partners and NATO Allies in confronting this crisis.  The Deputy Secretary also underscored the importance of the U.S. – Turkey Strategic Mechanism, which will deepen and expand the already robust cooperation between our two countries.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today in Ankara with Turkish Deputy Foreign Minister Sedat Onal to discuss Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine. Deputy Secretary Sherman thanked Turkey for its strong and vocal support in defense of Ukraine and expressed appreciation for the solidarity among partners and NATO Allies in confronting this crisis.  The Deputy Secretary also underscored the importance of the U.S. – Turkey Strategic Mechanism, which will deepen and expand the already robust cooperation between our two countries.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken At a Town Hall with Kyiv Embassy Personnel</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-town-hall-with-kyiv-embassy-personnel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 21:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rzeszow, Poland</p>
<p>Hotel Bristol</p>
<p><b>MS KVIEN:  </b>Well, it’s my great pleasure and honor to welcome Secretary Blinken to Embassy Kyiv-West here in Rzeszow, Poland.  What you have in front of you, Mr. Secretary, is about 50 folks who have been working night and day since we got here to help Ukrainians in need, to help American citizens in need to get out of Ukraine, to help bring assistance into Ukraine, and to help continue our work with the Ukrainian Government to make sure that we can do whatever we can to help them in their time of need.  So with that, I’ll just hand it over to you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.  Kristina, thank you very much.  And look, I really want to have a chance to hear from as many of you as possible, answer as many questions as I can in the time we have, and predictably, we’re running behind.  So I don&#8217;t want to talk at the beginning too much, except to say this:  I know that for virtually each and every one of you, this is not only professional – this is personal.  So many of you have deep ties, deep connections, deep feelings for Ukraine, for its people, for your friends that you’ve made, the professional relationships you’ve developed.</p>
<p>And I know how powerful that is, both as a driver but also, it’s a challenge, because I know what you’ve been through in the last weeks – shutting down in Kyiv, moving to Lviv, moving out of Lviv, back to Lviv, and out – and all the while determined to do everything that you can for our friends and partners in Ukraine.  And so again, I know this is this is deeply personal as well as professional.  And the professional part of the could not be more important, because you all know better than anyone what’s at stake in this effort.</p>
<p>What’s at stake is, of course, first and foremost, the lives, the wellbeing, the future of so many Ukrainians.  And for all the numbers we throw around, each and every one of those numbers has a real person behind it.  And that’s something I know you know better than anyone because you know the people, but it’s also big because the very principles that are at the heart of the international system, as challenged as it is, that are really important to try and keep peace and security – that we established after two world wars to try to make sure it never happened again – those principles are being assaulted by Vladimir Putin, along with the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p>And so our determination to make sure this doesn’t go with impunity is about Ukraine, and honestly, it’s about the whole world.  The part you’re playing in this town is vitally important, because you’re so much a part of the connectivity that we have with Ukraine and with Ukrainians, even from Embassy West here.  And I’m so grateful to all of you for doing this, not just doing it but, as Kristina said – and Kristina, thank you for your extraordinary leadership in this time – doing it with such determination, such passion, and such heart.</p>
<p>But with that, let me stop and let our friends from the press maybe get a espresso somewhere, and &#8212;</p>
<p><b>STAFF:  </b>All right, thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rzeszow, Poland</p>
<p>Hotel Bristol</p>
<p><b>MS KVIEN:  </b>Well, it’s my great pleasure and honor to welcome Secretary Blinken to Embassy Kyiv-West here in Rzeszow, Poland.  What you have in front of you, Mr. Secretary, is about 50 folks who have been working night and day since we got here to help Ukrainians in need, to help American citizens in need to get out of Ukraine, to help bring assistance into Ukraine, and to help continue our work with the Ukrainian Government to make sure that we can do whatever we can to help them in their time of need.  So with that, I’ll just hand it over to you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.  Kristina, thank you very much.  And look, I really want to have a chance to hear from as many of you as possible, answer as many questions as I can in the time we have, and predictably, we’re running behind.  So I don&#8217;t want to talk at the beginning too much, except to say this:  I know that for virtually each and every one of you, this is not only professional – this is personal.  So many of you have deep ties, deep connections, deep feelings for Ukraine, for its people, for your friends that you’ve made, the professional relationships you’ve developed.</p>
<p>And I know how powerful that is, both as a driver but also, it’s a challenge, because I know what you’ve been through in the last weeks – shutting down in Kyiv, moving to Lviv, moving out of Lviv, back to Lviv, and out – and all the while determined to do everything that you can for our friends and partners in Ukraine.  And so again, I know this is this is deeply personal as well as professional.  And the professional part of the could not be more important, because you all know better than anyone what’s at stake in this effort.</p>
<p>What’s at stake is, of course, first and foremost, the lives, the wellbeing, the future of so many Ukrainians.  And for all the numbers we throw around, each and every one of those numbers has a real person behind it.  And that’s something I know you know better than anyone because you know the people, but it’s also big because the very principles that are at the heart of the international system, as challenged as it is, that are really important to try and keep peace and security – that we established after two world wars to try to make sure it never happened again – those principles are being assaulted by Vladimir Putin, along with the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p>And so our determination to make sure this doesn’t go with impunity is about Ukraine, and honestly, it’s about the whole world.  The part you’re playing in this town is vitally important, because you’re so much a part of the connectivity that we have with Ukraine and with Ukrainians, even from Embassy West here.  And I’m so grateful to all of you for doing this, not just doing it but, as Kristina said – and Kristina, thank you for your extraordinary leadership in this time – doing it with such determination, such passion, and such heart.</p>
<p>But with that, let me stop and let our friends from the press maybe get a espresso somewhere, and &#8212;</p>
<p><b>STAFF:  </b>All right, thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken At a Meeting with Congressional Delegation</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-meeting-with-congressional-delegation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 20:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321102</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rzeszow, Poland</p>
<p>Hotel Bristol</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, greetings, everyone.  I’m particularly pleased to be here with friends and colleagues from the Congress.  This is, as always, very powerful to see a bipartisan group of leaders from Congress standing together, coming together in support of Ukraine, and standing strongly against Vladimir Putin’s war of choice and aggression that is not only – is first and foremost affecting the people of Ukraine, but poses a threat to the basic principles of the international order that all of us stand strongly for.  And we – I think we’re determined – as Republicans, as Democrats, as Americans – not to let this go with impunity.</p>
<p>So I think the fact that our colleagues are here with this strong show of support from the United States here in this moment at this time is a very powerful thing, and it’s just wonderful to be with you.</p>
<p><b>CHAIRMAN MEEKS:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>STAFF:  </b>All right, thanks, guys.</p>
<p><b>CHAIRMAN MEEKS:  </b>As you said, bipartisan group – many more members of Congress wanted to come.  We completely filled our plane, because we wanted to make sure that – number one, we wanted to say thank you to the Polish people.  The humanitarian concerns that they have had wreaked on them – now they’re able to help someone else.  And I thought, we all thought that it was extremely important for members of the Congress, in a bipartisan way, to come to say thank you and that we know – for those that had to leave their homes in Ukraine because of one man who decided that he’s going to make and commit war crimes, killing innocent men, women and children – that we wanted to also let them know that the United States has their back.  And we’re going to stay together.</p>
<p>So we’re definitely going to make sure that the – our NATO Ally here in Poland, we have your back.  We’re not going to leave you alone, and it’s a message united.  Mike McCaul is the ranking member – I’m the chair of the House Foreign Affairs Committee; he’s the ranking member.  Mike, why don’t you say something?</p>
<p><b>RANKING MEMBER MCCAUL:  </b>Well, (inaudible) we’re not here as Republicans or Democrats, but really as Americans supporting our NATO Ally, Poland, and the people of Ukraine.  We stand with you.  We just had a video conference with President Zelenskyy, one of the most courageous individuals I’ve ever seen.  Very inspiring.  And the chairman’s right:  Mr. Putin is a war criminal, he’s going to lose in the end, and we want to work with you and the administration to bring this to a – bring him to justice and stop the bloodshed.  And again, I just want to thank Poland and the people of Ukraine.  We are with you, and we will do everything we can to stop this.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rzeszow, Poland</p>
<p>Hotel Bristol</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, greetings, everyone.  I’m particularly pleased to be here with friends and colleagues from the Congress.  This is, as always, very powerful to see a bipartisan group of leaders from Congress standing together, coming together in support of Ukraine, and standing strongly against Vladimir Putin’s war of choice and aggression that is not only – is first and foremost affecting the people of Ukraine, but poses a threat to the basic principles of the international order that all of us stand strongly for.  And we – I think we’re determined – as Republicans, as Democrats, as Americans – not to let this go with impunity.</p>
<p>So I think the fact that our colleagues are here with this strong show of support from the United States here in this moment at this time is a very powerful thing, and it’s just wonderful to be with you.</p>
<p><b>CHAIRMAN MEEKS:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>STAFF:  </b>All right, thanks, guys.</p>
<p><b>CHAIRMAN MEEKS:  </b>As you said, bipartisan group – many more members of Congress wanted to come.  We completely filled our plane, because we wanted to make sure that – number one, we wanted to say thank you to the Polish people.  The humanitarian concerns that they have had wreaked on them – now they’re able to help someone else.  And I thought, we all thought that it was extremely important for members of the Congress, in a bipartisan way, to come to say thank you and that we know – for those that had to leave their homes in Ukraine because of one man who decided that he’s going to make and commit war crimes, killing innocent men, women and children – that we wanted to also let them know that the United States has their back.  And we’re going to stay together.</p>
<p>So we’re definitely going to make sure that the – our NATO Ally here in Poland, we have your back.  We’re not going to leave you alone, and it’s a message united.  Mike McCaul is the ranking member – I’m the chair of the House Foreign Affairs Committee; he’s the ranking member.  Mike, why don’t you say something?</p>
<p><b>RANKING MEMBER MCCAUL:  </b>Well, (inaudible) we’re not here as Republicans or Democrats, but really as Americans supporting our NATO Ally, Poland, and the people of Ukraine.  We stand with you.  We just had a video conference with President Zelenskyy, one of the most courageous individuals I’ve ever seen.  Very inspiring.  And the chairman’s right:  Mr. Putin is a war criminal, he’s going to lose in the end, and we want to work with you and the administration to bring this to a – bring him to justice and stop the bloodshed.  And again, I just want to thank Poland and the people of Ukraine.  We are with you, and we will do everything we can to stop this.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken At a Meeting with Ukrainian Civil Society</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-meeting-with-ukrainian-civil-society/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 19:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321091</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rzeszow, Poland</p>
<p>Hotel Bristol</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Good evening.  It’s wonderful to be able to see all of you, except I wish it was not here – I wish it was actually in Kyiv or somewhere else in Ukraine.  I’m first of all very sorry that – I know some of you have had very challenging journeys just to get here, but I&#8217;m grateful to see each of you.  I know from so much of the work that that you’ve been doing that over these years, you’ve been building civil society, building democracy in Ukraine.</p>
<p>And of course, one of the things that Vladimir Putin is trying to tear apart is the very work that you’ve been doing.  I think that that’s, in a sense, not a coincidence, because to the extent Ukraine is a successful and strong democracy with a strong civil society at its core, it stands in very stark juxtaposition to the society and system that President Putin has constructed in Russia.</p>
<p>And so in a sense, Ukraine’s success – the very success that you’ve been building – is a threat to everything President Putin is trying to do in Russia.  But I was just anxious to have a chance to hear from a few of you about the work you’ve been doing, the progress that that you’ve made in these years, and what we can do and how we can help to – even in these very, very difficult circumstances – continue the work you’re doing.</p>
<p>But in any event, welcome, and it’s good to see each of you here.  Kristina, is there anything you wanted to say at the top?</p>
<p><b>MS KVIEN:  </b>No, other than we’re very glad to have you here.  And these are partners that we work with closely on anti-corruption, but I think now they have moved into other areas.  And I think they’ll be happy to describe to you what they do now.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Wonderful.</p>
<p align="left">
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rzeszow, Poland</p>
<p>Hotel Bristol</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Good evening.  It’s wonderful to be able to see all of you, except I wish it was not here – I wish it was actually in Kyiv or somewhere else in Ukraine.  I’m first of all very sorry that – I know some of you have had very challenging journeys just to get here, but I&#8217;m grateful to see each of you.  I know from so much of the work that that you’ve been doing that over these years, you’ve been building civil society, building democracy in Ukraine.</p>
<p>And of course, one of the things that Vladimir Putin is trying to tear apart is the very work that you’ve been doing.  I think that that’s, in a sense, not a coincidence, because to the extent Ukraine is a successful and strong democracy with a strong civil society at its core, it stands in very stark juxtaposition to the society and system that President Putin has constructed in Russia.</p>
<p>And so in a sense, Ukraine’s success – the very success that you’ve been building – is a threat to everything President Putin is trying to do in Russia.  But I was just anxious to have a chance to hear from a few of you about the work you’ve been doing, the progress that that you’ve made in these years, and what we can do and how we can help to – even in these very, very difficult circumstances – continue the work you’re doing.</p>
<p>But in any event, welcome, and it’s good to see each of you here.  Kristina, is there anything you wanted to say at the top?</p>
<p><b>MS KVIEN:  </b>No, other than we’re very glad to have you here.  And these are partners that we work with closely on anti-corruption, but I think now they have moved into other areas.  And I think they’ll be happy to describe to you what they do now.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Wonderful.</p>
<p align="left">
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken  And Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba  At a Joint Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-ukrainian-foreign-minister-dmytro-kuleba-at-a-joint-press-availability-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 19:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321084</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Poland-Ukraine Border</p>
<p align="left"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Good afternoon, everyone.  The entire world stands with Ukraine, just as I am standing here in Ukraine with my friend, my colleague, Dmytro Kuleba, the foreign minister of Ukraine.  We’ve seen an extraordinary surgence of support from around the world against Russia’s aggression – against Russia’s war of choice, against what is happening every single day, every single minute in Ukraine to civilians throughout the country as a result of this aggression – but also extraordinary support for Ukraine itself.</p>
<p>We’ve come from several days of meetings with NATO, the European Union, countries beyond the G7, and we see that support not only continue – security support, humanitarian support, economic support – but that support will increase.  And as to the pressure on Russia, not only is it unprecedented, not only is it producing very, very concrete results in Russia, but that pressure too will not only continue – it will grow until this war, this war of choice, is brought to an end.</p>
<p>I have to say that I’m in awe of my friend, his entire government, President Zelenskyy.  The courage that they are showing every day, the leadership that they are showing to the world, it’s inspiring.  And the world is here; the world is with you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER KULEBA:  </b>Thank you.  Well, first of all, I would like to thank Tony for coming here to Ukraine – literally – we just crossed the line and we are standing here.  I hope the people of Ukraine will be able to see this as a clear manifestation that we have friends who literally stayed – stand by us.  Thank you for your leadership in consolidating international community in support of Ukraine.  We had meaningful discussions about weapons, about sanctions, about isolation of Russia on the international arena.</p>
<p>And the message that I have to convey, that I would like to convey now, is very simple.  Ukraine will win this war anyway, because this is the people’s war for their land, and we defend the right cause.  The question is the price, the price of our victory.  And if our partners continue to take bold, systemic decisions to step up economic and political pressure on Ukraine, if they continue to provide us with necessary weapons, the price will be lower.  This will save many lives in Ukraine, many houses.  Many children will be born.  Many sufferings will be avoided.  This is the only question that is on the agenda.  If anyone in the world one day starts feeling the sanctions fatigue, for example, then people – more people in Ukraine will be dying, suffering, and more destruction will be brought on us by Russian airplanes and by Russian weapons.</p>
<p>So we appreciate everything that has been done in the last week – unprecedented, swift reaction to the Russian aggression.  But it has to be continued, the pressure has to be stepped up, and Ukraine has to be provided with all weapons necessary to fight in this, as Tony said, war of choice of President Putin.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Minister, what kind of weapons do you need from the U.S. that you aren’t getting?</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER KULEBA:  </b>Well, we are satisfied with the already-arranged supplies of anti-tank weapons and ammunition – this is one of the most badly needed – and we destroy a lot of Russian tanks and armored vehicles using weapons that came from our friends, including the United States.  It’s no secret that the highest demand that we have is in fighting jets, attack aircrafts, and air defense systems. We thank all those countries, including the United States, who provided us the – with Stingers.  We effectively use them, and just today we shot down three Russian attack aircrafts, which were bombing our cities, with the use of Stingers.  But we need to, how to say, big air defense systems to ensure the safety of our skies.  If we lose the skies, there will be much, much more blood on the ground, and that will be the blood of civilians.  And I don’t want anyone to share responsibility for their blood, anyone in the world to share responsibility for their deaths and suffering.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Mr. Minister &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Sir, are you still calling for a no-fly zone?</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER KULEBA:  </b>Yes, yes, and we will continue to call.  I understand – I hear the messages.  I heard was the NATO secretary general said yesterday after the meeting of the Allies.  I regret – I think it’s a sign of weakness by – of NATO.  We’ve been saying many things for the last eight years about Russia, about intentions.  We were never heard.  Everyone was saying you’re – many were saying: you’re exaggerating; this is not going to happen.  People were – then at certain points, some countries were saying: no, we can never supply you with weapons.  But in the last eight days, the world politics were shattered by the Russian aggression against Ukraine, and those countries who had never supplied us with weapons are now doing so.</p>
<p>So I’m used to it.  We are now in the phase where NATO is saying: no, we’re going to not – we are not going to do that.  The time will come.  It’s, again, the issue of price.  We do not – it’s Ukrainians, it’s the people of Ukraine who pay the price for the reluctance of NATO to act.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Mr. Minister, could you tell us how the talks with the Russians are going, how any kind of negotiations are going?  And also, when you talk about the cost, even at what point that the fighting ends, what kind of country will the – Ukrainians go back to?  What will it look like?</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER KULEBA:  </b>Ukrainians will go back to the country to some – to a large extent destroyed by Russian bombers and artillery and rockets.  But then we will roll our sleeves up and we will build an even more beautiful country.  We are all committed to that and we will all take part in that.</p>
<p>When it comes to the talks with Russians, I cannot say that there is any progress in it.  We all hope that the humanitarian corridors, which were agreed upon during the last talks, would work.  Unfortunately, at least as we speak, they – these humanitarian corridors are not available because of the Russian fire and shellings.  But every war ends with diplomacy and with talks, so we have to continue talking, but we are not going to these talks to accept Russian ultimatums.  Again, trust me, thousands of people in Ukraine sacrifice their lives – men, women, old, young – to defend the country.  When we prevail – and I have no doubt in that – we will build a new Ukraine, and that country will be even better than the one that Russia destroyed.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b>Thank you all very much</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>(Off-mike.)</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Secretary Blinken, (inaudible) &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>He asked for fighter and attack aircraft.  Would you help your friend and partner, the Minister Kuleba, with fighter and attack aircraft?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>We are talking about and working on everything.  We’re doing that; Secretary of Defense Austin and his counterpart Mr. Reznikov are doing that.  We are, again, looking at everything, and as I said before, the support for Ukraine not only has been unprecedented, not only is it going to continue – it’s going to increase.  And what we’ve seen, I think, as Dmytro said, is a sea change, and a sea change that’s being shown around the world in terms of its support.  There’s a very, very strong tide in support of Ukraine and against the horrific aggression committed by Russia.</p>
<p>Putin has made a terrible, terrible, terrible mistake in many ways, but it starts with the proposition that somehow Ukraine doesn’t exist as an independent country.  What Ukrainians are showing every single day is, of course, exactly the opposite.  And ultimately, their strength, their resolve, their determination, backed by the United States and backed by the world, is going to prevail.  It’s as simple and straightforward as that.  But Dmytro’s right: at what price?  We want to do everything we can to make sure that that price is as low as possible and that this happens as quickly as possible, but we’re in it with Ukraine one way or another.  The short-run, the medium-run, the long-run. We’re in this together. We will succeed together. Ukraine is going to prevail.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b>Thank you all very much.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Poland-Ukraine Border</p>
<p align="left"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Good afternoon, everyone.  The entire world stands with Ukraine, just as I am standing here in Ukraine with my friend, my colleague, Dmytro Kuleba, the foreign minister of Ukraine.  We’ve seen an extraordinary surgence of support from around the world against Russia’s aggression – against Russia’s war of choice, against what is happening every single day, every single minute in Ukraine to civilians throughout the country as a result of this aggression – but also extraordinary support for Ukraine itself.</p>
<p>We’ve come from several days of meetings with NATO, the European Union, countries beyond the G7, and we see that support not only continue – security support, humanitarian support, economic support – but that support will increase.  And as to the pressure on Russia, not only is it unprecedented, not only is it producing very, very concrete results in Russia, but that pressure too will not only continue – it will grow until this war, this war of choice, is brought to an end.</p>
<p>I have to say that I’m in awe of my friend, his entire government, President Zelenskyy.  The courage that they are showing every day, the leadership that they are showing to the world, it’s inspiring.  And the world is here; the world is with you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER KULEBA:  </b>Thank you.  Well, first of all, I would like to thank Tony for coming here to Ukraine – literally – we just crossed the line and we are standing here.  I hope the people of Ukraine will be able to see this as a clear manifestation that we have friends who literally stayed – stand by us.  Thank you for your leadership in consolidating international community in support of Ukraine.  We had meaningful discussions about weapons, about sanctions, about isolation of Russia on the international arena.</p>
<p>And the message that I have to convey, that I would like to convey now, is very simple.  Ukraine will win this war anyway, because this is the people’s war for their land, and we defend the right cause.  The question is the price, the price of our victory.  And if our partners continue to take bold, systemic decisions to step up economic and political pressure on Ukraine, if they continue to provide us with necessary weapons, the price will be lower.  This will save many lives in Ukraine, many houses.  Many children will be born.  Many sufferings will be avoided.  This is the only question that is on the agenda.  If anyone in the world one day starts feeling the sanctions fatigue, for example, then people – more people in Ukraine will be dying, suffering, and more destruction will be brought on us by Russian airplanes and by Russian weapons.</p>
<p>So we appreciate everything that has been done in the last week – unprecedented, swift reaction to the Russian aggression.  But it has to be continued, the pressure has to be stepped up, and Ukraine has to be provided with all weapons necessary to fight in this, as Tony said, war of choice of President Putin.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Minister, what kind of weapons do you need from the U.S. that you aren’t getting?</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER KULEBA:  </b>Well, we are satisfied with the already-arranged supplies of anti-tank weapons and ammunition – this is one of the most badly needed – and we destroy a lot of Russian tanks and armored vehicles using weapons that came from our friends, including the United States.  It’s no secret that the highest demand that we have is in fighting jets, attack aircrafts, and air defense systems. We thank all those countries, including the United States, who provided us the – with Stingers.  We effectively use them, and just today we shot down three Russian attack aircrafts, which were bombing our cities, with the use of Stingers.  But we need to, how to say, big air defense systems to ensure the safety of our skies.  If we lose the skies, there will be much, much more blood on the ground, and that will be the blood of civilians.  And I don’t want anyone to share responsibility for their blood, anyone in the world to share responsibility for their deaths and suffering.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Mr. Minister &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Sir, are you still calling for a no-fly zone?</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER KULEBA:  </b>Yes, yes, and we will continue to call.  I understand – I hear the messages.  I heard was the NATO secretary general said yesterday after the meeting of the Allies.  I regret – I think it’s a sign of weakness by – of NATO.  We’ve been saying many things for the last eight years about Russia, about intentions.  We were never heard.  Everyone was saying you’re – many were saying: you’re exaggerating; this is not going to happen.  People were – then at certain points, some countries were saying: no, we can never supply you with weapons.  But in the last eight days, the world politics were shattered by the Russian aggression against Ukraine, and those countries who had never supplied us with weapons are now doing so.</p>
<p>So I’m used to it.  We are now in the phase where NATO is saying: no, we’re going to not – we are not going to do that.  The time will come.  It’s, again, the issue of price.  We do not – it’s Ukrainians, it’s the people of Ukraine who pay the price for the reluctance of NATO to act.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Mr. Minister, could you tell us how the talks with the Russians are going, how any kind of negotiations are going?  And also, when you talk about the cost, even at what point that the fighting ends, what kind of country will the – Ukrainians go back to?  What will it look like?</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER KULEBA:  </b>Ukrainians will go back to the country to some – to a large extent destroyed by Russian bombers and artillery and rockets.  But then we will roll our sleeves up and we will build an even more beautiful country.  We are all committed to that and we will all take part in that.</p>
<p>When it comes to the talks with Russians, I cannot say that there is any progress in it.  We all hope that the humanitarian corridors, which were agreed upon during the last talks, would work.  Unfortunately, at least as we speak, they – these humanitarian corridors are not available because of the Russian fire and shellings.  But every war ends with diplomacy and with talks, so we have to continue talking, but we are not going to these talks to accept Russian ultimatums.  Again, trust me, thousands of people in Ukraine sacrifice their lives – men, women, old, young – to defend the country.  When we prevail – and I have no doubt in that – we will build a new Ukraine, and that country will be even better than the one that Russia destroyed.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b>Thank you all very much</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>(Off-mike.)</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Secretary Blinken, (inaudible) &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>He asked for fighter and attack aircraft.  Would you help your friend and partner, the Minister Kuleba, with fighter and attack aircraft?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>We are talking about and working on everything.  We’re doing that; Secretary of Defense Austin and his counterpart Mr. Reznikov are doing that.  We are, again, looking at everything, and as I said before, the support for Ukraine not only has been unprecedented, not only is it going to continue – it’s going to increase.  And what we’ve seen, I think, as Dmytro said, is a sea change, and a sea change that’s being shown around the world in terms of its support.  There’s a very, very strong tide in support of Ukraine and against the horrific aggression committed by Russia.</p>
<p>Putin has made a terrible, terrible, terrible mistake in many ways, but it starts with the proposition that somehow Ukraine doesn’t exist as an independent country.  What Ukrainians are showing every single day is, of course, exactly the opposite.  And ultimately, their strength, their resolve, their determination, backed by the United States and backed by the world, is going to prevail.  It’s as simple and straightforward as that.  But Dmytro’s right: at what price?  We want to do everything we can to make sure that that price is as low as possible and that this happens as quickly as possible, but we’re in it with Ukraine one way or another.  The short-run, the medium-run, the long-run. We’re in this together. We will succeed together. Ukraine is going to prevail.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b>Thank you all very much.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Polish Foreign Minister Zbigniew Rau Statements to the Press</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-polish-foreign-minister-zbigniew-rau-statements-to-the-press/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 15:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321069</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rzeszow, Poland</p>
<p>Bristol Hotel</p>
<p align="left"><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Ladies and gentlemen, time for statements, and – for information, there won’t be any questions after the statements because of limited time.  Minister Rau, floor is yours.<b></b></p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER RAU:</b>  Thank you.  Ladies and gentlemen, we meeting – our meeting with Secretary, State Secretary Blinken, was devoted to coordinating actions in response to the Russian aggression against Ukraine, as well as political, economic, social, and humanitarian consequences of Russia’s war on our neighboring countries.  In the discussion with Secretary Blinken, we raised the most important issues arising from the ongoing conflict between Russia and Ukraine, Poland’s two eastern neighbors, both for Polish-American bilateral relations and for Allied cooperation between NATO, as well as for the coordination of political activities in the OSCE.<b></b></p>
<p>Poland will never recognize territorial changes brought about by unprovoked, unlawful aggression.  The way in which Russia conducts hostilities, based on the desire to break the will of Ukrainian resistance by means of attacks that terrorize civilian population – shelling residential areas, nuclear power plants, and non-military venues – are war crimes under international law which are not subjected to statute of limitation and will be prosecuted with utmost determination.<b></b></p>
<p>I call on Russia to refrain from attacks on civilian populations.  I call both parties to abide by international humanitarian law and to treat prisoners of war with dignity.  Turning over all war criminals must be considered in future peace negotiations.<b></b></p>
<p>Due to its own painful experience in the past, Poland will consequently demand prosecuting war criminals.  This is our historic debt to inhabitants of Guernica and (inaudible), whose sacrifices can never be forgotten.  Pursuing war criminals is an element of humankind’s common memory.  It’s our common obligation.  To achieve this, Poland (inaudible) center for documentation of war crimes in Ukraine.  We discussed possibilities for Polish-American cooperation in this area.</p>
<p>I call for an end of the bloodshed and ceasefire for the duration of the talks between Ukraine and Russia.  In my capacity as OSCE chairman in office, I welcomed understanding for recreation of humanitarian corridors that will facilitate the evacuation of civilians from Ukrainian cities under siege.  Along with the majority of OSCE countries, I appealed for this from the outset of the conflict.  I view this understanding as a ray of hope to prevent more Ukrainian civilians from falling victim to war.  Everything possible must be done to ensure they evacuate.</p>
<p>Russia’s aggression in Ukraine caused a humanitarian crisis of an unimaginable scale.  Our priority is organizing effective aid to hundreds of thousands and soon be millions of refugees.  Poland already received up to 700,000 refugees, and we will continue to do so for everyone that needs it, regardless of a nationality, race, (inaudible) religious creed.</p>
<p>The attack on Ukraine already transformed Europe and its sense of security.  Poland decided to immediately increase its defense spending budget to 3 percent of its GDP beginning next year.  As a key country for deterring and defending NATO’s eastern flank, Poland’s (inaudible) welcomed the Alliance’s swift reaction to the new strategic circumstances.  I’ve conveyed to Secretary Blinken my thanks to President Biden for his effective leadership in coordinating an explicit, united, and effective response from the transatlantic community and (inaudible) to Russia’s aggression.</p>
<p>As a host country for NATO response force on the eastern flank, Poland plays a critical role in this reaction, and we are determined to abide by it.  In line with the charter of the United Nations, Poland will provide all possible support to Ukraine, who is currently defending itself from an unlawful (inaudible) unprovoked aggression.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Secretary Blinken.<b></b></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.  Zbigniew, I want to thank you as always for the very good exchange, for the very warm welcome.  And we were just at NATO together, we were in Washington together just a few weeks ago, and it’s very good to to be here with you.</p>
<p>I’m also especially pleased that Ambassador Brzezinski is now here in Poland, credentialed last month.  The timing could not be better.  It’s vital that we have all of our confirmed ambassadors in place at this critical time.</p>
<p>And we are, in fact, meeting at one of the most urgent moments in the long history of friendship between our countries.</p>
<p>As Allies and partners, Poland and the United States have stood together through many, many challenges.  Now the very ideals that bind us – freedom, democracy, peace, security – are under threat in this region as never before, certainly not since the Second World War.</p>
<p>The people of Poland know how important it is to defend freedom.  So do Americans.  And we will stand together, as we’ve been standing together, in support of Ukraine and against Russia’s unprovoked, unwarranted, premeditated invasion.</p>
<p>In NATO, the European Union, the OSCE – where Zbigniew is the chair in office this year – Poland is doing vital work to respond to this crisis.  It’s hosted an increased NATO presence.  It supported the robust EU sanctions against Russia.  And it has done a great deal to facilitate security assistance to Ukraine.</p>
<p>As NATO Allies, defense cooperation between Poland and the United States, I think it’s safe to say, is closer than it’s ever been.  Since January 30th, the United States has more than doubled the number of our military personnel deployed in Poland to now more than 10,000, including a brigade of the 82nd Airborne Division.  And we’ve significantly increased the amount and types of military equipment and capabilities that we’ve positioned in Poland. As President Biden has said, we will defend every inch of NATO territory.</p>
<p>Poland is also a leading responder to the humanitarian crisis that Russia’s invasion of Ukraine has sparked.  As Zbigniew just said, as of today, more than 700,000 people have been forced to flee the violence perpetrated by Russia by crossing the border from Ukraine to Poland, with more coming every single day.  I’m going to have the opportunity to speak to some of the folks who’ve come over just recently from Ukraine, but I have to say it’s an incredibly powerful reflection of Poland’s values that vulnerable people know that here, they will find refuge.</p>
<p>To help support the needs of Ukrainians in Poland and other countries, the Biden administration just requested of Congress 2.5 – excuse me, $2.75 billion in humanitarian assistance.  That’s both to meet the need of vulnerable people and communities inside Ukraine as well as to support refugee services, including here in Poland.  That’s in addition to the more than $54 million in humanitarian assistance to Ukraine that we announced just last week</p>
<p>We also sent a Disaster Assistance Response Team to Poland, working very closely with humanitarian agencies to provide the critical health care, safe drinking water, sanitation, hygiene supplies, protection for vulnerable people, especially women and children.</p>
<p>We’ve delivered nearly 20,000 thermal blankets suited for cold climates; we’ve provided funding for emergency supplies to sustain health care for up to 100,000 people for three months and up to 500 emergency surgical procedures.</p>
<p>Embassy Kyiv has temporarily relocated to Poland as well, and I’m grateful for that, that Poland is hosting them.  They and our embassies and consulates in Poland and across the region are working hard to assist American citizens and their families departing Ukraine and to help them with the influx of U.S. military personnel, humanitarian workers, as well as assistance.  We established a U.S. Welcome Center close to the Ukrainian border.  It’s been operating 24/7 since hostilities began.  We have support teams as well stationed near the border in Romania, Hungary, Slovakia, and Moldova, to assist any Americans who are leaving Ukraine.</p>
<p>At this moment of crisis for millions of Ukrainians – and as the security of Europe hangs in the balance – Poland has stepped forward with generosity, with leadership, with resolve.  We’re grateful for the strong foundation of friendship and cooperation that we’ve built together over many, many decades, which so many are now relying on today.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rzeszow, Poland</p>
<p>Bristol Hotel</p>
<p align="left"><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Ladies and gentlemen, time for statements, and – for information, there won’t be any questions after the statements because of limited time.  Minister Rau, floor is yours.<b></b></p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER RAU:</b>  Thank you.  Ladies and gentlemen, we meeting – our meeting with Secretary, State Secretary Blinken, was devoted to coordinating actions in response to the Russian aggression against Ukraine, as well as political, economic, social, and humanitarian consequences of Russia’s war on our neighboring countries.  In the discussion with Secretary Blinken, we raised the most important issues arising from the ongoing conflict between Russia and Ukraine, Poland’s two eastern neighbors, both for Polish-American bilateral relations and for Allied cooperation between NATO, as well as for the coordination of political activities in the OSCE.<b></b></p>
<p>Poland will never recognize territorial changes brought about by unprovoked, unlawful aggression.  The way in which Russia conducts hostilities, based on the desire to break the will of Ukrainian resistance by means of attacks that terrorize civilian population – shelling residential areas, nuclear power plants, and non-military venues – are war crimes under international law which are not subjected to statute of limitation and will be prosecuted with utmost determination.<b></b></p>
<p>I call on Russia to refrain from attacks on civilian populations.  I call both parties to abide by international humanitarian law and to treat prisoners of war with dignity.  Turning over all war criminals must be considered in future peace negotiations.<b></b></p>
<p>Due to its own painful experience in the past, Poland will consequently demand prosecuting war criminals.  This is our historic debt to inhabitants of Guernica and (inaudible), whose sacrifices can never be forgotten.  Pursuing war criminals is an element of humankind’s common memory.  It’s our common obligation.  To achieve this, Poland (inaudible) center for documentation of war crimes in Ukraine.  We discussed possibilities for Polish-American cooperation in this area.</p>
<p>I call for an end of the bloodshed and ceasefire for the duration of the talks between Ukraine and Russia.  In my capacity as OSCE chairman in office, I welcomed understanding for recreation of humanitarian corridors that will facilitate the evacuation of civilians from Ukrainian cities under siege.  Along with the majority of OSCE countries, I appealed for this from the outset of the conflict.  I view this understanding as a ray of hope to prevent more Ukrainian civilians from falling victim to war.  Everything possible must be done to ensure they evacuate.</p>
<p>Russia’s aggression in Ukraine caused a humanitarian crisis of an unimaginable scale.  Our priority is organizing effective aid to hundreds of thousands and soon be millions of refugees.  Poland already received up to 700,000 refugees, and we will continue to do so for everyone that needs it, regardless of a nationality, race, (inaudible) religious creed.</p>
<p>The attack on Ukraine already transformed Europe and its sense of security.  Poland decided to immediately increase its defense spending budget to 3 percent of its GDP beginning next year.  As a key country for deterring and defending NATO’s eastern flank, Poland’s (inaudible) welcomed the Alliance’s swift reaction to the new strategic circumstances.  I’ve conveyed to Secretary Blinken my thanks to President Biden for his effective leadership in coordinating an explicit, united, and effective response from the transatlantic community and (inaudible) to Russia’s aggression.</p>
<p>As a host country for NATO response force on the eastern flank, Poland plays a critical role in this reaction, and we are determined to abide by it.  In line with the charter of the United Nations, Poland will provide all possible support to Ukraine, who is currently defending itself from an unlawful (inaudible) unprovoked aggression.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Secretary Blinken.<b></b></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.  Zbigniew, I want to thank you as always for the very good exchange, for the very warm welcome.  And we were just at NATO together, we were in Washington together just a few weeks ago, and it’s very good to to be here with you.</p>
<p>I’m also especially pleased that Ambassador Brzezinski is now here in Poland, credentialed last month.  The timing could not be better.  It’s vital that we have all of our confirmed ambassadors in place at this critical time.</p>
<p>And we are, in fact, meeting at one of the most urgent moments in the long history of friendship between our countries.</p>
<p>As Allies and partners, Poland and the United States have stood together through many, many challenges.  Now the very ideals that bind us – freedom, democracy, peace, security – are under threat in this region as never before, certainly not since the Second World War.</p>
<p>The people of Poland know how important it is to defend freedom.  So do Americans.  And we will stand together, as we’ve been standing together, in support of Ukraine and against Russia’s unprovoked, unwarranted, premeditated invasion.</p>
<p>In NATO, the European Union, the OSCE – where Zbigniew is the chair in office this year – Poland is doing vital work to respond to this crisis.  It’s hosted an increased NATO presence.  It supported the robust EU sanctions against Russia.  And it has done a great deal to facilitate security assistance to Ukraine.</p>
<p>As NATO Allies, defense cooperation between Poland and the United States, I think it’s safe to say, is closer than it’s ever been.  Since January 30th, the United States has more than doubled the number of our military personnel deployed in Poland to now more than 10,000, including a brigade of the 82nd Airborne Division.  And we’ve significantly increased the amount and types of military equipment and capabilities that we’ve positioned in Poland. As President Biden has said, we will defend every inch of NATO territory.</p>
<p>Poland is also a leading responder to the humanitarian crisis that Russia’s invasion of Ukraine has sparked.  As Zbigniew just said, as of today, more than 700,000 people have been forced to flee the violence perpetrated by Russia by crossing the border from Ukraine to Poland, with more coming every single day.  I’m going to have the opportunity to speak to some of the folks who’ve come over just recently from Ukraine, but I have to say it’s an incredibly powerful reflection of Poland’s values that vulnerable people know that here, they will find refuge.</p>
<p>To help support the needs of Ukrainians in Poland and other countries, the Biden administration just requested of Congress 2.5 – excuse me, $2.75 billion in humanitarian assistance.  That’s both to meet the need of vulnerable people and communities inside Ukraine as well as to support refugee services, including here in Poland.  That’s in addition to the more than $54 million in humanitarian assistance to Ukraine that we announced just last week</p>
<p>We also sent a Disaster Assistance Response Team to Poland, working very closely with humanitarian agencies to provide the critical health care, safe drinking water, sanitation, hygiene supplies, protection for vulnerable people, especially women and children.</p>
<p>We’ve delivered nearly 20,000 thermal blankets suited for cold climates; we’ve provided funding for emergency supplies to sustain health care for up to 100,000 people for three months and up to 500 emergency surgical procedures.</p>
<p>Embassy Kyiv has temporarily relocated to Poland as well, and I’m grateful for that, that Poland is hosting them.  They and our embassies and consulates in Poland and across the region are working hard to assist American citizens and their families departing Ukraine and to help them with the influx of U.S. military personnel, humanitarian workers, as well as assistance.  We established a U.S. Welcome Center close to the Ukrainian border.  It’s been operating 24/7 since hostilities began.  We have support teams as well stationed near the border in Romania, Hungary, Slovakia, and Moldova, to assist any Americans who are leaving Ukraine.</p>
<p>At this moment of crisis for millions of Ukrainians – and as the security of Europe hangs in the balance – Poland has stepped forward with generosity, with leadership, with resolve.  We’re grateful for the strong foundation of friendship and cooperation that we’ve built together over many, many decades, which so many are now relying on today.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with People’s Republic of China (PRC) State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-peoples-republic-of-china-prc-state-councilor-and-foreign-minister-wang/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321047</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with PRC State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi about Moscow’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war against Ukraine.  The Secretary noted the world is watching to see which nations stand up for the basic principles of freedom, self-determination and sovereignty.  He underscored that the world is acting in unison to repudiate and respond to the Russian aggression, ensuring that Moscow will pay a high price.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with PRC State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi about Moscow’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war against Ukraine.  The Secretary noted the world is watching to see which nations stand up for the basic principles of freedom, self-determination and sovereignty.  He underscored that the world is acting in unison to repudiate and respond to the Russian aggression, ensuring that Moscow will pay a high price.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Multilateral Leadership on the Crisis in Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-multilateral-leadership-on-the-crisis-in-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 13:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=321044</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Since President Putin launched his unprovoked, unjustified, and unconscionable invasion of Ukraine over a week ago, the international community across continents has spoken with powerful unity to denounce Russia’s aggression and demand its cessation. Giving voice and purpose to that common cause requires ready international venues such as the United Nations, where the Russian government and its dwindling supporters cannot impede scrutiny of their actions.</p>
<p align="left">One of President Biden’s early foreign policy priorities was to reestablish American leadership at the United Nations and other international organizations, where our values, security, and prosperity could be protected and advanced. The success of that effort can clearly be seen in this week’s remarkable series of multilateral actions.</p>
<p align="left">In the UN Security Council on February 25, the United States and Albania introduced a resolution co-sponsored by an additional 80 UN member states demanding an end to the invasion and making clear that Russia alone bears responsibility for the ongoing violence.  Russia’s veto of that resolution only underscored its growing international isolation.  As U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations Linda Thomas-Greenfield stated after the vote, “Russia cannot veto the UN Charter.  Russia cannot, and will not, veto accountability.”</p>
<p align="left">That action was followed quickly by a February 27 Security Council vote to call for an Emergency Special Session of the UN General Assembly on Ukraine.  That Special Session resulted in an unprecedented repudiation of Russia and its horrific assault on the people of Ukraine and Ukraine’s sovereignty.  One hundred forty-one UN Member States, from all regions, voted in support of a resolution condemning Russia’s aggression and calling for an immediate end to its invasion.  At the end of two days of discussion, Russia could only assemble a rogue’s gallery of four nations to support its unconscionable actions and false narratives.</p>
<p align="left">On Friday, the UN Human Rights Council concluded an Urgent Debate on the Kremlin’s war against Ukraine.  The Council voted overwhelmingly to demand that Russia halt its assault on the Ukrainian people.  Russia stood virtually isolated.  The resolution establishes the highest level of scrutiny the Council can create: a Commission of Inquiry.  This powerful investigative mechanism will ensure that Russia’s horrific conduct in Ukraine is carefully and verifiably documented so those responsible, like President Putin, can be held to account.</p>
<p align="left">We and our partners and allies are also raising Russia’s aggression in every corner of the UN system and in related international organizations, such as the International Atomic Energy Agency, International Civil Aviation Organization, and International Maritime Organization. Our message in all these bodies is clear: there can be no business as usual so long as Russia wages this brutal war on its neighbor.</p>
<p align="left">Multilateral diplomacy can at times frustrate even the most determined of diplomats.  But, when faced with such naked contempt for peace and security, the nations of the world took action to unite and isolate the aggressor.  The powerful display of international solidarity and collective action demonstrates the unique role and indispensability of multilateral organizations like the United Nations to effectively respond against threats to the rules-based international order.  This is not only a time to appreciate the role of the United Nations, but it is also an opportunity to strengthen and revitalize the international system to prevent such aggression in the future.</p>
<p align="left">As President Biden has said: “An overwhelming majority of nations recognize that Putin is not only attacking Ukraine, he is attacking the very foundations of global peace and security—and everything the United Nations stands for.”</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Since President Putin launched his unprovoked, unjustified, and unconscionable invasion of Ukraine over a week ago, the international community across continents has spoken with powerful unity to denounce Russia’s aggression and demand its cessation. Giving voice and purpose to that common cause requires ready international venues such as the United Nations, where the Russian government and its dwindling supporters cannot impede scrutiny of their actions.</p>
<p align="left">One of President Biden’s early foreign policy priorities was to reestablish American leadership at the United Nations and other international organizations, where our values, security, and prosperity could be protected and advanced. The success of that effort can clearly be seen in this week’s remarkable series of multilateral actions.</p>
<p align="left">In the UN Security Council on February 25, the United States and Albania introduced a resolution co-sponsored by an additional 80 UN member states demanding an end to the invasion and making clear that Russia alone bears responsibility for the ongoing violence.  Russia’s veto of that resolution only underscored its growing international isolation.  As U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations Linda Thomas-Greenfield stated after the vote, “Russia cannot veto the UN Charter.  Russia cannot, and will not, veto accountability.”</p>
<p align="left">That action was followed quickly by a February 27 Security Council vote to call for an Emergency Special Session of the UN General Assembly on Ukraine.  That Special Session resulted in an unprecedented repudiation of Russia and its horrific assault on the people of Ukraine and Ukraine’s sovereignty.  One hundred forty-one UN Member States, from all regions, voted in support of a resolution condemning Russia’s aggression and calling for an immediate end to its invasion.  At the end of two days of discussion, Russia could only assemble a rogue’s gallery of four nations to support its unconscionable actions and false narratives.</p>
<p align="left">On Friday, the UN Human Rights Council concluded an Urgent Debate on the Kremlin’s war against Ukraine.  The Council voted overwhelmingly to demand that Russia halt its assault on the Ukrainian people.  Russia stood virtually isolated.  The resolution establishes the highest level of scrutiny the Council can create: a Commission of Inquiry.  This powerful investigative mechanism will ensure that Russia’s horrific conduct in Ukraine is carefully and verifiably documented so those responsible, like President Putin, can be held to account.</p>
<p align="left">We and our partners and allies are also raising Russia’s aggression in every corner of the UN system and in related international organizations, such as the International Atomic Energy Agency, International Civil Aviation Organization, and International Maritime Organization. Our message in all these bodies is clear: there can be no business as usual so long as Russia wages this brutal war on its neighbor.</p>
<p align="left">Multilateral diplomacy can at times frustrate even the most determined of diplomats.  But, when faced with such naked contempt for peace and security, the nations of the world took action to unite and isolate the aggressor.  The powerful display of international solidarity and collective action demonstrates the unique role and indispensability of multilateral organizations like the United Nations to effectively respond against threats to the rules-based international order.  This is not only a time to appreciate the role of the United Nations, but it is also an opportunity to strengthen and revitalize the international system to prevent such aggression in the future.</p>
<p align="left">As President Biden has said: “An overwhelming majority of nations recognize that Putin is not only attacking Ukraine, he is attacking the very foundations of global peace and security—and everything the United Nations stands for.”</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
