<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 20:55:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Organization of Islamic Cooperation Secretary General Hissein Brahim Taha Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-organization-of-islamic-cooperation-secretary-general-hissein-brahim-taha-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 20:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=347433</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p> Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a real pleasure to see the Secretary General of the Organization of Islamic Cooperation here at the State Department in Washington.  We’ve just had the inaugural and unprecedented strategic dialogue between the United States and the OIC.  We are committed to cooperation and consultation between us.</p>
<p>We have a shared focus on very significant socioeconomic challenges, as well as on security challenges, human rights.  We are extremely pleased to be partnered in ever stronger ways with the OIC.  I appreciate also very much the partnership on Afghanistan and the work we’re doing there, as well as continued cooperation on COVID, climate, and other issues that are affecting the world.</p>
<p>When our two voices are joined, it has a real impact, and this is a very good opportunity which I’m very pleased to have to deepen our consultations with the secretary general.  Mr. Secretary General, welcome.  Very good to have you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY GENERAL TAHA:</b>  (Via interpreter) Mr. Secretary, thank you for honoring us and for hosting us in this high place of American diplomacy.  There’s a long history here, so it’s with great pleasure that myself and my delegation are joining you today.  It’s a great honor to discuss together and to make progress on our cooperation between the OIC and the United States.  We do hope that all of these works that have moved ahead will make it possible to implement this cooperation, and this is a good thing for our countries and for all of our populations. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p> Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a real pleasure to see the Secretary General of the Organization of Islamic Cooperation here at the State Department in Washington.  We’ve just had the inaugural and unprecedented strategic dialogue between the United States and the OIC.  We are committed to cooperation and consultation between us.</p>
<p>We have a shared focus on very significant socioeconomic challenges, as well as on security challenges, human rights.  We are extremely pleased to be partnered in ever stronger ways with the OIC.  I appreciate also very much the partnership on Afghanistan and the work we’re doing there, as well as continued cooperation on COVID, climate, and other issues that are affecting the world.</p>
<p>When our two voices are joined, it has a real impact, and this is a very good opportunity which I’m very pleased to have to deepen our consultations with the secretary general.  Mr. Secretary General, welcome.  Very good to have you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY GENERAL TAHA:</b>  (Via interpreter) Mr. Secretary, thank you for honoring us and for hosting us in this high place of American diplomacy.  There’s a long history here, so it’s with great pleasure that myself and my delegation are joining you today.  It’s a great honor to discuss together and to make progress on our cooperation between the OIC and the United States.  We do hope that all of these works that have moved ahead will make it possible to implement this cooperation, and this is a good thing for our countries and for all of our populations. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with OIC Secretary General Taha</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-oic-secretary-general-taha/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 19:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=347404</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today in Washington, DC with the Secretary General of the Organization of Islamic Cooperation (OIC), H.E. Hissein Brahim Taha, on the margins of the inaugural U.S.-OIC Strategic Dialogue.  Secretary Blinken thanked Secretary General Taha for the OIC’s sustained efforts on issues of global priority, including Afghanistan and countering violent extremism.  The Secretary underscored the importance of the OIC’s role as a valued partner in deescalating conflicts and working to protect human rights.  The Secretary reaffirmed the U.S. commitment to expanding collaboration with the OIC to advance joint priorities, including women’s empowerment, minority rights, religious freedom, climate change, health issues, strengthening economic ties, and expanding educational and cultural exchanges.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today in Washington, DC with the Secretary General of the Organization of Islamic Cooperation (OIC), H.E. Hissein Brahim Taha, on the margins of the inaugural U.S.-OIC Strategic Dialogue.  Secretary Blinken thanked Secretary General Taha for the OIC’s sustained efforts on issues of global priority, including Afghanistan and countering violent extremism.  The Secretary underscored the importance of the OIC’s role as a valued partner in deescalating conflicts and working to protect human rights.  The Secretary reaffirmed the U.S. commitment to expanding collaboration with the OIC to advance joint priorities, including women’s empowerment, minority rights, religious freedom, climate change, health issues, strengthening economic ties, and expanding educational and cultural exchanges.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement from the European Union, the United States, and the United Kingdom on the establishment of the Atrocity Crimes Advisory Group (ACA) for Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-from-the-european-union-the-united-states-and-the-united-kingdom-on-the-establishment-of-the-atrocity-crimes-advisory-group-aca-for-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 16:53:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=347301</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><i>Begin text:</i></p>
<p>Today, the European Union, the United States, and the United Kingdom announced the creation of the Atrocity Crimes Advisory Group (ACA), a mechanism aimed at ensuring efficient coordination of their respective support to accountability efforts on the ground. The ACA will reinforce current EU, US and UK efforts to further accountability for atrocity crimes in the context of Russia’s ongoing war of aggression against Ukraine. It advances commitments made by the European Union, the United States, and the United Kingdom to demonstrate international support and solidarity at this crucial historical moment for Ukraine.</p>
<p>The overarching mission of the ACA is to support the War Crimes Units of the Office of the Prosecutor General of Ukraine (OPG) in its investigation and prosecution of conflict-related crimes. The ACA seeks to streamline coordination and communication efforts to ensure best practices, avoid duplication of efforts, and encourage the expeditious deployment of financial resources and skilled personnel to respond to the needs of the OPG as the legally constituted authority in Ukraine responsible for dealing with the prosecution of war crimes on its own territory.</p>
<p><b>EU High Representative/Vice-President </b><b>Josep</b><b> Borrell said:</b> “<i>It is critical to ensure that all those responsible for the terrible atrocities committed during the unprovoked Russian military aggression in Ukraine are brought to justice. There can be no impunity for war crimes. The Atrocity Crimes Advisory Group will be providing advice and supporting the ongoing efforts of Ukraine’s Prosecutor General’s War Crimes Units to collect, preserve, and analyze evidence of atrocities to help the investigations and ensure justice takes its course.”</i></p>
<p><b>US Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken said</b>: “<i>This initiative will directly support efforts by the Ukrainian Office of the Prosecutor General to document, preserve, and analyze evidence of war crimes and other atrocities committed by members of Russia’s forces in Ukraine, with a view toward criminal prosecutions.  The ACA is an essential element of the United States’ commitment that those responsible for such crimes will be held to account.”</i></p>
<p><b>UK Foreign Secretary Liz Truss said: </b>“<i>We are determined to ensure those responsible for the vile atrocities committed in Ukraine are held to account. The UK has already made a clear commitment to supporting Ukraine in its investigations, including through deploying war crimes experts to the region and releasing additional funding to aid the ICC in their investigations. We are now stepping up our efforts through this landmark initiative with our partners in the US and EU. Justice will be done.</i><i>”</i></p>
<p><b>General Prosecutor of Ukraine, Iryna </b><b>Venediktova</b><b> said</b>: <i>“There is ample evidence of the atrocities committed by Russia’s forces on the territory of Ukraine against civilians, including children. The creation of this support group and the advice of international experts with experience in other international criminal tribunals and national criminal law practice will help the ongoing work of our teams in investigating and prosecuting these crimes.”</i></p>
<p><b>Operational support</b></p>
<p>The ACA will bring together multinational experts to provide strategic advice and operational assistance to OPG specialists and other stakeholders in areas such as collection and preservation of evidence, operational analysis, investigation of conflict-related sexual violence, crime scene and forensic investigations, drafting of indictments, and co-operation with international and national accountability mechanisms. This engagement with the OPG and other justice, law enforcement and security agencies of Ukraine has been and will continue to be driven by the needs of the Ukrainian government and the parameters of its support will be developed in close consultation with the OPG.    To this end, it will closely associate its activities with the ongoing operational work taking place in cooperation with EU Member States, partner third countries and the International Criminal Court, including the Joint Investigation Team coordinated by Eurojust.</p>
<p>The ACA brings together a multi-national group of war crimes experts from European Union countries, the United States, the United Kingdom and other countries. Due to the current security situation in Ukraine, the experts are primarily based in south-eastern Poland but are operationally engaged in Ukraine, including by means of short-term missions and on-site interaction with the OPG staff and other international partners engaged. As the security situation permits, it is anticipated that experts and support staff will relocate entirely to Ukraine.</p>
<p>The ACA activity will cover coordination of two key elements:</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Advisory Group to the OPG: </b>Experienced senior war crimes prosecutors, investigators, military analysts, forensic specialists, and other experts based in the region on an ongoing basis provide expertise, mentoring, advice and operational support to the OPG and to the field-level Mobile Justice Teams, as well as a wider range of state and non-state actors.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><b>Mobile Justice Teams: </b>Several Mobile Justice Teams (MJTs) are being created and deployed to increase the capacity of the OPG War Crimes Unit and regional prosecutors to conduct field investigations. The MJTs will be composed of both international and Ukrainian experts and will be deployed at the request of the OPG to assist Ukraine’s investigators on the ground. They will be part of the holistic chain for documentation, investigation and prosecution of grave international crimes that is led by the OPG.</li>
</ul>
<p>The ACA is supported by the U.S. State Department’s Office of Global Criminal Justice (GCJ) and Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs (INL). ACA partners include the Arizona State University Sandra Day O’Connor College of Law, Global Rights Compliance, and the International Development Law Organization (IDLO). On the EU side, coordination will be ensured by the European External Action Service (EEAS), through the EU Delegation to Ukraine, in coordination with the European Commission, the EU Project Pravo-Justice II and the EU Advisory Mission Ukraine (EUAM). The UK contribution will be coordinated by the Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Office (FCDO) and other relevant UK Government Departments.</p>
<p><b>Background</b></p>
<p>The ACA is an operational hub that coordinates assistance in response to the technical and legal needs of the Government of Ukraine to hold perpetrators of international crimes to account. It constitutes one essential component of a broader multilateral effort to support Ukraine.</p>
<p><i>End Text</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><i>Begin text:</i></p>
<p>Today, the European Union, the United States, and the United Kingdom announced the creation of the Atrocity Crimes Advisory Group (ACA), a mechanism aimed at ensuring efficient coordination of their respective support to accountability efforts on the ground. The ACA will reinforce current EU, US and UK efforts to further accountability for atrocity crimes in the context of Russia’s ongoing war of aggression against Ukraine. It advances commitments made by the European Union, the United States, and the United Kingdom to demonstrate international support and solidarity at this crucial historical moment for Ukraine.</p>
<p>The overarching mission of the ACA is to support the War Crimes Units of the Office of the Prosecutor General of Ukraine (OPG) in its investigation and prosecution of conflict-related crimes. The ACA seeks to streamline coordination and communication efforts to ensure best practices, avoid duplication of efforts, and encourage the expeditious deployment of financial resources and skilled personnel to respond to the needs of the OPG as the legally constituted authority in Ukraine responsible for dealing with the prosecution of war crimes on its own territory.</p>
<p><b>EU High Representative/Vice-President </b><b>Josep</b><b> Borrell said:</b> “<i>It is critical to ensure that all those responsible for the terrible atrocities committed during the unprovoked Russian military aggression in Ukraine are brought to justice. There can be no impunity for war crimes. The Atrocity Crimes Advisory Group will be providing advice and supporting the ongoing efforts of Ukraine’s Prosecutor General’s War Crimes Units to collect, preserve, and analyze evidence of atrocities to help the investigations and ensure justice takes its course.”</i></p>
<p><b>US Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken said</b>: “<i>This initiative will directly support efforts by the Ukrainian Office of the Prosecutor General to document, preserve, and analyze evidence of war crimes and other atrocities committed by members of Russia’s forces in Ukraine, with a view toward criminal prosecutions.  The ACA is an essential element of the United States’ commitment that those responsible for such crimes will be held to account.”</i></p>
<p><b>UK Foreign Secretary Liz Truss said: </b>“<i>We are determined to ensure those responsible for the vile atrocities committed in Ukraine are held to account. The UK has already made a clear commitment to supporting Ukraine in its investigations, including through deploying war crimes experts to the region and releasing additional funding to aid the ICC in their investigations. We are now stepping up our efforts through this landmark initiative with our partners in the US and EU. Justice will be done.</i><i>”</i></p>
<p><b>General Prosecutor of Ukraine, Iryna </b><b>Venediktova</b><b> said</b>: <i>“There is ample evidence of the atrocities committed by Russia’s forces on the territory of Ukraine against civilians, including children. The creation of this support group and the advice of international experts with experience in other international criminal tribunals and national criminal law practice will help the ongoing work of our teams in investigating and prosecuting these crimes.”</i></p>
<p><b>Operational support</b></p>
<p>The ACA will bring together multinational experts to provide strategic advice and operational assistance to OPG specialists and other stakeholders in areas such as collection and preservation of evidence, operational analysis, investigation of conflict-related sexual violence, crime scene and forensic investigations, drafting of indictments, and co-operation with international and national accountability mechanisms. This engagement with the OPG and other justice, law enforcement and security agencies of Ukraine has been and will continue to be driven by the needs of the Ukrainian government and the parameters of its support will be developed in close consultation with the OPG.    To this end, it will closely associate its activities with the ongoing operational work taking place in cooperation with EU Member States, partner third countries and the International Criminal Court, including the Joint Investigation Team coordinated by Eurojust.</p>
<p>The ACA brings together a multi-national group of war crimes experts from European Union countries, the United States, the United Kingdom and other countries. Due to the current security situation in Ukraine, the experts are primarily based in south-eastern Poland but are operationally engaged in Ukraine, including by means of short-term missions and on-site interaction with the OPG staff and other international partners engaged. As the security situation permits, it is anticipated that experts and support staff will relocate entirely to Ukraine.</p>
<p>The ACA activity will cover coordination of two key elements:</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Advisory Group to the OPG: </b>Experienced senior war crimes prosecutors, investigators, military analysts, forensic specialists, and other experts based in the region on an ongoing basis provide expertise, mentoring, advice and operational support to the OPG and to the field-level Mobile Justice Teams, as well as a wider range of state and non-state actors.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><b>Mobile Justice Teams: </b>Several Mobile Justice Teams (MJTs) are being created and deployed to increase the capacity of the OPG War Crimes Unit and regional prosecutors to conduct field investigations. The MJTs will be composed of both international and Ukrainian experts and will be deployed at the request of the OPG to assist Ukraine’s investigators on the ground. They will be part of the holistic chain for documentation, investigation and prosecution of grave international crimes that is led by the OPG.</li>
</ul>
<p>The ACA is supported by the U.S. State Department’s Office of Global Criminal Justice (GCJ) and Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs (INL). ACA partners include the Arizona State University Sandra Day O’Connor College of Law, Global Rights Compliance, and the International Development Law Organization (IDLO). On the EU side, coordination will be ensured by the European External Action Service (EEAS), through the EU Delegation to Ukraine, in coordination with the European Commission, the EU Project Pravo-Justice II and the EU Advisory Mission Ukraine (EUAM). The UK contribution will be coordinated by the Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Office (FCDO) and other relevant UK Government Departments.</p>
<p><b>Background</b></p>
<p>The ACA is an operational hub that coordinates assistance in response to the technical and legal needs of the Government of Ukraine to hold perpetrators of international crimes to account. It constitutes one essential component of a broader multilateral effort to support Ukraine.</p>
<p><i>End Text</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Launch of the Atrocity Crimes Advisory Group (ACA) for Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/launch-of-the-atrocity-crimes-advisory-group-aca-for-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 16:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=347295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States, along with the European Union and the United Kingdom, has created the Atrocity Crimes Advisory Group (ACA).  This joint initiative will directly support the efforts of the War Crimes Units of the Office of the Prosecutor General of Ukraine (OPG) to document, preserve, and analyze evidence of war crimes and other atrocities committed in Ukraine, with a view toward criminal prosecutions.  As we launch this initiative, the Department of State will continue to work closely with the Department of Justice and other partners to support the pursuit of justice and accountability. As the <a class="external-link" href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/quintet-attorneys-general-statement-support-prosecutor-general-ukraine-and-investigations-and" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">recent joint statement</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> issued by the Attorney General and his international counterparts makes clear, we are united across the globe in our resolve to hold perpetrators responsible.</p>
<p>Evidence of atrocities by members of Russia’s forces in Ukraine continues to mount.  Initially, this violence took the form of bombardments and missile and artillery strikes hitting densely-populated cities and towns, causing thousands of civilian deaths and destruction of civilian infrastructure.  Later, when journalists, human rights defenders, and Ukrainian officials gained access to areas following the retreat of Russia’s forces, we saw reports of violence of a different order &#8212; credible reports of unarmed civilians shot in the back; individuals killed execution-style with their hands bound; bodies showing signs of torture; and horrific accounts of sexual violence against women and girls.  Most recently, credible reports are emerging of Ukrainian children being forcibly transferred out of the country.</p>
<p>The establishment of this multilateral accountability effort, therefore, comes at a critical time. The ACA will provide strategic advice and operational assistance to the War Crimes Units of the OPG, the legally constituted authority responsible for prosecuting war crimes and other atrocities in Ukraine. Although the United States and our partners are supporting a range of international efforts to pursue accountability for atrocities, the OPG will play a crucial role in ensuring that those responsible for war crimes and other atrocities are held accountable.  The ACA is an essential element of the United States’ commitment that those responsible for such crimes will be held to account.</p>
<p>The ACA’s assistance to the War Crimes Units of the OPG includes expanded funding for the work of a multi-national team of international prosecutors and other war crimes experts already deployed to the region.  This interdisciplinary team is providing strategic advice and operational assistance in areas such as collection and preservation of evidence, military analysis, investigation of conflict-related sexual violence, and co-operation with international and national accountability mechanisms. In this regard, the ACA will liaise with the Department of Justice as it pursues accountability in U.S. courts.</p>
<p>The ACA will streamline coordination and communication efforts to ensure best practices, avoid duplication of efforts, and encourage the expeditious deployment of financial resources and skilled personnel to respond to the needs of the OPG. The ACA’s engagement with the OPG and other justice, law enforcement, and security agencies of Ukraine has been, and will continue to be, driven by the needs of the Ukrainian government, and the parameters of its support will be developed in close consultation with the OPG.</p>
<p>We look forward to working with Madame Prosecutor General Iryna Venediktova to further the cause of justice for the people of Ukraine. At the same time, our Department of Justice and other law enforcement agencies will be vigilant in doing our part to promote accountability for the war crimes and other atrocities being committed by Russia’s forces.</p>
<p>More information about the ACA can be found here: <a href="https://www.state.gov/creation-of-atrocity-crimes-advisory-group-for-ukraine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA1MjUuNTg0NDI0MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY3JlYXRpb24tb2YtYXRyb2NpdHktY3JpbWVzLWFkdmlzb3J5LWdyb3VwLWZvci11a3JhaW5lLyJ9.ZuRNeDOQ5rwAsexR-H_tRW4Wjyx5E78_zpWo1JJr-xU/s/2171565732/br/131871525518-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1653583357942000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2mApboDSztFrOpxZrO3wgd">https://www.state.gov/<wbr />creation-of-atrocity-crimes-<wbr />advisory-group-for-ukraine/</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States, along with the European Union and the United Kingdom, has created the Atrocity Crimes Advisory Group (ACA).  This joint initiative will directly support the efforts of the War Crimes Units of the Office of the Prosecutor General of Ukraine (OPG) to document, preserve, and analyze evidence of war crimes and other atrocities committed in Ukraine, with a view toward criminal prosecutions.  As we launch this initiative, the Department of State will continue to work closely with the Department of Justice and other partners to support the pursuit of justice and accountability. As the <a class="external-link" href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/quintet-attorneys-general-statement-support-prosecutor-general-ukraine-and-investigations-and" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">recent joint statement</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> issued by the Attorney General and his international counterparts makes clear, we are united across the globe in our resolve to hold perpetrators responsible.</p>
<p>Evidence of atrocities by members of Russia’s forces in Ukraine continues to mount.  Initially, this violence took the form of bombardments and missile and artillery strikes hitting densely-populated cities and towns, causing thousands of civilian deaths and destruction of civilian infrastructure.  Later, when journalists, human rights defenders, and Ukrainian officials gained access to areas following the retreat of Russia’s forces, we saw reports of violence of a different order &#8212; credible reports of unarmed civilians shot in the back; individuals killed execution-style with their hands bound; bodies showing signs of torture; and horrific accounts of sexual violence against women and girls.  Most recently, credible reports are emerging of Ukrainian children being forcibly transferred out of the country.</p>
<p>The establishment of this multilateral accountability effort, therefore, comes at a critical time. The ACA will provide strategic advice and operational assistance to the War Crimes Units of the OPG, the legally constituted authority responsible for prosecuting war crimes and other atrocities in Ukraine. Although the United States and our partners are supporting a range of international efforts to pursue accountability for atrocities, the OPG will play a crucial role in ensuring that those responsible for war crimes and other atrocities are held accountable.  The ACA is an essential element of the United States’ commitment that those responsible for such crimes will be held to account.</p>
<p>The ACA’s assistance to the War Crimes Units of the OPG includes expanded funding for the work of a multi-national team of international prosecutors and other war crimes experts already deployed to the region.  This interdisciplinary team is providing strategic advice and operational assistance in areas such as collection and preservation of evidence, military analysis, investigation of conflict-related sexual violence, and co-operation with international and national accountability mechanisms. In this regard, the ACA will liaise with the Department of Justice as it pursues accountability in U.S. courts.</p>
<p>The ACA will streamline coordination and communication efforts to ensure best practices, avoid duplication of efforts, and encourage the expeditious deployment of financial resources and skilled personnel to respond to the needs of the OPG. The ACA’s engagement with the OPG and other justice, law enforcement, and security agencies of Ukraine has been, and will continue to be, driven by the needs of the Ukrainian government, and the parameters of its support will be developed in close consultation with the OPG.</p>
<p>We look forward to working with Madame Prosecutor General Iryna Venediktova to further the cause of justice for the people of Ukraine. At the same time, our Department of Justice and other law enforcement agencies will be vigilant in doing our part to promote accountability for the war crimes and other atrocities being committed by Russia’s forces.</p>
<p>More information about the ACA can be found here: <a href="https://www.state.gov/creation-of-atrocity-crimes-advisory-group-for-ukraine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA1MjUuNTg0NDI0MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY3JlYXRpb24tb2YtYXRyb2NpdHktY3JpbWVzLWFkdmlzb3J5LWdyb3VwLWZvci11a3JhaW5lLyJ9.ZuRNeDOQ5rwAsexR-H_tRW4Wjyx5E78_zpWo1JJr-xU/s/2171565732/br/131871525518-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1653583357942000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2mApboDSztFrOpxZrO3wgd">https://www.state.gov/<wbr />creation-of-atrocity-crimes-<wbr />advisory-group-for-ukraine/</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Targeting an Oil Smuggling Network Supporting the IRGC-QF and Hizballah</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/targeting-an-oil-smuggling-network-supporting-the-irgc-qf-and-hizballah/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 14:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=347248</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States remains fully committed to imposing costs on the Iranian regime for its support to terrorist proxies that destabilize the Middle East.  To that end, today the United States is designating an international oil smuggling and money laundering network, led by Iran’s Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps-Qods Force (IRGC-QF) official Behnam Shahriyari and former IRGC-QF official Rostam Ghasemi, both of whom are designated persons.  This network is backed by senior levels of the Russian Federation government and state-run economic enterprises.  It has facilitated the sale of hundreds of millions of dollars’ worth of oil for the IRGC-QF and Hizballah, and it spans several jurisdictions, including Iran and Russia.  The IRGC-QF&#8217;s support for proxy militant groups continues to perpetuate conflict and suffering throughout the region.</p>
<p>We are taking this action pursuant to the counterterrorism authority Executive Order (E.O.) 13224, as amended.  The IRGC-QF was designated pursuant to E.O. 13224 in 2007 for providing support to multiple terrorist groups.</p>
<p>While the United States continues to seek a mutual return to full implementation of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA), we will strictly enforce sanctions on Iran’s illicit oil trade.  We will not hesitate to target those who provide critical support for the IRGC or Hizballah and facilitate their access to the international financial system.  We work vigorously to counter sanctions evasion and continue to strictly enforce sanctions on Iran’s illicit oil trade.  Anyone purchasing oil from Iran faces the prospect of U.S. sanctions.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0799" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States remains fully committed to imposing costs on the Iranian regime for its support to terrorist proxies that destabilize the Middle East.  To that end, today the United States is designating an international oil smuggling and money laundering network, led by Iran’s Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps-Qods Force (IRGC-QF) official Behnam Shahriyari and former IRGC-QF official Rostam Ghasemi, both of whom are designated persons.  This network is backed by senior levels of the Russian Federation government and state-run economic enterprises.  It has facilitated the sale of hundreds of millions of dollars’ worth of oil for the IRGC-QF and Hizballah, and it spans several jurisdictions, including Iran and Russia.  The IRGC-QF&#8217;s support for proxy militant groups continues to perpetuate conflict and suffering throughout the region.</p>
<p>We are taking this action pursuant to the counterterrorism authority Executive Order (E.O.) 13224, as amended.  The IRGC-QF was designated pursuant to E.O. 13224 in 2007 for providing support to multiple terrorist groups.</p>
<p>While the United States continues to seek a mutual return to full implementation of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA), we will strictly enforce sanctions on Iran’s illicit oil trade.  We will not hesitate to target those who provide critical support for the IRGC or Hizballah and facilitate their access to the international financial system.  We work vigorously to counter sanctions evasion and continue to strictly enforce sanctions on Iran’s illicit oil trade.  Anyone purchasing oil from Iran faces the prospect of U.S. sanctions.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0799" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Armenian Prime Minister Pashinyan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-armenian-prime-minister-pashinyan-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=347026</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Armenian Prime Minister Nikol Pashinyan.  The Secretary and the Prime Minister discussed the positive momentum toward peace in the South Caucasus.  Secretary Blinken offered the United States’ assistance with border delimitation and demarcation efforts and encouraged progress to develop regional transportation and communication links.  He highlighted the importance of continued bilateral dialogue to solve challenges in the South Caucasus and reaffirmed U.S. support for EU-brokered conversations between President Aliyev and Prime Minister Pashinyan.  Secretary Blinken reaffirmed U.S. readiness to help by engaging bilaterally and with likeminded partners, including through our role as an OSCE Minsk Group Co-Chair, to help Armenia and Azerbaijan find a long-term comprehensive peace.  The Secretary underscored the importance of normalization in relations between Armenia and Turkey in ensuring peace, stability, and prosperity for the wider region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Armenian Prime Minister Nikol Pashinyan.  The Secretary and the Prime Minister discussed the positive momentum toward peace in the South Caucasus.  Secretary Blinken offered the United States’ assistance with border delimitation and demarcation efforts and encouraged progress to develop regional transportation and communication links.  He highlighted the importance of continued bilateral dialogue to solve challenges in the South Caucasus and reaffirmed U.S. support for EU-brokered conversations between President Aliyev and Prime Minister Pashinyan.  Secretary Blinken reaffirmed U.S. readiness to help by engaging bilaterally and with likeminded partners, including through our role as an OSCE Minsk Group Co-Chair, to help Armenia and Azerbaijan find a long-term comprehensive peace.  The Secretary underscored the importance of normalization in relations between Armenia and Turkey in ensuring peace, stability, and prosperity for the wider region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken to Deliver Remarks at George Washington University</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinken-to-deliver-remarks-at-george-washington-university-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 19:38:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346960</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Asia Society will host Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken in delivering an address outlining the Administration&#8217;s policy toward the People’s Republic of China at 10:00 a.m. on Thursday, May 26, 2022.  The Secretary’s speech will be live-streamed on <a href="http://www.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1653507101781000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3ahLUeYL1SmHQiH3_BAU-M">www.state.gov</a> and <a class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/asiasociety" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://www.youtube.com/asiasociety</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>This event is open for press coverage.  Media who plan to cover in person must RSVP to <a href="mailto:EventsandTravel@State.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EventsandTravel@State.gov</a> by 9:00 a.m. on Wednesday, May 25, 2022.  All attendees will need to be vaccinated and boosted.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact the Office of Press Relations at <a href="mailto:EventsandTravel@State.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EventsandTravel@State.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Asia Society will host Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken in delivering an address outlining the Administration&#8217;s policy toward the People’s Republic of China at 10:00 a.m. on Thursday, May 26, 2022.  The Secretary’s speech will be live-streamed on <a href="http://www.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1653507101781000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3ahLUeYL1SmHQiH3_BAU-M">www.state.gov</a> and <a class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/asiasociety" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://www.youtube.com/asiasociety</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>This event is open for press coverage.  Media who plan to cover in person must RSVP to <a href="mailto:EventsandTravel@State.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EventsandTravel@State.gov</a> by 9:00 a.m. on Wednesday, May 25, 2022.  All attendees will need to be vaccinated and boosted.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact the Office of Press Relations at <a href="mailto:EventsandTravel@State.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EventsandTravel@State.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Targeting Covert Hamas Investment Network and Hamas Finance Official</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/targeting-covert-hamas-investment-network-and-hamas-finance-official/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 15:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346873</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>While Palestinians in Gaza face harsh living and economic conditions under Hamas, the terrorist group has amassed hundreds of millions in its secret investment portfolio.  Hamas maintains a violent agenda that harms both Israelis and Palestinians.  The United States is committed to denying Hamas the ability to generate and move funds and to holding it to account for its role in promoting and carrying out violence.  Today, the United States is designating an expansive network of three Hamas financial facilitators and six companies across the Middle East and North Africa that generated revenue for the terrorist group through the management of an international investment portfolio.  The United States is also designating a senior Hamas finance official.</p>
<p>These individuals and companies are being designated under Executive Order (E.O.) 13224, as amended, which targets terrorists, leaders, and officials of terrorist groups, and those providing support to terrorists or acts of terrorism.  The United States designated Hamas as a Foreign Terrorist Organization in October 1997, and as a Specially Designated Global Terrorist pursuant to E.O. 13224 in October 2001.</p>
<p>Today’s action targets the individuals and companies that Hamas uses to conceal and launder its funds.  For more information on this action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0798" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>While Palestinians in Gaza face harsh living and economic conditions under Hamas, the terrorist group has amassed hundreds of millions in its secret investment portfolio.  Hamas maintains a violent agenda that harms both Israelis and Palestinians.  The United States is committed to denying Hamas the ability to generate and move funds and to holding it to account for its role in promoting and carrying out violence.  Today, the United States is designating an expansive network of three Hamas financial facilitators and six companies across the Middle East and North Africa that generated revenue for the terrorist group through the management of an international investment portfolio.  The United States is also designating a senior Hamas finance official.</p>
<p>These individuals and companies are being designated under Executive Order (E.O.) 13224, as amended, which targets terrorists, leaders, and officials of terrorist groups, and those providing support to terrorists or acts of terrorism.  The United States designated Hamas as a Foreign Terrorist Organization in October 1997, and as a Specially Designated Global Terrorist pursuant to E.O. 13224 in October 2001.</p>
<p>Today’s action targets the individuals and companies that Hamas uses to conceal and launder its funds.  For more information on this action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0798" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Kuleba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-ukrainian-foreign-minister-kuleba-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 12:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346846</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to follow up on their May 15 meeting in Berlin.  The two leaders discussed ongoing diplomatic efforts to address the consequences of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine and to hold the Kremlin to account.  The Secretary noted the global food security crisis resulting from President Putin’s brutal war requires a global response, and they discussed potential means to export Ukraine’s grain to international markets.  The Secretary conveyed details on the $40.1 billion supplemental appropriations act signed by President Biden on May 21, which provides further funding for security, economic, and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and countries impacted by the war.  The Secretary again underscored the United States’ strong support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Moscow’s aggression.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to follow up on their May 15 meeting in Berlin.  The two leaders discussed ongoing diplomatic efforts to address the consequences of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine and to hold the Kremlin to account.  The Secretary noted the global food security crisis resulting from President Putin’s brutal war requires a global response, and they discussed potential means to export Ukraine’s grain to international markets.  The Secretary conveyed details on the $40.1 billion supplemental appropriations act signed by President Biden on May 21, which provides further funding for security, economic, and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and countries impacted by the war.  The Secretary again underscored the United States’ strong support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Moscow’s aggression.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Australian Foreign Minister Wong</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-australian-foreign-minister-wong/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 11:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346840</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met yesterday with Australian Foreign Minister Penny Wong in Tokyo on the sidelines of the Quad Leaders’ Summit to discuss the strong U.S.-Australia Alliance and our mutual efforts to ensure peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p align="left">The Secretary and Foreign Minister reaffirmed their commitment to working together bilaterally, through the Quad, and via the AUKUS partnership as well as their continued respect for ASEAN centrality. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Wong welcomed the launch of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, which will drive sustainable and inclusive economic growth and prosperity, and they noted the imperative of addressing the climate crisis.</p>
<p align="left">They also discussed collective efforts to hold the Russian Federation accountable for its unprovoked and unjust war of choice against Ukraine, as well as mutual efforts to provide security assistance to Ukraine.</p>
<p align="left">The Secretary and Foreign Minister expressed their concerns around ongoing developments in the region, including the DPRK&#8217;s continued destabilizing provocations, and committed to continue working closely with partners and allies to advance a free and open Indo-Pacific and to strengthen the resiliency, economic opportunity, and freedom for the Pacific Island region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met yesterday with Australian Foreign Minister Penny Wong in Tokyo on the sidelines of the Quad Leaders’ Summit to discuss the strong U.S.-Australia Alliance and our mutual efforts to ensure peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p align="left">The Secretary and Foreign Minister reaffirmed their commitment to working together bilaterally, through the Quad, and via the AUKUS partnership as well as their continued respect for ASEAN centrality. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Wong welcomed the launch of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, which will drive sustainable and inclusive economic growth and prosperity, and they noted the imperative of addressing the climate crisis.</p>
<p align="left">They also discussed collective efforts to hold the Russian Federation accountable for its unprovoked and unjust war of choice against Ukraine, as well as mutual efforts to provide security assistance to Ukraine.</p>
<p align="left">The Secretary and Foreign Minister expressed their concerns around ongoing developments in the region, including the DPRK&#8217;s continued destabilizing provocations, and committed to continue working closely with partners and allies to advance a free and open Indo-Pacific and to strengthen the resiliency, economic opportunity, and freedom for the Pacific Island region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
