<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 02:07:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Public Schedule &#8211; June 25, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/public-schedule-june-25-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 02:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=254966</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>                              ***THE DAILY PUBLIC SCHEDULE IS SUBJECT TO CHANGE***</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><u>SECRETARY ANTONY J. BLINKEN<br />
</u></strong>Secretary Blinken is on travel to Germany, France, Italy, and the Vatican, from June 22-29, 2021.  Please click <a href="https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-germany-france-italy-and-the-vatican/">here</a> for more information.</p>
<p><strong>9:15 a.m. LOCAL</strong> Secretary Blinken meets with OECD Secretary General Mathias Cormann, in Paris, France.<br />
<strong>(POOLED CAMERA SPRAY AT TOP)</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong><strong>10:30 a.m. LOCAL</strong> Secretary Blinken meets with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian, in Paris, France.<br />
<strong>(POOLED CAMERA SPRAY AT TOP)</strong></p>
<p><strong>12:00 p.m. LOCAL</strong> Secretary Blinken holds a joint press availability with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian, in Paris, France.<br />
<strong>(POOLED PRESS COVERAGE)</strong></p>
<p><strong>2:30 p.m. LOCAL</strong> Secretary Blinken participates in a Youth Outreach Event on Democracy and Human Rights, in Paris, France.<strong>(POOLED PRESS COVERAGE)</strong></p>
<p><strong>3:30 p.m. LOCAL</strong> Secretary Blinken holds a Meet and Greet with U.S. Mission France, in Paris, France.<br />
<strong>(POOLED PRESS COVERAGE OF OPENING REMARKS)</strong></p>
<p><strong>5:00 p.m. LOCAL </strong>Secretary Blinken meets with French President Emmanuel Macron, in Paris, France.<br />
<strong>(POOLED CAMERA SPRAY AT TOP)</strong></p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY WENDY R. SHERMAN</u></strong><br />
<strong>9:30 a.m</strong>. Deputy Secretary Sherman meets virtually with Tunisian Prime Minister Hichem Mechichi, from the Department of State.<br />
<strong>(CLOSED PRESS COVERAGE)</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong><strong>3:30 p.m. </strong>Deputy Secretary Sherman participates in the ceremony to raise the Progress Flag at the State Department in recognition of Pride Month, at the Department of State. Please click <a href="https://www.state.gov/u-s-department-of-state-raises-the-progress-flag-in-honor-of-pride-month/">here</a> for more information.<br />
<strong>(OPEN PRESS COVERAGE)</strong></p>
<p><em>This event will be live streamed on </em><a href="http://www.state.gov"><em>www.state.gov</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY FOR MANAGEMENT AND RESOURCES BRIAN P. MCKEON</u></strong></p>
<p><strong>3:30 p.m.</strong> Deputy Secretary McKeon attends President Biden’s meeting with President of the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan Mohammad Ashraf Ghani and Chairman of the High Council for National Reconciliation of the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan Dr. Abdullah Abdullah, at the White House.<br />
<strong>(MEDIA DETERMINED BY THE WHITE HOUSE)</strong></p>
<p><strong>UNDER SECRETARY FOR POLITICAL AFFAIRS VICTORIA J. NULAND<br />
</strong><strong>10:15 a.m.</strong> Under Secretary Nuland delivers virtual remarks to the American Council on Germany, from the Department of State.<strong>(CLOSED PRESS COVERAGE)</strong></p>
<p><strong><u>ACTING ASSISTANT SECRETARY FOR EUROPEAN AND EURASIAN AFFAIRS PHILIP T. REEKER<br />
</u></strong>Acting Assistant Secretary Reeker accompanies Secretary Blinken on travel to Germany, France, Italy, and the Vatican, from June 22-29, 2021.  Please click <a href="https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-germany-france-italy-and-the-vatican/">here</a> for more information.</p>
<p><strong>BRIEFING SCHEDULE<br />
</strong>No Department Press Briefing</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>                              ***THE DAILY PUBLIC SCHEDULE IS SUBJECT TO CHANGE***</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><u>SECRETARY ANTONY J. BLINKEN<br />
</u></strong>Secretary Blinken is on travel to Germany, France, Italy, and the Vatican, from June 22-29, 2021.  Please click <a href="https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-germany-france-italy-and-the-vatican/">here</a> for more information.</p>
<p><strong>9:15 a.m. LOCAL</strong> Secretary Blinken meets with OECD Secretary General Mathias Cormann, in Paris, France.<br />
<strong>(POOLED CAMERA SPRAY AT TOP)</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong><strong>10:30 a.m. LOCAL</strong> Secretary Blinken meets with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian, in Paris, France.<br />
<strong>(POOLED CAMERA SPRAY AT TOP)</strong></p>
<p><strong>12:00 p.m. LOCAL</strong> Secretary Blinken holds a joint press availability with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian, in Paris, France.<br />
<strong>(POOLED PRESS COVERAGE)</strong></p>
<p><strong>2:30 p.m. LOCAL</strong> Secretary Blinken participates in a Youth Outreach Event on Democracy and Human Rights, in Paris, France.<strong>(POOLED PRESS COVERAGE)</strong></p>
<p><strong>3:30 p.m. LOCAL</strong> Secretary Blinken holds a Meet and Greet with U.S. Mission France, in Paris, France.<br />
<strong>(POOLED PRESS COVERAGE OF OPENING REMARKS)</strong></p>
<p><strong>5:00 p.m. LOCAL </strong>Secretary Blinken meets with French President Emmanuel Macron, in Paris, France.<br />
<strong>(POOLED CAMERA SPRAY AT TOP)</strong></p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY WENDY R. SHERMAN</u></strong><br />
<strong>9:30 a.m</strong>. Deputy Secretary Sherman meets virtually with Tunisian Prime Minister Hichem Mechichi, from the Department of State.<br />
<strong>(CLOSED PRESS COVERAGE)</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong><strong>3:30 p.m. </strong>Deputy Secretary Sherman participates in the ceremony to raise the Progress Flag at the State Department in recognition of Pride Month, at the Department of State. Please click <a href="https://www.state.gov/u-s-department-of-state-raises-the-progress-flag-in-honor-of-pride-month/">here</a> for more information.<br />
<strong>(OPEN PRESS COVERAGE)</strong></p>
<p><em>This event will be live streamed on </em><a href="http://www.state.gov"><em>www.state.gov</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY FOR MANAGEMENT AND RESOURCES BRIAN P. MCKEON</u></strong></p>
<p><strong>3:30 p.m.</strong> Deputy Secretary McKeon attends President Biden’s meeting with President of the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan Mohammad Ashraf Ghani and Chairman of the High Council for National Reconciliation of the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan Dr. Abdullah Abdullah, at the White House.<br />
<strong>(MEDIA DETERMINED BY THE WHITE HOUSE)</strong></p>
<p><strong>UNDER SECRETARY FOR POLITICAL AFFAIRS VICTORIA J. NULAND<br />
</strong><strong>10:15 a.m.</strong> Under Secretary Nuland delivers virtual remarks to the American Council on Germany, from the Department of State.<strong>(CLOSED PRESS COVERAGE)</strong></p>
<p><strong><u>ACTING ASSISTANT SECRETARY FOR EUROPEAN AND EURASIAN AFFAIRS PHILIP T. REEKER<br />
</u></strong>Acting Assistant Secretary Reeker accompanies Secretary Blinken on travel to Germany, France, Italy, and the Vatican, from June 22-29, 2021.  Please click <a href="https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-germany-france-italy-and-the-vatican/">here</a> for more information.</p>
<p><strong>BRIEFING SCHEDULE<br />
</strong>No Department Press Briefing</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; June 24, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-june-24-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 22:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=254916</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:06 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Good afternoon, and thank you for joining today’s daily press briefing.  I have three updates at the top before I start taking your questions.</p>
<p>As you know, the Secretary arrived in Berlin yesterday for a multi-leg European trip that would also take him to Paris, Rome, Bari and Matera.  This trip gives the Secretary a chance to follow up on the President’s successful trip to the region last week and continued discussions with key partners to underscore the U.S. commitment to a strong transatlantic partnership.</p>
<p>Yesterday, the Secretary met with Chancellor Merkel and Foreign Minister Maas to discuss how we can further strengthen the U.S.-Germany relationship to address common challenges, including recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic, the climate crisis, as well as China and Russia.  The Secretary also participated in the second Berlin conference on Libya which was an opportunity for the international community to support the progress made by the Libyan people and underscore our support for the full implementation of the relevant UN Security Council resolutions and the October 2020 nationwide ceasefire agreement.</p>
<p>Today, the Secretary and Foreign Minister Maas launched the initial meeting of the U.S.-Germany Dialogue on the Holocaust to highlight our shared commitment to combating anti-Semitism and Holocaust denial and distortion and to find innovative new ways to enhance Holocaust education.  The leaders used this opportunity to emphasize how anti-Semitism is rising around the world and such hatred and prejudice are inimical to U.S. and transatlantic interests and values.</p>
<p>The Secretary departs this evening for Paris where he will continue his discussion with European leaders.</p>
<p>Next, I am pleased to announce that 3 million doses of Johnson &amp; Johnson COVID-19 vaccine will arrive in Campinas, Brazil tomorrow morning.</p>
<p>This donation is a part of 80 million doses that President Biden announced on May 17th and is the result of close collaboration between the governments of the United States and Brazil toward putting an end to this pandemic.</p>
<p>As President Biden has said, the United States is committed to bringing the same urgency to international vaccination efforts as we have demonstrated right here at home.</p>
<p>We are sharing these vaccines to save lives and to lead the world into bringing an end to this pandemic.</p>
<p>We’re working to get as many safe and effective vaccine doses to as many people around the world as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>Thanks to the innovation of U.S. companies and the resilience of and commitment of American people, we&#8217;re in a position to help others.</p>
<p>The United States congratulates law professor Gay McDougall on her election as an independent expert on the Committee on the Elimination of Racial Discrimination or CERD.  Given her extensive legal and international human rights experience, including two previous terms on the Committee, the United States considers Professor McDougall a highly qualified expert who has made and who will continue to make valuable contributions to the Committee.</p>
<p>Racial justice is at the forefront of our international engagements, as demonstrated by our engagement at the UN Human Rights Council (HRC) 46th session where we led a statement addressing systemic racism signed by 158 nations, our nomination of Professor McDougall to the CERD, and submitting overdue report on the CERD on June 2nd.</p>
<p>The United States will continue to engage the international community to find effective means to address systemic racism both at home and around the world.</p>
<p>And finally, leaders from 16 Southern African Development Community nations held a summit in Mozambique Wednesday June 23rd, 2021.  We applaud the Southern African Development Community’s focus on the threat of terrorism in Mozambique, as ISIS is not an isolated problem but rather a regional – a broader regional concern.</p>
<p>The United States is also committed to supporting the Government of Mozambique to counter terrorism and combat violent extremism with a holistic strategy that also includes socio-economic development, community resilience programs, and security assistance, as well as humanitarian aid.  We look forward to learning more of the South African Development Communities – Development Community, excuse me, plan coming out of the summit, and we will underscore the importance of keeping civilian protection and respect for human rights at the forefront of all security assistance.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Jiha Ham.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Jiha, your line is now open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Hi, Jalina.  I have a question related to Otto Warmbier, the University of Virginia student who was tortured by North Korea and later sent back home, but died in 2017.  New York City mayor Bill de Blasio and the council members of the city have been endorsing a bill that can change the name of their – one of their streets to Otto Warmbier Way to commemorate Otto Warmbier.  And the street that they want to rename is located right in front of the New York North Korean mission to the UN.  So I’m wondering if you support this idea or whether you have any concerns as the host country of the foreign missions to the UN.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Well, I’ll start off by saying that we certainly will continue to express our deepest condolences to the Warmbier family.  With respect to your question on the street naming and where specifically it is in New York City, I’d have to refer you back to the mayor of New York City and all the local officials in New York City for those specific decisions being made.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Said Arikat, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, Jalina.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello?  Yeah.  Thank you very kindly.  Very quickly, today Palestinian Authority security forces arrested a Palestinian activist and he died in custody.  I wonder if you have a position on this, because this really comes at the heels of many abuses by the Palestinian security forces against Palestinian activists.</p>
<p>And my second question is the fact that Senator Risch is holding $50 million in aid to the Palestinians that was approved by Congress.  Do you have – also have a comment on that?  Thank you, Jalina.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Thank you for your question, Said.  So I’m going to start with your second question first.  For that, we simply won’t comment on the holds, and for that I’d have to send you back to Senator Risch’s office for any specific commentary.</p>
<p>To your first question, I’ll just say that we’re deeply disturbed by the death of Palestinian activist Nizar Banat and the information that has been reported regarding the circumstances surrounding his death.  We certainly also offer our sincere condolences not only to his family but as well as the community who’s been impacted by his death.  We urge the Palestinian Authority to conduct a thorough and transparent investigation and to also ensure full accountability in this case.  And we also strongly encourage the Palestinian Authority to respect the rights to free expression as well as the work of civil society.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jen Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, Jalina.  Thanks for doing this.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Thank you.  On the SIV issue, I was wondering whether you could tell us anything about the role the State Department is playing in the planning for a potential evacuation to a third country.  Which countries are under consideration for relocating the SIV applicants?  And then is anyone from the State Department meeting with anybody from the Afghan delegation that is in D.C. right now?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  So to your second question, I don’t have anything to announce or report out.  But to your first question, we are identifying SIV applicants who have served as interpreters as well as translators to be relocated outside of Afghanistan before we complete our military drawdown by September, in order to safely complete the remainder of the Special Immigrant Visa application process.  These are individuals who are actually already in the SIV pipeline.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Abigail Williams.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks so much, Jalina.  Following up on Jenny’s question regarding SIVs, I wanted to ask if you have any updated numbers on where you are in the process at looking at the 18,000 applicants.  I know that Secretary Blinken had spoken of 9,000 being towards the beginning process and another 9,000 waiting and face delays.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  No, I don’t have any specific updates in regards to numbers, but just will continue to underscore that we have said that we’re committed to supporting those who’ve helped the military as well as other government personnel with their duties, of course often at great personal risk, not only to themselves but to their family members.  And we’re continuing to work on every way possible to make sure we can help those who have helped us.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Oskar Gorzynski.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, Jalina.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Yes, I can hear you.  Did I say your name correctly?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah.  Yeah, that’s pretty much right, as good as it gets.  So I wanted to ask about today’s meeting between German Minister of Economy Peter Altmaier and Secretary Kerry.  Do you have any information that – what are the topics?  And there have – relatedly, this week German Foreign Minister Heiko Maas said that he expects a deal with the U.S. on Nord Stream 2 by August.  Is that the State Department’s assessment as well, and what would such a deal include?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  I’ll take your second question first.  We have nothing to announce when it comes to any specific deadlines, but we’ll continue to underscore that the President has made rebuilding our relationship with our allies – and of course that would include Germany administration priority – the strength of these relationships will lay the foundation for many of our foreign policy priorities, such as economic recovery, recovery in combating COVID-19, as well as pushing back on the PRC and authoritarianism around the world.</p>
<p>To your first question, we don’t have anything to announce.  We’ll have to take that back and get back to you on the meeting you mentioned with Secretary Kerry.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Thanks very much, Jalina.  Just to follow up on the Afghanistan question, do you have a sense for where you may send those folks who worked for the U.S. while they await processing their SIV visas?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  So thank you for your question, Nick.  I don’t have anything to share about specific locations at this time, but I will say that we would take under any relocation in full compliance with all the applicable laws as well as in full coordination with Congress.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jose Luis Sanz.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  So Jalina, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, well a couple of questions about Central America.  First one is about Nicaragua.  The fact that the repression and the detention of opposition leaders or journalists has continued means that the sanctions and the international community and the United States strategy is not working, and how do you expect to continue trying to help to (inaudible) on transpiring election in Nicaragua.</p>
<p>And the second one is about the request to El Salvador for the extradition of MS-13 members.  Can you confirm how many of them has been – already been made by the United States?  I’m talking about the case that is being seen in New York.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  So to your second question about MS-13 members and El Salvador, I’ll have to refer you to the Department of Justice.  And to your first question about Nicaragua, what I’ll say largely speaking is that, of course, the courage of the Nicaraguan people is admirable.  And we will continue to support them in the United States.  We’ll also continue to use all of our diplomatic and economic tools at our disposal to support Nicaraguans’ call for greater freedoms as well as accountability.  And of course, that would also include free and fair elections.</p>
<p>Thank you for your questions.  That’s all we have time for today, and I hope you have a great week ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:24 p.m.)</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:06 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Good afternoon, and thank you for joining today’s daily press briefing.  I have three updates at the top before I start taking your questions.</p>
<p>As you know, the Secretary arrived in Berlin yesterday for a multi-leg European trip that would also take him to Paris, Rome, Bari and Matera.  This trip gives the Secretary a chance to follow up on the President’s successful trip to the region last week and continued discussions with key partners to underscore the U.S. commitment to a strong transatlantic partnership.</p>
<p>Yesterday, the Secretary met with Chancellor Merkel and Foreign Minister Maas to discuss how we can further strengthen the U.S.-Germany relationship to address common challenges, including recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic, the climate crisis, as well as China and Russia.  The Secretary also participated in the second Berlin conference on Libya which was an opportunity for the international community to support the progress made by the Libyan people and underscore our support for the full implementation of the relevant UN Security Council resolutions and the October 2020 nationwide ceasefire agreement.</p>
<p>Today, the Secretary and Foreign Minister Maas launched the initial meeting of the U.S.-Germany Dialogue on the Holocaust to highlight our shared commitment to combating anti-Semitism and Holocaust denial and distortion and to find innovative new ways to enhance Holocaust education.  The leaders used this opportunity to emphasize how anti-Semitism is rising around the world and such hatred and prejudice are inimical to U.S. and transatlantic interests and values.</p>
<p>The Secretary departs this evening for Paris where he will continue his discussion with European leaders.</p>
<p>Next, I am pleased to announce that 3 million doses of Johnson &amp; Johnson COVID-19 vaccine will arrive in Campinas, Brazil tomorrow morning.</p>
<p>This donation is a part of 80 million doses that President Biden announced on May 17th and is the result of close collaboration between the governments of the United States and Brazil toward putting an end to this pandemic.</p>
<p>As President Biden has said, the United States is committed to bringing the same urgency to international vaccination efforts as we have demonstrated right here at home.</p>
<p>We are sharing these vaccines to save lives and to lead the world into bringing an end to this pandemic.</p>
<p>We’re working to get as many safe and effective vaccine doses to as many people around the world as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>Thanks to the innovation of U.S. companies and the resilience of and commitment of American people, we&#8217;re in a position to help others.</p>
<p>The United States congratulates law professor Gay McDougall on her election as an independent expert on the Committee on the Elimination of Racial Discrimination or CERD.  Given her extensive legal and international human rights experience, including two previous terms on the Committee, the United States considers Professor McDougall a highly qualified expert who has made and who will continue to make valuable contributions to the Committee.</p>
<p>Racial justice is at the forefront of our international engagements, as demonstrated by our engagement at the UN Human Rights Council (HRC) 46th session where we led a statement addressing systemic racism signed by 158 nations, our nomination of Professor McDougall to the CERD, and submitting overdue report on the CERD on June 2nd.</p>
<p>The United States will continue to engage the international community to find effective means to address systemic racism both at home and around the world.</p>
<p>And finally, leaders from 16 Southern African Development Community nations held a summit in Mozambique Wednesday June 23rd, 2021.  We applaud the Southern African Development Community’s focus on the threat of terrorism in Mozambique, as ISIS is not an isolated problem but rather a regional – a broader regional concern.</p>
<p>The United States is also committed to supporting the Government of Mozambique to counter terrorism and combat violent extremism with a holistic strategy that also includes socio-economic development, community resilience programs, and security assistance, as well as humanitarian aid.  We look forward to learning more of the South African Development Communities – Development Community, excuse me, plan coming out of the summit, and we will underscore the importance of keeping civilian protection and respect for human rights at the forefront of all security assistance.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Jiha Ham.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Jiha, your line is now open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Hi, Jalina.  I have a question related to Otto Warmbier, the University of Virginia student who was tortured by North Korea and later sent back home, but died in 2017.  New York City mayor Bill de Blasio and the council members of the city have been endorsing a bill that can change the name of their – one of their streets to Otto Warmbier Way to commemorate Otto Warmbier.  And the street that they want to rename is located right in front of the New York North Korean mission to the UN.  So I’m wondering if you support this idea or whether you have any concerns as the host country of the foreign missions to the UN.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Well, I’ll start off by saying that we certainly will continue to express our deepest condolences to the Warmbier family.  With respect to your question on the street naming and where specifically it is in New York City, I’d have to refer you back to the mayor of New York City and all the local officials in New York City for those specific decisions being made.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Said Arikat, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, Jalina.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello?  Yeah.  Thank you very kindly.  Very quickly, today Palestinian Authority security forces arrested a Palestinian activist and he died in custody.  I wonder if you have a position on this, because this really comes at the heels of many abuses by the Palestinian security forces against Palestinian activists.</p>
<p>And my second question is the fact that Senator Risch is holding $50 million in aid to the Palestinians that was approved by Congress.  Do you have – also have a comment on that?  Thank you, Jalina.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Thank you for your question, Said.  So I’m going to start with your second question first.  For that, we simply won’t comment on the holds, and for that I’d have to send you back to Senator Risch’s office for any specific commentary.</p>
<p>To your first question, I’ll just say that we’re deeply disturbed by the death of Palestinian activist Nizar Banat and the information that has been reported regarding the circumstances surrounding his death.  We certainly also offer our sincere condolences not only to his family but as well as the community who’s been impacted by his death.  We urge the Palestinian Authority to conduct a thorough and transparent investigation and to also ensure full accountability in this case.  And we also strongly encourage the Palestinian Authority to respect the rights to free expression as well as the work of civil society.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jen Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, Jalina.  Thanks for doing this.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Thank you.  On the SIV issue, I was wondering whether you could tell us anything about the role the State Department is playing in the planning for a potential evacuation to a third country.  Which countries are under consideration for relocating the SIV applicants?  And then is anyone from the State Department meeting with anybody from the Afghan delegation that is in D.C. right now?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  So to your second question, I don’t have anything to announce or report out.  But to your first question, we are identifying SIV applicants who have served as interpreters as well as translators to be relocated outside of Afghanistan before we complete our military drawdown by September, in order to safely complete the remainder of the Special Immigrant Visa application process.  These are individuals who are actually already in the SIV pipeline.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Abigail Williams.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks so much, Jalina.  Following up on Jenny’s question regarding SIVs, I wanted to ask if you have any updated numbers on where you are in the process at looking at the 18,000 applicants.  I know that Secretary Blinken had spoken of 9,000 being towards the beginning process and another 9,000 waiting and face delays.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  No, I don’t have any specific updates in regards to numbers, but just will continue to underscore that we have said that we’re committed to supporting those who’ve helped the military as well as other government personnel with their duties, of course often at great personal risk, not only to themselves but to their family members.  And we’re continuing to work on every way possible to make sure we can help those who have helped us.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Oskar Gorzynski.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, Jalina.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Yes, I can hear you.  Did I say your name correctly?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah.  Yeah, that’s pretty much right, as good as it gets.  So I wanted to ask about today’s meeting between German Minister of Economy Peter Altmaier and Secretary Kerry.  Do you have any information that – what are the topics?  And there have – relatedly, this week German Foreign Minister Heiko Maas said that he expects a deal with the U.S. on Nord Stream 2 by August.  Is that the State Department’s assessment as well, and what would such a deal include?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  I’ll take your second question first.  We have nothing to announce when it comes to any specific deadlines, but we’ll continue to underscore that the President has made rebuilding our relationship with our allies – and of course that would include Germany administration priority – the strength of these relationships will lay the foundation for many of our foreign policy priorities, such as economic recovery, recovery in combating COVID-19, as well as pushing back on the PRC and authoritarianism around the world.</p>
<p>To your first question, we don’t have anything to announce.  We’ll have to take that back and get back to you on the meeting you mentioned with Secretary Kerry.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Thanks very much, Jalina.  Just to follow up on the Afghanistan question, do you have a sense for where you may send those folks who worked for the U.S. while they await processing their SIV visas?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  So thank you for your question, Nick.  I don’t have anything to share about specific locations at this time, but I will say that we would take under any relocation in full compliance with all the applicable laws as well as in full coordination with Congress.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jose Luis Sanz.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  So Jalina, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, well a couple of questions about Central America.  First one is about Nicaragua.  The fact that the repression and the detention of opposition leaders or journalists has continued means that the sanctions and the international community and the United States strategy is not working, and how do you expect to continue trying to help to (inaudible) on transpiring election in Nicaragua.</p>
<p>And the second one is about the request to El Salvador for the extradition of MS-13 members.  Can you confirm how many of them has been – already been made by the United States?  I’m talking about the case that is being seen in New York.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong>  So to your second question about MS-13 members and El Salvador, I’ll have to refer you to the Department of Justice.  And to your first question about Nicaragua, what I’ll say largely speaking is that, of course, the courage of the Nicaraguan people is admirable.  And we will continue to support them in the United States.  We’ll also continue to use all of our diplomatic and economic tools at our disposal to support Nicaraguans’ call for greater freedoms as well as accountability.  And of course, that would also include free and fair elections.</p>
<p>Thank you for your questions.  That’s all we have time for today, and I hope you have a great week ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:24 p.m.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Department of State Dedicates the New U.S. Embassy in Niamey, Niger</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-department-of-state-dedicates-the-new-u-s-embassy-in-niamey-niger-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 21:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=254909</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Bureau of Overseas Buildings Operations (OBO) celebrates today’s dedication of the new U.S. Embassy in Niamey, Niger by Ambassador Eric Paul Whitaker.</p>
<p>Situated on the existing 11-acre Embassy campus, this multi-building project embodies OBO’s goals for safe, secure, functional, and resilient facilities that provide a platform for U.S. diplomacy abroad.</p>
<p>Over the past 50 years, the campus has evolved to meet the needs of the diplomatic mission.  The campus’s new buildings are integrated into the existing site and represent the best of American architecture, engineering, and construction execution.  A concrete, lasting symbol of the United States&#8217; commitment to Niger, the Embassy is on track to become the first Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (LEED®) Platinum project in West Africa.</p>
<p>The Miller Hull Partnership of Seattle, Washington is the design architect and B.L. Harbert International of Birmingham, Alabama is the construction contractor with Page as Architect of Record.  Approximately 1,700 American, local, and third-country national employees have been involved in project construction, including 1,500 Nigeriens.  The construction team contributed more than 6 million work hours to this innovative project, which has generated $53 million to the local economy.</p>
<p>Since the start of the Department’s Capital Security Construction Program in 1999, OBO has completed 164 new diplomatic facilities.  OBO currently has more than 50 active projects either in design or under construction worldwide.</p>
<p>OBO provides safe, secure, functional, and resilient facilities that represent the U.S. Government to the host nation and that support U.S. diplomats in advancing U.S. foreign policy objectives abroad.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact Christine Foushee at <a href="mailto:FousheeCT@state.gov">FousheeCT@state.gov</a> or visit <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureaus-offices/bureau-of-overseas-buildings-operations/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.state.gov/obo&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1624655215195000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFwBBlOzaSv_4MlMHfKuiCbpvNL1Q">www.state.gov/obo</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Bureau of Overseas Buildings Operations (OBO) celebrates today’s dedication of the new U.S. Embassy in Niamey, Niger by Ambassador Eric Paul Whitaker.</p>
<p>Situated on the existing 11-acre Embassy campus, this multi-building project embodies OBO’s goals for safe, secure, functional, and resilient facilities that provide a platform for U.S. diplomacy abroad.</p>
<p>Over the past 50 years, the campus has evolved to meet the needs of the diplomatic mission.  The campus’s new buildings are integrated into the existing site and represent the best of American architecture, engineering, and construction execution.  A concrete, lasting symbol of the United States&#8217; commitment to Niger, the Embassy is on track to become the first Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (LEED®) Platinum project in West Africa.</p>
<p>The Miller Hull Partnership of Seattle, Washington is the design architect and B.L. Harbert International of Birmingham, Alabama is the construction contractor with Page as Architect of Record.  Approximately 1,700 American, local, and third-country national employees have been involved in project construction, including 1,500 Nigeriens.  The construction team contributed more than 6 million work hours to this innovative project, which has generated $53 million to the local economy.</p>
<p>Since the start of the Department’s Capital Security Construction Program in 1999, OBO has completed 164 new diplomatic facilities.  OBO currently has more than 50 active projects either in design or under construction worldwide.</p>
<p>OBO provides safe, secure, functional, and resilient facilities that represent the U.S. Government to the host nation and that support U.S. diplomats in advancing U.S. foreign policy objectives abroad.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact Christine Foushee at <a href="mailto:FousheeCT@state.gov">FousheeCT@state.gov</a> or visit <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureaus-offices/bureau-of-overseas-buildings-operations/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.state.gov/obo&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1624655215195000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFwBBlOzaSv_4MlMHfKuiCbpvNL1Q">www.state.gov/obo</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Senior State Department Official On Ongoing U.S. Engagement Regarding the JCPOA</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/senior-state-department-official-on-ongoing-u-s-engagement-regarding-the-jcpoa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 20:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=254877</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Thank you.  Good afternoon everyone and thanks for joining our call.  We have with us today .   is going to address the current status of the situation following conclusion of the sixth round of talks.  Just as a reminder,  will be speaking today on background.  And you may refer to him as a Senior State Department Official for the purposes of your reporting.</p>
<p>Also as another reminder, this call is embargoed until the conclusion of the call.  And the audio from this session is not for broadcast or replay.  So just one more time, this on background to a Senior State Department Official.  And with that, I’m going to go ahead and turn it over to  for ’s remarks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>Thank you.  And thanks for doing this again.  I know that in the last few weeks there’s been some confusion, some reporting that may have been – that have added to that confusion.  And part of it could be because we haven’t done one of these some time, so I’m glad to do it again and try to clear up any confusion that may exist.  So I’ll be brief in what I’ll say at the top, just to try to address two issues that I think have caused some of that imprecision.</p>
<p>First, where we are on the talks – and there has been some reporting that we basically have a deal already with Iran, that it’s just a matter of deciding when we’re going to put it out.  Let me make it absolutely clear:  We just concluded round six.  We will be resuming – or coming back for round seven sometime in the not-too-distant future, and we wouldn’t be doing that if the deal were already done.  We still have serious differences that have not been bridged, serious differences with Iran over the host of issues, whether it’s the nuclear steps that Iran needs to take to come back into compliance, the sanctions relief that the U.S. will be offering, or the sequence of steps that both sides would be taking.  Nothing is agreed until everything is agreed.  And since everything is not agreed, we still don’t have anything nailed down.  And there’s still some very important issues that need to be resolved.  By the same token, we wouldn’t be going back for a seventh round if we didn’t think that a deal was possible.  It remains possible.  It remains our objective, but we’re not there yet, and I’m not going to speculate as to if or when we will get there.</p>
<p>Second point, as to the issue of timing and in particular the impact of the elections (inaudible), first I think we’ve said already what we thought of the elections and of the new president, the fact that this was a pre-manufactured process that did not reflect the will of the Iranian people.  And we also have said what we thought about the background of the president-elect.  That said, from our point of view, it does not affect our determination to try to reach a deal or the pace at which we will go about pursuing it.  We’re not going to second guess any effect that it might have on Iranian decision making, but our goal is to pursue the objective that President Biden laid out both during the campaign and since, which is to try to address – diplomatically by – is our preference – our goal of preventing Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p>And we believe that diplomacy, by returning to the JCPOA, is the best way to achieve that goal, and we’ll do it with whoever is in power with Iran precisely because we have serious – very serious – differences with their leadership.  And we believe that preventing them from acquiring a nuclear weapon is an important step in then trying to address the other issues that we have with Iran.  Because again, as President Biden and the Secretary of State have made clear, we see the return to the JCPOA as a beginning of a diplomatic process, not at the end, because we have many other issues of concern that we need to raise from Iran’s (inaudible) groups in the region, to its ballistic missile program, to its many other destabilizing activities.</p>
<p>Finally, I want to say a word about an issue which is as important as anything I’ve said already, which is the issue of American citizens who are wrongfully detained in Iran.  That I still need to raise this, that they’re still not home, is a scandal and one that we are fighting every day to address.  And for Ahmad, for Siamak, for Baquer, for Morad, this is our priority.  We will not rest until they’re home and we’ll do everything in our power to make sure that that the day comes very, very soon.</p>
<p>So with that, I’m happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Great.  Thank you.  Let’s please go to the line of Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>One moment, please.  Wait until I announce your line is open before speaking.  And Nick, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thanks very much.  , understanding that you have differences on sequencing, do you – can you give us a sense for how the oil waivers would fit into this, whether you would grant waivers on day one or hold out to issue waivers until later on, maybe two to three months after the IAEA confirms compliance?  And would you be willing to give waivers without an IAEA confirmation of compliance?  And then second, can you just comment on the idea that the clock is ticking here because if too much time goes on, Iran will advance so far technologically that the original terms of the JCPOA essentially become moot, and you would have to negotiate an entirely new deal?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>So thanks, Nick.  So as to the first question, this may apply to a number of questions we’re going to get.  However much we’d prefer to be negotiating with the press corps than with Iran, it’s not what we’re going to do, so I’d rather – I won’t get into the details of what our position is on various issues, so I’ll skip the first question.</p>
<p>The second one about the clock, listen, there’s no – it’s not like there’s a scientific time at which point that threshold that you mentioned will be crossed, but certainly time is not a positive factor.  And this process won’t be open indefinitely, so we’re trying to get back into the deal.  We understand Iran is continuing to make progress, which is precisely why we believe withdrawing from the deal was a mistake and why we’re faced with this situation.  We’re going to try to get them back as soon as possible under the terms of the deal.  If it’s not done quickly and if Iran continues to make progress, of course it’s something that we’re going to have to consider in terms of the provisions of the deal that we’d be prepared to accept.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Let’s go to the line of Lara Jakes.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>One moment.  And Lara, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.  And Lara, please check your mute button.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Yes.  I’m sorry.  I was, in fact, on mute.  Apologies.  Thanks.  And  a minute ago you said that we see the return to the JCPOA as the beginning of the process and not the end.  Iran’s new president has very clearly said that he will not consider a longer and stronger deal for reining in the missile’s programs and the proxies.  So I’m wondering why you think that delta can be resolved.  And I’m also wondering if you’d speak a little bit about the IAEA inspections agreement that is, I think, expiring today.  I believe there’s a tentative agreement for it to be extended again.  Is that a reason for optimism?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Thanks, Lara.  So on the first point, yeah, we’ve heard what President-Elect Raisi said.  Frankly, that’s not very different from what other Iranian leaders have been saying for some time.  But we’ve been equally clear, crystal-clear, and President Biden was crystal-clear on this, from the campaign and from his first day in office, which is that we believe that we can – are going to need to discuss other issues after we – assuming we get back into the JCPOA.  There are many issues of concern that we have, but also there’s issues that Iran wants to address, and they’ve made that very clear to us, including during this talks, that they – there are some elements that they are asking for, which go beyond the terms of the JCPOA.  So our position remains the same, that we see the return to the JCPOA as a beginning of a diplomatic process, and we believe that we’re going to need to engage in discussions with Iran, various things to address those other issues.  So we’ll have to find a way to resolve that difference.</p>
<p>On the IAEA, it’s good that you mention it.  Obviously we are concerned that at – from the time that I’m speaking – maybe there’s been news since – in the last hour or so, but we have not heard that there’s been an understanding.  If one is reached, that would be positive.  Although, we shouldn’t be playing – Iran should not be playing brinkmanship each time these agreements get extended.  I’d simply say that in the absence of such an understanding, in the absence of the IAEA being able to monitor what Iran is doing, it will be that much more complicated to get back into the JCPOA, because we’re going to have to know what the baseline of their nuclear program is.  And if the IAEA is blind for a certain amount of time and we don’t know what that baseline is, it’s going to be much more difficult to find a way back into the deal.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Let’s go to the line of Jennifer Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And Jennifer, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, .  Thanks so much for doing this.  What are you telling the Iranians about guarantees that the U.S. won’t quit the deal in four years?  How are you assuaging their concerns on that?  And on the issue of the hostages, has there been any progress towards their release?  Is it still the case that their release is not a precondition for the U.S. re-entering the JCPOA?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Thanks.  So, I mean, there is no such thing as a guarantee, and I think Iran knows it and we know it.  We have no guarantee; they have no guarantee.  That’s the way the JCPOA is built, that if one side violated, the other side would – its remedy would be to take countermanding steps.  But what we do think is that the best guarantee is to get back into the deal and to implement it faithfully, and that’s – and we think that there’s a – that’s the best answer, because there is no such thing as a guarantee.</p>
<p>Secondly, on the question of the detainees, it’s the same thing as I said about the deal.  Because nothing is agreed until everything is agreed, because we don’t have a deal yet, I’m not going to speak about how close we are.  Yet, we’ve made progress.  We were engaged in indirect discussions with Iran about their release, but we’re not there yet, and until we’re there I don&#8217;t want to give false hopes to the families who’ve suffered too much already.  And as I’ve said in the past, it is a priority, and we are absolutely insistent that the four American citizens who are wrongfully detained be released.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  And let’s go the line of Arshad Mohammed.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And Arshad, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.  And Arshad, please check your mute button.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you, and sorry about mute.  Two things.  One, would you continue the negotiations if Iran fails to extend its agreement with the IAEA?  And secondly, you said this process will not be open indefinitely.  What happens if you cannot reach an agreement by August 3rd, the date on which the Raisi administration takes office?  Is that when the door closes?  Or is the door open?  It may be indefinite, but it could be open for months or even years?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Thanks.  And I know that both two good but difficult questions.  We still hope that Iran will extend its technical understanding with the IAEA or find – not prolong the understandings that currently exist.  As I said, it would be an issue of real concern if they didn’t.  I’m not going to speculate as to what impact it would have on the talks, but I think it is – we’ve already indicated clearly to Iran that it would be extremely complicated if they – a complicating factor if they did not find a way to continue the understandings with the IAEA.</p>
<p>On your second question, again, I’m not going to sit here and say there’s a deadline.  Obviously this will be a decision for the President and his national security team to take.  But when we’ve said – and others have said it – that this process is not going to be open forever, we mean it.  We – this is not something that we could go on indefinitely.  There’s – we’ve had serious discussions, and I don’t – as I’ve said, we’ve made progress, and the Iranians have been serious in the talks so far, but we do have differences.  And if we can’t bridge them in the foreseeable future, I think we’re going to have to regroup and figure out how we move ahead.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Let’s go to the line of Courtney McBride.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And Courtney, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  So assuming – I understand that you are loathe to talk about timelines, but how does the administration hope to get follow-on talks with President-elect Raisi?  And how do you – do you acknowledge that he would need to be removed from the sanctions list as part of a broader discussion in hope of a broader agreement with Iran?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  So, I mean, I’ll repeat what I said about the follow-on talks.  I think we couldn’t have been clearer about what our position is on that, that we think – we believe that it has to be a part of what – of the process that we’re discussing right now, and we’re in the middle of discussing the nature of what those talks could be.  We know what Iran’s position is, but that’s why one of their – these are one of many reasons that we are still engaged in the talks and why we haven’t concluded them yet.</p>
<p>And I’ll also add again that there are issues that Iran feels that need to be addressed which go beyond the four corners of the JCPOA, and the only way to address those is going to be by continuing conversations in some format with us, and so we believe that this is something that’s not just a U.S. interest.  It happens to also be an Iranian interest, although they’ll be a better judge of that.</p>
<p>And on the question of sanctions, I think National Security Advisor Sullivan addressed it the other day.  We’re not going to get into details of what we might do.  We’re going to look at what we – what sanctions relief we believe we need to take in order to be back in compliance with the JCPOA, and that’s what we’re going to be judging in terms of the steps that we’ll be prepared to take if – and I emphasize if we’re back in a deal.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Okay.  Let’s go to the line of Michel Ghandour.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And Michel, go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, thank you for doing this.  There are calls from the Congress to the administration to take the election of President Raisi as an opportunity for not joining or rejoining the JCPOA.  What’s your answer to that?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  My answer to that:  We’re not involved in negotiations because we trust, like, or have anything or share any values in common with our Iranian counterparts.  We’re doing it precisely because we have very deep concerns, very serious issues.  And so the fact that there is now a new president – or there will soon be a new president of Iran does not detract our core national security interest, which is to reach a deal that puts their nuclear program in a box and makes sure that we prevent them from acquiring a nuclear weapon.  The identity of the Iranian president doesn’t have an impact on that, core national security interests.  And I would add, again, as the National Security Advisor said, that we know that the president in the Iranian system is not the sole and not even the chief decision-maker.  It’s a leadership in which the supreme leader has the ultimate word, and that position, that person has not changed as a result of the Iranian elections.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Let’s go to the line of Laura Rosen.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And Laura, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  , as I understand, not all the other countries in the P4+1 agree there should be a follow-on deal.  Can you speak to that?  I mean, I think Russia especially has said they think the JCPOA is sufficient.  So does that affect something being in a document with Iran that would call for follow-on talks?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Our position is our position.  We’ve had many conversations with Russia, and I wouldn’t characterize &#8212;</p>
<p>(Break.)</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  I think somebody’s on this call.  I think I recognize their voice, but yeah, okay.  So I’m saying we know – we had many discussions with our Russian colleagues about this.  I’m not going to characterize their position.  I think many countries have agreed that they want more diplomacy with Iran to address a range of issues, including regional issues, and Russia has been at the – one of the parties that has put forward ideas for what that diplomacy could look like.  So I’m not sure that I would fully agree with how you put it, but there are differences of views, but our position is very clear – is that we’re going to need follow-on talks, discussions to strengthen the deal.</p>
<p>And again, we would make the point that this is not only something that we think would help us.  We do think that it would help – it would – it should be in Iran’s interest because they have issues that they’re going to want to bring to the table.  Of course, that – as I said, that’s going to be – they will have to make that assessment, but our position has been clear from the day we started these talks and very familiar to all the parties who are there, and they know that’s America’s position.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We have time for just a couple more questions.  Let’s go to the line of Nadia Bilbassy.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And one moment.  Nadia, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you so much.  Thank you,  and , for doing this.</p>
<p>, you just said that nothing agreed until all agreed.  You have been – it’s been six sessions so far and you’re entering the seventh.  Can you just outline for us what exactly you agreed upon?  Is it just a framework, is it technical issues, is it more than that?</p>
<p>And second, I’m sure you have seen the statements coming from the (inaudible) office saying that you’re going to lift sanction on the supreme leader.  Do you see this as, like, a (inaudible)?  Is it a lie from the Iranian?  Is it propaganda trying to get you to where they want?  How do you see it?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Thanks, Nadia.  So if I understood your question, I mean, when I say nothing’s agreed until everything is agreed, that’s precisely what I meant.  So there’s nothing.  It’s not like there’s a framework or – we are still negotiating every issue, whether it’s the scope of sanctions relief, the scope of the steps that Iran will take to come back into compliance with its nuclear obligations, the sequence – all of those are still being discussed, and so we don’t have like a provisional deal on anything.  We are still working through all the issues, and that includes the issues of sanctions that you mentioned.  We will have to see.</p>
<p>And again, I don’t want – I’m not going to negotiate in public, but at this point we need to continue negotiating to see whether we could reach a comprehensive package that will be satisfactory, and at this point we’re not there yet.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Let’s go to the line of Farhad Pouladi.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>And Farhad, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Yes, hi.  Do you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>Yes, we hear you.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Perfect.  So my question is in regard to the Israeli Government’s comments on the JCPOA, or the JCPOA resurrection talks in Vienna.  Prime Minister Netanyahu was staunchly against the deal, but the position has been actually transferred to the new government and they are still against the JCPOA.  I covered what comments came out of General Kochavi’s visit yesterday and today.  And also today, Prime Minister Bennett says that this regime – the one that no one should do business with.  How concerned are you that they may take any unilateral action, and what has the Biden administration been doing to persuade them not to do anything to jeopardize the talks?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>Thank you, Farhad.  That’s an important question.  I want to start by saying we – under the government of Prime Minister Netanyahu, we were having close consultations.  We know – we knew that they have and we know they had a different view about the JCPOA, but we are trying to talk to them to make sure that we were as aligned as possible given our common objective, which is to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon.  We had differences about the JCPOA.  We knew that, we recognized it, but we nonetheless were working closely with them.</p>
<p>And the same holds for the government of Prime Minister Bennett.  We already had some high-level contacts.  I think you all know that Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Lapid will be meeting in Rome on Sunday.  I don’t know the agenda, but I would be surprised if Iran did not figure in those conversations.  And again, we respect that they have a different point of view.  I think they respect ours and we are going to try to talk and be as transparent and as coordinated as possible so that the ultimate goal, which we share, is one that is pursued as effectively as possible.  And we expect to have extremely positive and productive discussions with the new Israeli Government and we look forward to as close coordination as possible.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Okay, thanks.  Just a couple more questions.  Let’s go to the line of Halley Toosi.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>One moment.  And Halley, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, thanks for doing this.  A couple questions.  When it comes to the follow-on agreements, does the United States want to include human rights as one of the issues that is negotiated along with ballistic missiles and support for terrorism and all that?</p>
<p>Secondly, you said that there are indirect talks on the hostages.  Can you tell us a little bit more about those discussions?  Like are you talking about a potential prisoner exchange, and is it totally on a separate track from the nuclear discussion?  Any information you can give on that.</p>
<p>And also lastly, what is the most surprising thing that’s happened in this process for you?  What’s something you just didn’t expect, but that’s come up?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>Thanks.  So on the follow-on talks, listen, we know that there are a number of issues that – concerns that we have above and beyond the nuclear issue which is central.  There are lots of concerns.  Some of them will be negotiated in some formal way, others will be dealt with through other means.  So I’m not going to get into the details of what they will cover, but we – all of the issues you mentioned and that I mentioned are issues of real concern to this administration, but the format, the shape that those discussions or other diplomatic tools will take to address them I won’t get into.  But again, it doesn’t mean that we’re going to ignore any issue.  All of them will be pursued in one fashion or another.</p>
<p>On the detainee issue, they are separate.  These are separate conversations that are being held.  Obviously, we – we’re doing them more intensely when we are in Vienna because we could get communication to a third party more quickly, but they’re separate from the nuclear talks and, as I said, they are absolute priority.  Regardless of what happens with the JCPOA, we want our detainees, our citizens, wrongfully-held citizens back home as soon as possible.</p>
<p>Out of what’s been most surprising, I’m at a loss to say.  I mean, it is unusual to have these discussions in an indirect fashion.  I’ve said that many times before.  It is ripe for misunderstanding.  It’s ripe for prolonging the talks.  It’s not the most effective way to do it.  It means that we spend a lot of time in hotel rooms with our European and other colleagues and not with the party that we’re supposed to be negotiating with.  But by this point, we’ve gotten used to it, so we’ll make do.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  And I think we have time for one more question.  Let’s go to Arshad Mohammed.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And Arshad, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, thanks for coming back to me.  Just to ask one specific question, do you have any idea now when the seventh round of talks will begin in Vienna?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  No.  I mean, we assume that there is obviously consultations going on in Iran given – in Tehran given the election.  And when those consultations will have concluded, we will be notified, and then we’ll figure out when we meet again.  But at this point, I don’t have – I don’t have any plane reservations.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Okay, I think that’s our last question.  I just want to quickly thank our senior State Department official, .  Just as a reminder to everyone, this call today is on background, and so you can refer to our briefer as a senior State Department official.  With that, this briefing is ended and the embargo is lifted.  Have a good day.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Thank you.  Good afternoon everyone and thanks for joining our call.  We have with us today .   is going to address the current status of the situation following conclusion of the sixth round of talks.  Just as a reminder,  will be speaking today on background.  And you may refer to him as a Senior State Department Official for the purposes of your reporting.</p>
<p>Also as another reminder, this call is embargoed until the conclusion of the call.  And the audio from this session is not for broadcast or replay.  So just one more time, this on background to a Senior State Department Official.  And with that, I’m going to go ahead and turn it over to  for ’s remarks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>Thank you.  And thanks for doing this again.  I know that in the last few weeks there’s been some confusion, some reporting that may have been – that have added to that confusion.  And part of it could be because we haven’t done one of these some time, so I’m glad to do it again and try to clear up any confusion that may exist.  So I’ll be brief in what I’ll say at the top, just to try to address two issues that I think have caused some of that imprecision.</p>
<p>First, where we are on the talks – and there has been some reporting that we basically have a deal already with Iran, that it’s just a matter of deciding when we’re going to put it out.  Let me make it absolutely clear:  We just concluded round six.  We will be resuming – or coming back for round seven sometime in the not-too-distant future, and we wouldn’t be doing that if the deal were already done.  We still have serious differences that have not been bridged, serious differences with Iran over the host of issues, whether it’s the nuclear steps that Iran needs to take to come back into compliance, the sanctions relief that the U.S. will be offering, or the sequence of steps that both sides would be taking.  Nothing is agreed until everything is agreed.  And since everything is not agreed, we still don’t have anything nailed down.  And there’s still some very important issues that need to be resolved.  By the same token, we wouldn’t be going back for a seventh round if we didn’t think that a deal was possible.  It remains possible.  It remains our objective, but we’re not there yet, and I’m not going to speculate as to if or when we will get there.</p>
<p>Second point, as to the issue of timing and in particular the impact of the elections (inaudible), first I think we’ve said already what we thought of the elections and of the new president, the fact that this was a pre-manufactured process that did not reflect the will of the Iranian people.  And we also have said what we thought about the background of the president-elect.  That said, from our point of view, it does not affect our determination to try to reach a deal or the pace at which we will go about pursuing it.  We’re not going to second guess any effect that it might have on Iranian decision making, but our goal is to pursue the objective that President Biden laid out both during the campaign and since, which is to try to address – diplomatically by – is our preference – our goal of preventing Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p>And we believe that diplomacy, by returning to the JCPOA, is the best way to achieve that goal, and we’ll do it with whoever is in power with Iran precisely because we have serious – very serious – differences with their leadership.  And we believe that preventing them from acquiring a nuclear weapon is an important step in then trying to address the other issues that we have with Iran.  Because again, as President Biden and the Secretary of State have made clear, we see the return to the JCPOA as a beginning of a diplomatic process, not at the end, because we have many other issues of concern that we need to raise from Iran’s (inaudible) groups in the region, to its ballistic missile program, to its many other destabilizing activities.</p>
<p>Finally, I want to say a word about an issue which is as important as anything I’ve said already, which is the issue of American citizens who are wrongfully detained in Iran.  That I still need to raise this, that they’re still not home, is a scandal and one that we are fighting every day to address.  And for Ahmad, for Siamak, for Baquer, for Morad, this is our priority.  We will not rest until they’re home and we’ll do everything in our power to make sure that that the day comes very, very soon.</p>
<p>So with that, I’m happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Great.  Thank you.  Let’s please go to the line of Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>One moment, please.  Wait until I announce your line is open before speaking.  And Nick, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thanks very much.  , understanding that you have differences on sequencing, do you – can you give us a sense for how the oil waivers would fit into this, whether you would grant waivers on day one or hold out to issue waivers until later on, maybe two to three months after the IAEA confirms compliance?  And would you be willing to give waivers without an IAEA confirmation of compliance?  And then second, can you just comment on the idea that the clock is ticking here because if too much time goes on, Iran will advance so far technologically that the original terms of the JCPOA essentially become moot, and you would have to negotiate an entirely new deal?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>So thanks, Nick.  So as to the first question, this may apply to a number of questions we’re going to get.  However much we’d prefer to be negotiating with the press corps than with Iran, it’s not what we’re going to do, so I’d rather – I won’t get into the details of what our position is on various issues, so I’ll skip the first question.</p>
<p>The second one about the clock, listen, there’s no – it’s not like there’s a scientific time at which point that threshold that you mentioned will be crossed, but certainly time is not a positive factor.  And this process won’t be open indefinitely, so we’re trying to get back into the deal.  We understand Iran is continuing to make progress, which is precisely why we believe withdrawing from the deal was a mistake and why we’re faced with this situation.  We’re going to try to get them back as soon as possible under the terms of the deal.  If it’s not done quickly and if Iran continues to make progress, of course it’s something that we’re going to have to consider in terms of the provisions of the deal that we’d be prepared to accept.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Let’s go to the line of Lara Jakes.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>One moment.  And Lara, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.  And Lara, please check your mute button.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Yes.  I’m sorry.  I was, in fact, on mute.  Apologies.  Thanks.  And  a minute ago you said that we see the return to the JCPOA as the beginning of the process and not the end.  Iran’s new president has very clearly said that he will not consider a longer and stronger deal for reining in the missile’s programs and the proxies.  So I’m wondering why you think that delta can be resolved.  And I’m also wondering if you’d speak a little bit about the IAEA inspections agreement that is, I think, expiring today.  I believe there’s a tentative agreement for it to be extended again.  Is that a reason for optimism?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Thanks, Lara.  So on the first point, yeah, we’ve heard what President-Elect Raisi said.  Frankly, that’s not very different from what other Iranian leaders have been saying for some time.  But we’ve been equally clear, crystal-clear, and President Biden was crystal-clear on this, from the campaign and from his first day in office, which is that we believe that we can – are going to need to discuss other issues after we – assuming we get back into the JCPOA.  There are many issues of concern that we have, but also there’s issues that Iran wants to address, and they’ve made that very clear to us, including during this talks, that they – there are some elements that they are asking for, which go beyond the terms of the JCPOA.  So our position remains the same, that we see the return to the JCPOA as a beginning of a diplomatic process, and we believe that we’re going to need to engage in discussions with Iran, various things to address those other issues.  So we’ll have to find a way to resolve that difference.</p>
<p>On the IAEA, it’s good that you mention it.  Obviously we are concerned that at – from the time that I’m speaking – maybe there’s been news since – in the last hour or so, but we have not heard that there’s been an understanding.  If one is reached, that would be positive.  Although, we shouldn’t be playing – Iran should not be playing brinkmanship each time these agreements get extended.  I’d simply say that in the absence of such an understanding, in the absence of the IAEA being able to monitor what Iran is doing, it will be that much more complicated to get back into the JCPOA, because we’re going to have to know what the baseline of their nuclear program is.  And if the IAEA is blind for a certain amount of time and we don’t know what that baseline is, it’s going to be much more difficult to find a way back into the deal.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Let’s go to the line of Jennifer Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And Jennifer, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, .  Thanks so much for doing this.  What are you telling the Iranians about guarantees that the U.S. won’t quit the deal in four years?  How are you assuaging their concerns on that?  And on the issue of the hostages, has there been any progress towards their release?  Is it still the case that their release is not a precondition for the U.S. re-entering the JCPOA?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Thanks.  So, I mean, there is no such thing as a guarantee, and I think Iran knows it and we know it.  We have no guarantee; they have no guarantee.  That’s the way the JCPOA is built, that if one side violated, the other side would – its remedy would be to take countermanding steps.  But what we do think is that the best guarantee is to get back into the deal and to implement it faithfully, and that’s – and we think that there’s a – that’s the best answer, because there is no such thing as a guarantee.</p>
<p>Secondly, on the question of the detainees, it’s the same thing as I said about the deal.  Because nothing is agreed until everything is agreed, because we don’t have a deal yet, I’m not going to speak about how close we are.  Yet, we’ve made progress.  We were engaged in indirect discussions with Iran about their release, but we’re not there yet, and until we’re there I don&#8217;t want to give false hopes to the families who’ve suffered too much already.  And as I’ve said in the past, it is a priority, and we are absolutely insistent that the four American citizens who are wrongfully detained be released.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  And let’s go the line of Arshad Mohammed.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And Arshad, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.  And Arshad, please check your mute button.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you, and sorry about mute.  Two things.  One, would you continue the negotiations if Iran fails to extend its agreement with the IAEA?  And secondly, you said this process will not be open indefinitely.  What happens if you cannot reach an agreement by August 3rd, the date on which the Raisi administration takes office?  Is that when the door closes?  Or is the door open?  It may be indefinite, but it could be open for months or even years?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Thanks.  And I know that both two good but difficult questions.  We still hope that Iran will extend its technical understanding with the IAEA or find – not prolong the understandings that currently exist.  As I said, it would be an issue of real concern if they didn’t.  I’m not going to speculate as to what impact it would have on the talks, but I think it is – we’ve already indicated clearly to Iran that it would be extremely complicated if they – a complicating factor if they did not find a way to continue the understandings with the IAEA.</p>
<p>On your second question, again, I’m not going to sit here and say there’s a deadline.  Obviously this will be a decision for the President and his national security team to take.  But when we’ve said – and others have said it – that this process is not going to be open forever, we mean it.  We – this is not something that we could go on indefinitely.  There’s – we’ve had serious discussions, and I don’t – as I’ve said, we’ve made progress, and the Iranians have been serious in the talks so far, but we do have differences.  And if we can’t bridge them in the foreseeable future, I think we’re going to have to regroup and figure out how we move ahead.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Let’s go to the line of Courtney McBride.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And Courtney, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  So assuming – I understand that you are loathe to talk about timelines, but how does the administration hope to get follow-on talks with President-elect Raisi?  And how do you – do you acknowledge that he would need to be removed from the sanctions list as part of a broader discussion in hope of a broader agreement with Iran?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  So, I mean, I’ll repeat what I said about the follow-on talks.  I think we couldn’t have been clearer about what our position is on that, that we think – we believe that it has to be a part of what – of the process that we’re discussing right now, and we’re in the middle of discussing the nature of what those talks could be.  We know what Iran’s position is, but that’s why one of their – these are one of many reasons that we are still engaged in the talks and why we haven’t concluded them yet.</p>
<p>And I’ll also add again that there are issues that Iran feels that need to be addressed which go beyond the four corners of the JCPOA, and the only way to address those is going to be by continuing conversations in some format with us, and so we believe that this is something that’s not just a U.S. interest.  It happens to also be an Iranian interest, although they’ll be a better judge of that.</p>
<p>And on the question of sanctions, I think National Security Advisor Sullivan addressed it the other day.  We’re not going to get into details of what we might do.  We’re going to look at what we – what sanctions relief we believe we need to take in order to be back in compliance with the JCPOA, and that’s what we’re going to be judging in terms of the steps that we’ll be prepared to take if – and I emphasize if we’re back in a deal.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Okay.  Let’s go to the line of Michel Ghandour.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And Michel, go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, thank you for doing this.  There are calls from the Congress to the administration to take the election of President Raisi as an opportunity for not joining or rejoining the JCPOA.  What’s your answer to that?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  My answer to that:  We’re not involved in negotiations because we trust, like, or have anything or share any values in common with our Iranian counterparts.  We’re doing it precisely because we have very deep concerns, very serious issues.  And so the fact that there is now a new president – or there will soon be a new president of Iran does not detract our core national security interest, which is to reach a deal that puts their nuclear program in a box and makes sure that we prevent them from acquiring a nuclear weapon.  The identity of the Iranian president doesn’t have an impact on that, core national security interests.  And I would add, again, as the National Security Advisor said, that we know that the president in the Iranian system is not the sole and not even the chief decision-maker.  It’s a leadership in which the supreme leader has the ultimate word, and that position, that person has not changed as a result of the Iranian elections.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Let’s go to the line of Laura Rosen.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And Laura, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  , as I understand, not all the other countries in the P4+1 agree there should be a follow-on deal.  Can you speak to that?  I mean, I think Russia especially has said they think the JCPOA is sufficient.  So does that affect something being in a document with Iran that would call for follow-on talks?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Our position is our position.  We’ve had many conversations with Russia, and I wouldn’t characterize &#8212;</p>
<p>(Break.)</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  I think somebody’s on this call.  I think I recognize their voice, but yeah, okay.  So I’m saying we know – we had many discussions with our Russian colleagues about this.  I’m not going to characterize their position.  I think many countries have agreed that they want more diplomacy with Iran to address a range of issues, including regional issues, and Russia has been at the – one of the parties that has put forward ideas for what that diplomacy could look like.  So I’m not sure that I would fully agree with how you put it, but there are differences of views, but our position is very clear – is that we’re going to need follow-on talks, discussions to strengthen the deal.</p>
<p>And again, we would make the point that this is not only something that we think would help us.  We do think that it would help – it would – it should be in Iran’s interest because they have issues that they’re going to want to bring to the table.  Of course, that – as I said, that’s going to be – they will have to make that assessment, but our position has been clear from the day we started these talks and very familiar to all the parties who are there, and they know that’s America’s position.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  We have time for just a couple more questions.  Let’s go to the line of Nadia Bilbassy.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And one moment.  Nadia, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you so much.  Thank you,  and , for doing this.</p>
<p>, you just said that nothing agreed until all agreed.  You have been – it’s been six sessions so far and you’re entering the seventh.  Can you just outline for us what exactly you agreed upon?  Is it just a framework, is it technical issues, is it more than that?</p>
<p>And second, I’m sure you have seen the statements coming from the (inaudible) office saying that you’re going to lift sanction on the supreme leader.  Do you see this as, like, a (inaudible)?  Is it a lie from the Iranian?  Is it propaganda trying to get you to where they want?  How do you see it?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  Thanks, Nadia.  So if I understood your question, I mean, when I say nothing’s agreed until everything is agreed, that’s precisely what I meant.  So there’s nothing.  It’s not like there’s a framework or – we are still negotiating every issue, whether it’s the scope of sanctions relief, the scope of the steps that Iran will take to come back into compliance with its nuclear obligations, the sequence – all of those are still being discussed, and so we don’t have like a provisional deal on anything.  We are still working through all the issues, and that includes the issues of sanctions that you mentioned.  We will have to see.</p>
<p>And again, I don’t want – I’m not going to negotiate in public, but at this point we need to continue negotiating to see whether we could reach a comprehensive package that will be satisfactory, and at this point we’re not there yet.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Let’s go to the line of Farhad Pouladi.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>And Farhad, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Yes, hi.  Do you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>Yes, we hear you.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>Yes, we can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Perfect.  So my question is in regard to the Israeli Government’s comments on the JCPOA, or the JCPOA resurrection talks in Vienna.  Prime Minister Netanyahu was staunchly against the deal, but the position has been actually transferred to the new government and they are still against the JCPOA.  I covered what comments came out of General Kochavi’s visit yesterday and today.  And also today, Prime Minister Bennett says that this regime – the one that no one should do business with.  How concerned are you that they may take any unilateral action, and what has the Biden administration been doing to persuade them not to do anything to jeopardize the talks?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>Thank you, Farhad.  That’s an important question.  I want to start by saying we – under the government of Prime Minister Netanyahu, we were having close consultations.  We know – we knew that they have and we know they had a different view about the JCPOA, but we are trying to talk to them to make sure that we were as aligned as possible given our common objective, which is to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon.  We had differences about the JCPOA.  We knew that, we recognized it, but we nonetheless were working closely with them.</p>
<p>And the same holds for the government of Prime Minister Bennett.  We already had some high-level contacts.  I think you all know that Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Lapid will be meeting in Rome on Sunday.  I don’t know the agenda, but I would be surprised if Iran did not figure in those conversations.  And again, we respect that they have a different point of view.  I think they respect ours and we are going to try to talk and be as transparent and as coordinated as possible so that the ultimate goal, which we share, is one that is pursued as effectively as possible.  And we expect to have extremely positive and productive discussions with the new Israeli Government and we look forward to as close coordination as possible.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Okay, thanks.  Just a couple more questions.  Let’s go to the line of Halley Toosi.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>One moment.  And Halley, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, thanks for doing this.  A couple questions.  When it comes to the follow-on agreements, does the United States want to include human rights as one of the issues that is negotiated along with ballistic missiles and support for terrorism and all that?</p>
<p>Secondly, you said that there are indirect talks on the hostages.  Can you tell us a little bit more about those discussions?  Like are you talking about a potential prisoner exchange, and is it totally on a separate track from the nuclear discussion?  Any information you can give on that.</p>
<p>And also lastly, what is the most surprising thing that’s happened in this process for you?  What’s something you just didn’t expect, but that’s come up?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:  </strong>Thanks.  So on the follow-on talks, listen, we know that there are a number of issues that – concerns that we have above and beyond the nuclear issue which is central.  There are lots of concerns.  Some of them will be negotiated in some formal way, others will be dealt with through other means.  So I’m not going to get into the details of what they will cover, but we – all of the issues you mentioned and that I mentioned are issues of real concern to this administration, but the format, the shape that those discussions or other diplomatic tools will take to address them I won’t get into.  But again, it doesn’t mean that we’re going to ignore any issue.  All of them will be pursued in one fashion or another.</p>
<p>On the detainee issue, they are separate.  These are separate conversations that are being held.  Obviously, we – we’re doing them more intensely when we are in Vienna because we could get communication to a third party more quickly, but they’re separate from the nuclear talks and, as I said, they are absolute priority.  Regardless of what happens with the JCPOA, we want our detainees, our citizens, wrongfully-held citizens back home as soon as possible.</p>
<p>Out of what’s been most surprising, I’m at a loss to say.  I mean, it is unusual to have these discussions in an indirect fashion.  I’ve said that many times before.  It is ripe for misunderstanding.  It’s ripe for prolonging the talks.  It’s not the most effective way to do it.  It means that we spend a lot of time in hotel rooms with our European and other colleagues and not with the party that we’re supposed to be negotiating with.  But by this point, we’ve gotten used to it, so we’ll make do.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  And I think we have time for one more question.  Let’s go to Arshad Mohammed.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And Arshad, your line is open.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Yeah, thanks for coming back to me.  Just to ask one specific question, do you have any idea now when the seventh round of talks will begin in Vienna?</p>
<p><strong>SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL:</strong>  No.  I mean, we assume that there is obviously consultations going on in Iran given – in Tehran given the election.  And when those consultations will have concluded, we will be notified, and then we’ll figure out when we meet again.  But at this point, I don’t have – I don’t have any plane reservations.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Okay, I think that’s our last question.  I just want to quickly thank our senior State Department official, .  Just as a reminder to everyone, this call today is on background, and so you can refer to our briefer as a senior State Department official.  With that, this briefing is ended and the embargo is lifted.  Have a good day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Venezuelan International Relations Commissioner Borges</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/readout-june-24-2021-deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-venezuelan-international-relations-commissioner-borges-the-below-is-attributable-to-spokesperson-ned-price-deputy-secretary-o/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 20:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=254870</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Venezuelan Interim Government International Relations Commissioner Julio Borges today in Washington, D.C.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Commissioner Borges emphasized the urgent need for time-bound, comprehensive Venezuelan-led negotiations to restore democracy, human rights, and the rule of the law in Venezuela through free and fair local, parliamentary, and presidential elections.  The Deputy Secretary also reaffirmed the United States will continue to coordinate with international partners and with Venezuelans to support efforts to address the humanitarian needs of the Venezuelan people.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Venezuelan Interim Government International Relations Commissioner Julio Borges today in Washington, D.C.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Commissioner Borges emphasized the urgent need for time-bound, comprehensive Venezuelan-led negotiations to restore democracy, human rights, and the rule of the law in Venezuela through free and fair local, parliamentary, and presidential elections.  The Deputy Secretary also reaffirmed the United States will continue to coordinate with international partners and with Venezuelans to support efforts to address the humanitarian needs of the Venezuelan people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at the Launch of the U.S.-Germany Dialogue on Holocaust Issues with German Foreign Minister Heiko Maas</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-the-launch-of-the-u-s-germany-dialogue-on-holocaust-issues-with-german-foreign-minister-heiko-maas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 20:01:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=254809</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Berlin, Germany</p>
<p>Memorial to the Murdered Jews of Europe</p>
<p><strong>MR NEUMARKER:</strong>  (In German.)  Dear Mr. Secretary of State of the United States of America.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) So everyone, I’d like to welcome you all here, and Minister Maas, (inaudible), also the vice president of the German association of Sinti and Roma in Germany, Mr. Romani Rose.</p>
<p>(In German.)</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) And I am the head and the chairperson of the Memorial to the Murdered Jews of Europe.  I’d like to hand over now to the moderator, Ms. Sauerbrey.</p>
<p><strong>MS SAUERBREY:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you, ladies and gentlemen, and most importantly, also survivors.  And ladies and gentlemen, the memory of the Holocaust, to research it and also to then – also give this on to new generations this year in the U.S. and Germany.  We’ll then now sign a letter of intent on this.</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony Blinken will speak to us.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good morning.  Foreign Minister Maas, Heiko, thank you for your partnership in launching what will be a historic dialogue.</p>
<p>Eighty years ago this week, Nazi forces invaded the Soviet-occupied city of Bialystok, Poland.  They pulled Jews from their homes, beat them, executed many on the spot.  Some forced older Jewish men to dance, and if they didn’t like the performance, set their beards on fire.</p>
<p>Then the Nazis herded more than 700 Jews into Bialystok’s synagogue and set it ablaze.</p>
<p>What happened in Bialystok was not isolated.  The barbarism was systematic.</p>
<p>By launching the U.S-Germany Dialogue on the Holocaust, we are helping to ensure that current and future generations learn about the Holocaust and also learn from it.</p>
<p>Together, we honor those who were killed.  They were not indistinct numbers, even if a number is seared in the minds of many of us.  But they were not just numbers.  They were not, as their killers saw them, indistinct, inhuman.  They were family members, they were friends, mothers, fathers, daughters, sisters, loved ones, human beings.</p>
<p>We honor the survivors who share their stories with enormous courage and determination, including those here today: Margot Friedlander, Franz Michalski, Peter Johan Gardosch.  You honor us with your presence, you honor us with your testimony, you honor us with your memory.</p>
<p>We study the past so that we can understand the Holocaust as more than the final act of exterminating six million Jews as well as Roma and Sinti, Slavs, disabled persons, LGBTQ individuals, and many others.  It was the culmination of countless individual steps designed to vilify and dehumanize people.</p>
<p>So we learned, for example, that as early as 1933, Jews were purged from Germany’s civil service, Jewish businesses boycotted, books by Jewish authors banned and burned in a massive pyre not very far from where we stand today.</p>
<p>Like the path through this memorial, the Shoah was not a sharp fall, but a gradual descent into darkness.  As survivor Primo Levi wrote, “To sink is the easiest of matters…like streams that run down to the sea.”</p>
<p>That understanding is particularly urgent today as survivors pass from us and those who deny the Holocaust are getting louder and finding insidious new ways to spread their lies.</p>
<p>A recent study found that during the pandemic, anti-Semitic content online increased seven-fold in French, thirteen-fold in German.</p>
<p>In recent months, a swastika was carved onto the door of a synagogue in America, museums dedicated to the Holocaust were defaced.</p>
<p>Today, as in the past, Holocaust denial and other forms of anti-Semitism often go hand-in-hand with homophobia, xenophobia, racism, other hatred.  It’s also a rallying cry for those who seek to tear down our democracies, which we’ve seen in both our countries is often a precursor to violence.</p>
<p>That’s why we have to find innovative ways to bring the history of the Holocaust to life not only to understand the past, but also to guide our present and to shape our future.</p>
<p>Together with the United States Holocaust Museum – Memorial Museum and the German Foundation for the Murdered Jews of Europe, our governments will strengthen Holocaust education.  We’ll counter Holocaust denial and distortion.  We’ll ensure that public servants, teachers, young people like the young leaders here today understand these issues in depth and feel a responsibility to stop atrocities wherever they occur.</p>
<p>We will build on decades of serious, remarkable work by Germany to grapple with the darkest past of its history, to honor all the victims of the Holocaust, to combat anti-Semitism, to foster a culture of remembrance here and around the world, including through leadership in the International Holocaust Remembrance Alliance.  This work has become a defining part of our transatlantic relationship and of shoring up our democracies.</p>
<p>For just as dissent is incremental, so is the work of building up principles and practices that can make real the promise of “Never again,” like the steady march ascending from the depths of this memorial.</p>
<p>My late stepfather Samuel Pisar was 12 years old when the Nazis invaded his home of Bialystok, Poland.  A week later, they lined up hundreds of Jewish men and boys, including his cousins Isaac, Grisha, Frol, and mowed them down.</p>
<p>Days later, he and his family were forced to move to Bialystok’s newly walled-off ghetto.  His father David was disappeared first, then his uncle, and then his grandmother, and then he was separated from his mother Helaina, his little sister Freida, and sent to Treblinka, later to Majdanek, to Auschwitz, to Dachau.</p>
<p>When he was liberated by American soldiers in 1945, he was the only surviving member of his family.</p>
<p>During the Holocaust, ghettos like the one in Bialoystok were in the heart of cities just like this memorial.  That meant that beyond the Nazis, everyone in those cities knew that Jews lived there.  They knew the trains were leaving, packed with people day after day.  The evil was visible, but most chose to look away, to do nothing.</p>
<p>This dialogue will help us remember all that can be lost, but also help us to see all that we can save if we choose – if we choose to stand up rather than stand by.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>MS SAUERBREY:</strong>  Thank you very much, Excellency, for these (inaudible) words.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) The German foreign minister now has the floor.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MAAS:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Survivors, ladies and gentlemen, my relationship with this nation’s poignant, painful, and powerful history is hazy.  I will never forget how much I loved the medieval city of Nuremburg, a city that was also the birthplace of the horrifying Nazi racial laws.  I cried privately at the Memorial to the Murdered Jews of Europe, and I rejoiced after the fact in Germany’s World Cup victory.</p>
<p>The U.S. student Avi Colonomos wrote these words in 2014 when he was 20 years old.  He had come to Berlin with a transatlantic program, Germany Close Up, along with other young Jewish people to learn more about today’s Germany.  What Avi Colonomos describes is the inner conflict that goes hand-in-hand with remembrance.  We are conflicted between tears and joy, conflicted in the face of this history that pains and divides us, just as it moves and unites us in our shared humanity.  And yet understanding where we come from is, despite the sins of inner conflict, the best compass to determine which direction we want to go in.  To borrow the words  of James Baldwin writing in <em>The New York Times</em> in 1962, and I quote, “Not everything that is faced can be changed, but nothing can be changed until it is faced.”</p>
<p>The 2,710 concrete stelae that make up the Memorial to the Murdered Jews of Europe behind me show us where we Germans come from and what we are responsible for.  The history of murder, horror, and suffering inflicted upon millions of people, incomparable, incontrovertible in its manmade monstrosity here between these stelae, created by the great U.S. architect Peter Eisenman, feelings of profound unease, solitude, grief, responsibility become almost palpable.  Yes, remembrance can be painful.  Yes, remembrance is a test of our mettle and it has to be painful.</p>
<p>And yet we stand here today, side by side, Americans and Germans, Jews, Muslims, Christians and Atheists united in shared remembrance, united by our belief in values such as freedom, democracy, and tolerance, united too in our determination to build a better future on this foundation of values.  That is what Europe is based on and that is what our transatlantic friendship is based on.</p>
<p>Dear Tony, I know how much your family’s personal experiences of the Holocaust influence what you do every day.  You’ve just shared this with us.  On your first day in office as Secretary of State, you said, and I quote, “I remember that the nation’s power isn’t measured only by the size of its military and economy, but by the moral choices it makes,” end of quote.  And the field of stelae behind us is proof of this statement cast in concrete.  America’s power, Germany’s and Europe’s power does not come from glorifying history or glossing over the wrong turns of the past, of which none led into such a terrible abyss as did the Holocaust.</p>
<p>Our strength lies in accepting the burden of historical responsibility unconditionally without drawing a final line.  Our strength lies in joining forces as we search for the best path forward and to do so together, ideally.</p>
<p>And so I am delighted, Dear Tony, that we’re here today in this unique place in the country of the perpetrators to launch a dialogue on Holocaust issues between the United States and Germany.  One of our most pressing tasks will be to prepare our culture of remembrance for changing times.  The memorial foundation with its director, Dr. Uwe Neumarker and the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum do outstanding work here every day.  The American Jewish Committee and its director David Harris as well as the Leo Baeck Institute with William Weitzer are also working with us for a lively culture of remembrance.</p>
<p>And I’m grateful for these approaches for their work because I believe that future generations will no longer be able to benefit from personal encounters with contemporary witnesses.  What a great loss.  But at the same time, what a great undertaking for us to find new forms of remembrance which do not allow the stories of individuals to fade from our consciousness.  We owe this to the victims and the survivors, and we’re delighted and honored – dear Margot Friedlander; Mr. Gardosch, dear Peter; and Franz Michalski – that you are with us today.  And we owe it to our children and grandchildren who we want to prevent as far as we can from repeating the errors of the past.</p>
<p>In recent years, we have seen anti-Semitism and racism eating into our societies on both sides of the Atlantic.  Just think of the yellow star badges seen at demonstrations against COVID measures, of the torrent of anti-Semitic conspiracy theories on the internet, of the attacks on synagogues and on Jewish people living in our countries, of the rioters in front of the Bundestag, or the rampaging mob in the U.S. Capitol.  The U.S. philosopher, Susan Neiman, president of the Einstein Forum in Potsdam and one of the wisest transatlantic voices in this country gave us a piece of advice some years ago that I believe to be very sage, namely that we must refuse to give evil – and racism and anti-Semitism are nothing other than that – any justification and any weight.  Only through this refusal and not through inaction, silence, or relativization can we subdue the forces that seek to divide our societies.</p>
<p>What we are doing here today will help.  Of course, remembrance is no panacea.  People in societies cannot make peace with their past as easily as that.  It remains a test, a source of inner conflict.  But sharing in remembrance with friends, as we are doing here today, unites us as we face up to this conflict.  And it strengthens us, and above all it strengthens our societies for the future.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>SAUERBREY:</strong>(Via interpreter) Thank you, Minister.  We now turn to the signing of the letter of intent.</li>
</ol>
<p>(The letter of intent is signed.)</p>
<p>And we have two more people to address us now.  First Ms. Margot Friedlander.  She was born in Berlin.  She survived the Holocaust in a number of hiding places until being deported in 1944 to Theresienstadt.  Her father, her mother, her brother, and many other relatives of her were murdered.  Margot Friedlander immigrated to the United States with her husband in 1946 and in 2010 she returned permanently to Berlin.  Ms. Friedlander, thank you for addressing us today.</p>
<p><strong>MS FRIEDLANDER:  </strong>I will tell you a little bit of my experiences.  In mid-January 1943, at about 2:00 p.m., I was on my way home from the factory where I was working (inaudible).  When I approached the house, I noticed a man entering the house.  I did not know him.  Is he waiting for someone?  To be careful, I covered my Jewish star before I was leaving – our apartment door was – happened for him, it is waiting.  I pass him coolly, walk up another floor, and ring the bell of Christian neighbors.  I hardly knew, hoping that they will be home.</p>
<p>I hear steps.  The doors open and the neighbors asked me quietly into the house.  On her face, I see stress, and I feel right away that something has happened.  She asked me into her living room; we both sit down, and she’s – she is telling me time, a few hours ago, she heard noise at the house.  “Open up,” banging on the door, then the clatter at the stairway, and she went to the window.  She saw them come out and rudely pushed them into the police car.  “Whom?” do I ask the neighbor.  “Some people I did not know?”  “The lady, Mrs. Meissner, who also lives in the apartment, and a boy.”</p>
<p>“My brother, Ralph; my mother?”  She tells me my mother was not there.  But one hour after she came home, she found the door locked and (inaudible).  I told her all –  “Where is she now?”  My mother was not waiting for me.  But she left a message with neighbors.  “Tell my daughter, if you should see her, I am going to the police.  I’m going with Ralph, wherever that will be.  Try to make your life.”  With her words, in my mind, I was able to find help and went underground into hiding.</p>
<p>German gentile people I have never seen before, humans, people with character and courage, helped me, who did not look away, but to do something that could have cost their head.  For 15 months, I was hiding with different people.  But in April 1944, my look – my luck ran out.  I was snitched and saw some good fortune.  I was deported to Theresienstadt, where again I was lucky to be able to work in a factory producing the splitting of glimmer that was needed for war effort.  That probably saved me from deportation from Theresienstadt to Auschwitz.  That was the fate of hundred thousands.</p>
<p>In early February 1945, a transport arrived, and with it came Adolf Friedlander.  They came from a special work arrangement near Frankfurt/Oder and because the Russians came closer, they were sent back to Theresienstadt.  I knew Adolf Friedlander years ago in Berlin.  It was so good to meet someone you had known in past life.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) I’ve lost track of where I am, I’m afraid.</p>
<p>(In English) Together, we experience the arrival of a transport in late February, about 10 days before liberation.  I got the assignment to help at the arrival of the train.  As the cattle car door was opened, the people, who were no more human – the masses fell out and were pushed out.  Many were already dead.  Men only, but indistinguishable looking – in striped-looking things like pajamas, but were already tatters.  They wear before Auschwitz was liberated on January 27, 1945, put on the death march for weeks, and the left ones, humans, were put on the cattle cars that now arrived in Theresienstadt, the one camp not liberated at the time.  At the moment I was seeing the masses, I realized I will not ever see my mother and brother again.</p>
<p>Adolf and I experienced the liberation together on the 8th of May, 1945, as, at first, the people who treated us as – left.  The Swiss International Cross came and the Red Cross flag was flying instead of the <em>Hakenkreuz</em>.  About 10 days later, they handed Theresienstadt over to the Russians.  That was on the 8th of May.</p>
<p>Weeks later, sitting on a bench talking to Adolf, he asked me if I could think of starting a life together with him in America, where his sister was living.  We got married on the 28th of June in Theresienstadt, just a day before the last rabbi left Theresienstadt.  One day after our marriage, a cable from his sister arrived, telling him how happy she is that he is alive and expect him in USA.</p>
<p>We left Theresienstadt in early July 1945 and spent one year in a DP camp in Germany before we could leave.  We arrived in July 28th in America.  My husband passed away in December 1997, after almost 53 years of a very special marriage.  We both had the same experience.  We both knew how very special life is.</p>
<p>A few months after my husband had passed away, I was asked to join the senior club of the 92nd Street Y, where my husband was in a leading position for 28 years.  There, many courses were offered, and after more than two years, a writing course started.  I was asked to join.  I was hesitant, but I did.  One night after sleep did not come, the memories, the many memories – I took paper and pen into the bed and started at last to tell my story.</p>
<p>For more than one year, for every course, I did tell the class one more experience, realizing right at the first meeting how very little they knew of these years, almost into my unimaginable happenings what was taking place under the Nazi regime, what humans did, (inaudible).</p>
<p>After living for 57 years in USA, I went for the first time in 2003 to Berlin where I was born and for a visit, and the possibility of planning to make a film, a documentary.  A filmmaker had heard about my story.  He did.  The film was shown in 2005 in Berlin at Jewish Film Festival.  After that, my life took a different turn, because I was asked to write something in German. Always thinking that for 70 years, I live with the messages my mother left for me, “Try to make your life,” I started to write my book.  It was published in Germany by Rowohlt.  It came out in (inaudible) with the title of the words my mother left for me, <em>Try To Make Your Life</em>.  In German, <em>Versuche, dein Leben zu machen</em>.</p>
<p>Right now, I came very often to Berlin because right at the start, I was asked to give readings in schools, bookstores, but many different places.  I talked – well, in cities in Germany, always finding that the students are most attentive, interested to talk to me, to ask questions, and want to know more about what my life is now after much (inaudible) experiences.  In 2009, I got surprise in German for the book as the best autobiography.  In July of 2009, I came to Berlin and stayed for seven months, having such wonderful experiences, meeting fine people.</p>
<p>People thank me for doing what now became my mission.  I often give two or three readings a week, again traveling to many cities.  I was reading always for one hour very special pages from the book, and telling to whom I spoke what I want them to do, what I do, because we will not be on with a life many – much longer, and it is for them that it should never happen again, that I don’t want anyone to experience what has been done to the 5 million Jews and millions of other innocent humans.</p>
<p>I tell them that there is no Christian, Jewish, or Muslim blood – that there’s only human blood.  We are all the same, that people did it because they did not respect humans.  Please, be a human being.</p>
<p>In 2010 I did return to Berlin for good, and never did I regret it for one moment.  And here I am and gold still – it’s now almost hundred years to talk to people.  It is for you.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>MS SAUERBREY:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you, Ms. Friedlander, for your words, for everything you have done for Holocaust remembrance and for everything you continue to do.  Margo Wieseler, 25 years old, will speak to us now.  She served as a volunteer at the Illinois Holocaust Museum and Education Center in Chicago, Illinois, Skokie.</p>
<p><strong>MS WIESELER:</strong>  Good morning.  Again, I would just really like to thank Ms. Friedlander.  Your words really shook me in a way I didn’t even expect, although I expected it to be emotional, but yeah.  So thank you very much, and your words of wisdom and passion are truly an inspiring call to action for my generation.</p>
<p>I also want to thank Secretary Blinken and Secretary Maas for highlighting innovative ways to commemorate the Holocaust.  Initiatives to preserve the voices of our survivors are essential to prevent my generation from choosing the ease of forgetting over the pain or the shame of remembering.  And sometimes standard high-school-level history education can sadly reinforce this tendency, as it can make the Holocaust feel unpersonal and much more distant than it is.</p>
<p>I myself only recently really started confronting my family history and involvement when I began to prepare for my year abroad with <em>Aktion Suhnezeichen Friedensdienste</em>.  <em>Aktion Suhnezeichen</em> is a German NGO aiding reconciliation between victims of Nazi persecution and young Germans today.  And with the help of them, I had the unique opportunity and great privilege to spend a year volunteering at the Illinois Holocaust Museum and Education Center, a world-leading institution in the field of digitalized Holocaust remembrance in Chicago.</p>
<p>So – and I did find my motivation for serving in the museum in my family history.  My great grandfather was a member of the Reichstag, appointed by the Nazi party.  I was, still am, and will always be ashamed of this piece of my family’s history, and I was especially anxious to share this with the survivors and their families.  They had every reason to be dismissive, hurt, or even hostile towards me, but to my great relief their response was full of love, understanding, and even curiosity towards me and my motivations.</p>
<p>This ability to distinguish between my generation and our ancestors left a lasting impression on me.  I was especially amazed by Fritzie Fritzshall, the museum’s longtime president and a teenage survivor of Auschwitz-Birkenau, who heavily accepted an invitation to dinner from me and a friend.  And the cuisine would be German, obviously.</p>
<p>In devastating news, Fritzie sadly died last weekend, leaving another hole that will never be filled.  However, her impressing ability to disband black-and-white thinking in place of a more nuanced approach is, I think, something I learned from and everybody else can do.</p>
<p>My generation, young as we are, has been fortunate enough to hear the stories of the Holocaust directly from survivors, reminding us just how recent these atrocities truly were.  Because they were – they did happen before our lifetimes.  With each passing day, preserving and retelling these lessons gets more important, lest we begin to distance ourselves and forget the lessons learned.</p>
<p>My year with <em>Aktion Suhnezeichen </em>has forever changed me, and I can confidently say that I understand the importance of combating anti-Semitism and using that voice to fight for a free and fair society better than before.  If young people like me sincerely want to make “Never again” or “<em>Nie wieder</em>” a reality, we must never stop openly building bridges between the most painful hours of the past, our lives today, and the future we wish to see.</p>
<p>Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>MS SAUERBREY:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you, Ms. Wieseler.  Ladies and gentlemen, the foreign ministers will now place a wreath on the Memorial to the Murdered Jews in Europe, and will then speak to the survivors who are with us today: Ms. Margot Friedlander, Peter Gardosch, and Franz Michalski.  Ms. Wieseler and a number of Anne Frank ambassadors are also here, peer guides and volunteers of the Anne Frank Center in Berlin.  Afterwards, this ceremony is concluded.  And I would like to use this opportunity to thank you on behalf of the foreign office and the U.S. Department of State for having come here.  Have a safe journey home.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Berlin, Germany</p>
<p>Memorial to the Murdered Jews of Europe</p>
<p><strong>MR NEUMARKER:</strong>  (In German.)  Dear Mr. Secretary of State of the United States of America.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) So everyone, I’d like to welcome you all here, and Minister Maas, (inaudible), also the vice president of the German association of Sinti and Roma in Germany, Mr. Romani Rose.</p>
<p>(In German.)</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) And I am the head and the chairperson of the Memorial to the Murdered Jews of Europe.  I’d like to hand over now to the moderator, Ms. Sauerbrey.</p>
<p><strong>MS SAUERBREY:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you, ladies and gentlemen, and most importantly, also survivors.  And ladies and gentlemen, the memory of the Holocaust, to research it and also to then – also give this on to new generations this year in the U.S. and Germany.  We’ll then now sign a letter of intent on this.</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony Blinken will speak to us.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good morning.  Foreign Minister Maas, Heiko, thank you for your partnership in launching what will be a historic dialogue.</p>
<p>Eighty years ago this week, Nazi forces invaded the Soviet-occupied city of Bialystok, Poland.  They pulled Jews from their homes, beat them, executed many on the spot.  Some forced older Jewish men to dance, and if they didn’t like the performance, set their beards on fire.</p>
<p>Then the Nazis herded more than 700 Jews into Bialystok’s synagogue and set it ablaze.</p>
<p>What happened in Bialystok was not isolated.  The barbarism was systematic.</p>
<p>By launching the U.S-Germany Dialogue on the Holocaust, we are helping to ensure that current and future generations learn about the Holocaust and also learn from it.</p>
<p>Together, we honor those who were killed.  They were not indistinct numbers, even if a number is seared in the minds of many of us.  But they were not just numbers.  They were not, as their killers saw them, indistinct, inhuman.  They were family members, they were friends, mothers, fathers, daughters, sisters, loved ones, human beings.</p>
<p>We honor the survivors who share their stories with enormous courage and determination, including those here today: Margot Friedlander, Franz Michalski, Peter Johan Gardosch.  You honor us with your presence, you honor us with your testimony, you honor us with your memory.</p>
<p>We study the past so that we can understand the Holocaust as more than the final act of exterminating six million Jews as well as Roma and Sinti, Slavs, disabled persons, LGBTQ individuals, and many others.  It was the culmination of countless individual steps designed to vilify and dehumanize people.</p>
<p>So we learned, for example, that as early as 1933, Jews were purged from Germany’s civil service, Jewish businesses boycotted, books by Jewish authors banned and burned in a massive pyre not very far from where we stand today.</p>
<p>Like the path through this memorial, the Shoah was not a sharp fall, but a gradual descent into darkness.  As survivor Primo Levi wrote, “To sink is the easiest of matters…like streams that run down to the sea.”</p>
<p>That understanding is particularly urgent today as survivors pass from us and those who deny the Holocaust are getting louder and finding insidious new ways to spread their lies.</p>
<p>A recent study found that during the pandemic, anti-Semitic content online increased seven-fold in French, thirteen-fold in German.</p>
<p>In recent months, a swastika was carved onto the door of a synagogue in America, museums dedicated to the Holocaust were defaced.</p>
<p>Today, as in the past, Holocaust denial and other forms of anti-Semitism often go hand-in-hand with homophobia, xenophobia, racism, other hatred.  It’s also a rallying cry for those who seek to tear down our democracies, which we’ve seen in both our countries is often a precursor to violence.</p>
<p>That’s why we have to find innovative ways to bring the history of the Holocaust to life not only to understand the past, but also to guide our present and to shape our future.</p>
<p>Together with the United States Holocaust Museum – Memorial Museum and the German Foundation for the Murdered Jews of Europe, our governments will strengthen Holocaust education.  We’ll counter Holocaust denial and distortion.  We’ll ensure that public servants, teachers, young people like the young leaders here today understand these issues in depth and feel a responsibility to stop atrocities wherever they occur.</p>
<p>We will build on decades of serious, remarkable work by Germany to grapple with the darkest past of its history, to honor all the victims of the Holocaust, to combat anti-Semitism, to foster a culture of remembrance here and around the world, including through leadership in the International Holocaust Remembrance Alliance.  This work has become a defining part of our transatlantic relationship and of shoring up our democracies.</p>
<p>For just as dissent is incremental, so is the work of building up principles and practices that can make real the promise of “Never again,” like the steady march ascending from the depths of this memorial.</p>
<p>My late stepfather Samuel Pisar was 12 years old when the Nazis invaded his home of Bialystok, Poland.  A week later, they lined up hundreds of Jewish men and boys, including his cousins Isaac, Grisha, Frol, and mowed them down.</p>
<p>Days later, he and his family were forced to move to Bialystok’s newly walled-off ghetto.  His father David was disappeared first, then his uncle, and then his grandmother, and then he was separated from his mother Helaina, his little sister Freida, and sent to Treblinka, later to Majdanek, to Auschwitz, to Dachau.</p>
<p>When he was liberated by American soldiers in 1945, he was the only surviving member of his family.</p>
<p>During the Holocaust, ghettos like the one in Bialoystok were in the heart of cities just like this memorial.  That meant that beyond the Nazis, everyone in those cities knew that Jews lived there.  They knew the trains were leaving, packed with people day after day.  The evil was visible, but most chose to look away, to do nothing.</p>
<p>This dialogue will help us remember all that can be lost, but also help us to see all that we can save if we choose – if we choose to stand up rather than stand by.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>MS SAUERBREY:</strong>  Thank you very much, Excellency, for these (inaudible) words.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) The German foreign minister now has the floor.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER MAAS:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Survivors, ladies and gentlemen, my relationship with this nation’s poignant, painful, and powerful history is hazy.  I will never forget how much I loved the medieval city of Nuremburg, a city that was also the birthplace of the horrifying Nazi racial laws.  I cried privately at the Memorial to the Murdered Jews of Europe, and I rejoiced after the fact in Germany’s World Cup victory.</p>
<p>The U.S. student Avi Colonomos wrote these words in 2014 when he was 20 years old.  He had come to Berlin with a transatlantic program, Germany Close Up, along with other young Jewish people to learn more about today’s Germany.  What Avi Colonomos describes is the inner conflict that goes hand-in-hand with remembrance.  We are conflicted between tears and joy, conflicted in the face of this history that pains and divides us, just as it moves and unites us in our shared humanity.  And yet understanding where we come from is, despite the sins of inner conflict, the best compass to determine which direction we want to go in.  To borrow the words  of James Baldwin writing in <em>The New York Times</em> in 1962, and I quote, “Not everything that is faced can be changed, but nothing can be changed until it is faced.”</p>
<p>The 2,710 concrete stelae that make up the Memorial to the Murdered Jews of Europe behind me show us where we Germans come from and what we are responsible for.  The history of murder, horror, and suffering inflicted upon millions of people, incomparable, incontrovertible in its manmade monstrosity here between these stelae, created by the great U.S. architect Peter Eisenman, feelings of profound unease, solitude, grief, responsibility become almost palpable.  Yes, remembrance can be painful.  Yes, remembrance is a test of our mettle and it has to be painful.</p>
<p>And yet we stand here today, side by side, Americans and Germans, Jews, Muslims, Christians and Atheists united in shared remembrance, united by our belief in values such as freedom, democracy, and tolerance, united too in our determination to build a better future on this foundation of values.  That is what Europe is based on and that is what our transatlantic friendship is based on.</p>
<p>Dear Tony, I know how much your family’s personal experiences of the Holocaust influence what you do every day.  You’ve just shared this with us.  On your first day in office as Secretary of State, you said, and I quote, “I remember that the nation’s power isn’t measured only by the size of its military and economy, but by the moral choices it makes,” end of quote.  And the field of stelae behind us is proof of this statement cast in concrete.  America’s power, Germany’s and Europe’s power does not come from glorifying history or glossing over the wrong turns of the past, of which none led into such a terrible abyss as did the Holocaust.</p>
<p>Our strength lies in accepting the burden of historical responsibility unconditionally without drawing a final line.  Our strength lies in joining forces as we search for the best path forward and to do so together, ideally.</p>
<p>And so I am delighted, Dear Tony, that we’re here today in this unique place in the country of the perpetrators to launch a dialogue on Holocaust issues between the United States and Germany.  One of our most pressing tasks will be to prepare our culture of remembrance for changing times.  The memorial foundation with its director, Dr. Uwe Neumarker and the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum do outstanding work here every day.  The American Jewish Committee and its director David Harris as well as the Leo Baeck Institute with William Weitzer are also working with us for a lively culture of remembrance.</p>
<p>And I’m grateful for these approaches for their work because I believe that future generations will no longer be able to benefit from personal encounters with contemporary witnesses.  What a great loss.  But at the same time, what a great undertaking for us to find new forms of remembrance which do not allow the stories of individuals to fade from our consciousness.  We owe this to the victims and the survivors, and we’re delighted and honored – dear Margot Friedlander; Mr. Gardosch, dear Peter; and Franz Michalski – that you are with us today.  And we owe it to our children and grandchildren who we want to prevent as far as we can from repeating the errors of the past.</p>
<p>In recent years, we have seen anti-Semitism and racism eating into our societies on both sides of the Atlantic.  Just think of the yellow star badges seen at demonstrations against COVID measures, of the torrent of anti-Semitic conspiracy theories on the internet, of the attacks on synagogues and on Jewish people living in our countries, of the rioters in front of the Bundestag, or the rampaging mob in the U.S. Capitol.  The U.S. philosopher, Susan Neiman, president of the Einstein Forum in Potsdam and one of the wisest transatlantic voices in this country gave us a piece of advice some years ago that I believe to be very sage, namely that we must refuse to give evil – and racism and anti-Semitism are nothing other than that – any justification and any weight.  Only through this refusal and not through inaction, silence, or relativization can we subdue the forces that seek to divide our societies.</p>
<p>What we are doing here today will help.  Of course, remembrance is no panacea.  People in societies cannot make peace with their past as easily as that.  It remains a test, a source of inner conflict.  But sharing in remembrance with friends, as we are doing here today, unites us as we face up to this conflict.  And it strengthens us, and above all it strengthens our societies for the future.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>SAUERBREY:</strong>(Via interpreter) Thank you, Minister.  We now turn to the signing of the letter of intent.</li>
</ol>
<p>(The letter of intent is signed.)</p>
<p>And we have two more people to address us now.  First Ms. Margot Friedlander.  She was born in Berlin.  She survived the Holocaust in a number of hiding places until being deported in 1944 to Theresienstadt.  Her father, her mother, her brother, and many other relatives of her were murdered.  Margot Friedlander immigrated to the United States with her husband in 1946 and in 2010 she returned permanently to Berlin.  Ms. Friedlander, thank you for addressing us today.</p>
<p><strong>MS FRIEDLANDER:  </strong>I will tell you a little bit of my experiences.  In mid-January 1943, at about 2:00 p.m., I was on my way home from the factory where I was working (inaudible).  When I approached the house, I noticed a man entering the house.  I did not know him.  Is he waiting for someone?  To be careful, I covered my Jewish star before I was leaving – our apartment door was – happened for him, it is waiting.  I pass him coolly, walk up another floor, and ring the bell of Christian neighbors.  I hardly knew, hoping that they will be home.</p>
<p>I hear steps.  The doors open and the neighbors asked me quietly into the house.  On her face, I see stress, and I feel right away that something has happened.  She asked me into her living room; we both sit down, and she’s – she is telling me time, a few hours ago, she heard noise at the house.  “Open up,” banging on the door, then the clatter at the stairway, and she went to the window.  She saw them come out and rudely pushed them into the police car.  “Whom?” do I ask the neighbor.  “Some people I did not know?”  “The lady, Mrs. Meissner, who also lives in the apartment, and a boy.”</p>
<p>“My brother, Ralph; my mother?”  She tells me my mother was not there.  But one hour after she came home, she found the door locked and (inaudible).  I told her all –  “Where is she now?”  My mother was not waiting for me.  But she left a message with neighbors.  “Tell my daughter, if you should see her, I am going to the police.  I’m going with Ralph, wherever that will be.  Try to make your life.”  With her words, in my mind, I was able to find help and went underground into hiding.</p>
<p>German gentile people I have never seen before, humans, people with character and courage, helped me, who did not look away, but to do something that could have cost their head.  For 15 months, I was hiding with different people.  But in April 1944, my look – my luck ran out.  I was snitched and saw some good fortune.  I was deported to Theresienstadt, where again I was lucky to be able to work in a factory producing the splitting of glimmer that was needed for war effort.  That probably saved me from deportation from Theresienstadt to Auschwitz.  That was the fate of hundred thousands.</p>
<p>In early February 1945, a transport arrived, and with it came Adolf Friedlander.  They came from a special work arrangement near Frankfurt/Oder and because the Russians came closer, they were sent back to Theresienstadt.  I knew Adolf Friedlander years ago in Berlin.  It was so good to meet someone you had known in past life.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) I’ve lost track of where I am, I’m afraid.</p>
<p>(In English) Together, we experience the arrival of a transport in late February, about 10 days before liberation.  I got the assignment to help at the arrival of the train.  As the cattle car door was opened, the people, who were no more human – the masses fell out and were pushed out.  Many were already dead.  Men only, but indistinguishable looking – in striped-looking things like pajamas, but were already tatters.  They wear before Auschwitz was liberated on January 27, 1945, put on the death march for weeks, and the left ones, humans, were put on the cattle cars that now arrived in Theresienstadt, the one camp not liberated at the time.  At the moment I was seeing the masses, I realized I will not ever see my mother and brother again.</p>
<p>Adolf and I experienced the liberation together on the 8th of May, 1945, as, at first, the people who treated us as – left.  The Swiss International Cross came and the Red Cross flag was flying instead of the <em>Hakenkreuz</em>.  About 10 days later, they handed Theresienstadt over to the Russians.  That was on the 8th of May.</p>
<p>Weeks later, sitting on a bench talking to Adolf, he asked me if I could think of starting a life together with him in America, where his sister was living.  We got married on the 28th of June in Theresienstadt, just a day before the last rabbi left Theresienstadt.  One day after our marriage, a cable from his sister arrived, telling him how happy she is that he is alive and expect him in USA.</p>
<p>We left Theresienstadt in early July 1945 and spent one year in a DP camp in Germany before we could leave.  We arrived in July 28th in America.  My husband passed away in December 1997, after almost 53 years of a very special marriage.  We both had the same experience.  We both knew how very special life is.</p>
<p>A few months after my husband had passed away, I was asked to join the senior club of the 92nd Street Y, where my husband was in a leading position for 28 years.  There, many courses were offered, and after more than two years, a writing course started.  I was asked to join.  I was hesitant, but I did.  One night after sleep did not come, the memories, the many memories – I took paper and pen into the bed and started at last to tell my story.</p>
<p>For more than one year, for every course, I did tell the class one more experience, realizing right at the first meeting how very little they knew of these years, almost into my unimaginable happenings what was taking place under the Nazi regime, what humans did, (inaudible).</p>
<p>After living for 57 years in USA, I went for the first time in 2003 to Berlin where I was born and for a visit, and the possibility of planning to make a film, a documentary.  A filmmaker had heard about my story.  He did.  The film was shown in 2005 in Berlin at Jewish Film Festival.  After that, my life took a different turn, because I was asked to write something in German. Always thinking that for 70 years, I live with the messages my mother left for me, “Try to make your life,” I started to write my book.  It was published in Germany by Rowohlt.  It came out in (inaudible) with the title of the words my mother left for me, <em>Try To Make Your Life</em>.  In German, <em>Versuche, dein Leben zu machen</em>.</p>
<p>Right now, I came very often to Berlin because right at the start, I was asked to give readings in schools, bookstores, but many different places.  I talked – well, in cities in Germany, always finding that the students are most attentive, interested to talk to me, to ask questions, and want to know more about what my life is now after much (inaudible) experiences.  In 2009, I got surprise in German for the book as the best autobiography.  In July of 2009, I came to Berlin and stayed for seven months, having such wonderful experiences, meeting fine people.</p>
<p>People thank me for doing what now became my mission.  I often give two or three readings a week, again traveling to many cities.  I was reading always for one hour very special pages from the book, and telling to whom I spoke what I want them to do, what I do, because we will not be on with a life many – much longer, and it is for them that it should never happen again, that I don’t want anyone to experience what has been done to the 5 million Jews and millions of other innocent humans.</p>
<p>I tell them that there is no Christian, Jewish, or Muslim blood – that there’s only human blood.  We are all the same, that people did it because they did not respect humans.  Please, be a human being.</p>
<p>In 2010 I did return to Berlin for good, and never did I regret it for one moment.  And here I am and gold still – it’s now almost hundred years to talk to people.  It is for you.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>MS SAUERBREY:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you, Ms. Friedlander, for your words, for everything you have done for Holocaust remembrance and for everything you continue to do.  Margo Wieseler, 25 years old, will speak to us now.  She served as a volunteer at the Illinois Holocaust Museum and Education Center in Chicago, Illinois, Skokie.</p>
<p><strong>MS WIESELER:</strong>  Good morning.  Again, I would just really like to thank Ms. Friedlander.  Your words really shook me in a way I didn’t even expect, although I expected it to be emotional, but yeah.  So thank you very much, and your words of wisdom and passion are truly an inspiring call to action for my generation.</p>
<p>I also want to thank Secretary Blinken and Secretary Maas for highlighting innovative ways to commemorate the Holocaust.  Initiatives to preserve the voices of our survivors are essential to prevent my generation from choosing the ease of forgetting over the pain or the shame of remembering.  And sometimes standard high-school-level history education can sadly reinforce this tendency, as it can make the Holocaust feel unpersonal and much more distant than it is.</p>
<p>I myself only recently really started confronting my family history and involvement when I began to prepare for my year abroad with <em>Aktion Suhnezeichen Friedensdienste</em>.  <em>Aktion Suhnezeichen</em> is a German NGO aiding reconciliation between victims of Nazi persecution and young Germans today.  And with the help of them, I had the unique opportunity and great privilege to spend a year volunteering at the Illinois Holocaust Museum and Education Center, a world-leading institution in the field of digitalized Holocaust remembrance in Chicago.</p>
<p>So – and I did find my motivation for serving in the museum in my family history.  My great grandfather was a member of the Reichstag, appointed by the Nazi party.  I was, still am, and will always be ashamed of this piece of my family’s history, and I was especially anxious to share this with the survivors and their families.  They had every reason to be dismissive, hurt, or even hostile towards me, but to my great relief their response was full of love, understanding, and even curiosity towards me and my motivations.</p>
<p>This ability to distinguish between my generation and our ancestors left a lasting impression on me.  I was especially amazed by Fritzie Fritzshall, the museum’s longtime president and a teenage survivor of Auschwitz-Birkenau, who heavily accepted an invitation to dinner from me and a friend.  And the cuisine would be German, obviously.</p>
<p>In devastating news, Fritzie sadly died last weekend, leaving another hole that will never be filled.  However, her impressing ability to disband black-and-white thinking in place of a more nuanced approach is, I think, something I learned from and everybody else can do.</p>
<p>My generation, young as we are, has been fortunate enough to hear the stories of the Holocaust directly from survivors, reminding us just how recent these atrocities truly were.  Because they were – they did happen before our lifetimes.  With each passing day, preserving and retelling these lessons gets more important, lest we begin to distance ourselves and forget the lessons learned.</p>
<p>My year with <em>Aktion Suhnezeichen </em>has forever changed me, and I can confidently say that I understand the importance of combating anti-Semitism and using that voice to fight for a free and fair society better than before.  If young people like me sincerely want to make “Never again” or “<em>Nie wieder</em>” a reality, we must never stop openly building bridges between the most painful hours of the past, our lives today, and the future we wish to see.</p>
<p>Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>MS SAUERBREY:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you, Ms. Wieseler.  Ladies and gentlemen, the foreign ministers will now place a wreath on the Memorial to the Murdered Jews in Europe, and will then speak to the survivors who are with us today: Ms. Margot Friedlander, Peter Gardosch, and Franz Michalski.  Ms. Wieseler and a number of Anne Frank ambassadors are also here, peer guides and volunteers of the Anne Frank Center in Berlin.  Afterwards, this ceremony is concluded.  And I would like to use this opportunity to thank you on behalf of the foreign office and the U.S. Department of State for having come here.  Have a safe journey home.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Department of State Raises the Progress Flag in Honor of Pride Month</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-department-of-state-raises-the-progress-flag-in-honor-of-pride-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 19:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=254790</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman, Chief Diversity and Inclusion Officer Ambassador Gina Abercrombie-Winstanley, and glifaa President Jeff Anderson will deliver remarks at a flag raising ceremony to fly the Progress flag at the Department of State’s Harry S Truman building. The flag-raising ceremony will take place on Friday, June 25, 2021, at 3:30 p.m.</p>
<p>The Progress flag is a symbol of the diversity and intersectionality of LGBTQI+ persons and communities around the world. As announced by Secretary Blinken, the flag will be flown during the period of June 26 to June 28 to mark two important turning points in the fight for LGBTQI+ rights: June 26, the anniversary of the historic Obergefell v. Hodges Supreme Court decision in 2015, which ruled that the fundamental right to marry is guaranteed to same-sex couples and is the law of the land; and June 28, which marks the anniversary of the start of the Stonewall riots of 1969.</p>
<p>This event is coordinated in partnership with glifaa – LGBTQI+ Pride in Foreign Affairs Agencies, the State Department’s official LGBTQI+ Employee Affinity Group.</p>
<p>The event will be outdoors and open to the press. This event will be live streamed on <a href="https://www.state.gov/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA2MjQuNDIzNzIzNDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdiJ9.7RL6IPLXxkmi1RopPRYFKUai8ng3QfWCHLWK8kzmMYc/s/1292923726/br/108390047411-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1624647719690000&amp;usg=AFQjCNF66spM4OfhzTO3iPCI41l2hcA4jg">www.state.gov</a>.</p>
<p>Pre-set time for video cameras: 2:45 p.m. from the C Street Entrance.</p>
<p>Final access time for journalists and still photographers: 3:15 p.m. from the C Street Entrance.</p>
<p>Media representatives may attend this event upon presentation of one of the following: (1) A U.S. Government-issued identification card (Department of State, White House, Congress, Department of Defense or Foreign Press Center), (2) a media-issued photo identification card, or (3) a letter from their employer on letterhead verifying their employment as a journalist, accompanied by an official photo identification card (driver&#8217;s license, passport).</p>
<p>For more information, please contact the Department of State’s Office of Press Relations at <a href="mailto:PAPressDuty@state.gov">PAPressDuty@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman, Chief Diversity and Inclusion Officer Ambassador Gina Abercrombie-Winstanley, and glifaa President Jeff Anderson will deliver remarks at a flag raising ceremony to fly the Progress flag at the Department of State’s Harry S Truman building. The flag-raising ceremony will take place on Friday, June 25, 2021, at 3:30 p.m.</p>
<p>The Progress flag is a symbol of the diversity and intersectionality of LGBTQI+ persons and communities around the world. As announced by Secretary Blinken, the flag will be flown during the period of June 26 to June 28 to mark two important turning points in the fight for LGBTQI+ rights: June 26, the anniversary of the historic Obergefell v. Hodges Supreme Court decision in 2015, which ruled that the fundamental right to marry is guaranteed to same-sex couples and is the law of the land; and June 28, which marks the anniversary of the start of the Stonewall riots of 1969.</p>
<p>This event is coordinated in partnership with glifaa – LGBTQI+ Pride in Foreign Affairs Agencies, the State Department’s official LGBTQI+ Employee Affinity Group.</p>
<p>The event will be outdoors and open to the press. This event will be live streamed on <a href="https://www.state.gov/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA2MjQuNDIzNzIzNDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdiJ9.7RL6IPLXxkmi1RopPRYFKUai8ng3QfWCHLWK8kzmMYc/s/1292923726/br/108390047411-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1624647719690000&amp;usg=AFQjCNF66spM4OfhzTO3iPCI41l2hcA4jg">www.state.gov</a>.</p>
<p>Pre-set time for video cameras: 2:45 p.m. from the C Street Entrance.</p>
<p>Final access time for journalists and still photographers: 3:15 p.m. from the C Street Entrance.</p>
<p>Media representatives may attend this event upon presentation of one of the following: (1) A U.S. Government-issued identification card (Department of State, White House, Congress, Department of Defense or Foreign Press Center), (2) a media-issued photo identification card, or (3) a letter from their employer on letterhead verifying their employment as a journalist, accompanied by an official photo identification card (driver&#8217;s license, passport).</p>
<p>For more information, please contact the Department of State’s Office of Press Relations at <a href="mailto:PAPressDuty@state.gov">PAPressDuty@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Death of Palestinian Activist Nizar Banat</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/death-of-palestinian-activist-nizar-banat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 18:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=254770</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We are deeply disturbed by the death of Palestinian activist Nizar Banat and the information that has been reported regarding the circumstances of his death.  We offer our sincere condolences to his family and community.  We urge the Palestinian Authority to conduct a thorough and transparent investigation and to ensure full accountability in this case.  We have serious concerns about Palestinian Authority restrictions on the exercise of freedom of expression by Palestinians and harassment of civil society activists and organizations.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We are deeply disturbed by the death of Palestinian activist Nizar Banat and the information that has been reported regarding the circumstances of his death.  We offer our sincere condolences to his family and community.  We urge the Palestinian Authority to conduct a thorough and transparent investigation and to ensure full accountability in this case.  We have serious concerns about Palestinian Authority restrictions on the exercise of freedom of expression by Palestinians and harassment of civil society activists and organizations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>East Asia Summit Senior Officials’ Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/east-asia-summit-senior-officials-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 18:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=254768</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Senior Bureau Official for the Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs Kin Moy met on June 24 with senior officials from the East Asia Summit (EAS) nations and Deputy Secretary General of ASEAN for Political-Security Community Michael Tene during the East Asia Summit (EAS) Senior Officials’ Meeting.  Senior Bureau Official Moy reaffirmed the U.S. commitment to ASEAN and the EAS, highlighting the strong U.S. support for ASEAN centrality and for ASEAN-centered institutions.  He discussed the importance of upholding the rules-based international order, and reiterated U.S. support for the ASEAN Outlook on the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>Senior Bureau Official Moy outlined U.S. assistance to combat COVID-19, including the historic announcement that the U.S. will donate more than 500 million vaccine doses globally.  He stressed the importance of taking bold action to address the climate crisis, with an emphasis on ambitious 2030 emissions reductions targets, a shared effort to reach zero emissions by 2050, and the importance of a green recovery.</p>
<p>Expressing concerns over escalating tension in the South China Sea, Senior Bureau Official Moy reiterated U.S. support for freedom of navigation and overflight.  He underscored the U.S. rejection of the People’s Republic of China’s unlawful maritime claims in the South China Sea and underscored U.S. support for Southeast Asian claimants’ lawful efforts to access their own maritime resources.</p>
<p>Senior Bureau Official Moy also highlighted the ongoing work of the Mekong-U.S. Partnership to promote transparency, autonomy, and inclusive growth in the Mekong sub-region.</p>
<p>Senior Bureau Official Moy urged ASEAN to take immediate action to hold the Burmese regime accountable to the ASEAN five-point consensus.  He called for joint action to press the Burmese military to end the violence, release those unjustly detained, and restore Burma to the path of democracy.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Senior Bureau Official for the Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs Kin Moy met on June 24 with senior officials from the East Asia Summit (EAS) nations and Deputy Secretary General of ASEAN for Political-Security Community Michael Tene during the East Asia Summit (EAS) Senior Officials’ Meeting.  Senior Bureau Official Moy reaffirmed the U.S. commitment to ASEAN and the EAS, highlighting the strong U.S. support for ASEAN centrality and for ASEAN-centered institutions.  He discussed the importance of upholding the rules-based international order, and reiterated U.S. support for the ASEAN Outlook on the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>Senior Bureau Official Moy outlined U.S. assistance to combat COVID-19, including the historic announcement that the U.S. will donate more than 500 million vaccine doses globally.  He stressed the importance of taking bold action to address the climate crisis, with an emphasis on ambitious 2030 emissions reductions targets, a shared effort to reach zero emissions by 2050, and the importance of a green recovery.</p>
<p>Expressing concerns over escalating tension in the South China Sea, Senior Bureau Official Moy reiterated U.S. support for freedom of navigation and overflight.  He underscored the U.S. rejection of the People’s Republic of China’s unlawful maritime claims in the South China Sea and underscored U.S. support for Southeast Asian claimants’ lawful efforts to access their own maritime resources.</p>
<p>Senior Bureau Official Moy also highlighted the ongoing work of the Mekong-U.S. Partnership to promote transparency, autonomy, and inclusive growth in the Mekong sub-region.</p>
<p>Senior Bureau Official Moy urged ASEAN to take immediate action to hold the Burmese regime accountable to the ASEAN five-point consensus.  He called for joint action to press the Burmese military to end the violence, release those unjustly detained, and restore Burma to the path of democracy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States and France: Allies, Partners, and Friends</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-and-france-allies-partners-and-friends/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 17:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=254748</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>“President Macron and I stand together, ready to take on the toughest challenges we face.&#8221; </em></p>
<p><em>– President Biden, June 11, 2021</em></p>
<p>Secretary Antony J. Blinken will travel to Paris, France, June 24-27, 2021, where he will meet with French President Emmanuel Macron and French Foreign Minister Jean Yves Le Drian.  During this trip to engage with the United States’ oldest Ally, Secretary Blinken will emphasize the importance of maintaining Transatlantic cooperation, addressing our joint response to the ongoing health crisis, tackling the climate crisis, and highlighting the strength of our longstanding bilateral partnership.</p>
<p><strong>The United States and France are Close Allies</strong></p>
<p>France is America’s oldest friend and Ally.  Our relationship is built upon our shared commitment to the same values – democracy, human rights, the rule of law, security, and prosperity.  The closeness of our military, economic, and political cooperation form the basis of our enduring partnership.</p>
<p>The United States has counted on France as a close partner since the very foundation of our country.  We remember Gilbert du Mortier, Marquis de Lafayette, and Jean-Baptiste Donatien de Vimeur, Comte de Rochambeau, as heroes of the American Revolution.  France came to the aid of our young country; the United States has not forgotten.</p>
<p>In 2021, we commemorated the 77th anniversary of D-Day and the sacrifices made on the beaches of Normandy.  As NATO Allies, France and the United States have built and sustained the post-war global order, which promotes freedom and prosperity.  Our joint commitment to shared Transatlantic values has brought us 77 years of peace and prosperity.</p>
<p><strong>Confronting Global Challenges: The United States Counts on France as a Partner</strong></p>
<p>Today’s global challenges underscore the importance of strong partnerships.  Security, economic, and cultural cooperation form the basis of our bilateral relationship.  France is a key NATO Ally and an important bilateral economic partner.  France will assume the presidency of the Council of the European Union in January 2022, and we look forward to working with France to revitalize and raise the level of ambition in the United States’ partnership with the EU.</p>
<p>Security cooperation underpins our bilateral relationship.  France remains a steadfast partner in the fight against terrorism, as both a member of the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS and through its counterterrorism leadership in the Sahel.  Around the world, we look to France as a partner in global security.</p>
<p>The United States and France agree on the need to hold Russia accountable for its aggressive and destabilizing activities, including in Ukraine.  France is a partner in standing up to Russia’s attempts to undermine democratic systems.</p>
<p>We coordinate with France on issues like human rights, economic coercion, and corruption, to amplify our voices and combat the PRC’s attempts to erode the values and institutions that undergird the rules-based international order.</p>
<p>The United States is dedicated to raising global climate ambitions. In the lead up to COP26, we will continue to work with France in implementing climate finance to achieve the goals of the Paris Agreement, and accelerating the transition to a clean energy economy to achieve net-zero emissions by mid-century.</p>
<p><strong>The Thriving Bilateral Economic Relationship Supports Our Workers</strong></p>
<p>The United States and France share a deep trade and investment relationship.  France is the United States’ third largest trading partner in Europe with $99.7 billion of goods and services traded in 2020.  The United States is the top destination for French investment and the United States is the largest foreign investor in France.  In total, we have invested more than $394 billion in each other&#8217;s economies.  The 4,800 French firms in the United States support 780,000 jobs, while the 4,500 U.S. firms in France support nearly 500,000 jobs.</p>
<p>First and foremost, the United States and France share concerns about the health of our citizens as we seek to reduce the spread of COVID-19 and ensure equitable access to vaccines.  The United States and France have both committed to share vaccine doses through COVAX and will continue to support global vaccination efforts.  We must work together to safely restore global travel and trade on a sustainable basis, and the United States looks forward to partnering with France to increase global preparedness to better prevent and respond to future outbreaks.</p>
<p><strong>Deep Historical and Cultural Ties Cement Our People-to-People Bonds </strong></p>
<p>The enduring relationship between our two countries is apparent in our historical connection and people-to-people ties.  France and the United States share a strong commitment to educational exchanges.  Before the coronavirus pandemic, approximately18,000 Americans studied abroad in France each year, making France among the top four most popular study abroad destinations for American students.  French students are also attracted to educational exchange opportunities in the United States.  In the 2019/2020 academic year, 8,471 French students chose to study at a U.S. college or university.   Although COVID-19 has forced many of our exchange programs to pause this year, interest in exchanges remains strong, and we will make every effort to ensure that these exchanges between our two countries not only continue but grow.</p>
<p>Established in 1948, the U.S.-French Fulbright program is one of the oldest Fulbright programs in the world.  Every year, approximately 160 French and American students, scholars, teaching assistants, and higher education administrators receive Fulbright awards to study, teach, and conduct research.  Since its inception, the program has supported approximately 30,000 individual Fulbright exchanges between the United States and France and will celebrate its 75th anniversary in 2023.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>“President Macron and I stand together, ready to take on the toughest challenges we face.&#8221; </em></p>
<p><em>– President Biden, June 11, 2021</em></p>
<p>Secretary Antony J. Blinken will travel to Paris, France, June 24-27, 2021, where he will meet with French President Emmanuel Macron and French Foreign Minister Jean Yves Le Drian.  During this trip to engage with the United States’ oldest Ally, Secretary Blinken will emphasize the importance of maintaining Transatlantic cooperation, addressing our joint response to the ongoing health crisis, tackling the climate crisis, and highlighting the strength of our longstanding bilateral partnership.</p>
<p><strong>The United States and France are Close Allies</strong></p>
<p>France is America’s oldest friend and Ally.  Our relationship is built upon our shared commitment to the same values – democracy, human rights, the rule of law, security, and prosperity.  The closeness of our military, economic, and political cooperation form the basis of our enduring partnership.</p>
<p>The United States has counted on France as a close partner since the very foundation of our country.  We remember Gilbert du Mortier, Marquis de Lafayette, and Jean-Baptiste Donatien de Vimeur, Comte de Rochambeau, as heroes of the American Revolution.  France came to the aid of our young country; the United States has not forgotten.</p>
<p>In 2021, we commemorated the 77th anniversary of D-Day and the sacrifices made on the beaches of Normandy.  As NATO Allies, France and the United States have built and sustained the post-war global order, which promotes freedom and prosperity.  Our joint commitment to shared Transatlantic values has brought us 77 years of peace and prosperity.</p>
<p><strong>Confronting Global Challenges: The United States Counts on France as a Partner</strong></p>
<p>Today’s global challenges underscore the importance of strong partnerships.  Security, economic, and cultural cooperation form the basis of our bilateral relationship.  France is a key NATO Ally and an important bilateral economic partner.  France will assume the presidency of the Council of the European Union in January 2022, and we look forward to working with France to revitalize and raise the level of ambition in the United States’ partnership with the EU.</p>
<p>Security cooperation underpins our bilateral relationship.  France remains a steadfast partner in the fight against terrorism, as both a member of the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS and through its counterterrorism leadership in the Sahel.  Around the world, we look to France as a partner in global security.</p>
<p>The United States and France agree on the need to hold Russia accountable for its aggressive and destabilizing activities, including in Ukraine.  France is a partner in standing up to Russia’s attempts to undermine democratic systems.</p>
<p>We coordinate with France on issues like human rights, economic coercion, and corruption, to amplify our voices and combat the PRC’s attempts to erode the values and institutions that undergird the rules-based international order.</p>
<p>The United States is dedicated to raising global climate ambitions. In the lead up to COP26, we will continue to work with France in implementing climate finance to achieve the goals of the Paris Agreement, and accelerating the transition to a clean energy economy to achieve net-zero emissions by mid-century.</p>
<p><strong>The Thriving Bilateral Economic Relationship Supports Our Workers</strong></p>
<p>The United States and France share a deep trade and investment relationship.  France is the United States’ third largest trading partner in Europe with $99.7 billion of goods and services traded in 2020.  The United States is the top destination for French investment and the United States is the largest foreign investor in France.  In total, we have invested more than $394 billion in each other&#8217;s economies.  The 4,800 French firms in the United States support 780,000 jobs, while the 4,500 U.S. firms in France support nearly 500,000 jobs.</p>
<p>First and foremost, the United States and France share concerns about the health of our citizens as we seek to reduce the spread of COVID-19 and ensure equitable access to vaccines.  The United States and France have both committed to share vaccine doses through COVAX and will continue to support global vaccination efforts.  We must work together to safely restore global travel and trade on a sustainable basis, and the United States looks forward to partnering with France to increase global preparedness to better prevent and respond to future outbreaks.</p>
<p><strong>Deep Historical and Cultural Ties Cement Our People-to-People Bonds </strong></p>
<p>The enduring relationship between our two countries is apparent in our historical connection and people-to-people ties.  France and the United States share a strong commitment to educational exchanges.  Before the coronavirus pandemic, approximately18,000 Americans studied abroad in France each year, making France among the top four most popular study abroad destinations for American students.  French students are also attracted to educational exchange opportunities in the United States.  In the 2019/2020 academic year, 8,471 French students chose to study at a U.S. college or university.   Although COVID-19 has forced many of our exchange programs to pause this year, interest in exchanges remains strong, and we will make every effort to ensure that these exchanges between our two countries not only continue but grow.</p>
<p>Established in 1948, the U.S.-French Fulbright program is one of the oldest Fulbright programs in the world.  Every year, approximately 160 French and American students, scholars, teaching assistants, and higher education administrators receive Fulbright awards to study, teach, and conduct research.  Since its inception, the program has supported approximately 30,000 individual Fulbright exchanges between the United States and France and will celebrate its 75th anniversary in 2023.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
