<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 23:00:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>East Asian and Pacific Affairs Assistant Secretary Daniel J. Kritenbrink and African Affairs Assistant Secretary Molly Phee on the Secretary’s Upcoming Travel to Cambodia, the Philippines, South Africa, the Democratic Republic of the Congo, and Rwanda</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/east-asian-and-pacific-affairs-assistant-secretary-daniel-j-kritenbrink-and-african-affairs-assistant-secretary-molly-phee-on-the-secretarys-upcoming-travel-to-cambodia-the-philippines-sou/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel J. Kritenbrink, Assistant SecretaryBureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs, Molly Phee, Assistant SecretaryBureau of African Affairs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 23:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=364234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Daniel J. Kritenbrink, Assistant SecretaryBureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs</p>
<p>Molly Phee, Assistant SecretaryBureau of African Affairs</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b>Thanks very much and good afternoon, everyone.  Thank you for joining this call.  We’re very pleased to have the opportunity to preview the Secretary’s upcoming travel to Cambodia, the Philippines, South Africa, the Democratic Republic of the Congo, and Rwanda.  We’ll be departing on Tuesday.  The Secretary will be on travel from August 2nd through August 12th.  We have two briefers for you today.  We have Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel Kritenbrink and Assistant Secretary of State for African Affairs Molly Phee.  Just a reminder, this call is on the record, but it is embargoed until the conclusion of the call.  With that, I’ll turn it over to Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink for some opening comments.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY KRITENBRINK:  </b>Thank you, Ned, and good afternoon everyone.  It’s great to be with you again.  I met with many of you earlier this month ahead of the Secretary’s trip to Indonesia, Thailand, and Japan and of course traveled with many of you on that trip.  And at that time, I noted that this level of senior-level engagement in the Indo-Pacific reflects just how profoundly important the region is to America’s long-term security and prosperity.</p>
<p>And now we’re here just a few weeks later to announce yet another visit to the Indo-Pacific.  Secretary Blinken will first head to Phnom Penh, Cambodia on August 3rd to participate in three separate ministerials hosted by Cambodia as ASEAN chair this year.  This is a profoundly important time in our relationship with ASEAN.  At May’s U.S.-ASEAN Summit here in Washington, D.C., we agreed to elevate our relationship to a Comprehensive Strategic Partnership.  The Secretary will discuss that matter with our ASEAN friends in Phnom Penh, which will lead up to the November U.S.-ASEAN Summit and East Asia Summit.</p>
<p>In Cambodia next week, again, I mentioned the Secretary will participate in three separate ministerials: first, the U.S.-ASEAN Ministerial, where we will highlight our enduring and committed partnership with ASEAN, our respect for ASEAN centrality, and our strong support for the ASEAN outlook on the Indo-Pacific, as well as our work with ASEAN partners on a range of shared challenges.</p>
<p>Secondly, in the East Asia Summit foreign ministers meeting, we will focus on strategic issues and global challenges.  For example, we’ll address transboundary challenges such as climate change and human rights.  We’ll also discuss the PRC’s growing coercive activity across the region.</p>
<p>And third and finally in the ASEAN Regional Forum, or ARF, the Secretary will address specific political and security concerns, encourage preventative diplomacy, and support ASEAN’s commitment to regional security and to nuclear nonproliferation and disarmament.</p>
<p>At all three ministerials, as well as at the many bilateral engagements that the Secretary has planned, Secretary Blinken will urge our partners to step up pressure on the Burmese military regime following its horrific and heinous execution of four pro-democracy advocates.  This is just the latest example of the regime’s brutality.  The Secretary will also press all countries in the region to enhance support for the people of Burma, the pro-democracy movement, and all those working to restore Burma’s path to democracy.</p>
<p>The Secretary will also discuss Russia’s ongoing war in Ukraine.  America’s goal is straightforward:  We want to see a democratic, independent, sovereign, and prosperous Ukraine with the means to deter and defend itself against further aggression.  If Russia does not pay a heavy price for its actions, it will send a message to other would-be aggressors that they too can seize territory and subjugate other countries.  It will put the survival of other peaceful sovereign states at risk.  There will, of course, also be discussions on issues related to food and energy security, which obviously have been negatively impacted by Russia’s war.</p>
<p>In his meeting with Cambodian leaders on a bilateral basis, the Secretary will stress his strong support for ASEAN and for the success of Cambodia’s chairmanship this year.  He will also underscore the U.S. desire to have a productive and positive relationship with Cambodia, highlighting strong bilateral cooperation on issues such as DPRK sanctions enforcement, law enforcement coordination, and condemnation of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.  At the same time, however, the Secretary will also stress the importance of Cambodia’s being open and transparent about its security cooperation with the PRC and the need for Cambodian leaders to make meaningful progress to support multi-party democracy, respect for human rights, and to reopen civic and political space.</p>
<p>Next, Secretary Blinken will visit the Philippines, where he will meet with newly elected President Ferdinand Marcos, Jr. and the new Secretary of Foreign Affairs Enrique Manalo.  We welcome the statements that President Marcos recently made about the importance of preserving the Philippines’ territorial integrity.  Secretary Blinken will reinforce and underscore to our Philippine allies that our commitment to our Mutual Defense Treaty is ironclad.  He also intends to have important discussions on enhanced cooperation on trade and investment and on clean energy, as well as on advancing our shared democratic values and strengthening respect for human rights, including press freedom.</p>
<p>With that, I’ll pass the phone to my friends and esteemed colleague, Assistant Secretary Molly Phee.  I’ll look forward to your questions later.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY PHEE:</b>  Thanks, Dan.  Great to be here with you.  Thanks, Ned, for organizing this.</p>
<p>We’re all excited about the Secretary’s upcoming travel to South Africa, the Democratic Republic of the Congo, and Rwanda from August 7th through 12th.  Each of these countries is a significant player on the continent and across the globe, so we’re looking forward to direct conversations and engagement about shared challenges and opportunities.</p>
<p>In South Africa, the Secretary will lead the U.S. delegation to the U.S.-South Africa Strategic Dialogue.  This dialogue will focus on health, environment, trade and investment, and infrastructure, priorities for both countries.  Given South Africa’s leadership role, it’s an ideal location for the Secretary to deliver a speech announcing and describing the U.S. strategy toward sub-Saharan Africa.</p>
<p>In the Democratic Republic of the Congo, the Secretary will meet with senior government officials as well as members of civil society to discuss efforts to hold peaceful, on-time free and fair elections in 2023.  He will want to hear the Congolese perspective about regional efforts to address the role of armed groups in eastern Congo and the recent spike in violence, including attacks against MONUSCO peacekeepers.</p>
<p>In both the DRC and Rwanda, the Secretary will highlight the need for respect for territorial integrity and explore how the United States can support efforts to reduce tensions.  In Kigali, he looks forward to the opportunity to meet President Kagame for the first time since he became Secretary of State to discuss a range of national and regional issues.  He will raise the case of Paul Rusesabagina, whom the Secretary has determined has been wrongfully detained.</p>
<p>At each stop, he will seek an exchange on the importance of democracy, good governance, and respect for human rights.  As you know, these are longstanding U.S. values that are part of all of our discussions, as Dan just described as well.</p>
<p>The Secretary is really interested in exploring how we can broaden economic prosperity.  As you know, we’re committed to contributing to efforts to build Africa’s self-sufficiency and resilience and to promote inclusive development.  To that end, we’re working with African governments and businesses, entrepreneurs, civil society, the U.S. private sector, and IFIs and MDBs to accelerate sustainable economic growth across the continent and to help Africans manage the disruptive economic shock of COVID and the food security crisis caused by Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>Finally, the Secretary will focus on the devastating impacts of climate change.  We are continuing to partner with African leaders to tackle the climate crisis and to work together on clean energy development and to provide needed tools and innovation to transition for the future.  We will want to consult on the decision to open up the Congolese rain forest to oil and gas exploration.  The consequences for the DRC, for Africa, and for the world are immense.  And we’ll also want to continue to work with the Congolese Government on how they can best diversify and grow their economy sustainably.</p>
<p>Just to note, we’ve had a lot of travel to Africa this summer.  In June, Under Secretary Nuland went to Somalia, Djibouti, Mozambique, and Nigeria.  Under Secretary Zeya just returned from a trip to Mozambique and Namibia.  Derek Chollet this week has been in Senegal, and Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield is going next week to Uganda and Rwanda.  We’ll also have a lot of CODELs in August.  So all of this is designed to create opportunities for us to meet our partners in person and to collaborate on these critical issues.</p>
<p>Over to you, Ned.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Terrific.  We have time for a few questions.  Operator, if you wouldn’t mind repeating the instructions to ask a question.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR: </b> Once again, ladies and gentlemen, if you do have a question, press * then 0 at this moment.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  We’ll start with the line of Jennifer Hansler, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  We can.  Go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Awesome.  Thank you.  Are there any plans for the Secretary to meet with Foreign Minister Lavrov while they are both in Cambodia for the ministerial?  And then on Paul Rusesabagina, will the Secretary be warning about any consequences should they continue to detain him, and what would those consequences be?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Jenny, I’ll start with your first question.  We have no plans to meet with Foreign Minister Lavrov when they are in Cambodia.  I’ll turn it over to Assistant Secretary Phee on your second.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY PHEE:</b>  Thanks, Ned.  Yeah, I don’t want to get ahead of those discussions with President Kagame.  We’ve been very clear with the Government of Rwanda about our concerns about his case, his trial, and his conviction, particularly the lack of fair trial guarantees in his case.  And I’m looking forward to the opportunity for this issue to be discussed at a senior level.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  We’ll go to the line of Dave Lawler.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Ned, a question on the last two stops, Rwanda and DRC.  I assume part of the reason for choosing those locations is to try to reduce tensions between them.  Can you talk a bit about that?  And you spoke about the need to respect territorial integrity; obviously, DRC has said Rwanda is arming and supporting the M23 rebels and so violating its territorial integrity.  I guess does the U.S. have any position on whether that is the case, and is it a problem for the U.S. if that is the case?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY PHEE:</b>  I think, as everybody knows, the situation in eastern Congo has tragically been volatile for about two decades, with over five million people who’ve lost their lives there, and a range of armed actors who also seek sanctuary in neighboring countries.</p>
<p>Recently, a few months ago, the Kenyans launched an initiative known as the Nairobi Process to try and work with the Congolese and neighboring countries to get a grip on the role of armed groups, including M23, and that effort has begun, I think, to address the concerns.  Angola also hosted both the – President Kagame and President Tshisekedi just a few weeks ago to help urge de-escalation in tension.  And I know that Secretary Blinken hopes to contribute to these conversations and see what the United States can do to reinforce these regional diplomatic efforts and to see how we can help calm the situation.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  We’ll go to the line of Simon Lewis, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi, thank you.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Simon, your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thanks.  Hi, thank you.  So the first question: Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink – I will – I just wanted to ask a couple of things on the Asia side of the trip.  One thing:  Is there any plans for a bilateral with Wang Yi during the Cambodia event?  And I wondered if you could give us an update given the recent developments in Myanmar with the execution of activists.  Does that change the thinking on potentially sanctioning the oil and gas enterprise?  Is that getting any closer to happening?</p>
<p>And I just wanted to follow up on the questions on Rwanda to Assistant Secretary Phee.  I just wondered, in the light of the letter that Senator Menendez wrote to the – to the Secretary about Rwanda, do – is there – is this sort of U.S. aid to Rwanda under discussion during this trip?  Is that something that – given those concerns about Paul Rusesabagina and also the Rwandan development with the M23 fighting, are you looking at reducing the level of aid that goes there?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Dan, would you like to start?</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY KRITENBRINK:</b>  Absolutely.  Thanks very much for the question.  Look, on your first question I would say at this point there are no formal or official plans to sit down and meet with State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi, particularly since the Secretary just saw him a couple of weeks ago, as you’re aware, in Bali, where they met for more than five hours and had a very candid and productive and comprehensive conversation.  But as you know, at these multilateral meetings there often are opportunities for pull-asides.  So we’ll see how things develop, but no formal plans at this point.</p>
<p>On your second question, on Myanmar, thanks very much for raising that.  Look, again, I’ll just reiterate: I think the international community is really horrified and incensed by these inhuman and heinous executions that were just carried out.  But really, this is just the latest demonstration of the regime’s brutality, which thus far has murdered more than 2,100 Burmese since the coup d’état.  What I would say is that you can see the depth of that indignation through the various international statements that have been issued.  Of course, the Secretary spoke, our friends in ASEAN issued a statement, the G7 has issued a statement, and other likeminded partners have as well.</p>
<p>As far as additional steps, this will be a real focus of our conversations at the ASEAN meetings in Cambodia.  I would just underscore that all options are on the table, including related to MOGE.  Certainly don’t have anything to announce today, but I think it’s fair to say that we’ll consider any and all means necessary to increase pressure on the regime in Burma and to cut off their funding streams that continue to fuel their repression.  And so we’ll continue to examine all of that across the board, and at the same time we’ll keep in mind that we want to make sure whatever we do, it doesn’t exacerbate the already difficult circumstances in which the Burmese people find themselves.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY PHEE:</b>  So on Rwanda, Secretary Blinken had an opportunity a few days ago to speak to Senator Menendez about his letter, and he told him that he intended to raise the issues outlined in the letter when he has an opportunity to speak with President Kagame, that that would be part of the discussion of a range of topics that he hopes to review with President Kagame.</p>
<p>So, as I said before, I don’t want to get ahead of that discussion.  I think it’s great that we’re going to have the opportunity to engage at a senior level and explore what’s possible for our future relationship.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  We’ll go to the line of Ryohei Takagi.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Can you hear me okay?</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Yes, please go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you, Ned and Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink.  I just wonder whether he will meet his counterparts from the DPRK on the sidelines of ASEAN Regional Forum in Cambodia.  And secondly, you have mentioned the security cooperation between Cambodia and the PRC.  It has been reported that China is secretly building a naval facility in Cambodia.  So could you tell us some updates on it, and what is the U.S. position to it?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY KRITENBRINK:</b>  Thank you for your questions.  I can say clearly that there are no plans to meet with North Korean counterparts.  You do point out rightly that North Korea is represented in the ASEAN Regional Forum.  I don’t have any information in front of me who may or may not be present representing North Korea, but no plans to meet with them, although I am confident that the Secretary will speak directly to the situation in North Korea during his intervention at the ARF.</p>
<p>You mentioned Cambodian security cooperation with the PRC, and I noted that in my opening comments as well.  Look, we’ve been crystal clear, and the Secretary has as well and the Deputy Secretary and myself publicly, that we have encouraged the Government of Cambodia to be fully transparent about the intent, nature, and scope of its project at Ream and the role of the PRC military in its construction there.  Certainly I think a number of us have significant concerns about that facility there, and in particular any exclusive PRC military presence at Ream would risk diminishing Cambodia’s autonomy and undermining regional security.  So again, we’ll have an opportunity to convey that message to Cambodian friends again, and I am confident that others in the region will as well.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Julian Pecquet.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you.  Sorry, I had a similar question regarding, more specifically, on any sanctions or anything else that you might announce.  I know you can’t talk about that, but is Roger Carstens traveling with the Secretary?  And more broadly, can you talk about other people who might be on the trip to Africa in particular?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY PHEE:</b>  The Secretary is taking several leaders to join him, particularly in South Africa, where we’re doing the Strategic Dialogue.  Under Secretary Jose Fernandez will be joining us; the head of USTDA, the Trade and Development Association, will be joining us; our new head of PEPFAR, who we stole from Africa CDC, the great Dr. John – I’m going to mispronounce his name – Nkengasong – I apologize; and also colleagues from HHS.  And Under Secretary Fernandez will also join the Secretary in Congo.  So Roger’s not traveling with the Secretary on this trip.  That’ll be a subject the Secretary himself will raise.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  And we’ll conclude with the line of Pearl Matibe.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you, Ned, and thank you so much, Assistant Secretary Phee.  My question is regarding South Africa.  So as evidence has shown in several countries, if unemployment and indigenous land and indigenous wealth is not tackled, conflict can follow.  So could you possibly preview for us how does the Secretary plan to concretely address issues of unemployment?</p>
<p>And then also, do you think that he might address the notion of foreign powers being viewed as an increasing – by an increasing number of – in the population, including young people, as the second most significant driver of negative change in South Africa?</p>
<p>And I know that you have always said that human rights is part and parcel or threaded into your interactions.  Will he address brutality and the extent of xenophobic violence and human rights of migrants while he is there?  I’d appreciate your comments on these, Secretary Phee.  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY PHEE:</b>  So thanks very much for your question and for highlighting those important concerns.  I wanted to draw your attention to the speech that he will deliver.  He spoke, as you may recall, when he was in Nigeria last November about U.S. policy and our approach towards Africa, and the formal announcement of this strategy is of course consistent with what he outlined and what we’ve been doing since the administration came into office.</p>
<p>But it will be an amplification of our conviction that partnership with Africa is really critical to meeting shared challenges.  And those shared challenges really include economic issues, and we recognize the incredible youth dynamic and the challenge that poses for African societies in terms of employment, and that’s why we’re working hard to mobilize greater trade and investment in Africa to help African economies develop in a way that addresses that youth bulge and also that is consistent with our shared climate change goals, as I said, to develop in a sustainable way.</p>
<p>So I think those themes will be very public while he’s there.  And again, as I said earlier, he always discusses – he believes passionately in human rights, and he always discusses it in all of his stops.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Excellent.  Well, thank you very much to our two speakers, Assistant Secretary Phee, Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink, and for everyone for tuning in.  Just a reminder this call was on the record, and the embargo is now lifted.  Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="100000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Daniel J. Kritenbrink, Assistant SecretaryBureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs</p>
<p>Molly Phee, Assistant SecretaryBureau of African Affairs</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b>Thanks very much and good afternoon, everyone.  Thank you for joining this call.  We’re very pleased to have the opportunity to preview the Secretary’s upcoming travel to Cambodia, the Philippines, South Africa, the Democratic Republic of the Congo, and Rwanda.  We’ll be departing on Tuesday.  The Secretary will be on travel from August 2nd through August 12th.  We have two briefers for you today.  We have Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel Kritenbrink and Assistant Secretary of State for African Affairs Molly Phee.  Just a reminder, this call is on the record, but it is embargoed until the conclusion of the call.  With that, I’ll turn it over to Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink for some opening comments.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY KRITENBRINK:  </b>Thank you, Ned, and good afternoon everyone.  It’s great to be with you again.  I met with many of you earlier this month ahead of the Secretary’s trip to Indonesia, Thailand, and Japan and of course traveled with many of you on that trip.  And at that time, I noted that this level of senior-level engagement in the Indo-Pacific reflects just how profoundly important the region is to America’s long-term security and prosperity.</p>
<p>And now we’re here just a few weeks later to announce yet another visit to the Indo-Pacific.  Secretary Blinken will first head to Phnom Penh, Cambodia on August 3rd to participate in three separate ministerials hosted by Cambodia as ASEAN chair this year.  This is a profoundly important time in our relationship with ASEAN.  At May’s U.S.-ASEAN Summit here in Washington, D.C., we agreed to elevate our relationship to a Comprehensive Strategic Partnership.  The Secretary will discuss that matter with our ASEAN friends in Phnom Penh, which will lead up to the November U.S.-ASEAN Summit and East Asia Summit.</p>
<p>In Cambodia next week, again, I mentioned the Secretary will participate in three separate ministerials: first, the U.S.-ASEAN Ministerial, where we will highlight our enduring and committed partnership with ASEAN, our respect for ASEAN centrality, and our strong support for the ASEAN outlook on the Indo-Pacific, as well as our work with ASEAN partners on a range of shared challenges.</p>
<p>Secondly, in the East Asia Summit foreign ministers meeting, we will focus on strategic issues and global challenges.  For example, we’ll address transboundary challenges such as climate change and human rights.  We’ll also discuss the PRC’s growing coercive activity across the region.</p>
<p>And third and finally in the ASEAN Regional Forum, or ARF, the Secretary will address specific political and security concerns, encourage preventative diplomacy, and support ASEAN’s commitment to regional security and to nuclear nonproliferation and disarmament.</p>
<p>At all three ministerials, as well as at the many bilateral engagements that the Secretary has planned, Secretary Blinken will urge our partners to step up pressure on the Burmese military regime following its horrific and heinous execution of four pro-democracy advocates.  This is just the latest example of the regime’s brutality.  The Secretary will also press all countries in the region to enhance support for the people of Burma, the pro-democracy movement, and all those working to restore Burma’s path to democracy.</p>
<p>The Secretary will also discuss Russia’s ongoing war in Ukraine.  America’s goal is straightforward:  We want to see a democratic, independent, sovereign, and prosperous Ukraine with the means to deter and defend itself against further aggression.  If Russia does not pay a heavy price for its actions, it will send a message to other would-be aggressors that they too can seize territory and subjugate other countries.  It will put the survival of other peaceful sovereign states at risk.  There will, of course, also be discussions on issues related to food and energy security, which obviously have been negatively impacted by Russia’s war.</p>
<p>In his meeting with Cambodian leaders on a bilateral basis, the Secretary will stress his strong support for ASEAN and for the success of Cambodia’s chairmanship this year.  He will also underscore the U.S. desire to have a productive and positive relationship with Cambodia, highlighting strong bilateral cooperation on issues such as DPRK sanctions enforcement, law enforcement coordination, and condemnation of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.  At the same time, however, the Secretary will also stress the importance of Cambodia’s being open and transparent about its security cooperation with the PRC and the need for Cambodian leaders to make meaningful progress to support multi-party democracy, respect for human rights, and to reopen civic and political space.</p>
<p>Next, Secretary Blinken will visit the Philippines, where he will meet with newly elected President Ferdinand Marcos, Jr. and the new Secretary of Foreign Affairs Enrique Manalo.  We welcome the statements that President Marcos recently made about the importance of preserving the Philippines’ territorial integrity.  Secretary Blinken will reinforce and underscore to our Philippine allies that our commitment to our Mutual Defense Treaty is ironclad.  He also intends to have important discussions on enhanced cooperation on trade and investment and on clean energy, as well as on advancing our shared democratic values and strengthening respect for human rights, including press freedom.</p>
<p>With that, I’ll pass the phone to my friends and esteemed colleague, Assistant Secretary Molly Phee.  I’ll look forward to your questions later.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY PHEE:</b>  Thanks, Dan.  Great to be here with you.  Thanks, Ned, for organizing this.</p>
<p>We’re all excited about the Secretary’s upcoming travel to South Africa, the Democratic Republic of the Congo, and Rwanda from August 7th through 12th.  Each of these countries is a significant player on the continent and across the globe, so we’re looking forward to direct conversations and engagement about shared challenges and opportunities.</p>
<p>In South Africa, the Secretary will lead the U.S. delegation to the U.S.-South Africa Strategic Dialogue.  This dialogue will focus on health, environment, trade and investment, and infrastructure, priorities for both countries.  Given South Africa’s leadership role, it’s an ideal location for the Secretary to deliver a speech announcing and describing the U.S. strategy toward sub-Saharan Africa.</p>
<p>In the Democratic Republic of the Congo, the Secretary will meet with senior government officials as well as members of civil society to discuss efforts to hold peaceful, on-time free and fair elections in 2023.  He will want to hear the Congolese perspective about regional efforts to address the role of armed groups in eastern Congo and the recent spike in violence, including attacks against MONUSCO peacekeepers.</p>
<p>In both the DRC and Rwanda, the Secretary will highlight the need for respect for territorial integrity and explore how the United States can support efforts to reduce tensions.  In Kigali, he looks forward to the opportunity to meet President Kagame for the first time since he became Secretary of State to discuss a range of national and regional issues.  He will raise the case of Paul Rusesabagina, whom the Secretary has determined has been wrongfully detained.</p>
<p>At each stop, he will seek an exchange on the importance of democracy, good governance, and respect for human rights.  As you know, these are longstanding U.S. values that are part of all of our discussions, as Dan just described as well.</p>
<p>The Secretary is really interested in exploring how we can broaden economic prosperity.  As you know, we’re committed to contributing to efforts to build Africa’s self-sufficiency and resilience and to promote inclusive development.  To that end, we’re working with African governments and businesses, entrepreneurs, civil society, the U.S. private sector, and IFIs and MDBs to accelerate sustainable economic growth across the continent and to help Africans manage the disruptive economic shock of COVID and the food security crisis caused by Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>Finally, the Secretary will focus on the devastating impacts of climate change.  We are continuing to partner with African leaders to tackle the climate crisis and to work together on clean energy development and to provide needed tools and innovation to transition for the future.  We will want to consult on the decision to open up the Congolese rain forest to oil and gas exploration.  The consequences for the DRC, for Africa, and for the world are immense.  And we’ll also want to continue to work with the Congolese Government on how they can best diversify and grow their economy sustainably.</p>
<p>Just to note, we’ve had a lot of travel to Africa this summer.  In June, Under Secretary Nuland went to Somalia, Djibouti, Mozambique, and Nigeria.  Under Secretary Zeya just returned from a trip to Mozambique and Namibia.  Derek Chollet this week has been in Senegal, and Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield is going next week to Uganda and Rwanda.  We’ll also have a lot of CODELs in August.  So all of this is designed to create opportunities for us to meet our partners in person and to collaborate on these critical issues.</p>
<p>Over to you, Ned.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Terrific.  We have time for a few questions.  Operator, if you wouldn’t mind repeating the instructions to ask a question.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR: </b> Once again, ladies and gentlemen, if you do have a question, press * then 0 at this moment.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  We’ll start with the line of Jennifer Hansler, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  We can.  Go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Awesome.  Thank you.  Are there any plans for the Secretary to meet with Foreign Minister Lavrov while they are both in Cambodia for the ministerial?  And then on Paul Rusesabagina, will the Secretary be warning about any consequences should they continue to detain him, and what would those consequences be?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Jenny, I’ll start with your first question.  We have no plans to meet with Foreign Minister Lavrov when they are in Cambodia.  I’ll turn it over to Assistant Secretary Phee on your second.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY PHEE:</b>  Thanks, Ned.  Yeah, I don’t want to get ahead of those discussions with President Kagame.  We’ve been very clear with the Government of Rwanda about our concerns about his case, his trial, and his conviction, particularly the lack of fair trial guarantees in his case.  And I’m looking forward to the opportunity for this issue to be discussed at a senior level.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  We’ll go to the line of Dave Lawler.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Ned, a question on the last two stops, Rwanda and DRC.  I assume part of the reason for choosing those locations is to try to reduce tensions between them.  Can you talk a bit about that?  And you spoke about the need to respect territorial integrity; obviously, DRC has said Rwanda is arming and supporting the M23 rebels and so violating its territorial integrity.  I guess does the U.S. have any position on whether that is the case, and is it a problem for the U.S. if that is the case?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY PHEE:</b>  I think, as everybody knows, the situation in eastern Congo has tragically been volatile for about two decades, with over five million people who’ve lost their lives there, and a range of armed actors who also seek sanctuary in neighboring countries.</p>
<p>Recently, a few months ago, the Kenyans launched an initiative known as the Nairobi Process to try and work with the Congolese and neighboring countries to get a grip on the role of armed groups, including M23, and that effort has begun, I think, to address the concerns.  Angola also hosted both the – President Kagame and President Tshisekedi just a few weeks ago to help urge de-escalation in tension.  And I know that Secretary Blinken hopes to contribute to these conversations and see what the United States can do to reinforce these regional diplomatic efforts and to see how we can help calm the situation.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  We’ll go to the line of Simon Lewis, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi, thank you.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Simon, your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thanks.  Hi, thank you.  So the first question: Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink – I will – I just wanted to ask a couple of things on the Asia side of the trip.  One thing:  Is there any plans for a bilateral with Wang Yi during the Cambodia event?  And I wondered if you could give us an update given the recent developments in Myanmar with the execution of activists.  Does that change the thinking on potentially sanctioning the oil and gas enterprise?  Is that getting any closer to happening?</p>
<p>And I just wanted to follow up on the questions on Rwanda to Assistant Secretary Phee.  I just wondered, in the light of the letter that Senator Menendez wrote to the – to the Secretary about Rwanda, do – is there – is this sort of U.S. aid to Rwanda under discussion during this trip?  Is that something that – given those concerns about Paul Rusesabagina and also the Rwandan development with the M23 fighting, are you looking at reducing the level of aid that goes there?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Dan, would you like to start?</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY KRITENBRINK:</b>  Absolutely.  Thanks very much for the question.  Look, on your first question I would say at this point there are no formal or official plans to sit down and meet with State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi, particularly since the Secretary just saw him a couple of weeks ago, as you’re aware, in Bali, where they met for more than five hours and had a very candid and productive and comprehensive conversation.  But as you know, at these multilateral meetings there often are opportunities for pull-asides.  So we’ll see how things develop, but no formal plans at this point.</p>
<p>On your second question, on Myanmar, thanks very much for raising that.  Look, again, I’ll just reiterate: I think the international community is really horrified and incensed by these inhuman and heinous executions that were just carried out.  But really, this is just the latest demonstration of the regime’s brutality, which thus far has murdered more than 2,100 Burmese since the coup d’état.  What I would say is that you can see the depth of that indignation through the various international statements that have been issued.  Of course, the Secretary spoke, our friends in ASEAN issued a statement, the G7 has issued a statement, and other likeminded partners have as well.</p>
<p>As far as additional steps, this will be a real focus of our conversations at the ASEAN meetings in Cambodia.  I would just underscore that all options are on the table, including related to MOGE.  Certainly don’t have anything to announce today, but I think it’s fair to say that we’ll consider any and all means necessary to increase pressure on the regime in Burma and to cut off their funding streams that continue to fuel their repression.  And so we’ll continue to examine all of that across the board, and at the same time we’ll keep in mind that we want to make sure whatever we do, it doesn’t exacerbate the already difficult circumstances in which the Burmese people find themselves.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY PHEE:</b>  So on Rwanda, Secretary Blinken had an opportunity a few days ago to speak to Senator Menendez about his letter, and he told him that he intended to raise the issues outlined in the letter when he has an opportunity to speak with President Kagame, that that would be part of the discussion of a range of topics that he hopes to review with President Kagame.</p>
<p>So, as I said before, I don’t want to get ahead of that discussion.  I think it’s great that we’re going to have the opportunity to engage at a senior level and explore what’s possible for our future relationship.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  We’ll go to the line of Ryohei Takagi.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Can you hear me okay?</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Yes, please go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you, Ned and Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink.  I just wonder whether he will meet his counterparts from the DPRK on the sidelines of ASEAN Regional Forum in Cambodia.  And secondly, you have mentioned the security cooperation between Cambodia and the PRC.  It has been reported that China is secretly building a naval facility in Cambodia.  So could you tell us some updates on it, and what is the U.S. position to it?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY KRITENBRINK:</b>  Thank you for your questions.  I can say clearly that there are no plans to meet with North Korean counterparts.  You do point out rightly that North Korea is represented in the ASEAN Regional Forum.  I don’t have any information in front of me who may or may not be present representing North Korea, but no plans to meet with them, although I am confident that the Secretary will speak directly to the situation in North Korea during his intervention at the ARF.</p>
<p>You mentioned Cambodian security cooperation with the PRC, and I noted that in my opening comments as well.  Look, we’ve been crystal clear, and the Secretary has as well and the Deputy Secretary and myself publicly, that we have encouraged the Government of Cambodia to be fully transparent about the intent, nature, and scope of its project at Ream and the role of the PRC military in its construction there.  Certainly I think a number of us have significant concerns about that facility there, and in particular any exclusive PRC military presence at Ream would risk diminishing Cambodia’s autonomy and undermining regional security.  So again, we’ll have an opportunity to convey that message to Cambodian friends again, and I am confident that others in the region will as well.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Julian Pecquet.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you.  Sorry, I had a similar question regarding, more specifically, on any sanctions or anything else that you might announce.  I know you can’t talk about that, but is Roger Carstens traveling with the Secretary?  And more broadly, can you talk about other people who might be on the trip to Africa in particular?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY PHEE:</b>  The Secretary is taking several leaders to join him, particularly in South Africa, where we’re doing the Strategic Dialogue.  Under Secretary Jose Fernandez will be joining us; the head of USTDA, the Trade and Development Association, will be joining us; our new head of PEPFAR, who we stole from Africa CDC, the great Dr. John – I’m going to mispronounce his name – Nkengasong – I apologize; and also colleagues from HHS.  And Under Secretary Fernandez will also join the Secretary in Congo.  So Roger’s not traveling with the Secretary on this trip.  That’ll be a subject the Secretary himself will raise.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  And we’ll conclude with the line of Pearl Matibe.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you, Ned, and thank you so much, Assistant Secretary Phee.  My question is regarding South Africa.  So as evidence has shown in several countries, if unemployment and indigenous land and indigenous wealth is not tackled, conflict can follow.  So could you possibly preview for us how does the Secretary plan to concretely address issues of unemployment?</p>
<p>And then also, do you think that he might address the notion of foreign powers being viewed as an increasing – by an increasing number of – in the population, including young people, as the second most significant driver of negative change in South Africa?</p>
<p>And I know that you have always said that human rights is part and parcel or threaded into your interactions.  Will he address brutality and the extent of xenophobic violence and human rights of migrants while he is there?  I’d appreciate your comments on these, Secretary Phee.  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY PHEE:</b>  So thanks very much for your question and for highlighting those important concerns.  I wanted to draw your attention to the speech that he will deliver.  He spoke, as you may recall, when he was in Nigeria last November about U.S. policy and our approach towards Africa, and the formal announcement of this strategy is of course consistent with what he outlined and what we’ve been doing since the administration came into office.</p>
<p>But it will be an amplification of our conviction that partnership with Africa is really critical to meeting shared challenges.  And those shared challenges really include economic issues, and we recognize the incredible youth dynamic and the challenge that poses for African societies in terms of employment, and that’s why we’re working hard to mobilize greater trade and investment in Africa to help African economies develop in a way that addresses that youth bulge and also that is consistent with our shared climate change goals, as I said, to develop in a sustainable way.</p>
<p>So I think those themes will be very public while he’s there.  And again, as I said earlier, he always discusses – he believes passionately in human rights, and he always discusses it in all of his stops.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Excellent.  Well, thank you very much to our two speakers, Assistant Secretary Phee, Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink, and for everyone for tuning in.  Just a reminder this call was on the record, and the embargo is now lifted.  Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="100000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-japanese-foreign-minister-hayashi-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 20:52:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=364185</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Japanese Minister for Foreign Affairs Hayashi Yoshimasa in Washington, DC to reaffirm the vital importance of the U.S.-Japan Alliance in promoting peace, security, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region and beyond. Secretary Blinken reiterated the United States’ unwavering support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and committed to continue working closely with Japan to hold Russia accountable and end its aggression against Ukraine. The Secretary and the Foreign Minister discussed collaboration through the Quad and the importance of U.S.-Japan cooperation with like-minded partners, such as the Republic of Korea and Australia, for maintaining a free, open, interconnected, prosperous, resilient, and secure Indo-Pacific region.</p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Japanese Minister for Foreign Affairs Hayashi Yoshimasa in Washington, DC to reaffirm the vital importance of the U.S.-Japan Alliance in promoting peace, security, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region and beyond. Secretary Blinken reiterated the United States’ unwavering support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and committed to continue working closely with Japan to hold Russia accountable and end its aggression against Ukraine. The Secretary and the Foreign Minister discussed collaboration through the Quad and the importance of U.S.-Japan cooperation with like-minded partners, such as the Republic of Korea and Australia, for maintaining a free, open, interconnected, prosperous, resilient, and secure Indo-Pacific region.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken, Secretary Raimondo, Foreign Minister Hayashi, and Minister Hagiuda at a Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinken-secretary-raimondo-foreign-minister-hayashi-and-minister-hagiuda-at-a-press-availability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 20:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=364177</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>Dean Acheson Auditorium</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Good afternoon, everyone.  So we just concluded the inaugural meeting of the new U.S.-Japan Economic Consultative Committee, otherwise known as the EPCC or “epic.”  Secretary Raimondo and I were very glad to welcome our colleagues here to Washington today.  Foreign Minister Hayashi and I saw each other just a few weeks ago in Bali for the G20 and then in Tokyo, where I had the opportunity to convey the profound sympathy and sorrow of the American people to the people of Japan after the assassination of Prime Minister Abe.</p>
<p>As you may know, the EPCC was a product of President Biden and Prime Minister Kishida’s meeting in January, their first major talk after the prime minister took office last fall.  They agreed that the U.S.-Japan alliance has never been stronger or more necessary and that our countries should deepen our cooperation to strengthen the rules-based economic order to address urgent challenges facing our workers, our businesses, people, and accelerate open, inclusive, and sustainable economic growth in the Indo-Pacific and beyond.</p>
<p>Today’s first meeting of the EPCC was, I think it’s fair to say, a resounding success: productive, substantive, directly connected to issues that matter in our peoples’ lives and in their futures.  We discussed building resilient supply chains after the COVID-19 pandemic revealed just how fragile they are.  We addressed emerging technologies which bring so much promise of opportunity but also risks to national security, human rights, consumer health and safety, intellectual property.</p>
<p>We talked about Moscow’s war on Ukraine.  Our countries are working closely to impose costs on Russia so that President Putin will end the war and address, of course, in the meantime food and fuel prices worldwide that have been spiked in part because of Russia’s aggression.  We discussed development finance and the problem of opaque lending practices that can weigh down countries with unsustainable debt.</p>
<p>And we addressed the People’s Republic of China and how its coercive economic practices go against an open, inclusive rules-based international economic order that gives all countries a chance to participate, to compete, and to grow.  Japan and the United States believe in a global economy where all countries hold themselves to norms, to standards, to practices that allow people, ideas, goods, capital to move freely; where disputes are resolved swiftly, peacefully, openly; and where trade and commerce support workers, raise incomes, protect the environment, and create opportunity for as many people as possible.  The EPCC is the latest addition to an ever growing partnership with Japan.</p>
<p>A few months ago in Tokyo, our two countries joined 12 others to launch the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework to support a stronger, fair, more resilient economy across the region.  Our countries work together through the Quad with India and Australia on issues from global health to the climate crisis to infrastructure.  We cooperate through the OECD to tackle bribery and corruption, through the Global Action Plan to fight COVID-19, through the new Mineral Security Partnership to bolster critical mineral supply chains.</p>
<p>And beyond all of these different initiatives and fora, the bilateral relationship between Japan and the United States encompasses just about every issue we face, from protecting our national security, to defending human rights, to advancing our vision for a free and open Indo-Pacific region.  The work that we did today, making clear together that our economic security is a vital component of our overall national security and well-being, I think just underscores the importance and the breadth and depth of our partnership.</p>
<p>We are deeply grateful for our alliance with Japan.  It stretches back decades, sustained by cherished ties of family and friendship between our peoples.  The work we did here today reflects the strength of that partnership but also importantly carries it forward.</p>
<p>On a separate note, earlier today I spoke with Russian Foreign Minister Lavrov.  We had a frank and direct conversation.  I pressed the Kremlin to accept the substantial proposal that we put forth on the release of Paul Whelan and Brittney Griner.  I also emphasized that the world expects Russia to fulfill its commitments under the deal it reached with Ukraine, Turkey, and the United Nations on grain shipments from Ukraine.  Ambassador Brink, our ambassador to Ukraine, was in Odessa this morning.  She confirmed that the ships are loaded and ready to go.  It is important and vital that Russia make good on the commitments it’s made – made to the world.  As I made clear, we’re looking to see that move forward as soon as possible.</p>
<p>I also made clear to Foreign Minister Lavrov that in light of recent statements coming from the Kremlin about their plans to proceed with the further annexation of Ukrainian territory – indeed, the foreign minister’s own words about replacing democratically elected Ukrainian Government as well as being part of their ongoing plans – those plans would never be accepted.  The world will not recognize annexations.</p>
<p>We will impose additional significant costs on Russia if it moves forward with its plans.  We’ll also continue to stand with Ukraine, support its ability to defend itself, impose costs on Russia until it ends its aggression.  We continue to coordinate closely with allies and partners, including very closely with Japan, to support Ukraine and to hold Moscow to account.  And as always, we’re prepared to work with Ukraine and others to support any meaningful diplomatic efforts to end the war, to end the aggression.</p>
<p>So with that, let me just thank my colleagues so much for an incredibly productive meeting and for designing together the way ahead and to make sure that the EPCC really is an epic achievement between our countries.  Thank you.</p>
<p>Yoshi.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI: </strong> (Via interpreter) Hello, everyone.  This is my very first visit to Washington, D.C., as a minister of foreign affairs.  First, I would like to extend my sincere gratitude for President Biden, Secretary Blinken, and many people from the United States Government for your deepest condolences for the passing of former Prime Minister Abe.  I would like to thank the thoughts extended by the people in the United States.</p>
<p>We have just come out of the very first ministerial-level Economic 2+2 with Secretary Blinken, Secretary Raimondo, and Minister Hagiuda.  We had a very fruitful exchange of thoughts.  I would like again to thank both secretaries for their wonderful hospitality.  The Economic 2+2 is the first attempt in the alliance of Japan and the United States to discuss foreign and security policy and economic policy as a unit.  In a background, there is a shared urgency between Japan and the United States that existing international order is challenged not only by unilateral attempt to change the status quo by force, but also by attempt to realize strategic interest by exerting economic influence in unfair and opaque ways.</p>
<p>In order to respond to such crisis effectively, today four ministers from Japan and the United States gathered and discussed a wide variety of issues, including economic policies of respective countries, establishment of regional economic order, and economic security.  This is the response to the requirement of time, and I believe it serves as a strong message about the adaptability of Japan-U.S. alliance in a rapidly changing international economy and about the resolve by Japan and United States to lead the international cooperation in this area.</p>
<p>Today we discussed the following points and confirmed on the cooperation.  First, we discussed a rules-based, free, and open international order.  As the economy has a strong influence on diplomacy today, Japan and the United States confirmed that we would cooperate with likeminded countries not only from the economic perspective but also from a strategic perspective in order to maintain and develop international order to ensure economic security.</p>
<p>Regarding energy security and food security, we discussed assistance to those countries that are gravely impacted by the invasion of Ukraine by Russia.</p>
<p>Also I expressed Japan’s support of IPEF and as the United States plays more active role in economic order of the Indo-Pacific region, and conveyed my strong hope to both secretaries that the United States come back to TPP soon.</p>
<p>Second, we discussed response to the exertion of international economic influence to hinder – sorry, intentional economic influence to hinder solidarity in the international community, and to distort foreign policies of different countries and confirmed on a shared awareness.  Economic coercion issue was also taken up by G7 Elmau summit, and I hope to deepen the discussion towards the G7 Hiroshima summit.</p>
<p>Also, regarding the unfair and opaque development finance, I hope that Japan and the United States can work together to ensure all countries comply to the international rules and standards.</p>
<p>In addition, we agreed that for Japan and the United States to ensure our own competitiveness and resilience, we will continue to promote cooperation based on core partnership that was concurred in April last year.  We also agreed to establish stronger supply chain cooperating with likeminded countries.</p>
<p>I would like to reiterate that we are not pursuing protectionism or bloc economy, but any policy will give due consideration to transparency and predictability for businesses.  I hope that we can continue to deepen our discussion in various related areas with likeminded countries, taking opportunities of occasion such as G7, chaired by Japan, and APEC, chaired by the United States.  We have agreed to hold the ministerial meeting on a regular basis, and I look forward to our next meeting.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you, good afternoon, and thank you to Secretary Blinken for hosting us, bringing us together.  And thank you to Ministers Hagiuda and Hayashi for joining us and for being present here in the United States for this very important meeting.  I also would like to join with Tony in expressing my condolences to our colleagues and to the people of Japan for the tragic loss of Prime Minister Abe.</p>
<p>So I share the assessment with Secretary Blinken that today’s meeting was a resounding success.  We had candid, productive, open, substantive discussion, and I’m very proud of the joint progress on promoting economic growth, addressing threats to the global order, and enhancing security and resilience.</p>
<p>The close ties between the United States and Japan support good jobs in both of our countries and contribute to our mutual prosperity and security.  Our alliance is an increasingly important force for peace and prosperity not only in the Indo-Pacific region but, in fact, throughout the world.</p>
<p>I also want to acknowledge how deeply grateful I am that Congress yesterday finally approved funding for the CHIPS Act.  As we discussed today, semiconductors are the linchpin of our economic and national security, and we had an excellent discussion today around how Japan and the United States could collaborate, especially with respect to advanced semiconductors.  The $52 billion investment in the CHIPS Act in domestic semiconductor production will enable us to create hundreds of thousands of jobs in the United States, rebuild American manufacturing, and strengthen our supply chain for decades to come.</p>
<p>Just as important, this funding will strengthen our partnerships with allies like Japan.  It will enhance our joint work on supply chains, promote the competitiveness of both of our nations, and importantly, make us less dependent on our adversaries for such a critical piece of technology.  It will build on – excuse me.  Just as importantly, the funding will strengthen our partnerships and will build on the meeting that Minister Hagiuda and I had in May, where we expressed shared intent for cooperation on semiconductor supply chains.</p>
<p>I look forward to the day, not too far from now, where here in America we have American-made chips supplying Japanese auto plants here in the United States.  Together our two nations are leading the way in investing in our futures.  So again, I just want to thank Minister Hagiuda and Minister Hayashi for joining us.  Thank you for your efforts to forge new and stronger bonds between our nations, our communities, and our people.</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER HAGIUDA: </strong>(Via interpreter) I am Hagiuda Koichi, Minister of Economy, Trade, and Industry.  First I express also my gratitude to American people for sending heartfelt condolences to former Prime Minister Abe.  Japan-U.S. alliance is a cornerstone of Japan’s diplomacy.  Former Prime Minister Abe has always said so.  On his historic visit to Hiroshima and Pearl Harbor with President Obama, I also accompanied them as then-deputy chief cabinet secretary.  Former Prime Minister Abe has staked his political life throughout, while making Japan-U.S. people’s ties stronger.</p>
<p>President Biden came to Japanese Embassy to express condolences.  Secretary Blinken came to Japan, and Secretary Raimondo gave us a heartfelt message.  I understand within the United States, flag was hoisted half-mast at many places, not only government buildings.  It shows deep ties at people’s level between our two countries.  In place of former Prime Minister Abe, I sincerely express my gratitude from the bottom of our heart.</p>
<p>“Japan is back,” Prime Minister Abe declared in Washington about 10 years ago.  Japan will once again exert leadership with the United States, the champion of democracy, hand in hand for peace and prosperity of the world.  So the determination was expressed in CPTPP, free and open Indo-Pacific, Quad, over a decade that its foundation underpinning peace and prosperity of the region was built.  State Secretary Blinken the other day said he feels such a loss.  Frankly, entire Japan is covered with a big sense of loss.</p>
<p>However, Japan is here to stay.  Going forward, Japan will work hand in hand with the United States and work toward peace and prosperity of the world.  To clearly state our determination to you, I came here.  Today, for the very first time, Economic 2+2 was held.  The framework has been laid down.  Supply chain risk, economic coercion, foreign security policy, and economic policy have become inseparable.  Under such an era, Japan-U.S. foreign and economic ministers are meeting together, having a intensive discussion and sending the unified messages to the world.  Its significance is very large.</p>
<p>To address new challenges such as digital, a new economic order based on rules will be built under U.S. administration’s leadership with wide participation of countries in the region.  We welcome that new economic architecture is being built at the IPEF.  Energy secretary, business and human rights, developing trusted infrastructure such as information communication, supply chain resilience such as batteries and critical minerals and such and such – there are heaps of issues out there to be tackled.</p>
<p>This time, alongside a joint statement, plan of action on specific items was also released.  This is a big outcome.  In critical and emerging technologies like space, ocean, and cyber cooperation will be strengthened, and economic security will be ensured.  Today, substantial time was spent on these topics for discussion.  Issues will be dealt with in an offensive way as well as defensive way at the same time; combined with protection with export control, advanced technology development will be promoted.</p>
<p>We concurred to accelerate the Japan-U.S. joint development over next-generation semi-conductors.  Japan will quickly move to action.  Japan’s wisdom will be collected from AIST, RIKEN, and University of Tokyo own research on next-generation semiconductor research.  Decision was made to launch a new R&amp;D organization.  It will be open to overseas businesses and to research institutes.  It will be an international joint research hub.  We are determined to collect the strength of Japan, science and technology-based nation, and lead a cooperation between Japan and the United States and among likeminded countries.  Unilateral use of economic force in violation of international rules to fulfill diplomatic demand should never happen.</p>
<p>From the Pacific Ocean to Indian Ocean, this wide expanse of ocean and sky is free and open to anyone.  Regardless of the size of the country, it should bring benefit to all the countries.  This economic 2+2 is, as it were, compass for realizing free and open Indo-Pacific.  This is a foundation for peace and prosperity of the region.  Toward that end, together with Commerce Secretary Raimondo, State Secretary Blinken, and Foreign Minister Hayashi, who are all here, I am determined to do my best.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll now turn to questions.  We’ll alternate two per side.  We’ll start with Shaun Tandon of the AFP.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi.  Good morning.  Good afternoon.  Mr. Secretary, could I begin by following up on your remarks about your conversation with Foreign Minister Lavrov?  How confident are you about this raising the chances of bringing home Brittney Griner and Paul Whelan?  What is the sense that you got from Foreign Minister Lavrov?  I know also you mentioned earlier this week that you’re not planning to negotiate on Ukraine with the Russians, but what was the overall sense that you got from Foreign Minister Lavrov?  Are you any more confident that the United States could be dealing with Russia and making progress in any area there?  And do you plan to speak to him again or even meet him?  As was announced today, you’re going to be in Cambodia next week for ASEAN.</p>
<p>And perhaps, if I could open up to everybody here – a week of phone calls, I suppose.  The phone call yesterday that the President had with President Xi of China, does this – do you feel that this makes any progress on the issue of Taiwan?  How concerned are you about the tensions in Taiwan right now, and a potential visit by Speaker Pelosi.  Do you think that – are you confident that that’s something that you can work through or are you worried about that aggravating the situation?  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Shaun, thank you very much.  First, just to put this in perspective, we said all along that if we thought there was any opportunity to advance diplomacy to end Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, we would of course take it.  Unfortunately, tragically, we’ve seen no opening, willingness on the part of Russia to engage meaningfully on ending the aggression.  At the same time, I’ve also said that if there are issues where it could make a difference in senior Russians hearing directly from me or from colleagues, we would of course pursue that.</p>
<p>And with regard to the call with the foreign minister today, as I noted the other day when we had an opportunity to speak, I told you what I intended to raise with him, and I raised exactly what I said I would raise with him – that is, the significant proposal that’s been on the table for some weeks now that would lead to bringing home Paul Whelan and Brittney Griner.  I urged Foreign Minister Lavrov to move forward with that proposal.  I’m not going to characterize his response, and I can’t give you an assessment of whether I think things are any more or less likely, but it was important that he heard directly from me on that.</p>
<p>Second, as I said the other day, on behalf of many, many countries around the world, getting Russia to move on the commitments it’s made – not just to the United Nations, Turkey, and Ukraine in the context of the deal that was agreed, but to the entire world that is looking for an end to the blockade of the Odessa port by Russia that has denied so many people the food that they need and depend on and has also resulted in a significant increase in food prices over many months – important that he hear directly from me on behalf of many other countries the expectation that Russia would move forward with its commitments and would stop, end the blockade, and allow the ships to sail.</p>
<p>And finally, you’ve heard me say the other day the deep concern that many countries around the world have in hearing in recent days about Russia’s expanded war aims in Ukraine, particularly their plans to proceed with the annexation of additional Ukrainian territory.  And I laid out exactly what we anticipate they will do in the weeks and months ahead – including having sham referendums in these parts of Ukraine, trying to falsely demonstrate that the people in these parts of Ukraine somehow seek to become part of Russia – all to advance President Putin’s objectives in gobbling up as much Ukrainian territory as he can and, from his perspective, trying to erase Ukraine as an independent, sovereign country.</p>
<p>That of course is not going to happen.  The Ukrainian people have made clear that that’s not going to happen, and the world has made clear they’re not going to let that happen.  But short of that, President Putin is trying to grab as much Ukrainian territory as he can, and it was very important that the Russians hear directly from us that that will not be accepted – and not only will it not be accepted; it will result in additional significant costs being imposed upon Russia if it follows through on those plans.</p>
<p>So I don’t want to characterize any of Foreign Minister Lavrov’s responses.  If you have an opportunity to ask him, please proceed.</p>
<p>With regard to the call between President Biden and President Xi, first, as you know, this followed previous discussions, including most recently in March, and it also builds on a number of recent engagements, including the time I spent with Foreign Minister Wang Yi in Bali where we spent about five hours together.  The National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, the Secretary of Defense, the Treasury Secretary, the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff have each had recent conversations or engagements with their counterparts.  And this is part of our effort to make sure that we maintain and deepen lines of communication with China to responsibly manage the many differences that we have and to work together wherever it is that our interests align.  And that was very much the nature of the conversation.</p>
<p>I can just say, again, it covered basically three things: where our two countries can work together, with a particular focus on climate change, on health security, on counternarcotics; second, an exchange of views on Russia’s aggression in Ukraine; and finally, Taiwan, where President Biden underscored that our policy has not changed.  The United States strongly opposes any unilateral efforts to change the status quo or to undermine peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait.  So that was the nature and basically the substance of the conversation they had.  They touched on a number of other issues.</p>
<p>But look, I’ll just say this in conclusion.  We have many differences when it comes to Taiwan, but over the past 40-plus years, we have managed those differences and done it in a way that has preserved peace and stability and has allowed the people on Taiwan to flourish.  It would be important as part of our shared responsibility to continue to manage this in a wise way that doesn’t create the prospect for conflict.  And keeping open lines of communication on this issue, especially between President Biden and President Xi, I think is vital to doing that.  We believe direct communication between the leaders is the most essential aspect of meeting our responsibilities to manage issues as fraught as Taiwan in the most responsible way possible.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Mr. Matsuura from Kyodo.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Thank you very much for the opportunity.  This is Matsuura.  This is a question to Minister Hayashi and Secretary Blinken.  Looking back at the history of Japan-U.S. relations, it was in 1990 that Security 2+2 was upgraded to the ministerial level.  Today 2+2 has been expanded to economic area, and the Japan-U.S. alliance has come to the new stage.  On the other hand, in the international community China is attempting to widely broaden its influence, leveraging its economic power.  So what is the significance of Japan and the United States coming together to try and maintain and strengthen the economic order?  Also, how do you plan to build on today’s discussion in G7 and with ASEAN, as they have a strong economic tie with China?</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:  </strong>(Via interpreter) First of all, Japan and the U.S. have been working together in solidarity to make sure that unilateral attempt to change status quo would not be allowed in the international community.  On the other hand, as I said at the outset, for Japan and U.S. to effectively respond to the unfair and opaque use of economic influence, it is necessary to think about diplomacy, security, and economy as a unit.  In particular, since the United States and Japan are number one and two democratic economies in the world, it would be beneficial for us to discuss strategically about the policies to be implemented in such situation.  Economic 2+2 is here to respond to this kind of requirement of this era, and to demonstrate that the alliance can adapt to the changes in the international environment.</p>
<p>Based on today’s Economic 2+2 discussion, the Governments of Japan and the United States will promote cooperation in various area and work to maintain and develop orders in the international community, including Indo-Pacific region.  Also, for forming international economic order, not only cooperation between Japan and United States, but also cooperation with likeminded countries is essential.  We hope to share strategic cooperation and issues that we discussed today at Economic 2+2 with the G7 countries in the summit chaired by Japan next year so that we can further expand the cooperation.</p>
<p>Also, regarding the relationship with ASEAN, Japan and the United States have always respected the unity and centrality of ASEAN while promoting concrete cooperation towards achievement of free and open Indo-Pacific and ASEAN Outlook on Indo-Pacific.  We will continue to closely cooperate with regional partners, aiming to achieve sustainable and inclusive economic growth in Indo-Pacific region and economic security that we discussed today during the Economic 2+2 and also by utilizing framework such as IPEF by the United States.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>I agree with everything that my colleague has said.  I would simply add a couple of points or reinforce a couple of points.  First, the United States and Japan share a conviction that economic security and national security are inseparable.  They are fundamentally linked.  And I think it was very important to both of us and our – all of our colleagues to further elevate the discussions we’re having on economic security issues because they’re really front and center on our agenda and on the world’s agenda and the very – the issues that you heard us talk about today I think really go to in many ways very practical things that our people in Japan and the United States and beyond are feeling and experiencing in their lives.  And we have a shared conviction that working together we can make a genuine difference in advancing opportunity and dealing with challenges to the wellbeing of our people in the economic sphere.  So that’s the most important thing.</p>
<p>Second, I would simply say that many of the initiatives that we’re engaged in together, whether it’s between the United States and Japan, whether it’s in the context of ASEAN, IPEF, the Quad; these are mutually reinforcing.  And they in affect add strength to each other, and I think we saw that today because many of the things that we talked about overlap with issues that are on the agenda of IPEF, the Quad, et cetera.  When the United States and Japan can work together to help drive some of these issues – and next year, as you know, Japan will be in the lead of the G7 – we will be in the lead of APEC – we can make a big, big difference in actually moving forward.</p>
<p>The last thing is this: we get to stand up here and share with all of you the results of our meeting.  The truth of the matter is, there are a number of people who are sitting with us today and others who are back in their ministries in Tokyo and here in Washington, who really drive the work every single day.  So we’ve agreed that we will meet again among the four of us next year, but in‑between then we’ve laid out a very detailed and concrete agenda for our teams to follow up on between now and the end of the year and then into next year so that not only have we set out a basic vision together and framework for the work that our countries can do; we’ll actually follow up with concrete initiatives to make all of this real.  So I think that’s the other importance of today, an agreement that we’re really going to drive this forward together over the next months.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>(Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, thank you for doing this.  Mr. Foreign Minister, I wonder – starting on Taiwan, is the Japanese Government making any contingency planning from a security perspective for a potential crisis in the near term, whether that would be prompted by a visit from Speaker Pelosi or some other visit?  And does the Japanese Government envision a role for the G7 to intervene with any economic leverage to deter or mitigate the risk of escalation in such a crisis?</p>
<p>Secretary Raimondo, you’ve spoken before about the Russian military being forced to strip semiconductors from kitchen appliances in Ukraine.  Do you have any sense of whether those supply constraints that they have are imposing a time limit on their military operations there?  And more generally, do you see that being applicable in a – with respect to China in a crisis or even on the other foot, does the U.S. have sufficient semiconductor supplies to see it through a Taiwan crisis in the near term?</p>
<p>And then to Secretary Blinken, the U.S.S. Ronald Reagan Carrier Striker is in the South China Sea, but there’s been a lot of ink spilled on the vulnerability of the surface fleet if there were a crisis with China.  Are you having any conversations about a near term prepositioning of defense assets and – with Japan or other allies in the region next week?</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Thank you for your question.  Regarding the visit by Speaker Pelosi, as a – we are not in the position as the Japanese Government to comment on that.  Now, going on to – between Japan and the U.S. in May in a summit at the Joint Declaration regarding Taiwan, the basic approach to Taiwan has not been changed.  It – Taiwan Strait peace and prosperity is important – remains the same.  And a peaceful resolution of the Strait issue has been agreed upon between the leaders.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:  </strong>Thank you.  With respect to the export controls, we have reason to believe that with each passing week and month, the export controls have an even more devastating effect on Russia’s ability to continue this war.  As the – they developed a stockpile in preparation for the war for these sorts of technology and spare parts.  As that continues to dwindle, their ability to continue to operate is reduced significantly.</p>
<p>I will say the reason that these export controls are having such an effect is because we’re doing them in coordination with our allies, first among them the Japanese.  I mean, this isn’t the United States acting alone; we have a coalition of 36 countries.  Japan stepped up immediately.  And together, we are denying Russia parts, including semiconductors, and importantly, as we discussed today, collaborating on enforcement.  And we will continue to collaborate on enforcement to continue to deny Russia what it needs to continue this war.</p>
<p>With respect to the United States, I have no concern that we have an ability to meet our needs.  And furthermore, the fact that Congress acted yesterday on the CHIPS Act is an enormous step forward to ensure that we’ll be able to protect ourselves and our allies and have adequate semiconductor supplies for decades to come.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  And with regard to any contingencies and any preparations made on a military level, I defer to the Pentagon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Well, I have a question to both Minister Hagiuda and Secretary Raimondo.  Well, economically, competition can take place and it might develop into a trade friction – it had happened in the past.  But what do you think about the alliance relationship covering the economic area?  And what are you thinking about further strengthening the semiconductor supply chain?  What will be the future state of cooperation between Japan and U.S., particularly in the semiconductor?  And also, do you have a plan to widen the framework between the Japan and the United States?</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER HAGIUDA:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you for your question.  Well, when you talk about competition, it should be based on the free and fair rules.  Then it can drive economic growth and can be a source of vitality.  We are the world’s number one and number three economic power.  Japan and U.S. will work closely, encouraging each other and enhance competitiveness and grow together.</p>
<p>On the other hand, problems have come about that there are conduct which might threaten economic order or free and fair rules.  Sometimes one country may use force of superiority over supply chain to their advantage.  Economic coercion violating international rule is totally unacceptable.  Freedom, democracy, basic human rights, rule of law – these are the universal values we share together between our two countries.  We need to keep on adhering to the economic order based on the rule.  We are always looking for a level playing field in terms of the competition so that a region of peace and prosperity’s foundation can be laid down.  That is a big responsibility incumbent upon the two countries.</p>
<p>Next-generation semiconductor technology development would determine the future and show competitiveness – top priority area for cooperation.  Leaders’ summit in May had agreed to have a joint task force on the research and development of next-generation semiconductor research.  Already met last month.  And together with Secretary Raimondo, we agreed on the basic principle for the cooperation on semiconductor.  We will work with likeminded countries to expand our cooperation toward a 2020s realization of R&amp;D on the next-generation semiconductors, HRD, and supply chain resilience.  We are going to put that into action.</p>
<p>We will look into the future implementation R&amp;D.  As I said, AIST, RIKEN, and University of Tokyo will offer their expertise in the next-generation semiconductor research.  Wisdom will be collected to launch a new R&amp;D organization.  It will be made open to overseas businesses and research institutes, inclusive of Japan, U.S., and likeminded countries in the region.  We hope to make into a hub for the international joint research.</p>
<p>Right before this press conference, I had a bilateral with Secretary Raimondo, and thanks to her effort, CHIPS Act have passed in the United States.  It’s epoch-making.   And there is going to be a way where further commitment can be made on both public and private side.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:</strong>  Extremely well said by my colleague.  I concur with everything he said.  I would simply underscore two points.</p>
<p>One, in the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, which we have launched and – with Japan and a dozen other economies in the Indo-Pacific, there is a pillar focused on supply chains, and we expect that a core piece of work in the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework in supply chains will be focused on semiconductors, aligning research and development, coordinating on export controls, working together.</p>
<p>Secondly, after the passage of the CHIPS Act, our goal now – the Department of Commerce will be implementing the CHIPS Act with the goal of rebuilding the entire semiconductor supply chain in America, and we welcome Japanese foreign direct investment into the United States as we develop that supply chain.  Specifically in the areas of chemicals and substrates, materials, the Japanese are world leaders – tooling – and we look forward to – and as the minister said, research and development in emerging technology.  It’s impossible to overstate the significance of Congress’s action yesterday and the opportunity for collaboration that that opens for the United States and Japan to strengthen the semiconductor supply chain.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  That concludes the press conference.  Thank you, Your Excellencies.  Thank you, everyone.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="100001000111" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>Dean Acheson Auditorium</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Good afternoon, everyone.  So we just concluded the inaugural meeting of the new U.S.-Japan Economic Consultative Committee, otherwise known as the EPCC or “epic.”  Secretary Raimondo and I were very glad to welcome our colleagues here to Washington today.  Foreign Minister Hayashi and I saw each other just a few weeks ago in Bali for the G20 and then in Tokyo, where I had the opportunity to convey the profound sympathy and sorrow of the American people to the people of Japan after the assassination of Prime Minister Abe.</p>
<p>As you may know, the EPCC was a product of President Biden and Prime Minister Kishida’s meeting in January, their first major talk after the prime minister took office last fall.  They agreed that the U.S.-Japan alliance has never been stronger or more necessary and that our countries should deepen our cooperation to strengthen the rules-based economic order to address urgent challenges facing our workers, our businesses, people, and accelerate open, inclusive, and sustainable economic growth in the Indo-Pacific and beyond.</p>
<p>Today’s first meeting of the EPCC was, I think it’s fair to say, a resounding success: productive, substantive, directly connected to issues that matter in our peoples’ lives and in their futures.  We discussed building resilient supply chains after the COVID-19 pandemic revealed just how fragile they are.  We addressed emerging technologies which bring so much promise of opportunity but also risks to national security, human rights, consumer health and safety, intellectual property.</p>
<p>We talked about Moscow’s war on Ukraine.  Our countries are working closely to impose costs on Russia so that President Putin will end the war and address, of course, in the meantime food and fuel prices worldwide that have been spiked in part because of Russia’s aggression.  We discussed development finance and the problem of opaque lending practices that can weigh down countries with unsustainable debt.</p>
<p>And we addressed the People’s Republic of China and how its coercive economic practices go against an open, inclusive rules-based international economic order that gives all countries a chance to participate, to compete, and to grow.  Japan and the United States believe in a global economy where all countries hold themselves to norms, to standards, to practices that allow people, ideas, goods, capital to move freely; where disputes are resolved swiftly, peacefully, openly; and where trade and commerce support workers, raise incomes, protect the environment, and create opportunity for as many people as possible.  The EPCC is the latest addition to an ever growing partnership with Japan.</p>
<p>A few months ago in Tokyo, our two countries joined 12 others to launch the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework to support a stronger, fair, more resilient economy across the region.  Our countries work together through the Quad with India and Australia on issues from global health to the climate crisis to infrastructure.  We cooperate through the OECD to tackle bribery and corruption, through the Global Action Plan to fight COVID-19, through the new Mineral Security Partnership to bolster critical mineral supply chains.</p>
<p>And beyond all of these different initiatives and fora, the bilateral relationship between Japan and the United States encompasses just about every issue we face, from protecting our national security, to defending human rights, to advancing our vision for a free and open Indo-Pacific region.  The work that we did today, making clear together that our economic security is a vital component of our overall national security and well-being, I think just underscores the importance and the breadth and depth of our partnership.</p>
<p>We are deeply grateful for our alliance with Japan.  It stretches back decades, sustained by cherished ties of family and friendship between our peoples.  The work we did here today reflects the strength of that partnership but also importantly carries it forward.</p>
<p>On a separate note, earlier today I spoke with Russian Foreign Minister Lavrov.  We had a frank and direct conversation.  I pressed the Kremlin to accept the substantial proposal that we put forth on the release of Paul Whelan and Brittney Griner.  I also emphasized that the world expects Russia to fulfill its commitments under the deal it reached with Ukraine, Turkey, and the United Nations on grain shipments from Ukraine.  Ambassador Brink, our ambassador to Ukraine, was in Odessa this morning.  She confirmed that the ships are loaded and ready to go.  It is important and vital that Russia make good on the commitments it’s made – made to the world.  As I made clear, we’re looking to see that move forward as soon as possible.</p>
<p>I also made clear to Foreign Minister Lavrov that in light of recent statements coming from the Kremlin about their plans to proceed with the further annexation of Ukrainian territory – indeed, the foreign minister’s own words about replacing democratically elected Ukrainian Government as well as being part of their ongoing plans – those plans would never be accepted.  The world will not recognize annexations.</p>
<p>We will impose additional significant costs on Russia if it moves forward with its plans.  We’ll also continue to stand with Ukraine, support its ability to defend itself, impose costs on Russia until it ends its aggression.  We continue to coordinate closely with allies and partners, including very closely with Japan, to support Ukraine and to hold Moscow to account.  And as always, we’re prepared to work with Ukraine and others to support any meaningful diplomatic efforts to end the war, to end the aggression.</p>
<p>So with that, let me just thank my colleagues so much for an incredibly productive meeting and for designing together the way ahead and to make sure that the EPCC really is an epic achievement between our countries.  Thank you.</p>
<p>Yoshi.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI: </strong> (Via interpreter) Hello, everyone.  This is my very first visit to Washington, D.C., as a minister of foreign affairs.  First, I would like to extend my sincere gratitude for President Biden, Secretary Blinken, and many people from the United States Government for your deepest condolences for the passing of former Prime Minister Abe.  I would like to thank the thoughts extended by the people in the United States.</p>
<p>We have just come out of the very first ministerial-level Economic 2+2 with Secretary Blinken, Secretary Raimondo, and Minister Hagiuda.  We had a very fruitful exchange of thoughts.  I would like again to thank both secretaries for their wonderful hospitality.  The Economic 2+2 is the first attempt in the alliance of Japan and the United States to discuss foreign and security policy and economic policy as a unit.  In a background, there is a shared urgency between Japan and the United States that existing international order is challenged not only by unilateral attempt to change the status quo by force, but also by attempt to realize strategic interest by exerting economic influence in unfair and opaque ways.</p>
<p>In order to respond to such crisis effectively, today four ministers from Japan and the United States gathered and discussed a wide variety of issues, including economic policies of respective countries, establishment of regional economic order, and economic security.  This is the response to the requirement of time, and I believe it serves as a strong message about the adaptability of Japan-U.S. alliance in a rapidly changing international economy and about the resolve by Japan and United States to lead the international cooperation in this area.</p>
<p>Today we discussed the following points and confirmed on the cooperation.  First, we discussed a rules-based, free, and open international order.  As the economy has a strong influence on diplomacy today, Japan and the United States confirmed that we would cooperate with likeminded countries not only from the economic perspective but also from a strategic perspective in order to maintain and develop international order to ensure economic security.</p>
<p>Regarding energy security and food security, we discussed assistance to those countries that are gravely impacted by the invasion of Ukraine by Russia.</p>
<p>Also I expressed Japan’s support of IPEF and as the United States plays more active role in economic order of the Indo-Pacific region, and conveyed my strong hope to both secretaries that the United States come back to TPP soon.</p>
<p>Second, we discussed response to the exertion of international economic influence to hinder – sorry, intentional economic influence to hinder solidarity in the international community, and to distort foreign policies of different countries and confirmed on a shared awareness.  Economic coercion issue was also taken up by G7 Elmau summit, and I hope to deepen the discussion towards the G7 Hiroshima summit.</p>
<p>Also, regarding the unfair and opaque development finance, I hope that Japan and the United States can work together to ensure all countries comply to the international rules and standards.</p>
<p>In addition, we agreed that for Japan and the United States to ensure our own competitiveness and resilience, we will continue to promote cooperation based on core partnership that was concurred in April last year.  We also agreed to establish stronger supply chain cooperating with likeminded countries.</p>
<p>I would like to reiterate that we are not pursuing protectionism or bloc economy, but any policy will give due consideration to transparency and predictability for businesses.  I hope that we can continue to deepen our discussion in various related areas with likeminded countries, taking opportunities of occasion such as G7, chaired by Japan, and APEC, chaired by the United States.  We have agreed to hold the ministerial meeting on a regular basis, and I look forward to our next meeting.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you, good afternoon, and thank you to Secretary Blinken for hosting us, bringing us together.  And thank you to Ministers Hagiuda and Hayashi for joining us and for being present here in the United States for this very important meeting.  I also would like to join with Tony in expressing my condolences to our colleagues and to the people of Japan for the tragic loss of Prime Minister Abe.</p>
<p>So I share the assessment with Secretary Blinken that today’s meeting was a resounding success.  We had candid, productive, open, substantive discussion, and I’m very proud of the joint progress on promoting economic growth, addressing threats to the global order, and enhancing security and resilience.</p>
<p>The close ties between the United States and Japan support good jobs in both of our countries and contribute to our mutual prosperity and security.  Our alliance is an increasingly important force for peace and prosperity not only in the Indo-Pacific region but, in fact, throughout the world.</p>
<p>I also want to acknowledge how deeply grateful I am that Congress yesterday finally approved funding for the CHIPS Act.  As we discussed today, semiconductors are the linchpin of our economic and national security, and we had an excellent discussion today around how Japan and the United States could collaborate, especially with respect to advanced semiconductors.  The $52 billion investment in the CHIPS Act in domestic semiconductor production will enable us to create hundreds of thousands of jobs in the United States, rebuild American manufacturing, and strengthen our supply chain for decades to come.</p>
<p>Just as important, this funding will strengthen our partnerships with allies like Japan.  It will enhance our joint work on supply chains, promote the competitiveness of both of our nations, and importantly, make us less dependent on our adversaries for such a critical piece of technology.  It will build on – excuse me.  Just as importantly, the funding will strengthen our partnerships and will build on the meeting that Minister Hagiuda and I had in May, where we expressed shared intent for cooperation on semiconductor supply chains.</p>
<p>I look forward to the day, not too far from now, where here in America we have American-made chips supplying Japanese auto plants here in the United States.  Together our two nations are leading the way in investing in our futures.  So again, I just want to thank Minister Hagiuda and Minister Hayashi for joining us.  Thank you for your efforts to forge new and stronger bonds between our nations, our communities, and our people.</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER HAGIUDA: </strong>(Via interpreter) I am Hagiuda Koichi, Minister of Economy, Trade, and Industry.  First I express also my gratitude to American people for sending heartfelt condolences to former Prime Minister Abe.  Japan-U.S. alliance is a cornerstone of Japan’s diplomacy.  Former Prime Minister Abe has always said so.  On his historic visit to Hiroshima and Pearl Harbor with President Obama, I also accompanied them as then-deputy chief cabinet secretary.  Former Prime Minister Abe has staked his political life throughout, while making Japan-U.S. people’s ties stronger.</p>
<p>President Biden came to Japanese Embassy to express condolences.  Secretary Blinken came to Japan, and Secretary Raimondo gave us a heartfelt message.  I understand within the United States, flag was hoisted half-mast at many places, not only government buildings.  It shows deep ties at people’s level between our two countries.  In place of former Prime Minister Abe, I sincerely express my gratitude from the bottom of our heart.</p>
<p>“Japan is back,” Prime Minister Abe declared in Washington about 10 years ago.  Japan will once again exert leadership with the United States, the champion of democracy, hand in hand for peace and prosperity of the world.  So the determination was expressed in CPTPP, free and open Indo-Pacific, Quad, over a decade that its foundation underpinning peace and prosperity of the region was built.  State Secretary Blinken the other day said he feels such a loss.  Frankly, entire Japan is covered with a big sense of loss.</p>
<p>However, Japan is here to stay.  Going forward, Japan will work hand in hand with the United States and work toward peace and prosperity of the world.  To clearly state our determination to you, I came here.  Today, for the very first time, Economic 2+2 was held.  The framework has been laid down.  Supply chain risk, economic coercion, foreign security policy, and economic policy have become inseparable.  Under such an era, Japan-U.S. foreign and economic ministers are meeting together, having a intensive discussion and sending the unified messages to the world.  Its significance is very large.</p>
<p>To address new challenges such as digital, a new economic order based on rules will be built under U.S. administration’s leadership with wide participation of countries in the region.  We welcome that new economic architecture is being built at the IPEF.  Energy secretary, business and human rights, developing trusted infrastructure such as information communication, supply chain resilience such as batteries and critical minerals and such and such – there are heaps of issues out there to be tackled.</p>
<p>This time, alongside a joint statement, plan of action on specific items was also released.  This is a big outcome.  In critical and emerging technologies like space, ocean, and cyber cooperation will be strengthened, and economic security will be ensured.  Today, substantial time was spent on these topics for discussion.  Issues will be dealt with in an offensive way as well as defensive way at the same time; combined with protection with export control, advanced technology development will be promoted.</p>
<p>We concurred to accelerate the Japan-U.S. joint development over next-generation semi-conductors.  Japan will quickly move to action.  Japan’s wisdom will be collected from AIST, RIKEN, and University of Tokyo own research on next-generation semiconductor research.  Decision was made to launch a new R&amp;D organization.  It will be open to overseas businesses and to research institutes.  It will be an international joint research hub.  We are determined to collect the strength of Japan, science and technology-based nation, and lead a cooperation between Japan and the United States and among likeminded countries.  Unilateral use of economic force in violation of international rules to fulfill diplomatic demand should never happen.</p>
<p>From the Pacific Ocean to Indian Ocean, this wide expanse of ocean and sky is free and open to anyone.  Regardless of the size of the country, it should bring benefit to all the countries.  This economic 2+2 is, as it were, compass for realizing free and open Indo-Pacific.  This is a foundation for peace and prosperity of the region.  Toward that end, together with Commerce Secretary Raimondo, State Secretary Blinken, and Foreign Minister Hayashi, who are all here, I am determined to do my best.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll now turn to questions.  We’ll alternate two per side.  We’ll start with Shaun Tandon of the AFP.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi.  Good morning.  Good afternoon.  Mr. Secretary, could I begin by following up on your remarks about your conversation with Foreign Minister Lavrov?  How confident are you about this raising the chances of bringing home Brittney Griner and Paul Whelan?  What is the sense that you got from Foreign Minister Lavrov?  I know also you mentioned earlier this week that you’re not planning to negotiate on Ukraine with the Russians, but what was the overall sense that you got from Foreign Minister Lavrov?  Are you any more confident that the United States could be dealing with Russia and making progress in any area there?  And do you plan to speak to him again or even meet him?  As was announced today, you’re going to be in Cambodia next week for ASEAN.</p>
<p>And perhaps, if I could open up to everybody here – a week of phone calls, I suppose.  The phone call yesterday that the President had with President Xi of China, does this – do you feel that this makes any progress on the issue of Taiwan?  How concerned are you about the tensions in Taiwan right now, and a potential visit by Speaker Pelosi.  Do you think that – are you confident that that’s something that you can work through or are you worried about that aggravating the situation?  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Shaun, thank you very much.  First, just to put this in perspective, we said all along that if we thought there was any opportunity to advance diplomacy to end Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, we would of course take it.  Unfortunately, tragically, we’ve seen no opening, willingness on the part of Russia to engage meaningfully on ending the aggression.  At the same time, I’ve also said that if there are issues where it could make a difference in senior Russians hearing directly from me or from colleagues, we would of course pursue that.</p>
<p>And with regard to the call with the foreign minister today, as I noted the other day when we had an opportunity to speak, I told you what I intended to raise with him, and I raised exactly what I said I would raise with him – that is, the significant proposal that’s been on the table for some weeks now that would lead to bringing home Paul Whelan and Brittney Griner.  I urged Foreign Minister Lavrov to move forward with that proposal.  I’m not going to characterize his response, and I can’t give you an assessment of whether I think things are any more or less likely, but it was important that he heard directly from me on that.</p>
<p>Second, as I said the other day, on behalf of many, many countries around the world, getting Russia to move on the commitments it’s made – not just to the United Nations, Turkey, and Ukraine in the context of the deal that was agreed, but to the entire world that is looking for an end to the blockade of the Odessa port by Russia that has denied so many people the food that they need and depend on and has also resulted in a significant increase in food prices over many months – important that he hear directly from me on behalf of many other countries the expectation that Russia would move forward with its commitments and would stop, end the blockade, and allow the ships to sail.</p>
<p>And finally, you’ve heard me say the other day the deep concern that many countries around the world have in hearing in recent days about Russia’s expanded war aims in Ukraine, particularly their plans to proceed with the annexation of additional Ukrainian territory.  And I laid out exactly what we anticipate they will do in the weeks and months ahead – including having sham referendums in these parts of Ukraine, trying to falsely demonstrate that the people in these parts of Ukraine somehow seek to become part of Russia – all to advance President Putin’s objectives in gobbling up as much Ukrainian territory as he can and, from his perspective, trying to erase Ukraine as an independent, sovereign country.</p>
<p>That of course is not going to happen.  The Ukrainian people have made clear that that’s not going to happen, and the world has made clear they’re not going to let that happen.  But short of that, President Putin is trying to grab as much Ukrainian territory as he can, and it was very important that the Russians hear directly from us that that will not be accepted – and not only will it not be accepted; it will result in additional significant costs being imposed upon Russia if it follows through on those plans.</p>
<p>So I don’t want to characterize any of Foreign Minister Lavrov’s responses.  If you have an opportunity to ask him, please proceed.</p>
<p>With regard to the call between President Biden and President Xi, first, as you know, this followed previous discussions, including most recently in March, and it also builds on a number of recent engagements, including the time I spent with Foreign Minister Wang Yi in Bali where we spent about five hours together.  The National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, the Secretary of Defense, the Treasury Secretary, the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff have each had recent conversations or engagements with their counterparts.  And this is part of our effort to make sure that we maintain and deepen lines of communication with China to responsibly manage the many differences that we have and to work together wherever it is that our interests align.  And that was very much the nature of the conversation.</p>
<p>I can just say, again, it covered basically three things: where our two countries can work together, with a particular focus on climate change, on health security, on counternarcotics; second, an exchange of views on Russia’s aggression in Ukraine; and finally, Taiwan, where President Biden underscored that our policy has not changed.  The United States strongly opposes any unilateral efforts to change the status quo or to undermine peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait.  So that was the nature and basically the substance of the conversation they had.  They touched on a number of other issues.</p>
<p>But look, I’ll just say this in conclusion.  We have many differences when it comes to Taiwan, but over the past 40-plus years, we have managed those differences and done it in a way that has preserved peace and stability and has allowed the people on Taiwan to flourish.  It would be important as part of our shared responsibility to continue to manage this in a wise way that doesn’t create the prospect for conflict.  And keeping open lines of communication on this issue, especially between President Biden and President Xi, I think is vital to doing that.  We believe direct communication between the leaders is the most essential aspect of meeting our responsibilities to manage issues as fraught as Taiwan in the most responsible way possible.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Mr. Matsuura from Kyodo.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Thank you very much for the opportunity.  This is Matsuura.  This is a question to Minister Hayashi and Secretary Blinken.  Looking back at the history of Japan-U.S. relations, it was in 1990 that Security 2+2 was upgraded to the ministerial level.  Today 2+2 has been expanded to economic area, and the Japan-U.S. alliance has come to the new stage.  On the other hand, in the international community China is attempting to widely broaden its influence, leveraging its economic power.  So what is the significance of Japan and the United States coming together to try and maintain and strengthen the economic order?  Also, how do you plan to build on today’s discussion in G7 and with ASEAN, as they have a strong economic tie with China?</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:  </strong>(Via interpreter) First of all, Japan and the U.S. have been working together in solidarity to make sure that unilateral attempt to change status quo would not be allowed in the international community.  On the other hand, as I said at the outset, for Japan and U.S. to effectively respond to the unfair and opaque use of economic influence, it is necessary to think about diplomacy, security, and economy as a unit.  In particular, since the United States and Japan are number one and two democratic economies in the world, it would be beneficial for us to discuss strategically about the policies to be implemented in such situation.  Economic 2+2 is here to respond to this kind of requirement of this era, and to demonstrate that the alliance can adapt to the changes in the international environment.</p>
<p>Based on today’s Economic 2+2 discussion, the Governments of Japan and the United States will promote cooperation in various area and work to maintain and develop orders in the international community, including Indo-Pacific region.  Also, for forming international economic order, not only cooperation between Japan and United States, but also cooperation with likeminded countries is essential.  We hope to share strategic cooperation and issues that we discussed today at Economic 2+2 with the G7 countries in the summit chaired by Japan next year so that we can further expand the cooperation.</p>
<p>Also, regarding the relationship with ASEAN, Japan and the United States have always respected the unity and centrality of ASEAN while promoting concrete cooperation towards achievement of free and open Indo-Pacific and ASEAN Outlook on Indo-Pacific.  We will continue to closely cooperate with regional partners, aiming to achieve sustainable and inclusive economic growth in Indo-Pacific region and economic security that we discussed today during the Economic 2+2 and also by utilizing framework such as IPEF by the United States.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>I agree with everything that my colleague has said.  I would simply add a couple of points or reinforce a couple of points.  First, the United States and Japan share a conviction that economic security and national security are inseparable.  They are fundamentally linked.  And I think it was very important to both of us and our – all of our colleagues to further elevate the discussions we’re having on economic security issues because they’re really front and center on our agenda and on the world’s agenda and the very – the issues that you heard us talk about today I think really go to in many ways very practical things that our people in Japan and the United States and beyond are feeling and experiencing in their lives.  And we have a shared conviction that working together we can make a genuine difference in advancing opportunity and dealing with challenges to the wellbeing of our people in the economic sphere.  So that’s the most important thing.</p>
<p>Second, I would simply say that many of the initiatives that we’re engaged in together, whether it’s between the United States and Japan, whether it’s in the context of ASEAN, IPEF, the Quad; these are mutually reinforcing.  And they in affect add strength to each other, and I think we saw that today because many of the things that we talked about overlap with issues that are on the agenda of IPEF, the Quad, et cetera.  When the United States and Japan can work together to help drive some of these issues – and next year, as you know, Japan will be in the lead of the G7 – we will be in the lead of APEC – we can make a big, big difference in actually moving forward.</p>
<p>The last thing is this: we get to stand up here and share with all of you the results of our meeting.  The truth of the matter is, there are a number of people who are sitting with us today and others who are back in their ministries in Tokyo and here in Washington, who really drive the work every single day.  So we’ve agreed that we will meet again among the four of us next year, but in‑between then we’ve laid out a very detailed and concrete agenda for our teams to follow up on between now and the end of the year and then into next year so that not only have we set out a basic vision together and framework for the work that our countries can do; we’ll actually follow up with concrete initiatives to make all of this real.  So I think that’s the other importance of today, an agreement that we’re really going to drive this forward together over the next months.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>(Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, thank you for doing this.  Mr. Foreign Minister, I wonder – starting on Taiwan, is the Japanese Government making any contingency planning from a security perspective for a potential crisis in the near term, whether that would be prompted by a visit from Speaker Pelosi or some other visit?  And does the Japanese Government envision a role for the G7 to intervene with any economic leverage to deter or mitigate the risk of escalation in such a crisis?</p>
<p>Secretary Raimondo, you’ve spoken before about the Russian military being forced to strip semiconductors from kitchen appliances in Ukraine.  Do you have any sense of whether those supply constraints that they have are imposing a time limit on their military operations there?  And more generally, do you see that being applicable in a – with respect to China in a crisis or even on the other foot, does the U.S. have sufficient semiconductor supplies to see it through a Taiwan crisis in the near term?</p>
<p>And then to Secretary Blinken, the U.S.S. Ronald Reagan Carrier Striker is in the South China Sea, but there’s been a lot of ink spilled on the vulnerability of the surface fleet if there were a crisis with China.  Are you having any conversations about a near term prepositioning of defense assets and – with Japan or other allies in the region next week?</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Thank you for your question.  Regarding the visit by Speaker Pelosi, as a – we are not in the position as the Japanese Government to comment on that.  Now, going on to – between Japan and the U.S. in May in a summit at the Joint Declaration regarding Taiwan, the basic approach to Taiwan has not been changed.  It – Taiwan Strait peace and prosperity is important – remains the same.  And a peaceful resolution of the Strait issue has been agreed upon between the leaders.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:  </strong>Thank you.  With respect to the export controls, we have reason to believe that with each passing week and month, the export controls have an even more devastating effect on Russia’s ability to continue this war.  As the – they developed a stockpile in preparation for the war for these sorts of technology and spare parts.  As that continues to dwindle, their ability to continue to operate is reduced significantly.</p>
<p>I will say the reason that these export controls are having such an effect is because we’re doing them in coordination with our allies, first among them the Japanese.  I mean, this isn’t the United States acting alone; we have a coalition of 36 countries.  Japan stepped up immediately.  And together, we are denying Russia parts, including semiconductors, and importantly, as we discussed today, collaborating on enforcement.  And we will continue to collaborate on enforcement to continue to deny Russia what it needs to continue this war.</p>
<p>With respect to the United States, I have no concern that we have an ability to meet our needs.  And furthermore, the fact that Congress acted yesterday on the CHIPS Act is an enormous step forward to ensure that we’ll be able to protect ourselves and our allies and have adequate semiconductor supplies for decades to come.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  And with regard to any contingencies and any preparations made on a military level, I defer to the Pentagon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Well, I have a question to both Minister Hagiuda and Secretary Raimondo.  Well, economically, competition can take place and it might develop into a trade friction – it had happened in the past.  But what do you think about the alliance relationship covering the economic area?  And what are you thinking about further strengthening the semiconductor supply chain?  What will be the future state of cooperation between Japan and U.S., particularly in the semiconductor?  And also, do you have a plan to widen the framework between the Japan and the United States?</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER HAGIUDA:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you for your question.  Well, when you talk about competition, it should be based on the free and fair rules.  Then it can drive economic growth and can be a source of vitality.  We are the world’s number one and number three economic power.  Japan and U.S. will work closely, encouraging each other and enhance competitiveness and grow together.</p>
<p>On the other hand, problems have come about that there are conduct which might threaten economic order or free and fair rules.  Sometimes one country may use force of superiority over supply chain to their advantage.  Economic coercion violating international rule is totally unacceptable.  Freedom, democracy, basic human rights, rule of law – these are the universal values we share together between our two countries.  We need to keep on adhering to the economic order based on the rule.  We are always looking for a level playing field in terms of the competition so that a region of peace and prosperity’s foundation can be laid down.  That is a big responsibility incumbent upon the two countries.</p>
<p>Next-generation semiconductor technology development would determine the future and show competitiveness – top priority area for cooperation.  Leaders’ summit in May had agreed to have a joint task force on the research and development of next-generation semiconductor research.  Already met last month.  And together with Secretary Raimondo, we agreed on the basic principle for the cooperation on semiconductor.  We will work with likeminded countries to expand our cooperation toward a 2020s realization of R&amp;D on the next-generation semiconductors, HRD, and supply chain resilience.  We are going to put that into action.</p>
<p>We will look into the future implementation R&amp;D.  As I said, AIST, RIKEN, and University of Tokyo will offer their expertise in the next-generation semiconductor research.  Wisdom will be collected to launch a new R&amp;D organization.  It will be made open to overseas businesses and research institutes, inclusive of Japan, U.S., and likeminded countries in the region.  We hope to make into a hub for the international joint research.</p>
<p>Right before this press conference, I had a bilateral with Secretary Raimondo, and thanks to her effort, CHIPS Act have passed in the United States.  It’s epoch-making.   And there is going to be a way where further commitment can be made on both public and private side.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:</strong>  Extremely well said by my colleague.  I concur with everything he said.  I would simply underscore two points.</p>
<p>One, in the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, which we have launched and – with Japan and a dozen other economies in the Indo-Pacific, there is a pillar focused on supply chains, and we expect that a core piece of work in the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework in supply chains will be focused on semiconductors, aligning research and development, coordinating on export controls, working together.</p>
<p>Secondly, after the passage of the CHIPS Act, our goal now – the Department of Commerce will be implementing the CHIPS Act with the goal of rebuilding the entire semiconductor supply chain in America, and we welcome Japanese foreign direct investment into the United States as we develop that supply chain.  Specifically in the areas of chemicals and substrates, materials, the Japanese are world leaders – tooling – and we look forward to – and as the minister said, research and development in emerging technology.  It’s impossible to overstate the significance of Congress’s action yesterday and the opportunity for collaboration that that opens for the United States and Japan to strengthen the semiconductor supply chain.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  That concludes the press conference.  Thank you, Your Excellencies.  Thank you, everyone.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="100001000111" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary of State for International Organization Affairs Michele J. Sison’s Travel to India, Bangladesh, and Kuwait</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-of-state-for-international-organization-affairs-michele-j-sisons-travel-to-india-bangladesh-and-kuwait/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 20:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=364170</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for International Organization Affairs Michele J. Sison will travel to India, Bangladesh, and Kuwait August 2-10 for consultations on a range of U.S. multilateral priorities, including combating food insecurity, advancing global health, addressing human rights and humanitarian needs, peacekeeping and peacebuilding, and support for Rohingya refugees.  Her meetings with senior government officials will focus on opportunities to deepen our cooperation at the United Nations, and U.S. support for the candidacy of Doreen Bogdan-Martin to become the next Secretary-General of the International Telecommunication Union.  In meetings with civil society leaders, the Assistant Secretary will exchange ideas on how the United States and other countries can collaborate on achieving the Sustainable Development Goals.</p>
<p>For updates, follow @State_IO on Twitter.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="100000000000" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for International Organization Affairs Michele J. Sison will travel to India, Bangladesh, and Kuwait August 2-10 for consultations on a range of U.S. multilateral priorities, including combating food insecurity, advancing global health, addressing human rights and humanitarian needs, peacekeeping and peacebuilding, and support for Rohingya refugees.  Her meetings with senior government officials will focus on opportunities to deepen our cooperation at the United Nations, and U.S. support for the candidacy of Doreen Bogdan-Martin to become the next Secretary-General of the International Telecommunication Union.  In meetings with civil society leaders, the Assistant Secretary will exchange ideas on how the United States and other countries can collaborate on achieving the Sustainable Development Goals.</p>
<p>For updates, follow @State_IO on Twitter.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="100000000000" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement of the U.S.-Japan Economic Policy Consultative Committee: Strengthening Economic Security and the Rules-Based Order</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-of-the-u-s-japan-economic-policy-consultative-committee-strengthening-economic-security-and-the-rules-based-order/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 19:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=364105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and Japan on the occasion of the inaugural ministerial meeting of the U.S.-Japan Economic Policy Consultative Committee.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text</em></p>
<p>United States Secretary of State Antony Blinken and Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo co-hosted Japan’s Minister for Foreign Affairs HAYASHI Yoshimasa and Minister of Economy, Trade and Industry HAGIUDA Koichi for the inaugural ministerial meeting of the U.S.-Japan Economic Policy Consultative Committee (EPCC) on July 29, 2022. The Ministers affirmed their shared resolve to present a positive economic vision that highlights the benefits of a rules-based international economic order and emphasized the need to make our economies more competitive and resilient.</p>
<p>The Ministers considered the complex global economic context that has produced increased levels of risk and uncertainty for all. They noted recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic remains incomplete, and the pandemic has contributed to various economic challenges including supply chain disruptions, increasing commodity prices, and greater inequalities, many of which have disproportionately impacted historically underserved communities. The Ministers strongly condemned Russia’s brutal, unprovoked, and unjustified aggression against Ukraine and shared the view that it has exacerbated such challenges and undermined energy and food security around the world. The Ministers affirmed the need to address the climate crisis in the face of complications due to energy insecurity.</p>
<p>The Ministers also recognized the pandemic has significantly altered social and economic life through accelerated adoption of various technologies, including digital transformation, providing new opportunities as well as challenges. They noted technological innovation &#8211; including in critical and emerging technologies such as artificial intelligence, quantum technologies, and renewable and circular technologies &#8211; presents transformative potential, as well as risks for our economies if abused. The Ministers committed to continue taking steps to realize a full and sustainable recovery from the pandemic and enhance the international order in the post-pandemic world to optimize new opportunities and prepare for unprecedented challenges.</p>
<p>The Ministers resolved that the United States and Japan stand for open, sustainable, and inclusive economic growth that delivers prosperity, upholds democratic values, reduces economic disparities, and protects human rights in the Indo-Pacific region and beyond. They reiterated the importance of commitments to promote broad-based economic prosperity for our middle classes, including through economic and foreign policies that benefit workers and small businesses and increase women’s economic participation. They intend to promote this vision through the EPCC and other platforms, including the G7, APEC, and the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity (IPEF). They committed to advancing policies that support a multilateral trading system based on free and fair trade and that counter economic coercion and non-market policies and practices, emphasizing the importance of offering workers, businesses, and countries around the world a level playing field.</p>
<p>The Ministers shared the view that the United States and Japan, as the world’s two largest democratic economies, can demonstrate that democracies provide the best model for prosperity, stability, and security. In this context, the Ministers committed to continue sharing insights and exchanging views on our respective economic agendas, including President Biden’s plan to build from the bottom up and the middle out, as well as Prime Minister Kishida’s “new form of capitalism.” They further reviewed ways to defend workers, companies, and investors against the harms of unfair, anti-competitive, and non-market policies and practices. The Ministers also welcomed cooperation between the two countries in furtherance of shared objectives under the CoRe Partnership, as well as with like-minded partners, and emphasized our joint leadership in enhancing the rules-based economic order and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region and beyond.</p>
<p>The Ministers committed to countering threats to economic security and to the rules-based international economic order and noted recent developments in both countries, including passage of Japan’s Economic Security Promotion Act. The Ministers focused on the resilience and diversification of critical supply chains to promote their transparency, security, and sustainability. The Ministers also intend to collaborate in promoting and protecting critical and emerging technologies in a manner consistent with international rules and norms, including through research and development, as well as export controls, so as to support technological competitiveness and resilience and to address the challenges posed by the illicit diversion of technology critical for weapons development.</p>
<p>The Ministers expressed grave concern about, and opposition to, harmful uses of economic influence, including economic coercion as well as unfair and opaque lending practices, in ways that threaten the legitimate interests of sovereign nations, as well as those of individuals and industries. The Ministers affirmed these practices undermine legitimate sovereign choices, challenge the free and open rules-based international order, and are best addressed through a collective response. Respecting the importance of sustainable finance for long-term economic growth and development, they stressed the need to work together bilaterally and multilaterally to promote fair and transparent development finance across all debtors and creditors in accordance with internationally recognized principles, rules, and standards. In addressing these issues, the Ministers expressed their intention to deepen discussions and foster cooperation among like-minded partners.</p>
<p>The Ministers emphasized their conviction that economic security is indispensable to overall security, and that diplomacy and economic policy are intertwined and require a coordinated approach. Towards that end, the EPCC can provide an essential channel for bilateral collaboration, and the Ministers also confirmed their intention to meet periodically in this forum and to cooperate on economic priorities during the United States’ 2023 APEC host year and Japan’s Presidency of the G7 in 2023.</p>
<p>Recognizing the importance of carrying forward the priorities identified under the EPCC, the Ministers charged their undersecretaries and vice-ministers with implementing the EPCC Plan of Action based on their economic vision, ensuring robust private sector engagement to inform ongoing efforts, and convening the next EPCC vice-ministerial meeting before the end of 2022.</p>
<h2>U.S.-Japan Economic Policy Consultative Committee 2022 Plan of Action</h2>
<h3>Realizing Peace and Prosperity through the Rules-Based Economic Order</h3>
<ol>
<li>The United States and Japan pledge to further improve competitiveness and resilience by expanding and deepening cooperation based on the CoRe Partnership. The two countries seek to further enhance cooperation, stability, prosperity, development, and peace in the Indo-Pacific region through innovative economic arrangements including the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity (IPEF).</li>
<li>The United States and Japan are united in our strong condemnation of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine. The two countries remain steadfast in our solidarity with Ukraine and continue to support Ukraine. In this regard, the two countries welcomed the Lugano Declaration.</li>
<li>The United States and Japan are committed to working together to mitigate the effects of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine on markets for energy and food. The two countries underscore the need to sustain momentum toward energy transition and decarbonization, and we recognize the roles of renewable energy, nuclear power, ammonia, clean hydrogen-based solutions, carbon capture utilization and storage, as well as carbon recycling in achieving long-term energy security and net zero greenhouse gas emissions no later than 2050. The United States and Japan also acknowledge the need to strengthen investment in the energy sector and to ensure secure energy resources in the near term, including liquefied natural gas (LNG), in response to the current crisis. Japan welcomes the increase of U.S. shale oil and gas production as needed to stabilize global energy markets. The two countries further affirm the necessity of supporting energy security and methane emissions reductions in the Indo-Pacific region and globally. The two countries also commend the progress of advanced nuclear reactor projects and pledge to work together to create more resilient nuclear supply chains.</li>
<li>The United States and Japan pledge to support the openness of our agricultural supply chains, reaffirming the importance of not imposing export prohibitions or restrictions on food in a manner inconsistent with relevant WTO provisions, and seek to cooperate with other partners to strengthen global food security. The two countries also call on all countries to implement policies that improve sustainability and productivity in food production, and to develop resiliency in agriculture, food systems, and the food supply chain, and to promote access to agricultural inputs such as fertilizer. In this regard, the two countries reiterated the importance of the Ministerial Declaration on the Emergency Response to Food Insecurity adopted at the 12th Session of the Ministerial Conference of the World Trade Organization. In addition, the United States and Japan encourage dialogue between producer and consumer countries as well as the use of data to enhance global food security.</li>
<li>The United States and Japan commit to enhancing international efforts to address barriers on cross-border data flows, while respecting different approaches to data governance. The two countries further reaffirm the role of U.S.-Japan cooperation in multilateral initiatives, such as promotion and expansion of the newly established Global Cross-Border Privacy Rules (CBPR) Forum and support for efforts to develop the OECD Trusted Government Access to Personal Data Held by the Private Sector. In doing so, U.S.-Japan cooperation advances a common understanding and foundation to promote data free flow with trust among like-minded democracies.</li>
<li>In cooperation with interagency partners, the United States and Japan intend to promote information sharing on cybersecurity threats including through discussion of threat assessment and mitigation efforts in the Japan-U.S. Cyber Dialogue. We also affirm our intention to collaborate on the Japan-U.S.-EU Industrial Control Systems Cybersecurity Week for the Indo-Pacific region.</li>
<li>The United States and Japan are committed to coordination on business and human rights to foster an environment in which companies uphold human rights, and we welcome ongoing bilateral discussions.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Countering Economic Coercion and Unfair and Opaque Lending Practices</h3>
<ol start="8">
<li>The United States and Japan pledge to coordinate with other like-minded partners to address and respond to economic coercion, effectively confront non-market policies and practices, and deliver calibrated messaging to the international community, including in multilateral fora such as the WTO, OECD, G7, and G20.</li>
<li>To help ensure debt transparency and sustainability, internationally coordinated debt treatments, fair lending practices that respect the autonomy of debtor countries, and society-friendly infrastructure investment, the United States and Japan call on all actors to adhere to international rules, standards, and recognized principles, including the G20 Principles for Quality Infrastructure Investment and the G20 Common Framework for Debt Treatments beyond the Debt Service Suspension Initiative. The two countries further call on all major economies to adhere to other relevant international obligations and standards, as appropriate, including the OECD Anti-Bribery Convention and the OECD Guidelines for Multinational Enterprises.</li>
<li>The United States and Japan plan to work together to promote fair and transparent development finance. We emphasize the critical role of creditor coordination to ensure fair burden sharing among all creditors in debt treatments under the Common Framework and for other vulnerable countries, such as Sri Lanka.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Promoting and Securing Critical and Emerging Technologies and Critical Infrastructure</h3>
<ol start="11">
<li>The United States and Japan, noting the transformative opportunities that technological innovation provides, commit to explore and support joint research and development projects for critical and emerging technologies both between the United States and Japan and among like-minded partners.</li>
<li>In support of the U.S.-Japan Global Digital Connectivity Partnership, the United States and Japan intend to continue supporting efforts to deploy secure and open 5G networks globally in view of an ambition to significantly expand market share of Open RAN in the global 5G market by 2030, particularly through workshops, seminars, and proof-of-concept projects in third countries, and to promote secure technology options for advanced communications networks, including Open RAN-based approaches to wireless network technology.</li>
<li>Recognizing the on-going efforts in the U.S.-Japan Policy Cooperation Dialogue on the Internet Economy (Internet Economy Dialogue), the United States and Japan intend to continue to strengthen our coordination in international and multilateral venues on digital policy issues and to foster collaboration with partners to promote and support strategically important and mutually beneficial projects of secure and trusted submarine cable systems.</li>
<li>The United States and Japan seek to continue joint efforts to enhance U.S.-Japan cooperation on more effective and agile export controls on critical and emerging technologies, including microelectronics and cyber surveillance systems, to address the misuse of critical and emerging technologies by malicious actors and inappropriate transfers of emerging technology through research activities. The two countries are continuing our collaboration to enhance export controls on materials, technology, and research that could be used to develop weapons, including WMDs and their means of delivery, and are doing so through international export control regimes, information exchange, and coordinated outreach.</li>
<li>The United States and Japan affirm the importance of sharing information relating to threats to critical infrastructure.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Strengthening Supply Chain Resilience</h3>
<ol start="16">
<li>The United States and Japan seek to advance efforts under the Japan-U.S. Commercial and Industrial Partnership and other frameworks to foster supply chain resilience in strategic sectors, including, in particular, semiconductors, batteries, and critical minerals. Towards this end, the two countries:
<ol style="list-style-type: lower-alpha;">
<li>Welcome the progress of the Joint Task Force announced by President Biden and Prime Minister Kishida to explore the development of next generation semiconductors and commit to continued cooperation through this mechanism.</li>
<li>Recognize that Japanese companies are increasing investment in battery manufacturing in the United States, contributing to supply chain resiliency, and that it is important for the two countries to build a strong battery supply chain to lead collaboration between like-minded countries.</li>
<li>Underscore the importance of cooperation, including providing financial support, to build a diverse and robust supply chain of critical minerals, including rare earths, especially to address bottlenecks in processing, which will increase energy security and support the clean energy transition. The two countries plan to work closely with other partners through the Minerals Security Partnership announced on June 14, 2022 in Toronto. We note the importance of engagement with the private sector.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<p><em>End Text</em></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and Japan on the occasion of the inaugural ministerial meeting of the U.S.-Japan Economic Policy Consultative Committee.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text</em></p>
<p>United States Secretary of State Antony Blinken and Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo co-hosted Japan’s Minister for Foreign Affairs HAYASHI Yoshimasa and Minister of Economy, Trade and Industry HAGIUDA Koichi for the inaugural ministerial meeting of the U.S.-Japan Economic Policy Consultative Committee (EPCC) on July 29, 2022. The Ministers affirmed their shared resolve to present a positive economic vision that highlights the benefits of a rules-based international economic order and emphasized the need to make our economies more competitive and resilient.</p>
<p>The Ministers considered the complex global economic context that has produced increased levels of risk and uncertainty for all. They noted recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic remains incomplete, and the pandemic has contributed to various economic challenges including supply chain disruptions, increasing commodity prices, and greater inequalities, many of which have disproportionately impacted historically underserved communities. The Ministers strongly condemned Russia’s brutal, unprovoked, and unjustified aggression against Ukraine and shared the view that it has exacerbated such challenges and undermined energy and food security around the world. The Ministers affirmed the need to address the climate crisis in the face of complications due to energy insecurity.</p>
<p>The Ministers also recognized the pandemic has significantly altered social and economic life through accelerated adoption of various technologies, including digital transformation, providing new opportunities as well as challenges. They noted technological innovation &#8211; including in critical and emerging technologies such as artificial intelligence, quantum technologies, and renewable and circular technologies &#8211; presents transformative potential, as well as risks for our economies if abused. The Ministers committed to continue taking steps to realize a full and sustainable recovery from the pandemic and enhance the international order in the post-pandemic world to optimize new opportunities and prepare for unprecedented challenges.</p>
<p>The Ministers resolved that the United States and Japan stand for open, sustainable, and inclusive economic growth that delivers prosperity, upholds democratic values, reduces economic disparities, and protects human rights in the Indo-Pacific region and beyond. They reiterated the importance of commitments to promote broad-based economic prosperity for our middle classes, including through economic and foreign policies that benefit workers and small businesses and increase women’s economic participation. They intend to promote this vision through the EPCC and other platforms, including the G7, APEC, and the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity (IPEF). They committed to advancing policies that support a multilateral trading system based on free and fair trade and that counter economic coercion and non-market policies and practices, emphasizing the importance of offering workers, businesses, and countries around the world a level playing field.</p>
<p>The Ministers shared the view that the United States and Japan, as the world’s two largest democratic economies, can demonstrate that democracies provide the best model for prosperity, stability, and security. In this context, the Ministers committed to continue sharing insights and exchanging views on our respective economic agendas, including President Biden’s plan to build from the bottom up and the middle out, as well as Prime Minister Kishida’s “new form of capitalism.” They further reviewed ways to defend workers, companies, and investors against the harms of unfair, anti-competitive, and non-market policies and practices. The Ministers also welcomed cooperation between the two countries in furtherance of shared objectives under the CoRe Partnership, as well as with like-minded partners, and emphasized our joint leadership in enhancing the rules-based economic order and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region and beyond.</p>
<p>The Ministers committed to countering threats to economic security and to the rules-based international economic order and noted recent developments in both countries, including passage of Japan’s Economic Security Promotion Act. The Ministers focused on the resilience and diversification of critical supply chains to promote their transparency, security, and sustainability. The Ministers also intend to collaborate in promoting and protecting critical and emerging technologies in a manner consistent with international rules and norms, including through research and development, as well as export controls, so as to support technological competitiveness and resilience and to address the challenges posed by the illicit diversion of technology critical for weapons development.</p>
<p>The Ministers expressed grave concern about, and opposition to, harmful uses of economic influence, including economic coercion as well as unfair and opaque lending practices, in ways that threaten the legitimate interests of sovereign nations, as well as those of individuals and industries. The Ministers affirmed these practices undermine legitimate sovereign choices, challenge the free and open rules-based international order, and are best addressed through a collective response. Respecting the importance of sustainable finance for long-term economic growth and development, they stressed the need to work together bilaterally and multilaterally to promote fair and transparent development finance across all debtors and creditors in accordance with internationally recognized principles, rules, and standards. In addressing these issues, the Ministers expressed their intention to deepen discussions and foster cooperation among like-minded partners.</p>
<p>The Ministers emphasized their conviction that economic security is indispensable to overall security, and that diplomacy and economic policy are intertwined and require a coordinated approach. Towards that end, the EPCC can provide an essential channel for bilateral collaboration, and the Ministers also confirmed their intention to meet periodically in this forum and to cooperate on economic priorities during the United States’ 2023 APEC host year and Japan’s Presidency of the G7 in 2023.</p>
<p>Recognizing the importance of carrying forward the priorities identified under the EPCC, the Ministers charged their undersecretaries and vice-ministers with implementing the EPCC Plan of Action based on their economic vision, ensuring robust private sector engagement to inform ongoing efforts, and convening the next EPCC vice-ministerial meeting before the end of 2022.</p>
<h2>U.S.-Japan Economic Policy Consultative Committee 2022 Plan of Action</h2>
<h3>Realizing Peace and Prosperity through the Rules-Based Economic Order</h3>
<ol>
<li>The United States and Japan pledge to further improve competitiveness and resilience by expanding and deepening cooperation based on the CoRe Partnership. The two countries seek to further enhance cooperation, stability, prosperity, development, and peace in the Indo-Pacific region through innovative economic arrangements including the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity (IPEF).</li>
<li>The United States and Japan are united in our strong condemnation of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine. The two countries remain steadfast in our solidarity with Ukraine and continue to support Ukraine. In this regard, the two countries welcomed the Lugano Declaration.</li>
<li>The United States and Japan are committed to working together to mitigate the effects of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine on markets for energy and food. The two countries underscore the need to sustain momentum toward energy transition and decarbonization, and we recognize the roles of renewable energy, nuclear power, ammonia, clean hydrogen-based solutions, carbon capture utilization and storage, as well as carbon recycling in achieving long-term energy security and net zero greenhouse gas emissions no later than 2050. The United States and Japan also acknowledge the need to strengthen investment in the energy sector and to ensure secure energy resources in the near term, including liquefied natural gas (LNG), in response to the current crisis. Japan welcomes the increase of U.S. shale oil and gas production as needed to stabilize global energy markets. The two countries further affirm the necessity of supporting energy security and methane emissions reductions in the Indo-Pacific region and globally. The two countries also commend the progress of advanced nuclear reactor projects and pledge to work together to create more resilient nuclear supply chains.</li>
<li>The United States and Japan pledge to support the openness of our agricultural supply chains, reaffirming the importance of not imposing export prohibitions or restrictions on food in a manner inconsistent with relevant WTO provisions, and seek to cooperate with other partners to strengthen global food security. The two countries also call on all countries to implement policies that improve sustainability and productivity in food production, and to develop resiliency in agriculture, food systems, and the food supply chain, and to promote access to agricultural inputs such as fertilizer. In this regard, the two countries reiterated the importance of the Ministerial Declaration on the Emergency Response to Food Insecurity adopted at the 12th Session of the Ministerial Conference of the World Trade Organization. In addition, the United States and Japan encourage dialogue between producer and consumer countries as well as the use of data to enhance global food security.</li>
<li>The United States and Japan commit to enhancing international efforts to address barriers on cross-border data flows, while respecting different approaches to data governance. The two countries further reaffirm the role of U.S.-Japan cooperation in multilateral initiatives, such as promotion and expansion of the newly established Global Cross-Border Privacy Rules (CBPR) Forum and support for efforts to develop the OECD Trusted Government Access to Personal Data Held by the Private Sector. In doing so, U.S.-Japan cooperation advances a common understanding and foundation to promote data free flow with trust among like-minded democracies.</li>
<li>In cooperation with interagency partners, the United States and Japan intend to promote information sharing on cybersecurity threats including through discussion of threat assessment and mitigation efforts in the Japan-U.S. Cyber Dialogue. We also affirm our intention to collaborate on the Japan-U.S.-EU Industrial Control Systems Cybersecurity Week for the Indo-Pacific region.</li>
<li>The United States and Japan are committed to coordination on business and human rights to foster an environment in which companies uphold human rights, and we welcome ongoing bilateral discussions.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Countering Economic Coercion and Unfair and Opaque Lending Practices</h3>
<ol start="8">
<li>The United States and Japan pledge to coordinate with other like-minded partners to address and respond to economic coercion, effectively confront non-market policies and practices, and deliver calibrated messaging to the international community, including in multilateral fora such as the WTO, OECD, G7, and G20.</li>
<li>To help ensure debt transparency and sustainability, internationally coordinated debt treatments, fair lending practices that respect the autonomy of debtor countries, and society-friendly infrastructure investment, the United States and Japan call on all actors to adhere to international rules, standards, and recognized principles, including the G20 Principles for Quality Infrastructure Investment and the G20 Common Framework for Debt Treatments beyond the Debt Service Suspension Initiative. The two countries further call on all major economies to adhere to other relevant international obligations and standards, as appropriate, including the OECD Anti-Bribery Convention and the OECD Guidelines for Multinational Enterprises.</li>
<li>The United States and Japan plan to work together to promote fair and transparent development finance. We emphasize the critical role of creditor coordination to ensure fair burden sharing among all creditors in debt treatments under the Common Framework and for other vulnerable countries, such as Sri Lanka.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Promoting and Securing Critical and Emerging Technologies and Critical Infrastructure</h3>
<ol start="11">
<li>The United States and Japan, noting the transformative opportunities that technological innovation provides, commit to explore and support joint research and development projects for critical and emerging technologies both between the United States and Japan and among like-minded partners.</li>
<li>In support of the U.S.-Japan Global Digital Connectivity Partnership, the United States and Japan intend to continue supporting efforts to deploy secure and open 5G networks globally in view of an ambition to significantly expand market share of Open RAN in the global 5G market by 2030, particularly through workshops, seminars, and proof-of-concept projects in third countries, and to promote secure technology options for advanced communications networks, including Open RAN-based approaches to wireless network technology.</li>
<li>Recognizing the on-going efforts in the U.S.-Japan Policy Cooperation Dialogue on the Internet Economy (Internet Economy Dialogue), the United States and Japan intend to continue to strengthen our coordination in international and multilateral venues on digital policy issues and to foster collaboration with partners to promote and support strategically important and mutually beneficial projects of secure and trusted submarine cable systems.</li>
<li>The United States and Japan seek to continue joint efforts to enhance U.S.-Japan cooperation on more effective and agile export controls on critical and emerging technologies, including microelectronics and cyber surveillance systems, to address the misuse of critical and emerging technologies by malicious actors and inappropriate transfers of emerging technology through research activities. The two countries are continuing our collaboration to enhance export controls on materials, technology, and research that could be used to develop weapons, including WMDs and their means of delivery, and are doing so through international export control regimes, information exchange, and coordinated outreach.</li>
<li>The United States and Japan affirm the importance of sharing information relating to threats to critical infrastructure.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Strengthening Supply Chain Resilience</h3>
<ol start="16">
<li>The United States and Japan seek to advance efforts under the Japan-U.S. Commercial and Industrial Partnership and other frameworks to foster supply chain resilience in strategic sectors, including, in particular, semiconductors, batteries, and critical minerals. Towards this end, the two countries:
<ol style="list-style-type: lower-alpha;">
<li>Welcome the progress of the Joint Task Force announced by President Biden and Prime Minister Kishida to explore the development of next generation semiconductors and commit to continued cooperation through this mechanism.</li>
<li>Recognize that Japanese companies are increasing investment in battery manufacturing in the United States, contributing to supply chain resiliency, and that it is important for the two countries to build a strong battery supply chain to lead collaboration between like-minded countries.</li>
<li>Underscore the importance of cooperation, including providing financial support, to build a diverse and robust supply chain of critical minerals, including rare earths, especially to address bottlenecks in processing, which will increase energy security and support the clean energy transition. The two countries plan to work closely with other partners through the Minerals Security Partnership announced on June 14, 2022 in Toronto. We note the importance of engagement with the private sector.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<p><em>End Text</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Targeting Russia’s Global Malign Influence Operations and Election Interference Activities</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/targeting-russias-global-malign-influence-operations-and-election-interference-activities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 19:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=364093</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The Russian Federation has demonstrated determination in its attempts to undermine the democratic processes and institutions essential to the functioning of our democracy and that of other countries.  It is crucial for our democracy, and democracies around the globe, to hold free and fair elections without malign outside interference.</p>
<p>In response, the United States is sanctioning two individuals and four entities that support the Kremlin’s global malign influence operations and election interference activities.  This action is separate and distinct from the broad range of measures the United States and its allies and partners continue to impose on Russia’s economy and financial system in response to its unlawful invasion of Ukraine, which constitutes another clear example of Russia’s disregard for the sovereignty and political independence of other states.</p>
<p>The sanctioned individuals and entities played various roles in Russia’s attempts to manipulate the United States and our allies and partners, including Ukraine.  This action follows a series of designations aimed to expose and disrupt Russia’s persistent election interference and destabilization efforts against Ukraine.  The United States will continue to act to deter and disrupt these efforts to safeguard our democracy, as well as help protect the democracies of our allies and partners.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s actions, please see the <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0899" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Department of the Treasury’s press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="100000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The Russian Federation has demonstrated determination in its attempts to undermine the democratic processes and institutions essential to the functioning of our democracy and that of other countries.  It is crucial for our democracy, and democracies around the globe, to hold free and fair elections without malign outside interference.</p>
<p>In response, the United States is sanctioning two individuals and four entities that support the Kremlin’s global malign influence operations and election interference activities.  This action is separate and distinct from the broad range of measures the United States and its allies and partners continue to impose on Russia’s economy and financial system in response to its unlawful invasion of Ukraine, which constitutes another clear example of Russia’s disregard for the sovereignty and political independence of other states.</p>
<p>The sanctioned individuals and entities played various roles in Russia’s attempts to manipulate the United States and our allies and partners, including Ukraine.  This action follows a series of designations aimed to expose and disrupt Russia’s persistent election interference and destabilization efforts against Ukraine.  The United States will continue to act to deter and disrupt these efforts to safeguard our democracy, as well as help protect the democracies of our allies and partners.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s actions, please see the <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0899" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Department of the Treasury’s press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="100000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opening Remarks with Secretary of Commerce Gina M. Raimondo and Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Yoshimasa and Minister of Economy, Trade, and Industry Hagiuda Koichi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/opening-remarks-with-secretary-of-commerce-gina-m-raimondo-and-japanese-foreign-minister-hayashi-yoshimasa-and-minister-of-economy-trade-and-industry-hagiuda-koichi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 18:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=364078</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>U.S.-Japan Economic Policy Consultative Committee</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, good morning everyone.  Ministers Hayashi, Hagiuda, Secretary Raimondo, it’s wonderful to welcome each of you here to the State Department.  And Gina and I are delighted to welcome you to Washington for what is the inaugural meeting of the U.S.-Japan Economic Policy Consultative Committee.</p>
<p>Earlier this year when President Biden and Prime Minister Kishida announced the creation of the EPCC – appropriately, “epic,” as we call it – this was a reflection of the strength of our two countries’ economic relationship and partnership, Japan’s and America’s leadership in the global economy, and the seriousness of the economic challenges facing our workers, our businesses, our people.  As the world’s first and third largest economies, it is critical that we work together to defend a rules-based international economic order, one in which all countries can participate, compete, and prosper.</p>
<p>Recent events in the world – around the world prove how necessary this new gathering is.  COVID-19 has revealed the vulnerability of critical supply chains.  A growing number of countries struggle with debt burdens due to unsustainable and nontransparent lending practices.  Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine, its blockade of the Port of Odessa has caused a spike in global food prices and fuel prices as well.  The coercive and retaliatory economic practices of the People’s Republic of China force countries into choices that compromise their security, their intellectual property, their economic independence.  These and other challenges call for our two countries to work together even more closely on economic matters.  This has always been a key element of our bilateral relationship, and with EPCC we will make our cooperation in this arena even stronger.</p>
<p>The EPCC also complements the work of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, which our two countries launched with 12 others in Tokyo this spring to create a stronger, fairer, more resilient economy across the entire Indo-Pacific.  Our conversations today and in the weeks ahead – and by the way, in the weeks ahead will also be leading to Japan assuming the leadership of the G7, the United States APEC next year – but all of these conversations, including through EPCC, will address our shared priorities, including securing critical infrastructure, building better supply lines and supply chains, shaping emerging technologies so that they deliver opportunity without undermining our security or, for that matter, our values.</p>
<p>On these issues and more, we will advance our shared vision of a open, inclusive, sustainable economic growth rooted in the rules-based international order.  Ultimately, our cooperation will help move us closer to a future in which trade and commerce support workers, create incomes, create opportunity where countries are secure from coercion and aggression, where people, ideas, goods, and capital move freely, where universal human rights are respected, and countries and people can forge their own paths.  Japan and the United States both share that vision.</p>
<p>(Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:  </strong>Thank you, Tony.  (Off-mike.)</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) I would like to thank Secretary Blinken and Secretary Raimondo for hosting.  Currently Russia’s invasion of Ukraine poses a serious challenge to the international order, but we must never allow unilateral attempts to change the status quo by force.</p>
<p>(Interruption.)</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) It is a powerful indication of the close collaboration between Japan and the United States that the first ministerial meeting of the Japan-U.S. Economic Policy Consultative Committee, which the two leaders concurred to hold in July at the Japan-U.S. summit meeting in May, was realized as concurred.  I would like to thank Secretary Blinken and Secretary Raimondo for hosting.</p>
<p>Currently, Russia’s invasion of Ukraine poses a serious challenge to the international order, but we must never allow unilateral attempts to change the status quo by force.  At the same time, we are concerned that there are prominent attempts to use economic influence unfairly and opaquely to realize their strategic interest and to modify the existing international order.  In order to effectively deal with this, it is essential to discuss foreign policy and economic policy as a unit, rather than discussing foreign policy and economic policy individually.  It is also necessary to strongly disseminate such efforts by Japan and United States and lead the collaboration of the international community.</p>
<p>From that point of view, this economic 2+2 is a timely framework.  In addition, it is important to promote multi-layered bilateral cooperation in terms of policies, institutions, and technological development, with a focus on the CoRe, or Competitiveness and Resilience Partnership, in order for Japan and the United States to maintain competitiveness and resilience in the ever-changing international economic situation.  Now, under Prime Minister Kishida’s new form of capitalism, Japan is aiming for an economic society that balances solving social issues and economic growth, while emphasizing investment in people and promotion of –</p>
<p>(Interruption.)</p>
<p>Japan and the United States should work together.</p>
<p>Today, I look forward to discussing how Japan and United States exert our leadership towards realization of sustainable and inclusive economic growth of the international community, including the Indo-Pacific region, as well as maintenance and reinforcement of the rules-based free and open economic order.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you very much, (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:  </strong>Good morning.  Tony and I are thrilled to host you this morning.  I had the opportunity the other evening to express my condolences to Minister Hagiuda, but I haven’t seen you, so Minister Hayashi, please – and your delegation, please accept our condolences for Prime Minister Abe.</p>
<p>It’s a pleasure to be here, as I said, and I could not agree more with you, Minister Hayashi, that the international rules-based order that the United States and Japan, along with our friends and allies, built is being challenged, which means it’s incumbent upon us to strengthen our tie and step up to ensure that they cannot challenge this rules-based order.  And I would suggest convenings of this kind are more important than ever, so thank you for enduring the long flight to be here with us.</p>
<p>We have a number of similar initiatives ongoing that all aim at the same goal.  Last November, Minister Hagiuda and I launched the JUCIP, the U.S.-Japan Commercial and Industrial Partnership, to ensure that METI and the Department of Commerce work together to promote competitiveness and innovation.  Today, of course, we are convening for the first time our economic 2+2 to discuss shared concerns of interest that are central to both foreign and economic policy.</p>
<p>I would say this format is the first of its kind.  It is ambitious, exciting, and timely in light of the threats that we are seeing around the world.  And the reality that, as you said, Minister Hayashi, economic security is very much more than ever tied to national security.</p>
<p>We have a mandate today to track what we have achieved together thus far and to drive cooperative efforts going forward in a way that can help further strengthen the rules-based economic order in the Indo-Pacific, and indeed, in the world.</p>
<p>I would take a minute to highlight that we’ve made significant achievements so far.  I’m especially proud of Commerce and METI’s joint work already underway in the JUCIP.  It’s already leading to concrete outcomes that we’ll discuss later today, including in the session which I am leading around building supply chain resilience.</p>
<p>Today in the rest of my comments, I also plan to focus on the newly launched Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, which we believe is vital to establishing strength in the – economic strength in the Indo-Pacific.  I want to thank Minister Hagiuda for the leadership you’re providing in the JUCIP, but also in the IPEF, and for your close partnership in ensuring the success of the supply chain ministerial last week and the virtual ministerial for IPEF this week.  I commend you for participating in the virtual ministerial for IPEF and then immediately getting on a plane and coming here today.</p>
<p>Our shared interests make it imperative for us to continue leveraging dialogues like this, like the 2+2, like the JUCIP, like the supply chain, like the IPEF, to figure out concrete joint solutions for promoting economic growth, economic security that will also help us address the threats to the global economic order and enhance economic security and resilience.  So I’m excited to have a productive discussion today.</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER HAGIUDA:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Commerce Secretary Raimondo, State Secretary Blinken, at the outset allow me to reiterate our heartfelt gratitude to deep condolences expressed to former Prime Minister Abe.  Former Prime Minister Abe always said Japan-U.S. alliance is the cornerstone of Japan’s diplomacy.</p>
<p>Today historic kickoff of Japan-U.S. Economic 2+2 has materialized.  Toward further deepening of Japan-U.S. alliance, a new page has been opened.  This is how we think.  Foreign and security policies and economic policy have become inseparable.  Unilateral use of economic force in violation of international rules to fulfill diplomatic demand should never take place.  State‑of‑the-art technology should be developed and utilized to further reinforce basic human rights and democracy.</p>
<p>Further, building economic architecture for a new era, including digital, is an urgent challenge that cannot wait.  Vis-à-vis wider-ranging challenges, Japan and the United States – the world’s number one and number two democratic economic powers sharing universal values – will have – work hand in hand.</p>
<p>The 2+2 will not only be confined to Japan-U.S. bilateral, but will be a foundation which will bring peace and prosperity widely in the Indo-Pacific region.  This is, as it were, compass for realizing free and open Indo-Pacific.  This is our belief.</p>
<p>I’m looking forward to having a very good discussion.  Let us send out to the world Japan‑United States unified and clear message.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you so much, Mr. Minister and colleagues.  And just to add my voice as well to Gina’s and to the minister’s, I had an opportunity to pay respects upon the assassination of Prime Minister Abe, and I think and I hope that the spirit of leadership and vision he brought to our relationship, which was exceptional, will help animate us in the work that we’re doing together.</p>
<p>It’s wonderful to have all of you here.  We’re going to get into our session.  I’m remiss in – for those of you who haven’t been here before, this is the Benjamin Franklin Room.  Ben Franklin is gazing at us.  He was our first diplomat, he signed our first treaty, he charted the Gulf Stream, he captured electricity, he forced an ethos of self-government – and virtually none of this did he do while sober.  (Laughter.)  But we will be serving tea this morning.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>So, Mark.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  And with that, I will be serving as your moderator today and try to keep us on time on this rather ambitious agenda.  We have two plenary sessions, each divided into two bits.  The first session will be “Realizing Peace and Prosperity Through the Rules-Based Economic Order.”  The speaking order will be Minister Hayashi, followed by Secretary Blinken, Minister Hagiuda, followed by Secretary Raimondo, and we’re going to allow about 20 minutes for this session.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>U.S.-Japan Economic Policy Consultative Committee</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, good morning everyone.  Ministers Hayashi, Hagiuda, Secretary Raimondo, it’s wonderful to welcome each of you here to the State Department.  And Gina and I are delighted to welcome you to Washington for what is the inaugural meeting of the U.S.-Japan Economic Policy Consultative Committee.</p>
<p>Earlier this year when President Biden and Prime Minister Kishida announced the creation of the EPCC – appropriately, “epic,” as we call it – this was a reflection of the strength of our two countries’ economic relationship and partnership, Japan’s and America’s leadership in the global economy, and the seriousness of the economic challenges facing our workers, our businesses, our people.  As the world’s first and third largest economies, it is critical that we work together to defend a rules-based international economic order, one in which all countries can participate, compete, and prosper.</p>
<p>Recent events in the world – around the world prove how necessary this new gathering is.  COVID-19 has revealed the vulnerability of critical supply chains.  A growing number of countries struggle with debt burdens due to unsustainable and nontransparent lending practices.  Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine, its blockade of the Port of Odessa has caused a spike in global food prices and fuel prices as well.  The coercive and retaliatory economic practices of the People’s Republic of China force countries into choices that compromise their security, their intellectual property, their economic independence.  These and other challenges call for our two countries to work together even more closely on economic matters.  This has always been a key element of our bilateral relationship, and with EPCC we will make our cooperation in this arena even stronger.</p>
<p>The EPCC also complements the work of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, which our two countries launched with 12 others in Tokyo this spring to create a stronger, fairer, more resilient economy across the entire Indo-Pacific.  Our conversations today and in the weeks ahead – and by the way, in the weeks ahead will also be leading to Japan assuming the leadership of the G7, the United States APEC next year – but all of these conversations, including through EPCC, will address our shared priorities, including securing critical infrastructure, building better supply lines and supply chains, shaping emerging technologies so that they deliver opportunity without undermining our security or, for that matter, our values.</p>
<p>On these issues and more, we will advance our shared vision of a open, inclusive, sustainable economic growth rooted in the rules-based international order.  Ultimately, our cooperation will help move us closer to a future in which trade and commerce support workers, create incomes, create opportunity where countries are secure from coercion and aggression, where people, ideas, goods, and capital move freely, where universal human rights are respected, and countries and people can forge their own paths.  Japan and the United States both share that vision.</p>
<p>(Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HAYASHI:  </strong>Thank you, Tony.  (Off-mike.)</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) I would like to thank Secretary Blinken and Secretary Raimondo for hosting.  Currently Russia’s invasion of Ukraine poses a serious challenge to the international order, but we must never allow unilateral attempts to change the status quo by force.</p>
<p>(Interruption.)</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) It is a powerful indication of the close collaboration between Japan and the United States that the first ministerial meeting of the Japan-U.S. Economic Policy Consultative Committee, which the two leaders concurred to hold in July at the Japan-U.S. summit meeting in May, was realized as concurred.  I would like to thank Secretary Blinken and Secretary Raimondo for hosting.</p>
<p>Currently, Russia’s invasion of Ukraine poses a serious challenge to the international order, but we must never allow unilateral attempts to change the status quo by force.  At the same time, we are concerned that there are prominent attempts to use economic influence unfairly and opaquely to realize their strategic interest and to modify the existing international order.  In order to effectively deal with this, it is essential to discuss foreign policy and economic policy as a unit, rather than discussing foreign policy and economic policy individually.  It is also necessary to strongly disseminate such efforts by Japan and United States and lead the collaboration of the international community.</p>
<p>From that point of view, this economic 2+2 is a timely framework.  In addition, it is important to promote multi-layered bilateral cooperation in terms of policies, institutions, and technological development, with a focus on the CoRe, or Competitiveness and Resilience Partnership, in order for Japan and the United States to maintain competitiveness and resilience in the ever-changing international economic situation.  Now, under Prime Minister Kishida’s new form of capitalism, Japan is aiming for an economic society that balances solving social issues and economic growth, while emphasizing investment in people and promotion of –</p>
<p>(Interruption.)</p>
<p>Japan and the United States should work together.</p>
<p>Today, I look forward to discussing how Japan and United States exert our leadership towards realization of sustainable and inclusive economic growth of the international community, including the Indo-Pacific region, as well as maintenance and reinforcement of the rules-based free and open economic order.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you very much, (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:  </strong>Good morning.  Tony and I are thrilled to host you this morning.  I had the opportunity the other evening to express my condolences to Minister Hagiuda, but I haven’t seen you, so Minister Hayashi, please – and your delegation, please accept our condolences for Prime Minister Abe.</p>
<p>It’s a pleasure to be here, as I said, and I could not agree more with you, Minister Hayashi, that the international rules-based order that the United States and Japan, along with our friends and allies, built is being challenged, which means it’s incumbent upon us to strengthen our tie and step up to ensure that they cannot challenge this rules-based order.  And I would suggest convenings of this kind are more important than ever, so thank you for enduring the long flight to be here with us.</p>
<p>We have a number of similar initiatives ongoing that all aim at the same goal.  Last November, Minister Hagiuda and I launched the JUCIP, the U.S.-Japan Commercial and Industrial Partnership, to ensure that METI and the Department of Commerce work together to promote competitiveness and innovation.  Today, of course, we are convening for the first time our economic 2+2 to discuss shared concerns of interest that are central to both foreign and economic policy.</p>
<p>I would say this format is the first of its kind.  It is ambitious, exciting, and timely in light of the threats that we are seeing around the world.  And the reality that, as you said, Minister Hayashi, economic security is very much more than ever tied to national security.</p>
<p>We have a mandate today to track what we have achieved together thus far and to drive cooperative efforts going forward in a way that can help further strengthen the rules-based economic order in the Indo-Pacific, and indeed, in the world.</p>
<p>I would take a minute to highlight that we’ve made significant achievements so far.  I’m especially proud of Commerce and METI’s joint work already underway in the JUCIP.  It’s already leading to concrete outcomes that we’ll discuss later today, including in the session which I am leading around building supply chain resilience.</p>
<p>Today in the rest of my comments, I also plan to focus on the newly launched Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, which we believe is vital to establishing strength in the – economic strength in the Indo-Pacific.  I want to thank Minister Hagiuda for the leadership you’re providing in the JUCIP, but also in the IPEF, and for your close partnership in ensuring the success of the supply chain ministerial last week and the virtual ministerial for IPEF this week.  I commend you for participating in the virtual ministerial for IPEF and then immediately getting on a plane and coming here today.</p>
<p>Our shared interests make it imperative for us to continue leveraging dialogues like this, like the 2+2, like the JUCIP, like the supply chain, like the IPEF, to figure out concrete joint solutions for promoting economic growth, economic security that will also help us address the threats to the global economic order and enhance economic security and resilience.  So I’m excited to have a productive discussion today.</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER HAGIUDA:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Commerce Secretary Raimondo, State Secretary Blinken, at the outset allow me to reiterate our heartfelt gratitude to deep condolences expressed to former Prime Minister Abe.  Former Prime Minister Abe always said Japan-U.S. alliance is the cornerstone of Japan’s diplomacy.</p>
<p>Today historic kickoff of Japan-U.S. Economic 2+2 has materialized.  Toward further deepening of Japan-U.S. alliance, a new page has been opened.  This is how we think.  Foreign and security policies and economic policy have become inseparable.  Unilateral use of economic force in violation of international rules to fulfill diplomatic demand should never take place.  State‑of‑the-art technology should be developed and utilized to further reinforce basic human rights and democracy.</p>
<p>Further, building economic architecture for a new era, including digital, is an urgent challenge that cannot wait.  Vis-à-vis wider-ranging challenges, Japan and the United States – the world’s number one and number two democratic economic powers sharing universal values – will have – work hand in hand.</p>
<p>The 2+2 will not only be confined to Japan-U.S. bilateral, but will be a foundation which will bring peace and prosperity widely in the Indo-Pacific region.  This is, as it were, compass for realizing free and open Indo-Pacific.  This is our belief.</p>
<p>I’m looking forward to having a very good discussion.  Let us send out to the world Japan‑United States unified and clear message.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you so much, Mr. Minister and colleagues.  And just to add my voice as well to Gina’s and to the minister’s, I had an opportunity to pay respects upon the assassination of Prime Minister Abe, and I think and I hope that the spirit of leadership and vision he brought to our relationship, which was exceptional, will help animate us in the work that we’re doing together.</p>
<p>It’s wonderful to have all of you here.  We’re going to get into our session.  I’m remiss in – for those of you who haven’t been here before, this is the Benjamin Franklin Room.  Ben Franklin is gazing at us.  He was our first diplomat, he signed our first treaty, he charted the Gulf Stream, he captured electricity, he forced an ethos of self-government – and virtually none of this did he do while sober.  (Laughter.)  But we will be serving tea this morning.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>So, Mark.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  And with that, I will be serving as your moderator today and try to keep us on time on this rather ambitious agenda.  We have two plenary sessions, each divided into two bits.  The first session will be “Realizing Peace and Prosperity Through the Rules-Based Economic Order.”  The speaking order will be Minister Hayashi, followed by Secretary Blinken, Minister Hagiuda, followed by Secretary Raimondo, and we’re going to allow about 20 minutes for this session.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vanuatu National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/vanuatu-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 14:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=363911</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I offer my best wishes in celebration of your National Day on July 30.</p>
<p>As we all emerge from the COVID-19 pandemic, we look forward to reconnecting and supporting the return of Peace Corps Volunteers to Vanuatu, a testament to the strength of our relationship. Our shared values serve as the foundation of our longstanding partnership, and we are committed to working together to address emerging challenges to shape a better future.</p>
<p>Please accept my congratulations as you celebrate your country’s independence.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I offer my best wishes in celebration of your National Day on July 30.</p>
<p>As we all emerge from the COVID-19 pandemic, we look forward to reconnecting and supporting the return of Peace Corps Volunteers to Vanuatu, a testament to the strength of our relationship. Our shared values serve as the foundation of our longstanding partnership, and we are committed to working together to address emerging challenges to shape a better future.</p>
<p>Please accept my congratulations as you celebrate your country’s independence.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary of State Blinken’s Travel to New York City for the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty Review Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-of-state-blinkens-travel-to-new-york-for-the-nuclear-non-proliferation-treaty-review-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 13:23:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=363862</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to New York City August 1 to deliver remarks and participate in meetings at the Nuclear-Nonproliferation Treaty Review Conference, which will take place at United Nations during the month of August.  In these meetings, Secretary Blinken will focus on reaffirming the U.S. commitment to the Nuclear-Nonproliferation Treaty and strengthening the nuclear nonproliferation regime for future generations.</p>
<p>For updates, follow @StateISN on Twitter.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to New York City August 1 to deliver remarks and participate in meetings at the Nuclear-Nonproliferation Treaty Review Conference, which will take place at United Nations during the month of August.  In these meetings, Secretary Blinken will focus on reaffirming the U.S. commitment to the Nuclear-Nonproliferation Treaty and strengthening the nuclear nonproliferation regime for future generations.</p>
<p>For updates, follow @StateISN on Twitter.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Israeli Minister for Public Security Bar Lev</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-israeli-minister-for-public-security-bar-lev/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 12:39:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=363845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Israeli Minister for Public Security Omer Bar Lev yesterday in Washington to discuss the U.S.-Israel relationship. The Deputy Secretary conveyed condolences for the terrorist attacks that claimed the lives of Israelis earlier this year and underscored the United States’ unwavering commitment to Israel’s security. They also discussed efforts to ensure all Palestinians and Israelis live safely and securely with equal measures of freedom, dignity, and prosperity. The Deputy Secretary also raised the tragic death of Palestinian-American reporter Shireen Abu Akleh and the need for accountability.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Israeli Minister for Public Security Omer Bar Lev yesterday in Washington to discuss the U.S.-Israel relationship. The Deputy Secretary conveyed condolences for the terrorist attacks that claimed the lives of Israelis earlier this year and underscored the United States’ unwavering commitment to Israel’s security. They also discussed efforts to ensure all Palestinians and Israelis live safely and securely with equal measures of freedom, dignity, and prosperity. The Deputy Secretary also raised the tragic death of Palestinian-American reporter Shireen Abu Akleh and the need for accountability.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
