<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 20:54:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Iceland’s National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/icelands-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 04:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=252428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I send best wishes to the people of Iceland as you celebrate your National Day.</p>
<p>The United States and Iceland have a shared commitment to fundamental freedoms, human rights, and democracy, the cornerstones of our relationship since the U.S. recognized Iceland’s independence in 1944.  In particular, we acknowledge Iceland’s impressive record and advocacy for the advancement of women’s rights, and we look forward to continuing our work together on global human rights priorities, including at the UN Human Rights Council.</p>
<p>The United States values our cooperation on Arctic issues.  We appreciated Iceland’s strong leadership as the chair of the Arctic Council, and we look forward to even closer collaboration on pressing issues, including the climate crisis.  We greatly value our strong cooperation in NATO on Transatlantic security, and we welcomed the 70th anniversary of the U.S.-Icelandic bilateral defense agreement, which underscored our relationship as steadfast Allies and partners for peace and prosperity in the Euro-Atlantic area and around the globe.</p>
<p>I very much appreciated the hospitality shown to me during my recent visit to Iceland, and I look forward to the continued strengthening of our relationship.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I send best wishes to the people of Iceland as you celebrate your National Day.</p>
<p>The United States and Iceland have a shared commitment to fundamental freedoms, human rights, and democracy, the cornerstones of our relationship since the U.S. recognized Iceland’s independence in 1944.  In particular, we acknowledge Iceland’s impressive record and advocacy for the advancement of women’s rights, and we look forward to continuing our work together on global human rights priorities, including at the UN Human Rights Council.</p>
<p>The United States values our cooperation on Arctic issues.  We appreciated Iceland’s strong leadership as the chair of the Arctic Council, and we look forward to even closer collaboration on pressing issues, including the climate crisis.  We greatly value our strong cooperation in NATO on Transatlantic security, and we welcomed the 70th anniversary of the U.S.-Icelandic bilateral defense agreement, which underscored our relationship as steadfast Allies and partners for peace and prosperity in the Euro-Atlantic area and around the globe.</p>
<p>I very much appreciated the hospitality shown to me during my recent visit to Iceland, and I look forward to the continued strengthening of our relationship.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary Nuland’s Travel to Brussels</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-nulands-travel-to-brussels/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 20:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=252508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland will travel to Brussels June 17-18 to follow up with our Allies and partners on the NATO and U.S.-EU summits and the President’s meeting with Russian President Putin.</p>
<p>Following President Biden’s travel to Brussels, Under Secretary Nuland will meet with NATO Deputy Secretary General Mircea Geoana and members of the North Atlantic Council.  The Under Secretary will also meet with European External Action Service Secretary General Stefano Sannino to highlight U.S.-EU cooperation on a wide range of issues, including tackling complex foreign policy challenges.  In Brussels, the Under Secretary will also meet with Belgian Director General of Multilateral Affairs Axel Kenes to discuss mutual policy priorities.  Finally, Under Secretary Nuland will participate virtually at the GLOBSEC Bratislava Forum to address and discuss key issues highlighted during President Biden’s visit to Europe.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland will travel to Brussels June 17-18 to follow up with our Allies and partners on the NATO and U.S.-EU summits and the President’s meeting with Russian President Putin.</p>
<p>Following President Biden’s travel to Brussels, Under Secretary Nuland will meet with NATO Deputy Secretary General Mircea Geoana and members of the North Atlantic Council.  The Under Secretary will also meet with European External Action Service Secretary General Stefano Sannino to highlight U.S.-EU cooperation on a wide range of issues, including tackling complex foreign policy challenges.  In Brussels, the Under Secretary will also meet with Belgian Director General of Multilateral Affairs Axel Kenes to discuss mutual policy priorities.  Finally, Under Secretary Nuland will participate virtually at the GLOBSEC Bratislava Forum to address and discuss key issues highlighted during President Biden’s visit to Europe.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry’s Visit to the United Arab Emirates, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, and Arab Republic of Egypt</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-presidential-envoy-for-climate-john-kerrys-visit-to-the-united-arab-emirates-kingdom-of-saudi-arabia-and-arab-republic-of-egypt/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 19:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=252459</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry traveled to the Middle East and North Africa June 13-17 to discuss collaboration on combating climate change and raising climate ambition ahead of the 26th Conference of the Parties (COP26) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change later this year and beyond.  All visited countries enthusiastically engaged in discussions on the need for increased action to address climate change, the importance of a successful COP26, and prospects for enhanced climate cooperation with the United States.</p>
<p>In the United Arab Emirates, Special Presidential Envoy Kerry met with the Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi, Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed bin Sultan Al Nahyan, as well as top UAE officials including Foreign Minister Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed bin Sultan Al Nahyan, National Security Advisor Sheikh Tahnoun bin Zayed Al Nahyan, and Special Envoy for Climate Change Dr. Sultan Al Jaber.  They reaffirmed the U.S. and U.A.E. commitment to the Agriculture Innovation Mission for Climate (AIM for Climate), which the two countries jointly announced at President Biden&#8217;s Leaders Summit on Climate and will launch formally at COP26 in Glasgow.  They also discussed jointly identifying opportunities for strategic investment in India’s clean energy transition and mobilizing investments in clean energy around the world; collaborating on climate and security, developing and scaling clean energy technologies; and working constructively to demonstrate ambition and make COP26 a success.</p>
<p>In the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, Special Presidential Envoy Kerry met with Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, Minister of Energy Abdulaziz bin Salman Al Saud, Minister of State for Foreign Affairs Adel al-Jubeir, Minister of Investment Khalid Al-Falih, Minister of Environment, Water, and Agriculture Abdulrahman al-Fadhli, and Minister of Communications and Information Technology Abdullah al-Swaha. Their discussions covered addressing the increasing climate challenge with seriousness and urgency; ongoing and future Saudi pathways and initiatives to scale clean energy technologies to reduce emissions; collaboration on research and investment in climate mitigation and adaptation; and constructive actions to promote a successful G20 and COP26.  In an extended workshop, the Ministry of Energy laid out concrete plans for achieving Saudi Arabia’s announced target of achieving 50 percent electricity generation from renewable sources by 2030 and for scaling up hydrogen and carbon capture technologies.  The two countries concluded a joint statement affirming their intention to intensify collaboration on the road to Glasgow and beyond, recognizing the importance of reducing greenhouse gas emissions and taking adaptation actions during the 2020s to avoid the worst consequences of climate change.</p>
<p>In the Arab Republic of Egypt, Special Presidential Envoy Kerry met with Prime Minister Mostafa Madbouly, as well as top Egyptian officials including Foreign Minister Sameh Shoukry, and Minister of Environment Yasmine Fouad. They discussed collaborating on COP27, which Egypt will host; advancing climate mitigation and adaptation in Egypt; and working constructively to promote a successful COP26.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry traveled to the Middle East and North Africa June 13-17 to discuss collaboration on combating climate change and raising climate ambition ahead of the 26th Conference of the Parties (COP26) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change later this year and beyond.  All visited countries enthusiastically engaged in discussions on the need for increased action to address climate change, the importance of a successful COP26, and prospects for enhanced climate cooperation with the United States.</p>
<p>In the United Arab Emirates, Special Presidential Envoy Kerry met with the Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi, Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed bin Sultan Al Nahyan, as well as top UAE officials including Foreign Minister Sheikh Abdullah bin Zayed bin Sultan Al Nahyan, National Security Advisor Sheikh Tahnoun bin Zayed Al Nahyan, and Special Envoy for Climate Change Dr. Sultan Al Jaber.  They reaffirmed the U.S. and U.A.E. commitment to the Agriculture Innovation Mission for Climate (AIM for Climate), which the two countries jointly announced at President Biden&#8217;s Leaders Summit on Climate and will launch formally at COP26 in Glasgow.  They also discussed jointly identifying opportunities for strategic investment in India’s clean energy transition and mobilizing investments in clean energy around the world; collaborating on climate and security, developing and scaling clean energy technologies; and working constructively to demonstrate ambition and make COP26 a success.</p>
<p>In the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, Special Presidential Envoy Kerry met with Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, Minister of Energy Abdulaziz bin Salman Al Saud, Minister of State for Foreign Affairs Adel al-Jubeir, Minister of Investment Khalid Al-Falih, Minister of Environment, Water, and Agriculture Abdulrahman al-Fadhli, and Minister of Communications and Information Technology Abdullah al-Swaha. Their discussions covered addressing the increasing climate challenge with seriousness and urgency; ongoing and future Saudi pathways and initiatives to scale clean energy technologies to reduce emissions; collaboration on research and investment in climate mitigation and adaptation; and constructive actions to promote a successful G20 and COP26.  In an extended workshop, the Ministry of Energy laid out concrete plans for achieving Saudi Arabia’s announced target of achieving 50 percent electricity generation from renewable sources by 2030 and for scaling up hydrogen and carbon capture technologies.  The two countries concluded a joint statement affirming their intention to intensify collaboration on the road to Glasgow and beyond, recognizing the importance of reducing greenhouse gas emissions and taking adaptation actions during the 2020s to avoid the worst consequences of climate change.</p>
<p>In the Arab Republic of Egypt, Special Presidential Envoy Kerry met with Prime Minister Mostafa Madbouly, as well as top Egyptian officials including Foreign Minister Sameh Shoukry, and Minister of Environment Yasmine Fouad. They discussed collaborating on COP27, which Egypt will host; advancing climate mitigation and adaptation in Egypt; and working constructively to promote a successful COP26.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-Saudi Arabia Joint Statement Addressing the Climate Challenge</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-saudi-arabia-joint-statement-addressing-the-climate-challenge/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 13:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=252386</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>At the conclusion of Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry’s visit to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, the two countries released the following statement:    <em>Begin text:</em>    The United States and the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia are committed to addressing the increasing climate challenge with seriousness and urgency.  They will work to strengthen the implementation of the Paris Agreement and actively promote a successful G20 in Italy and COP 26 in Glasgow.  Both countries affirm the importance of reducing greenhouse gas emissions and taking adaptation actions during the 2020s to avoid the worst consequences of climate change.  They affirmed their intention to work together:</p>
<p>to actively support and engage bilaterally on the Saudi Green Initiative and the Middle East Green Initiative, including on clean energy, sustainable agriculture, and land use;</p>
<p>to advance efforts under the announced Net-Zero Producers Forum, including, e.g., on methane abatement, the circular carbon economy, and clean-energy and carbon capture and storage technologies;</p>
<p>to cooperate on the potential of clean hydrogen to address the hardest to abate sectors and to partner to accelerate clean hydrogen’s development and deployment, recognizing the two countries’ respective initiatives in this regard;</p>
<p>to collaborate on accelerating the deployment of renewable energy and low-emissions power systems in the region;</p>
<p>to encourage private sector partnerships;</p>
<p>to support ocean-based and nature-based solutions for addressing both mitigation and adaptation; and</p>
<p>to launch cooperation on enhancing climate change research in the areas of mitigation and adaptation.</p>
<p>Recalling their fruitful, in-depth discussion on their respective ongoing and future climate initiatives, both sides acknowledge each other’s efforts and look forward to engaging with each other and enhancing their actions on the road to Glasgow and beyond.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>At the conclusion of Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry’s visit to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, the two countries released the following statement:    <em>Begin text:</em>    The United States and the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia are committed to addressing the increasing climate challenge with seriousness and urgency.  They will work to strengthen the implementation of the Paris Agreement and actively promote a successful G20 in Italy and COP 26 in Glasgow.  Both countries affirm the importance of reducing greenhouse gas emissions and taking adaptation actions during the 2020s to avoid the worst consequences of climate change.  They affirmed their intention to work together:</p>
<p>to actively support and engage bilaterally on the Saudi Green Initiative and the Middle East Green Initiative, including on clean energy, sustainable agriculture, and land use;</p>
<p>to advance efforts under the announced Net-Zero Producers Forum, including, e.g., on methane abatement, the circular carbon economy, and clean-energy and carbon capture and storage technologies;</p>
<p>to cooperate on the potential of clean hydrogen to address the hardest to abate sectors and to partner to accelerate clean hydrogen’s development and deployment, recognizing the two countries’ respective initiatives in this regard;</p>
<p>to collaborate on accelerating the deployment of renewable energy and low-emissions power systems in the region;</p>
<p>to encourage private sector partnerships;</p>
<p>to support ocean-based and nature-based solutions for addressing both mitigation and adaptation; and</p>
<p>to launch cooperation on enhancing climate change research in the areas of mitigation and adaptation.</p>
<p>Recalling their fruitful, in-depth discussion on their respective ongoing and future climate initiatives, both sides acknowledge each other’s efforts and look forward to engaging with each other and enhancing their actions on the road to Glasgow and beyond.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States Welcomes the Organization of American States Resolution on Nicaragua</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-welcomes-the-organization-of-american-states-resolution-on-nicaragua/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 12:25:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=252360</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Yesterday, an overwhelming majority of Organization of American States (OAS) member states sent a clear message of support for the Nicaraguan people and their fight for free and fair elections, respect for human rights, and accountability. The resolution approved yesterday condemns the Ortega-Murillo regime’s repression in Nicaragua and calls for the immediate release of the four presidential candidates recently detained, along with over 130 other political prisoners. It also concludes that, in the wake of the regime’s recent repression and its lack of meaningful electoral reform, the conditions for free and fair elections this November do not exist. The United States strongly supports the OAS Permanent Council’s call for President Ortega to take urgent action to restore full respect for human rights and to create the conditions for free and fair elections.</p>
<p>It is time for the Ortega-Murillo regime to change course, respect both its own constitution as well as its commitments under the Inter-American Democratic Charter, and allow the Nicaraguan people to fully exercise their rights—including their right to choose their leaders in free and fair elections. We look forward to continuing to work with OAS member states, as well as other democratic governments around the world, including with our partners in the European Union, to press for greater freedom for the Nicaraguan people. Through yesterday’s vote, the members of the OAS made clear that Ortega and Murillo’s actions have no place in this hemisphere, given our shared commitments to democracy and human rights.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Yesterday, an overwhelming majority of Organization of American States (OAS) member states sent a clear message of support for the Nicaraguan people and their fight for free and fair elections, respect for human rights, and accountability. The resolution approved yesterday condemns the Ortega-Murillo regime’s repression in Nicaragua and calls for the immediate release of the four presidential candidates recently detained, along with over 130 other political prisoners. It also concludes that, in the wake of the regime’s recent repression and its lack of meaningful electoral reform, the conditions for free and fair elections this November do not exist. The United States strongly supports the OAS Permanent Council’s call for President Ortega to take urgent action to restore full respect for human rights and to create the conditions for free and fair elections.</p>
<p>It is time for the Ortega-Murillo regime to change course, respect both its own constitution as well as its commitments under the Inter-American Democratic Charter, and allow the Nicaraguan people to fully exercise their rights—including their right to choose their leaders in free and fair elections. We look forward to continuing to work with OAS member states, as well as other democratic governments around the world, including with our partners in the European Union, to press for greater freedom for the Nicaraguan people. Through yesterday’s vote, the members of the OAS made clear that Ortega and Murillo’s actions have no place in this hemisphere, given our shared commitments to democracy and human rights.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>10th Anniversary of the UN Guiding Principles on Business and Human Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/10th-anniversary-of-the-un-guiding-principles-on-business-and-human-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 12:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=252361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Today marks the tenth anniversary of the unanimous endorsement by the UN Human Rights Council of the UN Guiding Principles on Business and Human Rights (UNGPs). These principles recognize a three-pronged approach to protecting human rights in the context of business activity: States have the duty to protect human rights; businesses have a responsibility to respect human rights; and victims affected by business-related human rights issues should have access to remedy. We commemorate the achievements made over the last decade in these areas, and take heed of the substantive work that still needs to be done toward realization of these principles.</p>
<p>Businesses can provide crucial support for democratic principles, including respect for human and labor rights. They have the capacity to help shape society and the environment – raising local wages, improving working conditions, building trust with communities, and operating sustainably. As a result, businesses have a key role in addressing human rights abuses, including throughout their value chains.</p>
<p>Looking ahead to the next decade, we must go further in shaping the business and human rights agenda. This will take concerted efforts by governments, businesses, and other stakeholders. Doing so is not only the right thing to do but the smart thing to do. We know that companies thrive and economies prosper when there is strong rule of law and adherence to human rights and fundamental freedoms as well as respect for international labor, environmental, and technical standards, good governance, and accountable institutions. Businesses in the rapidly evolving emerging technology sector have a particular opportunity to shape its deployment and establish guardrails against misuse. There also needs to be more attention on the leverage wielded by investors, including private equity, venture capital firms, and multilateral development banks to address human rights abuses, including those committed against environmental defenders. That is why today I am pleased to announce that the State Department, working with the White House and other federal departments and agencies, will soon begin the process of updating and revitalizing the United States’ National Action Plan (NAP) on Responsible Business Conduct.</p>
<p>The Department is renewing its commitment to advance business and human rights under the framework set out in the UNGPs, and in comparable provisions in the OECD Guidelines for Multinational Enterprises, which were updated 10 years ago as well. As we look forward to the next decade under the UNGPs, we recognize there is still much work to be done. The success of future efforts to build upon the UNGPs will depend upon maintaining the approaches that have made them such a success.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Today marks the tenth anniversary of the unanimous endorsement by the UN Human Rights Council of the UN Guiding Principles on Business and Human Rights (UNGPs). These principles recognize a three-pronged approach to protecting human rights in the context of business activity: States have the duty to protect human rights; businesses have a responsibility to respect human rights; and victims affected by business-related human rights issues should have access to remedy. We commemorate the achievements made over the last decade in these areas, and take heed of the substantive work that still needs to be done toward realization of these principles.</p>
<p>Businesses can provide crucial support for democratic principles, including respect for human and labor rights. They have the capacity to help shape society and the environment – raising local wages, improving working conditions, building trust with communities, and operating sustainably. As a result, businesses have a key role in addressing human rights abuses, including throughout their value chains.</p>
<p>Looking ahead to the next decade, we must go further in shaping the business and human rights agenda. This will take concerted efforts by governments, businesses, and other stakeholders. Doing so is not only the right thing to do but the smart thing to do. We know that companies thrive and economies prosper when there is strong rule of law and adherence to human rights and fundamental freedoms as well as respect for international labor, environmental, and technical standards, good governance, and accountable institutions. Businesses in the rapidly evolving emerging technology sector have a particular opportunity to shape its deployment and establish guardrails against misuse. There also needs to be more attention on the leverage wielded by investors, including private equity, venture capital firms, and multilateral development banks to address human rights abuses, including those committed against environmental defenders. That is why today I am pleased to announce that the State Department, working with the White House and other federal departments and agencies, will soon begin the process of updating and revitalizing the United States’ National Action Plan (NAP) on Responsible Business Conduct.</p>
<p>The Department is renewing its commitment to advance business and human rights under the framework set out in the UNGPs, and in comparable provisions in the OECD Guidelines for Multinational Enterprises, which were updated 10 years ago as well. As we look forward to the next decade under the UNGPs, we recognize there is still much work to be done. The success of future efforts to build upon the UNGPs will depend upon maintaining the approaches that have made them such a success.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; June 15, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-june-15-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 21:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=252304</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:11 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you so much for joining today’s State Department press briefing. I have two updates at the top before I start taking your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-252304-CentralAmerica"></a> I would like to draw your attention to the joint statement issued by Secretary Blinken and Secretary Mayorkas today about the expansion of the Central American Minors, or CAM, program, which provides certain Guatemalan, Honduran, or Salvadoran children access to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program.</p>
<p>As a part of our focus on a responsible, phased approach to humanely managing migration and expanding legal pathways, we continue to reopen cases in our efforts to reunite families. Since we announced CAM’s reopening in March, we have reopened approximately 1,100 cases.</p>
<p>As we continue to develop and expand initiatives that provide a safe, legal, and orderly alternative to dangerous irregular migration, we are announcing today the second phase of the CAM reopening that will expand the ability of tens of thousands of U.S.-based individuals to petition for children to access the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program through CAM.</p>
<p>Petitioner eligibility will now be extended to legal guardians, in addition to parents, who are lawfully present in the United States.</p>
<p>This expansion will also allow certain parents and legal guardians who have a pending asylum application or a pending U visa petition, filed prior to May 15th, 2021, the ability to reunite with their children.</p>
<p>This is just one component of the President’s multi-pronged approach to address the challenges of irregular migration through and from Central America.</p>
<p>The steps we are taking reflect our values as a nation and represent our continued commitment to ensure that we treat people with dignity and respect, and that we protect the most vulnerable people, especially our children.</p>
<p><a id="post-252304-DRC"></a> And as you might have seen, Acting Assistant Secretary for Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor Lisa Peterson is in Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of the Congo, or DRC, from June 14th through June 16th – I’m sorry, June 18th – representing the United States in the first ever U.S.-DRC bilateral human rights dialogue.</p>
<p>The dialogue is an opportunity to have an open discussion about the most pressing democratic and human rights issues facing the country and how the United States can support the DRC in its efforts to advance respect for democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>This dialogue is focused on promoting accountability for human rights abuses, ongoing Congolese preparations for an on-time, free, and fair election in 2023, continued progress in combating trafficking in persons under President Tshisekedi, and protecting and preserving fundamental freedoms.</p>
<p>With that, we’ll give it a few minutes before we start taking your questions.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Shaun Tandon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hello.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. Shaun Tandon’s line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Hope you’re well. I was wondering if you had anything to say about the march that’s going ahead today in Jerusalem. Does the State Department have any concerns about it? What’s your assessment of how it’s going, and what’s your message to the two sides on how to handle this?</p>
<p>If you can allow me, just briefly something else as well. The Hungarian parliament passed a law that – it aimed at prohibiting quote-unquote “promotion of homosexuality.” How does the State Department see that? Will this at all affect relations with Prime Minister Orban? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Shaun. <a id="post-252304-MiddleEastPeace"></a>To your first question, well, we certainly don’t have an assessment to state from here, but what we can say is we believe that it’s essential for all parties to refrain from any steps that exacerbate tensions.</p>
<p>And to your second question, I’ll just lead with, of course, <a id="post-252304-Hungary"></a>as you know, the United States is centering our foreign policy around human rights. And of course, that includes the struggle to end discrimination, criminalization, as well as stigma against LGBTQI persons all around the world. And of course, that is essential to the commitment that we have to fundamental freedoms for people who are individuals not only in the United States, but to our partners and allies globally as well.</p>
<p>So we’re certainly aware of the law that passed today, and of course it raises concerns about, again, what I said about freedoms of expression, as well as the restrictions on – which have no place in democratic societies. The United States is actually committed to strengthening our partnership with Hungary, as well as advancing the Biden administration’s support for democratic institutions, human rights, as well as rule of law globally.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jiha Ham.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Ms. Ham’s line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. So North Korea yesterday released a statement criticizing Japan because Japan is holding a symposium in the UN over the abduction issue later this month. North Korea claimed that the abduction issue was already resolved. But as you know, not only Japanese but also many South Koreans were taken to North Korea in the past. How do you view this issue? Could you tell us if the new policy on North Korea can handle this abduction issue, along with other critical issues? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Jiha. <a id="post-252304-NorthKoreaJapan"></a>So to your specific question on North Korea and Japan, I’d have to refer you to those governments. But from our end, our policy on the DPRK has not changed.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Simon Lewis, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Simon Lewis’s line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi. Thanks, Jalina. I wanted to see if you have any response to some calls coming out of meeting of Arab states in Qatar today, who are asking for the UN Security Council to discuss and step in over the Grand Ethiopian Renaissance Dam, or the GERD. Does the U.S. – would the U.S. sort of welcome that, and would you like to see that brought up in the Security Council, and is there any specific action that you would advocate for in that forum? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> <a id="post-252304-EthiopiaGERD"></a>So on that issue, we don’t have any updates or any announcements today. But what I will say, broadly speaking, is that the United States continues to support collaborative as well as constructive efforts by Ethiopia, Egypt, and Sudan in order to reach an arrangement on the GERD. And of course, we understand the importance of the Nile water to all three of those countries, and we’ll continue to encourage resumption of productive dialogue on the GERD. But outside of that, I have nothing to preview at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Tracy Wilkinson.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hello?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hi.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> He didn’t say my line was open; I was waiting. Okay. On the Central American Minors Program, can you – so this is going to vastly or largely expand the number of potential petitioners for people who want to bring their kids up. Do you have any estimate, ballpark figures of how many people – how many additional cases and kids we’re talking about could come up, could be – their arrival could be applied for? And I understand all of the processing is going to take place in the home country, so my question – the second question is whether you’ve had – what kind of discussions you’ve had with the governments of El Salvador, Honduras, and Guatemala for their cooperation in this. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> <a id="post-252304-CentralAmerica2"></a>So I’ll just say at the top – so in the restart of the CAM Program we’ve identified a little over 3,100 cases – that’d be 3,162 cases to be exact – representing 3,828 individuals. Right now we just can’t speculate on how many may ultimately be resettled as refugees or be admitted via parole status.</p>
<p>Now to your second question on any dialogue, I have nothing to preview at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Laura Kelly.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Laura Kelly, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you so much. Hi, Jalina. Thanks for taking my question. The Iranian presidential elections are set to take place this Friday and polling indicates a low turnout of voters. How is the administration viewing the legitimacy of these elections? And if I may, what is the impact that the Iranian presidential elections have on U.S. discussions in Vienna to rejoin the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> <a id="post-252304-Iran"></a>Well, we’re – I’m certainly not in the position to determine or state from here – to determine the legitimacy of Iran’s elections, and we certainly won’t get ahead of that this Friday. That’s something for the Iranian people to decide for themselves.</p>
<p>And just to your point on the talks in Vienna, as you know our Special Envoy for Iran Rob Malley is in his sixth round of talks in Vienna this week, and again, I’ll continue to underscore that meaningful process continues to be made on the language necessary to address nuclear and sanctions-related issues. But of course, there are – outstanding issues remain on both of them, as well. These meetings, of course, have been productive but they’re ongoing, so outside of that I don&#8217;t have anything to announce as well.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jessica Donati.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Jessica Donati, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi. Thank you. I just wanted to follow up with Tracy’s question. In the opening, you said that this could affect potentially tens of thousands of cases for children, but then later you said that there was just going – you only identified three to four thousand. I was wondering if you could clarify.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> <a id="post-252304-CentralAmerica3"></a>Yeah, my clarification was, again, in the restart of the CAM Program where identified – where we identified over 3,000 cases, which was 3,162 cases representing 3,828 individuals. Beyond that, if you have any other specific questions we’d be happy to take that for you, but that’s all we have to preview for today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Michele Kelemen.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Michele Kelemen, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. The new Israeli foreign minister is indicating that he wants to improve relations with Democrats in Washington, restore kind of the bipartisan nature of the U.S.-Israel relationship. And I’m wondering, would the State Department help facilitate that, and when might we see a visit by Yair Lapid? I saw that Blinken has – the Secretary has invited Lapid to Washington.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> <a id="post-252304-Israel"></a>For now, we don’t have any visits to announce at this time. And when it comes to their relations with Congress, we’ll leave that to members of the House and senators to determine their engagement, but that’s something that we wouldn’t facilitate or do anything like that from here.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Soyoung Kim.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thank you.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Soyoung Kim, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. South Korea’s minister of reunification was supposed to visit the U.S. for the U.S.-South Korea working group meeting to mainly discuss North Korea issues sometime this month, but it was called off with no official details. Do you know the reason why the plan was canceled, and when do you think the next meeting is possible and reschedule?</p>
<p>And just a briefly follow-up question: Is the U.S. still trying to reach out to the North Korea or waiting until there is response from the North? Any update? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> <a id="post-252304-NorthKoreaSouthKorea"></a>So your – the first question you asked, we’re going to have to take back to you. And to your second question on engagement, we don’t have anything to update you on today or any announcements to make.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Soyoung’s line is open again.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh, the first question? Excuse me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks. I believe we’ve asked – we’ve answered Soyoung’s questions. Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> We can go to Doug Byun.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> There is no one by that name in the question queue.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Okay. We’re going to take our last question from Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Jalina, just to follow up on Shaun’s question, it is really getting out of hand with this march. The Israelis are arresting all kinds of Palestinians, including my colleagues, journalists who are covering the event. And it’s a very volatile situation. The Israelis did not heed your call to hold back on this march. So are you not concerned that this may get out of hand and we may end up in a situation that we had in last May? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> <a id="post-252304-MiddleEastPeace2"></a>Thank you for your question, Said. From here, again, I’ll continue to underscore that we believe it’s essential for all parties to refrain from any steps that would exacerbate tensions.</p>
<p>And with that, thank you all for joining today’s press briefing, and I hope you have a wonderful week ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:31 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:11 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you so much for joining today’s State Department press briefing. I have two updates at the top before I start taking your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-252304-CentralAmerica"></a> I would like to draw your attention to the joint statement issued by Secretary Blinken and Secretary Mayorkas today about the expansion of the Central American Minors, or CAM, program, which provides certain Guatemalan, Honduran, or Salvadoran children access to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program.</p>
<p>As a part of our focus on a responsible, phased approach to humanely managing migration and expanding legal pathways, we continue to reopen cases in our efforts to reunite families. Since we announced CAM’s reopening in March, we have reopened approximately 1,100 cases.</p>
<p>As we continue to develop and expand initiatives that provide a safe, legal, and orderly alternative to dangerous irregular migration, we are announcing today the second phase of the CAM reopening that will expand the ability of tens of thousands of U.S.-based individuals to petition for children to access the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program through CAM.</p>
<p>Petitioner eligibility will now be extended to legal guardians, in addition to parents, who are lawfully present in the United States.</p>
<p>This expansion will also allow certain parents and legal guardians who have a pending asylum application or a pending U visa petition, filed prior to May 15th, 2021, the ability to reunite with their children.</p>
<p>This is just one component of the President’s multi-pronged approach to address the challenges of irregular migration through and from Central America.</p>
<p>The steps we are taking reflect our values as a nation and represent our continued commitment to ensure that we treat people with dignity and respect, and that we protect the most vulnerable people, especially our children.</p>
<p><a id="post-252304-DRC"></a> And as you might have seen, Acting Assistant Secretary for Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor Lisa Peterson is in Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of the Congo, or DRC, from June 14th through June 16th – I’m sorry, June 18th – representing the United States in the first ever U.S.-DRC bilateral human rights dialogue.</p>
<p>The dialogue is an opportunity to have an open discussion about the most pressing democratic and human rights issues facing the country and how the United States can support the DRC in its efforts to advance respect for democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>This dialogue is focused on promoting accountability for human rights abuses, ongoing Congolese preparations for an on-time, free, and fair election in 2023, continued progress in combating trafficking in persons under President Tshisekedi, and protecting and preserving fundamental freedoms.</p>
<p>With that, we’ll give it a few minutes before we start taking your questions.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Shaun Tandon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hello.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. Shaun Tandon’s line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Hope you’re well. I was wondering if you had anything to say about the march that’s going ahead today in Jerusalem. Does the State Department have any concerns about it? What’s your assessment of how it’s going, and what’s your message to the two sides on how to handle this?</p>
<p>If you can allow me, just briefly something else as well. The Hungarian parliament passed a law that – it aimed at prohibiting quote-unquote “promotion of homosexuality.” How does the State Department see that? Will this at all affect relations with Prime Minister Orban? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Shaun. <a id="post-252304-MiddleEastPeace"></a>To your first question, well, we certainly don’t have an assessment to state from here, but what we can say is we believe that it’s essential for all parties to refrain from any steps that exacerbate tensions.</p>
<p>And to your second question, I’ll just lead with, of course, <a id="post-252304-Hungary"></a>as you know, the United States is centering our foreign policy around human rights. And of course, that includes the struggle to end discrimination, criminalization, as well as stigma against LGBTQI persons all around the world. And of course, that is essential to the commitment that we have to fundamental freedoms for people who are individuals not only in the United States, but to our partners and allies globally as well.</p>
<p>So we’re certainly aware of the law that passed today, and of course it raises concerns about, again, what I said about freedoms of expression, as well as the restrictions on – which have no place in democratic societies. The United States is actually committed to strengthening our partnership with Hungary, as well as advancing the Biden administration’s support for democratic institutions, human rights, as well as rule of law globally.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jiha Ham.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Ms. Ham’s line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. So North Korea yesterday released a statement criticizing Japan because Japan is holding a symposium in the UN over the abduction issue later this month. North Korea claimed that the abduction issue was already resolved. But as you know, not only Japanese but also many South Koreans were taken to North Korea in the past. How do you view this issue? Could you tell us if the new policy on North Korea can handle this abduction issue, along with other critical issues? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Jiha. <a id="post-252304-NorthKoreaJapan"></a>So to your specific question on North Korea and Japan, I’d have to refer you to those governments. But from our end, our policy on the DPRK has not changed.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Simon Lewis, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Simon Lewis’s line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi. Thanks, Jalina. I wanted to see if you have any response to some calls coming out of meeting of Arab states in Qatar today, who are asking for the UN Security Council to discuss and step in over the Grand Ethiopian Renaissance Dam, or the GERD. Does the U.S. – would the U.S. sort of welcome that, and would you like to see that brought up in the Security Council, and is there any specific action that you would advocate for in that forum? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> <a id="post-252304-EthiopiaGERD"></a>So on that issue, we don’t have any updates or any announcements today. But what I will say, broadly speaking, is that the United States continues to support collaborative as well as constructive efforts by Ethiopia, Egypt, and Sudan in order to reach an arrangement on the GERD. And of course, we understand the importance of the Nile water to all three of those countries, and we’ll continue to encourage resumption of productive dialogue on the GERD. But outside of that, I have nothing to preview at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Tracy Wilkinson.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hello?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hi.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> He didn’t say my line was open; I was waiting. Okay. On the Central American Minors Program, can you – so this is going to vastly or largely expand the number of potential petitioners for people who want to bring their kids up. Do you have any estimate, ballpark figures of how many people – how many additional cases and kids we’re talking about could come up, could be – their arrival could be applied for? And I understand all of the processing is going to take place in the home country, so my question – the second question is whether you’ve had – what kind of discussions you’ve had with the governments of El Salvador, Honduras, and Guatemala for their cooperation in this. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> <a id="post-252304-CentralAmerica2"></a>So I’ll just say at the top – so in the restart of the CAM Program we’ve identified a little over 3,100 cases – that’d be 3,162 cases to be exact – representing 3,828 individuals. Right now we just can’t speculate on how many may ultimately be resettled as refugees or be admitted via parole status.</p>
<p>Now to your second question on any dialogue, I have nothing to preview at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Laura Kelly.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Laura Kelly, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you so much. Hi, Jalina. Thanks for taking my question. The Iranian presidential elections are set to take place this Friday and polling indicates a low turnout of voters. How is the administration viewing the legitimacy of these elections? And if I may, what is the impact that the Iranian presidential elections have on U.S. discussions in Vienna to rejoin the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> <a id="post-252304-Iran"></a>Well, we’re – I’m certainly not in the position to determine or state from here – to determine the legitimacy of Iran’s elections, and we certainly won’t get ahead of that this Friday. That’s something for the Iranian people to decide for themselves.</p>
<p>And just to your point on the talks in Vienna, as you know our Special Envoy for Iran Rob Malley is in his sixth round of talks in Vienna this week, and again, I’ll continue to underscore that meaningful process continues to be made on the language necessary to address nuclear and sanctions-related issues. But of course, there are – outstanding issues remain on both of them, as well. These meetings, of course, have been productive but they’re ongoing, so outside of that I don&#8217;t have anything to announce as well.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jessica Donati.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Jessica Donati, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi. Thank you. I just wanted to follow up with Tracy’s question. In the opening, you said that this could affect potentially tens of thousands of cases for children, but then later you said that there was just going – you only identified three to four thousand. I was wondering if you could clarify.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> <a id="post-252304-CentralAmerica3"></a>Yeah, my clarification was, again, in the restart of the CAM Program where identified – where we identified over 3,000 cases, which was 3,162 cases representing 3,828 individuals. Beyond that, if you have any other specific questions we’d be happy to take that for you, but that’s all we have to preview for today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Michele Kelemen.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Michele Kelemen, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. The new Israeli foreign minister is indicating that he wants to improve relations with Democrats in Washington, restore kind of the bipartisan nature of the U.S.-Israel relationship. And I’m wondering, would the State Department help facilitate that, and when might we see a visit by Yair Lapid? I saw that Blinken has – the Secretary has invited Lapid to Washington.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> <a id="post-252304-Israel"></a>For now, we don’t have any visits to announce at this time. And when it comes to their relations with Congress, we’ll leave that to members of the House and senators to determine their engagement, but that’s something that we wouldn’t facilitate or do anything like that from here.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Soyoung Kim.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thank you.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Soyoung Kim, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. South Korea’s minister of reunification was supposed to visit the U.S. for the U.S.-South Korea working group meeting to mainly discuss North Korea issues sometime this month, but it was called off with no official details. Do you know the reason why the plan was canceled, and when do you think the next meeting is possible and reschedule?</p>
<p>And just a briefly follow-up question: Is the U.S. still trying to reach out to the North Korea or waiting until there is response from the North? Any update? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> <a id="post-252304-NorthKoreaSouthKorea"></a>So your – the first question you asked, we’re going to have to take back to you. And to your second question on engagement, we don’t have anything to update you on today or any announcements to make.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Soyoung’s line is open again.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh, the first question? Excuse me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks. I believe we’ve asked – we’ve answered Soyoung’s questions. Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> We can go to Doug Byun.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> There is no one by that name in the question queue.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Okay. We’re going to take our last question from Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Jalina, just to follow up on Shaun’s question, it is really getting out of hand with this march. The Israelis are arresting all kinds of Palestinians, including my colleagues, journalists who are covering the event. And it’s a very volatile situation. The Israelis did not heed your call to hold back on this march. So are you not concerned that this may get out of hand and we may end up in a situation that we had in last May? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> <a id="post-252304-MiddleEastPeace2"></a>Thank you for your question, Said. From here, again, I’ll continue to underscore that we believe it’s essential for all parties to refrain from any steps that would exacerbate tensions.</p>
<p>And with that, thank you all for joining today’s press briefing, and I hope you have a wonderful week ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:31 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brazil Signs Artemis Accords</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/brazil-signs-artemis-accords/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 21:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=252301</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken delivered virtual remarks today to congratulate Brazil on signing the Artemis Accords.  Brazil is the first South American country to join the Accords.  Led by the Department of State and NASA, the Artemis Accords build a path toward peaceful and responsible space exploration beyond Earth’s orbit and are a keystone of our space diplomacy.  The Secretary thanked President Bolsonaro, Minister Pontes, Minister França, and all those gathered in Brasília, emphasizing that the United States looks forward to expanding space cooperation with international and commercial partners while aiming to land the first woman and the first person of color on the surface of the Moon.  NASA’s Artemis program will allow us to develop the technologies and experience necessary to mount a historic human mission to Mars.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov">OES-PA-DG@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken delivered virtual remarks today to congratulate Brazil on signing the Artemis Accords.  Brazil is the first South American country to join the Accords.  Led by the Department of State and NASA, the Artemis Accords build a path toward peaceful and responsible space exploration beyond Earth’s orbit and are a keystone of our space diplomacy.  The Secretary thanked President Bolsonaro, Minister Pontes, Minister França, and all those gathered in Brasília, emphasizing that the United States looks forward to expanding space cooperation with international and commercial partners while aiming to land the first woman and the first person of color on the surface of the Moon.  NASA’s Artemis program will allow us to develop the technologies and experience necessary to mount a historic human mission to Mars.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov">OES-PA-DG@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Lenderking’s Travel to Saudi Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-special-envoy-for-yemen-lenderkings-travel-to-saudi-arabia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 20:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=252294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking will travel to Saudi Arabia on June 15-17 where he will meet with senior officials from the Governments of the Republic of Yemen and Saudi Arabia, as well as UN Special Envoy Martin Griffiths.  Throughout the trip, Special Envoy Lenderking will discuss the latest efforts to achieve a comprehensive, nationwide ceasefire, which is the only way to bring Yemenis the relief they so urgently need.</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the recent Omani trip to Sanaa and the efforts undertaken by the Sultanate to support peace in Yemen.  The United States also recognizes Saudi Arabia&#8217;s efforts to advance implementation of the Riyadh Agreement, which is essential to stability, security, and prosperity in the south of Yemen.  Additionally, Special Envoy Lenderking will continue to press for the free flow of essential commodities and humanitarian aid into and throughout Yemen.</p>
<p>For any questions, please contact <a href="mailto:NEA-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NEA-Press@state.gov</a> and follow us on Twitter <a class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/StateDept_NEA#_blank" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">@StateDept_NEA</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking will travel to Saudi Arabia on June 15-17 where he will meet with senior officials from the Governments of the Republic of Yemen and Saudi Arabia, as well as UN Special Envoy Martin Griffiths.  Throughout the trip, Special Envoy Lenderking will discuss the latest efforts to achieve a comprehensive, nationwide ceasefire, which is the only way to bring Yemenis the relief they so urgently need.</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the recent Omani trip to Sanaa and the efforts undertaken by the Sultanate to support peace in Yemen.  The United States also recognizes Saudi Arabia&#8217;s efforts to advance implementation of the Riyadh Agreement, which is essential to stability, security, and prosperity in the south of Yemen.  Additionally, Special Envoy Lenderking will continue to press for the free flow of essential commodities and humanitarian aid into and throughout Yemen.</p>
<p>For any questions, please contact <a href="mailto:NEA-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NEA-Press@state.gov</a> and follow us on Twitter <a class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/StateDept_NEA#_blank" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">@StateDept_NEA</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement by the U.S. Department of State and U.S. Department of Homeland Security on the Expansion of Access to the Central American Minors Program</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-by-the-u-s-department-of-state-and-u-s-department-of-homeland-security-on-the-expansion-of-access-to-the-central-american-minors-program/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 18:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=252161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following joint statement was released by Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken and Secretary Alejandro N. Mayorkas.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>The Department of Homeland Security’s U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services and Department of State’s Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration have been making progress toward reinstituting and improving the Central American Minors (CAM) program since our agencies launched the first phase of its reopening on March 10.  As part of this focus on a responsible, phased approach, we continue to reopen cases that were closed when CAM was terminated in 2018.  This is just one component of the President’s multi-pronged approach to address the challenges of irregular migration throughout North and Central America.</p>
<p>Today, we are proud to announce the second phase of the CAM reopening, which will expand access to the program to a greater number of qualifying individuals.  Eligibility to petition will now be extended to include legal guardians (in addition to parents) who are in the United States pursuant to any of the following qualifying categories: lawful permanent residence; temporary protected status; parole; deferred action; deferred enforced departure; or withholding of removal.  In addition, this expansion of eligibility will now include certain U.S.-based parents or legal guardians who have a pending asylum application or a pending U visa petition filed before May 15, 2021.  It will allow them to petition for access to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program on behalf of their children who are nationals of El Salvador, Guatemala, or Honduras for potential resettlement in the United States.  These new changes will dramatically expand access to the CAM program.</p>
<p>We are firmly committed to welcoming people to the United States with humanity and respect, as well as providing a legal alternative to irregular migration.  We are delivering on our promise to promote safe, orderly, and humane migration from Central America through this expansion of legal pathways to seek humanitarian protection in the United States.</p>
<p><em>End Text.</em></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following joint statement was released by Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken and Secretary Alejandro N. Mayorkas.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>The Department of Homeland Security’s U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services and Department of State’s Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration have been making progress toward reinstituting and improving the Central American Minors (CAM) program since our agencies launched the first phase of its reopening on March 10.  As part of this focus on a responsible, phased approach, we continue to reopen cases that were closed when CAM was terminated in 2018.  This is just one component of the President’s multi-pronged approach to address the challenges of irregular migration throughout North and Central America.</p>
<p>Today, we are proud to announce the second phase of the CAM reopening, which will expand access to the program to a greater number of qualifying individuals.  Eligibility to petition will now be extended to include legal guardians (in addition to parents) who are in the United States pursuant to any of the following qualifying categories: lawful permanent residence; temporary protected status; parole; deferred action; deferred enforced departure; or withholding of removal.  In addition, this expansion of eligibility will now include certain U.S.-based parents or legal guardians who have a pending asylum application or a pending U visa petition filed before May 15, 2021.  It will allow them to petition for access to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program on behalf of their children who are nationals of El Salvador, Guatemala, or Honduras for potential resettlement in the United States.  These new changes will dramatically expand access to the CAM program.</p>
<p>We are firmly committed to welcoming people to the United States with humanity and respect, as well as providing a legal alternative to irregular migration.  We are delivering on our promise to promote safe, orderly, and humane migration from Central America through this expansion of legal pathways to seek humanitarian protection in the United States.</p>
<p><em>End Text.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
