<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 20:18:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Italian President Mattarella  </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-italian-president-mattarella/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 20:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255777</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Italian President Sergio Mattarella in Rome. Secretary Blinken and President Mattarella emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Italy partnership in the global effort to combat the climate crisis and recover from COVID-19.  They also discussed our shared values, including in the context of human rights in China and around the globe, as well as our collective support for Libya&#8217;s plan to hold national elections in December 2021.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Italian President Sergio Mattarella in Rome. Secretary Blinken and President Mattarella emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Italy partnership in the global effort to combat the climate crisis and recover from COVID-19.  They also discussed our shared values, including in the context of human rights in China and around the globe, as well as our collective support for Libya&#8217;s plan to hold national elections in December 2021.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Italian Foreign Minister Luigi Di Maio At a Joint Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-italian-foreign-minister-luigi-di-maio-at-a-joint-press-availability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 20:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255772</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rome, Italy</p>
<p>Fiera Roma</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Good morning, everyone, and welcome to Rome for this very important ministerial conference.  I will hand over right away to Minister Di Maio and Secretary of State Blinken for their opening remarks, and then we’ll take some questions from you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER DI MAIO:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you, and good afternoon, everyone.  Thank you very much for having come today.  Together with Secretary of State Tony Blinken, we just chaired the plenary ministerial meeting of the anti-Daesh coalition.  The coalition hadn’t met in this format since February of 2019 in Washington, and I must say that I am delighted that we managed to hold a meeting for the first time in Italy this time.  And this shows that we are, in fact, re-jumping, restarting our economies now.</p>
<p>Daesh is a big threat, and we had a chance to debate the solutions that we’ve come up in order to take it down.  Now in March 2019, we managed in fact to have the situation under control, but they continue to be a threat in Iraq in certain areas, and in other territories as well.</p>
<p>Today in the first session of our meeting, we focused on an update of the activities of the coalition in terms of the military operations and the stabilization of the Daesh-free areas.  Of course, we need to also fight the funding sources of Daesh, and we also talked about initiatives in Africa.  It is important to consider the military instruments as well as the civilian instruments that we have at our disposal, because we know that in order to take down Daesh, we need a number of different dimensions in our actions, and we need to also work on counter-messaging to counter their propaganda, and also repatriate foreign terrorist fighters.</p>
<p>Now, for Italy and for the United States, it was important to have the 2021 campaign in order to stabilize the Daesh-free areas in Iraq and in northeastern Syria.  Now, this was a very important activity because we have to ensure the socioeconomic conditions in that region so as to avoid a return of terrorism and violent extremism.  Italy traditionally has been working on this in Iraq; in fact, there is a huge effort on our part in order to allow the displaced persons to return, and we have the United Nations Office for Project Services and the Sinjar Action Fund, which was created by Nadia Murad, the peace prize – Nobel Peace Prize winner.</p>
<p>In northeastern Syria, we are operating with a number of different international organizations in order to support the local population to provide them with livelihood.  And we’re also supporting their agricultural activities.  We’re also working with the World Health Organization in order to contain and curb the pandemic in that area.</p>
<p>Now it was possible today for Italy and the United States to reiterate an important principle, a shared principle: Daesh is very dangerous still, and there are a number of instruments that we can use in order to take action not only in the Middle East.  Now there is an alarming phenomenon taking place on the African continent, and in particular in the Sahel region, but also in Eastern Africa, for example, as in the north of Mozambique.</p>
<p>Now last week I went to Mali and Niger myself.  And in fact, this shows how much Italy is focused on this region.  For this reason, with the support of the United States as well as many other partners, I suggested that we establish an Africa working group.  This way we can identify and curb the Daesh-related terrorist threats on the continent, and we can therefore determine measures, together with our local partners, and they can be put in place through the multilateral initiatives and programs that are already ongoing.</p>
<p>Now we are fearing the expansion and spread of Daesh in Africa, and therefore at the ministerial meeting, we invited some African countries that are not coalition members – Burkina Faso, Ghana, Mozambique, for example.  We invited them as observers to follow our meeting.</p>
<p>And I also took this opportunity today to reiterate the fact that Italy is continuing with its effort to take down Daesh.  And in fact, we’ve always taken a multidimensional approach.  Italy’s commitment is very strong.  We want to protect the security of our citizens, because this is an absolute priority for us.  Italy is one of the main military contributors to the coalition in Iraq.  We were there with our Carabinieri service.  We worked on the training of Iraqi and Kurd military and police forces, and our aircraft continue to do refueling and personnel transport activities as well.</p>
<p>One of our success stories in Iraq and in the coalition is linked to the protection of Iraqi cultural heritage.  Unfortunately, Daesh’s fury had tried to destroy this heritage, and we are also financing archeological activities here, and the taskforce for the heritage is in fact working on trying to combat an illicit trafficking of works of art and archaeological finds.</p>
<p>So there was a briefing during the meeting on all these different subjects, and Italy will continue to focus on counter-messaging to take down the Daesh propaganda, because we think that in addition to fighting their territorial control, we’ve got to fight their ideology as well.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much, and I’m very happy to hand over to the Secretary of State, Mr. Antony Blinken.</p>
<p>(In English) Now give the floor to Secretary Blinken.  Please, Tony.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you so much, Foreign Minister Di Maio.  Luigi, <em>grazie mille, amico</em>.</p>
<p>I am particularly delighted that we’re meeting so soon after the G7, NATO, the U.S.-EU leader summits.  Italy and the United States did significant work together in the leadup to those meetings, and that helped lay the groundwork for the real commitments the countries made at the summits themselves.</p>
<p>And now we’re following up on those commitments, making sure that our countries and others do what we said we would do.  It’s no accident that we started that follow-up in Italy, in France, and Germany this week, the three countries that I visited on this trip.  In addition to being three of our closest partners and strongest allies, they’re the only three countries that are members of the EU, NATO, and the G7, and their leadership will be crucial to delivering on our commitments.</p>
<p>Those commitments include revitalizing NATO, preparing the Alliance to deter adversaries and protect against a new range of threats from cyber attacks to a rapidly changing climate; delivering on the G7’s pledge to get a billion COVID vaccines to people around the world; to invest in much-needed infrastructure projects in developing countries in a way that’s open, sustainable, and empowers communities rather than saddling them with debt; deepening U.S.-EU cooperation across a range of areas, including trade and technology in particular.</p>
<p>Luigi was the first foreign minister to officially visit the State Department in the Biden-Harris administration, and that was just one of the many conversations that we’ve had, the work we’ve done together.  In fact, we even wrote an op-ed together a few months ago.</p>
<p>The reason that we’re in such close communication is because the interests and values of Italy and the United States are closely aligned.  We share a deep commitment to promoting democracy and human rights.  We see the same big challenges on the horizon and we recognize that we can’t tackle them alone, and we shouldn’t try to.  We’re better together, and that is what motivates our partnership.</p>
<p>I have to tell you we’re grateful for Italy’s leadership in putting these challenges at the center of the global agenda.  Italy made combating COVID-19 a focus of the G20 presidency this year as well as ensuring that the recovery not only rebuilds our economies, but tackles inequities within and between countries that the pandemic has only worsened and put in starker relief.  Italy is leading by example in pledging to donate $360 million in funds now to COVAX and sending 15 million vaccine doses from its own supply to lower and middle-income countries around the world.</p>
<p>And as you know, Luigi and I are co-hosting two high-level meetings tomorrow with our fellow foreign ministers focused on serious threats to international stability and security.  Today we began, of course, with the meeting of the Coalition to Defeat ISIS and what we have to do to eradicate what’s left of the terrorist group, and, very critically, as Italy has been emphasizing, to prevent its emergence in places like Africa.  Italy has not only contributed to this counterterrorism effort, but has demonstrated the way countries can take back nationals captured as foreign terrorist fighters.</p>
<p>And this afternoon, we’re also co-sponsoring a second meeting to address the urgent humanitarian crisis in Syria, particularly through broadening cross-border assistance, which is essential to reaching millions of Syrians who are in dire need of food, medicine, COVID vaccines, other lifesaving aid.  I’m announcing today that the United States is providing an additional $436 million in assistance – humanitarian assistance – to Syrians and the communities that host them, and that brings the total U.S. humanitarian assistance in response to the crisis in Syria to nearly $13.5 billion.  We’ll also use the meeting that’s upcoming to refocus on a path to a political solution in Syria, the only way to provide the Syrian people with a foundation upon which to reconcile, make peace, and begin to rebuild.</p>
<p>Of course, the relationship between the United States and Italy is about more than the challenges that we’re faced – that we’re facing and that we’re dealing with today and tomorrow.  Italy graciously hosts more than 34,000 U.S. servicemembers, civilians, their family members, and the U.S. Navy’s 6th Fleet headquarters in Naples.  Our two-way trade in goods and services amounted to about $80 billion last year.  Our direct investment in one another’s economies creates hundreds of thousands of jobs.  And we celebrated the 160th year of our diplomatic relationship.</p>
<p>But we know that the ties between the people of our countries have existed for even longer than that.  You see it in the 20 million Americans who proudly claim Italian heritage, in the Italian American pockets in big cities and small towns across our country, in the Americans who come to Italy every year to study, learn the language, trace their roots, and just enjoy Italy.  It’s hard to see a part of America’s national fabric that is not interwoven with threads from Italy, and we are so much richer for it.</p>
<p>As President Biden has pointed out, we meet at a time when our democracies face a grave threat from adversaries outside who seek to undermine the free and open rules-based order that has long provided the foundation of our shared security and prosperity, and from skeptics inside who question whether democracy can make their lives better in tangible ways.  I am confident that the rights, opportunities, and ability to keep improving on itself, that only democracy can provide, cannot be matched by any other system.  But I also know that if we’re going to overcome these challenges and show that we can deliver, we have to come together, we have to band together with our closest allies and partners.  For the United States, that means Italy.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER DI MAIO:</strong>  Thank you, Tony.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Thank you very much.  We can now take a few questions.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) Matteo Alviti from the Channel 1 news, Rai.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Via interpreter) I have a couple of questions.  Good afternoon.  The first has to do with your co-chairmanship two years after the meeting in Washington, as you yourselves pointed out.  Now there is a strengthened – is there a strengthened up – a stepped-up cooperation between Italy and the U.S. through this co-chairmanship?</p>
<p>My second question has to do with your meeting on Syria, which will be held in a few minutes.  On the issue of multilateralism, what can you tell us in advance of what you think will come up?  And in particular, the role of Turkey, what might that be in connection with the SDF force in Syria?</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER DI MAIO:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Well, firstly, I wish to say that Italy is indeed honored and very pleased to have been able to co-chair the meeting this morning, the ministerial meeting of the anti-Daesh coalition.  Certainly, this was a way of showing, as Tony just said, how strong the ties are between Italy and the United States, and that we are indeed cooperating on major global issues.  And this is quite natural if you consider that we are two allies, two great allies.</p>
<p>Now in our fight against international terrorism, no one can do this on their own, so that is why the cooperation between Italy and the United States is absolutely strategic, and it is also a way of recognizing the leading role played by Italy in the coalition.  And in fact, I’ll seize this opportunity to thank all the men and women in uniform, all the members of our armed forces that are engaged in missions abroad and trying to fight terrorism, in fact.</p>
<p>Now the coalition meeting today is taking place in a moment in which we fear that Daesh and ISIS can regain strength – regain their strength.  Now that is why we mustn’t lower our guard.  In fact, it’s an opportunity to tell one another that we must step up the action undertaken by the coalition, but not by shifting our focus, but by increasing the areas in which we can operate.  So this doesn’t only mean the Middle East, but Africa, the Sahel, and also Mozambique and the Horn of Africa.</p>
<p>The meeting on Syria that we will have in just a few minutes – we’ll be co-chairing that together, in fact – that is definitely another important opportunity that we have to have an exchange of views.  And the countries that are most interested in establishing peace in Syria will, of course, give us all a chance to plan our next steps.  Now Italy is supporting the UN program through the Special Envoy Mr. Pedersen, and we also know that the UN program and the institutional committee are initiatives that need to be supported by the allies, the main allies of multilateralism.  So on a bilateral level, Italy and the United States are great friends.  We share values and activities together, of course, and therefore, we must continue to support multilateralism as well, because we think that this is the main tool that we have in order to tackle crises all over the world.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>And I fully subscribe to everything that Luigi just said.  And I think it’s a reflection of the fact that when it comes to our own cooperation – both working together bilaterally but also in multilateral institutions where you see an extremely active Italy playing a leadership role – it’s a reflection of the fact that we both see, we both understand that there’s a greater imperative now than at any other time that I can think of for cooperation among like-minded countries.  Because the simple reality is that not a single one of the issues that we have to deal with that are having an impact on the lives of our citizens in Italy, in the United States, around the world, whether it’s climate change, whether it’s the pandemic, whether it’s the disruptive impact of new technologies, whether it’s the threat posed by terrorism, not a single one can be effectively addressed by any one country acting on its own, even the United States, even Italy.</p>
<p>And so we’re especially grateful at this moment to have such strong allies, partners, and friends as Italy who are taking the lead.  And that reflects itself in the work that we’re doing together; it reflects itself in the work that we’re doing in these international groupings, institutions.  Today is powerful evidence of that.</p>
<p>And just on Syria, we’ll have more to say I’m sure after the meeting.  There is a – an absolute premium here, too, on making sure that we’re doing everything possible to get humanitarian assistance to people in need in Syria.  And that’s going to be a focus of our conversations.  But, of course, that’s the immediate imperative, but the larger objective is to pursue a lasting resolution and peace that Syria so desperately, desperately needs.  And so we’ll make clear our support for a nationwide ceasefire, both to ensure the safe delivery of assistance, but also to try to create more of a foundation upon which the future of Syria can move forward.  But we’ll have more to say I’m sure after the meeting.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Our first question goes to Kylie Atwood from CNN.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.  Foreign Minister, I’d like to start with you.  You’ve said in the past that Italy and China need to forge closer ties, and Italy has been a supporter of China’s Belt and Road Initiative.  Does Italy today maintain steadfast support for the Belt and Road Initiative? And what do you make of Secretary Blinken saying that it would – that a Chinese-led world order would be profoundly illiberal in nature?</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER DE MAIO:  </strong>(Via interpreter)  I’d like to be very clear.  And actually, I’d like to thank you for having asked this question, because it gives me once again the opportunity to clarify what Italy’s position is with respect to alliances of value and geopolitical alliances.  And we see eye to eye with the United States in that respect.  We are allies of the United States, we are partners in NATO, we are members of the European Union, and this means that we are part of an alliance of values, which means that we can credibly tackle issues such as human rights violations.  Italy was in the front line, both at a multilateral level within the UN supporting the latest proposal tabled by Canada, for instance, and in the European Union when we supported the sanctions established in the face of human rights violations.  And our position was very clear in the last G7 summit in the UK, during which our leaders discussed the way in which we can enhance the UN’s effectiveness in combating human rights violations.</p>
<p>And I think that if we all around the world speak out in favor of multilateralism and in favor of the United Nations, we really cannot speak about juxtaposition between different countries.  There is a common action of the UN with the contribution of the High-Level Representative Bachelet with regard to human rights violations, and I believe that the UN representative must be in a position to verify whether there have been human rights violations.  And I would like to speak very clearly.  Italy is a strong trade partner of China.  We’ve enjoyed relations that have lasted for years, but they cannot and do not interfere with the alliance of values we have with the United States, we have with NATO, and the European Union.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Again, could I just follow up with you?  On China specifically, isn’t Italy’s support for China’s Belt and Road Initiative inherently contradictory to their support for the build back better effort that you guys just launched together last week?  And then on your meeting earlier today with Pope Francis, were there any discussions of President Biden receiving Holy Communion?  And on coronavirus, Pope Francis has assessed that those who refuse to get the COVID-19 vaccine are suicidal.  Do you agree?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Kylie, I was about to thank you for addressing your question to Foreign Minister Di Maio, so – but I’ll reserve that.  I think what Luigi said with regard to our approach to China is a very good answer to the question and one that I would simply reiterate.  Look, I think what you’ve seen across the board in recent weeks, particularly at the G7, NATO, the U.S.-EU summit, is an increasing convergence of views among the United States and our European partners and allies about China.  And I think we all recognize the complexity of the relationship, the fact that it is for all of us among the most consequential in the world.  And that complexity manifests itself in the fact that I think we all agree that the relationship has, as I’ve said many times, adversarial aspects, competitive ones, and cooperative ones, too.</p>
<p>And the common denominator is approaching these challenges, whether it’s adversarial, whether it’s competitive, whether it’s cooperative, together.  And increasingly, that’s exactly what you’re seeing.</p>
<p>When it comes to the initiative that we took at the G7, the Build Back Better World, Italy is a participant in that.  We’re going to work over the next months to move that forward.  And the point here is that there is an imperative here, too, around the world for investment in infrastructure in countries that are low and middle-income.  But it needs to be done in a way that’s a race to the top not a race to the bottom.  Italy and our other partners are going to be a full participant in that, and I think that will demonstrate itself in the months ahead.</p>
<p>With regard to the meeting with his holiness the pope, let me just say on a personal level what an honor it was.  The meeting was extremely warm and very wide ranging.  We covered a lot of ground, and I certainly don’t want to speak for his holiness, but just speaking for myself and speaking for the United States, I was very gratified by the meeting and gratified as well by the strong leadership of his holiness on the pandemic, on climate change, on the challenge that we have to address when it comes to irregular migration and refugees, and more broadly, and maybe most important of all, his leadership on the basic proposition that we have to stand for human dignity in everything we do to the best of our ability.</p>
<p>One of the luxuries of my job is that I don’t do domestic politics, and so I’ll simply say that it was truly a wonderful and memorable moment to have had the opportunity to speak to his holiness and to have such a warm and wide-ranging conversation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And can I just follow up?  Do you agree with Pope Francis’ assessment that those who refuse the COVID-19 vaccine are engaging in a suicidal effort?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>I’m not going to speak for the pope in any way.  I think we strongly believe in the importance of vaccination, of seeing as many people not just in our own countries but around the world get vaccinated and to do so as quickly as possible.  And, of course, one of the reasons that we came together at the G7 to push a billion vaccine doses out around the world is because of the absolute importance of this initiative and the need to be vaccinated.</p>
<p>Look, here is the reality that we’re faced with.  As long as the virus is replicating somewhere, it’s likely to be mutating.  And as long as it’s mutating, there is the distinct possibility that it comes back and bites even those who have been vaccinated, so we have to get ahead of this, and the way to get ahead of this is with the fastest possible vaccination around the world.  That’s why Italy and the United States are working so closely together to make sure that we get vaccines out there.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you.  Over to Annalisa Rapana, the Italian news agency, ANSA.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Via interpreter)<em> </em>Good evening.  I have a question for Minister Di Maio.  You mentioned the need for the coalition to focus specifically on Africa and on the Sahel.  I’d like to ask you whether this approach is also shared as – and in what way – and why have you underscored the importance of this step that the coalition ought to take – in focusing on Africa, that is?</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER DI MAIO:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you for your question.  I would like to start by saying that today the United States expressed its support to the proposal to focus part of the effort in the anti-Daesh coalition effort on Africa, on the Sahel, and on countries affected in that continent.  In my recent missions to Niger and Mali, I witnessed the cry for help of those communities, but this is not only typical to those parts of the continent.  We know that many villages have fallen in the hands of terrorists, and we know that we’re talking about huge territories.</p>
<p>Italy has a number of bilateral agreements with some of these countries, specifically to try and fight climate change and combat desertification.  We know that desertification is the root cause of poverty and of lower living standards, because we know that the amount of farmland is shrinking.  We’re also working with the UNHCR in support of refugees.  The UNHCR has a number of outreach initiatives, and these people can come to Italy, if needed, via legal humanitarian corridors.</p>
<p>The real problem is that the fight against terrorism calls for a holistic approach.  The coalition’s experience enables it to tackle this problem in a holistic fashion.  The institutions of those countries are being weakened on account of the attacks perpetrated by terrorist cells, and the time we speak protecting the Sahel also means protecting Europe and its securities and stopping the illicit trafficking of human beings and weapons.  We could achieve this with a step-to-step approach, but in the coming months we are planning to strengthen the will and – of this coalition.  All countries attending today have supported their – this initiative and we’d like to focus on coordinating via the coalition existing initiatives.  And at the same time, we want to draw a clear roadmap to avert the risk that these terrorist organizations may proliferate.  This doesn’t mean stopping the fight against Daesh in Syria and in Iraq.  It simply means that now, years after the territorial defeat of Daesh in the Middle East, we’re now seeing there’s a number of terrorist cells are proliferating in regions such as the Sahel where, obviously, the main migration routes are present, the routes of those who come to Europe, and climate change, poverty, and terrorism are creating millions and millions of poor people.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>If I could, let me just say very clearly that we strongly support Italy’s initiative to make sure that the coalition against Daesh focuses its expertise on Africa while keeping our eye closely on Syria and on Iraq for all of the reasons that Luigi just cited.  This is of significant importance, and I think we heard a strong consensus today on the part of coalition partners to do just that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Our final question goes to Michael Crowley of <em>The New York Times</em>.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  If I may, I have a question for you both on today’s meeting and then another for each of you separately.  For you both, did today’s meeting make you anymore optimistic about more quickly resolving the fate of the ISIS fighters and their families now held in Syria and Iraq?  And specifically, did any nations make new commitments to repatriate foreign fighters?</p>
<p>For Secretary Blinken, my question to you is on last night’s U.S. airstrikes on militia groups in Iraq and Syria.  The Biden administration conducted similar strikes in February calling them a deterrent, but attacks on U.S. forces continued, prompting this second strike.  Is the U.S. prepared to escalate its response if these strikes do not deter continued attacks on our personnel? And do you hold Iran responsible for these ongoing attacks?</p>
<p>And finally, for Minister Di Maio, the Biden administration recently waived sanctions on the Nord Stream 2 pipeline from Russia to Germany.  Italy has previously expressed concern about the project’s impact on European energy security dynamics.  Are you disappointed that the Biden administration is not doing more to block the pipeline’s completion?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER DI MAIO:  </strong>(Via interpreter) I would like to start by saying that today’s meeting has also given us the opportunity to take stock of a number of different initiatives that are in place in the fight against Daesh.  And I’m not just talking about military initiatives.  We have the working group against Daesh propaganda.  That is problematic, as we know, because it is a source of radicalization via the web, for instance.  And the other working group that we co-chair together with the United States and Saudi Arabia is the working group to counter, let’s say, the sources of financing for – of terrorist groups.  And we had a full group format meeting today, which enabled us to identify the next dates on which we will continue to pursue our initiative, both in terms of propaganda and countering financing.</p>
<p>But the best way to counter terrorism and Daesh is to strengthen local institutions, and as member-states of the coalition, and in more general terms, as countries and people who believe in multilateralism, we are striving to increase development assistance investment.  Development assistance is something Italy has always believed in, and this is what has guided Italy’s position in many different theaters.  Italy intends to increase its development assistance, its ODA, to support institutions in Afghanistan, for instance, because withdrawing, militarily speaking, from Afghanistan doesn’t mean pulling out of Afghanistan altogether; on the contrary.  For Italy, this means making an additional effort to strengthen institutions through development cooperation, through police and local forces training programs.</p>
<p>That said, with regard to the topic of diversification of energy sources, Italy has just completed the Trans Adriatic Pipeline precisely with a view to differentiating energy supply sources, particularly with regard to gas.  And Italy continues to believe that as far as energy goes and as far as energy production goes, we need to invest more and more in new technologies and we have to have a diversified energy mix.  We have, at the moment, a number of European programs underway, such as the one that aims to promote hydrogen production.  And I look ahead for the future of the European Union and our member-countries with common policies, with renewable sources of energy, and with transition instruments such as gas.  We believe that it will be possible for us to reduce significantly the dependence on imported sources.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you, Michael.<strong>  </strong>So on the question of foreign terrorist fighters, we spent some time talking about that today in the meeting.  And there is a need for countries to take action to repatriate foreign fighters that come from those countries, to prosecute them where appropriate, to rehabilitate and reintegrate them where appropriate.  And there is some urgency to this.  I noted in the meeting a number of countries that have taken very concrete steps, including, by the way, Italy, as well as the United States, but also a number of other countries, for example, in Central Asia, as well as in the Balkans that have taken important steps.  But more work clearly needs to be done.  The number of foreign terrorist fighters who are in detention in Syria is significant.  The larger group that comprises their family members, women, children is also a significant concern.</p>
<p>And I think the strong message coming out of today’s meeting was the need for countries to do more to that end.  So we’ll see going forward as countries, I hope, step up to this need.  It is something of tremendous importance in terms of making sure that we’re getting people off of and away from the battlefield, and hopefully to a place where they will either face further justice or, in some cases at least, hopefully can be rehabilitated and reintegrated.  But we’ll see the results in the weeks and months ahead.</p>
<p>With regard to the strike last night, at the President’s direction, U.S. military forces conducted airstrikes against facilities used by Iranian-backed militia groups in the Iraq-Syria border region. They targeted facilities used by groups responsible for recent attacks on U.S. interests in Iraq. Specifically, they targeted operational and weapons storage facilities at two locations in Syria, one location in Iraq, both with – very close to the border between the countries.  Several Iran-backed militia groups, including KH, including KSS, use these facilities.  We have been very clear, the President has been very clear throughout, that we will act to protect U.S. personnel.  And given these ongoing attacks that you referred to by Iran-backed groups targeting our interests in Iraq, he directed further military action – we had taken action previously – to disrupt and deter these attacks.</p>
<p>We took necessary, appropriate, deliberate action that is designed to limit the risk of escalation, but also to send a clear and unambiguous deterrent message.  This action in self-defense to do what’s necessary to prevent further attacks, I think, sends a very important and strong message. And I hope very much that it is received by those who are intended to receive it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>If I may just follow up, Mr. Secretary, the first airstrikes were described as having a deterrent purpose and appear not to have served that purpose.  Are you prepared to describe what action the United States might take should the militia attacks continue?  Would the U.S. escalate its response?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>I think we’ve demonstrated, both with the actions taken last night and actions taken previously, that the President is fully prepared to act and act appropriately and deliberately to protect U.S. interest, to protect our people, to protect our personnel.  And again, I would hope that the message sent by the strikes last night will be heard and deter future action.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>And the one other part of my question, I had asked whether you hold Iran responsible for these attacks.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, a number of the groups involved in recent attacks are militia that are backed by Iran.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Thank you very much.  That is all we have time for.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rome, Italy</p>
<p>Fiera Roma</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Good morning, everyone, and welcome to Rome for this very important ministerial conference.  I will hand over right away to Minister Di Maio and Secretary of State Blinken for their opening remarks, and then we’ll take some questions from you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER DI MAIO:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you, and good afternoon, everyone.  Thank you very much for having come today.  Together with Secretary of State Tony Blinken, we just chaired the plenary ministerial meeting of the anti-Daesh coalition.  The coalition hadn’t met in this format since February of 2019 in Washington, and I must say that I am delighted that we managed to hold a meeting for the first time in Italy this time.  And this shows that we are, in fact, re-jumping, restarting our economies now.</p>
<p>Daesh is a big threat, and we had a chance to debate the solutions that we’ve come up in order to take it down.  Now in March 2019, we managed in fact to have the situation under control, but they continue to be a threat in Iraq in certain areas, and in other territories as well.</p>
<p>Today in the first session of our meeting, we focused on an update of the activities of the coalition in terms of the military operations and the stabilization of the Daesh-free areas.  Of course, we need to also fight the funding sources of Daesh, and we also talked about initiatives in Africa.  It is important to consider the military instruments as well as the civilian instruments that we have at our disposal, because we know that in order to take down Daesh, we need a number of different dimensions in our actions, and we need to also work on counter-messaging to counter their propaganda, and also repatriate foreign terrorist fighters.</p>
<p>Now, for Italy and for the United States, it was important to have the 2021 campaign in order to stabilize the Daesh-free areas in Iraq and in northeastern Syria.  Now, this was a very important activity because we have to ensure the socioeconomic conditions in that region so as to avoid a return of terrorism and violent extremism.  Italy traditionally has been working on this in Iraq; in fact, there is a huge effort on our part in order to allow the displaced persons to return, and we have the United Nations Office for Project Services and the Sinjar Action Fund, which was created by Nadia Murad, the peace prize – Nobel Peace Prize winner.</p>
<p>In northeastern Syria, we are operating with a number of different international organizations in order to support the local population to provide them with livelihood.  And we’re also supporting their agricultural activities.  We’re also working with the World Health Organization in order to contain and curb the pandemic in that area.</p>
<p>Now it was possible today for Italy and the United States to reiterate an important principle, a shared principle: Daesh is very dangerous still, and there are a number of instruments that we can use in order to take action not only in the Middle East.  Now there is an alarming phenomenon taking place on the African continent, and in particular in the Sahel region, but also in Eastern Africa, for example, as in the north of Mozambique.</p>
<p>Now last week I went to Mali and Niger myself.  And in fact, this shows how much Italy is focused on this region.  For this reason, with the support of the United States as well as many other partners, I suggested that we establish an Africa working group.  This way we can identify and curb the Daesh-related terrorist threats on the continent, and we can therefore determine measures, together with our local partners, and they can be put in place through the multilateral initiatives and programs that are already ongoing.</p>
<p>Now we are fearing the expansion and spread of Daesh in Africa, and therefore at the ministerial meeting, we invited some African countries that are not coalition members – Burkina Faso, Ghana, Mozambique, for example.  We invited them as observers to follow our meeting.</p>
<p>And I also took this opportunity today to reiterate the fact that Italy is continuing with its effort to take down Daesh.  And in fact, we’ve always taken a multidimensional approach.  Italy’s commitment is very strong.  We want to protect the security of our citizens, because this is an absolute priority for us.  Italy is one of the main military contributors to the coalition in Iraq.  We were there with our Carabinieri service.  We worked on the training of Iraqi and Kurd military and police forces, and our aircraft continue to do refueling and personnel transport activities as well.</p>
<p>One of our success stories in Iraq and in the coalition is linked to the protection of Iraqi cultural heritage.  Unfortunately, Daesh’s fury had tried to destroy this heritage, and we are also financing archeological activities here, and the taskforce for the heritage is in fact working on trying to combat an illicit trafficking of works of art and archaeological finds.</p>
<p>So there was a briefing during the meeting on all these different subjects, and Italy will continue to focus on counter-messaging to take down the Daesh propaganda, because we think that in addition to fighting their territorial control, we’ve got to fight their ideology as well.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much, and I’m very happy to hand over to the Secretary of State, Mr. Antony Blinken.</p>
<p>(In English) Now give the floor to Secretary Blinken.  Please, Tony.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you so much, Foreign Minister Di Maio.  Luigi, <em>grazie mille, amico</em>.</p>
<p>I am particularly delighted that we’re meeting so soon after the G7, NATO, the U.S.-EU leader summits.  Italy and the United States did significant work together in the leadup to those meetings, and that helped lay the groundwork for the real commitments the countries made at the summits themselves.</p>
<p>And now we’re following up on those commitments, making sure that our countries and others do what we said we would do.  It’s no accident that we started that follow-up in Italy, in France, and Germany this week, the three countries that I visited on this trip.  In addition to being three of our closest partners and strongest allies, they’re the only three countries that are members of the EU, NATO, and the G7, and their leadership will be crucial to delivering on our commitments.</p>
<p>Those commitments include revitalizing NATO, preparing the Alliance to deter adversaries and protect against a new range of threats from cyber attacks to a rapidly changing climate; delivering on the G7’s pledge to get a billion COVID vaccines to people around the world; to invest in much-needed infrastructure projects in developing countries in a way that’s open, sustainable, and empowers communities rather than saddling them with debt; deepening U.S.-EU cooperation across a range of areas, including trade and technology in particular.</p>
<p>Luigi was the first foreign minister to officially visit the State Department in the Biden-Harris administration, and that was just one of the many conversations that we’ve had, the work we’ve done together.  In fact, we even wrote an op-ed together a few months ago.</p>
<p>The reason that we’re in such close communication is because the interests and values of Italy and the United States are closely aligned.  We share a deep commitment to promoting democracy and human rights.  We see the same big challenges on the horizon and we recognize that we can’t tackle them alone, and we shouldn’t try to.  We’re better together, and that is what motivates our partnership.</p>
<p>I have to tell you we’re grateful for Italy’s leadership in putting these challenges at the center of the global agenda.  Italy made combating COVID-19 a focus of the G20 presidency this year as well as ensuring that the recovery not only rebuilds our economies, but tackles inequities within and between countries that the pandemic has only worsened and put in starker relief.  Italy is leading by example in pledging to donate $360 million in funds now to COVAX and sending 15 million vaccine doses from its own supply to lower and middle-income countries around the world.</p>
<p>And as you know, Luigi and I are co-hosting two high-level meetings tomorrow with our fellow foreign ministers focused on serious threats to international stability and security.  Today we began, of course, with the meeting of the Coalition to Defeat ISIS and what we have to do to eradicate what’s left of the terrorist group, and, very critically, as Italy has been emphasizing, to prevent its emergence in places like Africa.  Italy has not only contributed to this counterterrorism effort, but has demonstrated the way countries can take back nationals captured as foreign terrorist fighters.</p>
<p>And this afternoon, we’re also co-sponsoring a second meeting to address the urgent humanitarian crisis in Syria, particularly through broadening cross-border assistance, which is essential to reaching millions of Syrians who are in dire need of food, medicine, COVID vaccines, other lifesaving aid.  I’m announcing today that the United States is providing an additional $436 million in assistance – humanitarian assistance – to Syrians and the communities that host them, and that brings the total U.S. humanitarian assistance in response to the crisis in Syria to nearly $13.5 billion.  We’ll also use the meeting that’s upcoming to refocus on a path to a political solution in Syria, the only way to provide the Syrian people with a foundation upon which to reconcile, make peace, and begin to rebuild.</p>
<p>Of course, the relationship between the United States and Italy is about more than the challenges that we’re faced – that we’re facing and that we’re dealing with today and tomorrow.  Italy graciously hosts more than 34,000 U.S. servicemembers, civilians, their family members, and the U.S. Navy’s 6th Fleet headquarters in Naples.  Our two-way trade in goods and services amounted to about $80 billion last year.  Our direct investment in one another’s economies creates hundreds of thousands of jobs.  And we celebrated the 160th year of our diplomatic relationship.</p>
<p>But we know that the ties between the people of our countries have existed for even longer than that.  You see it in the 20 million Americans who proudly claim Italian heritage, in the Italian American pockets in big cities and small towns across our country, in the Americans who come to Italy every year to study, learn the language, trace their roots, and just enjoy Italy.  It’s hard to see a part of America’s national fabric that is not interwoven with threads from Italy, and we are so much richer for it.</p>
<p>As President Biden has pointed out, we meet at a time when our democracies face a grave threat from adversaries outside who seek to undermine the free and open rules-based order that has long provided the foundation of our shared security and prosperity, and from skeptics inside who question whether democracy can make their lives better in tangible ways.  I am confident that the rights, opportunities, and ability to keep improving on itself, that only democracy can provide, cannot be matched by any other system.  But I also know that if we’re going to overcome these challenges and show that we can deliver, we have to come together, we have to band together with our closest allies and partners.  For the United States, that means Italy.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER DI MAIO:</strong>  Thank you, Tony.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Thank you very much.  We can now take a few questions.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) Matteo Alviti from the Channel 1 news, Rai.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Via interpreter) I have a couple of questions.  Good afternoon.  The first has to do with your co-chairmanship two years after the meeting in Washington, as you yourselves pointed out.  Now there is a strengthened – is there a strengthened up – a stepped-up cooperation between Italy and the U.S. through this co-chairmanship?</p>
<p>My second question has to do with your meeting on Syria, which will be held in a few minutes.  On the issue of multilateralism, what can you tell us in advance of what you think will come up?  And in particular, the role of Turkey, what might that be in connection with the SDF force in Syria?</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER DI MAIO:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Well, firstly, I wish to say that Italy is indeed honored and very pleased to have been able to co-chair the meeting this morning, the ministerial meeting of the anti-Daesh coalition.  Certainly, this was a way of showing, as Tony just said, how strong the ties are between Italy and the United States, and that we are indeed cooperating on major global issues.  And this is quite natural if you consider that we are two allies, two great allies.</p>
<p>Now in our fight against international terrorism, no one can do this on their own, so that is why the cooperation between Italy and the United States is absolutely strategic, and it is also a way of recognizing the leading role played by Italy in the coalition.  And in fact, I’ll seize this opportunity to thank all the men and women in uniform, all the members of our armed forces that are engaged in missions abroad and trying to fight terrorism, in fact.</p>
<p>Now the coalition meeting today is taking place in a moment in which we fear that Daesh and ISIS can regain strength – regain their strength.  Now that is why we mustn’t lower our guard.  In fact, it’s an opportunity to tell one another that we must step up the action undertaken by the coalition, but not by shifting our focus, but by increasing the areas in which we can operate.  So this doesn’t only mean the Middle East, but Africa, the Sahel, and also Mozambique and the Horn of Africa.</p>
<p>The meeting on Syria that we will have in just a few minutes – we’ll be co-chairing that together, in fact – that is definitely another important opportunity that we have to have an exchange of views.  And the countries that are most interested in establishing peace in Syria will, of course, give us all a chance to plan our next steps.  Now Italy is supporting the UN program through the Special Envoy Mr. Pedersen, and we also know that the UN program and the institutional committee are initiatives that need to be supported by the allies, the main allies of multilateralism.  So on a bilateral level, Italy and the United States are great friends.  We share values and activities together, of course, and therefore, we must continue to support multilateralism as well, because we think that this is the main tool that we have in order to tackle crises all over the world.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>And I fully subscribe to everything that Luigi just said.  And I think it’s a reflection of the fact that when it comes to our own cooperation – both working together bilaterally but also in multilateral institutions where you see an extremely active Italy playing a leadership role – it’s a reflection of the fact that we both see, we both understand that there’s a greater imperative now than at any other time that I can think of for cooperation among like-minded countries.  Because the simple reality is that not a single one of the issues that we have to deal with that are having an impact on the lives of our citizens in Italy, in the United States, around the world, whether it’s climate change, whether it’s the pandemic, whether it’s the disruptive impact of new technologies, whether it’s the threat posed by terrorism, not a single one can be effectively addressed by any one country acting on its own, even the United States, even Italy.</p>
<p>And so we’re especially grateful at this moment to have such strong allies, partners, and friends as Italy who are taking the lead.  And that reflects itself in the work that we’re doing together; it reflects itself in the work that we’re doing in these international groupings, institutions.  Today is powerful evidence of that.</p>
<p>And just on Syria, we’ll have more to say I’m sure after the meeting.  There is a – an absolute premium here, too, on making sure that we’re doing everything possible to get humanitarian assistance to people in need in Syria.  And that’s going to be a focus of our conversations.  But, of course, that’s the immediate imperative, but the larger objective is to pursue a lasting resolution and peace that Syria so desperately, desperately needs.  And so we’ll make clear our support for a nationwide ceasefire, both to ensure the safe delivery of assistance, but also to try to create more of a foundation upon which the future of Syria can move forward.  But we’ll have more to say I’m sure after the meeting.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Our first question goes to Kylie Atwood from CNN.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.  Foreign Minister, I’d like to start with you.  You’ve said in the past that Italy and China need to forge closer ties, and Italy has been a supporter of China’s Belt and Road Initiative.  Does Italy today maintain steadfast support for the Belt and Road Initiative? And what do you make of Secretary Blinken saying that it would – that a Chinese-led world order would be profoundly illiberal in nature?</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER DE MAIO:  </strong>(Via interpreter)  I’d like to be very clear.  And actually, I’d like to thank you for having asked this question, because it gives me once again the opportunity to clarify what Italy’s position is with respect to alliances of value and geopolitical alliances.  And we see eye to eye with the United States in that respect.  We are allies of the United States, we are partners in NATO, we are members of the European Union, and this means that we are part of an alliance of values, which means that we can credibly tackle issues such as human rights violations.  Italy was in the front line, both at a multilateral level within the UN supporting the latest proposal tabled by Canada, for instance, and in the European Union when we supported the sanctions established in the face of human rights violations.  And our position was very clear in the last G7 summit in the UK, during which our leaders discussed the way in which we can enhance the UN’s effectiveness in combating human rights violations.</p>
<p>And I think that if we all around the world speak out in favor of multilateralism and in favor of the United Nations, we really cannot speak about juxtaposition between different countries.  There is a common action of the UN with the contribution of the High-Level Representative Bachelet with regard to human rights violations, and I believe that the UN representative must be in a position to verify whether there have been human rights violations.  And I would like to speak very clearly.  Italy is a strong trade partner of China.  We’ve enjoyed relations that have lasted for years, but they cannot and do not interfere with the alliance of values we have with the United States, we have with NATO, and the European Union.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Again, could I just follow up with you?  On China specifically, isn’t Italy’s support for China’s Belt and Road Initiative inherently contradictory to their support for the build back better effort that you guys just launched together last week?  And then on your meeting earlier today with Pope Francis, were there any discussions of President Biden receiving Holy Communion?  And on coronavirus, Pope Francis has assessed that those who refuse to get the COVID-19 vaccine are suicidal.  Do you agree?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Kylie, I was about to thank you for addressing your question to Foreign Minister Di Maio, so – but I’ll reserve that.  I think what Luigi said with regard to our approach to China is a very good answer to the question and one that I would simply reiterate.  Look, I think what you’ve seen across the board in recent weeks, particularly at the G7, NATO, the U.S.-EU summit, is an increasing convergence of views among the United States and our European partners and allies about China.  And I think we all recognize the complexity of the relationship, the fact that it is for all of us among the most consequential in the world.  And that complexity manifests itself in the fact that I think we all agree that the relationship has, as I’ve said many times, adversarial aspects, competitive ones, and cooperative ones, too.</p>
<p>And the common denominator is approaching these challenges, whether it’s adversarial, whether it’s competitive, whether it’s cooperative, together.  And increasingly, that’s exactly what you’re seeing.</p>
<p>When it comes to the initiative that we took at the G7, the Build Back Better World, Italy is a participant in that.  We’re going to work over the next months to move that forward.  And the point here is that there is an imperative here, too, around the world for investment in infrastructure in countries that are low and middle-income.  But it needs to be done in a way that’s a race to the top not a race to the bottom.  Italy and our other partners are going to be a full participant in that, and I think that will demonstrate itself in the months ahead.</p>
<p>With regard to the meeting with his holiness the pope, let me just say on a personal level what an honor it was.  The meeting was extremely warm and very wide ranging.  We covered a lot of ground, and I certainly don’t want to speak for his holiness, but just speaking for myself and speaking for the United States, I was very gratified by the meeting and gratified as well by the strong leadership of his holiness on the pandemic, on climate change, on the challenge that we have to address when it comes to irregular migration and refugees, and more broadly, and maybe most important of all, his leadership on the basic proposition that we have to stand for human dignity in everything we do to the best of our ability.</p>
<p>One of the luxuries of my job is that I don’t do domestic politics, and so I’ll simply say that it was truly a wonderful and memorable moment to have had the opportunity to speak to his holiness and to have such a warm and wide-ranging conversation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And can I just follow up?  Do you agree with Pope Francis’ assessment that those who refuse the COVID-19 vaccine are engaging in a suicidal effort?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>I’m not going to speak for the pope in any way.  I think we strongly believe in the importance of vaccination, of seeing as many people not just in our own countries but around the world get vaccinated and to do so as quickly as possible.  And, of course, one of the reasons that we came together at the G7 to push a billion vaccine doses out around the world is because of the absolute importance of this initiative and the need to be vaccinated.</p>
<p>Look, here is the reality that we’re faced with.  As long as the virus is replicating somewhere, it’s likely to be mutating.  And as long as it’s mutating, there is the distinct possibility that it comes back and bites even those who have been vaccinated, so we have to get ahead of this, and the way to get ahead of this is with the fastest possible vaccination around the world.  That’s why Italy and the United States are working so closely together to make sure that we get vaccines out there.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you.  Over to Annalisa Rapana, the Italian news agency, ANSA.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Via interpreter)<em> </em>Good evening.  I have a question for Minister Di Maio.  You mentioned the need for the coalition to focus specifically on Africa and on the Sahel.  I’d like to ask you whether this approach is also shared as – and in what way – and why have you underscored the importance of this step that the coalition ought to take – in focusing on Africa, that is?</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER DI MAIO:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you for your question.  I would like to start by saying that today the United States expressed its support to the proposal to focus part of the effort in the anti-Daesh coalition effort on Africa, on the Sahel, and on countries affected in that continent.  In my recent missions to Niger and Mali, I witnessed the cry for help of those communities, but this is not only typical to those parts of the continent.  We know that many villages have fallen in the hands of terrorists, and we know that we’re talking about huge territories.</p>
<p>Italy has a number of bilateral agreements with some of these countries, specifically to try and fight climate change and combat desertification.  We know that desertification is the root cause of poverty and of lower living standards, because we know that the amount of farmland is shrinking.  We’re also working with the UNHCR in support of refugees.  The UNHCR has a number of outreach initiatives, and these people can come to Italy, if needed, via legal humanitarian corridors.</p>
<p>The real problem is that the fight against terrorism calls for a holistic approach.  The coalition’s experience enables it to tackle this problem in a holistic fashion.  The institutions of those countries are being weakened on account of the attacks perpetrated by terrorist cells, and the time we speak protecting the Sahel also means protecting Europe and its securities and stopping the illicit trafficking of human beings and weapons.  We could achieve this with a step-to-step approach, but in the coming months we are planning to strengthen the will and – of this coalition.  All countries attending today have supported their – this initiative and we’d like to focus on coordinating via the coalition existing initiatives.  And at the same time, we want to draw a clear roadmap to avert the risk that these terrorist organizations may proliferate.  This doesn’t mean stopping the fight against Daesh in Syria and in Iraq.  It simply means that now, years after the territorial defeat of Daesh in the Middle East, we’re now seeing there’s a number of terrorist cells are proliferating in regions such as the Sahel where, obviously, the main migration routes are present, the routes of those who come to Europe, and climate change, poverty, and terrorism are creating millions and millions of poor people.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>If I could, let me just say very clearly that we strongly support Italy’s initiative to make sure that the coalition against Daesh focuses its expertise on Africa while keeping our eye closely on Syria and on Iraq for all of the reasons that Luigi just cited.  This is of significant importance, and I think we heard a strong consensus today on the part of coalition partners to do just that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Our final question goes to Michael Crowley of <em>The New York Times</em>.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  If I may, I have a question for you both on today’s meeting and then another for each of you separately.  For you both, did today’s meeting make you anymore optimistic about more quickly resolving the fate of the ISIS fighters and their families now held in Syria and Iraq?  And specifically, did any nations make new commitments to repatriate foreign fighters?</p>
<p>For Secretary Blinken, my question to you is on last night’s U.S. airstrikes on militia groups in Iraq and Syria.  The Biden administration conducted similar strikes in February calling them a deterrent, but attacks on U.S. forces continued, prompting this second strike.  Is the U.S. prepared to escalate its response if these strikes do not deter continued attacks on our personnel? And do you hold Iran responsible for these ongoing attacks?</p>
<p>And finally, for Minister Di Maio, the Biden administration recently waived sanctions on the Nord Stream 2 pipeline from Russia to Germany.  Italy has previously expressed concern about the project’s impact on European energy security dynamics.  Are you disappointed that the Biden administration is not doing more to block the pipeline’s completion?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER DI MAIO:  </strong>(Via interpreter) I would like to start by saying that today’s meeting has also given us the opportunity to take stock of a number of different initiatives that are in place in the fight against Daesh.  And I’m not just talking about military initiatives.  We have the working group against Daesh propaganda.  That is problematic, as we know, because it is a source of radicalization via the web, for instance.  And the other working group that we co-chair together with the United States and Saudi Arabia is the working group to counter, let’s say, the sources of financing for – of terrorist groups.  And we had a full group format meeting today, which enabled us to identify the next dates on which we will continue to pursue our initiative, both in terms of propaganda and countering financing.</p>
<p>But the best way to counter terrorism and Daesh is to strengthen local institutions, and as member-states of the coalition, and in more general terms, as countries and people who believe in multilateralism, we are striving to increase development assistance investment.  Development assistance is something Italy has always believed in, and this is what has guided Italy’s position in many different theaters.  Italy intends to increase its development assistance, its ODA, to support institutions in Afghanistan, for instance, because withdrawing, militarily speaking, from Afghanistan doesn’t mean pulling out of Afghanistan altogether; on the contrary.  For Italy, this means making an additional effort to strengthen institutions through development cooperation, through police and local forces training programs.</p>
<p>That said, with regard to the topic of diversification of energy sources, Italy has just completed the Trans Adriatic Pipeline precisely with a view to differentiating energy supply sources, particularly with regard to gas.  And Italy continues to believe that as far as energy goes and as far as energy production goes, we need to invest more and more in new technologies and we have to have a diversified energy mix.  We have, at the moment, a number of European programs underway, such as the one that aims to promote hydrogen production.  And I look ahead for the future of the European Union and our member-countries with common policies, with renewable sources of energy, and with transition instruments such as gas.  We believe that it will be possible for us to reduce significantly the dependence on imported sources.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you, Michael.<strong>  </strong>So on the question of foreign terrorist fighters, we spent some time talking about that today in the meeting.  And there is a need for countries to take action to repatriate foreign fighters that come from those countries, to prosecute them where appropriate, to rehabilitate and reintegrate them where appropriate.  And there is some urgency to this.  I noted in the meeting a number of countries that have taken very concrete steps, including, by the way, Italy, as well as the United States, but also a number of other countries, for example, in Central Asia, as well as in the Balkans that have taken important steps.  But more work clearly needs to be done.  The number of foreign terrorist fighters who are in detention in Syria is significant.  The larger group that comprises their family members, women, children is also a significant concern.</p>
<p>And I think the strong message coming out of today’s meeting was the need for countries to do more to that end.  So we’ll see going forward as countries, I hope, step up to this need.  It is something of tremendous importance in terms of making sure that we’re getting people off of and away from the battlefield, and hopefully to a place where they will either face further justice or, in some cases at least, hopefully can be rehabilitated and reintegrated.  But we’ll see the results in the weeks and months ahead.</p>
<p>With regard to the strike last night, at the President’s direction, U.S. military forces conducted airstrikes against facilities used by Iranian-backed militia groups in the Iraq-Syria border region. They targeted facilities used by groups responsible for recent attacks on U.S. interests in Iraq. Specifically, they targeted operational and weapons storage facilities at two locations in Syria, one location in Iraq, both with – very close to the border between the countries.  Several Iran-backed militia groups, including KH, including KSS, use these facilities.  We have been very clear, the President has been very clear throughout, that we will act to protect U.S. personnel.  And given these ongoing attacks that you referred to by Iran-backed groups targeting our interests in Iraq, he directed further military action – we had taken action previously – to disrupt and deter these attacks.</p>
<p>We took necessary, appropriate, deliberate action that is designed to limit the risk of escalation, but also to send a clear and unambiguous deterrent message.  This action in self-defense to do what’s necessary to prevent further attacks, I think, sends a very important and strong message. And I hope very much that it is received by those who are intended to receive it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>If I may just follow up, Mr. Secretary, the first airstrikes were described as having a deterrent purpose and appear not to have served that purpose.  Are you prepared to describe what action the United States might take should the militia attacks continue?  Would the U.S. escalate its response?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>I think we’ve demonstrated, both with the actions taken last night and actions taken previously, that the President is fully prepared to act and act appropriately and deliberately to protect U.S. interest, to protect our people, to protect our personnel.  And again, I would hope that the message sent by the strikes last night will be heard and deter future action.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>And the one other part of my question, I had asked whether you hold Iran responsible for these attacks.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, a number of the groups involved in recent attacks are militia that are backed by Iran.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Thank you very much.  That is all we have time for.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the Ministerial Meeting on Syria</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-the-ministerial-meeting-on-syria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 15:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255697</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States, Italy, Canada, Egypt, France, Germany, Greece, Iraq, Ireland, Japan, Jordan, Lebanon, the Netherlands, Norway, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Turkey, the United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, and representatives of the League of Arab States and European Union, which met today to discuss the crisis in Syria.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>We, the Ministers and representatives of the United States, Italy, Canada, Egypt, France, Germany, Greece, Iraq, Ireland, Japan, Jordan, Lebanon, the Netherlands, Norway, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Turkey, the United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, and representatives of the League of Arab States and European Union, met today on the margins of the Defeat ISIS Coalition Ministerial to discuss the crisis in Syria.  We stressed the critical importance of meeting humanitarian needs, including life-saving assistance and COVID-19 response for all Syrians in need through all modalities, including through the provision and expansion of the UN cross-border mechanism to which there is no adequate alternative.  We also underlined the importance of continued support to Syrian refugees and host countries until Syrians can voluntarily return home with safety and dignity in line with UNHCR standards.</p>
<p>We welcomed UN Special Envoy Geir Pedersen’s briefing and reaffirmed strong support for UN-led efforts to implement all aspects of UN Security Council Resolution 2254, including continued support for an immediate nation-wide ceasefire, the unimpeded and safe delivery of aid, and the Constitutional Committee, as well as fighting against terrorism in all its forms and manifestations.</p>
<p>Reaffirming the unity and territorial integrity of Syria, we remain committed to continue working actively to reach a credible, sustainable, and inclusive political solution based on Resolution 2254.  This is the only solution that will bring an end to Syria’s decade long conflict and guarantee the security of the Syrian people and fulfil their aspirations.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States, Italy, Canada, Egypt, France, Germany, Greece, Iraq, Ireland, Japan, Jordan, Lebanon, the Netherlands, Norway, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Turkey, the United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, and representatives of the League of Arab States and European Union, which met today to discuss the crisis in Syria.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>We, the Ministers and representatives of the United States, Italy, Canada, Egypt, France, Germany, Greece, Iraq, Ireland, Japan, Jordan, Lebanon, the Netherlands, Norway, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Turkey, the United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, and representatives of the League of Arab States and European Union, met today on the margins of the Defeat ISIS Coalition Ministerial to discuss the crisis in Syria.  We stressed the critical importance of meeting humanitarian needs, including life-saving assistance and COVID-19 response for all Syrians in need through all modalities, including through the provision and expansion of the UN cross-border mechanism to which there is no adequate alternative.  We also underlined the importance of continued support to Syrian refugees and host countries until Syrians can voluntarily return home with safety and dignity in line with UNHCR standards.</p>
<p>We welcomed UN Special Envoy Geir Pedersen’s briefing and reaffirmed strong support for UN-led efforts to implement all aspects of UN Security Council Resolution 2254, including continued support for an immediate nation-wide ceasefire, the unimpeded and safe delivery of aid, and the Constitutional Committee, as well as fighting against terrorism in all its forms and manifestations.</p>
<p>Reaffirming the unity and territorial integrity of Syria, we remain committed to continue working actively to reach a credible, sustainable, and inclusive political solution based on Resolution 2254.  This is the only solution that will bring an end to Syria’s decade long conflict and guarantee the security of the Syrian people and fulfil their aspirations.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-global-coalition-to-defeat-isis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 15:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>At the Global Coalition Ministerial in Rome on June 28, the U.S. Department of State wishes to reaffirm its commitment to the Coalition and its goals. The 83-member Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS has worked diligently since 2014 to reduce the threat ISIS poses to international security and our homelands. The Coalition’s combined efforts have diminished ISIS’ military capability, territorial control, leadership, financial resources, and online influence. Members are united in common cause to defeat ISIS through a robust approach, including working by, with, and through local partners for military missions; supporting the stabilization of the territory liberated from ISIS; and enhancing international cooperation against ISIS’ global objectives through information sharing, law enforcement cooperation, severing ISIS’ financing, countering terrorist recruitment, and neutralizing ISIS’ narrative. The Coalition is also engaged in efforts to provide needs-based humanitarian aid assistance to communities suffering from displacement and conflict, and supporting stabilization efforts in territory liberated from ISIS.</p>
<p><strong>The Ministerial</strong></p>
<p>Secretary Blinken will join Italian Minister of Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation Luigi Di Maio in co-hosting a meeting of the Foreign Ministers of the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS. It will be the first in-person Ministerial of the Global Coalition since February 6, 2019. This will be an opportunity for the Foreign Ministers of the Coalition, led by the United States, to discuss ways to sustain pressure on ISIS remnants in Iraq and Syria, and to counter ISIS’s global networks, primarily in Africa. The Coalition will also assess priorities for its five lines of effort: stabilization, foreign terrorist fighters, counter-ISIS financing, political-military consultations, and counter-messaging efforts.</p>
<p><strong>Fast Facts</strong></p>
<p>Since 2014, the Coalition has carried out a comprehensive strategy to destroy and degrade ISIS. Milestones include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Removing Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi in October 2019 and scores of ISIS leaders;</li>
<li>Destroying 100 percent of ISIS’s fraudulent territorial “caliphate;”</li>
<li>Liberating over 42,000 square miles and supporting the safe and voluntary return of nearly 8 million people from ISIS’s brutal rule;</li>
<li>Addressing the root causes of support for ISIS through targeted justice and accountability assistance to local communities and survivors of ISIS atrocities;</li>
<li>Expanding the Coalition’s global reach to 83 members, adding 4 partners since the last Ministerial &#8211; Central African Republic, Democratic Republic of the Congo, Mauritania, and Yemen.</li>
</ul>
<table width="611">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="153"><strong><u>Africa<br />
</u></strong>Cameroon<br />
Central African Republic<br />
Chad<br />
Democratic Republic of Congo<br />
Djibouti<br />
Egypt<br />
Ethiopia<br />
Guinea<br />
Kenya<br />
Libya<br />
Mauritania<br />
Morocco<br />
Niger<br />
Nigeria<br />
Somalia<br />
Tunisia</td>
<td width="153"><strong><u>Americas<br />
</u></strong>Canada<br />
Panama<br />
United States</p>
<p><strong><u>Institutions<br />
</u></strong>Arab League<br />
CEN-SAD<br />
EU<br />
INTERPOL<br />
NATO</p>
<p><strong><u>Asia Pacific<br />
</u></strong>Afghanistan<br />
Australia<br />
Fiji<br />
Japan<br />
Malaysia<br />
New Zealand<br />
Philippines<br />
Singapore<br />
South Korea<br />
Taiwan</td>
<td width="153"><strong><u>Europe<br />
</u></strong>Albania<br />
Austria<br />
Belgium<br />
Bosnia and Herzegovina<br />
Bulgaria<br />
Croatia<br />
Cyprus<br />
Czech Republic<br />
Denmark<br />
Estonia<br />
Finland<br />
France<br />
Georgia<br />
Germany<br />
Greece<br />
Hungary<br />
Iceland<br />
Ireland<br />
Italy<br />
Kosovo<br />
Latvia<br />
Lithuania<br />
Luxembourg<br />
Moldova<br />
Montenegro<br />
Netherlands<br />
North Macedonia Norway<br />
Poland<br />
Portugal<br />
Romania<br />
Serbia<br />
Slovakia<br />
Slovenia<br />
Spain<br />
Sweden<br />
Turkey<br />
Ukraine<br />
United Kingdom</td>
<td width="153"><strong><u>Middle East<br />
</u></strong>Bahrain<br />
Iraq<br />
Jordan<br />
Kuwait<br />
Lebanon<br />
Oman<br />
Qatar<br />
Saudi Arabia<br />
United Arab Emirates<br />
Yemen</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>Coalition Members:</strong> 83 members, 78 nations, 5 institutions</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>At the Global Coalition Ministerial in Rome on June 28, the U.S. Department of State wishes to reaffirm its commitment to the Coalition and its goals. The 83-member Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS has worked diligently since 2014 to reduce the threat ISIS poses to international security and our homelands. The Coalition’s combined efforts have diminished ISIS’ military capability, territorial control, leadership, financial resources, and online influence. Members are united in common cause to defeat ISIS through a robust approach, including working by, with, and through local partners for military missions; supporting the stabilization of the territory liberated from ISIS; and enhancing international cooperation against ISIS’ global objectives through information sharing, law enforcement cooperation, severing ISIS’ financing, countering terrorist recruitment, and neutralizing ISIS’ narrative. The Coalition is also engaged in efforts to provide needs-based humanitarian aid assistance to communities suffering from displacement and conflict, and supporting stabilization efforts in territory liberated from ISIS.</p>
<p><strong>The Ministerial</strong></p>
<p>Secretary Blinken will join Italian Minister of Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation Luigi Di Maio in co-hosting a meeting of the Foreign Ministers of the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS. It will be the first in-person Ministerial of the Global Coalition since February 6, 2019. This will be an opportunity for the Foreign Ministers of the Coalition, led by the United States, to discuss ways to sustain pressure on ISIS remnants in Iraq and Syria, and to counter ISIS’s global networks, primarily in Africa. The Coalition will also assess priorities for its five lines of effort: stabilization, foreign terrorist fighters, counter-ISIS financing, political-military consultations, and counter-messaging efforts.</p>
<p><strong>Fast Facts</strong></p>
<p>Since 2014, the Coalition has carried out a comprehensive strategy to destroy and degrade ISIS. Milestones include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Removing Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi in October 2019 and scores of ISIS leaders;</li>
<li>Destroying 100 percent of ISIS’s fraudulent territorial “caliphate;”</li>
<li>Liberating over 42,000 square miles and supporting the safe and voluntary return of nearly 8 million people from ISIS’s brutal rule;</li>
<li>Addressing the root causes of support for ISIS through targeted justice and accountability assistance to local communities and survivors of ISIS atrocities;</li>
<li>Expanding the Coalition’s global reach to 83 members, adding 4 partners since the last Ministerial &#8211; Central African Republic, Democratic Republic of the Congo, Mauritania, and Yemen.</li>
</ul>
<table width="611">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="153"><strong><u>Africa<br />
</u></strong>Cameroon<br />
Central African Republic<br />
Chad<br />
Democratic Republic of Congo<br />
Djibouti<br />
Egypt<br />
Ethiopia<br />
Guinea<br />
Kenya<br />
Libya<br />
Mauritania<br />
Morocco<br />
Niger<br />
Nigeria<br />
Somalia<br />
Tunisia</td>
<td width="153"><strong><u>Americas<br />
</u></strong>Canada<br />
Panama<br />
United States</p>
<p><strong><u>Institutions<br />
</u></strong>Arab League<br />
CEN-SAD<br />
EU<br />
INTERPOL<br />
NATO</p>
<p><strong><u>Asia Pacific<br />
</u></strong>Afghanistan<br />
Australia<br />
Fiji<br />
Japan<br />
Malaysia<br />
New Zealand<br />
Philippines<br />
Singapore<br />
South Korea<br />
Taiwan</td>
<td width="153"><strong><u>Europe<br />
</u></strong>Albania<br />
Austria<br />
Belgium<br />
Bosnia and Herzegovina<br />
Bulgaria<br />
Croatia<br />
Cyprus<br />
Czech Republic<br />
Denmark<br />
Estonia<br />
Finland<br />
France<br />
Georgia<br />
Germany<br />
Greece<br />
Hungary<br />
Iceland<br />
Ireland<br />
Italy<br />
Kosovo<br />
Latvia<br />
Lithuania<br />
Luxembourg<br />
Moldova<br />
Montenegro<br />
Netherlands<br />
North Macedonia Norway<br />
Poland<br />
Portugal<br />
Romania<br />
Serbia<br />
Slovakia<br />
Slovenia<br />
Spain<br />
Sweden<br />
Turkey<br />
Ukraine<br />
United Kingdom</td>
<td width="153"><strong><u>Middle East<br />
</u></strong>Bahrain<br />
Iraq<br />
Jordan<br />
Kuwait<br />
Lebanon<br />
Oman<br />
Qatar<br />
Saudi Arabia<br />
United Arab Emirates<br />
Yemen</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>Coalition Members:</strong> 83 members, 78 nations, 5 institutions</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Communiqué by Ministers of the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-communique-by-ministers-of-the-global-coalition-to-defeat-isis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 14:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255658</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following statement was released by United States Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken and the Foreign Ministers of the Global Coalition to Defeat Daesh/ISIS following today’s meeting.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The Ministers of the Global Coalition to Defeat Daesh/ISIS, reconvening in-person after two years, met today in Rome at the invitation of Italian Minister of Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation Luigi Di Maio and U.S. Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken. The Ministers reaffirmed their shared determination to continue the fight against Daesh/ISIS, and to create conditions for the enduring defeat of the terrorist group, which remains the Coalition’s sole purpose, through a comprehensive, coordinated, and multifaceted effort. The Ministers welcomed new members joining the Coalition &#8211; Central African Republic, Democratic Republic of the Congo, Mauritania, and Yemen. Together the Ministers emphasized the protection of civilians as a priority and affirmed that international law, including international humanitarian law and international human rights law, as applicable, as well as relevant UN Security Council resolutions, must be upheld under all circumstances.</p>
<p>The Ministers committed to strengthening cooperation across all Coalition lines of effort in order to ensure that Daesh/ISIS Core in Iraq and Syria, and its affiliates and networks around the world are unable to reconstitute any territorial enclave or continue to threaten our homelands, people, and interests. The Ministers remain firmly united in our outrage at atrocities perpetrated by Daesh/ISIS and in our determination to eliminate this global threat, and stand alongside survivors and families of victims of Daesh/ISIS crimes working for accountability.</p>
<p>Daesh/ISIS no longer controls territory and nearly eight million people have been freed from its control in Iraq and Syria, but the threat remains. The resumption in Daesh/ISIS activities and its ability to rebuild its networks and capabilities to target security forces and civilians in areas in Iraq and Syria where the Coalition is not active, requires strong vigilance and coordinated action. This includes allocating adequate resources to sustain Coalition and legitimate partner forces’ efforts against Daesh/ISIS, and significant stabilization support, both to address the drivers that make communities vulnerable to recruitment by Daesh/ISIS and related violent ideological groups, as well as to provide support to liberated areas to safeguard our collective security interests. In this regard, the Ministers noted the 2021 Pledge Drive for Stabilization as an important means to help sustain the recovery of areas liberated from Daesh/ISIS and prevent its resurgence. The Ministers reaffirm that Daesh/ISIS will continue to be pressured by curbing its ability to raise revenue, enhancing information sharing on terrorists through bilateral and/or multilateral channels like INTERPOL, and fighting against Daesh/ISIS’ toxic propaganda and denying the group space to exploit social media online.</p>
<p>The Ministers acknowledged Iraq’s efforts to counter Daesh/ISIS’ remnants and prevent its resurgence, and commended the increased capacity of the Iraqi forces to combat Daesh/ISIS. Appropriate measures to enhance the operational efficiency and coordination of our collective efforts to maintain the necessary pressure on Daesh/ISIS remain essential. The Coalition operates in Iraq at the request of the Government of Iraq in full respect of Iraq’s unity, sovereignty, and territorial integrity, and to the benefit of the Iraqi people. The Ministers firmly condemned the continuing attacks against Coalition personnel and convoys, and diplomatic facilities, emphasizing the importance of the Government of Iraq protecting Coalition assets. The Ministers welcomed the incremental expansion of NATO’s non-combat advisory, training and capacity building mission in Iraq based on the requirements and consent of the Iraqi authorities and complementing the Coalition’s efforts. The Ministers also welcomed the EU’s support to the Iraqi authorities through the EUAM Iraq Mission.</p>
<p>In Syria, the Coalition stands with the Syrian people in support of a lasting political settlement in accordance with UN Security Council Resolution 2254. The Coalition must continue to be vigilant against the threat of terrorism, in all its forms and manifestations, to build on the success it has achieved and continue to act together against any threats to this outcome and to avoid security vacuums that Daesh/ISIS may exploit. The Coalition continues to support inclusive local recovery and stabilization in areas liberated from Daesh/ISIS and reconciliation and reintegration efforts to foster conditions conducive to a Syria-wide political resolution to the conflict under the parameters of UN Security Council Resolution 2254.</p>
<p>In a session of the meeting focused on the security situation in other continents and regions, particularly Africa, the Ministers noted with grave concern that Daesh/ISIS affiliates and networks in sub-Saharan Africa threaten security and stability, namely in the Sahel Region and in East Africa/Mozambique. The Coalition is committed to working with affected countries to address the threats posed by Daesh/ISIS in Africa to ensure the enduring global defeat of the organization upon the request and prior consent of the countries concerned, and in full respect of international law and in close coordination with existing initiatives, notably the Coalition for the Sahel and the Global Counter-Terrorism Forum. The Ministers welcomed the presence of delegations from several African nations as observers to this ministerial meeting. The Ministers discussed that reinforcing civilian state institutions and consolidating the rule of law, including law enforcement capacity, will be an essential component of combatting Daesh/ISIS, and that the Global Coalition to Defeat Daesh/ISIS will seek to have effective engagement on the African continent. The Ministers tasked the Coalition Working Groups to assess ways in which they can contribute to counter Daesh/ISIS efforts in the affected regions. The Ministers also welcomed Afghanistan’s efforts to counter the Islamic State in Iraq and Syria-Khurasan (ISIS-K).</p>
<p>Recognizing the challenge posed by foreign terrorist fighters who are in custody, as well as their family members who remain in Syria and Iraq, the Ministers committed to pursuing existing effective justice and accountability mechanisms in close coordination with the countries of origin. This also includes accountability for fighters who have used sexual violence as an instrument of terror. The Coalition remains committed to promoting efforts to ensure that accused terrorists, including those of foreign nationalities, are treated appropriately and tried consistently with applicable international law obligations, including fair trial guarantees, and urges the custodians of the detained Daesh/ISIS terrorists to treat them humanely at all times, in accordance with international law.  The Ministers further recognized that the situation for Daesh/ISIS detainees and family members in northeast Syria is of grave concern and recognized the importance of finding a comprehensive and long-term solution to this serious issue.</p>
<p>The Coalition reaffirmed its belief that a comprehensive and collective effort remains necessary to achieve a full and enduring defeat of Daesh/ISIS worldwide. The Global Coalition to Defeat Daesh/ISIS has proven that it is a cohesive, responsive tool that has achieved notable successes through military, political, stabilization, counter-messaging, financial, and law enforcement lines of effort.</p>
<p>The Ministers also reaffirmed their intent to hold the next ministerial meeting of the Global Coalition by June 2022 and to hold a Small Group Political Directors Meeting in Brussels in the fall of 2021, circumstances pending.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following statement was released by United States Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken and the Foreign Ministers of the Global Coalition to Defeat Daesh/ISIS following today’s meeting.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The Ministers of the Global Coalition to Defeat Daesh/ISIS, reconvening in-person after two years, met today in Rome at the invitation of Italian Minister of Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation Luigi Di Maio and U.S. Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken. The Ministers reaffirmed their shared determination to continue the fight against Daesh/ISIS, and to create conditions for the enduring defeat of the terrorist group, which remains the Coalition’s sole purpose, through a comprehensive, coordinated, and multifaceted effort. The Ministers welcomed new members joining the Coalition &#8211; Central African Republic, Democratic Republic of the Congo, Mauritania, and Yemen. Together the Ministers emphasized the protection of civilians as a priority and affirmed that international law, including international humanitarian law and international human rights law, as applicable, as well as relevant UN Security Council resolutions, must be upheld under all circumstances.</p>
<p>The Ministers committed to strengthening cooperation across all Coalition lines of effort in order to ensure that Daesh/ISIS Core in Iraq and Syria, and its affiliates and networks around the world are unable to reconstitute any territorial enclave or continue to threaten our homelands, people, and interests. The Ministers remain firmly united in our outrage at atrocities perpetrated by Daesh/ISIS and in our determination to eliminate this global threat, and stand alongside survivors and families of victims of Daesh/ISIS crimes working for accountability.</p>
<p>Daesh/ISIS no longer controls territory and nearly eight million people have been freed from its control in Iraq and Syria, but the threat remains. The resumption in Daesh/ISIS activities and its ability to rebuild its networks and capabilities to target security forces and civilians in areas in Iraq and Syria where the Coalition is not active, requires strong vigilance and coordinated action. This includes allocating adequate resources to sustain Coalition and legitimate partner forces’ efforts against Daesh/ISIS, and significant stabilization support, both to address the drivers that make communities vulnerable to recruitment by Daesh/ISIS and related violent ideological groups, as well as to provide support to liberated areas to safeguard our collective security interests. In this regard, the Ministers noted the 2021 Pledge Drive for Stabilization as an important means to help sustain the recovery of areas liberated from Daesh/ISIS and prevent its resurgence. The Ministers reaffirm that Daesh/ISIS will continue to be pressured by curbing its ability to raise revenue, enhancing information sharing on terrorists through bilateral and/or multilateral channels like INTERPOL, and fighting against Daesh/ISIS’ toxic propaganda and denying the group space to exploit social media online.</p>
<p>The Ministers acknowledged Iraq’s efforts to counter Daesh/ISIS’ remnants and prevent its resurgence, and commended the increased capacity of the Iraqi forces to combat Daesh/ISIS. Appropriate measures to enhance the operational efficiency and coordination of our collective efforts to maintain the necessary pressure on Daesh/ISIS remain essential. The Coalition operates in Iraq at the request of the Government of Iraq in full respect of Iraq’s unity, sovereignty, and territorial integrity, and to the benefit of the Iraqi people. The Ministers firmly condemned the continuing attacks against Coalition personnel and convoys, and diplomatic facilities, emphasizing the importance of the Government of Iraq protecting Coalition assets. The Ministers welcomed the incremental expansion of NATO’s non-combat advisory, training and capacity building mission in Iraq based on the requirements and consent of the Iraqi authorities and complementing the Coalition’s efforts. The Ministers also welcomed the EU’s support to the Iraqi authorities through the EUAM Iraq Mission.</p>
<p>In Syria, the Coalition stands with the Syrian people in support of a lasting political settlement in accordance with UN Security Council Resolution 2254. The Coalition must continue to be vigilant against the threat of terrorism, in all its forms and manifestations, to build on the success it has achieved and continue to act together against any threats to this outcome and to avoid security vacuums that Daesh/ISIS may exploit. The Coalition continues to support inclusive local recovery and stabilization in areas liberated from Daesh/ISIS and reconciliation and reintegration efforts to foster conditions conducive to a Syria-wide political resolution to the conflict under the parameters of UN Security Council Resolution 2254.</p>
<p>In a session of the meeting focused on the security situation in other continents and regions, particularly Africa, the Ministers noted with grave concern that Daesh/ISIS affiliates and networks in sub-Saharan Africa threaten security and stability, namely in the Sahel Region and in East Africa/Mozambique. The Coalition is committed to working with affected countries to address the threats posed by Daesh/ISIS in Africa to ensure the enduring global defeat of the organization upon the request and prior consent of the countries concerned, and in full respect of international law and in close coordination with existing initiatives, notably the Coalition for the Sahel and the Global Counter-Terrorism Forum. The Ministers welcomed the presence of delegations from several African nations as observers to this ministerial meeting. The Ministers discussed that reinforcing civilian state institutions and consolidating the rule of law, including law enforcement capacity, will be an essential component of combatting Daesh/ISIS, and that the Global Coalition to Defeat Daesh/ISIS will seek to have effective engagement on the African continent. The Ministers tasked the Coalition Working Groups to assess ways in which they can contribute to counter Daesh/ISIS efforts in the affected regions. The Ministers also welcomed Afghanistan’s efforts to counter the Islamic State in Iraq and Syria-Khurasan (ISIS-K).</p>
<p>Recognizing the challenge posed by foreign terrorist fighters who are in custody, as well as their family members who remain in Syria and Iraq, the Ministers committed to pursuing existing effective justice and accountability mechanisms in close coordination with the countries of origin. This also includes accountability for fighters who have used sexual violence as an instrument of terror. The Coalition remains committed to promoting efforts to ensure that accused terrorists, including those of foreign nationalities, are treated appropriately and tried consistently with applicable international law obligations, including fair trial guarantees, and urges the custodians of the detained Daesh/ISIS terrorists to treat them humanely at all times, in accordance with international law.  The Ministers further recognized that the situation for Daesh/ISIS detainees and family members in northeast Syria is of grave concern and recognized the importance of finding a comprehensive and long-term solution to this serious issue.</p>
<p>The Coalition reaffirmed its belief that a comprehensive and collective effort remains necessary to achieve a full and enduring defeat of Daesh/ISIS worldwide. The Global Coalition to Defeat Daesh/ISIS has proven that it is a cohesive, responsive tool that has achieved notable successes through military, political, stabilization, counter-messaging, financial, and law enforcement lines of effort.</p>
<p>The Ministers also reaffirmed their intent to hold the next ministerial meeting of the Global Coalition by June 2022 and to hold a Small Group Political Directors Meeting in Brussels in the fall of 2021, circumstances pending.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Opening Remarks at D-ISIS Meeting Opening Session</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-opening-remarks-at-d-isis-meeting-opening-session/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 13:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255644</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rome, Italy</p>
<p>Fiera Roma</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER DI MAIO:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you very much.  Mr. Secretary of State, dear Tony, dear colleagues, dear guests, welcome.  Welcome to Italy.  (Via interpreter) I’m delighted to welcome you here to Rome, to the ministerial meeting of the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS, which I have the privilege of co-chairing with Secretary of State Blinken.  I wish to thank my colleague and friend Tony and the State Department for the excellent teamwork and the partnership with the Italian Ministry for Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation which has brought us here.  The pandemic has shown us that only if we focus on multilateralism and international cooperation that we can adequately tackle the challenges ahead.</p>
<p>And this coalition is an example.  It brings together different continents.  It capitalizes on the contribution of each member.  It is flexible enough to take into account different viewpoints.  We have a good track record but a lot more remains to be done.  Daesh was defeated in its territorial dimension, but it hasn’t been uprooted, and that is why Italy, with over 800 units between Iraq and Kuwait, will continue to – while respecting Iraqi sovereignty and in agreement with the Baghdad agreement – will continue to keep its presence in support of local institutions so as to enable the country to tackle this threat autonomously.</p>
<p>We are also ready to increase our participation in the NATO commission in Iraq and to take over the command after Denmark.  Having consolidated our victory is important – consolidating it in Syria is essential in order to bolster the country’s stabilization.  That is why we support the 2254 resolution and the UN-guided operation.</p>
<p>The attacks in these recent months show that Daesh can still be a threat and attract certain segments of the population.  In order to consolidate the results achieved and limit the recruitment possibilities of Daesh and avoid its resurgence, we have to include civil initiatives to de-radicalize and stabilize the freed areas, giving social, economic conditions and opportunities to the local population so as to make them less vulnerable.  We are promoting these initiatives bearing in mind the key principles of our international approach, safeguarding human rights and the rule of law being our topmost priorities.</p>
<p>Despite the financial context, which has been worsened due to the pandemic, Italy is unswerving in its commitment in 2021.  We have planned to increase the resources earmarked for these activities.  Furthermore, we believe it is important to assess (inaudible) initiatives in favor of unaccompanied minors in (inaudible) camp, and to this end we are also in touch with players in the field.</p>
<p>Given the complexity and comprehensive nature of this problem, we need to work together in a joint approach.  We have to also take a comprehensive and targeted approach to dry up financial resources in the areas of activity of ISIS and in other parts of the world.  This is the aim of the Counter ISIS Finance Group, which Italy co-chairs with the United State and Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>Although the Daesh threat in Iraq and Syria is key in our coalition’s commitment, we must also take into consideration its global presence in the African continent and in the Sahel in particular.  The stability of this region is crucial for Europe and the broader Mediterranean.  I would like to thank the representatives from Burkina Faso, Ghana, Mozambique who have accepted our invitation to attend today’s meeting as observers.</p>
<p>Italy will do its part.  It will be committed to promoting peace and sustainable development in this area which is a priority for our foreign policy action.  As I confirmed in our – my recent missions in the region, we will continue to reinforce our diplomatic presence, take part in main international missions, and make a contribution for a sustainable approach to migration via capacity building.</p>
<p>Given the growing threat stemming from Daesh in Africa, I would like to propose to my coalition partners to take into account the possibility of creating a working group or a platform that can focus specifically on Africa.  Such an initiative would also enable us to involve all African countries interested in making a contribution to our mutual benefit.</p>
<p>In concluding, I would like to renew my warm welcome to all in Italy.  I am confident that your remarks will be extremely helpful in bringing forward the discussion, and I would like to now call on the co-chair of the meeting, Antony Blinken. Secretary of State, over to you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Mr. Foreign Minister, Luigi, my friend, thank you so much.  And thank you for the extraordinary job in bringing us all together, and it’s wonderful to be with so many colleagues today.  Mostly, thank you for hosting what is a very important meeting.  And to all of the members of the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS or Daesh, thank you for being part of this endeavor today, but also every day.</p>
<p>Since this coalition was created in 2014, our joint efforts by, with, and through our local partners have been a critical element in achieving ISIS’s territorial defeat in Iraq and in Syria.  Millions of civilians have been able to return to their homes.  The movement of foreign ISIS fighters from – into Syria and Iraq has virtually ceased.  And key ISIS leaders have either been captured or killed.  These achievements are significant and a reflection of what’s possible when we come together in common cause with a shared commitment.</p>
<p>But there is still more work to be done, and let me briefly outline what the United States sees as our top priorities now.  I think it will sound very familiar because it’s very much on track with what Luigi just said.  First, remaining ISIS elements in Iraq and Syria, though severely depleted, still aspire to conduct large-scale attacks, as we saw with January’s twin suicide bombings in Baghdad.  To sustain our military gains, we must reaffirm our commitment, including to Operation Inherent Resolve, the complementary NATO mission in Iraq, and to civilian-led counterterrorism capacity building.</p>
<p>Second, we must renew coalition support for stabilization assistance across Iraq and Syria, as Luigi said, to ensure that ISIS doesn’t have a resurgence in these countries.  Our stabilization assistance will address critical needs that the Syrians themselves have prioritized, deal with vulnerabilities previously exploited by ISIS, close gaps in local authorities’ capacities.  Those needs are particularly acute given the drought and economic downturn in Syria, which ISIS is seeking to exploit.</p>
<p>We’ve made good progress toward our 2021 fundraising goal for stabilization efforts in Iraq and northeast Syria.  We set out to raise $670 million.  I think we’re at close to $507 million now, so let’s keep going till we meet our goal.  Additionally, I can announce today that the United States will provide another $436 million in humanitarian assistance to Syrians and the communities that host them, bringing the total U.S. humanitarian assistance in response to the Syria crisis to nearly $13.5 billion.  Together we must stay as committed to our stabilization goals as we did to our military campaign that resulted in victory on the battlefield.</p>
<p>Third, 10,000 ISIS fighters remain in SDF detention in Syria.  This situation is simply untenable.  It just can’t persist indefinitely.  The United States continues to urge countries of origin, including coalition partners, to repatriate, rehabilitate, and, where applicable, prosecute their citizens.  Several countries have done good work on these fronts.  Kazakhstan has repatriated more than 600 fighters and family members and has enrolled many returnees in rehabilitation programs.  Uzbekistan, Tajikistan, the Kyrgyz Republic have repatriated foreign terrorist fighter family members from Iraq, and in the case of Uzbekistan, from Syria and Afghanistan as well.  Several Balkan countries, including Bosnia and Herzegovina, Kosovo, North Macedonia have also repatriated foreign terrorist fighters.  And Italy, of course, has distinguished itself as one of the few Western European countries willing to return nationals from the region.  Most recently, they repatriated a female foreign terrorist fighter and her children.  Finland has also shown leadership in its repatriation of multiple families from Finland originally.</p>
<p>Fourth, ensuring the enduring defeat of ISIS also means effectively confronting ISIS threats outside of Iraq and Syria, in the place where ISIS – places where ISIS has recently focused its efforts.  In particular, we’re grateful for support from coalition partners for expanding counterterrorism capacity building efforts for countries on the front lines of the ISIS threat in Africa.  And again, I strongly support what the foreign minister said in that regard.  Let’s use today’s discussion to try to expand on coalition plans for effectively dealing with the threat in Africa, as well as how we’ll synchronize our efforts with national, regional, and international partners.</p>
<p>To recap some recent steps the coalition has taken very briefly, last November the United States and Nigeria convened a coalition meeting with representatives of West African states to discuss countering the ISIS threat in West Africa and the Sahel.  We’ve also held informal discussions among coalition partners on the pressing ISIS threat in northern Mozambique and the steps that we could take there.  Several of the coalition’s working groups are expanding their focus to include Africa.  For example, the Communications Working Group recently proposed an Africa framework paper to guide the coalition’s approach to countering ISIS in Africa in the information space by undermining the brand, exposing the recruitment narrative, increasing opportunities for dialogue, sharing positive alternative narratives to ISIS.</p>
<p>This is a vitally important effort.  We are seeing – I know you all know this – we are seeing fighters of 13 and 14 years old take up weapons to kill people, and we have to get at this from every possible angle.  And information work is vitally important.  We urge more coalition working groups – for example, the Counter-ISIS Finance Group – to follow suit and pay additional attention to ISIS and its – the problem it poses in Africa.</p>
<p>And recent coalition expansion efforts have focused on African nations, with the Central African Republic and Mauritania joining as our 82nd and 83rd members.  We’ll continue to encourage key frontline states and regional leaders in Africa to consider becoming members of this coalition.</p>
<p>On a final related note today, the United States is announcing the designation of Ousmane Illiassou Djibo as a specially designated global terrorist. Djibo is a senior leader and key lieutenant in ISIS Greater Sahara.  This designation is part of our continuing effort to counter ISIS financing in Africa.</p>
<p>Let me just conclude by saying how grateful the United States is for your partnership and commitment to defeating ISIS in Iraq, in Syria, everywhere in the world.  We’ve made great progress because we’ve been working together.  So we hope to keep our eye on the fight, to keep up the fight against this terrorist organization until it is decisively defeated.  Thank you very much.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rome, Italy</p>
<p>Fiera Roma</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER DI MAIO:</strong>  Thank you.  Thank you very much.  Mr. Secretary of State, dear Tony, dear colleagues, dear guests, welcome.  Welcome to Italy.  (Via interpreter) I’m delighted to welcome you here to Rome, to the ministerial meeting of the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS, which I have the privilege of co-chairing with Secretary of State Blinken.  I wish to thank my colleague and friend Tony and the State Department for the excellent teamwork and the partnership with the Italian Ministry for Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation which has brought us here.  The pandemic has shown us that only if we focus on multilateralism and international cooperation that we can adequately tackle the challenges ahead.</p>
<p>And this coalition is an example.  It brings together different continents.  It capitalizes on the contribution of each member.  It is flexible enough to take into account different viewpoints.  We have a good track record but a lot more remains to be done.  Daesh was defeated in its territorial dimension, but it hasn’t been uprooted, and that is why Italy, with over 800 units between Iraq and Kuwait, will continue to – while respecting Iraqi sovereignty and in agreement with the Baghdad agreement – will continue to keep its presence in support of local institutions so as to enable the country to tackle this threat autonomously.</p>
<p>We are also ready to increase our participation in the NATO commission in Iraq and to take over the command after Denmark.  Having consolidated our victory is important – consolidating it in Syria is essential in order to bolster the country’s stabilization.  That is why we support the 2254 resolution and the UN-guided operation.</p>
<p>The attacks in these recent months show that Daesh can still be a threat and attract certain segments of the population.  In order to consolidate the results achieved and limit the recruitment possibilities of Daesh and avoid its resurgence, we have to include civil initiatives to de-radicalize and stabilize the freed areas, giving social, economic conditions and opportunities to the local population so as to make them less vulnerable.  We are promoting these initiatives bearing in mind the key principles of our international approach, safeguarding human rights and the rule of law being our topmost priorities.</p>
<p>Despite the financial context, which has been worsened due to the pandemic, Italy is unswerving in its commitment in 2021.  We have planned to increase the resources earmarked for these activities.  Furthermore, we believe it is important to assess (inaudible) initiatives in favor of unaccompanied minors in (inaudible) camp, and to this end we are also in touch with players in the field.</p>
<p>Given the complexity and comprehensive nature of this problem, we need to work together in a joint approach.  We have to also take a comprehensive and targeted approach to dry up financial resources in the areas of activity of ISIS and in other parts of the world.  This is the aim of the Counter ISIS Finance Group, which Italy co-chairs with the United State and Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>Although the Daesh threat in Iraq and Syria is key in our coalition’s commitment, we must also take into consideration its global presence in the African continent and in the Sahel in particular.  The stability of this region is crucial for Europe and the broader Mediterranean.  I would like to thank the representatives from Burkina Faso, Ghana, Mozambique who have accepted our invitation to attend today’s meeting as observers.</p>
<p>Italy will do its part.  It will be committed to promoting peace and sustainable development in this area which is a priority for our foreign policy action.  As I confirmed in our – my recent missions in the region, we will continue to reinforce our diplomatic presence, take part in main international missions, and make a contribution for a sustainable approach to migration via capacity building.</p>
<p>Given the growing threat stemming from Daesh in Africa, I would like to propose to my coalition partners to take into account the possibility of creating a working group or a platform that can focus specifically on Africa.  Such an initiative would also enable us to involve all African countries interested in making a contribution to our mutual benefit.</p>
<p>In concluding, I would like to renew my warm welcome to all in Italy.  I am confident that your remarks will be extremely helpful in bringing forward the discussion, and I would like to now call on the co-chair of the meeting, Antony Blinken. Secretary of State, over to you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Mr. Foreign Minister, Luigi, my friend, thank you so much.  And thank you for the extraordinary job in bringing us all together, and it’s wonderful to be with so many colleagues today.  Mostly, thank you for hosting what is a very important meeting.  And to all of the members of the Global Coalition to Defeat ISIS or Daesh, thank you for being part of this endeavor today, but also every day.</p>
<p>Since this coalition was created in 2014, our joint efforts by, with, and through our local partners have been a critical element in achieving ISIS’s territorial defeat in Iraq and in Syria.  Millions of civilians have been able to return to their homes.  The movement of foreign ISIS fighters from – into Syria and Iraq has virtually ceased.  And key ISIS leaders have either been captured or killed.  These achievements are significant and a reflection of what’s possible when we come together in common cause with a shared commitment.</p>
<p>But there is still more work to be done, and let me briefly outline what the United States sees as our top priorities now.  I think it will sound very familiar because it’s very much on track with what Luigi just said.  First, remaining ISIS elements in Iraq and Syria, though severely depleted, still aspire to conduct large-scale attacks, as we saw with January’s twin suicide bombings in Baghdad.  To sustain our military gains, we must reaffirm our commitment, including to Operation Inherent Resolve, the complementary NATO mission in Iraq, and to civilian-led counterterrorism capacity building.</p>
<p>Second, we must renew coalition support for stabilization assistance across Iraq and Syria, as Luigi said, to ensure that ISIS doesn’t have a resurgence in these countries.  Our stabilization assistance will address critical needs that the Syrians themselves have prioritized, deal with vulnerabilities previously exploited by ISIS, close gaps in local authorities’ capacities.  Those needs are particularly acute given the drought and economic downturn in Syria, which ISIS is seeking to exploit.</p>
<p>We’ve made good progress toward our 2021 fundraising goal for stabilization efforts in Iraq and northeast Syria.  We set out to raise $670 million.  I think we’re at close to $507 million now, so let’s keep going till we meet our goal.  Additionally, I can announce today that the United States will provide another $436 million in humanitarian assistance to Syrians and the communities that host them, bringing the total U.S. humanitarian assistance in response to the Syria crisis to nearly $13.5 billion.  Together we must stay as committed to our stabilization goals as we did to our military campaign that resulted in victory on the battlefield.</p>
<p>Third, 10,000 ISIS fighters remain in SDF detention in Syria.  This situation is simply untenable.  It just can’t persist indefinitely.  The United States continues to urge countries of origin, including coalition partners, to repatriate, rehabilitate, and, where applicable, prosecute their citizens.  Several countries have done good work on these fronts.  Kazakhstan has repatriated more than 600 fighters and family members and has enrolled many returnees in rehabilitation programs.  Uzbekistan, Tajikistan, the Kyrgyz Republic have repatriated foreign terrorist fighter family members from Iraq, and in the case of Uzbekistan, from Syria and Afghanistan as well.  Several Balkan countries, including Bosnia and Herzegovina, Kosovo, North Macedonia have also repatriated foreign terrorist fighters.  And Italy, of course, has distinguished itself as one of the few Western European countries willing to return nationals from the region.  Most recently, they repatriated a female foreign terrorist fighter and her children.  Finland has also shown leadership in its repatriation of multiple families from Finland originally.</p>
<p>Fourth, ensuring the enduring defeat of ISIS also means effectively confronting ISIS threats outside of Iraq and Syria, in the place where ISIS – places where ISIS has recently focused its efforts.  In particular, we’re grateful for support from coalition partners for expanding counterterrorism capacity building efforts for countries on the front lines of the ISIS threat in Africa.  And again, I strongly support what the foreign minister said in that regard.  Let’s use today’s discussion to try to expand on coalition plans for effectively dealing with the threat in Africa, as well as how we’ll synchronize our efforts with national, regional, and international partners.</p>
<p>To recap some recent steps the coalition has taken very briefly, last November the United States and Nigeria convened a coalition meeting with representatives of West African states to discuss countering the ISIS threat in West Africa and the Sahel.  We’ve also held informal discussions among coalition partners on the pressing ISIS threat in northern Mozambique and the steps that we could take there.  Several of the coalition’s working groups are expanding their focus to include Africa.  For example, the Communications Working Group recently proposed an Africa framework paper to guide the coalition’s approach to countering ISIS in Africa in the information space by undermining the brand, exposing the recruitment narrative, increasing opportunities for dialogue, sharing positive alternative narratives to ISIS.</p>
<p>This is a vitally important effort.  We are seeing – I know you all know this – we are seeing fighters of 13 and 14 years old take up weapons to kill people, and we have to get at this from every possible angle.  And information work is vitally important.  We urge more coalition working groups – for example, the Counter-ISIS Finance Group – to follow suit and pay additional attention to ISIS and its – the problem it poses in Africa.</p>
<p>And recent coalition expansion efforts have focused on African nations, with the Central African Republic and Mauritania joining as our 82nd and 83rd members.  We’ll continue to encourage key frontline states and regional leaders in Africa to consider becoming members of this coalition.</p>
<p>On a final related note today, the United States is announcing the designation of Ousmane Illiassou Djibo as a specially designated global terrorist. Djibo is a senior leader and key lieutenant in ISIS Greater Sahara.  This designation is part of our continuing effort to counter ISIS financing in Africa.</p>
<p>Let me just conclude by saying how grateful the United States is for your partnership and commitment to defeating ISIS in Iraq, in Syria, everywhere in the world.  We’ve made great progress because we’ve been working together.  So we hope to keep our eye on the fight, to keep up the fight against this terrorist organization until it is decisively defeated.  Thank you very much.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Pope Francis</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-pope-francis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 13:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with His Holiness Pope Francis in Vatican City.  Secretary Blinken reaffirmed the United States’ commitment to working closely with the Holy See to address global challenges and the needs of the world’s least fortunate and most vulnerable, including refugees and migrants.  The Secretary thanked Pope Francis for his longstanding leadership on the need to care for the environment and tackle the climate crisis.  The Secretary and Pope Francis also discussed China as well as the humanitarian crises in Lebanon, Syria, the Tigray region of Ethiopia, and Venezuela.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with His Holiness Pope Francis in Vatican City.  Secretary Blinken reaffirmed the United States’ commitment to working closely with the Holy See to address global challenges and the needs of the world’s least fortunate and most vulnerable, including refugees and migrants.  The Secretary thanked Pope Francis for his longstanding leadership on the need to care for the environment and tackle the climate crisis.  The Secretary and Pope Francis also discussed China as well as the humanitarian crises in Lebanon, Syria, the Tigray region of Ethiopia, and Venezuela.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>State Department Terrorist Designation of Ousmane Illiassou Djibo</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/state-department-terrorist-designation-of-ousmane-illiassou-djibo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 12:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255601</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Today, the United States is designating Ousmane Illiassou Djibo – also known as Petit Chapori – as a Specially Designated Global Terrorist (SDGT) under section 1(a)(ii)(B) of Executive Order (E.O.) 13224.</p>
<p>As a result of this designation, U.S. persons are generally prohibited from engaging in any transactions with Djibo.  His property and interests in property subject to U.S. jurisdiction are blocked.</p>
<p>Ousmane Illiassou Djibo, a native Nigerien, is an Islamic State of Iraq and Syria in the Greater Sahara (ISIS-GS) leader operating in the Menaka Region of Mali. Djibo is a close collaborator and key lieutenant of ISIS-GS leader, Adnan Abu Walid al-Sahrawi. Djibo directed subordinate ISIS-GS members to develop a network to kidnap or attack westerners in Niger and surrounding areas. Djibo has also taken part in numerous assaults on local forces. He led ISIS-GS fighters in the July 1, 2019 attack on the Nigerien Armed Forces (FAN) base in Inates, Tillaberi Region, Niger, and also provided the order for ISIS-GS fighters to take six Nigerien soldiers hostage during an ambush on Nigerien soldiers near Tongo Tongo on May 14, 2019.</p>
<p>ISIS-GS, which was designated as a Foreign Terrorist Organization (FTO) and SDGT in May 2018, continues to threaten the peace, security, and stability of Mali, Niger, and Burkina Faso. ISIS-GS emerged when Adnan Abu Walid al-Sahrawi and his followers split from Al-Mourabitoun, an al-Qa’ida splinter group and U.S.-designated FTO and SDGT.  Al-Sahrawi first pledged allegiance to ISIS in May 2015, and ISIS acknowledged the pledge in October 2016.</p>
<p>Today’s designation notifies the U.S. public and the international community that Ousmane Illiassou Djibo is a leader of a terrorist organization.  Terrorist designations expose and isolate entities and individuals, and limit their access to the U.S. financial system.  Moreover, designations can assist the law enforcement activities of U.S. agencies and other governments.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Today, the United States is designating Ousmane Illiassou Djibo – also known as Petit Chapori – as a Specially Designated Global Terrorist (SDGT) under section 1(a)(ii)(B) of Executive Order (E.O.) 13224.</p>
<p>As a result of this designation, U.S. persons are generally prohibited from engaging in any transactions with Djibo.  His property and interests in property subject to U.S. jurisdiction are blocked.</p>
<p>Ousmane Illiassou Djibo, a native Nigerien, is an Islamic State of Iraq and Syria in the Greater Sahara (ISIS-GS) leader operating in the Menaka Region of Mali. Djibo is a close collaborator and key lieutenant of ISIS-GS leader, Adnan Abu Walid al-Sahrawi. Djibo directed subordinate ISIS-GS members to develop a network to kidnap or attack westerners in Niger and surrounding areas. Djibo has also taken part in numerous assaults on local forces. He led ISIS-GS fighters in the July 1, 2019 attack on the Nigerien Armed Forces (FAN) base in Inates, Tillaberi Region, Niger, and also provided the order for ISIS-GS fighters to take six Nigerien soldiers hostage during an ambush on Nigerien soldiers near Tongo Tongo on May 14, 2019.</p>
<p>ISIS-GS, which was designated as a Foreign Terrorist Organization (FTO) and SDGT in May 2018, continues to threaten the peace, security, and stability of Mali, Niger, and Burkina Faso. ISIS-GS emerged when Adnan Abu Walid al-Sahrawi and his followers split from Al-Mourabitoun, an al-Qa’ida splinter group and U.S.-designated FTO and SDGT.  Al-Sahrawi first pledged allegiance to ISIS in May 2015, and ISIS acknowledged the pledge in October 2016.</p>
<p>Today’s designation notifies the U.S. public and the international community that Ousmane Illiassou Djibo is a leader of a terrorist organization.  Terrorist designations expose and isolate entities and individuals, and limit their access to the U.S. financial system.  Moreover, designations can assist the law enforcement activities of U.S. agencies and other governments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Holy See Secretary of State Cardinal Parolin and Secretary for Relations with States Archbishop Gallagher</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-holy-see-secretary-of-state-cardinal-parolin-and-secretary-for-relations-with-states-archbishop-gallagher/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 12:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255598</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Holy See Secretary of State Cardinal Pietro Parolin and Secretary for Relations with States Archbishop Paul Gallagher in Vatican City. Secretary Blinken reaffirmed our shared efforts to promote religious freedom and combat human trafficking. The Secretary reiterated U.S. support for a return to democracy in Venezuela and our desire to help the Venezuelan people rebuild their country. The Secretary, the Cardinal, and the Archbishop discussed global issues including migration, climate change, and efforts to expand distribution of vaccines against COVID-19. They underscored the importance of addressing the challenges in Syria and Lebanon, as well as Ethiopia and Belarus. They also discussed human rights and religious freedom in China.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Holy See Secretary of State Cardinal Pietro Parolin and Secretary for Relations with States Archbishop Paul Gallagher in Vatican City. Secretary Blinken reaffirmed our shared efforts to promote religious freedom and combat human trafficking. The Secretary reiterated U.S. support for a return to democracy in Venezuela and our desire to help the Venezuelan people rebuild their country. The Secretary, the Cardinal, and the Archbishop discussed global issues including migration, climate change, and efforts to expand distribution of vaccines against COVID-19. They underscored the importance of addressing the challenges in Syria and Lebanon, as well as Ethiopia and Belarus. They also discussed human rights and religious freedom in China.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President of Egypt and King of Jordan Visit Iraq</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/president-of-egypt-and-king-of-jordan-visit-iraq/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 22:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes today’s historic visit to Baghdad by the President of Egypt and King of Jordan.  This visit is an important step in strengthening regional economic and security ties between Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan and to advance regional stability.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes today’s historic visit to Baghdad by the President of Egypt and King of Jordan.  This visit is an important step in strengthening regional economic and security ties between Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan and to advance regional stability.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
