<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 22:24:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken On National Land Use, Land Cover, and Ecosystems Monitoring System (SIMOCUTE) Initiative</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-on-national-land-use-land-cover-and-ecosystems-monitoring-system-simocute-initiative/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 22:24:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248348</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>San Jose, Costa Rica</p>
<p>Rutas Naturbanas</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> Good afternoon. For Costa Rica it’s an honor to host the official visit of His Excellency Antony Blinken, Secretary of the United States of America. Also we are pleased to receive his distinguished delegation. For the Ministry of Environment and Energy, it’s a pleasure to host this event regarding nature-based solution for climate action in cities and its links with information systems. We give special thanks to the Central Bank of Costa Rica for being our meeting venue today. As mentioned before, we also greet Mrs. Claudia Dobles, first lady of the republic; Mrs. Andrea Meza, minister of environment and energy; Mr. Rodolfo Solano, minister of foreign affairs and worship; Mr. Andres Valenciano, minister of foreign trade; Mr. Rodrigo Cubero, president of the Central Bank of Costa Rica; and, of course, all the high authorities, members of diplomatic missions, private sector, non-state actors, ladies and gentlemen. With this, please now let’s hear our welcoming remarks from Mrs. Andrea Meza, minister of environment and energy. (Speaks in Spanish.)</p>
<p><b>ENVIRONMENT MINISTER MEZA:</b> Good morning. Good morning to everyone here, and I will start by saying that all protocol is observed, so let’s feel free, in a comfortable place. We are between friends. Good morning, Secretary Blinken – (speaks in Spanish) – which is more than our first lady. She’s our team leader in sustainable mobility and green cities. (Speaks in Spanish) Rodolfo Solano, minister of foreign affairs; Andres Valenciano, minister of foreign trade; Rodrigo Cubero, thank you for hosting us, for hosting this event; deputy ministers, diplomatic representatives, U.S. delegation, friends, thank you for being here.</p>
<p>Secretary and friends, we’re so pleased to be sharing this wonderful setting where we can see the seeds of how we can be transforming our cities, making them greener, embracing nature with more public spaces, with sustainable buildings – cities planned for our citizens and not for our cars. And this is the vision for the future. This is the city that we want and the city that we are fighting for right now.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Secretary Blinken, we mentioned that Costa Rica wants to be a strategic partner to catalyze a more inclusive green resilient development model for the Central American region. And let me elaborate a little bit more of what we understand is this green resilient model. We understand that it needs a transformational change that will take us to a net zero emission and a nature-positive economy. We need to move from just trying to create growth to a more systemic approach to generate welfare for our citizens, to boost our economies, to generate jobs but within the planetary boundaries, and addressing inequalities, generating solutions that offer justice to the countries and communities that have done little to create the climate problem.</p>
<p>And we know we can achieve that vision, and it is critical to do it fast. This is what the science is telling us. But the good news is that we have the technology, we have the resources, and right now we have the political will. And this is what makes everything happen for this transformational change. We recognized yesterday that we need to put people in the center of our development model, and I would just add that it is people and nature.</p>
<p>This pandemic is showing us how interconnected we are. If we want to see and if we want to have healthy economics, we need – and healthy societies, we need healthy ecosystems. And if we want to address the climate crisis, we need nature-based solutions.</p>
<p>But this is also a matter of opportunities, and to build the economy of the future, which within is circular, green, and blue. We must acknowledge that nature is an asset, and that we’re doing a terrible job right now in managing this portfolio.</p>
<p>Let me just share one report, one data from the Dasgupta report. It says that between 1992 and 2014, produced capital per person doubled, and human capital per person increased by about 30 percent globally. But the stock of natural capital per person declined by nearly 40 percent.</p>
<p>Nature-related risk matters to the business community. And do you know why? There we have representatives from the business community here. Because over half of the world’s total GDP is moderately or highly dependent on nature. And a nature-positive economy could create more than 400 million jobs by 2030, and we want those jobs for this region. And this is why we’re creating all this. We’re launching our decarbonization plan. We’re having specific packages of policies for short, medium, and long-term actions for strategic sectors – transport, energy, industry, construction, circular economy, agriculture, and nature-based solutions.</p>
<p>But the implementation of these measures needs a whole-of-government approach, and a whole-of-society approach. This is why we’re working with the different sectorial ministries – transport, agriculture. We’re working with the central bank. We’re working with foreign trade. Because we need alignment in these policies. And we are committed with the goals of the Paris Agreement. And we are also clear that we need to generate these good enabling conditions to facilitate engagement of the private sector and civil society in this agenda.</p>
<p>And this is why we selected this place, because Rutas Naturbanas, the project behind this, it’s an example of how we can integrate these kind of visions. Rutas Naturbanas is a grassroots, citizen-led initiative that was started in 2016 by a group of people and organizations committed to climate action and urban renewal, with the mandate – and this is so nice; I love the mandate – to connect people to the city through nature. And here we have Federico Cartin, who is one of the leaders. And we also have Daniel Mikoski as our representative from some of the private sector that it is supporting the initiative.</p>
<p>What I will say is that this project is showing us that it is possible to have public-private partnerships to be transforming the city and to be implementing decarbonization visions.</p>
<p>We also have other good examples through the different, nice stories that we have with CRUSA and the support with a lot of different entrepreneurs, SMEs, so they can adopt green practices, and with other of our strategic partners, such as AED. They are here.</p>
<p>And the other element that has been very interesting with Rutas Naturbanas is that many of the partners are (inaudible) members. And crowdfunding by the foundation has been majorly made possible through American contributions. So we want to thank these.</p>
<p>And the other element for this transformation is to have a robust, good, technical information. We strongly believe in science and data-based policy-making processes. And this is why we’re celebrating the launch of the formalization of the Costa Rica Comprehensive National Land Use, Land Cover, and Ecosystem Monitoring System, SIMOCUTE, with the official announcement of the executive decree that was signed by the president, the minister of agriculture, justice, and by myself – again, another instrument that is showing that it is possible to have this integrated approach.</p>
<p>But this is – this was possible because of the long-term presence and sustained funding from the U.S. Government, and alongside other international agencies like FAO, so thank you very much for the support.</p>
<p>This is the other element that it is critical: whole of government, whole of society, good information. So Secretary Blinken, thank you for all the support the U.S. has given us at the national level. Thank you for continuing your leadership in mobilizing climate finance for nature-based solutions.</p>
<p>As we mentioned yesterday, we welcome the LEAF Coalition presented by the United Kingdom, the U.S., and Norway. We’re working to submit a proposal soon. Count on us to accelerate climate action. Count on us in the multilateral arena to continue raising ambition on our way to Glasgow. We want to have a success COP and we are committed to that. Count on us to work in the Central American region. We’re partners that share values. Thank you. (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> <i>Muchas gracias</i>, Minister. Thank you, Minister Meza.</p>
<p>We invite His Excellency Antony Blinken, Secretary of State of the United States of America to give his remarks. Excellency.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, good afternoon, everyone, and first, Madam Minister, thank you. Thank you for not just your good words, but your important words, and also thank you for the partnership that we have, the United States and Costa Rica, on maybe the most critical issue of our times, and that is preserving and protecting our environment, combating climate change, and saving our planet. We value this partnership and we look to it, I think, more and more in the years ahead.</p>
<p>And let me say, first of all, greetings to everyone. Madam Minister, First Lady, thank you for honoring us with your presence today, and I very much enjoy the opportunity to speak as we were walking down this extraordinary corridor that I think is an example, really, to the world of how you bring people together with their cities through nature. It’s a very powerful idea, but it’s not – it’s more than an idea. We see it realized right here.</p>
<p>And as we were discussing, there is a powerful impact on all of our lives when we have an opportunity, especially those of us who live in cities, to spend some time surrounded by green, to be near the water and the extraordinary rivers that you have, to hear that sound. It has a profound, positive effect, I think, on all of us, and it’s wonderful to see this realized in a practical way right here.</p>
<p>But to both of you, to my colleague Rodolfo, and to all of the ministers here today, I think your presence speaks to Costa Rica’s recognition that all parts of government and all parts of our society, including the private sector, have a role to play in tackling the climate crisis – and more than tackling it, bringing nature and people together in meaningful ways.</p>
<p>I’m also delighted to celebrate the launch of Costa Rica’s National Land Use, Land Cover, and Ecosystems Monitoring System, as the minister mentioned, SIMOCUTE.</p>
<p>This system will make it possible for Costa Rica to collect and integrate high-quality data on natural, agricultural, and biodiversity resources across the entire country. And the aim is not just to measure the impact of greenhouse gas emissions but also to inform better decision making when it comes to managing forests and lands.</p>
<p>Its origins can be traced back to a partnership between Costa Rican experts, a U.S. Government climate fellow, Dr. Randy Hamilton, and several Costa Rican and U.S. Government agencies including, I’m pleased and proud to say, the United States Department of State. And the effort incorporated a range of partners including from the UN Food and Agricultural Organizations and 25 Costa Rican institutions – some of whom I know are represented here today.</p>
<p>This is precisely the kind of collaboration and knowledge sharing across borders, public and private institutions that’s essential to effectively tackling the climate challenge and the climate crisis.</p>
<p>The data it generates will be available online for all to access allowing experts and citizens alike to study them, to track whether government and private actors are actually meeting their commitments. That degree of transparency – and engagement of the citizens – I think is a model that others can and should aspire to.</p>
<p>Of course, SIMOCUTE program is just a small part of Costa Rica’s longstanding global leadership on climate. That’s evident in the targets that Costa Rica has set to achieve net zero emissions by 2050. Its proactive role in international climate change negotiations is pioneering use of debt-for-nature swaps.</p>
<p>And of course, what we know too is the powerful use and reliance on renewable energy here also sets a very, very strong example. Protecting nature by creating additional value for forests is at the heart of a new initiative the United States recently announced together with the United Kingdom, Norway, and nine leading companies at the climate summit that President Biden convened in April. And the minister referred to it – the Lowering Emissions by Accelerating Forest Finance Coalition. It’s a mouthful but the acronym, LEAF, is quite wonderful. It aims to mobilize at least a billion dollars this year to support tropical and subtropical countries in their efforts to reduce emissions from deforestation and forest degradation.</p>
<p>The concept is straightforward: generating verified emissions reductions can be rewarded with payments. These are the kinds of emissions SIMOCUTE is well placed to track. And given Costa Rica’s longstanding efforts to reduce deforestation and restore forests, we hope this is another area where indeed we can work together.</p>
<p>With nearly one-quarter of global greenhouse gas emissions today coming from forests, from agriculture, and other lands, this is an area where we must make significant and swift progress if we are going to avert a climate catastrophe.</p>
<p>I’d also like to thank Ambassador Lyster-Binns from the UK who I think is here today – somewhere – Ambassador. Good to see you. Thank you for your government’s partnership on this initiative.</p>
<p>I think we both know that this is not a battle that countries like Costa Rica can wage alone. Big emitters have their part to do.</p>
<p>The United States is prepared to lead by example, as President Biden demonstrated in the recent targets that he set for our country to cut emissions by at least half in 2030; to double the public international climate finance we provide, to $5.7 billion annually, by 2024.</p>
<p>And that brings me to my last point, which is why we are making such massive investments. Efforts to reduce emissions and build climate resilience are sometimes, maybe even often, presented as an impediment to growth, a strain on economies. But we believe that the climate crisis should be seen differently – as a once-in-generations opportunity to generate good-paying, sustainable jobs, something the minister also alluded to.</p>
<p>Every country in the world needs to reduce emissions, invest in climate resilience, capture more carbon dioxide. That’s an open space for innovation and broad-based growth – if only we seize it.</p>
<p>And I think that’s been Costa Rica’s experience, as Minister Meza pointed out at the climate summit, when she highlighted the millions of dollars in revenue that Costa Rica’s protected areas generate for communities, and the sustainable livelihoods that they support.</p>
<p>It is, as I said at the start, both a pleasure but also I think important that we are partnered in this effort. This is not just a once-in-a-generations opportunity, it’s in a sense a once-in-a-lifetime obligation that we have before us to try to get this right. We’re only going to succeed if we do it together, if we work in partnership, if we all meet our responsibilities and, in doing that, finding incredible opportunity in those responsibilities. So thank you so much for the warm welcome, but more important, thank you for what we’re doing, the United States and Costa Rica, every day to make progress for our people and for our planet. Thank you. (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR: </b>Thank you, your excellency. With this, now invite to the stage Mrs. Claudia Dobles, our first lady of the republic, to give her closing speech. Claudia.</p>
<p><b>MRS DOBLES:</b> Good day to everybody. Your excellency, Mr. Antony Blinken, Secretary of State of the United States, thank you so much for your visit for you and your team. Good day to all the ministers, vice ministers, and everybody from the government, from civil society, from all the institutions that work with us as a team. Thank you for being here today.</p>
<p>I would like to start saying that Costa Rica, it’s very well known for pioneering innovative policies, like abolishing the army more than 70 years ago, for investing and focusing on our health care which is universal and is free. That has been a enormous pillar in fighting this sanitary crisis. Also, that we invested in our people. That is the best resources that we have in Costa Rica is the talent of our people. So we don’t have oil, we don’t have other natural resources possibly; we don’t even want to explore that because we are pretty much focusing on our people and our human talent.</p>
<p>President Alvarado when we started this administration said very accurately that climate crisis is a challenge of this generation and that we really need to act and we need to act now. And we are in a pivotal point to make decisions for the future. That’s why we focusing on how to make a more equitable society, how to put our communities in the center, how to put our people in the center, how to put the services that we needed to provide in the center while lowering our carbon emissions, transitioning in a very just and fair transition towards a decarbonized economy; how to provide a new system, a new paradigm. So that’s why facing that we launch a little bit more than two years ago our national decarbonization plan. And it is important to say that while this is going to tackle climate crisis, it’s more of a social economical development based on sustainability and based on our people that we are talking about. So that is very important and this is something that we keep saying to our communities, that these type of interventions, that providing this type of quality of life, this is decarbonization, this is our national decarbonization plan. It’s part of it.</p>
<p>It’s important to say that Costa Rica, it’s pretty well-known – I was saying to Secretary Blinken that Costa Rica, it’s pretty much well-known for our biodiversity, our beaches, our mountains, our rivers. And we have done a very good job on nature-based solutions, on carbon capture, on reforestation, conservation. But if we really wanted to achieve the goals that we have in our national decarbonization plan, we really needed to focus on our urban agenda and we really need to start talking about urban planning, territorial planning. We need to start talking about how can we interconnect the public services that we provide to our people in order to provide better quality of life in order to enhance public transportation to incorporate the concepts of sustainable mobility. How can we work with the national government and the local governments and the rest of our society to provide answers bottom-up?</p>
<p>If we really want to tackle our goals, we need to focus on this urban agenda. That’s why under the leadership of the wonderful minister of environment, which I really want to thank you for your leadership, I have to say that this has been a team work, a whole government that is completely committed, that shared a vision, that really is working to achieve that vision and to create enabling conditions to continue this transition while – before we move to the next administration so the next administration can continue this transformation.</p>
<p>So thank you to all the government and the staff members that have been – made this possible. I really – I really have to say that this is teamwork. It’s even more important when we think about the recovery plans that we need to provide in a post-COVID era, and that we really need to focus on a green recovery, and when we – when we were talking about our national decarbonization plan, we provided specific actions that provided investment plans for a resilient infrastructure that will create new jobs, that will create new markets, that will create new industries based on new, clean technologies, based on the culture of knowledge, and based on sustainability. So I think our national decarbonization plan is also our green recovery plan post-COVID.</p>
<p>And Secretary Blinken said something that I think is very important. Costa Rica cannot do it alone. We have a strong voice and I am very proud to say that Costa Rica has a strong voice on sustainability. But we are not fighting this fight alone. We know that this is a global fight and we know that we have strategic partners in this, and we are very, very happy and I think the world is very happy to see that under President Biden’s administration, the U.S. has a strong commitment, a huge commitment in climate – in climate change and climate crisis.</p>
<p>So thank you very much, Secretary Blinken, for you and your team, and I am sure that we will keep working together. As the Minister Meza said, count on us because we’re committed, and we share the vision, and we share the values. Thank you so much for your visit, and we’ll keep working. Thank you so much. (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> <i>Muchas gracias, Dona Claudia.</i> Ladies and gentlemen, with this we have concluded the event. Thank you for being here and have a great afternoon.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>San Jose, Costa Rica</p>
<p>Rutas Naturbanas</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> Good afternoon. For Costa Rica it’s an honor to host the official visit of His Excellency Antony Blinken, Secretary of the United States of America. Also we are pleased to receive his distinguished delegation. For the Ministry of Environment and Energy, it’s a pleasure to host this event regarding nature-based solution for climate action in cities and its links with information systems. We give special thanks to the Central Bank of Costa Rica for being our meeting venue today. As mentioned before, we also greet Mrs. Claudia Dobles, first lady of the republic; Mrs. Andrea Meza, minister of environment and energy; Mr. Rodolfo Solano, minister of foreign affairs and worship; Mr. Andres Valenciano, minister of foreign trade; Mr. Rodrigo Cubero, president of the Central Bank of Costa Rica; and, of course, all the high authorities, members of diplomatic missions, private sector, non-state actors, ladies and gentlemen. With this, please now let’s hear our welcoming remarks from Mrs. Andrea Meza, minister of environment and energy. (Speaks in Spanish.)</p>
<p><b>ENVIRONMENT MINISTER MEZA:</b> Good morning. Good morning to everyone here, and I will start by saying that all protocol is observed, so let’s feel free, in a comfortable place. We are between friends. Good morning, Secretary Blinken – (speaks in Spanish) – which is more than our first lady. She’s our team leader in sustainable mobility and green cities. (Speaks in Spanish) Rodolfo Solano, minister of foreign affairs; Andres Valenciano, minister of foreign trade; Rodrigo Cubero, thank you for hosting us, for hosting this event; deputy ministers, diplomatic representatives, U.S. delegation, friends, thank you for being here.</p>
<p>Secretary and friends, we’re so pleased to be sharing this wonderful setting where we can see the seeds of how we can be transforming our cities, making them greener, embracing nature with more public spaces, with sustainable buildings – cities planned for our citizens and not for our cars. And this is the vision for the future. This is the city that we want and the city that we are fighting for right now.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Secretary Blinken, we mentioned that Costa Rica wants to be a strategic partner to catalyze a more inclusive green resilient development model for the Central American region. And let me elaborate a little bit more of what we understand is this green resilient model. We understand that it needs a transformational change that will take us to a net zero emission and a nature-positive economy. We need to move from just trying to create growth to a more systemic approach to generate welfare for our citizens, to boost our economies, to generate jobs but within the planetary boundaries, and addressing inequalities, generating solutions that offer justice to the countries and communities that have done little to create the climate problem.</p>
<p>And we know we can achieve that vision, and it is critical to do it fast. This is what the science is telling us. But the good news is that we have the technology, we have the resources, and right now we have the political will. And this is what makes everything happen for this transformational change. We recognized yesterday that we need to put people in the center of our development model, and I would just add that it is people and nature.</p>
<p>This pandemic is showing us how interconnected we are. If we want to see and if we want to have healthy economics, we need – and healthy societies, we need healthy ecosystems. And if we want to address the climate crisis, we need nature-based solutions.</p>
<p>But this is also a matter of opportunities, and to build the economy of the future, which within is circular, green, and blue. We must acknowledge that nature is an asset, and that we’re doing a terrible job right now in managing this portfolio.</p>
<p>Let me just share one report, one data from the Dasgupta report. It says that between 1992 and 2014, produced capital per person doubled, and human capital per person increased by about 30 percent globally. But the stock of natural capital per person declined by nearly 40 percent.</p>
<p>Nature-related risk matters to the business community. And do you know why? There we have representatives from the business community here. Because over half of the world’s total GDP is moderately or highly dependent on nature. And a nature-positive economy could create more than 400 million jobs by 2030, and we want those jobs for this region. And this is why we’re creating all this. We’re launching our decarbonization plan. We’re having specific packages of policies for short, medium, and long-term actions for strategic sectors – transport, energy, industry, construction, circular economy, agriculture, and nature-based solutions.</p>
<p>But the implementation of these measures needs a whole-of-government approach, and a whole-of-society approach. This is why we’re working with the different sectorial ministries – transport, agriculture. We’re working with the central bank. We’re working with foreign trade. Because we need alignment in these policies. And we are committed with the goals of the Paris Agreement. And we are also clear that we need to generate these good enabling conditions to facilitate engagement of the private sector and civil society in this agenda.</p>
<p>And this is why we selected this place, because Rutas Naturbanas, the project behind this, it’s an example of how we can integrate these kind of visions. Rutas Naturbanas is a grassroots, citizen-led initiative that was started in 2016 by a group of people and organizations committed to climate action and urban renewal, with the mandate – and this is so nice; I love the mandate – to connect people to the city through nature. And here we have Federico Cartin, who is one of the leaders. And we also have Daniel Mikoski as our representative from some of the private sector that it is supporting the initiative.</p>
<p>What I will say is that this project is showing us that it is possible to have public-private partnerships to be transforming the city and to be implementing decarbonization visions.</p>
<p>We also have other good examples through the different, nice stories that we have with CRUSA and the support with a lot of different entrepreneurs, SMEs, so they can adopt green practices, and with other of our strategic partners, such as AED. They are here.</p>
<p>And the other element that has been very interesting with Rutas Naturbanas is that many of the partners are (inaudible) members. And crowdfunding by the foundation has been majorly made possible through American contributions. So we want to thank these.</p>
<p>And the other element for this transformation is to have a robust, good, technical information. We strongly believe in science and data-based policy-making processes. And this is why we’re celebrating the launch of the formalization of the Costa Rica Comprehensive National Land Use, Land Cover, and Ecosystem Monitoring System, SIMOCUTE, with the official announcement of the executive decree that was signed by the president, the minister of agriculture, justice, and by myself – again, another instrument that is showing that it is possible to have this integrated approach.</p>
<p>But this is – this was possible because of the long-term presence and sustained funding from the U.S. Government, and alongside other international agencies like FAO, so thank you very much for the support.</p>
<p>This is the other element that it is critical: whole of government, whole of society, good information. So Secretary Blinken, thank you for all the support the U.S. has given us at the national level. Thank you for continuing your leadership in mobilizing climate finance for nature-based solutions.</p>
<p>As we mentioned yesterday, we welcome the LEAF Coalition presented by the United Kingdom, the U.S., and Norway. We’re working to submit a proposal soon. Count on us to accelerate climate action. Count on us in the multilateral arena to continue raising ambition on our way to Glasgow. We want to have a success COP and we are committed to that. Count on us to work in the Central American region. We’re partners that share values. Thank you. (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> <i>Muchas gracias</i>, Minister. Thank you, Minister Meza.</p>
<p>We invite His Excellency Antony Blinken, Secretary of State of the United States of America to give his remarks. Excellency.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, good afternoon, everyone, and first, Madam Minister, thank you. Thank you for not just your good words, but your important words, and also thank you for the partnership that we have, the United States and Costa Rica, on maybe the most critical issue of our times, and that is preserving and protecting our environment, combating climate change, and saving our planet. We value this partnership and we look to it, I think, more and more in the years ahead.</p>
<p>And let me say, first of all, greetings to everyone. Madam Minister, First Lady, thank you for honoring us with your presence today, and I very much enjoy the opportunity to speak as we were walking down this extraordinary corridor that I think is an example, really, to the world of how you bring people together with their cities through nature. It’s a very powerful idea, but it’s not – it’s more than an idea. We see it realized right here.</p>
<p>And as we were discussing, there is a powerful impact on all of our lives when we have an opportunity, especially those of us who live in cities, to spend some time surrounded by green, to be near the water and the extraordinary rivers that you have, to hear that sound. It has a profound, positive effect, I think, on all of us, and it’s wonderful to see this realized in a practical way right here.</p>
<p>But to both of you, to my colleague Rodolfo, and to all of the ministers here today, I think your presence speaks to Costa Rica’s recognition that all parts of government and all parts of our society, including the private sector, have a role to play in tackling the climate crisis – and more than tackling it, bringing nature and people together in meaningful ways.</p>
<p>I’m also delighted to celebrate the launch of Costa Rica’s National Land Use, Land Cover, and Ecosystems Monitoring System, as the minister mentioned, SIMOCUTE.</p>
<p>This system will make it possible for Costa Rica to collect and integrate high-quality data on natural, agricultural, and biodiversity resources across the entire country. And the aim is not just to measure the impact of greenhouse gas emissions but also to inform better decision making when it comes to managing forests and lands.</p>
<p>Its origins can be traced back to a partnership between Costa Rican experts, a U.S. Government climate fellow, Dr. Randy Hamilton, and several Costa Rican and U.S. Government agencies including, I’m pleased and proud to say, the United States Department of State. And the effort incorporated a range of partners including from the UN Food and Agricultural Organizations and 25 Costa Rican institutions – some of whom I know are represented here today.</p>
<p>This is precisely the kind of collaboration and knowledge sharing across borders, public and private institutions that’s essential to effectively tackling the climate challenge and the climate crisis.</p>
<p>The data it generates will be available online for all to access allowing experts and citizens alike to study them, to track whether government and private actors are actually meeting their commitments. That degree of transparency – and engagement of the citizens – I think is a model that others can and should aspire to.</p>
<p>Of course, SIMOCUTE program is just a small part of Costa Rica’s longstanding global leadership on climate. That’s evident in the targets that Costa Rica has set to achieve net zero emissions by 2050. Its proactive role in international climate change negotiations is pioneering use of debt-for-nature swaps.</p>
<p>And of course, what we know too is the powerful use and reliance on renewable energy here also sets a very, very strong example. Protecting nature by creating additional value for forests is at the heart of a new initiative the United States recently announced together with the United Kingdom, Norway, and nine leading companies at the climate summit that President Biden convened in April. And the minister referred to it – the Lowering Emissions by Accelerating Forest Finance Coalition. It’s a mouthful but the acronym, LEAF, is quite wonderful. It aims to mobilize at least a billion dollars this year to support tropical and subtropical countries in their efforts to reduce emissions from deforestation and forest degradation.</p>
<p>The concept is straightforward: generating verified emissions reductions can be rewarded with payments. These are the kinds of emissions SIMOCUTE is well placed to track. And given Costa Rica’s longstanding efforts to reduce deforestation and restore forests, we hope this is another area where indeed we can work together.</p>
<p>With nearly one-quarter of global greenhouse gas emissions today coming from forests, from agriculture, and other lands, this is an area where we must make significant and swift progress if we are going to avert a climate catastrophe.</p>
<p>I’d also like to thank Ambassador Lyster-Binns from the UK who I think is here today – somewhere – Ambassador. Good to see you. Thank you for your government’s partnership on this initiative.</p>
<p>I think we both know that this is not a battle that countries like Costa Rica can wage alone. Big emitters have their part to do.</p>
<p>The United States is prepared to lead by example, as President Biden demonstrated in the recent targets that he set for our country to cut emissions by at least half in 2030; to double the public international climate finance we provide, to $5.7 billion annually, by 2024.</p>
<p>And that brings me to my last point, which is why we are making such massive investments. Efforts to reduce emissions and build climate resilience are sometimes, maybe even often, presented as an impediment to growth, a strain on economies. But we believe that the climate crisis should be seen differently – as a once-in-generations opportunity to generate good-paying, sustainable jobs, something the minister also alluded to.</p>
<p>Every country in the world needs to reduce emissions, invest in climate resilience, capture more carbon dioxide. That’s an open space for innovation and broad-based growth – if only we seize it.</p>
<p>And I think that’s been Costa Rica’s experience, as Minister Meza pointed out at the climate summit, when she highlighted the millions of dollars in revenue that Costa Rica’s protected areas generate for communities, and the sustainable livelihoods that they support.</p>
<p>It is, as I said at the start, both a pleasure but also I think important that we are partnered in this effort. This is not just a once-in-a-generations opportunity, it’s in a sense a once-in-a-lifetime obligation that we have before us to try to get this right. We’re only going to succeed if we do it together, if we work in partnership, if we all meet our responsibilities and, in doing that, finding incredible opportunity in those responsibilities. So thank you so much for the warm welcome, but more important, thank you for what we’re doing, the United States and Costa Rica, every day to make progress for our people and for our planet. Thank you. (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR: </b>Thank you, your excellency. With this, now invite to the stage Mrs. Claudia Dobles, our first lady of the republic, to give her closing speech. Claudia.</p>
<p><b>MRS DOBLES:</b> Good day to everybody. Your excellency, Mr. Antony Blinken, Secretary of State of the United States, thank you so much for your visit for you and your team. Good day to all the ministers, vice ministers, and everybody from the government, from civil society, from all the institutions that work with us as a team. Thank you for being here today.</p>
<p>I would like to start saying that Costa Rica, it’s very well known for pioneering innovative policies, like abolishing the army more than 70 years ago, for investing and focusing on our health care which is universal and is free. That has been a enormous pillar in fighting this sanitary crisis. Also, that we invested in our people. That is the best resources that we have in Costa Rica is the talent of our people. So we don’t have oil, we don’t have other natural resources possibly; we don’t even want to explore that because we are pretty much focusing on our people and our human talent.</p>
<p>President Alvarado when we started this administration said very accurately that climate crisis is a challenge of this generation and that we really need to act and we need to act now. And we are in a pivotal point to make decisions for the future. That’s why we focusing on how to make a more equitable society, how to put our communities in the center, how to put our people in the center, how to put the services that we needed to provide in the center while lowering our carbon emissions, transitioning in a very just and fair transition towards a decarbonized economy; how to provide a new system, a new paradigm. So that’s why facing that we launch a little bit more than two years ago our national decarbonization plan. And it is important to say that while this is going to tackle climate crisis, it’s more of a social economical development based on sustainability and based on our people that we are talking about. So that is very important and this is something that we keep saying to our communities, that these type of interventions, that providing this type of quality of life, this is decarbonization, this is our national decarbonization plan. It’s part of it.</p>
<p>It’s important to say that Costa Rica, it’s pretty well-known – I was saying to Secretary Blinken that Costa Rica, it’s pretty much well-known for our biodiversity, our beaches, our mountains, our rivers. And we have done a very good job on nature-based solutions, on carbon capture, on reforestation, conservation. But if we really wanted to achieve the goals that we have in our national decarbonization plan, we really needed to focus on our urban agenda and we really need to start talking about urban planning, territorial planning. We need to start talking about how can we interconnect the public services that we provide to our people in order to provide better quality of life in order to enhance public transportation to incorporate the concepts of sustainable mobility. How can we work with the national government and the local governments and the rest of our society to provide answers bottom-up?</p>
<p>If we really want to tackle our goals, we need to focus on this urban agenda. That’s why under the leadership of the wonderful minister of environment, which I really want to thank you for your leadership, I have to say that this has been a team work, a whole government that is completely committed, that shared a vision, that really is working to achieve that vision and to create enabling conditions to continue this transition while – before we move to the next administration so the next administration can continue this transformation.</p>
<p>So thank you to all the government and the staff members that have been – made this possible. I really – I really have to say that this is teamwork. It’s even more important when we think about the recovery plans that we need to provide in a post-COVID era, and that we really need to focus on a green recovery, and when we – when we were talking about our national decarbonization plan, we provided specific actions that provided investment plans for a resilient infrastructure that will create new jobs, that will create new markets, that will create new industries based on new, clean technologies, based on the culture of knowledge, and based on sustainability. So I think our national decarbonization plan is also our green recovery plan post-COVID.</p>
<p>And Secretary Blinken said something that I think is very important. Costa Rica cannot do it alone. We have a strong voice and I am very proud to say that Costa Rica has a strong voice on sustainability. But we are not fighting this fight alone. We know that this is a global fight and we know that we have strategic partners in this, and we are very, very happy and I think the world is very happy to see that under President Biden’s administration, the U.S. has a strong commitment, a huge commitment in climate – in climate change and climate crisis.</p>
<p>So thank you very much, Secretary Blinken, for you and your team, and I am sure that we will keep working together. As the Minister Meza said, count on us because we’re committed, and we share the vision, and we share the values. Thank you so much for your visit, and we’ll keep working. Thank you so much. (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> <i>Muchas gracias, Dona Claudia.</i> Ladies and gentlemen, with this we have concluded the event. Thank you for being here and have a great afternoon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing – June 2, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-june-2-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 22:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=248345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:02 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-DEPARTMENT"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you for joining today’s briefing. I have three updates at the top and then we’ll resume taking your questions. I’d like to start off today by noting the tragic passing of our friend and colleague Tejinder Singh, who was the founder and editor of India America Today. Tejinder covered the State Department for 11 years, participating in many State Department briefings both in person and also calling in every telephonic briefing. We already miss seeing his name in the question queue here today. Tejinder was well-known for being a kind and generous colleague, and also for keeping us on our toes with his questions. Our thoughts are with his family, friends, and colleagues as we grieve his loss. And I speak for my colleagues here when I say that he was such a pleasure to work with for all of us, and his presence will be sorely missed.</p>
<p>Yesterday the United States began celebrating the first day of Pride Month. Not only do we recognize how far we have come in the fight for the protection of the human rights of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex persons, but we also acknowledge the distance that remains on the path to full equality and equity.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-_Hlk73544734"></a> The United States is committed to increasing U.S. engagement on LGBTQI+ issues intersectionally<sup><a id="post-248345-footnote-ref-1" href="#post-248345-footnote-1"></a></sup>, working to ensure the same-sex spouses for our diplomats assigned abroad are afforded the same privileges and immunities as opposite-sex spouses, and empowering local movements and persons advancing the rights of LGBTQI+ persons. We are proud of our work with local and international partners to build a more inclusive global society for all LGBTQI+ communities.</p>
<p>We seek to increase the visibility of and address the acute challenges faced by particularly marginalized members of these communities, including women and girls, transgender, non-binary, and intersex persons. Although the United States still has work to do, we strive to lead by example in the promotion and protection of human rights for all persons.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-SECRETARY"></a> And finally, as you know, Secretary Blinken was in Costa Rica yesterday and today, where he met with senior government officials from across the Central American region to discuss how our countries can work together to create a more democratic, prosperous, and secure region. They also worked to deepening the region’s collaborative approach to shared challenges of irregular migration.</p>
<p>Yesterday, the Secretary attended a meeting with foreign ministers and vice ministers from all seven Central American countries, as well as Mexico and the Dominican Republic. They discussed issues essential to the wellbeing of people in this region, including strategies for addressing root causes of migration and managing migration flows in and throughout the region; combating corruption and strengthening democratic institutions; generating inclusive economic growth; recovering from the COVID-19 pandemic; and healthy environmental stewardship.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken also met yesterday with President Alvarado and Foreign Minister Solano of Costa Rica to discuss the strong partnership between our countries on migration, climate change, and security. In addition, he met with the foreign secretary of Mexico and the foreign ministers of Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador to discuss vital work to address migration and other challenges within those countries.</p>
<p>This morning, Secretary Blinken visited a pair of joint U.S.-Costa Rican initiatives that show how the United States can successfully partner with the region to help build a better future. <a id="post-248345-_Hlk73544790"></a>He first visited a neighborhood that benefits from “<em>Sembremos Seguridad</em>,” an initiative<sup><a id="post-248345-footnote-ref-2" href="#post-248345-footnote-2"></a></sup> citizen security program for at-risk youth. He then visited an environmental stewardship initiative that sets a model for efforts to reduce deforestation and fight climate change in the region. He also sat down with a Costa Rican media outlet to communicate with local audiences and demonstrate support for media independence in Central America.</p>
<p>This trip is a part of the administration’s focus on Central America. Vice President Harris will be headed to the region next week to further advance our efforts to improve conditions for people of Central America, which also advances the interests of people in the United States.</p>
<p>And with that, we’ll give it a few minutes before taking your questions.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Ladies and gentlemen, if you wish to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 on your telephone keypad. You may withdraw your question at any time by repeating the 1, 0 command. If you are using a speaker phone, please pick up the handset before pressing the numbers. Once again, if you have a question, you may press 1 then 0 at this time.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Let’s go to Pearl Matibe, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-ETHIOPIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Good afternoon. Hope you’re having a great day today. My question is regarding President Joe Biden’s upcoming trip with President Vladimir Putin of Russia. And I’m just wondering after the sanctions and recent diplomatic tools you’re using regarding Ethiopia, Russia is now preparing to have an Africa summit in 2022. Is Africa going to be part of the agenda between President Biden and President Putin given the fact that Africa over the next decades beyond Biden’s administration will have such a huge population and role to play in the world? Is Africa going to be a significant topic on that agenda, and does the United States anticipate an Africa summit as well? Do you have anything to share? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you for your question, Pearl. Well, what I will say broadly is that Africa is a priority for – the relationship with Africa is a priority for the Biden administration, but I certainly won’t get ahead of any meetings and don’t have anything to share for you at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Casey O’Neill.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-BURMA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, hi, Jalina. Thanks so much for doing this. I – my question is actually on Myanmar. So I know today – earlier today, excuse me – Deputy Secretary Sherman in Bangkok delivered some remarks and spoke about the two American journalists that are detained in Myanmar, Danny Fenster and Nathan Maung. Their – excuse me – Mr. Fenster’s family has also been making the rounds on television and spoke earlier this morning and said that the United States Government has requested consular access, but so far that request has not been addressed by the military junta in Myanmar. So I’m just wondering if you could provide us any update on steps that the U.S. Government is taking to ensure that these two detained journalists are safe and if you have any update on whether or not the embassy personnel have been able to gain consular access to them. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks for your question, Casey. Well, I’ll start off by saying that the safety and safe return of U.S. citizens is a priority for the United States. At this time we have nothing to announce or any updates about these two specific cases.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Rosiland Jordan.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-CHINA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for taking my call. I have two questions. One: The anniversary of the Tiananmen Square massacre is coming up. Is the U.S. sending a message to Beijing about how its security forces should handle themselves on this anniversary, both in mainland China and in Hong Kong?</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-IRAN"></a> And the other question has to do with, one, the sinking of an Iranian oil tanker, the <em>Kharg</em>, in the Gulf of Oman, was – does the U.S. have any more information about whether this was an accident or perhaps an act of sabotage? And connected to that, does the U.S. have any more updates on the travel of two Iranian warships that rumor – that the rumors suggest may be heading to Venezuela? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Rosiland. I’ll start with your first question on Tiananmen, and I’ll start by broadly saying that the United States condemns actions by Hong Kong authorities that prompted organizers to close the June 4th Museum that commemorates the 1989 Tiananmen Square massacre. As far as your question of sending any particular messages, no, we’re not sending any direct messages at this time, other than saying that Hong Kong and Beijing authorities continue to silence dissenting voices by also attempting to erase the horrific massacre from history.</p>
<p>And to your question on Iran, speaking of the naval ships on the Gulf of Oman, well, we’ve definitely seen the media reports on the Iranian naval vessels that have caught fire and have sank. Other than that, we don’t have anything to announce at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Rich Edson.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-WORLDHEALTHASSEMBLY"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Jalina, just looking into the conclusion of the World Health Assembly, there is really no sense of a phase two investigation or commitment to one, Taiwan was excluded from the proceedings, Syria and Belarus are now on the executive committee. I was just wondering if you could provide what the State Department’s assessment of the proceedings were and how the U.S. plans on attempting to follow through with reforms of the World Health Organization.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Rich. What I’ll say is to your point about countries that you’ve mentioned. We have grave concerns that Syria and Belarus have been elected for a three-year term by the World Health Assembly Executive Board. Members of the executive board each have a duty to advance public health and likewise are expected to uphold universal values as well as human rights. And, of course, this would include providing access for delivery of lifesaving humanitarian supplies, and that would include medical equipment as well. <a id="post-248345-_Hlk73544881"></a>We don’t believe the actions of either Syria or Belarus demonstrate this, and although the U.S. is not currently part of the executive board, we’ll continue to monitor closely the board’s activities and make clear that – U.S. exemptions<sup><a id="post-248345-footnote-ref-3" href="#post-248345-footnote-3"></a></sup> that the board members uphold the highest standards of human rights.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Laura Rozen.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-IRAN1"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you have anything on the latest round of Iran talks in Vienna, which I think are wrapping up right now.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Laura. So the delegation led by Special Envoy for Iran Robert Malley is currently in Vienna, and he’s in Vienna for a fifth round of talks. And any update to share that he actually may come back to Washington for consultations at the end of the week. Outside of that, I’d just underscore that these last few rounds of discussion have actually helped crystallize the choices that need to be made by Iran, and also by us, the United States, in order to achieve a mutual return to compliance of the JCPOA.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Soyoung Kim, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> About North Korea, Deputy Secretary Sherman said today that the U.S. has made its policy known to the DPRK. Can you clarify whether this means the U.S. recently reached out to North Korea again or the separate contact made a few months ago the Department of State had confirmed before? And any response from North Korea?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hi, thanks for the question. I won’t get ahead of Deputy Secretary Sherman’s comments, and any other update we’ll be able to preview at a later time but nothing’s going out today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Said Arikat.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Said’s line has left the queue.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> All right. With that, let’s go to Michel Ghandour, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I have two questions on Iran. Sources in Vienna said that the parties reached a draft agreement. Can you confirm that? And any comment on the fire in Tehran’s refinery today?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks for your question. Nothing to announce. I’m not able to confirm the reports of a fire in Tehran today, but just to underscore what was mentioned previously, our Special Envoy for Iran Robert Malley, he’s currently in Vienna for his fifth round of talks and should be coming back to Washington sometime later this week. Anything beyond that and the decisions and the discussions that have been made, I have nothing to announce.</p>
<p>Looks like we have Said Arikat back in the queue. We’ll go to Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. Thank you, Jalina. And I also want to thank you for mentioning my good friend, Tejinder. May God bless his soul. We will miss him dearly. Jalina, I wanted to ask you about two issues: one, if you have any comment on a report by <em>The Washington Post</em> that Israel is preventing cancer patients from leaving Gaza through the Erez Crossing, if you have any comment on that. I also want to ask about the whereabouts of Mr. Hady Amr right now, and what is next on his agenda? What is he doing? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you for your question, Said. And again, to underscore, we definitely will all miss Tejinder and his spirit, and his vigor and his contributions to not only foreign affairs but journalism as well.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-_Hlk73546868"></a> To your first question on cancer, I certainly look forward to these reports and would have to get back to you specifically on that question. And I’d have to do the same for your question on Hady and what he’s doing. We don’t have anything to announce at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Lara Jakes.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> I do not see Lara Jakes’s line in queue.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Okay. Let’s go to the line of Jennifer Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> It looks like Jennifer’s line is not in queue either.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> All right. Let’s go to the line of Hiba Nasr.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thank you. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. I have one question about Israel. First, we saw during Secretary Blinken’s visit to Israel two weeks ago, he extended an invitation to the Israeli president to visit Washington, and tomorrow that Israeli defense minister is visiting Washington. Did this administration extend an invitation to Prime Minister Netanyahu to visit Washington? And my second question is on Nord Stream 2; yesterday Republicans in the House sent a letter to Secretary Blinken expressing concern over the decision to – over the decision to apply a waiver to some sanctions. Do you have any comments on that?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Hiba, for your first question on extending an invitation – on invites. We have nothing at all to announce on that. And your second question on NS2, I’ll have to take that one back for you.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Claudia Uceda.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-COSTARICA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi. Thanks for taking my questions. I have two questions. First is: How can Costa Rica help stop illegal immigration flow into the U.S.? What is the Secretary looking into specifically? And my second question is about Nicaragua. I would like a reaction to the fact that <a id="post-248345-NICARAGUA"></a>Nicaraguan prosecutors question and are investigating 16 independent journalists, and they are threatening them with a criminal investigation related to money laundering investigation into Violeta Chamorro, who is a prospective candidate. What’s your reaction to that? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you, Claudia. So to your first question, I won’t get into specifics on what Costa Rica should be doing when it comes to the fight for regular migration, but I will say that Costa Rica honestly is a top partner of the United States and it has a strong democracy. And we do have shared values as well as shared commitments. And part of that is championing human rights across the board, and that will be integral into fighting that common challenge together. To your second question, I’ll just say broadly speaking that the United States supports the freedom of the press and will continue to champion that not only in Nicaragua but all over the world.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-IRAN2"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Inaudible) press you a tiny bit more on Iran. In the past, you guys have said that there had been progress in the talks, though a lot of differences remained, and the U.S. and Iran were sort of closer to the start of the talks than they were toward the end of the talks. So do you believe that progress continues to be made? Have those talks stalled? And do you feel that the two sides are gradually inching closer to a resolution? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Well, certainly some progress has been made, and like I said, Rob Malley is in Vienna. He’ll be returning to Washington pretty soon. And again, talks are ongoing. And they will continue at a pace that’s honestly appropriate to address the significance of the issues that are currently on the table being negotiated right now. And I’ll continue to underscore that discussions like this are always thorough. They’re thoughtful. They’re businesslike even though they are indirect. And of course that’s to be expected. This isn’t going to be a quick or easy process.</p>
<p>It looks like we have Jennifer Hansler back on the line, so I’ll take that last question from her.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hello.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Hi, Jennifer.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi, Jalina. Thanks so much for taking my question. Just a little more on Iran, can you confirm that the indirect talks will resume next week? And then separately, has there been any communication with Russia in the wake of the latest cyber-attack on JBS? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks for your questions, Jennifer. To your first one, I don’t have anything to announce of any – for any future talks. And the second question, we’ll have to take that one back for you.</p>
<p>And thank you all very much for joining today’s briefing. I hope you have a wonderful rest of your day.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:29 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
<ol>
<li id="post-248345-footnote-1">internationally <a href="#post-248345-footnote-ref-1">↑</a></li>
<li id="post-248345-footnote-2">innovative <a href="#post-248345-footnote-ref-2">↑</a></li>
<li id="post-248345-footnote-3">expectations <a href="#post-248345-footnote-ref-3">↑</a></li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:02 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-DEPARTMENT"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you for joining today’s briefing. I have three updates at the top and then we’ll resume taking your questions. I’d like to start off today by noting the tragic passing of our friend and colleague Tejinder Singh, who was the founder and editor of India America Today. Tejinder covered the State Department for 11 years, participating in many State Department briefings both in person and also calling in every telephonic briefing. We already miss seeing his name in the question queue here today. Tejinder was well-known for being a kind and generous colleague, and also for keeping us on our toes with his questions. Our thoughts are with his family, friends, and colleagues as we grieve his loss. And I speak for my colleagues here when I say that he was such a pleasure to work with for all of us, and his presence will be sorely missed.</p>
<p>Yesterday the United States began celebrating the first day of Pride Month. Not only do we recognize how far we have come in the fight for the protection of the human rights of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex persons, but we also acknowledge the distance that remains on the path to full equality and equity.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-_Hlk73544734"></a> The United States is committed to increasing U.S. engagement on LGBTQI+ issues intersectionally<sup><a id="post-248345-footnote-ref-1" href="#post-248345-footnote-1"></a></sup>, working to ensure the same-sex spouses for our diplomats assigned abroad are afforded the same privileges and immunities as opposite-sex spouses, and empowering local movements and persons advancing the rights of LGBTQI+ persons. We are proud of our work with local and international partners to build a more inclusive global society for all LGBTQI+ communities.</p>
<p>We seek to increase the visibility of and address the acute challenges faced by particularly marginalized members of these communities, including women and girls, transgender, non-binary, and intersex persons. Although the United States still has work to do, we strive to lead by example in the promotion and protection of human rights for all persons.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-SECRETARY"></a> And finally, as you know, Secretary Blinken was in Costa Rica yesterday and today, where he met with senior government officials from across the Central American region to discuss how our countries can work together to create a more democratic, prosperous, and secure region. They also worked to deepening the region’s collaborative approach to shared challenges of irregular migration.</p>
<p>Yesterday, the Secretary attended a meeting with foreign ministers and vice ministers from all seven Central American countries, as well as Mexico and the Dominican Republic. They discussed issues essential to the wellbeing of people in this region, including strategies for addressing root causes of migration and managing migration flows in and throughout the region; combating corruption and strengthening democratic institutions; generating inclusive economic growth; recovering from the COVID-19 pandemic; and healthy environmental stewardship.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken also met yesterday with President Alvarado and Foreign Minister Solano of Costa Rica to discuss the strong partnership between our countries on migration, climate change, and security. In addition, he met with the foreign secretary of Mexico and the foreign ministers of Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador to discuss vital work to address migration and other challenges within those countries.</p>
<p>This morning, Secretary Blinken visited a pair of joint U.S.-Costa Rican initiatives that show how the United States can successfully partner with the region to help build a better future. <a id="post-248345-_Hlk73544790"></a>He first visited a neighborhood that benefits from “<em>Sembremos Seguridad</em>,” an initiative<sup><a id="post-248345-footnote-ref-2" href="#post-248345-footnote-2"></a></sup> citizen security program for at-risk youth. He then visited an environmental stewardship initiative that sets a model for efforts to reduce deforestation and fight climate change in the region. He also sat down with a Costa Rican media outlet to communicate with local audiences and demonstrate support for media independence in Central America.</p>
<p>This trip is a part of the administration’s focus on Central America. Vice President Harris will be headed to the region next week to further advance our efforts to improve conditions for people of Central America, which also advances the interests of people in the United States.</p>
<p>And with that, we’ll give it a few minutes before taking your questions.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Ladies and gentlemen, if you wish to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 on your telephone keypad. You may withdraw your question at any time by repeating the 1, 0 command. If you are using a speaker phone, please pick up the handset before pressing the numbers. Once again, if you have a question, you may press 1 then 0 at this time.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Let’s go to Pearl Matibe, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-ETHIOPIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Good afternoon. Hope you’re having a great day today. My question is regarding President Joe Biden’s upcoming trip with President Vladimir Putin of Russia. And I’m just wondering after the sanctions and recent diplomatic tools you’re using regarding Ethiopia, Russia is now preparing to have an Africa summit in 2022. Is Africa going to be part of the agenda between President Biden and President Putin given the fact that Africa over the next decades beyond Biden’s administration will have such a huge population and role to play in the world? Is Africa going to be a significant topic on that agenda, and does the United States anticipate an Africa summit as well? Do you have anything to share? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you for your question, Pearl. Well, what I will say broadly is that Africa is a priority for – the relationship with Africa is a priority for the Biden administration, but I certainly won’t get ahead of any meetings and don’t have anything to share for you at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Casey O’Neill.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-BURMA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, hi, Jalina. Thanks so much for doing this. I – my question is actually on Myanmar. So I know today – earlier today, excuse me – Deputy Secretary Sherman in Bangkok delivered some remarks and spoke about the two American journalists that are detained in Myanmar, Danny Fenster and Nathan Maung. Their – excuse me – Mr. Fenster’s family has also been making the rounds on television and spoke earlier this morning and said that the United States Government has requested consular access, but so far that request has not been addressed by the military junta in Myanmar. So I’m just wondering if you could provide us any update on steps that the U.S. Government is taking to ensure that these two detained journalists are safe and if you have any update on whether or not the embassy personnel have been able to gain consular access to them. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks for your question, Casey. Well, I’ll start off by saying that the safety and safe return of U.S. citizens is a priority for the United States. At this time we have nothing to announce or any updates about these two specific cases.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Rosiland Jordan.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-CHINA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for taking my call. I have two questions. One: The anniversary of the Tiananmen Square massacre is coming up. Is the U.S. sending a message to Beijing about how its security forces should handle themselves on this anniversary, both in mainland China and in Hong Kong?</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-IRAN"></a> And the other question has to do with, one, the sinking of an Iranian oil tanker, the <em>Kharg</em>, in the Gulf of Oman, was – does the U.S. have any more information about whether this was an accident or perhaps an act of sabotage? And connected to that, does the U.S. have any more updates on the travel of two Iranian warships that rumor – that the rumors suggest may be heading to Venezuela? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Rosiland. I’ll start with your first question on Tiananmen, and I’ll start by broadly saying that the United States condemns actions by Hong Kong authorities that prompted organizers to close the June 4th Museum that commemorates the 1989 Tiananmen Square massacre. As far as your question of sending any particular messages, no, we’re not sending any direct messages at this time, other than saying that Hong Kong and Beijing authorities continue to silence dissenting voices by also attempting to erase the horrific massacre from history.</p>
<p>And to your question on Iran, speaking of the naval ships on the Gulf of Oman, well, we’ve definitely seen the media reports on the Iranian naval vessels that have caught fire and have sank. Other than that, we don’t have anything to announce at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Rich Edson.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-WORLDHEALTHASSEMBLY"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Jalina, just looking into the conclusion of the World Health Assembly, there is really no sense of a phase two investigation or commitment to one, Taiwan was excluded from the proceedings, Syria and Belarus are now on the executive committee. I was just wondering if you could provide what the State Department’s assessment of the proceedings were and how the U.S. plans on attempting to follow through with reforms of the World Health Organization.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Rich. What I’ll say is to your point about countries that you’ve mentioned. We have grave concerns that Syria and Belarus have been elected for a three-year term by the World Health Assembly Executive Board. Members of the executive board each have a duty to advance public health and likewise are expected to uphold universal values as well as human rights. And, of course, this would include providing access for delivery of lifesaving humanitarian supplies, and that would include medical equipment as well. <a id="post-248345-_Hlk73544881"></a>We don’t believe the actions of either Syria or Belarus demonstrate this, and although the U.S. is not currently part of the executive board, we’ll continue to monitor closely the board’s activities and make clear that – U.S. exemptions<sup><a id="post-248345-footnote-ref-3" href="#post-248345-footnote-3"></a></sup> that the board members uphold the highest standards of human rights.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Laura Rozen.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-IRAN1"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you have anything on the latest round of Iran talks in Vienna, which I think are wrapping up right now.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Laura. So the delegation led by Special Envoy for Iran Robert Malley is currently in Vienna, and he’s in Vienna for a fifth round of talks. And any update to share that he actually may come back to Washington for consultations at the end of the week. Outside of that, I’d just underscore that these last few rounds of discussion have actually helped crystallize the choices that need to be made by Iran, and also by us, the United States, in order to achieve a mutual return to compliance of the JCPOA.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Soyoung Kim, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> About North Korea, Deputy Secretary Sherman said today that the U.S. has made its policy known to the DPRK. Can you clarify whether this means the U.S. recently reached out to North Korea again or the separate contact made a few months ago the Department of State had confirmed before? And any response from North Korea?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hi, thanks for the question. I won’t get ahead of Deputy Secretary Sherman’s comments, and any other update we’ll be able to preview at a later time but nothing’s going out today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Said Arikat.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Said’s line has left the queue.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> All right. With that, let’s go to Michel Ghandour, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I have two questions on Iran. Sources in Vienna said that the parties reached a draft agreement. Can you confirm that? And any comment on the fire in Tehran’s refinery today?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks for your question. Nothing to announce. I’m not able to confirm the reports of a fire in Tehran today, but just to underscore what was mentioned previously, our Special Envoy for Iran Robert Malley, he’s currently in Vienna for his fifth round of talks and should be coming back to Washington sometime later this week. Anything beyond that and the decisions and the discussions that have been made, I have nothing to announce.</p>
<p>Looks like we have Said Arikat back in the queue. We’ll go to Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. Thank you, Jalina. And I also want to thank you for mentioning my good friend, Tejinder. May God bless his soul. We will miss him dearly. Jalina, I wanted to ask you about two issues: one, if you have any comment on a report by <em>The Washington Post</em> that Israel is preventing cancer patients from leaving Gaza through the Erez Crossing, if you have any comment on that. I also want to ask about the whereabouts of Mr. Hady Amr right now, and what is next on his agenda? What is he doing? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you for your question, Said. And again, to underscore, we definitely will all miss Tejinder and his spirit, and his vigor and his contributions to not only foreign affairs but journalism as well.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-_Hlk73546868"></a> To your first question on cancer, I certainly look forward to these reports and would have to get back to you specifically on that question. And I’d have to do the same for your question on Hady and what he’s doing. We don’t have anything to announce at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Lara Jakes.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> I do not see Lara Jakes’s line in queue.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Okay. Let’s go to the line of Jennifer Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> It looks like Jennifer’s line is not in queue either.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> All right. Let’s go to the line of Hiba Nasr.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thank you. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. I have one question about Israel. First, we saw during Secretary Blinken’s visit to Israel two weeks ago, he extended an invitation to the Israeli president to visit Washington, and tomorrow that Israeli defense minister is visiting Washington. Did this administration extend an invitation to Prime Minister Netanyahu to visit Washington? And my second question is on Nord Stream 2; yesterday Republicans in the House sent a letter to Secretary Blinken expressing concern over the decision to – over the decision to apply a waiver to some sanctions. Do you have any comments on that?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Hiba, for your first question on extending an invitation – on invites. We have nothing at all to announce on that. And your second question on NS2, I’ll have to take that one back for you.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Claudia Uceda.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-COSTARICA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi. Thanks for taking my questions. I have two questions. First is: How can Costa Rica help stop illegal immigration flow into the U.S.? What is the Secretary looking into specifically? And my second question is about Nicaragua. I would like a reaction to the fact that <a id="post-248345-NICARAGUA"></a>Nicaraguan prosecutors question and are investigating 16 independent journalists, and they are threatening them with a criminal investigation related to money laundering investigation into Violeta Chamorro, who is a prospective candidate. What’s your reaction to that? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you, Claudia. So to your first question, I won’t get into specifics on what Costa Rica should be doing when it comes to the fight for regular migration, but I will say that Costa Rica honestly is a top partner of the United States and it has a strong democracy. And we do have shared values as well as shared commitments. And part of that is championing human rights across the board, and that will be integral into fighting that common challenge together. To your second question, I’ll just say broadly speaking that the United States supports the freedom of the press and will continue to champion that not only in Nicaragua but all over the world.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-IRAN2"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Inaudible) press you a tiny bit more on Iran. In the past, you guys have said that there had been progress in the talks, though a lot of differences remained, and the U.S. and Iran were sort of closer to the start of the talks than they were toward the end of the talks. So do you believe that progress continues to be made? Have those talks stalled? And do you feel that the two sides are gradually inching closer to a resolution? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Well, certainly some progress has been made, and like I said, Rob Malley is in Vienna. He’ll be returning to Washington pretty soon. And again, talks are ongoing. And they will continue at a pace that’s honestly appropriate to address the significance of the issues that are currently on the table being negotiated right now. And I’ll continue to underscore that discussions like this are always thorough. They’re thoughtful. They’re businesslike even though they are indirect. And of course that’s to be expected. This isn’t going to be a quick or easy process.</p>
<p>It looks like we have Jennifer Hansler back on the line, so I’ll take that last question from her.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hello.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Hi, Jennifer.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi, Jalina. Thanks so much for taking my question. Just a little more on Iran, can you confirm that the indirect talks will resume next week? And then separately, has there been any communication with Russia in the wake of the latest cyber-attack on JBS? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks for your questions, Jennifer. To your first one, I don’t have anything to announce of any – for any future talks. And the second question, we’ll have to take that one back for you.</p>
<p>And thank you all very much for joining today’s briefing. I hope you have a wonderful rest of your day.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:29 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
<ol>
<li id="post-248345-footnote-1">internationally <a href="#post-248345-footnote-ref-1">↑</a></li>
<li id="post-248345-footnote-2">innovative <a href="#post-248345-footnote-ref-2">↑</a></li>
<li id="post-248345-footnote-3">expectations <a href="#post-248345-footnote-ref-3">↑</a></li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken At Sembremos Seguridad Site Visit</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-sembremos-seguridad-site-visit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 20:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>San Jose, Costa Rica</p>
<p>Civic Center in Desamparados</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Well, good morning, everyone. <em>Buenos dias a todos.</em> Very, very good to be here, and I thank you so much for the incredibly warm welcome, and I especially thank so many of the young people whose activities I interrupted this morning. I’m grateful for them allowing me to do that. And I am very, very happy to be here in Desamparados to see for myself the truly outstanding work that you’re doing to support your community, especially the young people who are the heart of Costa Rica and its future.</p>
<p>I very much want to thank all of the colleagues from the government who are here today –Minister Soto, Vice Minister Solano, Vice Minister Vargas, Mayor Jimenez, Minister Solano, of course, Minister Salazar. All of you: Thank you, thank you so much for coming out and spending the time as well.</p>
<p>I know from my conversations that the leaders of Costa Rica take great pride in what you do here, and now I can see why. I had read about this project, but seeing it firsthand makes a huge difference.</p>
<p>Oh, okay. Thank you very much. Thank you.</p>
<p>So I just met with members of the youth police brigade. I heard a performance by the municipal band. I saw some extremely impressive skateboarding moves, and I’m glad I didn’t have to try that myself, so thank you. I visited workshops with students learning pottery, violin – and the wonderful young boy and young girl who played violin played one of my son’s favorite songs, so I’ll take that back as well – an amazing display of judo, and we just saw a classroom where young adults are studying for their high school equivalency degrees. In fact, the class that they were teaching – I asked – is on negotiation. So Mr. Minister, I asked if I could sit in and maybe you can sit in with me and maybe we’ll both learn some new skills.</p>
<p>This is an incredibly lively, creative, welcoming space. Everyone who works here – everyone who helps sustain this community – deserves a big round of applause. (Applause.)</p>
<p>Many of the programs here are part of Sembremos Seguridad, an initiative which in English means “We Grow Security,” and it’s now, as I understand it, in 64 municipalities across Costa Rica and will be in 82 by next year.</p>
<p>The United States is very proud to be your partner in “We Grow Security.” This program reflects the aspirations of the people of Costa Rica to live safe and secure lives; to create pathways to opportunity for all people from all neighborhoods; to give children fun and enriching activities in a safe environment, instead of having to choose between staying inside all day or risking being caught up in violence or targeted for recruitment by gangs.</p>
<p>In fact, maybe the hardest choice here: I asked the young man playing violin – there was also a foosball table right next to it – what he preferred and he honestly – he answered me honestly and said, “Foosball.” But that was a – he made the hard decision to also stick with the violin.</p>
<p>“We Grow Security” also creates a new kind of relationship between police and communities, based in partnership, not punishment. It focuses on preventing crime by addressing the root causes, because we know crime does not happen out of nowhere. To stop it, we need to make the right social, economic, educational, and security investments to support communities, to create the conditions for safety, for opportunity, for dignity for all. And we have our own experience in so many of our communities with programs that bring the police closer to the community, because, in fact, they’re part of the community, and the community should be part of them as well.</p>
<p>Best of all – and I heard it and now I’ve seen it – the program works. Crime rates have gone down in places where “We Grow Security” has been implemented – both violent crime and property crime. Communities are now stronger in other ways too. A number of the mayors who are here are able, I think, to have an even stronger relationship with the state. They also have greater connectivity with the police; they’re able to tell the police where to focus their efforts. Police trainers know how to teach officers to build closer ties with residents, with the community. Towns have reclaimed parks and plazas, where neighbors now feel safe gathering together. And of course, COVID has interrupted things a little bit but we’re going to get beyond that, and I think these gatherings will resume. And young people have discovered science, discovered music, discovered sports, jobs programs that make them feel excited and hopeful about their futures. And I think that’s the most important thing of all.</p>
<p>I recently heard two stories that capture the literally transformative power of this program, about two young people that I suspect many of you know – Ariana and Mariano.</p>
<p>Ariana started coming to the center when she was 15 years old – now she’s 18. She joined the cooking program here. She learned how to write a resume. She practiced interviewing for a job. And then thanks to the center, she got a paid internship at a local restaurant. Now Ariana is the first person in her family to have a high school degree. She’s on her way to fulfilling her dream of being a professional chef. And her two little siblings, as I understand it, have enrolled in programs here too. This center has transformed the futures of the entire family. I don’t know if she’s actually here with us today, but I send my greetings and my congratulations.</p>
<p>And Mariano is 22 years old. He’s also been coming to the center since the beginning. He enrolled in skating and guitar lessons. He graduated from high school. He’s now at the University of Costa Rica, studying to become a music teacher. And he has a job here at the center teaching music to hundreds of children, a lot like the one he used to be himself. As we say in the United States, we call that paying it forward – taking some benefit and experience that you’ve received and sharing it with others, making sure that the opportunities that you receive are shared with others.</p>
<p>What all of you have accomplished here – and what Costa Rica has accomplished across the country – I think is a model not just here in Costa Rica, not just in the region, but potentially for the world. And I’m very glad that the Government of Costa Rica will be sharing the lessons of “We Grow Security” with other governments across Central America at a citizen security conference next week.</p>
<p>Because the truth is too many young people in the region live in insecurity. Many are so desperate for a better life that they risk everything – everything: their families, their communities, their town, their language, their culture – they risk all of that to make a very dangerous journey north. People die along the way. They experience violence. And those who do make it to our border are turned around because the border is not open. The United States has made it clear – and I’ll say it again – that people should not make the dangerous journey to our border. But we know it is not enough to say, “Don’t come.” We have to work together to make it safer for people across Central America to stay in their homes and communities – without fear and with hope for a better future for themselves and for their children.</p>
<p>One of our colleagues last night in the meeting that we had with our Central American colleagues talked about the right to remain, and I think we have to give real meaning to that right because people should want to stay and build their own communities. We want to make that possible. I think it’s what people want everywhere. And together, I believe we can make it possible.</p>
<p>Seeing all the young people here today is proof that we can make it possible. And with all the challenges that we face around the world as well as the challenges we face in our work every day, a moment like this is more than anything else heartwarming. It creates a profound sense of hope. It demonstrates the power of community. So thank you for what really has been a very, very special visit. <em>Gracias a todos.</em> (Applause.)</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>San Jose, Costa Rica</p>
<p>Civic Center in Desamparados</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Well, good morning, everyone. <em>Buenos dias a todos.</em> Very, very good to be here, and I thank you so much for the incredibly warm welcome, and I especially thank so many of the young people whose activities I interrupted this morning. I’m grateful for them allowing me to do that. And I am very, very happy to be here in Desamparados to see for myself the truly outstanding work that you’re doing to support your community, especially the young people who are the heart of Costa Rica and its future.</p>
<p>I very much want to thank all of the colleagues from the government who are here today –Minister Soto, Vice Minister Solano, Vice Minister Vargas, Mayor Jimenez, Minister Solano, of course, Minister Salazar. All of you: Thank you, thank you so much for coming out and spending the time as well.</p>
<p>I know from my conversations that the leaders of Costa Rica take great pride in what you do here, and now I can see why. I had read about this project, but seeing it firsthand makes a huge difference.</p>
<p>Oh, okay. Thank you very much. Thank you.</p>
<p>So I just met with members of the youth police brigade. I heard a performance by the municipal band. I saw some extremely impressive skateboarding moves, and I’m glad I didn’t have to try that myself, so thank you. I visited workshops with students learning pottery, violin – and the wonderful young boy and young girl who played violin played one of my son’s favorite songs, so I’ll take that back as well – an amazing display of judo, and we just saw a classroom where young adults are studying for their high school equivalency degrees. In fact, the class that they were teaching – I asked – is on negotiation. So Mr. Minister, I asked if I could sit in and maybe you can sit in with me and maybe we’ll both learn some new skills.</p>
<p>This is an incredibly lively, creative, welcoming space. Everyone who works here – everyone who helps sustain this community – deserves a big round of applause. (Applause.)</p>
<p>Many of the programs here are part of Sembremos Seguridad, an initiative which in English means “We Grow Security,” and it’s now, as I understand it, in 64 municipalities across Costa Rica and will be in 82 by next year.</p>
<p>The United States is very proud to be your partner in “We Grow Security.” This program reflects the aspirations of the people of Costa Rica to live safe and secure lives; to create pathways to opportunity for all people from all neighborhoods; to give children fun and enriching activities in a safe environment, instead of having to choose between staying inside all day or risking being caught up in violence or targeted for recruitment by gangs.</p>
<p>In fact, maybe the hardest choice here: I asked the young man playing violin – there was also a foosball table right next to it – what he preferred and he honestly – he answered me honestly and said, “Foosball.” But that was a – he made the hard decision to also stick with the violin.</p>
<p>“We Grow Security” also creates a new kind of relationship between police and communities, based in partnership, not punishment. It focuses on preventing crime by addressing the root causes, because we know crime does not happen out of nowhere. To stop it, we need to make the right social, economic, educational, and security investments to support communities, to create the conditions for safety, for opportunity, for dignity for all. And we have our own experience in so many of our communities with programs that bring the police closer to the community, because, in fact, they’re part of the community, and the community should be part of them as well.</p>
<p>Best of all – and I heard it and now I’ve seen it – the program works. Crime rates have gone down in places where “We Grow Security” has been implemented – both violent crime and property crime. Communities are now stronger in other ways too. A number of the mayors who are here are able, I think, to have an even stronger relationship with the state. They also have greater connectivity with the police; they’re able to tell the police where to focus their efforts. Police trainers know how to teach officers to build closer ties with residents, with the community. Towns have reclaimed parks and plazas, where neighbors now feel safe gathering together. And of course, COVID has interrupted things a little bit but we’re going to get beyond that, and I think these gatherings will resume. And young people have discovered science, discovered music, discovered sports, jobs programs that make them feel excited and hopeful about their futures. And I think that’s the most important thing of all.</p>
<p>I recently heard two stories that capture the literally transformative power of this program, about two young people that I suspect many of you know – Ariana and Mariano.</p>
<p>Ariana started coming to the center when she was 15 years old – now she’s 18. She joined the cooking program here. She learned how to write a resume. She practiced interviewing for a job. And then thanks to the center, she got a paid internship at a local restaurant. Now Ariana is the first person in her family to have a high school degree. She’s on her way to fulfilling her dream of being a professional chef. And her two little siblings, as I understand it, have enrolled in programs here too. This center has transformed the futures of the entire family. I don’t know if she’s actually here with us today, but I send my greetings and my congratulations.</p>
<p>And Mariano is 22 years old. He’s also been coming to the center since the beginning. He enrolled in skating and guitar lessons. He graduated from high school. He’s now at the University of Costa Rica, studying to become a music teacher. And he has a job here at the center teaching music to hundreds of children, a lot like the one he used to be himself. As we say in the United States, we call that paying it forward – taking some benefit and experience that you’ve received and sharing it with others, making sure that the opportunities that you receive are shared with others.</p>
<p>What all of you have accomplished here – and what Costa Rica has accomplished across the country – I think is a model not just here in Costa Rica, not just in the region, but potentially for the world. And I’m very glad that the Government of Costa Rica will be sharing the lessons of “We Grow Security” with other governments across Central America at a citizen security conference next week.</p>
<p>Because the truth is too many young people in the region live in insecurity. Many are so desperate for a better life that they risk everything – everything: their families, their communities, their town, their language, their culture – they risk all of that to make a very dangerous journey north. People die along the way. They experience violence. And those who do make it to our border are turned around because the border is not open. The United States has made it clear – and I’ll say it again – that people should not make the dangerous journey to our border. But we know it is not enough to say, “Don’t come.” We have to work together to make it safer for people across Central America to stay in their homes and communities – without fear and with hope for a better future for themselves and for their children.</p>
<p>One of our colleagues last night in the meeting that we had with our Central American colleagues talked about the right to remain, and I think we have to give real meaning to that right because people should want to stay and build their own communities. We want to make that possible. I think it’s what people want everywhere. And together, I believe we can make it possible.</p>
<p>Seeing all the young people here today is proof that we can make it possible. And with all the challenges that we face around the world as well as the challenges we face in our work every day, a moment like this is more than anything else heartwarming. It creates a profound sense of hope. It demonstrates the power of community. So thank you for what really has been a very, very special visit. <em>Gracias a todos.</em> (Applause.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rewards for Justice – Reward Offer for Information on Abu Ubaydah Yusuf al-Anabi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/rewards-for-justice-reward-offer-for-information-on-abu-ubaydah-yusuf-al-anabi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 18:43:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248218</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State’s Rewards for Justice program, which is administered by the Diplomatic Security Service, is offering a reward of up to $7 million for information leading to the location or identification of Abu Ubaydah Yusuf al-Anabi, the leader of the terrorist organization al-Qa’ida in the Islamic Maghreb (AQIM).</p>
<p>In November 2020, AQIM announced al-Anabi, an Algerian citizen also known as Yazid Mubarak, as the group’s new leader after AQIM’s previous and first emir, Abdelmalek Droukdel, was killed in June 2020. Al-Anabi has pledged allegiance to al-Qa’ida leader Ayman al-Zawahiri on AQIM’s behalf and is expected to play a role in al-Qa’ida’s global management as Droukdel had done.</p>
<p>Al-Anabi was previously the leader of AQIM’s Council of Notables and served on AQIM’s Shura Council. Al-Anabi has also served as AQIM’s Media Chief.</p>
<p>On September 9, 2015, the U.S. Department of State designated al-Anabi as a Specially Designated Global Terrorist (SDGT) under Executive Order (E.O.) 13224. On February 29, 2016, he was placed on the United Nations (UNSCR 1267) sanctions list.</p>
<p>AQIM is responsible for the abduction and killing of Americans. AQIM, formerly known as the Salafist Group for Preaching and Combat (GSPC), was declared a Specially Designated Global Terrorist on September 23, 2001. The U.S. Department of State designated the group as a Foreign Terrorist Organization on March 27, 2002. In September 2006, GSPC officially joined al-Qa’ida’s terrorist network and re-branded itself as AQIM.</p>
<p>More information about this reward offer is located on the Rewards for Justice website at <a class="external-link" href="https://rewardsforjustice.net/english/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">www.rewardsforjustice.net</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>. We encourage anyone with information on Abu Ubaydah Yusuf al-Anabi to text Rewards for Justice via Signal, Telegram, or WhatsApp at +1-202-702-7843. All information will be kept strictly confidential.</p>
<p>The Rewards for Justice Program is an effective law enforcement tool. Since its inception in 1984, the program has paid in excess of $200 million to more than 200 people who provided actionable information that helped bring terrorists to justice or prevented acts of international terrorism worldwide. Follow us on Twitter at <a class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/rfj_usa" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://twitter.com/rfj_usa</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State’s Rewards for Justice program, which is administered by the Diplomatic Security Service, is offering a reward of up to $7 million for information leading to the location or identification of Abu Ubaydah Yusuf al-Anabi, the leader of the terrorist organization al-Qa’ida in the Islamic Maghreb (AQIM).</p>
<p>In November 2020, AQIM announced al-Anabi, an Algerian citizen also known as Yazid Mubarak, as the group’s new leader after AQIM’s previous and first emir, Abdelmalek Droukdel, was killed in June 2020. Al-Anabi has pledged allegiance to al-Qa’ida leader Ayman al-Zawahiri on AQIM’s behalf and is expected to play a role in al-Qa’ida’s global management as Droukdel had done.</p>
<p>Al-Anabi was previously the leader of AQIM’s Council of Notables and served on AQIM’s Shura Council. Al-Anabi has also served as AQIM’s Media Chief.</p>
<p>On September 9, 2015, the U.S. Department of State designated al-Anabi as a Specially Designated Global Terrorist (SDGT) under Executive Order (E.O.) 13224. On February 29, 2016, he was placed on the United Nations (UNSCR 1267) sanctions list.</p>
<p>AQIM is responsible for the abduction and killing of Americans. AQIM, formerly known as the Salafist Group for Preaching and Combat (GSPC), was declared a Specially Designated Global Terrorist on September 23, 2001. The U.S. Department of State designated the group as a Foreign Terrorist Organization on March 27, 2002. In September 2006, GSPC officially joined al-Qa’ida’s terrorist network and re-branded itself as AQIM.</p>
<p>More information about this reward offer is located on the Rewards for Justice website at <a class="external-link" href="https://rewardsforjustice.net/english/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">www.rewardsforjustice.net</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>. We encourage anyone with information on Abu Ubaydah Yusuf al-Anabi to text Rewards for Justice via Signal, Telegram, or WhatsApp at +1-202-702-7843. All information will be kept strictly confidential.</p>
<p>The Rewards for Justice Program is an effective law enforcement tool. Since its inception in 1984, the program has paid in excess of $200 million to more than 200 people who provided actionable information that helped bring terrorists to justice or prevented acts of international terrorism worldwide. Follow us on Twitter at <a class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/rfj_usa" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://twitter.com/rfj_usa</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Mexican Foreign Secretary Ebrard</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-mexican-foreign-secretary-ebrard-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 17:58:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Mexican Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard today in San Jose, Costa Rica. Secretary Blinken and Secretary Ebrard discussed continued cooperation between the United States and Mexico on a variety of issues to promote the prosperity and security of both nations.  Secretary Blinken thanked Secretary Ebrard for the Mexican government’s continued collaboration on addressing the root causes of irregular migration in the region.  The two leaders also discussed progress towards addressing COVID-19 and economic recovery, as well as issues related to regional democracy and governance, and security.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Mexican Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard today in San Jose, Costa Rica. Secretary Blinken and Secretary Ebrard discussed continued cooperation between the United States and Mexico on a variety of issues to promote the prosperity and security of both nations.  Secretary Blinken thanked Secretary Ebrard for the Mexican government’s continued collaboration on addressing the root causes of irregular migration in the region.  The two leaders also discussed progress towards addressing COVID-19 and economic recovery, as well as issues related to regional democracy and governance, and security.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Public Designation of Five Bulgarian Public Officials Due to Involvement in Significant Corruption</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/public-designation-of-five-bulgarian-public-officials-due-to-involvement-in-significant-corruption/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 15:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, we are announcing the public designation of former Bulgarian public officials Alexander Manolev, Petar Haralampiev, Krasimir Tomov, and Delyan Slavchev Peevski, as well as current Bulgarian public official Ilko Dimitrov Zhelyazkov, due to their involvement in significant corruption.  In their official capacities as Deputy Minister of the Economy, Director of the State Agency for Bulgarians Abroad, and Chief Secretary of the State Agency for Bulgarians Abroad, respectively, Manolev, Haralampiev, and Tomov were involved in corrupt acts that undermined the rule of law and the Bulgarian public’s faith in their government’s democratic institutions and public processes, including by using their political influence and official power for personal benefit.  In his capacity as a member of parliament, Peevski used Zhelyazkov, an official in the National Bureau for Control on Special Intelligence-Gathering Devices, as an intermediary and accomplice to peddle influence and pay bribes to protect himself from public scrutiny and to exert influence over key institutions and sectors in Bulgarian society.</p>
<p>The Department of the Treasury also has designated Peevski, Zhelyazkov and Bulgarian oligarch Vassil Bojkov, along with 64 entities owned and controlled by Bojkov and Peevski, for their roles in public corruption, pursuant to Executive Order 13818, which builds upon and implements the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act.</p>
<p>These designations are made under Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2021.  In addition to Manolev, Haralampiev, Tomov, Zhelyazkov, and Peevski, we are publicly designating Manolev’s wife, Nadya Manoleva, and his children, Alexa, Joanna, and Dimitar; Haralampiev’s wife and son, Veselka Haralampieva and Pavel Haralampiev; Peevski’s minor son and daughter; and Zhelyazkov’s daughters Vania Ilkova Zhelyazkova and Roza Ilkova Zhelyazkova.  This action renders Manolev, Haralampiev, Tomov, Zhelyazkov, and Peevski, and each of their immediate families, ineligible for entry into the United States.</p>
<p>Today’s actions reaffirm our commitment to supporting rule of law and strengthening democratic institutions in Bulgaria.  The United States stands with all Bulgarians whose work drives reforms forward, and the Department will continue to use its authorities to promote accountability for corrupt actors in the region and globally.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact <a href="mailto:INL-PAPD@state.gov">INL-PAPD@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, we are announcing the public designation of former Bulgarian public officials Alexander Manolev, Petar Haralampiev, Krasimir Tomov, and Delyan Slavchev Peevski, as well as current Bulgarian public official Ilko Dimitrov Zhelyazkov, due to their involvement in significant corruption.  In their official capacities as Deputy Minister of the Economy, Director of the State Agency for Bulgarians Abroad, and Chief Secretary of the State Agency for Bulgarians Abroad, respectively, Manolev, Haralampiev, and Tomov were involved in corrupt acts that undermined the rule of law and the Bulgarian public’s faith in their government’s democratic institutions and public processes, including by using their political influence and official power for personal benefit.  In his capacity as a member of parliament, Peevski used Zhelyazkov, an official in the National Bureau for Control on Special Intelligence-Gathering Devices, as an intermediary and accomplice to peddle influence and pay bribes to protect himself from public scrutiny and to exert influence over key institutions and sectors in Bulgarian society.</p>
<p>The Department of the Treasury also has designated Peevski, Zhelyazkov and Bulgarian oligarch Vassil Bojkov, along with 64 entities owned and controlled by Bojkov and Peevski, for their roles in public corruption, pursuant to Executive Order 13818, which builds upon and implements the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act.</p>
<p>These designations are made under Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2021.  In addition to Manolev, Haralampiev, Tomov, Zhelyazkov, and Peevski, we are publicly designating Manolev’s wife, Nadya Manoleva, and his children, Alexa, Joanna, and Dimitar; Haralampiev’s wife and son, Veselka Haralampieva and Pavel Haralampiev; Peevski’s minor son and daughter; and Zhelyazkov’s daughters Vania Ilkova Zhelyazkova and Roza Ilkova Zhelyazkova.  This action renders Manolev, Haralampiev, Tomov, Zhelyazkov, and Peevski, and each of their immediate families, ineligible for entry into the United States.</p>
<p>Today’s actions reaffirm our commitment to supporting rule of law and strengthening democratic institutions in Bulgaria.  The United States stands with all Bulgarians whose work drives reforms forward, and the Department will continue to use its authorities to promote accountability for corrupt actors in the region and globally.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact <a href="mailto:INL-PAPD@state.gov">INL-PAPD@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>G7 Ministers’ Statement on the UN General Assembly Special Session Against Corruption</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/g7-ministers-statement-on-the-un-general-assembly-special-session-against-corruption/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 12:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the G7 ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>We, the G7 Ministers<i>, </i>recognize that corruption is a pressing global challenge. As the UN Convention against Corruption notes, corruption threatens the stability and security of societies, undermining the institutions and values of democracy, ethical values and justice, and jeopardizing sustainable development and the rule of law. Corruption presents serious threats for individuals and societies and often enables other forms of crime, including organized crime and economic crime, including money laundering. These threats have been heightened by COVID-19. As the world continues to recover, it is critical that we do not let corruption threaten our efforts to build back better and address global challenges especially the achievement of the 2030 Sustainable Development Goals.</p>
<p>We are looking forward to the G7 ministerial meeting in September this year, where there will be a discussion on our joint efforts to address corruption.</p>
<p>Corruption is a challenge faced by all countries. Its effects are felt at local, national, and global levels and it is our common and shared responsibility to take action. We as the G7 stand up for an open society, with a strong civil society and free media. We are convinced that these actors are crucial in preventing and combatting corruption. Thus, it is our goal to acknowledge the role of civil society and free media and to promote their freedom and protection in the UNGASS declaration. We recognise that progress will catalyse prosperity, security and development.</p>
<p>G7 Foreign Ministers committed to work collectively to strengthen the foundations of open societies and protect against threats, including corruption, and illicit finance, and the closure of civic space. In this regard, we reaffirm the fundamental role of the UN Convention Against Corruption (UNCAC) and its supporting bodies play in the global fight against corruption.  It is the only legally binding universal instrument on corruption, negotiated on the basis of consensus. The Convention is the cornerstone of our international anti-corruption framework. It forms an integral part of the international anti-corruption architecture which, when fully and effectively implemented, will robustly combat corruption.</p>
<p>We fully support the aims of this Special Session of the General Assembly against corruption to address challenges and measures to more effectively prevent, detect, prosecute, and punish corruption and strengthen international cooperation.</p>
<p>We welcome the adoption of the action-oriented political declaration and commit to achieving its aims. Given our international responsibilities, we as the G7 recognise the need to enhance our efforts to prevent and combat corruption by leading by example. We must continue to make real progress on this issue. We will ensure strong and effective implementation of UNGASS commitments.  To this end, we commit to:</p>
<ol>
<li>Prevention: As the G7, we will work to ensure there are strong measures in place to prevent corruption and other forms of illicit finance to protect our financial centres and deny safe haven to the proceeds of crime. We will support other countries’ efforts to do the same, including anti-corruption safeguards and transparency mechanisms in the delivery of humanitarian aid to ensure that aid, required in times of natural disaster and other emergencies including the COVID-19 pandemic, reaches intended beneficiaries. We also reaffirm our commitment to putting in place measures that promote transparency in the beneficial ownership of legal entities. We further commit to promoting the effective implementation of the Financial Action Task Force (FATF) Standards, the global standard setter for combatting money laundering, terrorist financing and proliferation finance.</li>
<li>Transparency: Comprising many of the world’s most open societies, we note that enhancing transparency benefits citizens and societies and is the foundation on which effective anti-corruption efforts are built. As such, we reaffirm our commitment to implementing measures that afford a high degree of transparency in governance, including measures to enhance transparency in public procurement, and supply chain transparency in the private sector. Consistent with our legal obligations, we will protect and promote access to information for all citizens, including civil society organisations, media and journalists.</li>
<li>Law Enforcement Cooperation/Criminalization:</li>
<li>Foreign bribery: As major centres of private enterprise, we commit to actively enforcing our domestic and foreign bribery laws and ensuring effective implementation of the OECD Anti-Bribery Convention and we urge all G20 countries to do the same.  We recognize the positive impact that incentivizing robust private sector corporate compliance can have on the goal of effectively preventing corruption. We also recognise the corrosive effect of bribe solicitation and call for greater preventive action including awareness raising and training.</li>
<li>Denial of Safe Haven: As some of our financial centres and industries can attract corrupt actors and the proceeds of crime, we commit to strengthening international cooperation to deny safe haven to corrupt individuals and their ill-gotten gains, including through information sharing, and the appropriate use of sanctions and visa restrictions.</li>
<li>International Cooperation and Technical Assistance (TA):  As many of the world’s largest donors, we recognise the role of Official Development Assistance and commit to using our programmes efficiently to build capacities and provide timely, sustainable, adequate and effective technical assistance that meet needs. We call on our partner countries to take a lead in the coordination of TA at country level, including by, publishing needs identified by the implementation review mechanism, involving all relevant stakeholders and, mainstreaming gender in analysis and the delivery of programmes.</li>
<li>Civil Society (including protection of journalists and role of the media): We commit to championing the role of civil society and media freedom as a vital part of upholding democracy and human rights around the world. We condemn all attacks on those who work to expose corruption, including journalists, civil society and individual whistle-blowers, and commit to support and protect those who report and stand up against corruption.</li>
<li>Asset Recovery:  As home to many of the world’s leading financial centres and as recipients of some of the largest volumes of mutual legal assistance requests in the world, we renew our commitment to counter money laundering linked to foreign corruption and to effectively recover proceeds of crime, particularly money laundering proceeds. We further underline the importance of ensuring confiscated stolen assets, when returned, are returned in a transparent and accountable manner, within the framework of the UNCAC, that ultimately benefits those harmed by corruption. We will promote and support international co-operation among relevant law enforcement agencies including in asset recovery.</li>
<li>Rule of Law and Fundamental Freedoms: We recognise that the fight against corruption must be based on respect for the rule of law, support for democratic governance, fundamental freedoms and human rights including due process rights of those accused of and sought for corruption. Rule of law is an essential component to achieve sustainability, to counter abuses of power and to foster an environment needed to effectively achieve the goals of the 2030 Agenda.</li>
<li>Implementation of anti-corruption conventions and other initiatives: As global leaders in the fight against corruption, we recognise the importance of international and regional conventions and other initiatives to fight corruption and emphasise our individual and collective responsibility to step up our efforts towards their effective implementation.</li>
<li>Commit to consulting civil society in our country reviews and promoting their inclusion as observers in subsidiary bodies of the UNCAC and Conference of States Parties.</li>
<li>Call all countries under review by UNCAC to publish their full UNCAC country reports and invite inputs from a wide range of stakeholders.</li>
<li>Support UNODC to prepare a comprehensive report on member state implementation of UNCAC, after completion of the current review phase, and report its findings to the COSP.</li>
<li>Support the effective implementation of existing regional anticorruption frameworks and the FATF standards, including their review mechanisms for compliance.</li>
<li>Urge those who have not ratified the UNCAC to join the 187 other state parties who have done so.</li>
</ol>
<p>We firmly reiterate the importance of strong and unified leadership in addressing corruption. We look to forthcoming processes in relevant fora with close cooperation with other stakeholders such as, the US Summit for Democracy and the Open Government Partnership 10-year Anniversary Summit in South Korea and the UK presidency of the G7 to build on these commitments. We commit to working within these forums, as well as through the G20 Anti-Corruption Working Group, to continue to drive progress on this important agenda.</p>
<p><i>End text.</i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000000" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the G7 ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>We, the G7 Ministers<i>, </i>recognize that corruption is a pressing global challenge. As the UN Convention against Corruption notes, corruption threatens the stability and security of societies, undermining the institutions and values of democracy, ethical values and justice, and jeopardizing sustainable development and the rule of law. Corruption presents serious threats for individuals and societies and often enables other forms of crime, including organized crime and economic crime, including money laundering. These threats have been heightened by COVID-19. As the world continues to recover, it is critical that we do not let corruption threaten our efforts to build back better and address global challenges especially the achievement of the 2030 Sustainable Development Goals.</p>
<p>We are looking forward to the G7 ministerial meeting in September this year, where there will be a discussion on our joint efforts to address corruption.</p>
<p>Corruption is a challenge faced by all countries. Its effects are felt at local, national, and global levels and it is our common and shared responsibility to take action. We as the G7 stand up for an open society, with a strong civil society and free media. We are convinced that these actors are crucial in preventing and combatting corruption. Thus, it is our goal to acknowledge the role of civil society and free media and to promote their freedom and protection in the UNGASS declaration. We recognise that progress will catalyse prosperity, security and development.</p>
<p>G7 Foreign Ministers committed to work collectively to strengthen the foundations of open societies and protect against threats, including corruption, and illicit finance, and the closure of civic space. In this regard, we reaffirm the fundamental role of the UN Convention Against Corruption (UNCAC) and its supporting bodies play in the global fight against corruption.  It is the only legally binding universal instrument on corruption, negotiated on the basis of consensus. The Convention is the cornerstone of our international anti-corruption framework. It forms an integral part of the international anti-corruption architecture which, when fully and effectively implemented, will robustly combat corruption.</p>
<p>We fully support the aims of this Special Session of the General Assembly against corruption to address challenges and measures to more effectively prevent, detect, prosecute, and punish corruption and strengthen international cooperation.</p>
<p>We welcome the adoption of the action-oriented political declaration and commit to achieving its aims. Given our international responsibilities, we as the G7 recognise the need to enhance our efforts to prevent and combat corruption by leading by example. We must continue to make real progress on this issue. We will ensure strong and effective implementation of UNGASS commitments.  To this end, we commit to:</p>
<ol>
<li>Prevention: As the G7, we will work to ensure there are strong measures in place to prevent corruption and other forms of illicit finance to protect our financial centres and deny safe haven to the proceeds of crime. We will support other countries’ efforts to do the same, including anti-corruption safeguards and transparency mechanisms in the delivery of humanitarian aid to ensure that aid, required in times of natural disaster and other emergencies including the COVID-19 pandemic, reaches intended beneficiaries. We also reaffirm our commitment to putting in place measures that promote transparency in the beneficial ownership of legal entities. We further commit to promoting the effective implementation of the Financial Action Task Force (FATF) Standards, the global standard setter for combatting money laundering, terrorist financing and proliferation finance.</li>
<li>Transparency: Comprising many of the world’s most open societies, we note that enhancing transparency benefits citizens and societies and is the foundation on which effective anti-corruption efforts are built. As such, we reaffirm our commitment to implementing measures that afford a high degree of transparency in governance, including measures to enhance transparency in public procurement, and supply chain transparency in the private sector. Consistent with our legal obligations, we will protect and promote access to information for all citizens, including civil society organisations, media and journalists.</li>
<li>Law Enforcement Cooperation/Criminalization:</li>
<li>Foreign bribery: As major centres of private enterprise, we commit to actively enforcing our domestic and foreign bribery laws and ensuring effective implementation of the OECD Anti-Bribery Convention and we urge all G20 countries to do the same.  We recognize the positive impact that incentivizing robust private sector corporate compliance can have on the goal of effectively preventing corruption. We also recognise the corrosive effect of bribe solicitation and call for greater preventive action including awareness raising and training.</li>
<li>Denial of Safe Haven: As some of our financial centres and industries can attract corrupt actors and the proceeds of crime, we commit to strengthening international cooperation to deny safe haven to corrupt individuals and their ill-gotten gains, including through information sharing, and the appropriate use of sanctions and visa restrictions.</li>
<li>International Cooperation and Technical Assistance (TA):  As many of the world’s largest donors, we recognise the role of Official Development Assistance and commit to using our programmes efficiently to build capacities and provide timely, sustainable, adequate and effective technical assistance that meet needs. We call on our partner countries to take a lead in the coordination of TA at country level, including by, publishing needs identified by the implementation review mechanism, involving all relevant stakeholders and, mainstreaming gender in analysis and the delivery of programmes.</li>
<li>Civil Society (including protection of journalists and role of the media): We commit to championing the role of civil society and media freedom as a vital part of upholding democracy and human rights around the world. We condemn all attacks on those who work to expose corruption, including journalists, civil society and individual whistle-blowers, and commit to support and protect those who report and stand up against corruption.</li>
<li>Asset Recovery:  As home to many of the world’s leading financial centres and as recipients of some of the largest volumes of mutual legal assistance requests in the world, we renew our commitment to counter money laundering linked to foreign corruption and to effectively recover proceeds of crime, particularly money laundering proceeds. We further underline the importance of ensuring confiscated stolen assets, when returned, are returned in a transparent and accountable manner, within the framework of the UNCAC, that ultimately benefits those harmed by corruption. We will promote and support international co-operation among relevant law enforcement agencies including in asset recovery.</li>
<li>Rule of Law and Fundamental Freedoms: We recognise that the fight against corruption must be based on respect for the rule of law, support for democratic governance, fundamental freedoms and human rights including due process rights of those accused of and sought for corruption. Rule of law is an essential component to achieve sustainability, to counter abuses of power and to foster an environment needed to effectively achieve the goals of the 2030 Agenda.</li>
<li>Implementation of anti-corruption conventions and other initiatives: As global leaders in the fight against corruption, we recognise the importance of international and regional conventions and other initiatives to fight corruption and emphasise our individual and collective responsibility to step up our efforts towards their effective implementation.</li>
<li>Commit to consulting civil society in our country reviews and promoting their inclusion as observers in subsidiary bodies of the UNCAC and Conference of States Parties.</li>
<li>Call all countries under review by UNCAC to publish their full UNCAC country reports and invite inputs from a wide range of stakeholders.</li>
<li>Support UNODC to prepare a comprehensive report on member state implementation of UNCAC, after completion of the current review phase, and report its findings to the COSP.</li>
<li>Support the effective implementation of existing regional anticorruption frameworks and the FATF standards, including their review mechanisms for compliance.</li>
<li>Urge those who have not ratified the UNCAC to join the 187 other state parties who have done so.</li>
</ol>
<p>We firmly reiterate the importance of strong and unified leadership in addressing corruption. We look to forthcoming processes in relevant fora with close cooperation with other stakeholders such as, the US Summit for Democracy and the Open Government Partnership 10-year Anniversary Summit in South Korea and the UK presidency of the G7 to build on these commitments. We commit to working within these forums, as well as through the G20 Anti-Corruption Working Group, to continue to drive progress on this important agenda.</p>
<p><i>End text.</i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000000" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Foreign Ministers from Central America and Mexico</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-foreign-ministers-from-central-america-and-mexico/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 12:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met yesterday with Foreign Ministers from Costa Rica, Guatemala, Honduras, El Salvador, Nicaragua, Panama, and Mexico in San Jose at a meeting of the Central America Integration System (SICA), the economic and political organization of the region’s states. Secretary Blinken emphasized the importance of strong democratic institutions and a commitment to combatting corruption as well as the need for governments to serve their people.  The leaders discussed the U.S. strategy to address the root causes of irregular migration, including generating economic opportunities for Central Americans and advancing the essential work of reducing violence and addressing the COVID-19 pandemic and climate change. Secretary Blinken underscored, on the 20th anniversary of the InterAmerican Democratic Charter, the need for commitment from all leaders to free and fair elections, good governance, separation of powers, rule of law, respect for human rights, and a level economic playing field.  Secretary Blinken also noted that Central America can be a stronger region if the people and countries cooperate to jointly tackle challenges, including with partners like Mexico. </span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met yesterday with Foreign Ministers from Costa Rica, Guatemala, Honduras, El Salvador, Nicaragua, Panama, and Mexico in San Jose at a meeting of the Central America Integration System (SICA), the economic and political organization of the region’s states. Secretary Blinken emphasized the importance of strong democratic institutions and a commitment to combatting corruption as well as the need for governments to serve their people.  The leaders discussed the U.S. strategy to address the root causes of irregular migration, including generating economic opportunities for Central Americans and advancing the essential work of reducing violence and addressing the COVID-19 pandemic and climate change. Secretary Blinken underscored, on the 20th anniversary of the InterAmerican Democratic Charter, the need for commitment from all leaders to free and fair elections, good governance, separation of powers, rule of law, respect for human rights, and a level economic playing field.  Secretary Blinken also noted that Central America can be a stronger region if the people and countries cooperate to jointly tackle challenges, including with partners like Mexico. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On the 75th Anniversary of the Founding of the Italian Republic</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/on-the-75th-anniversary-of-the-founding-of-the-italian-republic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 04:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248054</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I send sincere congratulations to the people of Italy as they celebrate the 75th anniversary of the founding of the Italian Republic.</p>
<p>On this day, Italy and the United States celebrate our deep and enduring friendship which is based on shared values, including democracy, freedom, free and fair trade, and the rule of law.  Our countries and cultures continue to be enriched by deep people-to-people ties, illustrated by the millions of proud Americans of Italian ancestry.</p>
<p>It was my pleasure to welcome Foreign Minister Di Maio to Washington to commemorate the 160th anniversary of the establishment of U.S.-Italy diplomatic relations.  Our partnership has never been more important, and we look forward to continued close cooperation with Italy, both as NATO Allies and long-standing economic partners, as we address global challenges and build a better, more prosperous world.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I send sincere congratulations to the people of Italy as they celebrate the 75th anniversary of the founding of the Italian Republic.</p>
<p>On this day, Italy and the United States celebrate our deep and enduring friendship which is based on shared values, including democracy, freedom, free and fair trade, and the rule of law.  Our countries and cultures continue to be enriched by deep people-to-people ties, illustrated by the millions of proud Americans of Italian ancestry.</p>
<p>It was my pleasure to welcome Foreign Minister Di Maio to Washington to commemorate the 160th anniversary of the establishment of U.S.-Italy diplomatic relations.  Our partnership has never been more important, and we look forward to continued close cooperation with Italy, both as NATO Allies and long-standing economic partners, as we address global challenges and build a better, more prosperous world.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Costa Rican President Carlos Alvarado at a Joint Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-costa-rican-president-carlos-alvarado-at-a-joint-press-availability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 03:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248062</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>San Jose, Costa Rica</p>
<p>Casa Presidencial</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  Good afternoon.  On behalf of the people of Costa Rica, we would like to give a warm welcome to our presidential home to the Secretary of State of the United States, Mr. Antony Blinken, and his distinguished delegation.  We would like to greet Mr. President, Mr. Carlos Alvarado Quesada, the ministers and leaders of the Republic of Costa Rica, and the media for both sister countries, as well as all those people who are watching this transmission live.</p>
<p>Costa Rica is the first country in Latin America to receive the visit of the United States Secretary of State.  We will now listen to the message given by Mr. President of the Republic of Costa Rica Carlos Alvarado Quesada, who is going to give us a summary of the breadth of the meeting.  Good afternoon, Mr. President.</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ALVARADO:</strong>  Good afternoon, everybody. Good afternoon, Mr. Secretary Antony Blinken and his delegation.  He honors us with his visit here to Costa Rica.  We are very grateful being that it is the first visit to the Western Hemisphere is to Costa Rica.  And along those lines, we have worked on a very important agenda on topics that are very important in the bilateral relationship between the United States and Costa Rica – a relationship that encompasses common values, and that is the most important things: values of democracy, of human rights, and progress, and focused on people; values of believing in multilateralism and the way that countries in this globalized world can coexist peacefully and get ahead as a humanity.</p>
<p>And so along those lines, we have talked about some of the challenges that we face in our bilateral relationship as well as in the region, and how can we take some of the successes that we have achieved together regarding the fight against drugs, regarding environmental sustainability, the fight against climate change and integration processes, or in commerce, or more recently, Costa Rica has become a part of the OCDE, or fighting the pandemic and how to recover after the pandemic so that Costa Rica and the entire region, the countries that conform SICA, can have a fast and satisfactory recovery and together we can face all these problems that our different peoples are suffering, and always keeping in mind – people – how to resolve the different problems for the good of the people.</p>
<p>The conversation has focused on an agenda where the greatest challenge that we face is this relationship that is based on principles and values, this strategic relationship.  How can we take it to the next level, a level of cooperation in bilateral issues in the region as well as in a multilateral fashion?</p>
<p>Once again, I would like to thank Mr. Blinken for his visit.  I am very pleased to meet him.  We have had a very frank and open and fluid conversation, common interests.  And once again, Mr. Secretary, I would like to thank you very much for your visit here in Costa Rica and please know that President Biden and yourself are always welcome to Costa Rica.  We would like to deepen our friendship between our people.  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Thank you very much.  The United States and the United – and Costa Rica have a long history of cooperation (inaudible) in fundamental topics to consolidate liberty and democracy.  The Secretary of State of the United States Antony Blinken will now deliver his message to the Costa Rican people.  Good afternoon.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  <em>Muchas gracias, Senor Presidente.</em>  It’s wonderful to be here.  President Alvarado, thank you for your incredibly warm welcome.  Thank you for a very productive, concrete conversation.  And I have to tell you, the president and I found many common points of interest beyond the responsibilities that we have, including in history and music and many other things.  So it was particularly wonderful to have the opportunity to spend some time with you today.  I’m grateful for that.</p>
<p>I am delighted to be in Costa Rica for my first visit to Central America as Secretary of State.  And it really is no accident that we’re here.  Of course, we have the very important meeting a little later today with our partners in the Central American Integration System led by the foreign minister.  But it’s no accident because Costa Rica and the United States are joined in partnership based on shared values, based on a shared approach to the most pressing issues that our people face today.  And especially now in these moments of great challenge, the United States values our partnerships and values this partnership, and we wanted to make that very clear.</p>
<p>The president was kind enough to invite me to participate in the Central American Integration System ministerial meeting a little bit later, but we also had the opportunity to reflect on ways we can strengthen even more the robust relationship between the United States and Costa Rica.  That relationship is reflected in our cooperation across a range of issues, from development to decarbonization to fighting transnational organized crime, and it demonstrates the way our partnership can help Costa Rica and the United States deliver for people in our respective countries.</p>
<p>And I apologize, I don’t know if you want to do interpretation or not, in which case I can stop and &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>INTERPRETER:</strong>  I am interpreting you simultaneously, sir.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Let me just give you a few quick examples of how we’re doing this.</p>
<p>Our bilateral trade relationship is valued at $11 billion every year.  Forty percent of Costa Rica’s exports come to the United States.  Our investment accounts for approximately 70 percent of all foreign direct investment in Costa Rica.  And that together has created thousands of jobs, tens of thousands of jobs, in both of our countries.  Before the pandemic, more U.S. young people studied here in Costa Rica than anywhere else in the hemisphere, and we’re looking forward to their return when we get through COVID.  We also continue to work together to fight transnational organized crime.  That includes training judges, prosecutors, law enforcement, investing in community-based efforts to give underserved youth access to education and other opportunities.</p>
<p>Tomorrow I’m very much looking forward to visiting one of these neighborhood programs which I’ve read about that’s had tremendous success and I think could be a model for many other countries.  I commend Costa Rica for bringing together leaders of innovative initiatives like this one for a regional citizen security conference next week where participants will share best practices.  The example Costa Rica is setting can be an example for many other countries.</p>
<p>The president and I also had a chance to speak about regional issues.  Let me just highlight quickly three of the most important ones, and I’ll focus on those as well in our engagement a little later with our regional partners.</p>
<p>First, the fate of the people in the United States is more intertwined than ever with our neighbors in Central America.  To effectively confront the biggest challenges we face, like COVID-19, like the climate crisis, like migration, like corruption, regional cooperation is more important than ever.  And these are problems that all of us have to contend with.  It’s not just about the United States or just about Costa Rica.  These are regional challenges and we are more effective when we face them together.</p>
<p>The same is true when it comes to delivering broad-based, inclusive economic growth in our countries that our people expect and deserve.  For too long, the United States and others measured our economic success only by rising GDP or the stock market.  We turned a blind eye to declining opportunity for hardworking people in our societies.  Both of us are determined to put the focus on our people, and the big question we’re both asking ourselves is:  Is what we are doing, is it working for our people?  That’s what motivates us.</p>
<p>President Biden is planning to make an unprecedented $4 billion investment in the region that will focus on helping all people, not just the well-off or the well-connected, much like the investments we’re looking to make at home in the United States.  We think that’s the best way to ensure greater stability and improve the lives of people across the region, which ultimately is in the United States’ interest as well.</p>
<p>And this is my second point:  We have to deliver this growth with equity.  That’s the best way to give people a horizon of hope in their own communities.  Without that, many people are willing to take significant risks at the hands of coyotes to seek out opportunities in other countries, including the United States.</p>
<p>Third, good governance is crucial for confronting the challenges and seizing the opportunities of this moment.  And yet, we meet at a moment when democracy and human rights are being undermined in many parts of the region.  We see this in the erosion of judicial independence, a crackdown on independent media and NGOs, the barring of political opponents, the quashing of anticorruption efforts.  We understand how fragile democracy is.  We’ve experienced setbacks in our own country in recent years.  But that experience has underscored for us just how important it is to shore up the institutions and the norms that safeguard our democracy.  And it’s affirmed that the way to fix our flaws is to address them out in the open, directly, transparently.  That’s the most effective thing we can do.</p>
<p>And that holds for our partners as well.  The United States will partner with governments across the region – left, right, center – to work toward the commitments our countries made nearly 20 years ago when we adopted the Inter-American Democratic Charter.  All we expect of those governments is what their citizens expect: that elected officials are accountable to their people and respect their rights; that they ensure free and fair elections; that they not use their power to punish their critics; and that all of us continue to work to improve the lives of people in our countries in real, concrete ways.</p>
<p>We’re looking forward to hearing how we can continue to work together toward these critical – critically important goals a little later this evening with our partners.  But meanwhile, Mr. President, thank you.  Thank you for your warmth, for your hospitality, and especially for the work that our countries are doing together.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary of the United States.  And now we will hear the media questions, and we are going to start with the first question from the Costa Rican press, by Yessenia Alvarado, journalist for Telenoticias representing the national media.</p>
<p>Good afternoon, Yessenia.  Go ahead, ask your question.</p>
<p><strong>INTERPRETER:</strong>  I can’t hear.  We can’t hear her.  We can’t – we’re sorry, we cannot – the interpreters cannot hear the question.  Yes, there – we are listening to the question from Yessenia Alvarado.  If you could please repeat it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Is there a possibility for Costa Rica to be included in the vaccine donation the United States is planning in July?</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) My other question is for President Alvarado.  We wanted to know if in this meeting you had the opportunity to ask some of the topics that you have been talking about – about vaccines – with us, so that there is more justice, there is no hoarding in the world.  And also in the beginning of May, you had requested the United States – you had requested President Biden if they could lend us some vaccines, and so I would like to know if those topics were able to be addressed.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you to journalist Yessenia Alvarado from Telenoticias, and Mr. Secretary of State, if you could please answer the question.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much for your question.  In short, yes, we did discuss vaccines at length and COVID – and the fight against COVID that we’re joined in more broadly, and let me say this:  I think you heard President Biden a couple of weeks ago announce that we will be making available globally about 80 million vaccine doses that we have access to between now and the end of June.  And in the next week or so – sometime in the next week to two weeks – we will be announcing the process by which we will distribute those vaccines, what the criteria are, how we will do it.  And among other things, we will focus on equity, on the equitable distribution of vaccines; we’ll focus on science; we’ll work in coordination with COVAX; and we will distribute vaccines without political requirements of those receiving them.  And so I expect that there will be news in much more detail in – within the next two weeks.</p>
<p>I would point out that we’ve worked closely with Costa Rica in – over the last year-plus in terms of helping to provide personal protective equipment, medical supplies, mobile hospitals, et cetera, but now we are focused on making available vaccines that we have access to.  And, as I said, within the next two weeks or so I expect we’ll be able to make clear exactly how we’re going to do that.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Mr. President.</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ALVARADO:</strong>  Thank you very much, and yes, that was one of the topics that we talked about in the meeting that we had, our work meeting session.  And Secretary Blinken let us know what he has just shared with you along the lines of the announcement from President Biden, and that soon they will be announcing and explaining how the process is going to be to cooperate on the vaccine issue, and we are grateful already.  And also we are very grateful that throughout the pandemic and since the beginning, the United States has been helping – the United States – with protective equipment.  They have helped with mobile hospitals as well as other installations that have been part of the cooperation in this process, and obviously, the people of Costa Rica is waiting – awaiting the news, the announcements that might come our way according to – regarding the vaccines.  We are accelerating in vaccinating, as we have been doing.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Thank you very much.  Now we’re going to have the first question from the United States press from Mr. Ned Price.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Our first question will go to Tracey Wilkinson of the <em>LA Times</em>.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Hi.  Mr. Secretary, you’ll be meeting later this evening with the ministers of El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras.  What do you want to hear from them that will convince you that they are trustworthy partners in carrying out the agenda that you’ve just described in terms of the money and democratization and good governance?</p>
<p>Secondly, the new State Department budget request has a huge increase in military spending for Central America.  How do you justify that given the backsliding in democracy that you yourself just described?</p>
<p>And for President Alvarado, did you receive assurances from the United States that you will be getting some of the vaccines, that Central America will be getting some of the vaccines?  Are you considering, if not, getting vaccines from China?  And if so – taking them from China – are you worried about what some people say are strings attached that China imposes?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Thank you very much.  Mr. Secretary of State.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  A couple of things.  We – we’re looking forward to the meeting in a short while, and I think first and foremost what we would like to see is a recommitment by all of the countries that signed the Inter-American Charter on Democracy to recommit to its principles, to recommit to the principles and, in effect, the commitments that we each made to our own people: to have strong democratic institutions; to follow the rule of law; to ensure that we have freedom of press, freedom of assembly, freedom to criticize.  Because what we’re seeing in too many places around the world, including in this region, is backsliding from those basic principles and from democracy.  That’s one.</p>
<p>Second, we’re in many of these challenges together.  And just to focus on migration for a minute, the migration – the irregular migration that we’re seeing – doesn’t just affect the United States, it affects virtually every country in the region, including Costa Rica.  And we have a shared responsibility to meet the challenge of irregular migration.  We’re going to talk about that, following on the very important work that Vice President Harris is doing and continues to do.  And here’s what we expect there:  First, we have our own commitments and the own work that we’re doing to make sure that, for example, we strengthen our own asylum system, that we offer the appropriate protections to people, that we increase legal pathways to migration even as we are very clear about the security of our border and the fact that that border is not open.  But we are working to strengthen the system of legal migration to deal effectively with and humanely with those seeking asylum, those who would be refugees.  And other countries have important roles to play in this process too.</p>
<p>But as important – and ultimately, over time, more important – is working together to deal with the drivers of irregular migration, the root causes that compel people to leave everything they know – to leave their homes, their families, their communities, their cultures, their language – because they have – they feel they have no other choice.  And what we need to hear from our partners is a shared commitment with us to address those root causes.  President Biden proposes to make a very historically significant investment of $4 billion over four years to help countries address these roots causes.</p>
<p>And what are they?  We know: governance or the lack thereof, corruption, insecurity, and ultimately opportunity, because at heart people need to have confidence that they can put food on the table, that they can provide for themselves and for their families, and that there’s actually the prospect of a better life going forward.  And that requires some very basic things like jobs, and those jobs often follow from investment.  And investment, in turn, requires that countries and governments take certain steps to make sure that there’s an investment environment that attracts companies, that attracts investors.  And there, again, rule of law, transparency, a predictable judiciary; combating corruption, not encouraging it – all of these things are vital.</p>
<p>So what we hope and expect to hear from our partners are commitments to address all of these issues together.  The United States is willing to make the investments, the United States is determined to work in partnership, and our hope and expectation is that our – other countries will join us in these efforts.  It affects all of us.</p>
<p>And as to the budget, I’ll have an opportunity to address that next week before Congress.  One critical component, of course, is dealing with security challenges that we face, including the question of transnational organized crime, the drugs and the interdiction efforts that are necessary to deal with that, cooperation on terrorism, et cetera.  So there are very good and important reasons for strengthening our security cooperation and the resources that need to follow in order to do that.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter) President Alavarado.</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ALVARADO:</strong>  Thank you for your question.  On the topic of vaccines and vaccinations, I’ve been vocal recently about the necessity of an equitable distribution of vaccines across the globe, and particularly on developing and emerging economies and poor countries which have a small quantity of doses.  That being said, given the announcement of Secretary Blinken, we look forward to what the United States is going to announce in the matter of vaccines.  We hope to be part of that – of the countries that receive that.  Also, given that – as Secretary Blinken has mentioned, it’s going to be following a series of principles to make that happen, so we’ll be looking forward to that announcement.</p>
<p>Also, on other sources of – to receive vaccines, Costa Rica has implemented a principle that we are open to discussions to receive vaccines.  Our condition is that those vaccines that we buy or receive as donations should be qualified by a strict agency, sanitary agency.  And in terms of cooperation, some vaccines, I need – I think we – I think not.  We implement a principle of global cooperation, particularly for the ones that receive cooperation, which is dignity and no strings attached in that sense.  I mean, here we’re talking about saving lives, and we’re – but that doesn’t mean we in receiving a donation will compromise our dignity as a nation in order to receive those.  We welcome the donations for friends, for countries, but those are our terms.  It needs to be vaccines that are guaranteed by an entity, a sanitary entity – strict one – and no strings attached.</p>
<p>And just to briefly follow on the situation on the region, I wanted to point out that we also look forward to having a role to contribute positively in finding solutions, in working together.  We think that Costa Rica can be part of a – can be handy in having solutions for Central America, and we believe that starting now, at this point, is a good point of departure.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter) We will continue with a question from Costa Rica, and it will be Marco Marin from digital media El Observador.  Marco.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  <em>Buenos tardes.  Bienvenido, </em>Secretary Blinken.  (Via interpreter) You were just talking about the importance of having this cooperation, of having the U.S. invest in Costa Rica.  You were talking about jobs.  You were also talking about the state of corruption in the region.  In recent weeks, there has been news here in Costa Rica that two criminal organizations that were dedicated to drug trafficking were able to penetrate higher authorities, the – some of the highest levels of authorities.  At the same time, the economy in Costa Rica has been tanking a little bit given the pandemic and the lack of tourism, mainly.  So now that you’re announcing a $4 billion plan for the next four years, my two questions are:  Is there a specific investment plan from the U.S. towards Costa Rica to increase that 70 percent, to increase the investment the U.S. has in the country, given the fact that Costa Rica is one of the biggest, most important social, economic – social allies that the U.S. has in the region?  And (b), is that cooperation for the – to fight drug trafficking included in that plan?</p>
<p>And (via interpreter) President Alvarado, specifically about the topics of more investment and – which questions did you ask regarding drug traffic?</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Thank you very much.  We will listen to the reply for the Secretary – from the Secretary of State.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>We are very proud of our partnership with Costa Rica across the board in so many different areas, many of which we discussed today with the president, with the cabinet ministers.  And some of that does involve significant assistance from the United States.  Some of that is financial, some of that is technical, but it’s all done in the spirit of partnership.  We have significant results just from the security partnership and the assistance that has gone into that, including in significant interdictions of drugs in recent years.  We are joined together – and I know the President&#8217;s commitment – in combating corruption and dealing with that.  We spoke about the corrosive impact that corruption and also the money that comes with drug trafficking and transnational criminal organizations – the corrosive impact that has on other societies.  We’re both very focused on that.</p>
<p>And as well, we’ve been able to help support the very important work that Costa Rica is doing to host vulnerable migrants, asylum seekers, other forcibly displaced persons.  And we’ve announced very recently some additional assistance.  Vice President Harris announced that a short while ago – more than $28 million for programs inside of Costa Rica.  There are at least a half a dozen areas that we talked about today in which we&#8217;ll be working more – even more closely together, and that will involve no doubt some additional assistance, both financial but also technical experts, bringing our people together.</p>
<p>One of the things I should say that’s so important, and why this partnership is so both important and, frankly, valuable to us, is because Costa Rica enjoys something extraordinary.  And that is an abundance of human resources, the most important resource, really, of any of them; more important than natural resources, more important than the size of your military – and in Costa Rica&#8217;s case, it doesn’t have one – remarkable richness in human resources.  And that’s where working together, connecting our people, connecting our experts, connecting our businesses, connecting our governments – I think that’s where we&#8217;re going to see even stronger work in our partnership together.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>(Via interpreter) President Alvardo, your reply.</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ALVARADO:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Thank you for the question, and yes, that was one of the issues that we talked about.  And if we review – let’s call it the strategic partnership in security issues – throughout the years of our administration, we have seen an increase, more effectiveness, for example, in trafficking – or in interdicting cocaine and marijuana, and that has been a result of the cooperation between both countries.  And in these three years we’ve also seen, before Secretary Blinken came here, the work on the field and the preventative issues to protect communities.  And a third pillar that we talked about the most – and speaking of what you have just mentioned – is everything that has to do with organized crime, because of the amount of money that they handle and how that can hit the different powers in the country, the different powers.  And that was the concern that the leaders of the different powers mentioned here in the statement, the declaration that we gave, and also how can we protect our institutions, our democratic institutions from that imminent risk.  So there is something that is important to say.</p>
<p>I think that there is no country or people who are completely shielded, institutions that are immune to those risks, and precisely because of that is that we need to work in the prevention in those topics.  And certainly, we have a shared concern regarding corruption and regarding the possible penetration, and so that is part of the joint conversations that we have had is in strengthening all of this so that we can strengthen our security issues.  But also something that&#8217;s very important – and we talked about that before with Secretary Blinken – everything has to be done in order to protect our people, our citizens, the people that live in the country.  And that is the way we are focusing our efforts for this pillar and for the other two that we have mentioned: the environment, health, trade – we need to protect our people.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>(Via interpreter) And are we going to continue – we’re going to continue with a question from the United States in order to finish this press conference.  The last question is from the United States media moderated by Mr. Ned Price.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Final question, we’ll go to Cristina Smit of VOA.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Good afternoon, President Alvarado.  Costa Rica in the last few years has noticed an increase in the number of Nicaraguan and Venezuelan populations that reach the country.  In your meeting with the Secretary of State, what did you ask in terms of support to the country to tackle this increase in refugees from these communities?  Do you believe that maybe an alleviation of the sanctions that the U.S. Government has adopted vis-a-vis these two governments could reduce the influx of migrants from these two countries in Costa Rica?<strong> </strong></p>
<p>(In English)<strong> </strong>You think that maybe if the U.S. will alleviate some of the sanctions that has on Nicaragua and Venezuela, the governments, will alleviate some of the migration on – or the exodus that Venezuelans and Nicaraguans are having in their countries?</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ALVARADO:  </strong><em>Mucha gracias</em>.  (Via interpreter) Regarding immigration and refugees, we need to keep in mind that Costa Rica has the condition of being a receiving country, receiving migrants and receiving refugees, more so than being a source of people migrating out of the country.  With the State Department and also with the help of the secretary’s office for migration and refugees, the IOM, there was a conference that I participated in November 2019, and so Costa Rica has deployed a plan to give the best possible attention to that migrating population and the population of refugees.  Of course, it’s a shared interest that we are working with the United States, and particularly the topics that we talked about have to do with the strengthening in the region of those democratic institutions.  That was a very particular emphasis and was the emphasis that we spoke about, is the strengthening in the region of the common principles that we have, such as democracy, respect of human rights, respect of freedom, respect of freedom of the press and others that are – so that’s what we touched upon in the bilateral meeting.  Mr. Secretary of State.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>And a couple of points to address your question.  First, let me start by applauding the remarkable generosity of Costa Rica and the Costa Rican people, including with regard to Venezuelans who have been displaced or made refugees from their country.  Also support for Nicaraguans, of course – there are deep ties between Nicaragua and Costa Rica over many years and a strong community here, but I think we’re seeing a very generous society when it comes to Costa Rica.  And as I noted a short while ago, we have increased the assistance that we’re providing to help care for and attend to the needs of those who are forcibly displaced, who are irregular migrants, including assistance that Vice President Harris announced for Costa Rica just a short while ago of an additional $28 million.</p>
<p>With regard to sanctions, a few things are important.  Sanctions are there for a purpose, and that is to promote accountability for those who engage in human rights abuses, corruption, or undermine democracy.  And unfortunately, that’s exactly what we’ve seen in both Venezuela and Nicaragua.  This is in line with U.S. values; I think it’s in line with Costa Rican values as well.  And it’s always been clear and we’ve always said that sanctions are not permanent.  They’re intended to bring about positive changes in the behavior and actions of a government and the – or individuals, and the removal of sanctions is always available for individuals and entities or governments that take meaningful actions to restore democratic order, to refuse to take part in human rights abuses, to speak out against abuses committed by the authorities, et cetera.</p>
<p>Finally, our sanctions when it comes, for example, to Venezuela, target those responsible for the abuses.  They also have very clear carve-outs in order to ensure that humanitarian assistance and other forms of assistance and aid can continue even as the sanctions are focused on those responsible for undermining human rights and democracy.  And so I think the most important answer to the question when it comes to the suffering of Venezuelans or Nicaraguans is for governments to do the right thing and to actually address the concerns of their people and to actually support democracy, human rights, and the values that all of these countries signed on to, including in the Inter-American Charter for Democracy.  That’s the answer.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Thank you very much.  We would like to say farewell and thank Mr. Secretary of State and their distinguished delegation for their visit to the presidential palace in the Republic of Costa Rica.  You will always be welcome to our country.  Thank you to the media for their presence here and the people who followed this transmission live.  Right now, Mr. President of the country says goodbye to Secretary Blinken.  There&#8217;s also the Foreign Relations Minister Mr. Rodolfo Solano as well as the state minister, health and safety ministers, foreign trade minister.  And immediately, Secretary Blinken, as the foreign relations office in the United States and the United States embassy mentioned, is going to have a meeting with the ministers in SICA along with the Minister of Mexico Mr. Ebrard.  We thank you all for your presence here and for having followed this transmission live.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>San Jose, Costa Rica</p>
<p>Casa Presidencial</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  Good afternoon.  On behalf of the people of Costa Rica, we would like to give a warm welcome to our presidential home to the Secretary of State of the United States, Mr. Antony Blinken, and his distinguished delegation.  We would like to greet Mr. President, Mr. Carlos Alvarado Quesada, the ministers and leaders of the Republic of Costa Rica, and the media for both sister countries, as well as all those people who are watching this transmission live.</p>
<p>Costa Rica is the first country in Latin America to receive the visit of the United States Secretary of State.  We will now listen to the message given by Mr. President of the Republic of Costa Rica Carlos Alvarado Quesada, who is going to give us a summary of the breadth of the meeting.  Good afternoon, Mr. President.</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ALVARADO:</strong>  Good afternoon, everybody. Good afternoon, Mr. Secretary Antony Blinken and his delegation.  He honors us with his visit here to Costa Rica.  We are very grateful being that it is the first visit to the Western Hemisphere is to Costa Rica.  And along those lines, we have worked on a very important agenda on topics that are very important in the bilateral relationship between the United States and Costa Rica – a relationship that encompasses common values, and that is the most important things: values of democracy, of human rights, and progress, and focused on people; values of believing in multilateralism and the way that countries in this globalized world can coexist peacefully and get ahead as a humanity.</p>
<p>And so along those lines, we have talked about some of the challenges that we face in our bilateral relationship as well as in the region, and how can we take some of the successes that we have achieved together regarding the fight against drugs, regarding environmental sustainability, the fight against climate change and integration processes, or in commerce, or more recently, Costa Rica has become a part of the OCDE, or fighting the pandemic and how to recover after the pandemic so that Costa Rica and the entire region, the countries that conform SICA, can have a fast and satisfactory recovery and together we can face all these problems that our different peoples are suffering, and always keeping in mind – people – how to resolve the different problems for the good of the people.</p>
<p>The conversation has focused on an agenda where the greatest challenge that we face is this relationship that is based on principles and values, this strategic relationship.  How can we take it to the next level, a level of cooperation in bilateral issues in the region as well as in a multilateral fashion?</p>
<p>Once again, I would like to thank Mr. Blinken for his visit.  I am very pleased to meet him.  We have had a very frank and open and fluid conversation, common interests.  And once again, Mr. Secretary, I would like to thank you very much for your visit here in Costa Rica and please know that President Biden and yourself are always welcome to Costa Rica.  We would like to deepen our friendship between our people.  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Thank you very much.  The United States and the United – and Costa Rica have a long history of cooperation (inaudible) in fundamental topics to consolidate liberty and democracy.  The Secretary of State of the United States Antony Blinken will now deliver his message to the Costa Rican people.  Good afternoon.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  <em>Muchas gracias, Senor Presidente.</em>  It’s wonderful to be here.  President Alvarado, thank you for your incredibly warm welcome.  Thank you for a very productive, concrete conversation.  And I have to tell you, the president and I found many common points of interest beyond the responsibilities that we have, including in history and music and many other things.  So it was particularly wonderful to have the opportunity to spend some time with you today.  I’m grateful for that.</p>
<p>I am delighted to be in Costa Rica for my first visit to Central America as Secretary of State.  And it really is no accident that we’re here.  Of course, we have the very important meeting a little later today with our partners in the Central American Integration System led by the foreign minister.  But it’s no accident because Costa Rica and the United States are joined in partnership based on shared values, based on a shared approach to the most pressing issues that our people face today.  And especially now in these moments of great challenge, the United States values our partnerships and values this partnership, and we wanted to make that very clear.</p>
<p>The president was kind enough to invite me to participate in the Central American Integration System ministerial meeting a little bit later, but we also had the opportunity to reflect on ways we can strengthen even more the robust relationship between the United States and Costa Rica.  That relationship is reflected in our cooperation across a range of issues, from development to decarbonization to fighting transnational organized crime, and it demonstrates the way our partnership can help Costa Rica and the United States deliver for people in our respective countries.</p>
<p>And I apologize, I don’t know if you want to do interpretation or not, in which case I can stop and &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>INTERPRETER:</strong>  I am interpreting you simultaneously, sir.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Let me just give you a few quick examples of how we’re doing this.</p>
<p>Our bilateral trade relationship is valued at $11 billion every year.  Forty percent of Costa Rica’s exports come to the United States.  Our investment accounts for approximately 70 percent of all foreign direct investment in Costa Rica.  And that together has created thousands of jobs, tens of thousands of jobs, in both of our countries.  Before the pandemic, more U.S. young people studied here in Costa Rica than anywhere else in the hemisphere, and we’re looking forward to their return when we get through COVID.  We also continue to work together to fight transnational organized crime.  That includes training judges, prosecutors, law enforcement, investing in community-based efforts to give underserved youth access to education and other opportunities.</p>
<p>Tomorrow I’m very much looking forward to visiting one of these neighborhood programs which I’ve read about that’s had tremendous success and I think could be a model for many other countries.  I commend Costa Rica for bringing together leaders of innovative initiatives like this one for a regional citizen security conference next week where participants will share best practices.  The example Costa Rica is setting can be an example for many other countries.</p>
<p>The president and I also had a chance to speak about regional issues.  Let me just highlight quickly three of the most important ones, and I’ll focus on those as well in our engagement a little later with our regional partners.</p>
<p>First, the fate of the people in the United States is more intertwined than ever with our neighbors in Central America.  To effectively confront the biggest challenges we face, like COVID-19, like the climate crisis, like migration, like corruption, regional cooperation is more important than ever.  And these are problems that all of us have to contend with.  It’s not just about the United States or just about Costa Rica.  These are regional challenges and we are more effective when we face them together.</p>
<p>The same is true when it comes to delivering broad-based, inclusive economic growth in our countries that our people expect and deserve.  For too long, the United States and others measured our economic success only by rising GDP or the stock market.  We turned a blind eye to declining opportunity for hardworking people in our societies.  Both of us are determined to put the focus on our people, and the big question we’re both asking ourselves is:  Is what we are doing, is it working for our people?  That’s what motivates us.</p>
<p>President Biden is planning to make an unprecedented $4 billion investment in the region that will focus on helping all people, not just the well-off or the well-connected, much like the investments we’re looking to make at home in the United States.  We think that’s the best way to ensure greater stability and improve the lives of people across the region, which ultimately is in the United States’ interest as well.</p>
<p>And this is my second point:  We have to deliver this growth with equity.  That’s the best way to give people a horizon of hope in their own communities.  Without that, many people are willing to take significant risks at the hands of coyotes to seek out opportunities in other countries, including the United States.</p>
<p>Third, good governance is crucial for confronting the challenges and seizing the opportunities of this moment.  And yet, we meet at a moment when democracy and human rights are being undermined in many parts of the region.  We see this in the erosion of judicial independence, a crackdown on independent media and NGOs, the barring of political opponents, the quashing of anticorruption efforts.  We understand how fragile democracy is.  We’ve experienced setbacks in our own country in recent years.  But that experience has underscored for us just how important it is to shore up the institutions and the norms that safeguard our democracy.  And it’s affirmed that the way to fix our flaws is to address them out in the open, directly, transparently.  That’s the most effective thing we can do.</p>
<p>And that holds for our partners as well.  The United States will partner with governments across the region – left, right, center – to work toward the commitments our countries made nearly 20 years ago when we adopted the Inter-American Democratic Charter.  All we expect of those governments is what their citizens expect: that elected officials are accountable to their people and respect their rights; that they ensure free and fair elections; that they not use their power to punish their critics; and that all of us continue to work to improve the lives of people in our countries in real, concrete ways.</p>
<p>We’re looking forward to hearing how we can continue to work together toward these critical – critically important goals a little later this evening with our partners.  But meanwhile, Mr. President, thank you.  Thank you for your warmth, for your hospitality, and especially for the work that our countries are doing together.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary of the United States.  And now we will hear the media questions, and we are going to start with the first question from the Costa Rican press, by Yessenia Alvarado, journalist for Telenoticias representing the national media.</p>
<p>Good afternoon, Yessenia.  Go ahead, ask your question.</p>
<p><strong>INTERPRETER:</strong>  I can’t hear.  We can’t hear her.  We can’t – we’re sorry, we cannot – the interpreters cannot hear the question.  Yes, there – we are listening to the question from Yessenia Alvarado.  If you could please repeat it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Is there a possibility for Costa Rica to be included in the vaccine donation the United States is planning in July?</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) My other question is for President Alvarado.  We wanted to know if in this meeting you had the opportunity to ask some of the topics that you have been talking about – about vaccines – with us, so that there is more justice, there is no hoarding in the world.  And also in the beginning of May, you had requested the United States – you had requested President Biden if they could lend us some vaccines, and so I would like to know if those topics were able to be addressed.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you to journalist Yessenia Alvarado from Telenoticias, and Mr. Secretary of State, if you could please answer the question.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much for your question.  In short, yes, we did discuss vaccines at length and COVID – and the fight against COVID that we’re joined in more broadly, and let me say this:  I think you heard President Biden a couple of weeks ago announce that we will be making available globally about 80 million vaccine doses that we have access to between now and the end of June.  And in the next week or so – sometime in the next week to two weeks – we will be announcing the process by which we will distribute those vaccines, what the criteria are, how we will do it.  And among other things, we will focus on equity, on the equitable distribution of vaccines; we’ll focus on science; we’ll work in coordination with COVAX; and we will distribute vaccines without political requirements of those receiving them.  And so I expect that there will be news in much more detail in – within the next two weeks.</p>
<p>I would point out that we’ve worked closely with Costa Rica in – over the last year-plus in terms of helping to provide personal protective equipment, medical supplies, mobile hospitals, et cetera, but now we are focused on making available vaccines that we have access to.  And, as I said, within the next two weeks or so I expect we’ll be able to make clear exactly how we’re going to do that.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Mr. President.</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ALVARADO:</strong>  Thank you very much, and yes, that was one of the topics that we talked about in the meeting that we had, our work meeting session.  And Secretary Blinken let us know what he has just shared with you along the lines of the announcement from President Biden, and that soon they will be announcing and explaining how the process is going to be to cooperate on the vaccine issue, and we are grateful already.  And also we are very grateful that throughout the pandemic and since the beginning, the United States has been helping – the United States – with protective equipment.  They have helped with mobile hospitals as well as other installations that have been part of the cooperation in this process, and obviously, the people of Costa Rica is waiting – awaiting the news, the announcements that might come our way according to – regarding the vaccines.  We are accelerating in vaccinating, as we have been doing.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Thank you very much.  Now we’re going to have the first question from the United States press from Mr. Ned Price.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Our first question will go to Tracey Wilkinson of the <em>LA Times</em>.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Hi.  Mr. Secretary, you’ll be meeting later this evening with the ministers of El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras.  What do you want to hear from them that will convince you that they are trustworthy partners in carrying out the agenda that you’ve just described in terms of the money and democratization and good governance?</p>
<p>Secondly, the new State Department budget request has a huge increase in military spending for Central America.  How do you justify that given the backsliding in democracy that you yourself just described?</p>
<p>And for President Alvarado, did you receive assurances from the United States that you will be getting some of the vaccines, that Central America will be getting some of the vaccines?  Are you considering, if not, getting vaccines from China?  And if so – taking them from China – are you worried about what some people say are strings attached that China imposes?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Thank you very much.  Mr. Secretary of State.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  A couple of things.  We – we’re looking forward to the meeting in a short while, and I think first and foremost what we would like to see is a recommitment by all of the countries that signed the Inter-American Charter on Democracy to recommit to its principles, to recommit to the principles and, in effect, the commitments that we each made to our own people: to have strong democratic institutions; to follow the rule of law; to ensure that we have freedom of press, freedom of assembly, freedom to criticize.  Because what we’re seeing in too many places around the world, including in this region, is backsliding from those basic principles and from democracy.  That’s one.</p>
<p>Second, we’re in many of these challenges together.  And just to focus on migration for a minute, the migration – the irregular migration that we’re seeing – doesn’t just affect the United States, it affects virtually every country in the region, including Costa Rica.  And we have a shared responsibility to meet the challenge of irregular migration.  We’re going to talk about that, following on the very important work that Vice President Harris is doing and continues to do.  And here’s what we expect there:  First, we have our own commitments and the own work that we’re doing to make sure that, for example, we strengthen our own asylum system, that we offer the appropriate protections to people, that we increase legal pathways to migration even as we are very clear about the security of our border and the fact that that border is not open.  But we are working to strengthen the system of legal migration to deal effectively with and humanely with those seeking asylum, those who would be refugees.  And other countries have important roles to play in this process too.</p>
<p>But as important – and ultimately, over time, more important – is working together to deal with the drivers of irregular migration, the root causes that compel people to leave everything they know – to leave their homes, their families, their communities, their cultures, their language – because they have – they feel they have no other choice.  And what we need to hear from our partners is a shared commitment with us to address those root causes.  President Biden proposes to make a very historically significant investment of $4 billion over four years to help countries address these roots causes.</p>
<p>And what are they?  We know: governance or the lack thereof, corruption, insecurity, and ultimately opportunity, because at heart people need to have confidence that they can put food on the table, that they can provide for themselves and for their families, and that there’s actually the prospect of a better life going forward.  And that requires some very basic things like jobs, and those jobs often follow from investment.  And investment, in turn, requires that countries and governments take certain steps to make sure that there’s an investment environment that attracts companies, that attracts investors.  And there, again, rule of law, transparency, a predictable judiciary; combating corruption, not encouraging it – all of these things are vital.</p>
<p>So what we hope and expect to hear from our partners are commitments to address all of these issues together.  The United States is willing to make the investments, the United States is determined to work in partnership, and our hope and expectation is that our – other countries will join us in these efforts.  It affects all of us.</p>
<p>And as to the budget, I’ll have an opportunity to address that next week before Congress.  One critical component, of course, is dealing with security challenges that we face, including the question of transnational organized crime, the drugs and the interdiction efforts that are necessary to deal with that, cooperation on terrorism, et cetera.  So there are very good and important reasons for strengthening our security cooperation and the resources that need to follow in order to do that.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter) President Alavarado.</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ALVARADO:</strong>  Thank you for your question.  On the topic of vaccines and vaccinations, I’ve been vocal recently about the necessity of an equitable distribution of vaccines across the globe, and particularly on developing and emerging economies and poor countries which have a small quantity of doses.  That being said, given the announcement of Secretary Blinken, we look forward to what the United States is going to announce in the matter of vaccines.  We hope to be part of that – of the countries that receive that.  Also, given that – as Secretary Blinken has mentioned, it’s going to be following a series of principles to make that happen, so we’ll be looking forward to that announcement.</p>
<p>Also, on other sources of – to receive vaccines, Costa Rica has implemented a principle that we are open to discussions to receive vaccines.  Our condition is that those vaccines that we buy or receive as donations should be qualified by a strict agency, sanitary agency.  And in terms of cooperation, some vaccines, I need – I think we – I think not.  We implement a principle of global cooperation, particularly for the ones that receive cooperation, which is dignity and no strings attached in that sense.  I mean, here we’re talking about saving lives, and we’re – but that doesn’t mean we in receiving a donation will compromise our dignity as a nation in order to receive those.  We welcome the donations for friends, for countries, but those are our terms.  It needs to be vaccines that are guaranteed by an entity, a sanitary entity – strict one – and no strings attached.</p>
<p>And just to briefly follow on the situation on the region, I wanted to point out that we also look forward to having a role to contribute positively in finding solutions, in working together.  We think that Costa Rica can be part of a – can be handy in having solutions for Central America, and we believe that starting now, at this point, is a good point of departure.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  (Via interpreter) We will continue with a question from Costa Rica, and it will be Marco Marin from digital media El Observador.  Marco.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  <em>Buenos tardes.  Bienvenido, </em>Secretary Blinken.  (Via interpreter) You were just talking about the importance of having this cooperation, of having the U.S. invest in Costa Rica.  You were talking about jobs.  You were also talking about the state of corruption in the region.  In recent weeks, there has been news here in Costa Rica that two criminal organizations that were dedicated to drug trafficking were able to penetrate higher authorities, the – some of the highest levels of authorities.  At the same time, the economy in Costa Rica has been tanking a little bit given the pandemic and the lack of tourism, mainly.  So now that you’re announcing a $4 billion plan for the next four years, my two questions are:  Is there a specific investment plan from the U.S. towards Costa Rica to increase that 70 percent, to increase the investment the U.S. has in the country, given the fact that Costa Rica is one of the biggest, most important social, economic – social allies that the U.S. has in the region?  And (b), is that cooperation for the – to fight drug trafficking included in that plan?</p>
<p>And (via interpreter) President Alvarado, specifically about the topics of more investment and – which questions did you ask regarding drug traffic?</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Thank you very much.  We will listen to the reply for the Secretary – from the Secretary of State.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>We are very proud of our partnership with Costa Rica across the board in so many different areas, many of which we discussed today with the president, with the cabinet ministers.  And some of that does involve significant assistance from the United States.  Some of that is financial, some of that is technical, but it’s all done in the spirit of partnership.  We have significant results just from the security partnership and the assistance that has gone into that, including in significant interdictions of drugs in recent years.  We are joined together – and I know the President&#8217;s commitment – in combating corruption and dealing with that.  We spoke about the corrosive impact that corruption and also the money that comes with drug trafficking and transnational criminal organizations – the corrosive impact that has on other societies.  We’re both very focused on that.</p>
<p>And as well, we’ve been able to help support the very important work that Costa Rica is doing to host vulnerable migrants, asylum seekers, other forcibly displaced persons.  And we’ve announced very recently some additional assistance.  Vice President Harris announced that a short while ago – more than $28 million for programs inside of Costa Rica.  There are at least a half a dozen areas that we talked about today in which we&#8217;ll be working more – even more closely together, and that will involve no doubt some additional assistance, both financial but also technical experts, bringing our people together.</p>
<p>One of the things I should say that’s so important, and why this partnership is so both important and, frankly, valuable to us, is because Costa Rica enjoys something extraordinary.  And that is an abundance of human resources, the most important resource, really, of any of them; more important than natural resources, more important than the size of your military – and in Costa Rica&#8217;s case, it doesn’t have one – remarkable richness in human resources.  And that’s where working together, connecting our people, connecting our experts, connecting our businesses, connecting our governments – I think that’s where we&#8217;re going to see even stronger work in our partnership together.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>(Via interpreter) President Alvardo, your reply.</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ALVARADO:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Thank you for the question, and yes, that was one of the issues that we talked about.  And if we review – let’s call it the strategic partnership in security issues – throughout the years of our administration, we have seen an increase, more effectiveness, for example, in trafficking – or in interdicting cocaine and marijuana, and that has been a result of the cooperation between both countries.  And in these three years we’ve also seen, before Secretary Blinken came here, the work on the field and the preventative issues to protect communities.  And a third pillar that we talked about the most – and speaking of what you have just mentioned – is everything that has to do with organized crime, because of the amount of money that they handle and how that can hit the different powers in the country, the different powers.  And that was the concern that the leaders of the different powers mentioned here in the statement, the declaration that we gave, and also how can we protect our institutions, our democratic institutions from that imminent risk.  So there is something that is important to say.</p>
<p>I think that there is no country or people who are completely shielded, institutions that are immune to those risks, and precisely because of that is that we need to work in the prevention in those topics.  And certainly, we have a shared concern regarding corruption and regarding the possible penetration, and so that is part of the joint conversations that we have had is in strengthening all of this so that we can strengthen our security issues.  But also something that&#8217;s very important – and we talked about that before with Secretary Blinken – everything has to be done in order to protect our people, our citizens, the people that live in the country.  And that is the way we are focusing our efforts for this pillar and for the other two that we have mentioned: the environment, health, trade – we need to protect our people.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>(Via interpreter) And are we going to continue – we’re going to continue with a question from the United States in order to finish this press conference.  The last question is from the United States media moderated by Mr. Ned Price.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Final question, we’ll go to Cristina Smit of VOA.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Good afternoon, President Alvarado.  Costa Rica in the last few years has noticed an increase in the number of Nicaraguan and Venezuelan populations that reach the country.  In your meeting with the Secretary of State, what did you ask in terms of support to the country to tackle this increase in refugees from these communities?  Do you believe that maybe an alleviation of the sanctions that the U.S. Government has adopted vis-a-vis these two governments could reduce the influx of migrants from these two countries in Costa Rica?<strong> </strong></p>
<p>(In English)<strong> </strong>You think that maybe if the U.S. will alleviate some of the sanctions that has on Nicaragua and Venezuela, the governments, will alleviate some of the migration on – or the exodus that Venezuelans and Nicaraguans are having in their countries?</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ALVARADO:  </strong><em>Mucha gracias</em>.  (Via interpreter) Regarding immigration and refugees, we need to keep in mind that Costa Rica has the condition of being a receiving country, receiving migrants and receiving refugees, more so than being a source of people migrating out of the country.  With the State Department and also with the help of the secretary’s office for migration and refugees, the IOM, there was a conference that I participated in November 2019, and so Costa Rica has deployed a plan to give the best possible attention to that migrating population and the population of refugees.  Of course, it’s a shared interest that we are working with the United States, and particularly the topics that we talked about have to do with the strengthening in the region of those democratic institutions.  That was a very particular emphasis and was the emphasis that we spoke about, is the strengthening in the region of the common principles that we have, such as democracy, respect of human rights, respect of freedom, respect of freedom of the press and others that are – so that’s what we touched upon in the bilateral meeting.  Mr. Secretary of State.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>And a couple of points to address your question.  First, let me start by applauding the remarkable generosity of Costa Rica and the Costa Rican people, including with regard to Venezuelans who have been displaced or made refugees from their country.  Also support for Nicaraguans, of course – there are deep ties between Nicaragua and Costa Rica over many years and a strong community here, but I think we’re seeing a very generous society when it comes to Costa Rica.  And as I noted a short while ago, we have increased the assistance that we’re providing to help care for and attend to the needs of those who are forcibly displaced, who are irregular migrants, including assistance that Vice President Harris announced for Costa Rica just a short while ago of an additional $28 million.</p>
<p>With regard to sanctions, a few things are important.  Sanctions are there for a purpose, and that is to promote accountability for those who engage in human rights abuses, corruption, or undermine democracy.  And unfortunately, that’s exactly what we’ve seen in both Venezuela and Nicaragua.  This is in line with U.S. values; I think it’s in line with Costa Rican values as well.  And it’s always been clear and we’ve always said that sanctions are not permanent.  They’re intended to bring about positive changes in the behavior and actions of a government and the – or individuals, and the removal of sanctions is always available for individuals and entities or governments that take meaningful actions to restore democratic order, to refuse to take part in human rights abuses, to speak out against abuses committed by the authorities, et cetera.</p>
<p>Finally, our sanctions when it comes, for example, to Venezuela, target those responsible for the abuses.  They also have very clear carve-outs in order to ensure that humanitarian assistance and other forms of assistance and aid can continue even as the sanctions are focused on those responsible for undermining human rights and democracy.  And so I think the most important answer to the question when it comes to the suffering of Venezuelans or Nicaraguans is for governments to do the right thing and to actually address the concerns of their people and to actually support democracy, human rights, and the values that all of these countries signed on to, including in the Inter-American Charter for Democracy.  That’s the answer.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>(Via interpreter) Thank you very much.  We would like to say farewell and thank Mr. Secretary of State and their distinguished delegation for their visit to the presidential palace in the Republic of Costa Rica.  You will always be welcome to our country.  Thank you to the media for their presence here and the people who followed this transmission live.  Right now, Mr. President of the country says goodbye to Secretary Blinken.  There&#8217;s also the Foreign Relations Minister Mr. Rodolfo Solano as well as the state minister, health and safety ministers, foreign trade minister.  And immediately, Secretary Blinken, as the foreign relations office in the United States and the United States embassy mentioned, is going to have a meeting with the ministers in SICA along with the Minister of Mexico Mr. Ebrard.  We thank you all for your presence here and for having followed this transmission live.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
