<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 14:01:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Anne Claire Coudray of TF1</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-anne-claire-coudray-of-tf1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 13:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255492</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Quai d’Orsay</p>
<p>Paris, France</p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Via Translation</span></i></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Antony Blinken, good evening.  Thank you very much for agreeing to answer our questions.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s my pleasure.  Thank you.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, when Joe Biden appointed you head of American diplomacy, we, French people, wanted to see it as a sign because you speak absolutely perfect French.  You lived in France, in Paris, when you were a student.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Actually, you are too nice.  In fact, the good thing is that since January, I have had the opportunity to practice my French, especially when collaborating with my friend Jean-Yves Le Drian and with other French colleagues.  Indeed, I came to France at the age of 9.  I stayed until I was 18.  I passed my baccalaureate in Paris and then obviously, I’ve kept in touch ever since.  I even came back when I was 30 before starting a career in government.  I spent two more years in Paris.  I made friends then who are still friends today.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Precisely, it is often said that the French and the Americans are like cousins.  And yet, in recent years, we have also discovered sometimes rather brutally that we do not always think the same.  You are familiar with both ways of thinking.  What would you say? What makes us different sometimes?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes there are differences – nuances, changes in tactics, sometimes on issues.  That’s normal.  It’s normal in a family.  It’s normal with friends.  But, more important than our differences, are the things that bring us together on a deeper level.  That is what I learned in my youth. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are certain values, ​​and we use these words very easily, but there is something behind these values, which we, French and Americans, are trying to implement.  Liberty, equality, fraternity. That means something.  The obligation to support human rights means something.  And most importantly, right now we both live in democracies that are being significantly challenged, both internally and externally.  I think we both see the same challenge: it is to show through our actions, and especially our collective actions, to our citizens, that we can obtain results that will improve their lives and, hopefully, the lives of people around the world.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Antony Blinken, the French people know you too, since you appear in one of the most famous photos of the last ten years, in the Situation room, near Barack Obama during the assault on Osama bin Laden. Would you say that it is the highlight of your career?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s mostly – it’s true that it was a highlight. The strongest? I don’t know, but it’s something that I remember because it was a moment of justice, if you will, because he was the one who led the attack on the United States for seven years. So it was a moment of justice for him, for us and above all, of course, there was some tension because the mission was complicated.  And finally, it was a relief.  But it is indeed an important moment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That being said, I have to tell you that a few weeks after this photo was taken – I am in the background.  We have a TV show, back home, in the evening, with a comedian called David Letterman, you may also know him in France, who showed a close-up of this photo.  One of my government colleagues was on set with him.  He pointed at me, and he said, “Who is that guy in the back of the picture? Is this someone who got lost because he was trying to visit the White House?” So, this moment is both a moment I will remember all my life, and one that will keep things in perspective.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Joe Biden has chosen to travel to Europe for the first time for the sake of the Europeans, with a very strong message: to restore a relationship of trust battered by the four years of Donald Trump’s mandate.  How do you assess the damage caused by this Trump mandate in your mission?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m totally focused on today and tomorrow and the work we need to do together to face the challenges…</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">But when you arrive in a country, you must feel that these four years have been difficult and that they have damaged this relationship between Europe and America.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I remember two things.  First of all, there is a resurgence of confidence between the United States and our closest allies.  And especially with France.  This is very important, and this for a very practical reason.  When we look at the challenges that we’re facing – whether it be the challenge of this COVID pandemic, the climate, the emergence of new technologies that have major impacts on the lives of our citizens – we find that there is no one country acting alone that has the capacity to deal effectively with these problems and there is no wall that we can build high enough, strong enough, to avoid them. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, at the moment, I think there is a need to work together, to find the means to cooperate, to coordinate, to work together.  And that’s why President Biden wanted to focus on our partnerships during the first six months, our alliances with our closest friends, and our oldest ally: France.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Will it be a more balanced relationship? It is true that before, the United States appeared to be masters of the world.  During these four Trump years, there was also a lot of humiliation. The Europeans have been forced to find another balance.  It implies that you can’t go back to the same relationship as before.  Do we need a more balanced relationship?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">In any case, you can’t go back because the world has changed and is changing extremely quickly.  So, above all what we need is to work and face these challenges together and not look back.  And that also involves, maybe, doing things differently. Listening is as important as talking. And I think we have done some important work, especially these last six months, not only in terms of our commitment to our partners and friends, but above all by listening to them – whether it is bilaterally, or in the G7, in NATO, in the EU – and that allows us to establish a joint approach much more effectively.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is one point that we do not quite agree upon, and that is the way you see China.  It is true that you consider this country an adversary, even a commercial enemy, and it is true that it is a tone with which the Europeans take a little distance, in particular Emmanuel Macron.  Do you think we are being naive with China?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">What I’ve seen, especially these last few weeks, is a convergence with regard to the approach to China and I think we see it the same way.  It is, for all our countries, a very complicated relationship that cannot be simplified with a single word or a single sentence.  But what I will say, and I think we have the same point of view with France, is that there are antagonistic elements in the relationship, competitive elements, and elements of cooperation.  And what’s important, whether it’s antagonistic, whether it’s competitive, whether it’s cooperative, is that we will have a lot more impact when we approach China together than if we act alone.  And whether it is at the G7, NATO, or the EU, I think that we have seen a convergence in the declarations and in the decisions that have been made.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And I want to be clear on this, our goal is not to hold China back. It is not to establish a policy against China.  It is to support a free and open system based on the rules and standards that France and the United States established after WWII, and which have served us well.  Because if we don’t have a system where countries act according to the rules, respecting the agreements they have made, the alternative is war. It’s a jungle, it’s the law of the jungle, the survival of the fittest.  And we know from our common history that it leads somewhere we no longer want to go.  So, for us, the idea is to support this system with our allies and partners, not against China, but for a positive vision of the future and relations between countries.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I have two final questions.  There is one area in which our cooperation is unprecedented.  It is the military.  France and the United States are working together, and in particular in the Sahel.  We know that France is imagining another form of engagement in the field.  Will the United States participate in the future coalition, particularly in terms of intelligence and logistical support? How are you prepared to continue helping us in the Sahel?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">The answer is simple.  Quite simply: yes, we have a very important partnership with France in the Sahel.  We have a lot of appreciation for the leadership of France.  I think it makes perfect sense to rework the strategy.  It’s obviously been eight years now since France has been involved with the Sahel and above all, we are trying to strengthen the capacity of our partners on the ground, not only to strengthen their military capacities, but also their capacities for governance and to create a future for their people.  I believe this is the right thing to do, while obviously maintaining what it takes to counter terrorism, and we will do it together.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Joe Biden will receive Angela Merkel on July 15 at the White House.  It is said that the United States chose Germany as their main partner in Europe.  You yourself, a few days ago, said that there was no better friend of America than Germany.  Isn’t that a little surprising given our common history?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">No, our common history is that France is our oldest friend.  When we founded our country &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Independence.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">France was there for our independence.  Something we never forget.  The best symbol of our democracy is the Statue of Liberty from France.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Will there be a meeting between Joe Biden and Emmanuel Macron?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes, absolutely, there has obviously already been a meeting in Cornwall.  A very, very, not only positive, but productive meeting.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do you have an invitation to give to Emmanuel Macron?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am sure and convinced that we will have the opportunity and the chance to receive the President of the French Republic.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thank you very much Antony Blinken for agreeing to answer our questions.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thank you.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Quai d’Orsay</p>
<p>Paris, France</p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Via Translation</span></i></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Antony Blinken, good evening.  Thank you very much for agreeing to answer our questions.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s my pleasure.  Thank you.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, when Joe Biden appointed you head of American diplomacy, we, French people, wanted to see it as a sign because you speak absolutely perfect French.  You lived in France, in Paris, when you were a student.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Actually, you are too nice.  In fact, the good thing is that since January, I have had the opportunity to practice my French, especially when collaborating with my friend Jean-Yves Le Drian and with other French colleagues.  Indeed, I came to France at the age of 9.  I stayed until I was 18.  I passed my baccalaureate in Paris and then obviously, I’ve kept in touch ever since.  I even came back when I was 30 before starting a career in government.  I spent two more years in Paris.  I made friends then who are still friends today.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Precisely, it is often said that the French and the Americans are like cousins.  And yet, in recent years, we have also discovered sometimes rather brutally that we do not always think the same.  You are familiar with both ways of thinking.  What would you say? What makes us different sometimes?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes there are differences – nuances, changes in tactics, sometimes on issues.  That’s normal.  It’s normal in a family.  It’s normal with friends.  But, more important than our differences, are the things that bring us together on a deeper level.  That is what I learned in my youth. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are certain values, ​​and we use these words very easily, but there is something behind these values, which we, French and Americans, are trying to implement.  Liberty, equality, fraternity. That means something.  The obligation to support human rights means something.  And most importantly, right now we both live in democracies that are being significantly challenged, both internally and externally.  I think we both see the same challenge: it is to show through our actions, and especially our collective actions, to our citizens, that we can obtain results that will improve their lives and, hopefully, the lives of people around the world.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Antony Blinken, the French people know you too, since you appear in one of the most famous photos of the last ten years, in the Situation room, near Barack Obama during the assault on Osama bin Laden. Would you say that it is the highlight of your career?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s mostly – it’s true that it was a highlight. The strongest? I don’t know, but it’s something that I remember because it was a moment of justice, if you will, because he was the one who led the attack on the United States for seven years. So it was a moment of justice for him, for us and above all, of course, there was some tension because the mission was complicated.  And finally, it was a relief.  But it is indeed an important moment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That being said, I have to tell you that a few weeks after this photo was taken – I am in the background.  We have a TV show, back home, in the evening, with a comedian called David Letterman, you may also know him in France, who showed a close-up of this photo.  One of my government colleagues was on set with him.  He pointed at me, and he said, “Who is that guy in the back of the picture? Is this someone who got lost because he was trying to visit the White House?” So, this moment is both a moment I will remember all my life, and one that will keep things in perspective.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Joe Biden has chosen to travel to Europe for the first time for the sake of the Europeans, with a very strong message: to restore a relationship of trust battered by the four years of Donald Trump’s mandate.  How do you assess the damage caused by this Trump mandate in your mission?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m totally focused on today and tomorrow and the work we need to do together to face the challenges…</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">But when you arrive in a country, you must feel that these four years have been difficult and that they have damaged this relationship between Europe and America.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I remember two things.  First of all, there is a resurgence of confidence between the United States and our closest allies.  And especially with France.  This is very important, and this for a very practical reason.  When we look at the challenges that we’re facing – whether it be the challenge of this COVID pandemic, the climate, the emergence of new technologies that have major impacts on the lives of our citizens – we find that there is no one country acting alone that has the capacity to deal effectively with these problems and there is no wall that we can build high enough, strong enough, to avoid them. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, at the moment, I think there is a need to work together, to find the means to cooperate, to coordinate, to work together.  And that’s why President Biden wanted to focus on our partnerships during the first six months, our alliances with our closest friends, and our oldest ally: France.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Will it be a more balanced relationship? It is true that before, the United States appeared to be masters of the world.  During these four Trump years, there was also a lot of humiliation. The Europeans have been forced to find another balance.  It implies that you can’t go back to the same relationship as before.  Do we need a more balanced relationship?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">In any case, you can’t go back because the world has changed and is changing extremely quickly.  So, above all what we need is to work and face these challenges together and not look back.  And that also involves, maybe, doing things differently. Listening is as important as talking. And I think we have done some important work, especially these last six months, not only in terms of our commitment to our partners and friends, but above all by listening to them – whether it is bilaterally, or in the G7, in NATO, in the EU – and that allows us to establish a joint approach much more effectively.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is one point that we do not quite agree upon, and that is the way you see China.  It is true that you consider this country an adversary, even a commercial enemy, and it is true that it is a tone with which the Europeans take a little distance, in particular Emmanuel Macron.  Do you think we are being naive with China?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">What I’ve seen, especially these last few weeks, is a convergence with regard to the approach to China and I think we see it the same way.  It is, for all our countries, a very complicated relationship that cannot be simplified with a single word or a single sentence.  But what I will say, and I think we have the same point of view with France, is that there are antagonistic elements in the relationship, competitive elements, and elements of cooperation.  And what’s important, whether it’s antagonistic, whether it’s competitive, whether it’s cooperative, is that we will have a lot more impact when we approach China together than if we act alone.  And whether it is at the G7, NATO, or the EU, I think that we have seen a convergence in the declarations and in the decisions that have been made.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And I want to be clear on this, our goal is not to hold China back. It is not to establish a policy against China.  It is to support a free and open system based on the rules and standards that France and the United States established after WWII, and which have served us well.  Because if we don’t have a system where countries act according to the rules, respecting the agreements they have made, the alternative is war. It’s a jungle, it’s the law of the jungle, the survival of the fittest.  And we know from our common history that it leads somewhere we no longer want to go.  So, for us, the idea is to support this system with our allies and partners, not against China, but for a positive vision of the future and relations between countries.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I have two final questions.  There is one area in which our cooperation is unprecedented.  It is the military.  France and the United States are working together, and in particular in the Sahel.  We know that France is imagining another form of engagement in the field.  Will the United States participate in the future coalition, particularly in terms of intelligence and logistical support? How are you prepared to continue helping us in the Sahel?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">The answer is simple.  Quite simply: yes, we have a very important partnership with France in the Sahel.  We have a lot of appreciation for the leadership of France.  I think it makes perfect sense to rework the strategy.  It’s obviously been eight years now since France has been involved with the Sahel and above all, we are trying to strengthen the capacity of our partners on the ground, not only to strengthen their military capacities, but also their capacities for governance and to create a future for their people.  I believe this is the right thing to do, while obviously maintaining what it takes to counter terrorism, and we will do it together.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Joe Biden will receive Angela Merkel on July 15 at the White House.  It is said that the United States chose Germany as their main partner in Europe.  You yourself, a few days ago, said that there was no better friend of America than Germany.  Isn’t that a little surprising given our common history?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">No, our common history is that France is our oldest friend.  When we founded our country &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Independence.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">France was there for our independence.  Something we never forget.  The best symbol of our democracy is the Statue of Liberty from France.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Will there be a meeting between Joe Biden and Emmanuel Macron?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes, absolutely, there has obviously already been a meeting in Cornwall.  A very, very, not only positive, but productive meeting.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do you have an invitation to give to Emmanuel Macron?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am sure and convinced that we will have the opportunity and the chance to receive the President of the French Republic.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thank you very much Antony Blinken for agreeing to answer our questions.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thank you.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>International Day in Support of Victims of Torture  </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/international-day-in-support-of-victims-of-torture/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 12:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the International Day in Support of Victims of Torture, we recognize the bravery and humanity of victims and survivors of torture around the world.  The absolute prohibition of torture is a human right enshrined in international law.  Since its inception in 1987, 171 countries—including the United States—have become parties to the Convention against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman, or Degrading Treatment or Punishment, which is inspired by Article 5 of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights and its core tenet: “No one shall be subjected to torture or to cruel, inhuman or degrading treatment or punishment.”  </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nevertheless, we continue to see governments using torture and other violations of human rights as tools of ongoing repression against political opponents, members of minority groups and marginalized populations, human rights advocates, and those who simply voice an opinion that these governments do not like.  The United States condemns torture wherever and whenever it occurs and strongly urges governments to abide by their international obligations and end impunity for these crimes.  We also underscore the importance of rehabilitation and transitional justice so victims and survivors can transition from horror to healing.  For this reason, the United States is the largest contributor to the UN Voluntary Fund for Victims of Torture that provides support to survivors and their families. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today is an opportunity for UN Member States, civil society, and individuals around the globe to unite against torture and urge truth, justice, and accountability for perpetrators of this human rights violation.  As long as there are those who would commit torture, the United States will not waver in its commitment to eliminate it. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the International Day in Support of Victims of Torture, we recognize the bravery and humanity of victims and survivors of torture around the world.  The absolute prohibition of torture is a human right enshrined in international law.  Since its inception in 1987, 171 countries—including the United States—have become parties to the Convention against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman, or Degrading Treatment or Punishment, which is inspired by Article 5 of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights and its core tenet: “No one shall be subjected to torture or to cruel, inhuman or degrading treatment or punishment.”  </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nevertheless, we continue to see governments using torture and other violations of human rights as tools of ongoing repression against political opponents, members of minority groups and marginalized populations, human rights advocates, and those who simply voice an opinion that these governments do not like.  The United States condemns torture wherever and whenever it occurs and strongly urges governments to abide by their international obligations and end impunity for these crimes.  We also underscore the importance of rehabilitation and transitional justice so victims and survivors can transition from horror to healing.  For this reason, the United States is the largest contributor to the UN Voluntary Fund for Victims of Torture that provides support to survivors and their families. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today is an opportunity for UN Member States, civil society, and individuals around the globe to unite against torture and urge truth, justice, and accountability for perpetrators of this human rights violation.  As long as there are those who would commit torture, the United States will not waver in its commitment to eliminate it. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Madagascar National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/madagascar-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 04:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Madagascar on the occasion of your Independence Day.</p>
<p>The United States values our strong relationship with Madagascar, which is buttressed by our mutual commitment to addressing climate change and fostering inclusive economic development.  We look forward to continued cooperation to advance democratic good governance, human rights, and sustainable growth for the Malagasy people in the years to come.</p>
<p>Best wishes on this auspicious day!</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Madagascar on the occasion of your Independence Day.</p>
<p>The United States values our strong relationship with Madagascar, which is buttressed by our mutual commitment to addressing climate change and fostering inclusive economic development.  We look forward to continued cooperation to advance democratic good governance, human rights, and sustainable growth for the Malagasy people in the years to come.</p>
<p>Best wishes on this auspicious day!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Killing of Doctors Without Borders Staff in Tigray</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/killing-of-doctors-without-borders-staff-in-tigray/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 22:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We are appalled and deeply saddened to learn about the horrific killings of three Doctors Without Borders staff members in Ethiopia&#8217;s Tigray region today.  Attacks on humanitarian workers are indefensible and must end immediately.  We call for an independent investigation and for the perpetrators to be held accountable for these killings.  The Government of Ethiopia ultimately bears full responsibility for ensuring the safety of humanitarian workers and free and unhindered access to humanitarian assistance.  A cessation of hostilities is essential to ensure that humanitarian workers can safely assist citizens, prevent further suffering, and address the myriad challenges, including famine.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We are appalled and deeply saddened to learn about the horrific killings of three Doctors Without Borders staff members in Ethiopia&#8217;s Tigray region today.  Attacks on humanitarian workers are indefensible and must end immediately.  We call for an independent investigation and for the perpetrators to be held accountable for these killings.  The Government of Ethiopia ultimately bears full responsibility for ensuring the safety of humanitarian workers and free and unhindered access to humanitarian assistance.  A cessation of hostilities is essential to ensure that humanitarian workers can safely assist citizens, prevent further suffering, and address the myriad challenges, including famine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland’s Travel to Paraguay, Panama, and El Salvador</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-of-state-for-political-affairs-victoria-nulands-travel-to-paraguay-panama-and-el-salvador/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 21:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland will travel to Asuncion, Paraguay; Panama City, Panama; and San Salvador, El Salvador, June 27-June 30 with an interagency delegation to engage with senior leaders, government officials, and civil society throughout the region.  Other senior members of the delegation include Acting Assistant Secretary for the Western Hemisphere Julie Chung, Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for the Western Hemisphere Daniel Erikson, National Security Council Director for Central America Megan Oates, and Director of Policy and Plans for U.S. Southern Command Brigadier General Rick Uribe.</p>
<p>During their trip to Paraguay, Under Secretary Nuland and the U.S. delegation will meet with Paraguayan President Mario Abdo Benitez to discuss cooperation to address the challenges posed by the global pandemic and ways to strengthen democracy in our hemisphere.  Under Secretary Nuland and Foreign Minister Acevedo will co-chair the second U.S.-Paraguay Strategic Partnership Dialogue on regional democracy and security, trade and investment, development, and governance cooperation, and the bilateral relationship.</p>
<p>In Panama, the delegation will meet with President Cortizo and Vice Foreign Minister Carrizo.  They will also visit the Panama Canal to speak with Canal Administrator Vásquez.  The meetings will focus on protecting citizens from the pandemic and its economic devastation, mitigating climate change, deepening trade ties, addressing regional migration challenges, and strengthening security in the region.  Under Secretary Nuland and the U.S. delegation will also meet with environmental NGOs and innovation leaders.</p>
<p>During their trip to El Salvador, the U.S. delegation will meet with President Bukele and other political leaders to discuss migration, democracy, and regional goals.  They will also meet with members of civil society and the private sector to discuss the key role these groups play in creating an environment in which all Salvadorans can thrive.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland will travel to Asuncion, Paraguay; Panama City, Panama; and San Salvador, El Salvador, June 27-June 30 with an interagency delegation to engage with senior leaders, government officials, and civil society throughout the region.  Other senior members of the delegation include Acting Assistant Secretary for the Western Hemisphere Julie Chung, Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for the Western Hemisphere Daniel Erikson, National Security Council Director for Central America Megan Oates, and Director of Policy and Plans for U.S. Southern Command Brigadier General Rick Uribe.</p>
<p>During their trip to Paraguay, Under Secretary Nuland and the U.S. delegation will meet with Paraguayan President Mario Abdo Benitez to discuss cooperation to address the challenges posed by the global pandemic and ways to strengthen democracy in our hemisphere.  Under Secretary Nuland and Foreign Minister Acevedo will co-chair the second U.S.-Paraguay Strategic Partnership Dialogue on regional democracy and security, trade and investment, development, and governance cooperation, and the bilateral relationship.</p>
<p>In Panama, the delegation will meet with President Cortizo and Vice Foreign Minister Carrizo.  They will also visit the Panama Canal to speak with Canal Administrator Vásquez.  The meetings will focus on protecting citizens from the pandemic and its economic devastation, mitigating climate change, deepening trade ties, addressing regional migration challenges, and strengthening security in the region.  Under Secretary Nuland and the U.S. delegation will also meet with environmental NGOs and innovation leaders.</p>
<p>During their trip to El Salvador, the U.S. delegation will meet with President Bukele and other political leaders to discuss migration, democracy, and regional goals.  They will also meet with members of civil society and the private sector to discuss the key role these groups play in creating an environment in which all Salvadorans can thrive.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Deputy Secretary Brian P. McKeon Meetings in Atlanta and Clarkston, Georgia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/readout-of-deputy-secretary-brian-p-mckeon-meetings-in-atlanta-and-clarkston-georgia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 21:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On Thursday, June 24, Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brian P. McKeon traveled to Atlanta and Clarkston, Georgia, along with Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration Senior Bureau Official Nancy Izzo Jackson, and met with resettlement agency staff including State Refugee Coordinator Michael Singleton and state and local officials including Mayor of Clarkston Beverly Burks and DeKalb County Commissioners Ted Terry and Lorraine Cochran-Johnson.  The Deputy Secretary also met with refugee services partners including  the Coalition of Refugee Service Agencies (CRSA), Georgia Welcoming Co-Op, Refugee Women Network, Global Village Project (GVP), Positive Growth, the Center for Victims of Torture, as well as other education, employment, and medical specialists.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary McKeon discussed the integral role of resettlement agency staff in the welcoming process for new refugee arrivals, the resources necessary to re-build the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program (USRAP), the integral role local communities play in ensuring the successful integration of refugees, and the valuable contributions refugees make to their new communities and economies.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary McKeon also greeted newly arrived refugees, spoke with resettled refugees about their experiences arriving to their new communities, and underscored the United States’ deep commitment to supporting refugees in the U.S. and around the world.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact PRM at <a href="mailto:prmpress@state.gov">prmpress@state.gov.</a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On Thursday, June 24, Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brian P. McKeon traveled to Atlanta and Clarkston, Georgia, along with Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration Senior Bureau Official Nancy Izzo Jackson, and met with resettlement agency staff including State Refugee Coordinator Michael Singleton and state and local officials including Mayor of Clarkston Beverly Burks and DeKalb County Commissioners Ted Terry and Lorraine Cochran-Johnson.  The Deputy Secretary also met with refugee services partners including  the Coalition of Refugee Service Agencies (CRSA), Georgia Welcoming Co-Op, Refugee Women Network, Global Village Project (GVP), Positive Growth, the Center for Victims of Torture, as well as other education, employment, and medical specialists.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary McKeon discussed the integral role of resettlement agency staff in the welcoming process for new refugee arrivals, the resources necessary to re-build the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program (USRAP), the integral role local communities play in ensuring the successful integration of refugees, and the valuable contributions refugees make to their new communities and economies.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary McKeon also greeted newly arrived refugees, spoke with resettled refugees about their experiences arriving to their new communities, and underscored the United States’ deep commitment to supporting refugees in the U.S. and around the world.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact PRM at <a href="mailto:prmpress@state.gov">prmpress@state.gov.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with French President Macron</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-french-president-macron/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 19:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255156</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with French President Emmanuel Macron in Paris to discuss our shared commitments to Transatlantic security and to the enduring NATO Alliance. Secretary Blinken and President Macron emphasized the shared goals of establishing a stable and predictable relationship with Moscow while addressing Russia’s aggressive and irresponsible behavior, including towards Ukraine. They discussed Transatlantic cooperation in addressing the People’s Republic of China’s coercive economic practices and attempts at undermining the rules-based international order. Secretary Blinken and President Macron exchanged views on countering terrorist threats, supporting democracy, and joint efforts to improve the capacity of our African partners in the Sahel region. They also discussed efforts underway with African and other partners to address the humanitarian and human rights crises in Tigray, while emphasizing the need for Lebanon’s leaders to come together for the good of the Lebanese people.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with French President Emmanuel Macron in Paris to discuss our shared commitments to Transatlantic security and to the enduring NATO Alliance. Secretary Blinken and President Macron emphasized the shared goals of establishing a stable and predictable relationship with Moscow while addressing Russia’s aggressive and irresponsible behavior, including towards Ukraine. They discussed Transatlantic cooperation in addressing the People’s Republic of China’s coercive economic practices and attempts at undermining the rules-based international order. Secretary Blinken and President Macron exchanged views on countering terrorist threats, supporting democracy, and joint efforts to improve the capacity of our African partners in the Sahel region. They also discussed efforts underway with African and other partners to address the humanitarian and human rights crises in Tigray, while emphasizing the need for Lebanon’s leaders to come together for the good of the Lebanese people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-EU-Canada:  Joint Statement on Venezuela</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-eu-canada-joint-statement-on-venezuela/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 19:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255153</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following statement was released by Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken, the EU High Representative for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy Josep Borrell, and Canadian Minister of Foreign Affairs Marc Garneau.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>We remain deeply concerned about the ongoing crisis in Venezuela and its regional and global impact.</p>
<p>The peaceful solution to that deep political, social, and economic crisis has to come from the Venezuelan people themselves through Venezuelan-led, comprehensive negotiations with participation from all stakeholders. A time-bound and comprehensive negotiation process should restore the country’s institutions and allow for all Venezuelans to express themselves politically through credible, inclusive and transparent local, parliamentary, and presidential elections.</p>
<p>We call for the unconditional release of all those unjustly detained for political reasons, the independence of political parties, freedom of expression including for members of the press, and an end to human rights abuses.</p>
<p>We welcome substantive, credible advancements to restore core democratic processes and institutions in Venezuela and are willing to review sanctions policies based on meaningful progress in a comprehensive negotiation.</p>
<p>We call for electoral conditions that abide by international standards for democracy, beginning with the local and regional elections scheduled for November 2021.</p>
<p>We remain committed to addressing the dire humanitarian crisis inside Venezuela and welcome further agreement among all political actors in Venezuela to allow for unfettered access to humanitarian assistance, to include food, medicine, and critical COVID-19 relief supplies.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following statement was released by Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken, the EU High Representative for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy Josep Borrell, and Canadian Minister of Foreign Affairs Marc Garneau.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>We remain deeply concerned about the ongoing crisis in Venezuela and its regional and global impact.</p>
<p>The peaceful solution to that deep political, social, and economic crisis has to come from the Venezuelan people themselves through Venezuelan-led, comprehensive negotiations with participation from all stakeholders. A time-bound and comprehensive negotiation process should restore the country’s institutions and allow for all Venezuelans to express themselves politically through credible, inclusive and transparent local, parliamentary, and presidential elections.</p>
<p>We call for the unconditional release of all those unjustly detained for political reasons, the independence of political parties, freedom of expression including for members of the press, and an end to human rights abuses.</p>
<p>We welcome substantive, credible advancements to restore core democratic processes and institutions in Venezuela and are willing to review sanctions policies based on meaningful progress in a comprehensive negotiation.</p>
<p>We call for electoral conditions that abide by international standards for democracy, beginning with the local and regional elections scheduled for November 2021.</p>
<p>We remain committed to addressing the dire humanitarian crisis inside Venezuela and welcome further agreement among all political actors in Venezuela to allow for unfettered access to humanitarian assistance, to include food, medicine, and critical COVID-19 relief supplies.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Meet and Greet with U.S Mission France Staff</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-meet-and-greet-with-u-s-mission-france-staff/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 19:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Paris, France</p>
<p>U.S. Ambassador’s Residence</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you, thank you.  Thank you all very much.  A lot of familiar faces – I feel like I was just in a photograph with some of you.  It is particularly wonderful to be in this modest house, to be back here and be with all of you.  And I really wanted to have an opportunity to simply say thank you for the great and remarkable work you’ve been doing under incredibly challenging conditions, and I’ll come back to that in a minute.</p>
<p>But let me just start first by thanking Brian for your terrific leadership of this mission over these months.  I’m really grateful for that.  We’ve had an opportunity to spend some time together and get caught up, which I very much appreciate.  And also to Whitney Baird, who is leading our efforts at the OECD, where we had a very good start to the day as well.  So thank you both for your leadership at this particularly important time.</p>
<p>Now, I want to point out a couple of people because one of the things that I like to do every time I have a chance to visit with our missions abroad is spend a moment saying thank you to a particular group.  And that’s our locally employed staff; every single place I go really, as I keep saying, the lifeblood of our missions and the connectivity in so many ways between the missions and the people of the country in which the mission is serving.  There is, I hope with us today either here in person or virtually, the LES of the Year in France, Pedrick Jean Marie Desiree.  Here, right there.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>Working in the Defense Attache office, you’ve facilitated hundreds of DOD movements, ground clearance, as I understand it, for 600 soldiers, 2,000 shipping containers, 110 helicopters.  Thank you, thank you, thank you for your remarkable work and for your partnership with this mission.  We’re grateful to you.  Thank you very much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>We also have some colleagues who’ve been working with the mission for just a little while who have decided nonetheless to retire.  Corinne Foltier-Thonnel Financial Management Center, served the U.S. Government for 40 plus years.  Thank you so much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>Jessica Webster, where are you?  Jessica, Minister Counselor for Economic Affairs, for more than 30 years of service.  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>And Kate Snipes, where are you?  Kate, Agriculture Counselor, more than 20 years of service.  You’ve each in your individual ways been remarkable public servants, and just on behalf of the State Department, on behalf of the country, I want to express my thanks, my appreciation for everything you’ve done.  We’re grateful for it.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>So you’ve all been dealing, as we all have, with that small problem called COVID-19.  And in all seriousness, I know, especially hearing from so many of your colleagues around the world, hearing already from some of you today, the impact that’s had.  And I know it’s had an impact, a profound impact, on a personal level.  Some of you have lost friends or loved ones.  Many of you know people who got sick.  It’s had an impact on a professional level, because we know how challenging it’s made work, made the mission.</p>
<p>But you have persevered with remarkable resilience, with creativity, with determination, and you’ve kept the mission going, and you’ve kept doing what you’re here to do, which is serve the interests of the American people and serve the relationship between the United States and France.</p>
<p>I really want to thank the Health Unit for the work that you’ve done running vaccine clinics.  I’m so proud of the folks in our Health Units from embassy to embassy around the world and the remarkable job that they have done.</p>
<p>The Information Systems people who have helped people telework, find ways to do their jobs, even while they’ve stayed home.  And Community Liaison, who did virtual programming from wine tastings – okay? – to Toddler Story Hour, to Zumba.  That is a pretty good way of keeping morale going and keeping the mission going.</p>
<p>But I also want to say that one of the things that’s been so important in keeping the mission going – and Brian, thank you again for your leadership on this – is that we’re moving forward in a very demonstrable way on policy, too.  And the Political team, working closely here with our French counterparts in fashioning an even stronger joint approach to the challenges posed by Russia and China – tremendous work done there.  I’ve seen some of the work that the Regional Security Office has done, particularly finding new solutions to deal with visa fraud.  The DAO joint military exercises with U.S., French, UK fighter jets, and then work that was done on data security, fighting disinformation.  It’s just a short way of pointing to a couple of examples where the work of this mission not only has gone on but has been producing real results.</p>
<p>Let me say too, Whitney, for the OECD we’ve had just – the first leadership change there in 15 years, and it was a – both a pleasure and important to connect with the new leader and – Mathias Cormann.  We chair the Ministerial Council of the OECD for the 60th anniversary year.  We’ve got a very important, significant agenda.  We started – or I should say continued work on that today, and if all goes well, I look forward to being back here in the fall to do that.  By the way, it’s the first time in a decide that we’ve been in the position of chairing the council.  So a great start, and I think we’ll continue that in October.</p>
<p>But mostly I just want to emphasize one last thing to all of you, and it’s something I’ve been saying pretty much everywhere.  And our friends who follow us around are probably sick of hearing me say it, but I keep repeating it because it really goes to the heart of what the President is all about and what we’re trying to do.  And that is simply the premium that we all have to place on finding ways, including new ways, to cooperate closely with our partners, starting with France.  As I’ve said – again, repeatedly – if you think about it, not a single one of the challenges that we have to deal with, the things that are actually having an impact on the lives of our fellow citizens back home, whether it’s climate change, whether it’s the pandemic, whether it’s the impact of disruptive technologies, not a single one can be dealt with effectively by any one country acting alone, including the United States, for all the power and resources that we have.</p>
<p>And so there really is a greater need than at least I think ever in my own experience to find ways to work with others.  And that’s exactly what you’re doing.  That is precisely the mission that you’re carrying out every single day.  And so I wanted to share that with you just to underscore the point the work that you’re doing matters.  It’s vitally important.  It really is the difference between whether we’re going to fail or whether we’re going to succeed in meeting the challenges of our time and actually making a difference in the lives of our fellow citizens.</p>
<p>So on behalf of the President, on behalf of everyone back home in Washington, thank you, thank you, thank you for what you’re doing every single day.  (Applause.)</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Paris, France</p>
<p>U.S. Ambassador’s Residence</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you, thank you.  Thank you all very much.  A lot of familiar faces – I feel like I was just in a photograph with some of you.  It is particularly wonderful to be in this modest house, to be back here and be with all of you.  And I really wanted to have an opportunity to simply say thank you for the great and remarkable work you’ve been doing under incredibly challenging conditions, and I’ll come back to that in a minute.</p>
<p>But let me just start first by thanking Brian for your terrific leadership of this mission over these months.  I’m really grateful for that.  We’ve had an opportunity to spend some time together and get caught up, which I very much appreciate.  And also to Whitney Baird, who is leading our efforts at the OECD, where we had a very good start to the day as well.  So thank you both for your leadership at this particularly important time.</p>
<p>Now, I want to point out a couple of people because one of the things that I like to do every time I have a chance to visit with our missions abroad is spend a moment saying thank you to a particular group.  And that’s our locally employed staff; every single place I go really, as I keep saying, the lifeblood of our missions and the connectivity in so many ways between the missions and the people of the country in which the mission is serving.  There is, I hope with us today either here in person or virtually, the LES of the Year in France, Pedrick Jean Marie Desiree.  Here, right there.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>Working in the Defense Attache office, you’ve facilitated hundreds of DOD movements, ground clearance, as I understand it, for 600 soldiers, 2,000 shipping containers, 110 helicopters.  Thank you, thank you, thank you for your remarkable work and for your partnership with this mission.  We’re grateful to you.  Thank you very much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>We also have some colleagues who’ve been working with the mission for just a little while who have decided nonetheless to retire.  Corinne Foltier-Thonnel Financial Management Center, served the U.S. Government for 40 plus years.  Thank you so much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>Jessica Webster, where are you?  Jessica, Minister Counselor for Economic Affairs, for more than 30 years of service.  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>And Kate Snipes, where are you?  Kate, Agriculture Counselor, more than 20 years of service.  You’ve each in your individual ways been remarkable public servants, and just on behalf of the State Department, on behalf of the country, I want to express my thanks, my appreciation for everything you’ve done.  We’re grateful for it.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>So you’ve all been dealing, as we all have, with that small problem called COVID-19.  And in all seriousness, I know, especially hearing from so many of your colleagues around the world, hearing already from some of you today, the impact that’s had.  And I know it’s had an impact, a profound impact, on a personal level.  Some of you have lost friends or loved ones.  Many of you know people who got sick.  It’s had an impact on a professional level, because we know how challenging it’s made work, made the mission.</p>
<p>But you have persevered with remarkable resilience, with creativity, with determination, and you’ve kept the mission going, and you’ve kept doing what you’re here to do, which is serve the interests of the American people and serve the relationship between the United States and France.</p>
<p>I really want to thank the Health Unit for the work that you’ve done running vaccine clinics.  I’m so proud of the folks in our Health Units from embassy to embassy around the world and the remarkable job that they have done.</p>
<p>The Information Systems people who have helped people telework, find ways to do their jobs, even while they’ve stayed home.  And Community Liaison, who did virtual programming from wine tastings – okay? – to Toddler Story Hour, to Zumba.  That is a pretty good way of keeping morale going and keeping the mission going.</p>
<p>But I also want to say that one of the things that’s been so important in keeping the mission going – and Brian, thank you again for your leadership on this – is that we’re moving forward in a very demonstrable way on policy, too.  And the Political team, working closely here with our French counterparts in fashioning an even stronger joint approach to the challenges posed by Russia and China – tremendous work done there.  I’ve seen some of the work that the Regional Security Office has done, particularly finding new solutions to deal with visa fraud.  The DAO joint military exercises with U.S., French, UK fighter jets, and then work that was done on data security, fighting disinformation.  It’s just a short way of pointing to a couple of examples where the work of this mission not only has gone on but has been producing real results.</p>
<p>Let me say too, Whitney, for the OECD we’ve had just – the first leadership change there in 15 years, and it was a – both a pleasure and important to connect with the new leader and – Mathias Cormann.  We chair the Ministerial Council of the OECD for the 60th anniversary year.  We’ve got a very important, significant agenda.  We started – or I should say continued work on that today, and if all goes well, I look forward to being back here in the fall to do that.  By the way, it’s the first time in a decide that we’ve been in the position of chairing the council.  So a great start, and I think we’ll continue that in October.</p>
<p>But mostly I just want to emphasize one last thing to all of you, and it’s something I’ve been saying pretty much everywhere.  And our friends who follow us around are probably sick of hearing me say it, but I keep repeating it because it really goes to the heart of what the President is all about and what we’re trying to do.  And that is simply the premium that we all have to place on finding ways, including new ways, to cooperate closely with our partners, starting with France.  As I’ve said – again, repeatedly – if you think about it, not a single one of the challenges that we have to deal with, the things that are actually having an impact on the lives of our fellow citizens back home, whether it’s climate change, whether it’s the pandemic, whether it’s the impact of disruptive technologies, not a single one can be dealt with effectively by any one country acting alone, including the United States, for all the power and resources that we have.</p>
<p>And so there really is a greater need than at least I think ever in my own experience to find ways to work with others.  And that’s exactly what you’re doing.  That is precisely the mission that you’re carrying out every single day.  And so I wanted to share that with you just to underscore the point the work that you’re doing matters.  It’s vitally important.  It really is the difference between whether we’re going to fail or whether we’re going to succeed in meeting the challenges of our time and actually making a difference in the lives of our fellow citizens.</p>
<p>So on behalf of the President, on behalf of everyone back home in Washington, thank you, thank you, thank you for what you’re doing every single day.  (Applause.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman’s Engagements with Tunisian Government Officials and Civil Society Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-of-state-wendy-shermans-engagements-with-tunisian-government-officials-and-civil-society-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 18:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=255143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman held a virtual meeting with Tunisian Prime Minister Hichem Mechichi to discuss the U.S.-Tunisian bilateral relationship. They discussed promoting democracy, protecting human rights, addressing economic challenges, and working together to respond to the COVID-19 global pandemic. Deputy Secretary Sherman also met virtually with women leaders from Tunisian civil society and spoke with Tunisian media professionals. In her meetings, Deputy Secretary Sherman reiterated the United States’ unwavering support to the Tunisian government and the Tunisian people at a crucial time in the country’s democratic transition 10 years after the revolution. The United States views Tunisia as a partner of choice, grounded in our shared commitment to democratic values, and to promoting regional security.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman held a virtual meeting with Tunisian Prime Minister Hichem Mechichi to discuss the U.S.-Tunisian bilateral relationship. They discussed promoting democracy, protecting human rights, addressing economic challenges, and working together to respond to the COVID-19 global pandemic. Deputy Secretary Sherman also met virtually with women leaders from Tunisian civil society and spoke with Tunisian media professionals. In her meetings, Deputy Secretary Sherman reiterated the United States’ unwavering support to the Tunisian government and the Tunisian people at a crucial time in the country’s democratic transition 10 years after the revolution. The United States views Tunisia as a partner of choice, grounded in our shared commitment to democratic values, and to promoting regional security.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
