<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 20:29:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Travel to Israel, the West Bank, Morocco, and Algeria</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-israel-the-west-bank-morocco-and-algeria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 15:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Israel, the West Bank, Morocco, and Algeria March 26-30 to consult with partners on a range of regional and global priorities, including the Russian government’s war on Ukraine, Iran’s destabilizing activities, the Abraham Accords and normalization agreements with Israel, Israeli-Palestinian relations, and preserving the possibility of a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, among other topics.</p>
<p>The Secretary will start his trip in Israel and the West Bank.  There, he will meet with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett, Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Yair Lapid, Defense Minister Benny Gantz, and Israeli President Isaac Herzog.  The Secretary will underscore the unwavering U.S. commitment to Israel’s security, engage on Israeli-Palestinian issues, and discuss regional and global challenges with his counterparts in the Israeli government.  The Secretary will also meet with President Mahmoud Abbas in Ramallah as well as with representatives of Palestinian civil society.  In these meetings, the Secretary will emphasize the importance of strengthening U.S.-Palestinian relations, and advancing freedom, security and prosperity for the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>In Morocco, he will meet with Foreign Minister Nasser Bourita and other senior government officials to exchange views on regional issues and bilateral cooperation, as well as advancing human rights and fundamental freedoms.  The Secretary will also meet with exceptional Moroccan alumnae of U.S.-sponsored exchange programs.</p>
<p>While in Rabat, the Secretary will also meet Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan to discuss regional security and international developments.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Algiers, Algeria for meetings with President Abdelmadjid Tebboune and Foreign Minister Ramtane Lamamra to discuss regional security and stability, commercial cooperation, advancing human rights and fundamental freedoms, and other areas of mutual concern.  The Secretary will also officially inaugurate the United States as the Country of Honor at the Algiers International Trade Fair, the largest trade show of its kind in Africa. He will meet with U.S. business representatives in Algeria to discuss deepening economic ties and promoting U.S.-Algeria trade and investment.</p>
<p>During the course of his trip, the Secretary will emphasize to all of the foreign leaders he meets that the United States stands in solidarity with the government and people of Ukraine in the face of the Kremlin’s aggression.  We will continue to work closely with our allies and partners to impose further costs on Putin and his enablers if Putin does not change course.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Israel, the West Bank, Morocco, and Algeria March 26-30 to consult with partners on a range of regional and global priorities, including the Russian government’s war on Ukraine, Iran’s destabilizing activities, the Abraham Accords and normalization agreements with Israel, Israeli-Palestinian relations, and preserving the possibility of a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, among other topics.</p>
<p>The Secretary will start his trip in Israel and the West Bank.  There, he will meet with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett, Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Yair Lapid, Defense Minister Benny Gantz, and Israeli President Isaac Herzog.  The Secretary will underscore the unwavering U.S. commitment to Israel’s security, engage on Israeli-Palestinian issues, and discuss regional and global challenges with his counterparts in the Israeli government.  The Secretary will also meet with President Mahmoud Abbas in Ramallah as well as with representatives of Palestinian civil society.  In these meetings, the Secretary will emphasize the importance of strengthening U.S.-Palestinian relations, and advancing freedom, security and prosperity for the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>In Morocco, he will meet with Foreign Minister Nasser Bourita and other senior government officials to exchange views on regional issues and bilateral cooperation, as well as advancing human rights and fundamental freedoms.  The Secretary will also meet with exceptional Moroccan alumnae of U.S.-sponsored exchange programs.</p>
<p>While in Rabat, the Secretary will also meet Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan to discuss regional security and international developments.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Algiers, Algeria for meetings with President Abdelmadjid Tebboune and Foreign Minister Ramtane Lamamra to discuss regional security and stability, commercial cooperation, advancing human rights and fundamental freedoms, and other areas of mutual concern.  The Secretary will also officially inaugurate the United States as the Country of Honor at the Algiers International Trade Fair, the largest trade show of its kind in Africa. He will meet with U.S. business representatives in Algeria to discuss deepening economic ties and promoting U.S.-Algeria trade and investment.</p>
<p>During the course of his trip, the Secretary will emphasize to all of the foreign leaders he meets that the United States stands in solidarity with the government and people of Ukraine in the face of the Kremlin’s aggression.  We will continue to work closely with our allies and partners to impose further costs on Putin and his enablers if Putin does not change course.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sanctioning Additional Members of Russia’s Duma, Russian Elites, Bank Board Members, and Defense Entities</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/sanctioning-additional-members-of-russias-duma-russian-elites-bank-board-members-and-defense-entities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 14:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327483</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>President Putin’s war continues to inflict horror and widespread suffering on the people of Ukraine.  At the same time, in Russia, the State Duma continues to use its legislative power to target domestic dissenters and political opponents, disrupt the free flow of information, and restrict the human rights and fundamental freedoms of the citizens of Russia.  The United States today is designating 328 members of the Russian State Duma, in addition to the 12 members designated on March 11.  These members supported the Kremlin’s violations of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, including through treaties recognizing the self-proclaimed independence of Russian-proxy controlled areas of eastern Ukraine, the so-called Donetsk People’s Republic (DNR) and Luhansk People’s Republic (LNR).</p>
<p>The United States is also designating the Russian State Duma in its entirety, as well as Herman Gref, the head of Sberbank and a close ally of Putin.  Today’s actions are taken pursuant to Executive Order 14024, which authorizes sanctions against Russia for its harmful foreign activities.  These actions complement the ongoing efforts of our allies and partners to hold to account enablers of this unconscionable war of choice against Ukraine and its people.</p>
<p>As part of this action, we are also targeting multiple Russian elites to include their properties and family members.  Notably, this will include 17 members of the board of PJSC Sovcombank, a designated entity.  These executives join the growing list of individuals associated with blocked Russian financial institutions that now also find themselves subject to U.S. sanctions.  Additionally, OOO Volga Group is being re-designated for having operated in the financial services sector of the Russian Federation economy.  As a result, Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko, the owner of OOO Volga Group, will also be re-designated along with OOO Transoil, which Timchenko owns.  Timchenko’s wife, Elena Petrovna Timchenko, and daughter, Natalya Browning, will now also be designated along with Ksenia Gennadevna Frank, a board member of OOO Transoil and her spouse Gleb Sergeevich Frank.</p>
<p>Additionally, the United States is taking action to impose additional severe costs on Russia’s defense establishment.  This includes designating multiple defense-related entities and one associated individual.  An important component of today’s action is designating Russian defense companies that are part of Russia’s defense-industrial base and that produce weapons that have been used in Russia’s war of aggression.  By cutting off dozens of Russian defense companies from the U.S. financial system, today’s action will have a deep and long-lasting effect on Russia’s defense-industrial base.  We are targeting, and will continue to target, the suppliers of Russia’s war effort and, in turn, their supply chain.</p>
<p>With our partners and allies, the United States aims to strike the heart of Russia’s ability to engage in warfare and carry out aggression against other countries, including Ukraine.  We will continue to impose costs until Putin ends this unprovoked war against Ukraine.  We call on those closest to Putin to cease and publicly condemn this cold-blooded war, which has caused the unconscionable death of hundreds of civilians, including children, and the largest humanitarian catastrophe in Europe since the Second World War.</p>
<p>At the same time, we continue to support Ukraine, including through an additional $800 million in security assistance, bringing the total U.S. security assistance committed to Ukraine to $1 billion in the past two weeks and more than $2 billion since last March.  The United States is the largest single country donor of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  We stand with the brave people of Ukraine who are demonstrating incredible courage and fierce determination in defending their country against the Kremlin’s aggression.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of State <a href="https://www.state.gov/targeting-elites-of-the-russian-federation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMjQuNTUzODUzNDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvdGFyZ2V0aW5nLWVsaXRlcy1vZi10aGUtcnVzc2lhbi1mZWRlcmF0aW9uLyJ9.KrvJ1UrgUvrd-WX5rkiryY6WVkQwUFL1jDgyv2xd2kk/s/1006560560/br/128587650881-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1648215944405000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0lNcuXrCzLv4RkpfaqfLWR">Fact Sheet</a> and the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0677" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>President Putin’s war continues to inflict horror and widespread suffering on the people of Ukraine.  At the same time, in Russia, the State Duma continues to use its legislative power to target domestic dissenters and political opponents, disrupt the free flow of information, and restrict the human rights and fundamental freedoms of the citizens of Russia.  The United States today is designating 328 members of the Russian State Duma, in addition to the 12 members designated on March 11.  These members supported the Kremlin’s violations of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, including through treaties recognizing the self-proclaimed independence of Russian-proxy controlled areas of eastern Ukraine, the so-called Donetsk People’s Republic (DNR) and Luhansk People’s Republic (LNR).</p>
<p>The United States is also designating the Russian State Duma in its entirety, as well as Herman Gref, the head of Sberbank and a close ally of Putin.  Today’s actions are taken pursuant to Executive Order 14024, which authorizes sanctions against Russia for its harmful foreign activities.  These actions complement the ongoing efforts of our allies and partners to hold to account enablers of this unconscionable war of choice against Ukraine and its people.</p>
<p>As part of this action, we are also targeting multiple Russian elites to include their properties and family members.  Notably, this will include 17 members of the board of PJSC Sovcombank, a designated entity.  These executives join the growing list of individuals associated with blocked Russian financial institutions that now also find themselves subject to U.S. sanctions.  Additionally, OOO Volga Group is being re-designated for having operated in the financial services sector of the Russian Federation economy.  As a result, Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko, the owner of OOO Volga Group, will also be re-designated along with OOO Transoil, which Timchenko owns.  Timchenko’s wife, Elena Petrovna Timchenko, and daughter, Natalya Browning, will now also be designated along with Ksenia Gennadevna Frank, a board member of OOO Transoil and her spouse Gleb Sergeevich Frank.</p>
<p>Additionally, the United States is taking action to impose additional severe costs on Russia’s defense establishment.  This includes designating multiple defense-related entities and one associated individual.  An important component of today’s action is designating Russian defense companies that are part of Russia’s defense-industrial base and that produce weapons that have been used in Russia’s war of aggression.  By cutting off dozens of Russian defense companies from the U.S. financial system, today’s action will have a deep and long-lasting effect on Russia’s defense-industrial base.  We are targeting, and will continue to target, the suppliers of Russia’s war effort and, in turn, their supply chain.</p>
<p>With our partners and allies, the United States aims to strike the heart of Russia’s ability to engage in warfare and carry out aggression against other countries, including Ukraine.  We will continue to impose costs until Putin ends this unprovoked war against Ukraine.  We call on those closest to Putin to cease and publicly condemn this cold-blooded war, which has caused the unconscionable death of hundreds of civilians, including children, and the largest humanitarian catastrophe in Europe since the Second World War.</p>
<p>At the same time, we continue to support Ukraine, including through an additional $800 million in security assistance, bringing the total U.S. security assistance committed to Ukraine to $1 billion in the past two weeks and more than $2 billion since last March.  The United States is the largest single country donor of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  We stand with the brave people of Ukraine who are demonstrating incredible courage and fierce determination in defending their country against the Kremlin’s aggression.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of State <a href="https://www.state.gov/targeting-elites-of-the-russian-federation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMjQuNTUzODUzNDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvdGFyZ2V0aW5nLWVsaXRlcy1vZi10aGUtcnVzc2lhbi1mZWRlcmF0aW9uLyJ9.KrvJ1UrgUvrd-WX5rkiryY6WVkQwUFL1jDgyv2xd2kk/s/1006560560/br/128587650881-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1648215944405000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0lNcuXrCzLv4RkpfaqfLWR">Fact Sheet</a> and the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0677" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Targeting Elites of the Russian Federation</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/targeting-elites-of-the-russian-federation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 13:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327474</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, the Department of State and the Department of the Treasury have taken additional sweeping actions as part of our response, together with our allies and partners, to the Russian Federation’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war against Ukraine.  We are steadfast in our commitment to ensuring Russia pays a severe economic and diplomatic price for its further invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>The Department of State is targeting elites close to Putin, along with their property, holdings, and family members.  Today, the Department has designated:</p>
<ul>
<li>Dmitry Vladimirovich Gusev, Mikhail Lvovich Kuchment, Anatoly Alexandrovich Bravverman, Ilya Borisovich Brodskiy, Aleksey Leonidovich Fisun, Dmitry Vladimirovich Khotimskiy, Sergey Vladimirovich Khotimskiy, Mikhail Vasilyevich Klyukin, Mikhal Olegovich Avtukhov, Albert Alexandrovich Boris, Dmitry Vladimirovich Beryshnikov, Elena Alexandrovna Cherstvova, Sergey Nikolaevich Bondarovich, Oleg Alexandrovich Mashtalyar, Alexey Valeryevich Panferov, Irina Nikoalyevna Kashina, and Joel Raymon Lautier
<ul>
<li>These individuals are each being designated for being or having been a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of PJSC Sovcombank, pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>OOO Volga Group
<ul>
<li>OOO Volga Group is being designated for operating or having operated in the financial services sector of the Russian Federation economy, pursuant to Section 1(a)(i) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko
<ul>
<li>Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko is being designated for being or having been a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of OOO Volga Group, pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>OOO Transoil
<ul>
<li>OOO Transoil is being designated for being owned or controlled by, or having acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko, pursuant to section 1(a)(vii) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Ksenia Gennadevna Frank
<ul>
<li>Ksenia Gennadevna Frank is being designated for being or having been a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of OOO Transoil, pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Gleb Sergeevich Frank
<ul>
<li>Gleb Sergeevich Frank is being designated for being the spouse of Ksenia Gennadevna Frank, pursuant to Section 1(a)(v) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Elena Petrovna Timchenko and Natalya Browning
<ul>
<li>Elena Petrovna Timchenko and Natalya Browning are each being designated for being a spouse or adult child of Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko, pursuant to Section 1(a)(v) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The Yacht <em>Lena </em>
<ul>
<li>The Yacht <em>Lena</em> is property in which Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko has an interest and is therefore blocked property.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>SANCTIONS IMPLICATIONS </strong></p>
<p>The Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) will add the individuals, entities, and property above to the list of Specially Designated Nationals and Blocked Persons.  As a result of today’s action, all property and interests in property of the individuals and entities above that are in the United States or in the possession or control of U.S. persons are blocked and must be reported to OFAC.  In addition, any entities that are owned, directly or indirectly, 50 percent or more, by one or more blocked persons are also blocked.  All transactions by U.S. persons or within (or transiting) the United States that involve any property or interests in property of designated or otherwise blocked persons are prohibited unless authorized by a general or specific license issued by OFAC or exempt.  These prohibitions include the making of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services by, to, or for the benefit of any blocked person and the receipt of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services from any such person.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, the Department of State and the Department of the Treasury have taken additional sweeping actions as part of our response, together with our allies and partners, to the Russian Federation’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war against Ukraine.  We are steadfast in our commitment to ensuring Russia pays a severe economic and diplomatic price for its further invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>The Department of State is targeting elites close to Putin, along with their property, holdings, and family members.  Today, the Department has designated:</p>
<ul>
<li>Dmitry Vladimirovich Gusev, Mikhail Lvovich Kuchment, Anatoly Alexandrovich Bravverman, Ilya Borisovich Brodskiy, Aleksey Leonidovich Fisun, Dmitry Vladimirovich Khotimskiy, Sergey Vladimirovich Khotimskiy, Mikhail Vasilyevich Klyukin, Mikhal Olegovich Avtukhov, Albert Alexandrovich Boris, Dmitry Vladimirovich Beryshnikov, Elena Alexandrovna Cherstvova, Sergey Nikolaevich Bondarovich, Oleg Alexandrovich Mashtalyar, Alexey Valeryevich Panferov, Irina Nikoalyevna Kashina, and Joel Raymon Lautier
<ul>
<li>These individuals are each being designated for being or having been a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of PJSC Sovcombank, pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>OOO Volga Group
<ul>
<li>OOO Volga Group is being designated for operating or having operated in the financial services sector of the Russian Federation economy, pursuant to Section 1(a)(i) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko
<ul>
<li>Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko is being designated for being or having been a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of OOO Volga Group, pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>OOO Transoil
<ul>
<li>OOO Transoil is being designated for being owned or controlled by, or having acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko, pursuant to section 1(a)(vii) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Ksenia Gennadevna Frank
<ul>
<li>Ksenia Gennadevna Frank is being designated for being or having been a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of OOO Transoil, pursuant to section 1(a)(iii)(C) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Gleb Sergeevich Frank
<ul>
<li>Gleb Sergeevich Frank is being designated for being the spouse of Ksenia Gennadevna Frank, pursuant to Section 1(a)(v) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Elena Petrovna Timchenko and Natalya Browning
<ul>
<li>Elena Petrovna Timchenko and Natalya Browning are each being designated for being a spouse or adult child of Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko, pursuant to Section 1(a)(v) of E.O. 14024.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The Yacht <em>Lena </em>
<ul>
<li>The Yacht <em>Lena</em> is property in which Gennady Nikolayevich Timchenko has an interest and is therefore blocked property.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>SANCTIONS IMPLICATIONS </strong></p>
<p>The Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) will add the individuals, entities, and property above to the list of Specially Designated Nationals and Blocked Persons.  As a result of today’s action, all property and interests in property of the individuals and entities above that are in the United States or in the possession or control of U.S. persons are blocked and must be reported to OFAC.  In addition, any entities that are owned, directly or indirectly, 50 percent or more, by one or more blocked persons are also blocked.  All transactions by U.S. persons or within (or transiting) the United States that involve any property or interests in property of designated or otherwise blocked persons are prohibited unless authorized by a general or specific license issued by OFAC or exempt.  These prohibitions include the making of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services by, to, or for the benefit of any blocked person and the receipt of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services from any such person.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Democratic People&#8217;s Republic of Korea&#8217;s Ballistic Missile Launch</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-democratic-peoples-republic-of-koreas-ballistic-missile-launch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 12:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>The United States condemns the DPRK&#8217;s ballistic missile launch. Like the DPRK&#8217;s other escalatory tests this year, including at least two intercontinental ballistic missiles, this launch is a clear violation of multiple United Nations Security Council resolutions, and demonstrates the threat the DPRK&#8217;s unlawful weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs pose to the DPRK&#8217;s neighbors and the region as a whole. We stand with the international community to call on the DPRK to refrain from further provocations and engage in sustained and substantive dialogue. Our commitment to the defense of the Republic of Korea and Japan remains ironclad. We have been and will continue to coordinate closely with our allies and partners to address the threats posed by the DPRK, and to advance our shared objective of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>The United States condemns the DPRK&#8217;s ballistic missile launch. Like the DPRK&#8217;s other escalatory tests this year, including at least two intercontinental ballistic missiles, this launch is a clear violation of multiple United Nations Security Council resolutions, and demonstrates the threat the DPRK&#8217;s unlawful weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs pose to the DPRK&#8217;s neighbors and the region as a whole. We stand with the international community to call on the DPRK to refrain from further provocations and engage in sustained and substantive dialogue. Our commitment to the defense of the Republic of Korea and Japan remains ironclad. We have been and will continue to coordinate closely with our allies and partners to address the threats posed by the DPRK, and to advance our shared objective of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with South African Foreign Minister Pandor</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-south-african-foreign-minister-pandor-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 01:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with South African Minister of International Relations and Cooperation Naledi Pandor about the ongoing humanitarian crisis in Ukraine and the negative ripple effects it is already causing to food security and prices for essential commodities in Africa.  The Secretary underscored U.S. views on the need for a clear, unified international response to President Putin’s invasion to put a swift end to this crisis.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with South African Minister of International Relations and Cooperation Naledi Pandor about the ongoing humanitarian crisis in Ukraine and the negative ripple effects it is already causing to food security and prices for essential commodities in Africa.  The Secretary underscored U.S. views on the need for a clear, unified international response to President Putin’s invasion to put a swift end to this crisis.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women and Girls’ Education in Afghanistan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/women-and-girls-education-in-afghanistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Education is a human right, and the United States rejects the Taliban’s excuses for reversing their commitment to the people of Afghanistan that all Afghans would be able to return to school at all levels today.  As many girls and women were returning to secondary classrooms across the country, they were told to go home until further notice.  We stand with Afghan girls and their families, who see education as a path to realizing the full potential of Afghanistan&#8217;s society and economy.</p>
<p>This decision by the Taliban, if it is not swiftly reversed, will profoundly harm the Afghan people, the country’s prospects for economic growth, and the Taliban’s ambition to improve their relations with the international community.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Education is a human right, and the United States rejects the Taliban’s excuses for reversing their commitment to the people of Afghanistan that all Afghans would be able to return to school at all levels today.  As many girls and women were returning to secondary classrooms across the country, they were told to go home until further notice.  We stand with Afghan girls and their families, who see education as a path to realizing the full potential of Afghanistan&#8217;s society and economy.</p>
<p>This decision by the Taliban, if it is not swiftly reversed, will profoundly harm the Afghan people, the country’s prospects for economic growth, and the Taliban’s ambition to improve their relations with the international community.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with New Zealand Secretary of Foreign Affairs and Trade Seed</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-new-zealand-secretary-of-foreign-affairs-and-trade-seed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 22:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with New Zealand Secretary of Foreign Affairs and Trade Chris Seed and New Zealand Secretary of Defence Andrew Bridgman in Washington, D.C.  Deputy Secretary Sherman condemned Putin’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war against Ukraine and thanked Secretary Seed for New Zealand’s strong response, including new sanctions legislation.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">The Deputy Secretary reiterated the U.S. commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific and underscored that New Zealand is a critical partner to achieving this vision. The Deputy Secretary also commended New Zealand’s leadership on ending the COVID-19 pandemic and combating climate change and discussed how the U.S. and New Zealand can collaborate on both issues.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with New Zealand Secretary of Foreign Affairs and Trade Chris Seed and New Zealand Secretary of Defence Andrew Bridgman in Washington, D.C.  Deputy Secretary Sherman condemned Putin’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war against Ukraine and thanked Secretary Seed for New Zealand’s strong response, including new sanctions legislation.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">The Deputy Secretary reiterated the U.S. commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific and underscored that New Zealand is a critical partner to achieving this vision. The Deputy Secretary also commended New Zealand’s leadership on ending the COVID-19 pandemic and combating climate change and discussed how the U.S. and New Zealand can collaborate on both issues.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Estonian Foreign Ministry Secretary General Vseviov</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-estonian-foreign-ministry-secretary-general-vseviov/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 19:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Estonian Foreign Ministry Secretary General Jonatan Vseviov today in Washington, DC.  They discussed efforts to provide additional assistance to Ukraine and raise the costs on the Russian government for Putin’s premeditated, unjustified, and unprovoked war against Ukraine.  They also noted the strength of the bilateral partnership and explored ways to deepen cooperation.  The Deputy Secretary reaffirmed U.S. commitment to the security of our NATO Allies.  She underscored U.S. support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and called on Putin to end his war of choice.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Estonian Foreign Ministry Secretary General Jonatan Vseviov today in Washington, DC.  They discussed efforts to provide additional assistance to Ukraine and raise the costs on the Russian government for Putin’s premeditated, unjustified, and unprovoked war against Ukraine.  They also noted the strength of the bilateral partnership and explored ways to deepen cooperation.  The Deputy Secretary reaffirmed U.S. commitment to the security of our NATO Allies.  She underscored U.S. support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and called on Putin to end his war of choice.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>War Crimes by Russia’s Forces in Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/war-crimes-by-russias-forces-in-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 17:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=327143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p align="left">Since launching his unprovoked and unjust war of choice, Russian President Vladimir Putin has unleashed unrelenting violence that has caused death and destruction across Ukraine.  We’ve seen numerous credible reports of indiscriminate attacks and attacks deliberately targeting civilians, as well as other atrocities.  Russia’s forces have destroyed apartment buildings, schools, hospitals, critical infrastructure, civilian vehicles, shopping centers, and ambulances, leaving thousands of innocent civilians killed or wounded.  Many of the sites Russia’s forces have hit have been clearly identifiable as in-use by civilians.  This includes the Mariupol maternity hospital, as the UN Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights expressly noted in a March 11 report.  It also includes a strike that hit a Mariupol theater, clearly marked with the word “дети” — Russian for “children” — in huge letters visible from the sky.  Putin’s forces used these same tactics in Grozny, Chechnya, and Aleppo, Syria, where they intensified their bombardment of cities to break the will of the people.  Their attempt to do so in Ukraine has again shocked the world and, as President Zelenskyy has soberly attested, “bathed the people of Ukraine in blood and tears.”</p>
<p align="left">Every day that Russia’s forces continue their brutal attacks, the number of innocent civilians killed and wounded, including women and children, climbs.  As of March 22, officials in besieged Mariupol said that more than 2,400 civilians had been killed in that city alone.  Not including the Mariupol devastation, the United Nations has officially confirmed more than 2,500 civilian casualties, including dead and wounded, and emphasizes the actual toll is likely higher.</p>
<p align="left">Last week, I echoed President Biden’s statement, based on the countless accounts and images of destruction and suffering we have all seen, that war crimes had been committed by Putin’s forces in Ukraine.  I noted then that the deliberate targeting of civilians is a war crime.  I emphasized that Department of State and other U.S. government experts were documenting and assessing potential war crimes in Ukraine.</p>
<p align="left">Today, I can announce that, based on information currently available, the U.S. government assesses that members of Russia&#8217;s forces have committed war crimes in Ukraine.</p>
<p align="left">Our assessment is based on a careful review of available information from public and intelligence sources.  As with any alleged crime, a court of law with jurisdiction over the crime is ultimately responsible for determining criminal guilt in specific cases.  The U.S. government will continue to track reports of war crimes and will share information we gather with allies, partners, and international institutions and organizations, as appropriate.  We are committed to pursuing accountability using every tool available, including criminal prosecutions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p align="left">Since launching his unprovoked and unjust war of choice, Russian President Vladimir Putin has unleashed unrelenting violence that has caused death and destruction across Ukraine.  We’ve seen numerous credible reports of indiscriminate attacks and attacks deliberately targeting civilians, as well as other atrocities.  Russia’s forces have destroyed apartment buildings, schools, hospitals, critical infrastructure, civilian vehicles, shopping centers, and ambulances, leaving thousands of innocent civilians killed or wounded.  Many of the sites Russia’s forces have hit have been clearly identifiable as in-use by civilians.  This includes the Mariupol maternity hospital, as the UN Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights expressly noted in a March 11 report.  It also includes a strike that hit a Mariupol theater, clearly marked with the word “дети” — Russian for “children” — in huge letters visible from the sky.  Putin’s forces used these same tactics in Grozny, Chechnya, and Aleppo, Syria, where they intensified their bombardment of cities to break the will of the people.  Their attempt to do so in Ukraine has again shocked the world and, as President Zelenskyy has soberly attested, “bathed the people of Ukraine in blood and tears.”</p>
<p align="left">Every day that Russia’s forces continue their brutal attacks, the number of innocent civilians killed and wounded, including women and children, climbs.  As of March 22, officials in besieged Mariupol said that more than 2,400 civilians had been killed in that city alone.  Not including the Mariupol devastation, the United Nations has officially confirmed more than 2,500 civilian casualties, including dead and wounded, and emphasizes the actual toll is likely higher.</p>
<p align="left">Last week, I echoed President Biden’s statement, based on the countless accounts and images of destruction and suffering we have all seen, that war crimes had been committed by Putin’s forces in Ukraine.  I noted then that the deliberate targeting of civilians is a war crime.  I emphasized that Department of State and other U.S. government experts were documenting and assessing potential war crimes in Ukraine.</p>
<p align="left">Today, I can announce that, based on information currently available, the U.S. government assesses that members of Russia&#8217;s forces have committed war crimes in Ukraine.</p>
<p align="left">Our assessment is based on a careful review of available information from public and intelligence sources.  As with any alleged crime, a court of law with jurisdiction over the crime is ultimately responsible for determining criminal guilt in specific cases.  The U.S. government will continue to track reports of war crimes and will share information we gather with allies, partners, and international institutions and organizations, as appropriate.  We are committed to pursuing accountability using every tool available, including criminal prosecutions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on Kosovo</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-kosovo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 13:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=326906</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left"><i>The following is the text of a joint statement by the Governments of the United States of America and France, Italy, Germany, and the United Kingdom.</i></p>
<p align="left"><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p align="left">France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom and the United States have intensely engaged with the governments of Kosovo and Serbia in the past months in order to find a pragmatic solution to allow eligible Kosovo citizens to exercise their right to participate in Serbia&#8217;s elections on April 3, 2022.</p>
<p align="left">We acknowledge that it is the Kosovo Government’s prerogative to decide whether or not to permit facilitation of voting in another country’s elections. While we appreciate Serbia’s availability to find a solution, it is with great disappointment that we take note of Kosovo Government’s decision to reject a constructive proposal presented by the Quint. With this decision, Kosovo’s Government failed to demonstrate its commitment to the principle of protecting the civil and political rights of all its citizens, including of members of minority groups.</p>
<p align="left">Such an attitude of the Kosovo Government is not in line with our values and principles and will undermine its European aspirations.</p>
<p align="left">Following Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, we welcomed Kosovo’s alignment with the statements and declarations EU and the Quint members adopted. However, Kosovo is also expected to uphold its core values and responsibility towards regional stability and respect democratic processes, as well as to commit to protection of the rights of members of minority groups.</p>
<p align="left">We expect the Kosovo Government to act in the interests of all its citizens, to work to decrease tensions and to engage constructively in the EU-facilitated Dialogue on normalization of relations with Serbia. This is crucial to achieve progress towards a comprehensive normalization agreement that will ultimately unlock the EU perspective of Kosovo.</p>
<p align="left">We reiterate our strong call upon Kosovo and Serbia to refrain from any actions and rhetoric that increase tensions and may lead to incidents.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left"><i>The following is the text of a joint statement by the Governments of the United States of America and France, Italy, Germany, and the United Kingdom.</i></p>
<p align="left"><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p align="left">France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom and the United States have intensely engaged with the governments of Kosovo and Serbia in the past months in order to find a pragmatic solution to allow eligible Kosovo citizens to exercise their right to participate in Serbia&#8217;s elections on April 3, 2022.</p>
<p align="left">We acknowledge that it is the Kosovo Government’s prerogative to decide whether or not to permit facilitation of voting in another country’s elections. While we appreciate Serbia’s availability to find a solution, it is with great disappointment that we take note of Kosovo Government’s decision to reject a constructive proposal presented by the Quint. With this decision, Kosovo’s Government failed to demonstrate its commitment to the principle of protecting the civil and political rights of all its citizens, including of members of minority groups.</p>
<p align="left">Such an attitude of the Kosovo Government is not in line with our values and principles and will undermine its European aspirations.</p>
<p align="left">Following Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, we welcomed Kosovo’s alignment with the statements and declarations EU and the Quint members adopted. However, Kosovo is also expected to uphold its core values and responsibility towards regional stability and respect democratic processes, as well as to commit to protection of the rights of members of minority groups.</p>
<p align="left">We expect the Kosovo Government to act in the interests of all its citizens, to work to decrease tensions and to engage constructively in the EU-facilitated Dialogue on normalization of relations with Serbia. This is crucial to achieve progress towards a comprehensive normalization agreement that will ultimately unlock the EU perspective of Kosovo.</p>
<p align="left">We reiterate our strong call upon Kosovo and Serbia to refrain from any actions and rhetoric that increase tensions and may lead to incidents.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
