<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:30:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Venezuela National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/venezuela-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 04:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=257301</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I wish to congratulate the people of Venezuela as you celebrate the country’s independence this July 5.</p>
<p>Despite significant challenges, the people and the coalition of democratic actors in Venezuela have continued their tireless efforts to preserve their dream of an independent and democratic future.  As you mark the 210<sup>th</sup> anniversary of Venezuela’s independence, please know that you will continue to find in the people and government of the United States a committed partner ready to support you in the struggle to build a peaceful, free, prosperous, and democratic future for your nation.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I wish to congratulate the people of Venezuela as you celebrate the country’s independence this July 5.</p>
<p>Despite significant challenges, the people and the coalition of democratic actors in Venezuela have continued their tireless efforts to preserve their dream of an independent and democratic future.  As you mark the 210<sup>th</sup> anniversary of Venezuela’s independence, please know that you will continue to find in the people and government of the United States a committed partner ready to support you in the struggle to build a peaceful, free, prosperous, and democratic future for your nation.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States Takes Further Actions against the Burmese Military Regime</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-takes-further-actions-against-the-burmese-military-regime/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=257062</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>In response to the brutal campaign of violence perpetrated by the Burmese military regime and to continue imposing costs in connection with the military coup, the U.S. Department of the Treasury’s Office of Assets Control is designating today 22 individuals connected to the regime, pursuant to Executive Order 14014 “Blocking Property With Respect to the Situation in Burma.” These include three additional State Administration Council (SAC) members and four military-appointed cabinet members, as well as 15 adult children or spouses of previously designated Burmese military officials whose financial networks have contributed to military officials’ ill-gotten gains.</p>
<p>In addition, the U.S. Department of Commerce is adding Wanbao Mining, Ltd., two of its subsidiaries, and King Royal Technologies to its Entity List.  These entities provide revenue and/or other support to the Burmese military, and Wanbao Mining and its subsidiaries have long been implicated in labor rights violations and human rights abuses, including at the Letpadaung copper mine.</p>
<p>Today’s measures further demonstrate that we will continue to take additional action against, and impose costs on, the military and its leaders until they reverse course and provide for a return to democracy.</p>
<p>The United States is committed to promoting accountability for the Burmese military, the SAC, and all those who have provided support for the military coup. The United States will continue to urge the Burmese military to fully cooperate in expeditious implementation of the ASEAN Five Point Consensus, and immediately restore Burma’s path to democracy.  The United States will remain a steadfast advocate for the people of Burma’s ability to determine the future of their country.</p>
<p>For more information about today’s action, see Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0260" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release </span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> and Commerce’s <a class="external-link" href="https://www.commerce.gov/news/press-releases/2021/07/commerce-increases-restrictions-burmese-military-adding-four-entities" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>In response to the brutal campaign of violence perpetrated by the Burmese military regime and to continue imposing costs in connection with the military coup, the U.S. Department of the Treasury’s Office of Assets Control is designating today 22 individuals connected to the regime, pursuant to Executive Order 14014 “Blocking Property With Respect to the Situation in Burma.” These include three additional State Administration Council (SAC) members and four military-appointed cabinet members, as well as 15 adult children or spouses of previously designated Burmese military officials whose financial networks have contributed to military officials’ ill-gotten gains.</p>
<p>In addition, the U.S. Department of Commerce is adding Wanbao Mining, Ltd., two of its subsidiaries, and King Royal Technologies to its Entity List.  These entities provide revenue and/or other support to the Burmese military, and Wanbao Mining and its subsidiaries have long been implicated in labor rights violations and human rights abuses, including at the Letpadaung copper mine.</p>
<p>Today’s measures further demonstrate that we will continue to take additional action against, and impose costs on, the military and its leaders until they reverse course and provide for a return to democracy.</p>
<p>The United States is committed to promoting accountability for the Burmese military, the SAC, and all those who have provided support for the military coup. The United States will continue to urge the Burmese military to fully cooperate in expeditious implementation of the ASEAN Five Point Consensus, and immediately restore Burma’s path to democracy.  The United States will remain a steadfast advocate for the people of Burma’s ability to determine the future of their country.</p>
<p>For more information about today’s action, see Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0260" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release </span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> and Commerce’s <a class="external-link" href="https://www.commerce.gov/news/press-releases/2021/07/commerce-increases-restrictions-burmese-military-adding-four-entities" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Public Schedule &#8211; July 2, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/public-schedule-july-2-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=256905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>                                    ***THE DAILY PUBLIC SCHEDULE IS SUBJECT TO CHANGE***</strong></p>
<p><strong><u>SECRETARY ANTONY J. BLINKEN</u></strong></p>
<p>Secretary Blinken has no public appointments.</p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY WENDY R. SHERMAN</u></strong></p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman has no public appointments.</p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY FOR MANAGEMENT AND RESOURCES BRIAN P. MCKEON</u></strong></p>
<p>Deputy Secretary McKeon attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>UNDER SECRETARY FOR POLITICAL AFFAIRS VICTORIA J. NULAND </u></strong></p>
<p>Under Secretary Nuland attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>ACTING ASSISTANT SECRETARY FOR EUROPEAN AND EURASIAN AFFAIRS PHILIP T. REEKER </u></strong></p>
<p>Acting Assistant Secretary Reeker is on travel to Ohrid, North Macedonia, from July 1-3, 2021. Please click <a href="https://www.state.gov/acting-assistant-secretary-reekers-travel-to-italy-albania-and-north-macedonia/">here</a> for more information.</p>
<p><strong><u>BRIEFING SCHEDULE </u></strong></p>
<p>No Department Press Briefing</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>                                    ***THE DAILY PUBLIC SCHEDULE IS SUBJECT TO CHANGE***</strong></p>
<p><strong><u>SECRETARY ANTONY J. BLINKEN</u></strong></p>
<p>Secretary Blinken has no public appointments.</p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY WENDY R. SHERMAN</u></strong></p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman has no public appointments.</p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY FOR MANAGEMENT AND RESOURCES BRIAN P. MCKEON</u></strong></p>
<p>Deputy Secretary McKeon attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>UNDER SECRETARY FOR POLITICAL AFFAIRS VICTORIA J. NULAND </u></strong></p>
<p>Under Secretary Nuland attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>ACTING ASSISTANT SECRETARY FOR EUROPEAN AND EURASIAN AFFAIRS PHILIP T. REEKER </u></strong></p>
<p>Acting Assistant Secretary Reeker is on travel to Ohrid, North Macedonia, from July 1-3, 2021. Please click <a href="https://www.state.gov/acting-assistant-secretary-reekers-travel-to-italy-albania-and-north-macedonia/">here</a> for more information.</p>
<p><strong><u>BRIEFING SCHEDULE </u></strong></p>
<p>No Department Press Briefing</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Eighth U.S.-Tajikistan Annual Bilateral Consultations</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-eighth-u-s-tajikistan-annual-bilateral-consultations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=256899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The State Department hosted Foreign Minister Sirojiddin Muhriddin and a delegation from the Government of Tajikistan for the eighth U.S.-Tajikistan Annual Bilateral Consultations on July 1, following 30 years of bilateral partnership between the United States and Tajikistan.</p>
<p>The United States delegation, led by Acting Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs Dean Thompson, reiterated the United States’ commitment to Tajikistan’s independence, sovereignty, and prosperity and cited our shared goal of a just and durable settlement in Afghanistan. The delegations discussed issues related to security and law enforcement, human rights, and energy and the economy.  Participants affirmed their countries&#8217; commitments to jointly address regional security threats, cooperate on efforts to counter terrorism, and professionalize security services.  Officials discussed opportunities for advancing mutual goals to promote religious freedom and combat trafficking in persons.  The delegations also discussed joint initiatives to increase regional connectivity and improve bilateral trade and investment opportunities.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The State Department hosted Foreign Minister Sirojiddin Muhriddin and a delegation from the Government of Tajikistan for the eighth U.S.-Tajikistan Annual Bilateral Consultations on July 1, following 30 years of bilateral partnership between the United States and Tajikistan.</p>
<p>The United States delegation, led by Acting Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs Dean Thompson, reiterated the United States’ commitment to Tajikistan’s independence, sovereignty, and prosperity and cited our shared goal of a just and durable settlement in Afghanistan. The delegations discussed issues related to security and law enforcement, human rights, and energy and the economy.  Participants affirmed their countries&#8217; commitments to jointly address regional security threats, cooperate on efforts to counter terrorism, and professionalize security services.  Officials discussed opportunities for advancing mutual goals to promote religious freedom and combat trafficking in persons.  The delegations also discussed joint initiatives to increase regional connectivity and improve bilateral trade and investment opportunities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Envoy for the Northern Triangle Ricardo Zuniga On Release of the Section 353 Report (aka Corrupt Actors List)</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-envoy-for-the-northern-triangle-ricardo-zuniga-on-release-of-the-section-353-report-aka-corrupt-actors-list/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=256894</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thanks very much, and thanks very much for joining us, everyone.  We wanted to take a moment to offer a bit of context on what you saw from Secretary Blinken earlier today.  As you saw, we transmitted to Congress and released publicly our Corrupt and Undemocratic Actors List.</p>
<p>We have joining us today Special Envoy for the Northern Triangle Ricardo Zuniga, who will offer some remarks at the top of the call and who will then look forward to taking your questions on today’s report.</p>
<p>So without further ado, I’ll offer a reminder that this call is embargoed until its conclusion, but I will then turn it over to Ricardo to get us started.  Over to you, sir.</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  Ned, thank you very much.  So thank all of you for joining us today for this briefing.  As the White House recently emphasized, combating corruption is a U.S. national security priority.  As you know, President Biden and Vice President Harris are very focused on leveraging their experience – years of experience – in addressing the root causes of irregular migration from Central America, and these two topics come together very closely in that part of the world because corruption and attacks on democracy are viewed as some of the most important root causes of irregular migration from Central America.  They hobble governance, they distort markets, they undercut development efforts, and ultimately, they demoralize a population that decides to embark on a very dangerous irregular migration to Mexico and the United States because they don’t believe they can build their futures at home.</p>
<p>Today the Secretary of State announced the transmittal to Congress of the Corrupt and Undemocratic Actors List, a report required by Section 353 of the United States-Northern Triangle Enhanced Engagement Act.  So this report lists individuals from Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador who have undermined democratic processes or institutions, engaged in significant corruption, or who have obstructed investigations into such acts.</p>
<p>So these efforts are very much in support of the people of Central America.  The citizens of Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador have consistently repudiated corruption, demanded accountability from their governments and private actors, and acted in defense of democratic institutions.  Unfortunately, all too often corruption and abuse from office go unpunished even though they are often investigated by public servants who are attempting to complete their work.  The United States stands with Central American citizens, organizations, and public servants who are committed to promoting the public good.</p>
<p>We’re committed to generating opportunity and hope among the people of the region in the face of attacks on democratic institutions and setbacks on the rule of law and efforts to combat impunity.  So we will use the full range of tools, including actions like this one provided by Congress, to shine a light on corruption and encourage the strengthening of democratic institutions to make life better for our neighbors in Central America.</p>
<p>So with that, I’ll take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Wonderful.  Operator, if you want to repeat the instructions for asking a question.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Certainly.  Once again, if you’d like to ask a question, please press 1, then 0 at this time.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Ted Hesson.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  It’s Ted Hesson with Reuters.  One thing we noticed with this list of actors is there didn’t seem to be too many officials who were involved or allegedly involved in narco-crimes, and specifically with Guatemala’s UCN party.  And we were wondering why that was, if there was a reason for it, and what your response is to that.</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  So, there was no effort to exclude people who were involved in narco-trafficking, and in fact, some of the people who were listed do have some affiliation with either trafficking or with criminal organizations.  This is – this list is one of a variety of tools that we have available for providing accountability for corruption and undemocratic actions.  It’s also not a final list.  This is an initial list provided in response to the congressional mandate.  It’s required at least once a year, so we will use this and other tools to highlight people who are involved either in corrupt acts or in obstructing the democratic process, or perhaps we can use other tools as well to highlight people who are involved in organized crime.  So this is – this list is not exclusive of that, and there certainly was no effort to exclude people who were potentially involved in organized crime activity.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to Chris Sherman.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello, good afternoon.  Thank you.  This piggybacks a bit on Ted’s question.  But obviously, this could always be a longer list, and you said this was just the initial one, but can you speak at all to how the line was drawn at where these are?  Obviously, there are some people in the region.  You had expected to see some other names on there.  Can you talk about how it was composed?</p>
<p>And in terms of (inaudible) &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  &#8212; is that just an initial step?  Could there be harsher sanctions for these people?</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  So I’ll start with the second part first.  And yes, the action that we take under this authority does not exclude other sanctions, and in fact, a number of the people who are on this list have been the subject of other measures by – from the United States, including by the Department of State, to hold them accountable.</p>
<p>The list was prepared based on an extensive review of credible information that we had that was both classified and unclassified information pertaining to the known engagement in acts that undermine democratic processes or institutions who are involved in significant corruption or in obstruction into investigation into such acts of corruption.  We vetted those names.  There was more of a focus on – because this list is intended to both identify people involved in these actions and to dissuade future activity, certainly there was more attention to more recent cases where we had more recent information and for people who were either currently involved in government or near or were in positions of influence to demonstrate that that’s – this is our area of focus.</p>
<p>As you said, this is not a – we don’t view this as the end of the action but as an initial response to the request from Congress.  We are also considering if additional actions will be taken based on information we developed during the – during our – the organization of this list.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Let’s go to the line of Rafael Bernal.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you for having this.  I guess that they asked a couple questions that I had, but I noticed in the Salvadoran list you have a couple of actors here who allegedly engaged with the Chinese in inappropriate behaviors.  What’s the message that you want to give Central American, at least government officials, et cetera, on their engagement with other world powers that might be wanting to move in into the region, particularly China and Russia?</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:  </strong>So the real message there as it relates to this list is that it’s the type of activity that we’re targeting.  If there’s corruption around efforts to build influence, certainly that is something that is going to get a great deal of scrutiny.</p>
<p>But again, it has to do, in the case of this list, with the act of – acting corruptly to obtain or to act on behalf of another actor.  And certainly there – in the cases that you cite, there was concern, very much concern at the time expressed by people in El Salvador and which United States echoed, regarding the use of corruption to try to expand the influence in a commercial deal.  And that is very much at issue.</p>
<p>We certainly are aware of there being the real line between normal economic competition and competition that is undermined by the use of purchasing influence or by suborning actors inside of Central America to act on behalf of – well, really any power should – those are all of great concern to us.</p>
<p>So one thing is the normal economic competition that you would have, and the other is actions that are corrupt and that are in – on behalf of an external actor that seeks to build influence that way.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll go the line of Matthew Russell Lee.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Sure.  Thanks a lot.  And thanks, thanks for doing the call.  I wanted to ask about Honduras.  In looking at the list, you have former President Pepe Lobo, you have current Congressman Oscar Najera, and you mention this <em>Cachiros</em>.  But being here in the Southern District of New York court and covering the trials of the brother of the current president and of Geovanny Fuentes Ramirez, it’s clear that President Juan Orlando Hernandez is mentioned repeatedly by Department of Justice prosecutors as not only getting campaign contributions from drug traffickers but perhaps being involved in it himself.  So I’m wondering:  On this specific case, can you say what the reasoning is of not having him on the list?</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:  </strong>So for questions about U.S. criminal prosecutions, we obviously refer you to the Department of Justice.  We do – this list is intended to demonstrate that we have a commitment to the rule of law and to fighting impunity in Honduras.  We’ve made that clear in our communications with governments across the region, including Honduras, and we’ve made clear that leaders who seek a close relationship with the United States have to demonstrate a commitment to combating corruption.</p>
<p>We use, again, a variety of tools for promoting accountability and combating impunity.  This is one – this list is one of several tools that we use for that purpose.  We do work with other actors in Honduras in government, in civil society, in private sector, and – but again, our primary commitment is to leaders who demonstrate a commitment to combating corruption.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well, it looks like we’ve exhausted the questions in queue unless anyone else wishes to jump in.  I want to thank our speaker, Special Envoy Zuniga, for spending some time with us today.  And thank you to everyone who called in, and we look forward to speaking with you soon.</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:  </strong>Thank you very much, Ned.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thanks.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thanks very much, and thanks very much for joining us, everyone.  We wanted to take a moment to offer a bit of context on what you saw from Secretary Blinken earlier today.  As you saw, we transmitted to Congress and released publicly our Corrupt and Undemocratic Actors List.</p>
<p>We have joining us today Special Envoy for the Northern Triangle Ricardo Zuniga, who will offer some remarks at the top of the call and who will then look forward to taking your questions on today’s report.</p>
<p>So without further ado, I’ll offer a reminder that this call is embargoed until its conclusion, but I will then turn it over to Ricardo to get us started.  Over to you, sir.</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  Ned, thank you very much.  So thank all of you for joining us today for this briefing.  As the White House recently emphasized, combating corruption is a U.S. national security priority.  As you know, President Biden and Vice President Harris are very focused on leveraging their experience – years of experience – in addressing the root causes of irregular migration from Central America, and these two topics come together very closely in that part of the world because corruption and attacks on democracy are viewed as some of the most important root causes of irregular migration from Central America.  They hobble governance, they distort markets, they undercut development efforts, and ultimately, they demoralize a population that decides to embark on a very dangerous irregular migration to Mexico and the United States because they don’t believe they can build their futures at home.</p>
<p>Today the Secretary of State announced the transmittal to Congress of the Corrupt and Undemocratic Actors List, a report required by Section 353 of the United States-Northern Triangle Enhanced Engagement Act.  So this report lists individuals from Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador who have undermined democratic processes or institutions, engaged in significant corruption, or who have obstructed investigations into such acts.</p>
<p>So these efforts are very much in support of the people of Central America.  The citizens of Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador have consistently repudiated corruption, demanded accountability from their governments and private actors, and acted in defense of democratic institutions.  Unfortunately, all too often corruption and abuse from office go unpunished even though they are often investigated by public servants who are attempting to complete their work.  The United States stands with Central American citizens, organizations, and public servants who are committed to promoting the public good.</p>
<p>We’re committed to generating opportunity and hope among the people of the region in the face of attacks on democratic institutions and setbacks on the rule of law and efforts to combat impunity.  So we will use the full range of tools, including actions like this one provided by Congress, to shine a light on corruption and encourage the strengthening of democratic institutions to make life better for our neighbors in Central America.</p>
<p>So with that, I’ll take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Wonderful.  Operator, if you want to repeat the instructions for asking a question.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Certainly.  Once again, if you’d like to ask a question, please press 1, then 0 at this time.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Ted Hesson.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  It’s Ted Hesson with Reuters.  One thing we noticed with this list of actors is there didn’t seem to be too many officials who were involved or allegedly involved in narco-crimes, and specifically with Guatemala’s UCN party.  And we were wondering why that was, if there was a reason for it, and what your response is to that.</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  So, there was no effort to exclude people who were involved in narco-trafficking, and in fact, some of the people who were listed do have some affiliation with either trafficking or with criminal organizations.  This is – this list is one of a variety of tools that we have available for providing accountability for corruption and undemocratic actions.  It’s also not a final list.  This is an initial list provided in response to the congressional mandate.  It’s required at least once a year, so we will use this and other tools to highlight people who are involved either in corrupt acts or in obstructing the democratic process, or perhaps we can use other tools as well to highlight people who are involved in organized crime.  So this is – this list is not exclusive of that, and there certainly was no effort to exclude people who were potentially involved in organized crime activity.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to Chris Sherman.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello, good afternoon.  Thank you.  This piggybacks a bit on Ted’s question.  But obviously, this could always be a longer list, and you said this was just the initial one, but can you speak at all to how the line was drawn at where these are?  Obviously, there are some people in the region.  You had expected to see some other names on there.  Can you talk about how it was composed?</p>
<p>And in terms of (inaudible) &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  &#8212; is that just an initial step?  Could there be harsher sanctions for these people?</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:</strong>  So I’ll start with the second part first.  And yes, the action that we take under this authority does not exclude other sanctions, and in fact, a number of the people who are on this list have been the subject of other measures by – from the United States, including by the Department of State, to hold them accountable.</p>
<p>The list was prepared based on an extensive review of credible information that we had that was both classified and unclassified information pertaining to the known engagement in acts that undermine democratic processes or institutions who are involved in significant corruption or in obstruction into investigation into such acts of corruption.  We vetted those names.  There was more of a focus on – because this list is intended to both identify people involved in these actions and to dissuade future activity, certainly there was more attention to more recent cases where we had more recent information and for people who were either currently involved in government or near or were in positions of influence to demonstrate that that’s – this is our area of focus.</p>
<p>As you said, this is not a – we don’t view this as the end of the action but as an initial response to the request from Congress.  We are also considering if additional actions will be taken based on information we developed during the – during our – the organization of this list.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Let’s go to the line of Rafael Bernal.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you for having this.  I guess that they asked a couple questions that I had, but I noticed in the Salvadoran list you have a couple of actors here who allegedly engaged with the Chinese in inappropriate behaviors.  What’s the message that you want to give Central American, at least government officials, et cetera, on their engagement with other world powers that might be wanting to move in into the region, particularly China and Russia?</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:  </strong>So the real message there as it relates to this list is that it’s the type of activity that we’re targeting.  If there’s corruption around efforts to build influence, certainly that is something that is going to get a great deal of scrutiny.</p>
<p>But again, it has to do, in the case of this list, with the act of – acting corruptly to obtain or to act on behalf of another actor.  And certainly there – in the cases that you cite, there was concern, very much concern at the time expressed by people in El Salvador and which United States echoed, regarding the use of corruption to try to expand the influence in a commercial deal.  And that is very much at issue.</p>
<p>We certainly are aware of there being the real line between normal economic competition and competition that is undermined by the use of purchasing influence or by suborning actors inside of Central America to act on behalf of – well, really any power should – those are all of great concern to us.</p>
<p>So one thing is the normal economic competition that you would have, and the other is actions that are corrupt and that are in – on behalf of an external actor that seeks to build influence that way.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll go the line of Matthew Russell Lee.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Sure.  Thanks a lot.  And thanks, thanks for doing the call.  I wanted to ask about Honduras.  In looking at the list, you have former President Pepe Lobo, you have current Congressman Oscar Najera, and you mention this <em>Cachiros</em>.  But being here in the Southern District of New York court and covering the trials of the brother of the current president and of Geovanny Fuentes Ramirez, it’s clear that President Juan Orlando Hernandez is mentioned repeatedly by Department of Justice prosecutors as not only getting campaign contributions from drug traffickers but perhaps being involved in it himself.  So I’m wondering:  On this specific case, can you say what the reasoning is of not having him on the list?</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:  </strong>So for questions about U.S. criminal prosecutions, we obviously refer you to the Department of Justice.  We do – this list is intended to demonstrate that we have a commitment to the rule of law and to fighting impunity in Honduras.  We’ve made that clear in our communications with governments across the region, including Honduras, and we’ve made clear that leaders who seek a close relationship with the United States have to demonstrate a commitment to combating corruption.</p>
<p>We use, again, a variety of tools for promoting accountability and combating impunity.  This is one – this list is one of several tools that we use for that purpose.  We do work with other actors in Honduras in government, in civil society, in private sector, and – but again, our primary commitment is to leaders who demonstrate a commitment to combating corruption.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well, it looks like we’ve exhausted the questions in queue unless anyone else wishes to jump in.  I want to thank our speaker, Special Envoy Zuniga, for spending some time with us today.  And thank you to everyone who called in, and we look forward to speaking with you soon.</p>
<p><strong>MR ZUNIGA:  </strong>Thank you very much, Ned.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thanks.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland Travel to Paraguay, Panama, and El Salvador</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-of-state-for-political-affairs-victoria-nuland-travel-to-paraguay-panama-and-el-salvador/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 22:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=256850</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland and an interagency delegation, including representatives from the National Security Council, the Department of Defense, and the U.S. Southern Command, visited Paraguay, Panama, and El Salvador from June 27-30.  The delegation met with Paraguayan President Mario Abdo Benitez, Paraguayan Foreign Minister Euclides Acevedo, and other cabinet members; with Panamanian President Laurentino Cortizo Cohen and Acting Foreign Minister Dayra Carrizo, as well as the Panama Canal Administrator Ricaurte Vásquez; and with Salvadoran President Nayib Bukele, Foreign Minister Alexandra Hill Tinoco, and other Salvadoran leaders.  They also met with successful young innovators, entrepreneurs, and other civil society leaders in the three countries to discuss their visions for the future.</p>
<p>During her trip, Under Secretary of State Nuland:</p>
<ul>
<li>Relaunched the U.S.-Paraguay Strategic Partnership Dialogue, which last met in 2016, to expand bilateral coordination on issues of mutual interest, including democracy and security, trade and investment, development and good governance, and cooperation with likeminded partners like Taiwan.</li>
<li>Announced the U.S. donation of one million Pfizer COVID-19 vaccine doses to Paraguay, with additional vaccine donations to Panama and El Salvador in the coming weeks. This is in addition to $2 billion in funding and additional vaccine donations to Gavi, which supported procurement and delivery of vaccines through COVAX the COVID-19 vaccine-sharing facility, for worldwide distribution.</li>
<li>Announced an agreement between Banco Sudameris and the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC), and a parallel agreement with Citibank, for $125 million of financing for Paraguayan Small and Medium Enterprises to focus on enabling women-owned and led businesses as well as those that benefit women, with 30 percent of DFC loan proceeds going to this purpose.</li>
<li>Announced the start of talks to establish a network of Small Business Development Centers in Paraguay to provide counseling and services to help small businesses grow and create jobs.</li>
<li>In a meeting with President Laurentino Cortizo, advanced our partnership with Panama to manage the ongoing challenges of irregular migration and forced displacement in and through the region.</li>
<li>Emphasized the importance of data privacy and customer trust in maintaining regional technological infrastructure integrity with Panamanian telecommunications sector leaders, recognizing Panama’s development toward serving as a digital hub for the region.</li>
<li>Reaffirmed the close relationship between the United States and Panama on key issues of climate change, and environmental preservation. Panama remains a leader in the region for championing the environment, and their aggressive climate goals make them the ideal hosts for the Energy and Climate Partnership of the Americas (ECPA) Ministerial in 2022 and the Our Ocean Conference in 2023.</li>
<li>Underscored U.S. support for Panama’s efforts to combat illicit finance, particularly through the joint Anti-Money Laundering and Anti-Corruption Task Force,</li>
<li>In El Salvador, reinforced U.S. support for strong democratic institutions, transparency, and rule of law in meetings with Salvadoran President Bukele Foreign Minister Hill, and in roundtables with civil society and with young Salvadoran political leaders.</li>
<li>Engaged with Salvadoran entrepreneurs on job creation and investment in the region to address one of the root causes of irregular migration.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland and an interagency delegation, including representatives from the National Security Council, the Department of Defense, and the U.S. Southern Command, visited Paraguay, Panama, and El Salvador from June 27-30.  The delegation met with Paraguayan President Mario Abdo Benitez, Paraguayan Foreign Minister Euclides Acevedo, and other cabinet members; with Panamanian President Laurentino Cortizo Cohen and Acting Foreign Minister Dayra Carrizo, as well as the Panama Canal Administrator Ricaurte Vásquez; and with Salvadoran President Nayib Bukele, Foreign Minister Alexandra Hill Tinoco, and other Salvadoran leaders.  They also met with successful young innovators, entrepreneurs, and other civil society leaders in the three countries to discuss their visions for the future.</p>
<p>During her trip, Under Secretary of State Nuland:</p>
<ul>
<li>Relaunched the U.S.-Paraguay Strategic Partnership Dialogue, which last met in 2016, to expand bilateral coordination on issues of mutual interest, including democracy and security, trade and investment, development and good governance, and cooperation with likeminded partners like Taiwan.</li>
<li>Announced the U.S. donation of one million Pfizer COVID-19 vaccine doses to Paraguay, with additional vaccine donations to Panama and El Salvador in the coming weeks. This is in addition to $2 billion in funding and additional vaccine donations to Gavi, which supported procurement and delivery of vaccines through COVAX the COVID-19 vaccine-sharing facility, for worldwide distribution.</li>
<li>Announced an agreement between Banco Sudameris and the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC), and a parallel agreement with Citibank, for $125 million of financing for Paraguayan Small and Medium Enterprises to focus on enabling women-owned and led businesses as well as those that benefit women, with 30 percent of DFC loan proceeds going to this purpose.</li>
<li>Announced the start of talks to establish a network of Small Business Development Centers in Paraguay to provide counseling and services to help small businesses grow and create jobs.</li>
<li>In a meeting with President Laurentino Cortizo, advanced our partnership with Panama to manage the ongoing challenges of irregular migration and forced displacement in and through the region.</li>
<li>Emphasized the importance of data privacy and customer trust in maintaining regional technological infrastructure integrity with Panamanian telecommunications sector leaders, recognizing Panama’s development toward serving as a digital hub for the region.</li>
<li>Reaffirmed the close relationship between the United States and Panama on key issues of climate change, and environmental preservation. Panama remains a leader in the region for championing the environment, and their aggressive climate goals make them the ideal hosts for the Energy and Climate Partnership of the Americas (ECPA) Ministerial in 2022 and the Our Ocean Conference in 2023.</li>
<li>Underscored U.S. support for Panama’s efforts to combat illicit finance, particularly through the joint Anti-Money Laundering and Anti-Corruption Task Force,</li>
<li>In El Salvador, reinforced U.S. support for strong democratic institutions, transparency, and rule of law in meetings with Salvadoran President Bukele Foreign Minister Hill, and in roundtables with civil society and with young Salvadoran political leaders.</li>
<li>Engaged with Salvadoran entrepreneurs on job creation and investment in the region to address one of the root causes of irregular migration.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Tajikistan Foreign Minister Muhriddin</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-tajikistan-foreign-minister-muhriddin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 22:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=256835</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Tajikistan Foreign Minister Sirojiddin Muhriddin in Washington, D.C.  The Secretary welcomed the eighth iteration of the U.S.-Tajik Annual Bilateral Consultations held today at the State Department.  The Secretary reaffirmed the strength and importance of the U.S.-Tajikistan bilateral relationship and expressed his appreciation for Foreign Minister Muhriddin’s continued leadership on regional security issues.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister agreed that a just and durable settlement in Afghanistan would advance regional economic growth and integration.  The Secretary expressed a desire for further bilateral collaboration on promoting human rights and fundamental freedoms as well as economic development, and affirmed the U.S. commitment to Tajikistan’s security, stability, and territorial integrity.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Tajikistan Foreign Minister Sirojiddin Muhriddin in Washington, D.C.  The Secretary welcomed the eighth iteration of the U.S.-Tajik Annual Bilateral Consultations held today at the State Department.  The Secretary reaffirmed the strength and importance of the U.S.-Tajikistan bilateral relationship and expressed his appreciation for Foreign Minister Muhriddin’s continued leadership on regional security issues.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister agreed that a just and durable settlement in Afghanistan would advance regional economic growth and integration.  The Secretary expressed a desire for further bilateral collaboration on promoting human rights and fundamental freedoms as well as economic development, and affirmed the U.S. commitment to Tajikistan’s security, stability, and territorial integrity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Uzbekistan Foreign Minister Kamilov</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-uzbekistan-foreign-minister-kamilov/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 22:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=256830</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Today in Washington, D.C., Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Uzbekistan’s Foreign Minister Abdulaziz Kamilov.  The Secretary expressed the United States’ desire to deepen its strategic partnership with Uzbekistan, noting that the two countries celebrate 30 years of diplomatic relations this year.  The Secretary offered support for Uzbekistan’s continuing reforms, including strengthening human rights and democracy.  The Secretary commended Uzbekistan’s initiatives to improve relations within Central Asia, noting the two countries’ active cooperation through the C5+1 regional diplomatic platform.  The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Uzbekistan&#8217;s continued support for a just and durable peace settlement in Afghanistan.  He also welcomed Uzbekistan&#8217;s focus on regional connectivity, including closer political and economic cooperation with Afghanistan in ways that would support prosperity and growth across Central and South Asia.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Today in Washington, D.C., Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Uzbekistan’s Foreign Minister Abdulaziz Kamilov.  The Secretary expressed the United States’ desire to deepen its strategic partnership with Uzbekistan, noting that the two countries celebrate 30 years of diplomatic relations this year.  The Secretary offered support for Uzbekistan’s continuing reforms, including strengthening human rights and democracy.  The Secretary commended Uzbekistan’s initiatives to improve relations within Central Asia, noting the two countries’ active cooperation through the C5+1 regional diplomatic platform.  The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Uzbekistan&#8217;s continued support for a just and durable peace settlement in Afghanistan.  He also welcomed Uzbekistan&#8217;s focus on regional connectivity, including closer political and economic cooperation with Afghanistan in ways that would support prosperity and growth across Central and South Asia.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Uzbek Foreign Minister Abdulaziz Kamilov Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-uzbek-foreign-minister-abdulaziz-kamilov-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 21:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=256827</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Good afternoon.  I am very pleased to have Foreign Minister Kamilov here today.  We’ve spoken several times on the phone and by videoconference, but it’s very good to actually have you here in person.</p>
<p>A lot of good and important work being done this week on the vital relationship between the United States and Uzbekistan.  We have strong shared interests when it comes to security in the region, particularly with regard to Afghanistan.  Uzbekistan has been a leader in bringing countries in the region together, particularly with regard to economic and infrastructure connectivity, something else that we’ll talk about, as well as the bilateral relationship between our countries.</p>
<p>So welcome.  It’s very good to have you here.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER KAMILOV:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.  First of all, I’d like to thank Mr. Secretary, Secretary Blinken, for inviting our interagency delegation of the Republic of Uzbekistan.  We have a broad agenda during this visit, and we are going to exchange views on the state and the future of our bilateral relations, as well as we will pay serious attention to the situation in the region, in Central Asia.</p>
<p>And a lot has been changing in the world and in the region, and that’s why, as Mr. Secretary said, of course, we will exchange views on the situation in Afghanistan, too.  And we have a lot of issues, a lot to speak about, and that’s why I’d like once again to thank the American friends we invite throughout the region.<strong>  </strong>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Treaty Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Good afternoon.  I am very pleased to have Foreign Minister Kamilov here today.  We’ve spoken several times on the phone and by videoconference, but it’s very good to actually have you here in person.</p>
<p>A lot of good and important work being done this week on the vital relationship between the United States and Uzbekistan.  We have strong shared interests when it comes to security in the region, particularly with regard to Afghanistan.  Uzbekistan has been a leader in bringing countries in the region together, particularly with regard to economic and infrastructure connectivity, something else that we’ll talk about, as well as the bilateral relationship between our countries.</p>
<p>So welcome.  It’s very good to have you here.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER KAMILOV:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.  First of all, I’d like to thank Mr. Secretary, Secretary Blinken, for inviting our interagency delegation of the Republic of Uzbekistan.  We have a broad agenda during this visit, and we are going to exchange views on the state and the future of our bilateral relations, as well as we will pay serious attention to the situation in the region, in Central Asia.</p>
<p>And a lot has been changing in the world and in the region, and that’s why, as Mr. Secretary said, of course, we will exchange views on the situation in Afghanistan, too.  And we have a lot of issues, a lot to speak about, and that’s why I’d like once again to thank the American friends we invite throughout the region.<strong>  </strong>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at the 2021 Trafficking in Persons Report Launch Ceremony</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-the-2021-trafficking-in-persons-report-launch-ceremony/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Dr. Kari Johnstone, Acting DirectorOffice to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 20:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=256707</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Dr. Kari Johnstone, Acting DirectorOffice to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Ben Franklin Room</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE: </b>Good afternoon, and welcome. My name is Kari Johnstone. I am the acting director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons.</p>
<p>Thank you all for joining us virtually to mark the release of the 2021 Trafficking in Persons Report, or the TIP Report. I am grateful to be here with Secretary of State Antony Blinken.</p>
<p>A quick word about our program today: First, Secretary Blinken will offer remarks on this year’s report. We will then honor this year’s eight wonderful TIP Report Heroes, who have dedicated their lives to combat human trafficking, and we will hear briefly from each of them in a pre-recorded video. I will offer brief closing remarks and then we hope you will click over to <a href="http://state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1625257487712000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG6ZnQYIEQEeJPXejoWNj6RAHS1eA">state.gov</a> to access the report online.</p>
<p>I would like to start by thanking our colleagues across the State Department, including our overseas embassies, for the strong collaboration and time spent to produce an accurate and comprehensive report. And I want to give a second thank you – a special thank you and kudos to the staff of the Trafficking in Persons Office for your dedication and commitment. Your long hours and hard work producing this report make a difference. And finally, thank you to our colleagues across the U.S. Government as well as our vital partners in NGOs and international organizations, those with lived experience of human trafficking, and other experts who contributed to the TIP Report and work to facilitate progress in addressing human trafficking year-round.</p>
<p>And it is now such an honor to join Secretary Blinken here today. Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for elevating the issue of human trafficking and for hosting today’s event. Under your leadership, we look forward to advancing our efforts to combat human trafficking.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, Secretary of State Antony Blinken.</p>
<p>(Applause.)</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b>Thank you, Kari. Thank you very much for that introduction, but especially thank you for the terrific work leading the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons here at State. You and your team – and I know some of the team members are here with us today – did exceptional work producing this year’s report under the difficult circumstances of COVID-19.</p>
<p>Thanks to everyone else who&#8217;s here for joining us for what is a very important occasion. And a special thank you to the Heroes that we&#8217;re celebrating today, women and men around the world who have dedicated their careers to stopping human trafficking. They’re advocates, public servants, leaders of NGOs, and they help stop trafficking in all kinds of ways by supporting victims, helping to bring traffickers to justice, creating national action plans, addressing the root causes of trafficking.</p>
<p>In many ways, the fight against trafficking is fought on the local level, one community at a time. And we celebrate the brave people leading the fight, often at great risk to themselves. Trafficking in persons is an appalling crime. It&#8217;s a global crisis; it&#8217;s an enormous source of human suffering. By its nature, it&#8217;s often hidden from view. Exact figures are sometimes hard to determine. The estimate we often cite is that nearly 25 million people worldwide are victims of human trafficking. Many are compelled into commercial sex work. Many are forced to work in factories or fields, or to join armed groups. Millions of trafficking victims are children.</p>
<p>This crime is an affront to human rights; it&#8217;s an affront to human dignity. We fight it, you fight it, because it&#8217;s the right thing to do. It&#8217;s also in our interest to stop trafficking. We know it&#8217;s destabilizing to societies and to economies. So we must do everything we can as a country, but also as a global community, to stop trafficking wherever it occurs.</p>
<p>The State Department&#8217;s Trafficking in Persons Report is indeed the world&#8217;s most comprehensive resource of the anti-trafficking efforts being undertaken by governments around the globe. It reflects the United States longstanding commitment and bipartisan commitment to this issue. We see it from administration to administration, we see it in Congress, and it&#8217;s something that we should take pride in. It’s the product of a great deal of work by our team here in Washington, our embassies around the world, and by NGOs, by journalists, academics, and survivors who help us to identify and document trends in human trafficking so that governments worldwide can more effectively combat it.</p>
<p>Part of this report is our country data. This year, we assessed 188 countries, including the United States. Some made encouraging progress; some slid backward. It&#8217;s important to remember that progress against trafficking is rarely linear. Traffickers are constantly adapting their methods, and every country, including the United States, must keep adapting our own strategies to stay ahead of them. We&#8217;ve got to identify and acknowledge our own shortcomings and be willing to course correct when needed. The TIP Report can help us do that by laying out the significant steps the United States and other countries must take to fight this crime and protect victims.</p>
<p>In addition to the country data, this year’s report explores a few topics in depth. The first is the impact of COVID-19. In many places, as governments diverted resources to try to control the pandemic and address its secondary impacts, human traffickers seized the opportunity to grow their operations. People who were pushed into dire economic circumstances by the pandemic became more vulnerable to exploitation. And as more people spent hours online for school and work, traffickers used the internet to groom and recruit potential victims.</p>
<p>So the pandemic has had a real impact on this fight. It’s another reason why it’s so important to stop the pandemic as quickly as we can and help communities around the world. The longer it takes, the more people will become vulnerable to trafficking.</p>
<p>We applaud those governments that found ways to step up their work against trafficking even during COVID. For example, in Paraguay, as thousands of citizens abroad sought to return home, the government established temporary quarantine facilities at the border. They asked everyone screening questions, and through those questions they were able to identify nearly 300 victims of human trafficking. That’s nearly four times the average number of victims they had identified in previous years. Then the Paraguayan Government moved those victims to their own dedicated facilities, where they began receiving critical health and social support services right away. It was a brilliant strategy for moving fast to help victims of trafficking when the opportunity presented itself.</p>
<p>Second, this year’s report focuses on state-sponsored human trafficking. We documented 11 countries where the government itself is the trafficker – for example, through forced labor on public work projects or in sectors of the economy that the government feels are particularly important.</p>
<p>For the 10th year in a row, the report documents how the Cuban Government has profited from exploitative overseas medical missions. They send doctors and other medical personnel abroad, fail to inform them of the terms of their contracts, confiscate their documents and salaries, threaten them and their family members when they try to leave.</p>
<p>We also report on what’s happening in Xinjiang, in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region of China. The Chinese Government has detained more than 1 million people in as many as 1,200 state-run internment camps throughout Xinjiang. Many detainees are subjected to physical violence, sexual abuse, and torture to induce them to work producing apparel, electronics, solar equipment, agricultural products.</p>
<p>And while the practices are the most egregious in Xinjiang, this year’s report notes that China has subjected its citizens to coercive labor practices in other parts of the country as well. The United States has taken measures to stop Chinese goods made with forced labor from making their way into our country. For example, last year, the Departments of State, Commerce, Treasury, and Homeland Security issued a Xinjiang supply chain business advisory to alert U.S. companies of the economic, legal, and reputational exposure to or in connection with operations, supply chains, or laborers from Xinjiang.</p>
<p>We’ll continue to call on our partners around the world to join us in condemning China’s genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang and in taking steps to prevent goods made with forced labor from entering our supply chains. Governments should protect and serve their citizens, not terrorize and subjugate them for profit.</p>
<p>And third, the report explicitly acknowledges the connection between systemic inequality and human trafficking. This is something many countries need to grapple with, including the United States. Part of doing right by our people means taking a hard look at the ways that our history and our policies have created the conditions for crimes like human trafficking, because traffickers prey on those who are vulnerable – those who are less likely to have access to good jobs or educational opportunities, who are less likely to be treated as equal by police or the justice system, and who are less likely to be believed when they report that they’re being targeted or abused.</p>
<p>If we’re serious about ending trafficking in persons, we must also work to root out systemic racism, sexism, and other forms of discrimination, and to build a more equitable society in every dimension. These goals go hand in hand. So let’s keep that in mind as we work to build back better from the devastation of the pandemic.</p>
<p>I often talked about how the most urgent challenges facing our world cannot be solved by any one country acting alone. That’s true for stopping COVID, it’s true for dealing with the climate crisis, it’s true for the fight against human trafficking. We need to work together, share information, hold each other accountable. That’s how we’ll create a world where no one is exploited by trafficking and everyone is able to live in safety and in dignity.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for your strong message and those encouraging words. You have long been a champion for anchoring U.S. foreign policy on ensuring human dignity and expanding opportunities for all.</p>
<p>I am thrilled to now turn to celebrating the 2021 TIP Report Heroes. Traditionally we have honored these Heroes in-person at this event. While we wish we could be together, due to COVID-19 precautions, our Heroes are joining us virtually again this year.</p>
<p>To get to know each of our honorees better, we asked this year’s Heroes to prepare short videos answering: “What do you hope to achieve through your anti-trafficking work?” In the following video, you will hear their responses. I am certain you will understand why we are honoring each of them today.</p>
<p>Please join me as we recognize and honor this year’s eight TIP Report Heroes.</p>
<p>(Video is played.)</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Imelda Poole, in recognition of her exceptional activism in combating human trafficking in Albania and across Europe that has achieved systemic change through grassroots action, employing big picture solutions to address the root causes of vulnerability to the crime, and empowering those with lived experience through her organization’s principles of freedom, justice, truth, and joy.</p>
<p><b>MS POOLE:</b> Hello. My name is Imelda Poole. Working with Mary Ward Loreto in Albania and RENATE across Europe, my dream for the future is a social economy with a change in law and its implementation which will adopt a trauma-informed, victim-centered, and human rights approach to the law, both in its practice and in terms of real life. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Josiane Lina Bemaka-Soui, in recognition of her herculean efforts in creating and driving the Central African Republic’s anti-trafficking response by operationalizing the country’s interagency committee, leading the development of the government’s first national action plan to combat human trafficking, and catalyzing action even in difficult conditions at often great personal sacrifice.</p>
<p><b>MS BEMAKA-SOUI:</b> (Via translation) I am Josiane Lina Bemaka-Soui, Advisor to the President on the Protection of Children and Child Soldiers. With this award, my goal will be to completely eradicate human trafficking in the Central African Republic and establish a new legal code on protection of victims of human trafficking in my country.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Chantal Sagbo Sasse, in recognition of her unwavering and heartfelt commitment to the protection and care of child trafficking victims, her creativity and persistence in raising awareness among community members and government officials about human trafficking, and her invaluable anti-trafficking contributions and expertise shared with the Government of Gabon.</p>
<p><b>MS SAGBO:</b> (Via translation) Hello, everyone. I am Chantal Sagbo, president and founder of the NGO Sifos. Sifos is a non-profit organization that has worked over the last 20 years to promote and protect human rights. Our biggest focus is fighting human trafficking and exploitation. Our vision for 2022 is to build an education and training center for victims, so that they can become the leaders of tomorrow. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Shoichi Ibusuki, in recognition of his relentless persistence in advocating for the rights of foreign workers in Japan by providing legal representation to many who experienced exploitation, including forced labor, and by elevating the issue and insisting that the government strengthen its efforts to protect foreign workers.</p>
<p><b>MR IBUSUKI:</b> (Via translation) Hello. I am Ibusuki Shoichi from Tokyo. I am an attorney. Japan’s Technical Intern Training Program is a hotbed of human trafficking and intermediary exploitation. We aim to have this program abolished within the next few years. We will also create conditions where foreign workers can join together and insist on their rights. We will fight together with likeminded people around the world to fight human trafficking. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Shakhnoza Khassanova, in recognition of her extraordinary leadership in building the organizational capacity of civil society organizations and the judicial system in Kazakhstan to combat human trafficking, her central role in orchestrating humanitarian assistance and ensuring safe migration during the COVID-19 pandemic, and her steadfast dedication to the protection of vulnerable populations.</p>
<p><b>MS KHASSANOVA: </b> I’m Shakhnoza Khassanova, director of the public association, Legal Center for Women’s Initiatives, Sana Sezim, from Shymkent, Kazakhstan. It’s an honor to receive this prestigious Department of State TIP Hero Report Award. This award is a result of the ongoing joint effort of our team and all stakeholders who continue to provide assistance to migrant workers and victims of human trafficking during the pandemic. We hope that our cooperation in future will become stronger and continue contributing to fight against human trafficking. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Guillermina Cabrera Figueroa, in recognition of her resolute determination to hold human traffickers in Mexico accountable for their crimes, her persistent efforts to secure funding for the creation of multidisciplinary shelters for human trafficking victims, and her longstanding, dynamic leadership in the Attorney General’s Office.</p>
<p><b>MS CABRERA FIGUEROA:</b> (Via translation) Hello. I am Guillermina Cabrera Figueroa, Specialized Prosecutor for Trafficking in Persons at the Office of the Attorney General of Mexico. In the coming years, through my work fighting human trafficking, I hope to: strengthen my team with more training and resources; rescue more victims and give them specialized care so they can reintegrate into society; and bring more perpetrators to justice.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Mohammed al-Obaidly, in recognition of his pivotal leadership in the ongoing implementation of bold and sweeping reforms in Qatar to strengthen protections for foreign workers and prevent forced labor, his perseverance to instill real changes, and his tireless efforts to enhance collaboration and forge connections with workers, the business community, and foreign governments.</p>
<p><b>MR AL-OBAIDLY: </b> (Via translation) Hello. My name is Mohammed Hasan al-Obaidly. In the area of combating human trafficking, I would like to develop a guide for the country to identify trafficking in persons victims and provide them with assistance and protection. I also would like to enhance international cooperation and coordination to combat this crime by creating an integrated international law enforcement and security system to prevent, detect and expose human trafficking crimes and bring their perpetrators to justice.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE: </b>Rocio Mora-Nieto,<b> </b>in recognition of her exceptional dedication and efforts to combat sex trafficking in Spain for more than a quarter of a century, her unparalleled compassion and commitment for women exploited in commercial sex, and her highly effective outreach and victim-centered provision of services for victims of human trafficking.<b></b></p>
<p><b>MS NIETO:</b> (Via translation) I am Rocio Mora Nieto. I am the director of APRAMP Madrid, in Spain. I am very grateful for this award because it makes slavery visible. The slavery of thousands and thousands of women who are being trafficked for sexual exploitation. For me, it is crucial to give these women alternatives so that they can escape from this situation and have freedom and dignity in their lives so that no woman is a slave in our streets and in our industrial parks. Thank you very much.</p>
<p>(Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> What an inspiring group of leaders. It is such an honor to celebrate your important work.</p>
<p>The TIP Report represents a key tool to effect positive change and encourage governments to increase and improve their anti-trafficking efforts. This includes the United States.</p>
<p>As we evaluated the ongoing impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic on anti-trafficking efforts around the world for this year’s report, it was impossible to ignore the pandemic’s devastating effects. In the chaos and hardship of the last year, we have also seen excellent examples of leadership, resilience, adaptability across the anti-trafficking community – from international organizations to local NGOs, governments, and survivor leaders.</p>
<p>Mexico secured its first trafficking in persons conviction from a virtual court session in June 2020, just weeks after resuming legal proceedings following a two-month shutdown.</p>
<p>In Albania, Senegal, and Jordan, COVID-19 mitigation measures were combined with strategic outreach to populations vulnerable to trafficking.</p>
<p>In addition to these great adaptations, I want to highlight another excellent resource that the department will release in the coming weeks – a guidance document on COVID-19 considerations for anti-trafficking efforts – developed by our Human Trafficking Expert Consultant Network, which comprises individuals with lived experience of human trafficking and other subject matter experts. This guide will include promising practices and helpful standard operating procedures to continue anti-trafficking efforts during a crisis – like this pandemic – while still integrating a trauma-informed approach. Considerable work remains to address the challenges we still face related to the pandemic, but we hope this guidance will advance the integration of a trauma-informed approach into any new crisis-related adaptations.</p>
<p>For the last few years, we have sought to increasingly highlight through our report the importance of governments engaging with survivors and implementing trauma-informed approaches when doing so. We have done so, and our report is all the stronger for it. For the second year, Network experts developed the “Topics of Special Interest” for this year’s report – one about the unique complexities in familial trafficking and another about unifying trauma-informed practices and survivor leadership.</p>
<p>The Network also helped us evaluate and improve the process we use to select photos for the TIP Report. We did this in response to recommendations made in previous years by experts with lived experience of human trafficking. You will notice as you flip through the introduction that there are more photos that include the input of those survivors being photographed. I know we still have a long way to go to truly realize a trauma-informed approach across our anti-trafficking efforts, but I am thankful for the Network experts who helped us to make concrete improvements this year. We will continue to raise the importance of survivor engagement in building a truly effective, comprehensive anti-trafficking response – not just on paper through the TIP Report – but in our year-round engagement with governments around the world.</p>
<p>We know that we can do even better, and we will seek to hold ourselves and – accountable and be transparent in our efforts. I am encouraged by the innovative adaptations of governments, NGOs, and survivor leaders to ensure that our anti-trafficking response is comprehensive and addresses issues as they arise. I look forward to working with all of you to continue the fight against human trafficking.</p>
<p>Thank you again for joining us today, and please remember to go to <a href="http://state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1625257487712000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG6ZnQYIEQEeJPXejoWNj6RAHS1eA">state.gov</a> to access this year’s TIP Report online. Thank you all.</p>
<p>(Applause.)</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Dr. Kari Johnstone, Acting DirectorOffice to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Ben Franklin Room</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE: </b>Good afternoon, and welcome. My name is Kari Johnstone. I am the acting director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons.</p>
<p>Thank you all for joining us virtually to mark the release of the 2021 Trafficking in Persons Report, or the TIP Report. I am grateful to be here with Secretary of State Antony Blinken.</p>
<p>A quick word about our program today: First, Secretary Blinken will offer remarks on this year’s report. We will then honor this year’s eight wonderful TIP Report Heroes, who have dedicated their lives to combat human trafficking, and we will hear briefly from each of them in a pre-recorded video. I will offer brief closing remarks and then we hope you will click over to <a href="http://state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1625257487712000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG6ZnQYIEQEeJPXejoWNj6RAHS1eA">state.gov</a> to access the report online.</p>
<p>I would like to start by thanking our colleagues across the State Department, including our overseas embassies, for the strong collaboration and time spent to produce an accurate and comprehensive report. And I want to give a second thank you – a special thank you and kudos to the staff of the Trafficking in Persons Office for your dedication and commitment. Your long hours and hard work producing this report make a difference. And finally, thank you to our colleagues across the U.S. Government as well as our vital partners in NGOs and international organizations, those with lived experience of human trafficking, and other experts who contributed to the TIP Report and work to facilitate progress in addressing human trafficking year-round.</p>
<p>And it is now such an honor to join Secretary Blinken here today. Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for elevating the issue of human trafficking and for hosting today’s event. Under your leadership, we look forward to advancing our efforts to combat human trafficking.</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, Secretary of State Antony Blinken.</p>
<p>(Applause.)</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b>Thank you, Kari. Thank you very much for that introduction, but especially thank you for the terrific work leading the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons here at State. You and your team – and I know some of the team members are here with us today – did exceptional work producing this year’s report under the difficult circumstances of COVID-19.</p>
<p>Thanks to everyone else who&#8217;s here for joining us for what is a very important occasion. And a special thank you to the Heroes that we&#8217;re celebrating today, women and men around the world who have dedicated their careers to stopping human trafficking. They’re advocates, public servants, leaders of NGOs, and they help stop trafficking in all kinds of ways by supporting victims, helping to bring traffickers to justice, creating national action plans, addressing the root causes of trafficking.</p>
<p>In many ways, the fight against trafficking is fought on the local level, one community at a time. And we celebrate the brave people leading the fight, often at great risk to themselves. Trafficking in persons is an appalling crime. It&#8217;s a global crisis; it&#8217;s an enormous source of human suffering. By its nature, it&#8217;s often hidden from view. Exact figures are sometimes hard to determine. The estimate we often cite is that nearly 25 million people worldwide are victims of human trafficking. Many are compelled into commercial sex work. Many are forced to work in factories or fields, or to join armed groups. Millions of trafficking victims are children.</p>
<p>This crime is an affront to human rights; it&#8217;s an affront to human dignity. We fight it, you fight it, because it&#8217;s the right thing to do. It&#8217;s also in our interest to stop trafficking. We know it&#8217;s destabilizing to societies and to economies. So we must do everything we can as a country, but also as a global community, to stop trafficking wherever it occurs.</p>
<p>The State Department&#8217;s Trafficking in Persons Report is indeed the world&#8217;s most comprehensive resource of the anti-trafficking efforts being undertaken by governments around the globe. It reflects the United States longstanding commitment and bipartisan commitment to this issue. We see it from administration to administration, we see it in Congress, and it&#8217;s something that we should take pride in. It’s the product of a great deal of work by our team here in Washington, our embassies around the world, and by NGOs, by journalists, academics, and survivors who help us to identify and document trends in human trafficking so that governments worldwide can more effectively combat it.</p>
<p>Part of this report is our country data. This year, we assessed 188 countries, including the United States. Some made encouraging progress; some slid backward. It&#8217;s important to remember that progress against trafficking is rarely linear. Traffickers are constantly adapting their methods, and every country, including the United States, must keep adapting our own strategies to stay ahead of them. We&#8217;ve got to identify and acknowledge our own shortcomings and be willing to course correct when needed. The TIP Report can help us do that by laying out the significant steps the United States and other countries must take to fight this crime and protect victims.</p>
<p>In addition to the country data, this year’s report explores a few topics in depth. The first is the impact of COVID-19. In many places, as governments diverted resources to try to control the pandemic and address its secondary impacts, human traffickers seized the opportunity to grow their operations. People who were pushed into dire economic circumstances by the pandemic became more vulnerable to exploitation. And as more people spent hours online for school and work, traffickers used the internet to groom and recruit potential victims.</p>
<p>So the pandemic has had a real impact on this fight. It’s another reason why it’s so important to stop the pandemic as quickly as we can and help communities around the world. The longer it takes, the more people will become vulnerable to trafficking.</p>
<p>We applaud those governments that found ways to step up their work against trafficking even during COVID. For example, in Paraguay, as thousands of citizens abroad sought to return home, the government established temporary quarantine facilities at the border. They asked everyone screening questions, and through those questions they were able to identify nearly 300 victims of human trafficking. That’s nearly four times the average number of victims they had identified in previous years. Then the Paraguayan Government moved those victims to their own dedicated facilities, where they began receiving critical health and social support services right away. It was a brilliant strategy for moving fast to help victims of trafficking when the opportunity presented itself.</p>
<p>Second, this year’s report focuses on state-sponsored human trafficking. We documented 11 countries where the government itself is the trafficker – for example, through forced labor on public work projects or in sectors of the economy that the government feels are particularly important.</p>
<p>For the 10th year in a row, the report documents how the Cuban Government has profited from exploitative overseas medical missions. They send doctors and other medical personnel abroad, fail to inform them of the terms of their contracts, confiscate their documents and salaries, threaten them and their family members when they try to leave.</p>
<p>We also report on what’s happening in Xinjiang, in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region of China. The Chinese Government has detained more than 1 million people in as many as 1,200 state-run internment camps throughout Xinjiang. Many detainees are subjected to physical violence, sexual abuse, and torture to induce them to work producing apparel, electronics, solar equipment, agricultural products.</p>
<p>And while the practices are the most egregious in Xinjiang, this year’s report notes that China has subjected its citizens to coercive labor practices in other parts of the country as well. The United States has taken measures to stop Chinese goods made with forced labor from making their way into our country. For example, last year, the Departments of State, Commerce, Treasury, and Homeland Security issued a Xinjiang supply chain business advisory to alert U.S. companies of the economic, legal, and reputational exposure to or in connection with operations, supply chains, or laborers from Xinjiang.</p>
<p>We’ll continue to call on our partners around the world to join us in condemning China’s genocide and crimes against humanity in Xinjiang and in taking steps to prevent goods made with forced labor from entering our supply chains. Governments should protect and serve their citizens, not terrorize and subjugate them for profit.</p>
<p>And third, the report explicitly acknowledges the connection between systemic inequality and human trafficking. This is something many countries need to grapple with, including the United States. Part of doing right by our people means taking a hard look at the ways that our history and our policies have created the conditions for crimes like human trafficking, because traffickers prey on those who are vulnerable – those who are less likely to have access to good jobs or educational opportunities, who are less likely to be treated as equal by police or the justice system, and who are less likely to be believed when they report that they’re being targeted or abused.</p>
<p>If we’re serious about ending trafficking in persons, we must also work to root out systemic racism, sexism, and other forms of discrimination, and to build a more equitable society in every dimension. These goals go hand in hand. So let’s keep that in mind as we work to build back better from the devastation of the pandemic.</p>
<p>I often talked about how the most urgent challenges facing our world cannot be solved by any one country acting alone. That’s true for stopping COVID, it’s true for dealing with the climate crisis, it’s true for the fight against human trafficking. We need to work together, share information, hold each other accountable. That’s how we’ll create a world where no one is exploited by trafficking and everyone is able to live in safety and in dignity.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for your strong message and those encouraging words. You have long been a champion for anchoring U.S. foreign policy on ensuring human dignity and expanding opportunities for all.</p>
<p>I am thrilled to now turn to celebrating the 2021 TIP Report Heroes. Traditionally we have honored these Heroes in-person at this event. While we wish we could be together, due to COVID-19 precautions, our Heroes are joining us virtually again this year.</p>
<p>To get to know each of our honorees better, we asked this year’s Heroes to prepare short videos answering: “What do you hope to achieve through your anti-trafficking work?” In the following video, you will hear their responses. I am certain you will understand why we are honoring each of them today.</p>
<p>Please join me as we recognize and honor this year’s eight TIP Report Heroes.</p>
<p>(Video is played.)</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Imelda Poole, in recognition of her exceptional activism in combating human trafficking in Albania and across Europe that has achieved systemic change through grassroots action, employing big picture solutions to address the root causes of vulnerability to the crime, and empowering those with lived experience through her organization’s principles of freedom, justice, truth, and joy.</p>
<p><b>MS POOLE:</b> Hello. My name is Imelda Poole. Working with Mary Ward Loreto in Albania and RENATE across Europe, my dream for the future is a social economy with a change in law and its implementation which will adopt a trauma-informed, victim-centered, and human rights approach to the law, both in its practice and in terms of real life. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Josiane Lina Bemaka-Soui, in recognition of her herculean efforts in creating and driving the Central African Republic’s anti-trafficking response by operationalizing the country’s interagency committee, leading the development of the government’s first national action plan to combat human trafficking, and catalyzing action even in difficult conditions at often great personal sacrifice.</p>
<p><b>MS BEMAKA-SOUI:</b> (Via translation) I am Josiane Lina Bemaka-Soui, Advisor to the President on the Protection of Children and Child Soldiers. With this award, my goal will be to completely eradicate human trafficking in the Central African Republic and establish a new legal code on protection of victims of human trafficking in my country.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Chantal Sagbo Sasse, in recognition of her unwavering and heartfelt commitment to the protection and care of child trafficking victims, her creativity and persistence in raising awareness among community members and government officials about human trafficking, and her invaluable anti-trafficking contributions and expertise shared with the Government of Gabon.</p>
<p><b>MS SAGBO:</b> (Via translation) Hello, everyone. I am Chantal Sagbo, president and founder of the NGO Sifos. Sifos is a non-profit organization that has worked over the last 20 years to promote and protect human rights. Our biggest focus is fighting human trafficking and exploitation. Our vision for 2022 is to build an education and training center for victims, so that they can become the leaders of tomorrow. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Shoichi Ibusuki, in recognition of his relentless persistence in advocating for the rights of foreign workers in Japan by providing legal representation to many who experienced exploitation, including forced labor, and by elevating the issue and insisting that the government strengthen its efforts to protect foreign workers.</p>
<p><b>MR IBUSUKI:</b> (Via translation) Hello. I am Ibusuki Shoichi from Tokyo. I am an attorney. Japan’s Technical Intern Training Program is a hotbed of human trafficking and intermediary exploitation. We aim to have this program abolished within the next few years. We will also create conditions where foreign workers can join together and insist on their rights. We will fight together with likeminded people around the world to fight human trafficking. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Shakhnoza Khassanova, in recognition of her extraordinary leadership in building the organizational capacity of civil society organizations and the judicial system in Kazakhstan to combat human trafficking, her central role in orchestrating humanitarian assistance and ensuring safe migration during the COVID-19 pandemic, and her steadfast dedication to the protection of vulnerable populations.</p>
<p><b>MS KHASSANOVA: </b> I’m Shakhnoza Khassanova, director of the public association, Legal Center for Women’s Initiatives, Sana Sezim, from Shymkent, Kazakhstan. It’s an honor to receive this prestigious Department of State TIP Hero Report Award. This award is a result of the ongoing joint effort of our team and all stakeholders who continue to provide assistance to migrant workers and victims of human trafficking during the pandemic. We hope that our cooperation in future will become stronger and continue contributing to fight against human trafficking. Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Guillermina Cabrera Figueroa, in recognition of her resolute determination to hold human traffickers in Mexico accountable for their crimes, her persistent efforts to secure funding for the creation of multidisciplinary shelters for human trafficking victims, and her longstanding, dynamic leadership in the Attorney General’s Office.</p>
<p><b>MS CABRERA FIGUEROA:</b> (Via translation) Hello. I am Guillermina Cabrera Figueroa, Specialized Prosecutor for Trafficking in Persons at the Office of the Attorney General of Mexico. In the coming years, through my work fighting human trafficking, I hope to: strengthen my team with more training and resources; rescue more victims and give them specialized care so they can reintegrate into society; and bring more perpetrators to justice.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> Mohammed al-Obaidly, in recognition of his pivotal leadership in the ongoing implementation of bold and sweeping reforms in Qatar to strengthen protections for foreign workers and prevent forced labor, his perseverance to instill real changes, and his tireless efforts to enhance collaboration and forge connections with workers, the business community, and foreign governments.</p>
<p><b>MR AL-OBAIDLY: </b> (Via translation) Hello. My name is Mohammed Hasan al-Obaidly. In the area of combating human trafficking, I would like to develop a guide for the country to identify trafficking in persons victims and provide them with assistance and protection. I also would like to enhance international cooperation and coordination to combat this crime by creating an integrated international law enforcement and security system to prevent, detect and expose human trafficking crimes and bring their perpetrators to justice.</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE: </b>Rocio Mora-Nieto,<b> </b>in recognition of her exceptional dedication and efforts to combat sex trafficking in Spain for more than a quarter of a century, her unparalleled compassion and commitment for women exploited in commercial sex, and her highly effective outreach and victim-centered provision of services for victims of human trafficking.<b></b></p>
<p><b>MS NIETO:</b> (Via translation) I am Rocio Mora Nieto. I am the director of APRAMP Madrid, in Spain. I am very grateful for this award because it makes slavery visible. The slavery of thousands and thousands of women who are being trafficked for sexual exploitation. For me, it is crucial to give these women alternatives so that they can escape from this situation and have freedom and dignity in their lives so that no woman is a slave in our streets and in our industrial parks. Thank you very much.</p>
<p>(Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MS JOHNSTONE:</b> What an inspiring group of leaders. It is such an honor to celebrate your important work.</p>
<p>The TIP Report represents a key tool to effect positive change and encourage governments to increase and improve their anti-trafficking efforts. This includes the United States.</p>
<p>As we evaluated the ongoing impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic on anti-trafficking efforts around the world for this year’s report, it was impossible to ignore the pandemic’s devastating effects. In the chaos and hardship of the last year, we have also seen excellent examples of leadership, resilience, adaptability across the anti-trafficking community – from international organizations to local NGOs, governments, and survivor leaders.</p>
<p>Mexico secured its first trafficking in persons conviction from a virtual court session in June 2020, just weeks after resuming legal proceedings following a two-month shutdown.</p>
<p>In Albania, Senegal, and Jordan, COVID-19 mitigation measures were combined with strategic outreach to populations vulnerable to trafficking.</p>
<p>In addition to these great adaptations, I want to highlight another excellent resource that the department will release in the coming weeks – a guidance document on COVID-19 considerations for anti-trafficking efforts – developed by our Human Trafficking Expert Consultant Network, which comprises individuals with lived experience of human trafficking and other subject matter experts. This guide will include promising practices and helpful standard operating procedures to continue anti-trafficking efforts during a crisis – like this pandemic – while still integrating a trauma-informed approach. Considerable work remains to address the challenges we still face related to the pandemic, but we hope this guidance will advance the integration of a trauma-informed approach into any new crisis-related adaptations.</p>
<p>For the last few years, we have sought to increasingly highlight through our report the importance of governments engaging with survivors and implementing trauma-informed approaches when doing so. We have done so, and our report is all the stronger for it. For the second year, Network experts developed the “Topics of Special Interest” for this year’s report – one about the unique complexities in familial trafficking and another about unifying trauma-informed practices and survivor leadership.</p>
<p>The Network also helped us evaluate and improve the process we use to select photos for the TIP Report. We did this in response to recommendations made in previous years by experts with lived experience of human trafficking. You will notice as you flip through the introduction that there are more photos that include the input of those survivors being photographed. I know we still have a long way to go to truly realize a trauma-informed approach across our anti-trafficking efforts, but I am thankful for the Network experts who helped us to make concrete improvements this year. We will continue to raise the importance of survivor engagement in building a truly effective, comprehensive anti-trafficking response – not just on paper through the TIP Report – but in our year-round engagement with governments around the world.</p>
<p>We know that we can do even better, and we will seek to hold ourselves and – accountable and be transparent in our efforts. I am encouraged by the innovative adaptations of governments, NGOs, and survivor leaders to ensure that our anti-trafficking response is comprehensive and addresses issues as they arise. I look forward to working with all of you to continue the fight against human trafficking.</p>
<p>Thank you again for joining us today, and please remember to go to <a href="http://state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1625257487712000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG6ZnQYIEQEeJPXejoWNj6RAHS1eA">state.gov</a> to access this year’s TIP Report online. Thank you all.</p>
<p>(Applause.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
