<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 21:35:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Juan Carlos Lopez of CNN en Español</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-juan-carlos-lopez-of-cnn-en-espanol-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 21:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350822</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Los Angeles, California</p>
<p>Herald Examiner Building</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary.  <em>Gracias, Secretario Blinken, por la entrevista.  El Presidente Biden llega el miércoles.</em>  President Biden arrives on Wednesday.  That’s when the summit starts.  Before it even started, there are those calling it a failure and saying that it shows lack of leadership, of American leadership, to the region.  What is there to make this summit a success?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, I think the summit is going to be a success.  We’re already seeing that.  We have delegations – more than 60 delegations that are here.  We will have more than 20, I think 23 heads of government or heads of state who will be here.  And maybe as important as anything else, we have civil society, we have young people, we have the media, we have the business community – everyone coming together.  This is, of course, about the governments, but it’s also about the much broader community of the Americas, all of which is coming together here in Los Angeles over the next three days.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Nine heads of state won’t be here.  Three weren’t invited – Cuba, Venezuela, Nicaragua.  Three decided not to come because they weren’t invited – Mexico, Honduras, and Bolivia.  El Salvador and Guatemala didn’t come for other reasons, and Uruguay because the president has COVID.  Is it going to be the same, and is it a Summit of the Americas if these – if all the leaders aren’t here?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, first, it’s a democratic hemisphere – at least, that’s what we want and hope, and that’s something we want to affirm with this summit.  People can make their own decisions and choices about who’s here and who’s not.  But virtually all of these governments are represented in the formal summit of leaders at very senior levels – either the head of state or, in some cases, the foreign minister.  For example, my friend and counterpart Marcelo Ebrard from Mexico will be a full and active participant in this summit.</p>
<p>I can also tell you that Cuba, Venezuela, Nicaragua are here.  I saw them.  I met with them.  I met with civil society leaders and activists from Cuba, Venezuela, and Nicaragua.  There will be people from NGOs, from different parts of those societies, who are as representative and, frankly, more representative in my judgment of the Cuban, Nicaraguan, and Venezuelan people than the regimes that are in place right now, and they’ve very much a part of the summit.  I’ve already met with a number of them.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You were at Arizona State University.  You met with students.  You spoke about journalism and the challenges that journalists face &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  &#8212; in Cuba, in Nicaragua, in Venezuela.  And someone highlighted that you’re planning a trip to Saudi Arabia, which doesn’t respect journalists – we have the Jamal Khashoggi case – which isn’t considered a full democracy.  Isn’t there a double standard where the U.S. has a – is looking for a closer relationship with Saudi Arabia, a country that has oil, but signals Cuba, Venezuela, and Nicaragua and gets Andrés Manuel López Obrador to react and decide not to come?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, just in the case of Saudi Arabia, what we’ve said from the start of the administration is that we sought to recalibrate – not rupture, recalibrate – our relationship with Saudi Arabia to make sure that it reflected, better than we thought it did in the past, our own interests and our own values.  Part of that was putting human rights and freedom at the center of that relationship.</p>
<p>We did that, among other ways, by putting out, with the full imprimatur of the United States Government, the report on the murder of Jamal Khashoggi.  We did that by instituting something called the Khashoggi Ban, which enacts penalties against governments that seek to repress those who are engaged in criticizing the government when they do it from other countries, including from the United States.  At the same time, we have, as we do with countries in the hemisphere, broad relationships that have many interests in play.  We try to make – we try to account for all of them to best reflect our own interests and values.  But the President has been very clear that whether it’s Saudi Arabia or other partners around the world, or whether it’s adversaries, we are going to make sure that human rights is fully reflected in our foreign policy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Vice President Harris announced a 1.9 billion investment in Central America.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But there’s a caravan forming and coming up.  Now, it’s been very clear for months that they can’t get in.  Title 42 is in place.  There are measures for people not to be able to come in place.  Why aren’t these announcements working?  Why aren’t these measures working?  Why aren’t people listening?  And why do you think this has become such a focal issue in the United States that people are coming even if they can’t get in?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, there’s a lot going on here.  And the first thing to recognize is that we’re dealing with a challenge that is quite literally historic, by which I mean this:  Around the globe, there are more people on the move from their homes than at any time since World War II.  In our own hemisphere, there are more people on the move than at any time that anyone can remember.  And of course, it’s not only people in our hemisphere from Mexico, from El Salvador, from Honduras, from Guatemala, the so-called Northern Triangle countries; it’s also Venezuelans, it’s Nicaraguans, it’s Haitians, it’s Cubans, it’s Haitians and Cubans who have been living in other parts of the hemisphere who are moving north.</p>
<p>So we’re dealing with a challenge that, for a whole variety of reasons, is beyond anything that anyone has seen before, which is exactly why the approach that we’re taking, including here at the summit, is so important.  And that is an approach of shared responsibility, where everyone in the hemisphere who is affected by irregular migration in particular, migration more generally – that is, countries of origin, transit countries, countries of destination – come together to take shared responsibility for managing this in a safe, humane, and orderly way.  There’s going to be a declaration on migration coming out of the summit.  I think that’s a very important indicator of a new sense of shared responsibility.  We’re engaged in arrangements with different countries that also get at specific actions countries can take to try to deal with this challenge.</p>
<p>Ultimately, we – I think we both know this very well – there are short-term things that have to be done, but ultimately, this is a long-term challenge about dealing with what people famously called the root causes of migration.  What is it that causes someone to give up everything they know, to maybe leave behind their family, their culture, their language, their home, their community, and to make an incredibly perilous journey northward and toward the United States?  There has to be a profound driver for that to happen.  We have to address that.  We have to create opportunity for people where they live.</p>
<p>One of my colleagues in the hemisphere I remember at a meeting said that there should be a right to remain.  Well, we are working to put that into force by actually creating the investment, creating the opportunity that over time will give people that right to remain.  Meantime, countries are coming together to take shared responsibility for meeting this challenge today.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Before coming, President Bolsonaro, who will meet President Biden, once again questioned the legitimacy of President Biden’s victory, and that’s a country that’s supposed to be an ally.  Now the region is leaning left.  Lula could come back in Brazil.  There is a possibility that Petro could win in Colombia.  You have Xiomara Castro who had the Vice President go to her swearing-in, and she didn’t come.  Is the U.S. losing leverage?  Is the U.S. Government giving Russia and China the opportunity to expand their presence in the region?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Oh, I think on the contrary.  And again, I think after a few days of the summit when you see the conclusions that come out of this, when you see the concrete actions, commitments, principles that countries across the hemisphere are signing on to, I think it reflects an agenda – a common agenda – that is trying to be responsive to the needs of our people.</p>
<p>So whether it’s greater health security for our citizens, whether it’s dealing with the impacts of climate change and helping countries adapt and show real resilience, whether it’s dealing with the challenges of migration, whether it’s trying to deepen our democracies and show that they’re responsive to citizens’ needs.  All of this is exactly what we’re going to be talking about, and not only talking about – actually acting on.  And that’s a shared agenda for the overwhelming majority of the countries in this hemisphere.  It happens to reflect many of the things that we believe in as well.</p>
<p>So let’s see where we are after Friday when the summit concludes.  But I’ll also say this:  As important as these summits are, it’s as much the day-in, day-out work that we’re doing together.  I have been engaged on behalf of President Biden intensely in our hemisphere, working with so many countries and so many partners on these shared issues.  And there’s a common realization that I think most of us have, even when there’s a different political perspective sometimes being brought to bear, which is that these challenges like health and COVID, like climate, like the impact that all of these emerging technologies are having on us – no one country can effectively deal with them alone, even the United States.  We need to be acting in partnership.  I think there’s a realization of that.  And even if you’re coming at this from a different political perspective, that’s a common denominator that ultimately, I think, brings us together.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Secretary Antony Blinken, <em>muchas gracias</em> *for the time you are giving to us today.*</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  <em>Gracias</em>.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  It’s good to be with you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you for your time.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Los Angeles, California</p>
<p>Herald Examiner Building</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary.  <em>Gracias, Secretario Blinken, por la entrevista.  El Presidente Biden llega el miércoles.</em>  President Biden arrives on Wednesday.  That’s when the summit starts.  Before it even started, there are those calling it a failure and saying that it shows lack of leadership, of American leadership, to the region.  What is there to make this summit a success?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, I think the summit is going to be a success.  We’re already seeing that.  We have delegations – more than 60 delegations that are here.  We will have more than 20, I think 23 heads of government or heads of state who will be here.  And maybe as important as anything else, we have civil society, we have young people, we have the media, we have the business community – everyone coming together.  This is, of course, about the governments, but it’s also about the much broader community of the Americas, all of which is coming together here in Los Angeles over the next three days.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Nine heads of state won’t be here.  Three weren’t invited – Cuba, Venezuela, Nicaragua.  Three decided not to come because they weren’t invited – Mexico, Honduras, and Bolivia.  El Salvador and Guatemala didn’t come for other reasons, and Uruguay because the president has COVID.  Is it going to be the same, and is it a Summit of the Americas if these – if all the leaders aren’t here?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, first, it’s a democratic hemisphere – at least, that’s what we want and hope, and that’s something we want to affirm with this summit.  People can make their own decisions and choices about who’s here and who’s not.  But virtually all of these governments are represented in the formal summit of leaders at very senior levels – either the head of state or, in some cases, the foreign minister.  For example, my friend and counterpart Marcelo Ebrard from Mexico will be a full and active participant in this summit.</p>
<p>I can also tell you that Cuba, Venezuela, Nicaragua are here.  I saw them.  I met with them.  I met with civil society leaders and activists from Cuba, Venezuela, and Nicaragua.  There will be people from NGOs, from different parts of those societies, who are as representative and, frankly, more representative in my judgment of the Cuban, Nicaraguan, and Venezuelan people than the regimes that are in place right now, and they’ve very much a part of the summit.  I’ve already met with a number of them.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  You were at Arizona State University.  You met with students.  You spoke about journalism and the challenges that journalists face &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  &#8212; in Cuba, in Nicaragua, in Venezuela.  And someone highlighted that you’re planning a trip to Saudi Arabia, which doesn’t respect journalists – we have the Jamal Khashoggi case – which isn’t considered a full democracy.  Isn’t there a double standard where the U.S. has a – is looking for a closer relationship with Saudi Arabia, a country that has oil, but signals Cuba, Venezuela, and Nicaragua and gets Andrés Manuel López Obrador to react and decide not to come?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, just in the case of Saudi Arabia, what we’ve said from the start of the administration is that we sought to recalibrate – not rupture, recalibrate – our relationship with Saudi Arabia to make sure that it reflected, better than we thought it did in the past, our own interests and our own values.  Part of that was putting human rights and freedom at the center of that relationship.</p>
<p>We did that, among other ways, by putting out, with the full imprimatur of the United States Government, the report on the murder of Jamal Khashoggi.  We did that by instituting something called the Khashoggi Ban, which enacts penalties against governments that seek to repress those who are engaged in criticizing the government when they do it from other countries, including from the United States.  At the same time, we have, as we do with countries in the hemisphere, broad relationships that have many interests in play.  We try to make – we try to account for all of them to best reflect our own interests and values.  But the President has been very clear that whether it’s Saudi Arabia or other partners around the world, or whether it’s adversaries, we are going to make sure that human rights is fully reflected in our foreign policy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Vice President Harris announced a 1.9 billion investment in Central America.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But there’s a caravan forming and coming up.  Now, it’s been very clear for months that they can’t get in.  Title 42 is in place.  There are measures for people not to be able to come in place.  Why aren’t these announcements working?  Why aren’t these measures working?  Why aren’t people listening?  And why do you think this has become such a focal issue in the United States that people are coming even if they can’t get in?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, there’s a lot going on here.  And the first thing to recognize is that we’re dealing with a challenge that is quite literally historic, by which I mean this:  Around the globe, there are more people on the move from their homes than at any time since World War II.  In our own hemisphere, there are more people on the move than at any time that anyone can remember.  And of course, it’s not only people in our hemisphere from Mexico, from El Salvador, from Honduras, from Guatemala, the so-called Northern Triangle countries; it’s also Venezuelans, it’s Nicaraguans, it’s Haitians, it’s Cubans, it’s Haitians and Cubans who have been living in other parts of the hemisphere who are moving north.</p>
<p>So we’re dealing with a challenge that, for a whole variety of reasons, is beyond anything that anyone has seen before, which is exactly why the approach that we’re taking, including here at the summit, is so important.  And that is an approach of shared responsibility, where everyone in the hemisphere who is affected by irregular migration in particular, migration more generally – that is, countries of origin, transit countries, countries of destination – come together to take shared responsibility for managing this in a safe, humane, and orderly way.  There’s going to be a declaration on migration coming out of the summit.  I think that’s a very important indicator of a new sense of shared responsibility.  We’re engaged in arrangements with different countries that also get at specific actions countries can take to try to deal with this challenge.</p>
<p>Ultimately, we – I think we both know this very well – there are short-term things that have to be done, but ultimately, this is a long-term challenge about dealing with what people famously called the root causes of migration.  What is it that causes someone to give up everything they know, to maybe leave behind their family, their culture, their language, their home, their community, and to make an incredibly perilous journey northward and toward the United States?  There has to be a profound driver for that to happen.  We have to address that.  We have to create opportunity for people where they live.</p>
<p>One of my colleagues in the hemisphere I remember at a meeting said that there should be a right to remain.  Well, we are working to put that into force by actually creating the investment, creating the opportunity that over time will give people that right to remain.  Meantime, countries are coming together to take shared responsibility for meeting this challenge today.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Before coming, President Bolsonaro, who will meet President Biden, once again questioned the legitimacy of President Biden’s victory, and that’s a country that’s supposed to be an ally.  Now the region is leaning left.  Lula could come back in Brazil.  There is a possibility that Petro could win in Colombia.  You have Xiomara Castro who had the Vice President go to her swearing-in, and she didn’t come.  Is the U.S. losing leverage?  Is the U.S. Government giving Russia and China the opportunity to expand their presence in the region?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Oh, I think on the contrary.  And again, I think after a few days of the summit when you see the conclusions that come out of this, when you see the concrete actions, commitments, principles that countries across the hemisphere are signing on to, I think it reflects an agenda – a common agenda – that is trying to be responsive to the needs of our people.</p>
<p>So whether it’s greater health security for our citizens, whether it’s dealing with the impacts of climate change and helping countries adapt and show real resilience, whether it’s dealing with the challenges of migration, whether it’s trying to deepen our democracies and show that they’re responsive to citizens’ needs.  All of this is exactly what we’re going to be talking about, and not only talking about – actually acting on.  And that’s a shared agenda for the overwhelming majority of the countries in this hemisphere.  It happens to reflect many of the things that we believe in as well.</p>
<p>So let’s see where we are after Friday when the summit concludes.  But I’ll also say this:  As important as these summits are, it’s as much the day-in, day-out work that we’re doing together.  I have been engaged on behalf of President Biden intensely in our hemisphere, working with so many countries and so many partners on these shared issues.  And there’s a common realization that I think most of us have, even when there’s a different political perspective sometimes being brought to bear, which is that these challenges like health and COVID, like climate, like the impact that all of these emerging technologies are having on us – no one country can effectively deal with them alone, even the United States.  We need to be acting in partnership.  I think there’s a realization of that.  And even if you’re coming at this from a different political perspective, that’s a common denominator that ultimately, I think, brings us together.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Secretary Antony Blinken, <em>muchas gracias</em> *for the time you are giving to us today.*</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  <em>Gracias</em>.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  It’s good to be with you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you for your time.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Secretary General of the Organization of American States Luis Almagro At a Meeting of the Summit Implementation Review Group</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-secretary-general-of-the-organization-of-american-states-luis-almagro-at-a-meeting-of-the-summit-implementation-review-group/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 20:27:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350793</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Los Angeles, California</p>
<p>Los Angeles Convention Center</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  This is the great power of being the chair.  Again, welcome, everyone.  Good morning.  Welcome to Los Angeles.  It is wonderful to see my fellow ministers, all of your teams here for the Ninth Summit of the Americas.  And welcome to each of you.  Welcome to the Summit Implementation Review Group Ministerial.</p>
<p>For those of you who are not familiar with this group, it is made up of national coordinators from countries across our hemisphere, who negotiate the political commitments that our nations’ leaders will adopt at the summit in the days ahead.</p>
<p>Months of work have gone into the commitments that we’ll discuss today and to ensuring that our level of ambition meets the level of need of people across our shared hemisphere.  And let me simply say this:  We are deeply grateful for all of the efforts that our respective teams have made.  Thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>
<p>In particular, I’d like to thank my colleagues from Canada, Chile, Colombia, the Dominican Republic, Ecuador, Guyana, Jamaica, Panama, Peru, and Uruguay, each of whom chaired working groups on the summit’s five central themes: health and resilience, digital transformation, clean energy, environmental sustainability, and democratic governance.  Your leadership was crucial to reaching the consensus that I expect we’ll finalize today.</p>
<p>I’d also like to give a very special shout-out to our team’s summit coordinator, Kevin O’Reilly, and Kevin – where is Kevin?  Right.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  And our deputy coordinator, Dave Silverman, who is serving his seventh summit.  There’s got to be an award that goes with that.  So thank you both for remarkable service and remarkable work.</p>
<p>And I’ll say this, too:  I actually participated in the very first Summit of the Americas in 1994 in  Miami.  It’s wonderful to come full circle now here in Los Angeles.</p>
<p>To my friend and colleague, the secretary general of the OAS, Luis Almagro, welcome.  It’s wonderful to be working with you as always.  To Vice Chair Duclós Parodi, colleagues, the commitments that we will discuss are intended to address some of the most pressing challenges that we face in our hemisphere, including COVID-19; the climate crisis; deep inequity; and threats to democracy and human rights; as well, of course, as the migration crisis that all of these problems are contributing to drive even further.</p>
<p>We all know this from the work that we do every single day:  None of these challenges stay within our national borders, and they’re mutually reinforcing.  When individual countries don’t do enough to invest in detecting infectious disease or reducing emissions, it puts people across the region and the world at risk.  And we’ve seen, of course, how COVID-19 and the consequences of the climate crisis are hitting underserved communities the hardest, deepening inequities within our hemisphere.</p>
<p>Much like the problems, the solutions are interconnected.  And to be effective, they have to reach across borders.  That’s why we’re here.  That’s really what it comes down to.</p>
<p>Addressing these challenges also demands that we try to bridge the divide between domestic and foreign policy, whether we’re working to improve health security or energy security; defending an open, secure, reliable internet; or strengthening regulations to make sure that illicit finance cannot find a safe haven in any of our countries.  And you see that in the diverse teams that each of our countries has put together for these discussions and to try to tackle these problems.</p>
<p>Let me simply focus us now on the five areas that we will discuss today and that our leaders will take up later.</p>
<p>First, we will build greater health and pandemic resilience by strengthening our public health systems to ensure that people across our hemisphere have access to quality care.  That includes expanding people- and community-centered health services, investing in education and training in medicine, public health, nutrition, biomedical science research.  It also includes preparing for future health emergencies by strengthening our capacity to detect, to prevent, and to deal with future outbreaks of pandemics and other emergencies, improving coordination, transparency, accountability across the region, because when it comes to global health – we’ve learned this – we’re all in it together.</p>
<p>Second, we will establish the first-ever regional agenda on digital transformation to close an enduring digital divide in our societies so that all people can access and use the digital tools that are increasingly essential to their daily lives – from running a small business to getting an education.  The agenda will include expanding internet access, particularly in historically marginalized communities, driving innovation and social inclusion through increased access to digital government services.  It also includes expanding digital technology’s role in promoting quality education, digital literacy, digital citizenry.</p>
<p>Third, we will accelerate the region’s transition to clean energy, drawing on the strength, the knowledge, the capabilities of governance, but also businesses, NGOs, researchers, communities across our hemisphere.  We’ll make it easier to share technical knowledge and best practices; to foster greater collaboration with the private sector and other stakeholders to identify opportunities for manufacturing or trade in clean energy goods and services; we’ll advance sustainable, attainable, responsible mining sector principles; and secure the integration of mineral supply chains in our own hemisphere.</p>
<p>Fourth, we will double down on investing in climate resilience and adaptation to better equip our communities to deal with the changes to the environment that all of us are already experiencing, and which we know are going to grow no matter how effective we are in accelerating the shift to clean energy.  That includes meeting our commitments to halt and reverse deforestation, decreasing the amount of carbon from land use activities, increasing our capacity to store carbon.</p>
<p>Fifth and finally, we will recommit ourselves to one of the core aspirations that brought us together 30 years ago, when the United States hosted the first Summit of the Americas in Miami: advancing democracy.  We’ll push ourselves, we’ll push our neighbors across the region to shore up the rule of law, free and fair elections, human rights, and other pillars of free and open societies.  And we’ll work together to address common threats to our democracies, from corruption to disinformation.</p>
<p>We all know the democratic process is not always easy or swift.  That’s true within a single democracy.  It’s amplified when we bring together dozens of democracies, as we’ve done for this summit.  But the fact is we also acknowledge our shortcomings.  They’re out in the open.  We don’t sweep them under a rug.  And we work to try to address them together, and ultimately that is the greatest strength that we bring to the table as democracies.</p>
<p>And there are few regions in the world like this one, where you see so many democracies – from the left, from the right, from the center – that are able to set out a shared roadmap for addressing complex problems.  I think that’s something to celebrate even as we’re clear-eyed about all of the work that we have ahead of us.</p>
<p>Another strength is that we don’t lose sight of the people that we serve.  A big part of this process has actually been listening – to individual citizens, to NGOs, to young people, to communities, to businesses, including those that are critical of how we’re performing.  The input we sought from stakeholders has been crucial to understanding what our people actually need from us, what they expect of us, what we need to try to deliver together.</p>
<p>So going forward, citizens will be critical partners in carrying out these efforts and holding us to our commitments that we make here at the summit.  We’re here for a few days, but this is 365 days every year that matter.  And whatever we commit to here, we have to carry it forward.  We have to work on it every day.  We have to do it together.  That’s the spirit that we hope will come out of Los Angeles.</p>
<p>With that, it’s my pleasure to give the floor to Secretary General Almagro.  Luis.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY GENERAL ALMAGRO:</strong>  Thank you, Secretary of State.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) Thank you.  And we want to thank the United States Government, the SIRG, Secretary of State Blinken, for getting us together before the summit.  Ladies and gentlemen, ministers, foreign affairs coordinators, national coordinators, summit coordinators, participants, representatives of the joint working group – Joint Summit Working Group.</p>
<p>As secretary general and the technical secretariat and institutional memory of the summit process, as president of the Joint Summit Working Group, we want to congratulate the host country for their leadership and for assuming this enormous responsibility in this Summit of the Americas.</p>
<p>Since the summit was – became official in January of 2022, the president of SIRG has worked together with the participating delegates to include all the priorities.  When the United States launched the Summit of the Americas in 1994, it was considered then that the democratic leaders of the hemisphere would work together as true partners for prosperity.  Throughout the years, we have achieved important advances to achieve prosperity, democracy, and security in the Americas.</p>
<p>However, though some of the challenges we faced at the time still persist, the current challenge have no precedent, in contrast to the first summit with a true consensus around democracy.  Today, we definitely have to ensure that we achieve a democratic governance instrument as one fundamental to strengthen the democratic charter of the Americas.</p>
<p>The summit offers the leaders of the Americas the opportunity to reaffirm that commitment to democracy.  Citizens who achieve this and the peoples who achieve this authority is through the adoption of a plan of action geared to strengthen this democratic governance.  That’s why it’s more important than ever now that the governments, institutions, enterprises, and the citizens of the America work together to deal with these challenges and to create new opportunities to advance in the – with the objectives of the ninth summit.  In this context, the Government of the United States has shown true determination in bringing a series of proposals that are essential for the economic, social recovery of the nation.</p>
<p>The ninth Summit of the Americas takes place as an opportunity to catalyze these responses to face the challenges of the regional scenario in topics related to health, energy transition, digital transformation, the defense of the democratic principles, the social dynamics and the security dynamic and the migration issues.  In 2021, as a result of a series of consultations and dialogue with civil society, the national coordinators of the private sector summit and other involved sectors, they identified the priority topics for this host country.  The inputs in the consultation became a reality of conducing a sustainable, resilient, and equitable future.</p>
<p>As a result of the many challenges faced by the countries of the region, the later context of COVID must be taken advantage to promote a collective agenda for which we must strengthen the coordination of all agents and reinforce multilateral coordination in the inter-American system.  The whole system begins with this summit.  It does not end here.  It begins with the summit.</p>
<p>It’s a new period of partnerships in the Americas.  Today we have two entities of the inter-American system – United Nations, multilateral banks – who have actively participated throughout the negotiations.  I’ve had a chance to meet virtually with them, and we’ve closely followed the evolution of all the discussions, with interest in identifying, of course, the financing sources because these efforts require that we pay several bills.  And that’s the effort that the host country has promoted to find the solutions needed by the hemisphere.</p>
<p>And I want to end saying that in view of the social, political, economic, and health impacts caused by the COVID pandemic in the regions, it’s necessary that we go back to the Sustainable Development Goals, which means that we adopt strategic measures to deal with the systemic and structural deficiencies and shortcomings in the region.  This requires greater convergence amongst our institutions.</p>
<p>We call upon us to overcome differences so that we can truly achieve the implementation as a result of the work adopted.  The role of the technical secretariat of the summit process will continue to harmonize the efforts of all regional, public, and private agents to support member countries around all the priorities adopted at this summit.</p>
<p>I wish you a very productive and successful discussion and summit.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  <em>Gracias,</em> Luis.  Thank you very much.  We’ll take a moment to let our colleagues from the media leave the room.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Los Angeles, California</p>
<p>Los Angeles Convention Center</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  This is the great power of being the chair.  Again, welcome, everyone.  Good morning.  Welcome to Los Angeles.  It is wonderful to see my fellow ministers, all of your teams here for the Ninth Summit of the Americas.  And welcome to each of you.  Welcome to the Summit Implementation Review Group Ministerial.</p>
<p>For those of you who are not familiar with this group, it is made up of national coordinators from countries across our hemisphere, who negotiate the political commitments that our nations’ leaders will adopt at the summit in the days ahead.</p>
<p>Months of work have gone into the commitments that we’ll discuss today and to ensuring that our level of ambition meets the level of need of people across our shared hemisphere.  And let me simply say this:  We are deeply grateful for all of the efforts that our respective teams have made.  Thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>
<p>In particular, I’d like to thank my colleagues from Canada, Chile, Colombia, the Dominican Republic, Ecuador, Guyana, Jamaica, Panama, Peru, and Uruguay, each of whom chaired working groups on the summit’s five central themes: health and resilience, digital transformation, clean energy, environmental sustainability, and democratic governance.  Your leadership was crucial to reaching the consensus that I expect we’ll finalize today.</p>
<p>I’d also like to give a very special shout-out to our team’s summit coordinator, Kevin O’Reilly, and Kevin – where is Kevin?  Right.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  And our deputy coordinator, Dave Silverman, who is serving his seventh summit.  There’s got to be an award that goes with that.  So thank you both for remarkable service and remarkable work.</p>
<p>And I’ll say this, too:  I actually participated in the very first Summit of the Americas in 1994 in  Miami.  It’s wonderful to come full circle now here in Los Angeles.</p>
<p>To my friend and colleague, the secretary general of the OAS, Luis Almagro, welcome.  It’s wonderful to be working with you as always.  To Vice Chair Duclós Parodi, colleagues, the commitments that we will discuss are intended to address some of the most pressing challenges that we face in our hemisphere, including COVID-19; the climate crisis; deep inequity; and threats to democracy and human rights; as well, of course, as the migration crisis that all of these problems are contributing to drive even further.</p>
<p>We all know this from the work that we do every single day:  None of these challenges stay within our national borders, and they’re mutually reinforcing.  When individual countries don’t do enough to invest in detecting infectious disease or reducing emissions, it puts people across the region and the world at risk.  And we’ve seen, of course, how COVID-19 and the consequences of the climate crisis are hitting underserved communities the hardest, deepening inequities within our hemisphere.</p>
<p>Much like the problems, the solutions are interconnected.  And to be effective, they have to reach across borders.  That’s why we’re here.  That’s really what it comes down to.</p>
<p>Addressing these challenges also demands that we try to bridge the divide between domestic and foreign policy, whether we’re working to improve health security or energy security; defending an open, secure, reliable internet; or strengthening regulations to make sure that illicit finance cannot find a safe haven in any of our countries.  And you see that in the diverse teams that each of our countries has put together for these discussions and to try to tackle these problems.</p>
<p>Let me simply focus us now on the five areas that we will discuss today and that our leaders will take up later.</p>
<p>First, we will build greater health and pandemic resilience by strengthening our public health systems to ensure that people across our hemisphere have access to quality care.  That includes expanding people- and community-centered health services, investing in education and training in medicine, public health, nutrition, biomedical science research.  It also includes preparing for future health emergencies by strengthening our capacity to detect, to prevent, and to deal with future outbreaks of pandemics and other emergencies, improving coordination, transparency, accountability across the region, because when it comes to global health – we’ve learned this – we’re all in it together.</p>
<p>Second, we will establish the first-ever regional agenda on digital transformation to close an enduring digital divide in our societies so that all people can access and use the digital tools that are increasingly essential to their daily lives – from running a small business to getting an education.  The agenda will include expanding internet access, particularly in historically marginalized communities, driving innovation and social inclusion through increased access to digital government services.  It also includes expanding digital technology’s role in promoting quality education, digital literacy, digital citizenry.</p>
<p>Third, we will accelerate the region’s transition to clean energy, drawing on the strength, the knowledge, the capabilities of governance, but also businesses, NGOs, researchers, communities across our hemisphere.  We’ll make it easier to share technical knowledge and best practices; to foster greater collaboration with the private sector and other stakeholders to identify opportunities for manufacturing or trade in clean energy goods and services; we’ll advance sustainable, attainable, responsible mining sector principles; and secure the integration of mineral supply chains in our own hemisphere.</p>
<p>Fourth, we will double down on investing in climate resilience and adaptation to better equip our communities to deal with the changes to the environment that all of us are already experiencing, and which we know are going to grow no matter how effective we are in accelerating the shift to clean energy.  That includes meeting our commitments to halt and reverse deforestation, decreasing the amount of carbon from land use activities, increasing our capacity to store carbon.</p>
<p>Fifth and finally, we will recommit ourselves to one of the core aspirations that brought us together 30 years ago, when the United States hosted the first Summit of the Americas in Miami: advancing democracy.  We’ll push ourselves, we’ll push our neighbors across the region to shore up the rule of law, free and fair elections, human rights, and other pillars of free and open societies.  And we’ll work together to address common threats to our democracies, from corruption to disinformation.</p>
<p>We all know the democratic process is not always easy or swift.  That’s true within a single democracy.  It’s amplified when we bring together dozens of democracies, as we’ve done for this summit.  But the fact is we also acknowledge our shortcomings.  They’re out in the open.  We don’t sweep them under a rug.  And we work to try to address them together, and ultimately that is the greatest strength that we bring to the table as democracies.</p>
<p>And there are few regions in the world like this one, where you see so many democracies – from the left, from the right, from the center – that are able to set out a shared roadmap for addressing complex problems.  I think that’s something to celebrate even as we’re clear-eyed about all of the work that we have ahead of us.</p>
<p>Another strength is that we don’t lose sight of the people that we serve.  A big part of this process has actually been listening – to individual citizens, to NGOs, to young people, to communities, to businesses, including those that are critical of how we’re performing.  The input we sought from stakeholders has been crucial to understanding what our people actually need from us, what they expect of us, what we need to try to deliver together.</p>
<p>So going forward, citizens will be critical partners in carrying out these efforts and holding us to our commitments that we make here at the summit.  We’re here for a few days, but this is 365 days every year that matter.  And whatever we commit to here, we have to carry it forward.  We have to work on it every day.  We have to do it together.  That’s the spirit that we hope will come out of Los Angeles.</p>
<p>With that, it’s my pleasure to give the floor to Secretary General Almagro.  Luis.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY GENERAL ALMAGRO:</strong>  Thank you, Secretary of State.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) Thank you.  And we want to thank the United States Government, the SIRG, Secretary of State Blinken, for getting us together before the summit.  Ladies and gentlemen, ministers, foreign affairs coordinators, national coordinators, summit coordinators, participants, representatives of the joint working group – Joint Summit Working Group.</p>
<p>As secretary general and the technical secretariat and institutional memory of the summit process, as president of the Joint Summit Working Group, we want to congratulate the host country for their leadership and for assuming this enormous responsibility in this Summit of the Americas.</p>
<p>Since the summit was – became official in January of 2022, the president of SIRG has worked together with the participating delegates to include all the priorities.  When the United States launched the Summit of the Americas in 1994, it was considered then that the democratic leaders of the hemisphere would work together as true partners for prosperity.  Throughout the years, we have achieved important advances to achieve prosperity, democracy, and security in the Americas.</p>
<p>However, though some of the challenges we faced at the time still persist, the current challenge have no precedent, in contrast to the first summit with a true consensus around democracy.  Today, we definitely have to ensure that we achieve a democratic governance instrument as one fundamental to strengthen the democratic charter of the Americas.</p>
<p>The summit offers the leaders of the Americas the opportunity to reaffirm that commitment to democracy.  Citizens who achieve this and the peoples who achieve this authority is through the adoption of a plan of action geared to strengthen this democratic governance.  That’s why it’s more important than ever now that the governments, institutions, enterprises, and the citizens of the America work together to deal with these challenges and to create new opportunities to advance in the – with the objectives of the ninth summit.  In this context, the Government of the United States has shown true determination in bringing a series of proposals that are essential for the economic, social recovery of the nation.</p>
<p>The ninth Summit of the Americas takes place as an opportunity to catalyze these responses to face the challenges of the regional scenario in topics related to health, energy transition, digital transformation, the defense of the democratic principles, the social dynamics and the security dynamic and the migration issues.  In 2021, as a result of a series of consultations and dialogue with civil society, the national coordinators of the private sector summit and other involved sectors, they identified the priority topics for this host country.  The inputs in the consultation became a reality of conducing a sustainable, resilient, and equitable future.</p>
<p>As a result of the many challenges faced by the countries of the region, the later context of COVID must be taken advantage to promote a collective agenda for which we must strengthen the coordination of all agents and reinforce multilateral coordination in the inter-American system.  The whole system begins with this summit.  It does not end here.  It begins with the summit.</p>
<p>It’s a new period of partnerships in the Americas.  Today we have two entities of the inter-American system – United Nations, multilateral banks – who have actively participated throughout the negotiations.  I’ve had a chance to meet virtually with them, and we’ve closely followed the evolution of all the discussions, with interest in identifying, of course, the financing sources because these efforts require that we pay several bills.  And that’s the effort that the host country has promoted to find the solutions needed by the hemisphere.</p>
<p>And I want to end saying that in view of the social, political, economic, and health impacts caused by the COVID pandemic in the regions, it’s necessary that we go back to the Sustainable Development Goals, which means that we adopt strategic measures to deal with the systemic and structural deficiencies and shortcomings in the region.  This requires greater convergence amongst our institutions.</p>
<p>We call upon us to overcome differences so that we can truly achieve the implementation as a result of the work adopted.  The role of the technical secretariat of the summit process will continue to harmonize the efforts of all regional, public, and private agents to support member countries around all the priorities adopted at this summit.</p>
<p>I wish you a very productive and successful discussion and summit.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  <em>Gracias,</em> Luis.  Thank you very much.  We’ll take a moment to let our colleagues from the media leave the room.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>World Ocean Day  </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/world-ocean-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:24:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350762</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The health and productivity of our ocean is under threat. Greenhouse gas emissions are making our ocean warmer, higher, more acidic, and less productive. Meanwhile, illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing is threatening fish stocks and marine biodiversity, while plastic pollution is choking our ocean.</p>
<p>The ocean crisis is a climate crisis, and the United States is leading the world in efforts to confront these multifaceted threats. We continue to urge all countries — especially major emitters — whose 2030 Nationally Determined Contribution (NDC) targets are not yet aligned with a 1.5-degree Celsius pathway to increase the ambition of these 2030 targets ahead of COP27. Through President Biden’s Emergency Plan for Adaptation and Resilience (PREPARE), we are focused on helping more than 500 million people in developing countries adapt to and manage climate impacts, including ocean-climate impacts. We are also working to leverage the power of ocean-based climate solutions, including green shipping, to help keep the 1.5-degree Celsius target within reach. For example, we are working with countries in the International Maritime Organization to adopt a goal of zero emissions from international shipping no later than 2050 and have announced a Green Shipping Challenge for COP27 to help spur concrete action this decade that will help put the sector on a credible pathway toward full decarbonization.</p>
<p>The United States co-hosted the Our Ocean Conference with Palau in April 2022, when we announced plans totaling nearly $250 million to combat IUU fishing through policy initiatives, strengthened governance, and innovative forms of monitoring and traceability. These measures are designed not only to protect marine biodiversity and fish stocks, but also the coastal communities that depend on them for their livelihoods. We are helping partners and allies implement the Port State Measures Agreement, the first binding international agreement to specifically target IUU fishing.</p>
<p>The United States is also leading the charge to combat the flow of an estimated 8 to 11 million tons of plastic waste into the ocean each year. At the second session of the fifth UN Environment Assembly in Nairobi in March 2022, the United States was proud to join other nations in adopting a resolution launching negotiations on a global agreement on plastic pollution that would address the full lifecycle of plastics and take an ambitious, innovative, and country-driven approach. Such a global agreement will be a critical step in cleaning up our ocean and has been hailed as the most important step forward on the environment since the Paris Agreement. As we work with the rest of the world toward this global agreement, the United States is taking action now to combat plastic pollution—both domestically and internationally. For example, we are working with other countries to build capacity to improve environmentally-sound waste management and to reduce the amount of abandoned, lost, or otherwise discarded fishing gear in the ocean.</p>
<p>In the face of these challenges, we must continue to protect and enhance the resilience of fragile marine ecosystems. The United States has established nearly 1,000 marine protected areas in our ocean, estuaries, coastal waters, and Great Lakes, and we are continuing to work towards the goal of conserving 30 percent of our land and waters by 2030, as directed by President Biden. We encourage all countries to take equally ambitious action by committing to conserving or protecting 30 percent of their land and waters by 2030, including their national ocean waters, by joining the Ocean Conservation Pledge launched at the 2022 Our Ocean Conference.</p>
<p>Additionally, we look forward to supporting the Eastern Tropical Pacific Marine Corridor, a precedent-setting regional effort created by the governments of Colombia, Costa Rica, Ecuador, and Panama. We are also the current chair of the International Coral Reef Initiative, a unique partnership of governments, international organizations, scientific entities, and non-governmental organizations, where we are committed to increasing global efforts to protect and restore coral reefs.</p>
<p>We recognize that the decisions we make and the actions we take today will affect the health of our ocean for centuries to come. The United States will continue our efforts and work with our allies and partners to protect our ocean and secure a better future for the planet.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The health and productivity of our ocean is under threat. Greenhouse gas emissions are making our ocean warmer, higher, more acidic, and less productive. Meanwhile, illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing is threatening fish stocks and marine biodiversity, while plastic pollution is choking our ocean.</p>
<p>The ocean crisis is a climate crisis, and the United States is leading the world in efforts to confront these multifaceted threats. We continue to urge all countries — especially major emitters — whose 2030 Nationally Determined Contribution (NDC) targets are not yet aligned with a 1.5-degree Celsius pathway to increase the ambition of these 2030 targets ahead of COP27. Through President Biden’s Emergency Plan for Adaptation and Resilience (PREPARE), we are focused on helping more than 500 million people in developing countries adapt to and manage climate impacts, including ocean-climate impacts. We are also working to leverage the power of ocean-based climate solutions, including green shipping, to help keep the 1.5-degree Celsius target within reach. For example, we are working with countries in the International Maritime Organization to adopt a goal of zero emissions from international shipping no later than 2050 and have announced a Green Shipping Challenge for COP27 to help spur concrete action this decade that will help put the sector on a credible pathway toward full decarbonization.</p>
<p>The United States co-hosted the Our Ocean Conference with Palau in April 2022, when we announced plans totaling nearly $250 million to combat IUU fishing through policy initiatives, strengthened governance, and innovative forms of monitoring and traceability. These measures are designed not only to protect marine biodiversity and fish stocks, but also the coastal communities that depend on them for their livelihoods. We are helping partners and allies implement the Port State Measures Agreement, the first binding international agreement to specifically target IUU fishing.</p>
<p>The United States is also leading the charge to combat the flow of an estimated 8 to 11 million tons of plastic waste into the ocean each year. At the second session of the fifth UN Environment Assembly in Nairobi in March 2022, the United States was proud to join other nations in adopting a resolution launching negotiations on a global agreement on plastic pollution that would address the full lifecycle of plastics and take an ambitious, innovative, and country-driven approach. Such a global agreement will be a critical step in cleaning up our ocean and has been hailed as the most important step forward on the environment since the Paris Agreement. As we work with the rest of the world toward this global agreement, the United States is taking action now to combat plastic pollution—both domestically and internationally. For example, we are working with other countries to build capacity to improve environmentally-sound waste management and to reduce the amount of abandoned, lost, or otherwise discarded fishing gear in the ocean.</p>
<p>In the face of these challenges, we must continue to protect and enhance the resilience of fragile marine ecosystems. The United States has established nearly 1,000 marine protected areas in our ocean, estuaries, coastal waters, and Great Lakes, and we are continuing to work towards the goal of conserving 30 percent of our land and waters by 2030, as directed by President Biden. We encourage all countries to take equally ambitious action by committing to conserving or protecting 30 percent of their land and waters by 2030, including their national ocean waters, by joining the Ocean Conservation Pledge launched at the 2022 Our Ocean Conference.</p>
<p>Additionally, we look forward to supporting the Eastern Tropical Pacific Marine Corridor, a precedent-setting regional effort created by the governments of Colombia, Costa Rica, Ecuador, and Panama. We are also the current chair of the International Coral Reef Initiative, a unique partnership of governments, international organizations, scientific entities, and non-governmental organizations, where we are committed to increasing global efforts to protect and restore coral reefs.</p>
<p>We recognize that the decisions we make and the actions we take today will affect the health of our ocean for centuries to come. The United States will continue our efforts and work with our allies and partners to protect our ocean and secure a better future for the planet.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Executive Vice President and Head of International Affairs at the U.S. Chamber of Commerce Myron Brillant At the CEO Summit of the Americas</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-executive-vice-president-and-head-of-international-affairs-at-the-u-s-chamber-of-commerce-myron-brillant-at-the-ceo-summit-of-the-americas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350742</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Los Angeles, California</p>
<p> InterContinental Hotel</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Well, Mr. Secretary, first off let me just say thank you for being here with us today.  And I just want to acknowledge upfront the strong partnership that we’ve had with the State Department in putting together the 4th annual Summit of the Americas.  And I want to give a shoutout to Jose Fernandez, the under secretary of state, and to Assistant Secretary Brian Nichols, but to your entire team &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>&#8212; because this is going to be, I know, a crazy week for the State Department.  And I want to begin by just acknowledging how complex and challenging a time it is for the U.S. Government, for the world community – the conflict in Europe, obviously the challenges with the U.S.-China relationship, and more broadly the issues you’re grappling with. So the fact that you’re here today at this summit, we very much greatly appreciate.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thanks, Myron.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>I want to ask you, Mr. Secretary, at the outset:  As you look at this Summit of Americas, and not just the CEO summit of it but the broader summit that President Biden and you are engaging with all these leaders from the region, tell us what’s important about it as you look at the foreign policy agenda, the administration, you think about it regionally, you think about it globally.  How does this summit fit into it?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, first, Myron, thank you.  Thank you for this partnership on our end, too.  We can’t do it without you.  We’ve had a partnership in so many ways with the Chamber across so many issues.  I think it’s especially important in our own hemisphere, so I’m grateful for everything that you’ve done and that the Chamber has done to be such an important presence here at the summit over the next three days.  Hugely, hugely, important.</p>
<p>And this is a critical moment for us.  On one level, it’s pretty simple, and it’s obvious but it’s no more – no less important for being obvious.  No other region in the world has the same direct impact on the lives and livelihoods of Americans than the hemisphere that we share.  It’s as simple as that.  So to some extent as goes the hemisphere, so go we.  And so we have a real stake in making sure that, together, we get this right.  And again, to state the obvious, this is a time of incredible challenge for all of us.  We’ve had a confluence of almost perfect storm events over the last few years that have had a profound effect here in the Americas: COVID, climate, some – a democratic deficit, migration, and of course the daily and changing impact of technologies on the lives of everyone.  You put all that together, we’ve lost 2.7 million lives &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>&#8212; from COVID in our hemisphere.  Our hemisphere has suffered the most from COVID.  At the same time, it’s 30 percent of global GDP.  If we get our act together and mobilize that effectively, there is so much we can do.  The leaders have not met in more than four years.  It’s time.</p>
<p>But to your point, and this is what I find so vital about this summit, as important as the government-to-government work is, that is far from the sum and substance of this gathering.  We have the business community, we have civil society, we have young people, we have all the different stakeholders in our hemisphere.  And if these three days, four days can galvanize some collective action together and then we can take that from the summit, I think we’ll have done a good thing.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Well, Mr. Secretary, thank you for framing it in the context of all the things that this region has to think about – the pandemic, the return to health and the return to stronger economies.  You have an economic plan that you want to talk about at this summit.  Can you give us a preview about what that economic plan looks like and a little bit about how the private sector will play into that economic plan?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, first, never get ahead of your boss, so the President &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Just a little bit of a &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Just a little bit.  The President’s going to be speaking to this later today, and I’m very excited about that.  It dovetails with a number of things that we’re doing here.  First, we have – with our partners throughout the region, we have a number of areas and issues that we’re trying to drive together.  There’s going to be a lengthy summit declaration that you’ll see that actually focuses in our work together on a number of areas, and the President’s economic plan dovetails with those areas.</p>
<p>So for example, we need to build greater health resilience in our hemisphere in two ways: we need to be better prepared to manage a future pandemic, but also in the daily lives of people.  We need to be able to provide better basic health services.  There are huge disparities.  One of the great things coming out of the summit – and this is where the private sector also is critical – is we have a commitment over the next couple of years to train 500,000 health professionals, generalists and specialists.  That’s going to make a huge difference if they are effectively deployed throughout our hemisphere in raising the basic level of health services.  That’s one, but the president’s going to address some of that.</p>
<p>Second, on the climate and energy agenda, there are huge needs but also huge opportunities to come together in a way that actually is beneficial to our economies and also beneficial to climate, beneficial to our energy security and infrastructure development.  He will speak to that.  We have to do more and we will do more in a positive way to bridge digital divides that exist within our countries, but also within the hemisphere itself.  Facilitating digital trade, doing it in a way that’s secure, that upholds basic democratic principles, but that also is much more inclusive so that we bridge some of these divides.  That’s going to be a big part of it.</p>
<p>But also – and this is really imperative and this is, again, where our partnership with the private sector is so important – we have to find ways together and make good on commitments together to create an environment in which business can really work effectively.</p>
<p>So we know there remain huge challenges when it comes to everything from regulatory frameworks to corruption.  It is vital that all of our partners – and we – work together to deal with these.  Because, for example, as we’ve discussed, there’s a lot of capital out there.  But it’s not going to be deployed if the environment in which you want to deploy it is simply too risky and too complicated.</p>
<p>We have these conversations all the time with our counterparts.  Hearing it from us is one thing; I think hearing it from the business community directly, that’s important too.  So the President’s going to address all that.</p>
<p>There are huge infrastructure demands throughout the world; there are huge infrastructure demands in our hemisphere.  How do we facilitate making sure that the government is playing its part in helping to support viable projects, in helping to mobilize capital?  All of that will be there.  I don’t want to get too far ahead of where he’s going to be; stay tuned.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Always smart not to get ahead of POTUS, of the President, your boss.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yes, it’s a good rule.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Look, you talked about energy security, you talked about the digital transformation, you talked about digital trade – all these are important areas for business to be in partnership with government, and not just our government but governments around the region.  How receptive is the message being heard in the region?  Now, I know you’re going to begin your bilaterals over the next couple days, you’ll have the big summit – do you see government leaders across the region understanding that this is a critical moment to come together?  Because we see quite a bit of change politically in the region, and I wonder how that factors into what you’re trying to achieve.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, look.  One of the, I think, strengths, in a sense, of our region, is – look, there are political differences.  We have democratic governments of the left, of the right, and of the center.  But despite what political differences there are, if the fundamentals are there, we’re going to be able to work very, very effectively together.  And whether it’s of the left, the right, or the center, there’s a common challenge for every single democracy in our hemisphere, and that’s to actually deliver concrete results for people.  One of the reasons you may see changes in governance is simply because people have lost faith in the – whatever the current existing administration is in a given country, whether it’s left, right, or center, in its ability to deliver practical things, concrete things.</p>
<p>So my sense, Myron, is in our conversations, governments are very motivated to figure out how do we actually deliver.  And it’s partly because it’s the right and necessary thing to do.  It’s probably the politically self-preservation thing to do as well.</p>
<p>So I think we have to work with that, work with partners, and find ways together to support change that creates the right environment – again, to, among other things, mobilize capital throughout the hemisphere.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Well, all those are very important principles and issues to think about.  One thing that you’ve talked about but I want to get a little deeper on is the rule of law &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yep.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  For business leaders, rule of law is fundamental.  We need certainty, we need transparency, we need accountability, and by the way, we want to be accountable also to the system.  Talk to me about the Alliance for Development in Democracy.  You have this pathway with a couple of countries in the region.  I’m sure you want to expand that to others.  How does that fit into this narrative, and how does it link up to the business community in terms of us working with you?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So I think this is a terrific initiative and it brings together, as you know, Costa Rica, the Dominican Republic, Panama.  In fact, I had my counterparts from those countries in Washington three or four months ago for a meeting of this alliance.  And we’re focused on very practical things like: how do we make governance work better for people, how do we make sure it’s inclusive, and how do we make sure that it does exactly what we’re talking about, it creates a better environment for, among other things, investment?</p>
<p>So one of the things we talked about is using some of the digital tools that have been developed to make sure governments adopt them.  That’s a way of combatting corruption, which is one of the single biggest challenges we face not only in the hemisphere, but around the world.  It cuts through red tape, so that also helps create a better business environment.  These are the kinds of initiatives that, in a very practical way, we’re trying to bring together.  And if we can demonstrate among a small number of countries that this works, I expect that’ll expand to others as well.</p>
<p><strong>BRILLIANT:</strong>  What does success look like at the end of this summit?  After our CEO summit, after your summit that the President leads, what does success look like, and how do we go forward and make sure that whatever is discussed here, we take into action?  And here, you can challenge the private sector.  We need to play a role.  But what does success look like?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Look, I think the private sector’s a critical partner on virtually everything that we’re doing.  And in fact, one of the greatest strengths we bring to the table is our ability to work together with the private sector in ways that other countries don’t or can’t.  So we want to see that mobilized to the greatest extent possible.</p>
<p>I think when it comes to the issues we’ve talked about, when it comes to basic good governance, when it comes to transparency, when it comes to rule of law, when it comes to combatting corruption, I think that’s something that the private sector rightly should and must insist on.  And hearing it directly from the private sector makes a big difference.  Certainly our partners hear it from us, and of course we have to deal with our own challenges, as we are.</p>
<p>But what does success look like?  It’s two things.  Yes, it’s what gets agreed at this – at the summit.  There’ll be important commitments; there’ll be important initiatives; there’ll be important declarations of intent.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Right.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>But three days is not 365 days.  This has to be done over 365 days.  We have to hold ourselves accountable to what is agreed here, the commitments that all of us make to try to move forward, and then really see where we are at every step along the way.  Are we delivering on that intent?  We’re not going to know that right away.  So look, I think we’ll have important – the lingo that we use – deliverables.  We’ll have good deliverables.  But the deliverables are only as good as their implementation.  They’re only as good as the sustained commitment to getting them done.</p>
<p>So maybe we should come back together in Los Angeles in a year’s time and see how we’re doing.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT: </strong> Los Angeles or others?  Well, this is the City of Angels, so I shouldn’t say other cities.  But we’ve got a lot of great cities in this country that would be happy to have this forum.</p>
<p>Look, I know you have limited time, and I want to ask you just sort of what should we be thinking about?  What should the business community be thinking about?  You’ve mentioned the big issues.  But what is it that we all need to be thinking about to drive home success?  Underscoring everything you just said.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> So for me, it’s a pretty simple proposition.  Not a single one of the issues that we’re working on and that are actually having an impact on the lives of people in every country in this hemisphere – not a single one can we effectively deal with alone.  And by alone, I mean no single government can do it and no – and even a group of governments can’t do it because we need to have partnerships with the private sector, with civil society, with other major stakeholders.  Climate, COVID, emerging technology, migration, all of these things defy unilateral solutions, either unilateral, again, on the part of a single government or unilateral on the part of a single stakeholder.</p>
<p>So it’s in a sense as basic as that.  If we can’t find ways to effectively partner, we’re not going to meet these challenges.  If we don’t meet these challenges, we’re not going to be responsive to our citizens.  And if we’re not responsive to our citizens, they’ll let us know.</p>
<p>So we need to get this right, but last thing I’ll say is this, and I think you’ll hear this from the President this afternoon because he is the eternal optimist and it’s an occupational requirement.  (Laughter.)  There’s huge opportunity here.  You all know this better than anyone.  You can see it, you can feel it, and you’re doing it.  The Vice President, with the call to action for investment in the Northern Triangle countries, that’s been a remarkable success – $3.2 billion in new investments generated just in the space of about a year.</p>
<p>So the opportunity is there.  The question is: How do we effectively work together to seize it?  And here, Myron, with the Chamber, hearing from you, talk – working with you, engaging with you so that we understand from the perspective of the business community what’s needed, and then we can use what influence we have to try to create – help create that environment.  That’s hugely important.</p>
<p>We’ll share the same with you, and I think if we’re working together, we’re going to get a lot done.  You take a step at a time, it doesn’t feel like you’re traveling too far.  As I say, in a year’s time, maybe we’ll see that we’ve actually covered a little bit of distance.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Well, one thing, and I know we have to run, is – I would add to the agenda is food security.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> Yeah.  Absolutely.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  We talked about energy security, rule of law, governance – all of these are important.  I think also at this time, with what’s happening in Europe, we have to work together on the food security issue.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> And I’m really glad you raised that.  And I know we’re over time, but let me say a quick word about that because it’s hugely important.  We have a, here again, historic food insecurity crisis that is global in nature.  Three years ago there were roughly 100 million people around the world who were considered severely food insecure.  That went up to about 160 million people last year.  Now, with Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, we’re adding another 40 million people to those who are severely food insecure around the world, so about 200 million people.  This is reaching historic proportions.</p>
<p>And here, too, we know we’ve had a perfect storm.  This has been the result of COVID.  It’s been the result of climate change.  And now it’s the result of conflict.  So we obviously have to deal with the underlying conditions one way or another.  But that’s going to take time.</p>
<p>In the meantime, what we’ve done is we’ve tried to bring countries together around the world to deal with the immediate challenge as well as the long-term challenge.  We have the presidency of the UN Security Council in the month of May.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT: </strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> Rotating presidency.  We decided to dedicate that presidency to focusing on food insecurity.  I went up to New York, spent a couple of days there.  We had about 40 countries together coming together on this, 40 foreign ministers, the Security Council itself, looking at the resources we need to put right now into the organizations that are helping deal with those who are food insecure – World Food Program, Food and Agricultural Organization, and others.  We looked at what can be done, and the President has done it, to generate, for example, the production of more fertilizer, half a billion dollars from the United States, to make sure that are folks are producing more.  If you don’t have the fertilizer on the market, crop yields go down, prices go up.  So we’ve got – we’re doing that.  Janet Yellen, our Secretary of the Treasury, is mobilizing the international financial institutions to help alleviate some of the financial burdens on countries that are dealing with this.</p>
<p>And at the same time, of course, we’re working, for example, to get wheat out of Ukraine.  There are 25 million tons of wheat that are sitting in silos at the ports in Odessa.  There’s 84, 85 ships filled with grain that can’t get out because of the Russian blockade.  We’re working to see that that gets lifted with the United Nations.  And we’re also working at other ways to get grain and other goods out of Ukraine so that they can get on to markets, people can have food, prices can go down.  All of this coming together.</p>
<p>But it takes continued action.  So we’re going to be working, for example, with the G7 countries to make sure that we are getting sustained action on this.  We had a – there, too, in New York at the UN, now more than 80 countries have signed on to a call to action that has specific things that each of us need to do to address this crisis.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Well, I know we’re running up against the clock, and I know that you’ve got staff that’s ready to pull me.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> We’ve literally run against the &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  And I would simply say, look, it may not be a fun job right now, but it’s certainly an interesting job, and we are so grateful for your leadership and for the President’s leadership at this critical time.  And I would just simply hope that you’re getting a little bit of a break periodically from your busy schedule.  But thank you so much for being at this summit and for offering your perspectives.  And very much appreciate the partnership that you expressed about the private sector and the Chamber in particular.</p>
<p>So please give him a round of applause.  Thank you very much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>Thanks.  Thank you.  Appreciate it.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Los Angeles, California</p>
<p> InterContinental Hotel</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Well, Mr. Secretary, first off let me just say thank you for being here with us today.  And I just want to acknowledge upfront the strong partnership that we’ve had with the State Department in putting together the 4th annual Summit of the Americas.  And I want to give a shoutout to Jose Fernandez, the under secretary of state, and to Assistant Secretary Brian Nichols, but to your entire team &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>&#8212; because this is going to be, I know, a crazy week for the State Department.  And I want to begin by just acknowledging how complex and challenging a time it is for the U.S. Government, for the world community – the conflict in Europe, obviously the challenges with the U.S.-China relationship, and more broadly the issues you’re grappling with. So the fact that you’re here today at this summit, we very much greatly appreciate.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thanks, Myron.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>I want to ask you, Mr. Secretary, at the outset:  As you look at this Summit of Americas, and not just the CEO summit of it but the broader summit that President Biden and you are engaging with all these leaders from the region, tell us what’s important about it as you look at the foreign policy agenda, the administration, you think about it regionally, you think about it globally.  How does this summit fit into it?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, first, Myron, thank you.  Thank you for this partnership on our end, too.  We can’t do it without you.  We’ve had a partnership in so many ways with the Chamber across so many issues.  I think it’s especially important in our own hemisphere, so I’m grateful for everything that you’ve done and that the Chamber has done to be such an important presence here at the summit over the next three days.  Hugely, hugely, important.</p>
<p>And this is a critical moment for us.  On one level, it’s pretty simple, and it’s obvious but it’s no more – no less important for being obvious.  No other region in the world has the same direct impact on the lives and livelihoods of Americans than the hemisphere that we share.  It’s as simple as that.  So to some extent as goes the hemisphere, so go we.  And so we have a real stake in making sure that, together, we get this right.  And again, to state the obvious, this is a time of incredible challenge for all of us.  We’ve had a confluence of almost perfect storm events over the last few years that have had a profound effect here in the Americas: COVID, climate, some – a democratic deficit, migration, and of course the daily and changing impact of technologies on the lives of everyone.  You put all that together, we’ve lost 2.7 million lives &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>&#8212; from COVID in our hemisphere.  Our hemisphere has suffered the most from COVID.  At the same time, it’s 30 percent of global GDP.  If we get our act together and mobilize that effectively, there is so much we can do.  The leaders have not met in more than four years.  It’s time.</p>
<p>But to your point, and this is what I find so vital about this summit, as important as the government-to-government work is, that is far from the sum and substance of this gathering.  We have the business community, we have civil society, we have young people, we have all the different stakeholders in our hemisphere.  And if these three days, four days can galvanize some collective action together and then we can take that from the summit, I think we’ll have done a good thing.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Well, Mr. Secretary, thank you for framing it in the context of all the things that this region has to think about – the pandemic, the return to health and the return to stronger economies.  You have an economic plan that you want to talk about at this summit.  Can you give us a preview about what that economic plan looks like and a little bit about how the private sector will play into that economic plan?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, first, never get ahead of your boss, so the President &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Just a little bit of a &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Just a little bit.  The President’s going to be speaking to this later today, and I’m very excited about that.  It dovetails with a number of things that we’re doing here.  First, we have – with our partners throughout the region, we have a number of areas and issues that we’re trying to drive together.  There’s going to be a lengthy summit declaration that you’ll see that actually focuses in our work together on a number of areas, and the President’s economic plan dovetails with those areas.</p>
<p>So for example, we need to build greater health resilience in our hemisphere in two ways: we need to be better prepared to manage a future pandemic, but also in the daily lives of people.  We need to be able to provide better basic health services.  There are huge disparities.  One of the great things coming out of the summit – and this is where the private sector also is critical – is we have a commitment over the next couple of years to train 500,000 health professionals, generalists and specialists.  That’s going to make a huge difference if they are effectively deployed throughout our hemisphere in raising the basic level of health services.  That’s one, but the president’s going to address some of that.</p>
<p>Second, on the climate and energy agenda, there are huge needs but also huge opportunities to come together in a way that actually is beneficial to our economies and also beneficial to climate, beneficial to our energy security and infrastructure development.  He will speak to that.  We have to do more and we will do more in a positive way to bridge digital divides that exist within our countries, but also within the hemisphere itself.  Facilitating digital trade, doing it in a way that’s secure, that upholds basic democratic principles, but that also is much more inclusive so that we bridge some of these divides.  That’s going to be a big part of it.</p>
<p>But also – and this is really imperative and this is, again, where our partnership with the private sector is so important – we have to find ways together and make good on commitments together to create an environment in which business can really work effectively.</p>
<p>So we know there remain huge challenges when it comes to everything from regulatory frameworks to corruption.  It is vital that all of our partners – and we – work together to deal with these.  Because, for example, as we’ve discussed, there’s a lot of capital out there.  But it’s not going to be deployed if the environment in which you want to deploy it is simply too risky and too complicated.</p>
<p>We have these conversations all the time with our counterparts.  Hearing it from us is one thing; I think hearing it from the business community directly, that’s important too.  So the President’s going to address all that.</p>
<p>There are huge infrastructure demands throughout the world; there are huge infrastructure demands in our hemisphere.  How do we facilitate making sure that the government is playing its part in helping to support viable projects, in helping to mobilize capital?  All of that will be there.  I don’t want to get too far ahead of where he’s going to be; stay tuned.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Always smart not to get ahead of POTUS, of the President, your boss.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yes, it’s a good rule.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Look, you talked about energy security, you talked about the digital transformation, you talked about digital trade – all these are important areas for business to be in partnership with government, and not just our government but governments around the region.  How receptive is the message being heard in the region?  Now, I know you’re going to begin your bilaterals over the next couple days, you’ll have the big summit – do you see government leaders across the region understanding that this is a critical moment to come together?  Because we see quite a bit of change politically in the region, and I wonder how that factors into what you’re trying to achieve.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, look.  One of the, I think, strengths, in a sense, of our region, is – look, there are political differences.  We have democratic governments of the left, of the right, and of the center.  But despite what political differences there are, if the fundamentals are there, we’re going to be able to work very, very effectively together.  And whether it’s of the left, the right, or the center, there’s a common challenge for every single democracy in our hemisphere, and that’s to actually deliver concrete results for people.  One of the reasons you may see changes in governance is simply because people have lost faith in the – whatever the current existing administration is in a given country, whether it’s left, right, or center, in its ability to deliver practical things, concrete things.</p>
<p>So my sense, Myron, is in our conversations, governments are very motivated to figure out how do we actually deliver.  And it’s partly because it’s the right and necessary thing to do.  It’s probably the politically self-preservation thing to do as well.</p>
<p>So I think we have to work with that, work with partners, and find ways together to support change that creates the right environment – again, to, among other things, mobilize capital throughout the hemisphere.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Well, all those are very important principles and issues to think about.  One thing that you’ve talked about but I want to get a little deeper on is the rule of law &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yep.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  For business leaders, rule of law is fundamental.  We need certainty, we need transparency, we need accountability, and by the way, we want to be accountable also to the system.  Talk to me about the Alliance for Development in Democracy.  You have this pathway with a couple of countries in the region.  I’m sure you want to expand that to others.  How does that fit into this narrative, and how does it link up to the business community in terms of us working with you?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So I think this is a terrific initiative and it brings together, as you know, Costa Rica, the Dominican Republic, Panama.  In fact, I had my counterparts from those countries in Washington three or four months ago for a meeting of this alliance.  And we’re focused on very practical things like: how do we make governance work better for people, how do we make sure it’s inclusive, and how do we make sure that it does exactly what we’re talking about, it creates a better environment for, among other things, investment?</p>
<p>So one of the things we talked about is using some of the digital tools that have been developed to make sure governments adopt them.  That’s a way of combatting corruption, which is one of the single biggest challenges we face not only in the hemisphere, but around the world.  It cuts through red tape, so that also helps create a better business environment.  These are the kinds of initiatives that, in a very practical way, we’re trying to bring together.  And if we can demonstrate among a small number of countries that this works, I expect that’ll expand to others as well.</p>
<p><strong>BRILLIANT:</strong>  What does success look like at the end of this summit?  After our CEO summit, after your summit that the President leads, what does success look like, and how do we go forward and make sure that whatever is discussed here, we take into action?  And here, you can challenge the private sector.  We need to play a role.  But what does success look like?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Look, I think the private sector’s a critical partner on virtually everything that we’re doing.  And in fact, one of the greatest strengths we bring to the table is our ability to work together with the private sector in ways that other countries don’t or can’t.  So we want to see that mobilized to the greatest extent possible.</p>
<p>I think when it comes to the issues we’ve talked about, when it comes to basic good governance, when it comes to transparency, when it comes to rule of law, when it comes to combatting corruption, I think that’s something that the private sector rightly should and must insist on.  And hearing it directly from the private sector makes a big difference.  Certainly our partners hear it from us, and of course we have to deal with our own challenges, as we are.</p>
<p>But what does success look like?  It’s two things.  Yes, it’s what gets agreed at this – at the summit.  There’ll be important commitments; there’ll be important initiatives; there’ll be important declarations of intent.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Right.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>But three days is not 365 days.  This has to be done over 365 days.  We have to hold ourselves accountable to what is agreed here, the commitments that all of us make to try to move forward, and then really see where we are at every step along the way.  Are we delivering on that intent?  We’re not going to know that right away.  So look, I think we’ll have important – the lingo that we use – deliverables.  We’ll have good deliverables.  But the deliverables are only as good as their implementation.  They’re only as good as the sustained commitment to getting them done.</p>
<p>So maybe we should come back together in Los Angeles in a year’s time and see how we’re doing.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT: </strong> Los Angeles or others?  Well, this is the City of Angels, so I shouldn’t say other cities.  But we’ve got a lot of great cities in this country that would be happy to have this forum.</p>
<p>Look, I know you have limited time, and I want to ask you just sort of what should we be thinking about?  What should the business community be thinking about?  You’ve mentioned the big issues.  But what is it that we all need to be thinking about to drive home success?  Underscoring everything you just said.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> So for me, it’s a pretty simple proposition.  Not a single one of the issues that we’re working on and that are actually having an impact on the lives of people in every country in this hemisphere – not a single one can we effectively deal with alone.  And by alone, I mean no single government can do it and no – and even a group of governments can’t do it because we need to have partnerships with the private sector, with civil society, with other major stakeholders.  Climate, COVID, emerging technology, migration, all of these things defy unilateral solutions, either unilateral, again, on the part of a single government or unilateral on the part of a single stakeholder.</p>
<p>So it’s in a sense as basic as that.  If we can’t find ways to effectively partner, we’re not going to meet these challenges.  If we don’t meet these challenges, we’re not going to be responsive to our citizens.  And if we’re not responsive to our citizens, they’ll let us know.</p>
<p>So we need to get this right, but last thing I’ll say is this, and I think you’ll hear this from the President this afternoon because he is the eternal optimist and it’s an occupational requirement.  (Laughter.)  There’s huge opportunity here.  You all know this better than anyone.  You can see it, you can feel it, and you’re doing it.  The Vice President, with the call to action for investment in the Northern Triangle countries, that’s been a remarkable success – $3.2 billion in new investments generated just in the space of about a year.</p>
<p>So the opportunity is there.  The question is: How do we effectively work together to seize it?  And here, Myron, with the Chamber, hearing from you, talk – working with you, engaging with you so that we understand from the perspective of the business community what’s needed, and then we can use what influence we have to try to create – help create that environment.  That’s hugely important.</p>
<p>We’ll share the same with you, and I think if we’re working together, we’re going to get a lot done.  You take a step at a time, it doesn’t feel like you’re traveling too far.  As I say, in a year’s time, maybe we’ll see that we’ve actually covered a little bit of distance.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Well, one thing, and I know we have to run, is – I would add to the agenda is food security.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> Yeah.  Absolutely.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  We talked about energy security, rule of law, governance – all of these are important.  I think also at this time, with what’s happening in Europe, we have to work together on the food security issue.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> And I’m really glad you raised that.  And I know we’re over time, but let me say a quick word about that because it’s hugely important.  We have a, here again, historic food insecurity crisis that is global in nature.  Three years ago there were roughly 100 million people around the world who were considered severely food insecure.  That went up to about 160 million people last year.  Now, with Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, we’re adding another 40 million people to those who are severely food insecure around the world, so about 200 million people.  This is reaching historic proportions.</p>
<p>And here, too, we know we’ve had a perfect storm.  This has been the result of COVID.  It’s been the result of climate change.  And now it’s the result of conflict.  So we obviously have to deal with the underlying conditions one way or another.  But that’s going to take time.</p>
<p>In the meantime, what we’ve done is we’ve tried to bring countries together around the world to deal with the immediate challenge as well as the long-term challenge.  We have the presidency of the UN Security Council in the month of May.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT: </strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> Rotating presidency.  We decided to dedicate that presidency to focusing on food insecurity.  I went up to New York, spent a couple of days there.  We had about 40 countries together coming together on this, 40 foreign ministers, the Security Council itself, looking at the resources we need to put right now into the organizations that are helping deal with those who are food insecure – World Food Program, Food and Agricultural Organization, and others.  We looked at what can be done, and the President has done it, to generate, for example, the production of more fertilizer, half a billion dollars from the United States, to make sure that are folks are producing more.  If you don’t have the fertilizer on the market, crop yields go down, prices go up.  So we’ve got – we’re doing that.  Janet Yellen, our Secretary of the Treasury, is mobilizing the international financial institutions to help alleviate some of the financial burdens on countries that are dealing with this.</p>
<p>And at the same time, of course, we’re working, for example, to get wheat out of Ukraine.  There are 25 million tons of wheat that are sitting in silos at the ports in Odessa.  There’s 84, 85 ships filled with grain that can’t get out because of the Russian blockade.  We’re working to see that that gets lifted with the United Nations.  And we’re also working at other ways to get grain and other goods out of Ukraine so that they can get on to markets, people can have food, prices can go down.  All of this coming together.</p>
<p>But it takes continued action.  So we’re going to be working, for example, with the G7 countries to make sure that we are getting sustained action on this.  We had a – there, too, in New York at the UN, now more than 80 countries have signed on to a call to action that has specific things that each of us need to do to address this crisis.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Well, I know we’re running up against the clock, and I know that you’ve got staff that’s ready to pull me.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> We’ve literally run against the &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  And I would simply say, look, it may not be a fun job right now, but it’s certainly an interesting job, and we are so grateful for your leadership and for the President’s leadership at this critical time.  And I would just simply hope that you’re getting a little bit of a break periodically from your busy schedule.  But thank you so much for being at this summit and for offering your perspectives.  And very much appreciate the partnership that you expressed about the private sector and the Chamber in particular.</p>
<p>So please give him a round of applause.  Thank you very much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>Thanks.  Thank you.  Appreciate it.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States Establishes Complementary Mechanisms to Bolster Resiliency of the Hemisphere’s Health Economies and Ecosystems</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-establishes-complementary-mechanisms-to-bolster-resiliency-of-the-hemispheres-health-economies-and-ecosystems/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 18:57:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350749</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Department of Commerce, with the support of the U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services, announces annual multisectoral forum Americas RISE for Health. U.S. Department of State announces government-only Economy and Health Dialogue of the Americas. Together the two mechanisms will bolster resiliency of the hemisphere’s health economies and ecosystems.</p>
<p>Today on the eve of the Ninth Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles, Deputy Secretary of Commerce Don Graves and Under Secretary of State for Economic Affairs Growth, Energy, and the Environment Jose W. Fernandez announced the United States will establish complementary mechanisms to bolster resiliency of the hemisphere’s health economies and ecosystems. This announcement represents a first of its kind effort that will focus the region’s governments, private sector and civil society on shared challenges and opportunities to build resilient, inclusive, sustainable, equitable health economies and ecosystems.</p>
<p>Americas RISE for Health, convened by the U.S. Department of Commerce, with the support of the U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services, will harness the collective strengths of the region’s private sector and civil society and partner with the region’s governments to build the hemisphere’s supply chains back to be more resilient, enable digital health solutions to reach underserved populations, accelerate regulatory improvements, reduce trade and investment barriers to health financing, create ethical environments so health economies can thrive, and address other areas of need.</p>
<p>Economy and Health Dialogue of the Americas (EHA), convened by the U.S. Department of State, will establish a series of official sector-only convenings to increase political will and commitments across health and economy sectors necessary to strengthen public health systems in the Americas by initiating collaboration among countries in the region through ministries of foreign affairs, health, economy, trade and with regional expert organizations. The EHA will support the region’s governments to coordinate on pandemic prevention, preparedness, and response; identify and leverage best practices in the public sector to include health gap assessments, sustainable health budgeting, and effective service delivery to support economic resilience and recovery; promote anti-corruption practices to increase efficiency; and build more resilient health systems. Working in coordination with the Americas Business Dialogue, the EHA provides a government and member state-only platform to enable governments to assess country-specific concrete actions towards policy reform that would enable greater private sector and civil society participation in the region’s health economies, and investment opportunities.</p>
<p>Coordinating these two mechanisms will link governments with civil and private stakeholders to help meet the Biden-Harris Administration’s objectives of building a resilient hemisphere and bolstering economic resilience and opportunity in the Americas.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact: <a href="mailto:E_Communications@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="NotApplicable" data-linkindex="0">E_Communications@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Department of Commerce, with the support of the U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services, announces annual multisectoral forum Americas RISE for Health. U.S. Department of State announces government-only Economy and Health Dialogue of the Americas. Together the two mechanisms will bolster resiliency of the hemisphere’s health economies and ecosystems.</p>
<p>Today on the eve of the Ninth Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles, Deputy Secretary of Commerce Don Graves and Under Secretary of State for Economic Affairs Growth, Energy, and the Environment Jose W. Fernandez announced the United States will establish complementary mechanisms to bolster resiliency of the hemisphere’s health economies and ecosystems. This announcement represents a first of its kind effort that will focus the region’s governments, private sector and civil society on shared challenges and opportunities to build resilient, inclusive, sustainable, equitable health economies and ecosystems.</p>
<p>Americas RISE for Health, convened by the U.S. Department of Commerce, with the support of the U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services, will harness the collective strengths of the region’s private sector and civil society and partner with the region’s governments to build the hemisphere’s supply chains back to be more resilient, enable digital health solutions to reach underserved populations, accelerate regulatory improvements, reduce trade and investment barriers to health financing, create ethical environments so health economies can thrive, and address other areas of need.</p>
<p>Economy and Health Dialogue of the Americas (EHA), convened by the U.S. Department of State, will establish a series of official sector-only convenings to increase political will and commitments across health and economy sectors necessary to strengthen public health systems in the Americas by initiating collaboration among countries in the region through ministries of foreign affairs, health, economy, trade and with regional expert organizations. The EHA will support the region’s governments to coordinate on pandemic prevention, preparedness, and response; identify and leverage best practices in the public sector to include health gap assessments, sustainable health budgeting, and effective service delivery to support economic resilience and recovery; promote anti-corruption practices to increase efficiency; and build more resilient health systems. Working in coordination with the Americas Business Dialogue, the EHA provides a government and member state-only platform to enable governments to assess country-specific concrete actions towards policy reform that would enable greater private sector and civil society participation in the region’s health economies, and investment opportunities.</p>
<p>Coordinating these two mechanisms will link governments with civil and private stakeholders to help meet the Biden-Harris Administration’s objectives of building a resilient hemisphere and bolstering economic resilience and opportunity in the Americas.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact: <a href="mailto:E_Communications@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="NotApplicable" data-linkindex="0">E_Communications@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the Republic of Korea-U.S.-Japan Trilateral Vice Foreign Ministerial Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-the-republic-of-korea-u-s-japan-trilateral-vice-foreign-ministerial-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 16:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350669</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is the joint statement released by the Vice Foreign Ministers of the Republic of Korea and Japan and the Deputy Secretary of State of the United States.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin Text.</em></p>
<p>Republic of Korea (ROK) First Vice Foreign Minister Cho Hyundong, U.S. Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman, and Japan Vice Foreign Minister Mori Takeo met today in Seoul to discuss how our three countries will work together to address the challenges of the 21st Century for the benefit of the region and the world.</p>
<p>The Vice Foreign Ministers and the Deputy Secretary strongly condemned the repeated unlawful ballistic missile launches by the DPRK. They reaffirmed the outcomes of the May 27 Minister-level trilateral joint statement and committed to advance trilateral security cooperation to curb threats from the DPRK. The Deputy Secretary reaffirmed the United States’ steadfast commitments to the defense of the Republic of Korea and Japan, including extended deterrence. The Vice Ministers and the Deputy Secretary urged the DPRK to abide by its obligations under relevant UNSC resolutions and immediately cease actions that violate international law, escalate tensions, destabilize the region, or endanger global peace and security, and instead engage in dialogue toward the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. They stressed that a path to serious and sustained dialogue remains open and urged the DPRK to return to negotiations, while also expressing their hope that the DPRK will respond positively to international offers of assistance to fight against COVID-19. They reaffirmed the importance of achieving a swift resolution to the abductions issue.</p>
<p>The Vice Foreign Ministers and the Deputy Secretary discussed a range of pressing regional and global issues, including our joint efforts to support Ukraine, restore Myanmar to a democratic path, bolster engagement with ASEAN and within ASEAN-led architecture, enhance cooperation with Pacific Island countries, strengthen economic and energy security, prioritize women’s empowerment and workforce development, uphold international law, and promote a free and open Indo-Pacific, which is inclusive.</p>
<p>ROK-U.S.-Japan trilateral cooperation, grounded in our shared values, demonstrates that democracies can build a better future for their people, and the Vice Foreign Ministers and the Deputy Secretary decided to meet in Tokyo to continue their regular trilateral consultations as we advance our shared efforts.</p>
<p align="left"><em>End Text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is the joint statement released by the Vice Foreign Ministers of the Republic of Korea and Japan and the Deputy Secretary of State of the United States.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin Text.</em></p>
<p>Republic of Korea (ROK) First Vice Foreign Minister Cho Hyundong, U.S. Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman, and Japan Vice Foreign Minister Mori Takeo met today in Seoul to discuss how our three countries will work together to address the challenges of the 21st Century for the benefit of the region and the world.</p>
<p>The Vice Foreign Ministers and the Deputy Secretary strongly condemned the repeated unlawful ballistic missile launches by the DPRK. They reaffirmed the outcomes of the May 27 Minister-level trilateral joint statement and committed to advance trilateral security cooperation to curb threats from the DPRK. The Deputy Secretary reaffirmed the United States’ steadfast commitments to the defense of the Republic of Korea and Japan, including extended deterrence. The Vice Ministers and the Deputy Secretary urged the DPRK to abide by its obligations under relevant UNSC resolutions and immediately cease actions that violate international law, escalate tensions, destabilize the region, or endanger global peace and security, and instead engage in dialogue toward the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. They stressed that a path to serious and sustained dialogue remains open and urged the DPRK to return to negotiations, while also expressing their hope that the DPRK will respond positively to international offers of assistance to fight against COVID-19. They reaffirmed the importance of achieving a swift resolution to the abductions issue.</p>
<p>The Vice Foreign Ministers and the Deputy Secretary discussed a range of pressing regional and global issues, including our joint efforts to support Ukraine, restore Myanmar to a democratic path, bolster engagement with ASEAN and within ASEAN-led architecture, enhance cooperation with Pacific Island countries, strengthen economic and energy security, prioritize women’s empowerment and workforce development, uphold international law, and promote a free and open Indo-Pacific, which is inclusive.</p>
<p>ROK-U.S.-Japan trilateral cooperation, grounded in our shared values, demonstrates that democracies can build a better future for their people, and the Vice Foreign Ministers and the Deputy Secretary decided to meet in Tokyo to continue their regular trilateral consultations as we advance our shared efforts.</p>
<p align="left"><em>End Text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on Limited Resumption of Arctic Council Cooperation</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-limited-resumption-of-arctic-council-cooperation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 14:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350548</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The governments of Canada, the Kingdom of Denmark, Finland, Iceland, Norway, Sweden, and the United States have issued the following joint statement.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>In response to Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine, a flagrant violation of the principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity, based on international law, the other Arctic Council founding states – Canada, Finland, Iceland, the Kingdom of Denmark, Norway, Sweden, and the United States – on March 3 announced a pause in their participation in the Arctic Council. Since March 3, representatives from these States have examined modalities to allow a resumption of the work in the Arctic Council.</p>
<p>We remain convinced of the enduring value of the Arctic Council for circumpolar cooperation and reiterate our support for this forum and its important work.</p>
<p>We intend to implement a limited resumption of our work in the Arctic Council, in projects that do not involve the participation of the Russian Federation. These projects, contained in the workplan approved by all eight Arctic States at the Reykjavik ministerial, are a vital component of our responsibility to the people of the Arctic, including Indigenous Peoples.</p>
<p>We continue to examine additional modalities to allow us to further continue the Council’s important work.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The governments of Canada, the Kingdom of Denmark, Finland, Iceland, Norway, Sweden, and the United States have issued the following joint statement.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>In response to Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine, a flagrant violation of the principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity, based on international law, the other Arctic Council founding states – Canada, Finland, Iceland, the Kingdom of Denmark, Norway, Sweden, and the United States – on March 3 announced a pause in their participation in the Arctic Council. Since March 3, representatives from these States have examined modalities to allow a resumption of the work in the Arctic Council.</p>
<p>We remain convinced of the enduring value of the Arctic Council for circumpolar cooperation and reiterate our support for this forum and its important work.</p>
<p>We intend to implement a limited resumption of our work in the Arctic Council, in projects that do not involve the participation of the Russian Federation. These projects, contained in the workplan approved by all eight Arctic States at the Reykjavik ministerial, are a vital component of our responsibility to the people of the Arctic, including Indigenous Peoples.</p>
<p>We continue to examine additional modalities to allow us to further continue the Council’s important work.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Support for International Joint Commission Recommendations to Address Transboundary Pollution from Mining</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/support-for-international-joint-commission-recommendations-to-address-transboundary-pollution-from-mining/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 13:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On June 7, representatives from the Department of State, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, and U.S. Geological Survey met with Council members from the six governments of the transboundary Ktunaxa Nation, including the four Ktunaxa First Nation Governments of Yaq̓it ʔa·knuqⱡi’it First Nation (Tobacco Plains), ʔakisq̓nuk̓ First Nation, Yaqan Nuʔkiy (Lower Kootenay) and ʔaq̓am, the Kootenai Tribe of Idaho, and the Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes, in Bonners Ferry, Idaho, to discuss addressing pollution from mining in British Columbia that affects the United States and Canada.</p>
<p>The meeting underscored the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to strengthening Nation-to-Nation relationships by listening to Tribal priorities and respecting Tribal sovereignty.  During the meeting, the Department reaffirmed the Administration’s support for a joint reference to the International Joint Commission (IJC) under the Boundary Waters Treaty of 1909 for the Kootenai Basin regarding the transboundary impacts of mining.  A joint reference would respond to the need for impartial recommendations and transparent communication, build trust, and forge a common understanding of this issue among local, Indigenous, state, provincial, and federal governments as well as stakeholders and the public in both countries.</p>
<p>Support for a joint IJC reference reflects the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to protect public health; conserve our lands, waters, and biodiversity; and deliver environmental justice to communities overburdened by pollution.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On June 7, representatives from the Department of State, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, and U.S. Geological Survey met with Council members from the six governments of the transboundary Ktunaxa Nation, including the four Ktunaxa First Nation Governments of Yaq̓it ʔa·knuqⱡi’it First Nation (Tobacco Plains), ʔakisq̓nuk̓ First Nation, Yaqan Nuʔkiy (Lower Kootenay) and ʔaq̓am, the Kootenai Tribe of Idaho, and the Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes, in Bonners Ferry, Idaho, to discuss addressing pollution from mining in British Columbia that affects the United States and Canada.</p>
<p>The meeting underscored the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to strengthening Nation-to-Nation relationships by listening to Tribal priorities and respecting Tribal sovereignty.  During the meeting, the Department reaffirmed the Administration’s support for a joint reference to the International Joint Commission (IJC) under the Boundary Waters Treaty of 1909 for the Kootenai Basin regarding the transboundary impacts of mining.  A joint reference would respond to the need for impartial recommendations and transparent communication, build trust, and forge a common understanding of this issue among local, Indigenous, state, provincial, and federal governments as well as stakeholders and the public in both countries.</p>
<p>Support for a joint IJC reference reflects the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to protect public health; conserve our lands, waters, and biodiversity; and deliver environmental justice to communities overburdened by pollution.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meetings with Republic of Korea Minister of Unification Kwon and Vice Minister Kim</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meetings-with-republic-of-korea-minister-of-unification-kwon-and-vice-minister-kim/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 12:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350520</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met separately with Republic of Korea (ROK) Minister of Unification Kwon Young-se and Vice Minister of Unification Kim Ki-woong on June 8 and condemned the DPRK’s ballistic missile launches as a violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions and as deeply destabilizing to the region.  The Deputy Secretary underscored the importance of close cooperation between and among the United States, the ROK, and Japan to achieve the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>The Deputy Secretary, Minister, and Vice Minister also expressed concern about the impact of the DPRK’s COVID-19 outbreak on the North Korean people.  Deputy Secretary Sherman expressed support for efforts to prevent the spread of COVID-19 in the DPRK, including inter-Korean cooperation efforts.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met separately with Republic of Korea (ROK) Minister of Unification Kwon Young-se and Vice Minister of Unification Kim Ki-woong on June 8 and condemned the DPRK’s ballistic missile launches as a violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions and as deeply destabilizing to the region.  The Deputy Secretary underscored the importance of close cooperation between and among the United States, the ROK, and Japan to achieve the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>The Deputy Secretary, Minister, and Vice Minister also expressed concern about the impact of the DPRK’s COVID-19 outbreak on the North Korean people.  Deputy Secretary Sherman expressed support for efforts to prevent the spread of COVID-19 in the DPRK, including inter-Korean cooperation efforts.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Japanese Vice Foreign Minister Mori</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-japanese-vice-foreign-minister-mori-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 12:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with Japanese Vice Foreign Minister Mori Takeo in Seoul.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Vice Foreign Minister Mori emphasized the enduring importance of the U.S.-Japan Alliance to uphold an inclusive, free, and open Indo-Pacific.  The Deputy Secretary and Vice Foreign Minister discussed deepening U.S.-Japan economic cooperation, including plans for a ministerial-level Economic Policy Consultative Committee (EPCC) meeting in July and the importance of strengthening supply chain resiliency in high-tech sectors.  The Deputy Secretary and Vice Foreign Minister condemned DPRK missile launches and emphasized the importance of trilateral U.S.-Japan-ROK cooperation to tackle the most pressing regional and global challenges of the 21<sup>st</sup> Century.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with Japanese Vice Foreign Minister Mori Takeo in Seoul.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Vice Foreign Minister Mori emphasized the enduring importance of the U.S.-Japan Alliance to uphold an inclusive, free, and open Indo-Pacific.  The Deputy Secretary and Vice Foreign Minister discussed deepening U.S.-Japan economic cooperation, including plans for a ministerial-level Economic Policy Consultative Committee (EPCC) meeting in July and the importance of strengthening supply chain resiliency in high-tech sectors.  The Deputy Secretary and Vice Foreign Minister condemned DPRK missile launches and emphasized the importance of trilateral U.S.-Japan-ROK cooperation to tackle the most pressing regional and global challenges of the 21<sup>st</sup> Century.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
