<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 17:33:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Recognizing World Ocean Day 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/recognizing-world-ocean-day-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 17:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=250352</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p align="left">Our ocean covers more than 70 percent of the Earth’s surface, supports billions of livelihoods worldwide, and provides more than half the oxygen we breathe.  The United States has set a goal of conserving 30 percent of our lands and waters by 2030.  Efforts to expand marine protected areas are an important part of meeting that goal, as they are an essential tool that can help protect biodiversity and habitats, support fisheries, capture and store carbon, and build ocean resilience. We must also address the ocean plastic pollution crisis.  The United States looks forward to working with countries as we consider global action.</p>
<p align="left">The climate crisis is also an ocean crisis. The ocean has absorbed 20 to 30 percent of human-caused carbon dioxide emissions since the 1980s, and more than 90 percent of the Earth’s warming over the past 50 years has occurred in the ocean.  Sea level rise, ocean acidification, coral bleaching, storm and flood damage, change in abundance and distribution of marine species, and biodiversity loss are just some of the effects of greenhouse gas pollution on the ocean, imperiling communities worldwide.</p>
<p align="left">Protecting our ocean also means fighting illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing, which costs the world tens of billions of dollars each year.  The United States actively supports efforts to combat the threat that IUU fishing poses to the livelihoods of coastal communities.  IUU fishing operations may also be linked to criminal activities such as money laundering, drug trafficking, and human trafficking, including forced labor.  The United States champions building cooperative, science-based rules to ensure that these fisheries can be sustainable for the long term, helping to work together with countries around the world towards our shared goals.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p align="left">Our ocean covers more than 70 percent of the Earth’s surface, supports billions of livelihoods worldwide, and provides more than half the oxygen we breathe.  The United States has set a goal of conserving 30 percent of our lands and waters by 2030.  Efforts to expand marine protected areas are an important part of meeting that goal, as they are an essential tool that can help protect biodiversity and habitats, support fisheries, capture and store carbon, and build ocean resilience. We must also address the ocean plastic pollution crisis.  The United States looks forward to working with countries as we consider global action.</p>
<p align="left">The climate crisis is also an ocean crisis. The ocean has absorbed 20 to 30 percent of human-caused carbon dioxide emissions since the 1980s, and more than 90 percent of the Earth’s warming over the past 50 years has occurred in the ocean.  Sea level rise, ocean acidification, coral bleaching, storm and flood damage, change in abundance and distribution of marine species, and biodiversity loss are just some of the effects of greenhouse gas pollution on the ocean, imperiling communities worldwide.</p>
<p align="left">Protecting our ocean also means fighting illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing, which costs the world tens of billions of dollars each year.  The United States actively supports efforts to combat the threat that IUU fishing poses to the livelihoods of coastal communities.  IUU fishing operations may also be linked to criminal activities such as money laundering, drug trafficking, and human trafficking, including forced labor.  The United States champions building cooperative, science-based rules to ensure that these fisheries can be sustainable for the long term, helping to work together with countries around the world towards our shared goals.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opening Remarks by Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken Before the Senate Committee on Appropriations</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/opening-remarks-by-secretary-of-state-antony-j-blinken-before-the-senate-committee-on-appropriations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 17:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=250334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you very much, Mr. Chairman.  There we go.  Mr. Chairman, Vice Chairman Shelby, Chairman Coons, Ranking Member Graham, all the committee members, thank you very much for coming together today and giving me this opportunity to talk about the administration’s proposed budget and how we believe it will help us achieve our national security priorities and deliver results for the American people, which is our common mission.</p>
<p>Let me just say that the last time I had the honor of actually appearing before the subcommittee, and Senator Graham will remember this, I had – was seated next to another witness who seemed to get a lot more attention: Bono.  (Laughter.)  So a very, very memorable day before the subcommittee, but Senator Coons, Senator Graham, very much looking forward to working with you going forward as well.</p>
<p>This is a critical moment for the United States and for our global leadership.  We have major tests, including stopping COVID-19; rising to the challenge of the climate crisis; supporting a global economic recovery that delivers for American workers and families; we have to revitalize our alliances and partnerships; outcompete China and defend the international rules-based order against those who seek to undermine it; renew democratic values at home and abroad; and push back against malign activity by our adversaries.</p>
<p>In a more competitive world, other countries are making historic investments in their foreign policy toolkit.  We need to do the same thing.  That’s why in this budget we proposed $58.5 billion for the State Department and USAID for Fiscal Year 2022.  And just to cover some of the specifics, this budget will strengthen global health.  The United States has been a leader in this field for decades – in Africa, around the world.  We’re asking for $10 billion for global health programs, including nearly $1 billion for global health security to help us prevent, prepare for, respond to future global health crises so we can stop outbreaks before they turn into pandemics that put our safety and prosperity in danger.</p>
<p>The budget will accelerate the global response to the climate crisis by providing $2.5 billion for international climate programs, including 1.25 billion to the Green Climate Fund to help developing countries implement climate adaptation and emissions mitigation programs, which is directly in our interest.</p>
<p>The budget will double down on the fight for democracy, which, as we all know, is under threat in many places around the world.  People talk of a democratic recession around the world.  Our budget request includes $2.8 billion in foreign assistance to advance human rights, fight corruption, stem the tide of democratic backsliding, and strengthen and defend democracies – for example, through technical training for elections and support for independent media and civil society.  It also requests $300 million for the National Endowment for Democracy.</p>
<p>The budget will support a comprehensive strategy to address the root causes of irregular migration from Central America.  It will invest 861 million in the region as a first step toward a four-year commitment of $4 billion to help prevent violence, reduce poverty, curtail endemic corruption, and expand job and educational opportunities.</p>
<p>The budget would re-establish U.S. humanitarian leadership with a request of $10 billion in assistance to support refugees, victims of conflict, other displaced people, and to rebuild our refugee admissions program.</p>
<p>It will support our partners in the Middle East by fully funding our commitments to key countries, including Israel and Jordan, and by restoring humanitarian assistance to the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>It includes a budget request of 3.6 billion to pay our assessed contributions in full to international organizations, initiatives, peacekeeping efforts, including to restore our annual contributions to the World Health Organization.</p>
<p>As China and others work hard to bend international organizations to their worldview, we have to ensure that these organizations instead remain grounded in the values, principles, and rules of the road that have made our shared progress possible for so many decades.</p>
<p>Finally, to deliver in all of these areas, the budget will reinvest in our most vital asset, and that’s our people.  It will provide new resources to recruit, to train, and to retain a first-rate, diverse global workforce, with nearly 500 additional Foreign and Civil Service positions – the largest increase for State Department staffing, excuse me, in a decade.  And it will modernize our technology – cybersecurity – protect our embassies and consulates, and include a direct appropriation of $320 million for consular services worldwide so that we can continue to provide these vital services to Americans and those who seek to study, to travel, to do business with the United States.</p>
<p>Our national security depends not only on the strength of our armed forces, but also our ability to conduct effective diplomacy and development.  That’s how we solve global challenges, forge cooperation, advance our interests and values, protect our people, prevent crises overseas from becoming emergencies here at home.  And that’s why diplomacy and development are smart investments for American taxpayers.</p>
<p>Mr. Chairman, Mr. Vice Chairman, a top priority for me as Secretary is to restore the traditional role of Congress as a partner in our foreign policymaking.  That’s the spirit that I bring to today’s conversation, the spirit I’ll bring to all future conversations and engagements with this committee, and I’m grateful for the chance to answer your questions.  Thank you very much.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you very much, Mr. Chairman.  There we go.  Mr. Chairman, Vice Chairman Shelby, Chairman Coons, Ranking Member Graham, all the committee members, thank you very much for coming together today and giving me this opportunity to talk about the administration’s proposed budget and how we believe it will help us achieve our national security priorities and deliver results for the American people, which is our common mission.</p>
<p>Let me just say that the last time I had the honor of actually appearing before the subcommittee, and Senator Graham will remember this, I had – was seated next to another witness who seemed to get a lot more attention: Bono.  (Laughter.)  So a very, very memorable day before the subcommittee, but Senator Coons, Senator Graham, very much looking forward to working with you going forward as well.</p>
<p>This is a critical moment for the United States and for our global leadership.  We have major tests, including stopping COVID-19; rising to the challenge of the climate crisis; supporting a global economic recovery that delivers for American workers and families; we have to revitalize our alliances and partnerships; outcompete China and defend the international rules-based order against those who seek to undermine it; renew democratic values at home and abroad; and push back against malign activity by our adversaries.</p>
<p>In a more competitive world, other countries are making historic investments in their foreign policy toolkit.  We need to do the same thing.  That’s why in this budget we proposed $58.5 billion for the State Department and USAID for Fiscal Year 2022.  And just to cover some of the specifics, this budget will strengthen global health.  The United States has been a leader in this field for decades – in Africa, around the world.  We’re asking for $10 billion for global health programs, including nearly $1 billion for global health security to help us prevent, prepare for, respond to future global health crises so we can stop outbreaks before they turn into pandemics that put our safety and prosperity in danger.</p>
<p>The budget will accelerate the global response to the climate crisis by providing $2.5 billion for international climate programs, including 1.25 billion to the Green Climate Fund to help developing countries implement climate adaptation and emissions mitigation programs, which is directly in our interest.</p>
<p>The budget will double down on the fight for democracy, which, as we all know, is under threat in many places around the world.  People talk of a democratic recession around the world.  Our budget request includes $2.8 billion in foreign assistance to advance human rights, fight corruption, stem the tide of democratic backsliding, and strengthen and defend democracies – for example, through technical training for elections and support for independent media and civil society.  It also requests $300 million for the National Endowment for Democracy.</p>
<p>The budget will support a comprehensive strategy to address the root causes of irregular migration from Central America.  It will invest 861 million in the region as a first step toward a four-year commitment of $4 billion to help prevent violence, reduce poverty, curtail endemic corruption, and expand job and educational opportunities.</p>
<p>The budget would re-establish U.S. humanitarian leadership with a request of $10 billion in assistance to support refugees, victims of conflict, other displaced people, and to rebuild our refugee admissions program.</p>
<p>It will support our partners in the Middle East by fully funding our commitments to key countries, including Israel and Jordan, and by restoring humanitarian assistance to the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>It includes a budget request of 3.6 billion to pay our assessed contributions in full to international organizations, initiatives, peacekeeping efforts, including to restore our annual contributions to the World Health Organization.</p>
<p>As China and others work hard to bend international organizations to their worldview, we have to ensure that these organizations instead remain grounded in the values, principles, and rules of the road that have made our shared progress possible for so many decades.</p>
<p>Finally, to deliver in all of these areas, the budget will reinvest in our most vital asset, and that’s our people.  It will provide new resources to recruit, to train, and to retain a first-rate, diverse global workforce, with nearly 500 additional Foreign and Civil Service positions – the largest increase for State Department staffing, excuse me, in a decade.  And it will modernize our technology – cybersecurity – protect our embassies and consulates, and include a direct appropriation of $320 million for consular services worldwide so that we can continue to provide these vital services to Americans and those who seek to study, to travel, to do business with the United States.</p>
<p>Our national security depends not only on the strength of our armed forces, but also our ability to conduct effective diplomacy and development.  That’s how we solve global challenges, forge cooperation, advance our interests and values, protect our people, prevent crises overseas from becoming emergencies here at home.  And that’s why diplomacy and development are smart investments for American taxpayers.</p>
<p>Mr. Chairman, Mr. Vice Chairman, a top priority for me as Secretary is to restore the traditional role of Congress as a partner in our foreign policymaking.  That’s the spirit that I bring to today’s conversation, the spirit I’ll bring to all future conversations and engagements with this committee, and I’m grateful for the chance to answer your questions.  Thank you very much.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Affirming the Conviction of Former Bosnian Serb Army Commander Ratko Mladic for Genocide, Crimes Against Humanity, and War Crimes</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/affirming-the-conviction-of-former-bosnian-serb-army-commander-ratko-mladic-for-genocide-crimes-against-humanity-and-war-crimes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 16:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=250314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p align="left">Today’s decision from the United Nations International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals affirming the conviction of Ratko Mladic on charges of genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes brings a measure of long-awaited justice to victims and their families in Bosnia and Herzegovina.</p>
<p align="left">As the former Commander of the Bosnian Serb Army, Mladic was a key figure in a campaign with the horrifying objective to permanently remove the Bosniak and Croat populations of Bosnia and Herzegovina from Serb-controlled territory.  The crimes committed in Bosnia and Herzegovina mark one of the darkest chapters of history following the Second World War.</p>
<p align="left">Despite efforts of perpetrators to silence witnesses, keep evidence of their crimes buried, and evade warrants of arrest, justice has prevailed in this case. We commend the courage and resilience of survivors and their loved ones who have continued to fight for the official acknowledgment of these crimes.  As we approach the 26th anniversary of the genocide at Srebrenica, we hope the verdict of the Appeals Chamber brings a measure of peace to the victims and their loved ones.  We are grateful for the years of work by the International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals in carrying out justice in this case.</p>
<p align="left">The United States will continue to press for justice, mutual trust, and reconciliation as the foundation for peace and stability.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p align="left">Today’s decision from the United Nations International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals affirming the conviction of Ratko Mladic on charges of genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes brings a measure of long-awaited justice to victims and their families in Bosnia and Herzegovina.</p>
<p align="left">As the former Commander of the Bosnian Serb Army, Mladic was a key figure in a campaign with the horrifying objective to permanently remove the Bosniak and Croat populations of Bosnia and Herzegovina from Serb-controlled territory.  The crimes committed in Bosnia and Herzegovina mark one of the darkest chapters of history following the Second World War.</p>
<p align="left">Despite efforts of perpetrators to silence witnesses, keep evidence of their crimes buried, and evade warrants of arrest, justice has prevailed in this case. We commend the courage and resilience of survivors and their loved ones who have continued to fight for the official acknowledgment of these crimes.  As we approach the 26th anniversary of the genocide at Srebrenica, we hope the verdict of the Appeals Chamber brings a measure of peace to the victims and their loved ones.  We are grateful for the years of work by the International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals in carrying out justice in this case.</p>
<p align="left">The United States will continue to press for justice, mutual trust, and reconciliation as the foundation for peace and stability.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Engagement with the UN Population Fund (UNFPA)</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-engagement-with-the-un-population-fund-unfpa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 22:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=250065</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Since the January 28, 2021 Presidential Memorandum on Protecting Women’s Health at Home and Abroad, the United States has been re-engaging with UNFPA in support of its essential work to address preventable maternal deaths and the unmet need for family planning, and prevent and respond to gender-based violence and harmful practices around the world.  Our re-engagement directly benefits communities around the globe, especially in the context of the COVID-19 pandemic.  Some of the efforts that have taken place or are currently underway include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Revitalizing High-Level Engagement: On June 7, U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations Linda Thomas-Greenfield met with UNFPA Executive Director Dr. Natalie Kanem.  This meeting represents the top-level U.S. government commitment to rebuilding U.S. support for UNFPA, implementing the directive of the January 28 Presidential Memorandum to advance sexual and reproductive health and rights.</li>
<li>Restoring Core Funding: The U.S. Department of State is taking the necessary steps to provide $30.8 million to UNFPA in Fiscal Year 2021.</li>
<li>Responding to the Rohingya Refugee Crisis: Some $2.6 million of the nearly $155 million in U.S. humanitarian assistance announced on May 18, 2021 will support UNFPA operations in responding to this crisis.</li>
<li>Responding to the Tigray Humanitarian Crisis: Nearly $1.2 million in U.S. humanitarian assistance for UNFPA will increase support for crisis-affected women who have fled the violence and instability in Ethiopia’s Tigray region to seek safe haven in Sudan.</li>
<li>Responding to Humanitarian Needs in Afghanistan: Nearly $1.5 million of the more than $266 million in U.S. humanitarian assistance announced on June 4, 2021 will support UNFPA operations as part of our commitment to international protection in Afghanistan, particularly for Afghan returnees and internally displaced persons.</li>
<li>Responding to Humanitarian Needs in Sudan: Some $1.3 million in humanitarian assistance in Sudan for a strengthened and coordinated multi-sectoral response to gender-based violence to support internally displaced persons and vulnerable populations.</li>
</ul>
<p>For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:PRMPress@state.gov">PRMPress@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Since the January 28, 2021 Presidential Memorandum on Protecting Women’s Health at Home and Abroad, the United States has been re-engaging with UNFPA in support of its essential work to address preventable maternal deaths and the unmet need for family planning, and prevent and respond to gender-based violence and harmful practices around the world.  Our re-engagement directly benefits communities around the globe, especially in the context of the COVID-19 pandemic.  Some of the efforts that have taken place or are currently underway include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Revitalizing High-Level Engagement: On June 7, U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations Linda Thomas-Greenfield met with UNFPA Executive Director Dr. Natalie Kanem.  This meeting represents the top-level U.S. government commitment to rebuilding U.S. support for UNFPA, implementing the directive of the January 28 Presidential Memorandum to advance sexual and reproductive health and rights.</li>
<li>Restoring Core Funding: The U.S. Department of State is taking the necessary steps to provide $30.8 million to UNFPA in Fiscal Year 2021.</li>
<li>Responding to the Rohingya Refugee Crisis: Some $2.6 million of the nearly $155 million in U.S. humanitarian assistance announced on May 18, 2021 will support UNFPA operations in responding to this crisis.</li>
<li>Responding to the Tigray Humanitarian Crisis: Nearly $1.2 million in U.S. humanitarian assistance for UNFPA will increase support for crisis-affected women who have fled the violence and instability in Ethiopia’s Tigray region to seek safe haven in Sudan.</li>
<li>Responding to Humanitarian Needs in Afghanistan: Nearly $1.5 million of the more than $266 million in U.S. humanitarian assistance announced on June 4, 2021 will support UNFPA operations as part of our commitment to international protection in Afghanistan, particularly for Afghan returnees and internally displaced persons.</li>
<li>Responding to Humanitarian Needs in Sudan: Some $1.3 million in humanitarian assistance in Sudan for a strengthened and coordinated multi-sectoral response to gender-based violence to support internally displaced persons and vulnerable populations.</li>
</ul>
<p>For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:PRMPress@state.gov">PRMPress@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opening Statement Before the House Committee on Appropriations, Subcommittee on State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/opening-statement-before-the-house-committee-on-appropriations-subcommittee-on-state-foreign-operations-and-related-programs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 20:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=250031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Great.  Thank you very much.  I appreciate it, and again, it’s really a pleasure to be with both of you and all the members of this committee, and I really appreciate this opportunity to talk about the administration’s proposed budget and how it will help achieve our national security priorities and deliver results for the American people, which is our common objective.</p>
<p>I do think this is a critical moment for the United States and our global leadership.  As you both alluded to, we face major tests, including stopping COVID-19, rising to the challenge of the climate crisis, supporting a global economic recovery that delivers for American workers and families.</p>
<p>We have to revitalize our alliances and partnerships; out-compete China and defend the international rules-based order against those who seek to undermine it; renew democratic values at home and abroad; and push back against malign activity by our adversaries.</p>
<p>In a more competitive world, other countries are making historic investments in their foreign policy toolkit.  We need to do the same thing.  That’s why, in this budget, we’ve requested 58.5 billion for the State Department and USAID for Fiscal Year 2022.  And Ranking Member Rogers, I just want to point out I’m already saving you some money right there.  I think it’s 58.5 billion, so I’ve been responsive to your concern.</p>
<p>And let me just give you some specifics about how we plan to spend these funds if you support them.</p>
<p>First, the budget will strengthen global health.  The United States has been a leader in this field for decades in Africa, around the world.  We’re asking for $10 billion for global health programs, including nearly $1 billion for global health security, to help us prevent, prepare for, and respond to future global health crises so we can stop outbreaks before they turn into pandemics that put our safety and prosperity in danger.</p>
<p>This budget will accelerate the global response to the climate crisis by providing 2.5 billion for international climate programs, including $1.25 billion to the Green Climate Fund, to help developing countries implement climate adaptation and emissions mitigation programs, which is directly in our interest.</p>
<p>The budget would double down on the fight for democracy, which, as we all know, is under threat in too many places.  The budget request includes $2.8 billion in foreign assistance to advance human rights, fight corruption, stem the tide of democratic backsliding, and strengthen and defend democracies – for example, through technical training for elections and support for independent media and civil society.  It also requests $300 million for the National Endowment for Democracy.</p>
<p>The budget will support a comprehensive strategy to address the root causes of irregular migration from Central America.  It will invest $861 million in the region as a first step toward a four-year commitment of $4 billion to help prevent violence, reduce poverty, curtail endemic corruption, and expand job and educational opportunity.</p>
<p>It will re-establish American humanitarian leadership, with a request of $10 billion in assistance to support refugees, victims of conflict, other displaced people, and to rebuild the refugee admissions program.</p>
<p>It will support our partners in the Middle East by fully funding our commitments to key countries, including Israel and Jordan, and by restoring humanitarian assistance to the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>It includes a budget request of $3.6 billion to pay our assessed contributions in full to international organizations, initiatives, and peacekeeping efforts, including to restore our annual contribution to the World Health Organization.</p>
<p>As China and others work hard to bend international organizations to their worldview, we need to ensure that these organizations remain grounded in the values, principles, and rules of the world – road, excuse me – that have made our shared progress possible for so many decades.</p>
<p>Finally, to deliver in all these areas, the budget will reinvest in our most vital asset – our people.  It will provide new resources to recruit, train, and retain a first-rate, diverse global workforce, with nearly 500 additional Foreign and Civil Service positions – the largest increase in State staffing in a decade.</p>
<p>And it will modernize our technology and cyber security; protect our embassies and consulates; and include a direct appropriation of $320 million for consular services worldwide, so we can continue to provide these vital services to Americans and those who seek to travel, study, or do business with the United States.</p>
<p>Our national security depends not only on the strength of our armed forces but also our ability to conduct effective diplomacy and development.  That’s how we solve global challenges, forge cooperation, advance our interests and values, protect our people, and prevent crises overseas from turning into emergencies here at home. And that’s why diplomacy and development are smart investments for American taxpayers.</p>
<p>A top priority for me as Secretary is to restore the traditional role of Congress as a partner in our foreign policy making.  That’s the spirit that I bring to today’s conversation, and I’m very grateful for this opportunity and the chance to answer any questions.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Great.  Thank you very much.  I appreciate it, and again, it’s really a pleasure to be with both of you and all the members of this committee, and I really appreciate this opportunity to talk about the administration’s proposed budget and how it will help achieve our national security priorities and deliver results for the American people, which is our common objective.</p>
<p>I do think this is a critical moment for the United States and our global leadership.  As you both alluded to, we face major tests, including stopping COVID-19, rising to the challenge of the climate crisis, supporting a global economic recovery that delivers for American workers and families.</p>
<p>We have to revitalize our alliances and partnerships; out-compete China and defend the international rules-based order against those who seek to undermine it; renew democratic values at home and abroad; and push back against malign activity by our adversaries.</p>
<p>In a more competitive world, other countries are making historic investments in their foreign policy toolkit.  We need to do the same thing.  That’s why, in this budget, we’ve requested 58.5 billion for the State Department and USAID for Fiscal Year 2022.  And Ranking Member Rogers, I just want to point out I’m already saving you some money right there.  I think it’s 58.5 billion, so I’ve been responsive to your concern.</p>
<p>And let me just give you some specifics about how we plan to spend these funds if you support them.</p>
<p>First, the budget will strengthen global health.  The United States has been a leader in this field for decades in Africa, around the world.  We’re asking for $10 billion for global health programs, including nearly $1 billion for global health security, to help us prevent, prepare for, and respond to future global health crises so we can stop outbreaks before they turn into pandemics that put our safety and prosperity in danger.</p>
<p>This budget will accelerate the global response to the climate crisis by providing 2.5 billion for international climate programs, including $1.25 billion to the Green Climate Fund, to help developing countries implement climate adaptation and emissions mitigation programs, which is directly in our interest.</p>
<p>The budget would double down on the fight for democracy, which, as we all know, is under threat in too many places.  The budget request includes $2.8 billion in foreign assistance to advance human rights, fight corruption, stem the tide of democratic backsliding, and strengthen and defend democracies – for example, through technical training for elections and support for independent media and civil society.  It also requests $300 million for the National Endowment for Democracy.</p>
<p>The budget will support a comprehensive strategy to address the root causes of irregular migration from Central America.  It will invest $861 million in the region as a first step toward a four-year commitment of $4 billion to help prevent violence, reduce poverty, curtail endemic corruption, and expand job and educational opportunity.</p>
<p>It will re-establish American humanitarian leadership, with a request of $10 billion in assistance to support refugees, victims of conflict, other displaced people, and to rebuild the refugee admissions program.</p>
<p>It will support our partners in the Middle East by fully funding our commitments to key countries, including Israel and Jordan, and by restoring humanitarian assistance to the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>It includes a budget request of $3.6 billion to pay our assessed contributions in full to international organizations, initiatives, and peacekeeping efforts, including to restore our annual contribution to the World Health Organization.</p>
<p>As China and others work hard to bend international organizations to their worldview, we need to ensure that these organizations remain grounded in the values, principles, and rules of the world – road, excuse me – that have made our shared progress possible for so many decades.</p>
<p>Finally, to deliver in all these areas, the budget will reinvest in our most vital asset – our people.  It will provide new resources to recruit, train, and retain a first-rate, diverse global workforce, with nearly 500 additional Foreign and Civil Service positions – the largest increase in State staffing in a decade.</p>
<p>And it will modernize our technology and cyber security; protect our embassies and consulates; and include a direct appropriation of $320 million for consular services worldwide, so we can continue to provide these vital services to Americans and those who seek to travel, study, or do business with the United States.</p>
<p>Our national security depends not only on the strength of our armed forces but also our ability to conduct effective diplomacy and development.  That’s how we solve global challenges, forge cooperation, advance our interests and values, protect our people, and prevent crises overseas from turning into emergencies here at home. And that’s why diplomacy and development are smart investments for American taxpayers.</p>
<p>A top priority for me as Secretary is to restore the traditional role of Congress as a partner in our foreign policy making.  That’s the spirit that I bring to today’s conversation, and I’m very grateful for this opportunity and the chance to answer any questions.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Announcement of Visa Restrictions on Those Undermining the Peaceful Resolution of the Crisis in the Anglophone Regions of Cameroon</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/announcement-of-visa-restrictions-on-those-undermining-the-peaceful-resolution-of-the-crisis-in-the-anglophone-regions-of-cameroon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 20:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=250022</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is deeply concerned by the continued violence in the Anglophone regions of Cameroon.  We continue to call for both the Cameroonian government and separatist armed groups to end the violence and engage in a dialogue without preconditions to peacefully resolve the crisis.  It is important that children can attend school and that humanitarian aid can be delivered.  We urge all relevant stakeholders in Cameroon and in the diaspora to engage constructively and seek a peaceful resolution to the crisis.</p>
<p>We condemn those who undermine peace through engaging in or inciting violence, human rights violations and abuses, and threats against advocates for peace or humanitarian workers.</p>
<p>I am establishing a policy imposing visa restrictions on individuals who are believed to be responsible for, or complicit in, undermining the peaceful resolution of the crisis in the Anglophone regions of Cameroon. This decision reflects our commitment to advance a dialogue to peacefully resolve the Anglophone crisis and support respect for human rights.  The United States strongly supports the Cameroonian people, and we remain committed to working together to advance democracy and mutual prosperity for both our countries.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is deeply concerned by the continued violence in the Anglophone regions of Cameroon.  We continue to call for both the Cameroonian government and separatist armed groups to end the violence and engage in a dialogue without preconditions to peacefully resolve the crisis.  It is important that children can attend school and that humanitarian aid can be delivered.  We urge all relevant stakeholders in Cameroon and in the diaspora to engage constructively and seek a peaceful resolution to the crisis.</p>
<p>We condemn those who undermine peace through engaging in or inciting violence, human rights violations and abuses, and threats against advocates for peace or humanitarian workers.</p>
<p>I am establishing a policy imposing visa restrictions on individuals who are believed to be responsible for, or complicit in, undermining the peaceful resolution of the crisis in the Anglophone regions of Cameroon. This decision reflects our commitment to advance a dialogue to peacefully resolve the Anglophone crisis and support respect for human rights.  The United States strongly supports the Cameroonian people, and we remain committed to working together to advance democracy and mutual prosperity for both our countries.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States Joins Intergovernmental Forum on Mining</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-joins-intergovernmental-forum-on-mining/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 17:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=249766</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary Antony Blinken signed an agreement for the United States to join the Intergovernmental Forum on Mining, Minerals, Metals, and Sustainable Development (IGF).  The IGF is a voluntary partnership that includes more than 75 member nations from six continents.  Its members share a commitment to ensure mining contributes to sustainable development and that negative impacts are limited, and financial benefits shared.</p>
<p>By joining the IGF, the United States strengthens its dedication to mining that seeks poverty reduction, inclusive growth, social development, and environmental stewardship.  The United States will continue to forge a path to improve resource governance and decision making by governments involved in mining, as it has done with the Energy Resource Governance Initiative (ERGI), which was launched in 2019.  IGF and ERGI efforts will dovetail to foster the adoption of responsible mining practices with strong environmental and ecological standards internationally and work to strengthen mineral supply chains through engagement with governments, industry, and civil society.</p>
<p>For further information, contact Donald Kilburg, Spokesperson for the Bureau of Energy Resources, at <a href="mailto:KilburgDF@state.gov">KilburgDF@state.gov</a> or visit <a href="http://www.state.gov/e/enr" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.state.gov/e/enr&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1623172661120000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFmf2gQ8GFMm9jWprzSgtGE07iWow">http://www.state.gov/e/enr</a>.  Additional information is also available on Twitter at @EnergyAtState.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary Antony Blinken signed an agreement for the United States to join the Intergovernmental Forum on Mining, Minerals, Metals, and Sustainable Development (IGF).  The IGF is a voluntary partnership that includes more than 75 member nations from six continents.  Its members share a commitment to ensure mining contributes to sustainable development and that negative impacts are limited, and financial benefits shared.</p>
<p>By joining the IGF, the United States strengthens its dedication to mining that seeks poverty reduction, inclusive growth, social development, and environmental stewardship.  The United States will continue to forge a path to improve resource governance and decision making by governments involved in mining, as it has done with the Energy Resource Governance Initiative (ERGI), which was launched in 2019.  IGF and ERGI efforts will dovetail to foster the adoption of responsible mining practices with strong environmental and ecological standards internationally and work to strengthen mineral supply chains through engagement with governments, industry, and civil society.</p>
<p>For further information, contact Donald Kilburg, Spokesperson for the Bureau of Energy Resources, at <a href="mailto:KilburgDF@state.gov">KilburgDF@state.gov</a> or visit <a href="http://www.state.gov/e/enr" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.state.gov/e/enr&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1623172661120000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFmf2gQ8GFMm9jWprzSgtGE07iWow">http://www.state.gov/e/enr</a>.  Additional information is also available on Twitter at @EnergyAtState.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opening Remarks by Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken Before the House Committee on Foreign Affairs</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/opening-remarks-by-secretary-of-state-antony-j-blinken-before-the-house-committee-on-foreign-affairs-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 16:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=249763</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Mr. Chairman, Ranking Member McCaul, all committee members, thank you very, very much for this opportunity to talk about our proposed budget and how it will help achieve our national security priorities and deliver results for the American people, which is what I know all of us are about.</p>
<p>This is a critical moment for the United States and our global leadership.</p>
<p>We face major tests – you’ve alluded to some of them already – including stopping COVID-19, rising to the challenge of the climate crisis, supporting a global economic recovery that delivers for our workers and their families.</p>
<p>We got to revitalize our alliances and partnerships, out-compete China, and defend the international rules-based order against those who would seek to undermine it, renew democratic values at home and abroad, and push back against malign activity by our adversaries.</p>
<p>In a more competitive world, other countries are making historic investments in their foreign policy toolkits.  We need to do the same.</p>
<p>That’s why, in this budget, we’ve requested $58.5 billion for the State Department and USAID for Fiscal Year 2022.</p>
<p>Here are some specifics.</p>
<p>This budget will strengthen global health. The United States has been a leader in this field for decades – in Africa, around the world.</p>
<p>We’re asking for $10 billion for global health programs, including nearly $1 billion for global health security, to help us prevent, prepare for, and better respond to future global health crises so we can stop outbreaks before they turn into pandemics that put our safety and our prosperity in danger.</p>
<p>The budget will accelerate the global response to climate change and the climate crisis by providing $2.5 billion for international climate programs, including $1.25 billion for the Green Climate Fund, to help developing countries implement climate adaptation and emissions mitigation programs, which is directly in our own interest as well.</p>
<p>The budget will double down on the fight for democracy, which, as we all know, is under threat in too many places.</p>
<p>Our budget request includes $2.8 billion in foreign assistance to advance human rights, to fight corruption, stem the tide of democratic backsliding, and strengthen and defend democracies – for example, through technical training for elections and support for independent media and civil society.</p>
<p>It also requests $300 million for the National Endowment for Democracy.</p>
<p>The budget will support a comprehensive strategy to address the root causes of irregular migration from Central America.</p>
<p>It will invest $861 million in the region, as a first step toward a four-year commitment of $4 billion to help prevent violence, reduce poverty, curtail endemic corruption, and expand job and educational opportunities.</p>
<p>The budget will reestablish U.S. humanitarian leadership, with a request for 10 billion in assistance to support refugees, victims of conflict, and other displaced people, and to rebuild our refugee admissions program.</p>
<p>It will support our partners in the Middle East by fully funding our commitments to key countries, including Israel and Jordan, and by restoring humanitarian assistance to the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>It includes a budget request of $3.6 billion to pay our assessed contributions in full to international organizations, initiatives, and peacekeeping efforts, including to restore our annual contributions to the World Health Organization.</p>
<p>As China and others work hard to bend international organizations to their worldview, we need to ensure that these organizations instead remain grounded in the values, principles, and rules of road and rules of the world that have made our shared progress possible for so many decades.</p>
<p>Finally, to deliver in all of these areas, this budget reinvests in our most vital asset – our people.</p>
<p>It will provide new resources to recruit, train, and retain a first-rate, diverse global workforce, with nearly 500 additional Foreign and Civil Service positions – the largest increase for the State Department staffing in a decade.</p>
<p>And it will modernize our technology and cybersecurity, protect our embassies and consulates, and include a direct appropriation of $320 million for consular services worldwide, so we can continue to provide these vital services to Americans and those who seek to travel, study, or do business in the United States.</p>
<p>Our national security depends not only on the strength of our armed forces but also our ability to conduct effective diplomacy and development.</p>
<p>That’s how we solve global challenges, forge cooperation, advance our interests and values, protect our people, and prevent crises overseas from turning into emergencies here at home.</p>
<p>And that’s why diplomacy and development are smart investments for our taxpayers.</p>
<p>A top priority for me as Secretary is to restore the traditional role of Congress as a partner in our foreign policy making.</p>
<p>That’s the spirit that I bring to today’s conversation, and I’m grateful for the chance to answer your questions.</p>
<p>Thank you very much.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Mr. Chairman, Ranking Member McCaul, all committee members, thank you very, very much for this opportunity to talk about our proposed budget and how it will help achieve our national security priorities and deliver results for the American people, which is what I know all of us are about.</p>
<p>This is a critical moment for the United States and our global leadership.</p>
<p>We face major tests – you’ve alluded to some of them already – including stopping COVID-19, rising to the challenge of the climate crisis, supporting a global economic recovery that delivers for our workers and their families.</p>
<p>We got to revitalize our alliances and partnerships, out-compete China, and defend the international rules-based order against those who would seek to undermine it, renew democratic values at home and abroad, and push back against malign activity by our adversaries.</p>
<p>In a more competitive world, other countries are making historic investments in their foreign policy toolkits.  We need to do the same.</p>
<p>That’s why, in this budget, we’ve requested $58.5 billion for the State Department and USAID for Fiscal Year 2022.</p>
<p>Here are some specifics.</p>
<p>This budget will strengthen global health. The United States has been a leader in this field for decades – in Africa, around the world.</p>
<p>We’re asking for $10 billion for global health programs, including nearly $1 billion for global health security, to help us prevent, prepare for, and better respond to future global health crises so we can stop outbreaks before they turn into pandemics that put our safety and our prosperity in danger.</p>
<p>The budget will accelerate the global response to climate change and the climate crisis by providing $2.5 billion for international climate programs, including $1.25 billion for the Green Climate Fund, to help developing countries implement climate adaptation and emissions mitigation programs, which is directly in our own interest as well.</p>
<p>The budget will double down on the fight for democracy, which, as we all know, is under threat in too many places.</p>
<p>Our budget request includes $2.8 billion in foreign assistance to advance human rights, to fight corruption, stem the tide of democratic backsliding, and strengthen and defend democracies – for example, through technical training for elections and support for independent media and civil society.</p>
<p>It also requests $300 million for the National Endowment for Democracy.</p>
<p>The budget will support a comprehensive strategy to address the root causes of irregular migration from Central America.</p>
<p>It will invest $861 million in the region, as a first step toward a four-year commitment of $4 billion to help prevent violence, reduce poverty, curtail endemic corruption, and expand job and educational opportunities.</p>
<p>The budget will reestablish U.S. humanitarian leadership, with a request for 10 billion in assistance to support refugees, victims of conflict, and other displaced people, and to rebuild our refugee admissions program.</p>
<p>It will support our partners in the Middle East by fully funding our commitments to key countries, including Israel and Jordan, and by restoring humanitarian assistance to the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>It includes a budget request of $3.6 billion to pay our assessed contributions in full to international organizations, initiatives, and peacekeeping efforts, including to restore our annual contributions to the World Health Organization.</p>
<p>As China and others work hard to bend international organizations to their worldview, we need to ensure that these organizations instead remain grounded in the values, principles, and rules of road and rules of the world that have made our shared progress possible for so many decades.</p>
<p>Finally, to deliver in all of these areas, this budget reinvests in our most vital asset – our people.</p>
<p>It will provide new resources to recruit, train, and retain a first-rate, diverse global workforce, with nearly 500 additional Foreign and Civil Service positions – the largest increase for the State Department staffing in a decade.</p>
<p>And it will modernize our technology and cybersecurity, protect our embassies and consulates, and include a direct appropriation of $320 million for consular services worldwide, so we can continue to provide these vital services to Americans and those who seek to travel, study, or do business in the United States.</p>
<p>Our national security depends not only on the strength of our armed forces but also our ability to conduct effective diplomacy and development.</p>
<p>That’s how we solve global challenges, forge cooperation, advance our interests and values, protect our people, and prevent crises overseas from turning into emergencies here at home.</p>
<p>And that’s why diplomacy and development are smart investments for our taxpayers.</p>
<p>A top priority for me as Secretary is to restore the traditional role of Congress as a partner in our foreign policy making.</p>
<p>That’s the spirit that I bring to today’s conversation, and I’m grateful for the chance to answer your questions.</p>
<p>Thank you very much.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcoming the Inaugural Meeting of the Blue Dot Network Executive Consultation Group</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/welcoming-the-inaugural-meeting-of-the-blue-dot-network-executive-consultation-group/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 14:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=249706</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomed the inaugural meeting of the Blue Dot Network Executive Consultation Group (ECG) held on June 7, 2021.  The OECD, through technical support funded by the United States and Australia, organized the ECG to convene the private sector, civil society, and academia to advise on the design and implementation of the Blue Dot Network infrastructure initiative.</p>
<p>The Blue Dot Network, announced by the United States, Australia, and Japan in November 2019, is being developed to become a certification mechanism to distinguish quality infrastructure projects that demonstrate and uphold robust standards for development.  The Blue Dot Network will be a globally recognized symbol of market-driven, transparent, and sustainable infrastructure projects.</p>
<p>More than 180 representatives from the ECG, comprising leading financiers, infrastructure developers, construction companies, and civil society organizations from around the world, gathered virtually for a strategic dialogue on catalyzing investment into quality infrastructure.   Participants exchanged views and ideas on how the Blue Dot Network initiative could help close the global infrastructure gap and create high standard, sustainable infrastructure in emerging markets.</p>
<p>The ECG meeting is part of a broader OECD effort to support development of the Blue Dot Network.  In addition to mobilizing stakeholder partnerships and establishing the value proposition of the Blue Dot Network, the OECD has begun helping the Blue Dot Network design the certification framework that is at the heart of the initiative.</p>
<p>The United States also welcomed the results of an OECD survey in which respondents endorsed the concept of the Blue Dot Network and agreed that such a certification framework to identify sustainable, high standard projects could spur greater infrastructure investment in emerging markets.  The report also identified challenges faced by infrastructure investors, including poor governance, lack of transparency, and weak legal and regulatory frameworks.  Respondents also acknowledged environmental and social risks when designing and implementing infrastructure projects.</p>
<p>The survey highlighted strong interest among respondents in environmental and social governance issues, including a commitment by 70 percent of industry respondents to establish targets to meet net-zero emissions by 2050.</p>
<p>The United States, Australia, and Japan look forward to continued collaboration with the OECD and the Executive Consultation Group on development of the Blue Dot Network.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomed the inaugural meeting of the Blue Dot Network Executive Consultation Group (ECG) held on June 7, 2021.  The OECD, through technical support funded by the United States and Australia, organized the ECG to convene the private sector, civil society, and academia to advise on the design and implementation of the Blue Dot Network infrastructure initiative.</p>
<p>The Blue Dot Network, announced by the United States, Australia, and Japan in November 2019, is being developed to become a certification mechanism to distinguish quality infrastructure projects that demonstrate and uphold robust standards for development.  The Blue Dot Network will be a globally recognized symbol of market-driven, transparent, and sustainable infrastructure projects.</p>
<p>More than 180 representatives from the ECG, comprising leading financiers, infrastructure developers, construction companies, and civil society organizations from around the world, gathered virtually for a strategic dialogue on catalyzing investment into quality infrastructure.   Participants exchanged views and ideas on how the Blue Dot Network initiative could help close the global infrastructure gap and create high standard, sustainable infrastructure in emerging markets.</p>
<p>The ECG meeting is part of a broader OECD effort to support development of the Blue Dot Network.  In addition to mobilizing stakeholder partnerships and establishing the value proposition of the Blue Dot Network, the OECD has begun helping the Blue Dot Network design the certification framework that is at the heart of the initiative.</p>
<p>The United States also welcomed the results of an OECD survey in which respondents endorsed the concept of the Blue Dot Network and agreed that such a certification framework to identify sustainable, high standard projects could spur greater infrastructure investment in emerging markets.  The report also identified challenges faced by infrastructure investors, including poor governance, lack of transparency, and weak legal and regulatory frameworks.  Respondents also acknowledged environmental and social risks when designing and implementing infrastructure projects.</p>
<p>The survey highlighted strong interest among respondents in environmental and social governance issues, including a commitment by 70 percent of industry respondents to establish targets to meet net-zero emissions by 2050.</p>
<p>The United States, Australia, and Japan look forward to continued collaboration with the OECD and the Executive Consultation Group on development of the Blue Dot Network.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Mike Allen of Axios on HBO Max</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-mike-allen-of-axios-on-hbo-max/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 12:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=249674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Ben Franklin Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Mike Allen.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Mr. Secretary, welcome back.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Good to see you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Mr. Secretary, thank you for welcoming Axios on HBO into the State Department, the Benjamin Franklin State Dining Room.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>That’s right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>So you’ve said that job one for you is restoring partnerships and alliances.  That’s been harder than it sounded.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, it was a challenge, especially in the first couple of months.  Hard to travel because of COVID, so a lot of it was getting on the phone, starting to re-engage with partners.  We’ve finally been able to travel, and I’m finding that there’s been a real thirst and a welcoming of U.S. engagement.  I think it’s a reflection of the fact that our partners see the same thing that we do.  If you’re looking at all of the really big problems that we’re trying to solve that actually have an impact on our people’s lives – like the pandemic, like climate change, like emerging technologies that are changing lives in different ways – no one country can do it alone.  We have to find ways to cooperate, to collaborate, to do it together.  So there’s a lot of welcoming of the United States being back in the game.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>When you say back in the game, the implication is the previous administration, out of the game.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, look, I’m focused on looking forward.  When we’re not engaged, then one of two things is likely to happen.  Some other country is likely to try to engage in our place &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>China.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>For example, and maybe not in a way that advances are interests and values.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>And is that already happening?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>We’ve certainly seen that.  We’ve certainly seen &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>With China?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>&#8212; China try to fill voids where we’ve been relatively disengaged.  Or maybe just as bad, no one does it and then you are likely to have chaos before you have anything else – nature, of course, a vacuum.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Naftali Bennett, who is poised to be the next prime minister of Israel, has said that he’s opposed to a two-state solution.  He says that based on security concerns, it would be suicide for Israel.  So what’s the path?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, first, let’s see what actually happens in Israel in terms of the government &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>But you agree that that’s expected?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>That seems to be expected, but again, I’m not doing politics, I’m going to focus on the policy, so we’ll see.  We will work, as we always have, with whatever the Israeli government is.  When it comes to two states, our President’s been very clear about this.  We see a two-state solution as the best and probably only means to ensure that, going forward, Israel remains not only a secure but a Jewish and democratic state, and the Palestinians have the state to which they’re entitled.</p>
<p>But the conditions right now are not – are not there.  We’ve just come off of the violence in Gaza and elsewhere.  We’re working very hard not only to make sure that the ceasefire stays in place, but to start to deal with the humanitarian situation in Gaza.  And over time, if we can build a little bit more hope, a little bit more trust, a little bit more confidence, maybe then the conditions are in place to re-engage on two states.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  The department said in May that you hadn’t personally seen the evidence Israel says it has that Hamas was occupying the tower in Gaza – that they’d took down – that had news organizations including the AP in it.  What happens if there turns out to be no smoking gun?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Two things.  First, President Biden has been very clear Israel has the right to defend itself and it was on the receiving end of indiscriminate rocket attacks coming from Gaza going after Israeli civilians.  And &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So you were fine with that building being taken down?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Any country would defend itself and Israel has the right.  However, having said that, Israel as a democracy I think has an added burden to make sure it is doing everything possible to avoid civilian causalities.  And that’s what is expected of us; it’s expected of Israel.  We have our own experience with this, and I think one of the things that we found ourselves, speaking only for the United States, is that the more transparency you can provide, the more legitimacy you’re going to have.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So based on that, do you think that we’ll see clear evidence?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  All I can tell you is we’ve had information shared in intelligence channels, which I can’t, for obvious reasons, comment on.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Did you find it convincing?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I can’t comment on it.  But I do think from our own experience, the more transparency, the better.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  China.  Can we win an open-ended arms race with Beijing?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, we don’t want to be in an arms race with Beijing or anyone.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  We are.  We are.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  What we want – no, we’re in a very stiff competition.  Look, the relationship with China is both the most complicated and most consequential that we have.  There are adversarial aspects to it, there are competitive aspects, there are cooperative aspects.  And we have tremendous sources of strength when it comes to each one of those aspects.  We have our allies and partners, but most important, we have ourselves.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, what are the implications if Beijing is found to have been covering up a Wuhan lab leak?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We have to get to the bottom of what happened.  There’s accountability, but from my perspective the most important thing, and the most important reason we have to get to the bottom of this, is that’s the only way we’re going to be able to prevent the next pandemic, or at least do a better job in mitigating it.  What the government didn’t do in the early days and still hasn’t done is given us the transparency we need, the international community – access for inspectors and experts, the sharing of information in real time.  That has to happen.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So to get those answers, to do a proper investigation, you’re going to need – the U.S. is going to need access to the labs.  Will you demand that?  Will you put teeth on it?  Will you even go as far as sanctions on China if they keep inspectors out?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I think the international community is clear that we have to have – the international community has to have access, it has to have information, it has to have meaningful international &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So what’s the real pressure the U.S. will put on China for access to the lab?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  If China denies the information, denies the access, denies the transparency that’s needed, it is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And you kind of expect that?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, let’s see.  Because &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>That’s been the history.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Mike, at the end of the day it’s profoundly in China’s interest to do this as well, because, look, it suffered too in the outbreak of this pandemic.  It presumably has an interest as well, especially if it purports to be a responsible international actor, to do everything it can to provide all the information it has to make sure we can hopefully prevent this from happening again.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>The Trump administration had a number of executive orders cracking down on people who were tied to the Chinese Communist Party – we’re talking about export bans.  How are you thinking about that and will you be tougher?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Look, I think the Trump administration was right to look at that.  And we’re &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And to act on it?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  And to act on it.  And we’re reviewing all of that as we speak.  And for example, it’s very important that we not – American companies or individuals – aid and abet, for example, China’s ability to use surveillance technology to repress its own people, or to export that technology to allow other autocratic or authoritarian governments from doing the same thing.  I think that’s very important.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Last stop on the tour, Russia.  With these cyber attacks, President Putin is thumbing his nose at the U.S. – blatant disrespect.  What is the U.S. going to do about it?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, what we’re going to do about it is to do what President Biden has already done, which is to make very clear &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But it’s not working.  We’ve had our food supply threatened, we’ve had our energy supply threatened, now transportation threatened.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Look, there are – we would prefer to have a more stable, predictable relationship with Russia.  We’ve made that clear.  But we’ve made equally clear that if Russia chooses to act aggressively or recklessly toward us or toward our allies and partners, we’ll respond.</p>
<p>When it comes to these ransomware attacks, of course, we’ve already talked to the Russians about this.  One of the things we’re seeing is that criminal enterprises seem to be engaged in these attacks.  And it is an obligation on the part of any country, including Russia, if it has a criminal enterprise acting from its territory against anyone else, to do what’s necessary to stop it, to bring it to justice.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And yet, Mr. Secretary, Putin is clearly completely undeterred.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  One of the reasons that the President will be meeting with President Putin in a week’s time is not in spite of these aggressions, these attacks, it’s because of them, to tell him directly and clearly what he can expect from the United States if aggressive, reckless actions toward us continue.  Equally, though, to make clear that if Russia by its actions chooses a different course, we would prefer a more stable, predictable relationship.  There are things we can do together that would advance the security of our people, the Russian people, people around the world – strategic stability, arms control.  So we’re going to explore that.  We have to test the proposition, and the best way to do that is for the two presidents to meet face to face.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Are you optimistic that after that summit that there will be a, as you put it, “more stable” relationship?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  This is going to be a test of that proposition.  I can’t tell you whether I’m optimistic or not about the results of that test, but it’s important to do that.  And also, I don’t think we’re going to know after one meeting, but we’ll have some indications and we’ll see.  We’re prepared either way.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  What do you mean by prepared?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, as I said, we’re prepared if Russia chooses to continue reckless and aggressive action – we’re prepared to deal with that, as we have – on the other hand, if it chooses a different course, we’re prepared to engage.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Ben Franklin Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Mike Allen.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Mr. Secretary, welcome back.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Good to see you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Mr. Secretary, thank you for welcoming Axios on HBO into the State Department, the Benjamin Franklin State Dining Room.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>That’s right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>So you’ve said that job one for you is restoring partnerships and alliances.  That’s been harder than it sounded.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, it was a challenge, especially in the first couple of months.  Hard to travel because of COVID, so a lot of it was getting on the phone, starting to re-engage with partners.  We’ve finally been able to travel, and I’m finding that there’s been a real thirst and a welcoming of U.S. engagement.  I think it’s a reflection of the fact that our partners see the same thing that we do.  If you’re looking at all of the really big problems that we’re trying to solve that actually have an impact on our people’s lives – like the pandemic, like climate change, like emerging technologies that are changing lives in different ways – no one country can do it alone.  We have to find ways to cooperate, to collaborate, to do it together.  So there’s a lot of welcoming of the United States being back in the game.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>When you say back in the game, the implication is the previous administration, out of the game.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, look, I’m focused on looking forward.  When we’re not engaged, then one of two things is likely to happen.  Some other country is likely to try to engage in our place &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>China.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>For example, and maybe not in a way that advances are interests and values.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>And is that already happening?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>We’ve certainly seen that.  We’ve certainly seen &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>With China?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>&#8212; China try to fill voids where we’ve been relatively disengaged.  Or maybe just as bad, no one does it and then you are likely to have chaos before you have anything else – nature, of course, a vacuum.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Naftali Bennett, who is poised to be the next prime minister of Israel, has said that he’s opposed to a two-state solution.  He says that based on security concerns, it would be suicide for Israel.  So what’s the path?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, first, let’s see what actually happens in Israel in terms of the government &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>But you agree that that’s expected?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>That seems to be expected, but again, I’m not doing politics, I’m going to focus on the policy, so we’ll see.  We will work, as we always have, with whatever the Israeli government is.  When it comes to two states, our President’s been very clear about this.  We see a two-state solution as the best and probably only means to ensure that, going forward, Israel remains not only a secure but a Jewish and democratic state, and the Palestinians have the state to which they’re entitled.</p>
<p>But the conditions right now are not – are not there.  We’ve just come off of the violence in Gaza and elsewhere.  We’re working very hard not only to make sure that the ceasefire stays in place, but to start to deal with the humanitarian situation in Gaza.  And over time, if we can build a little bit more hope, a little bit more trust, a little bit more confidence, maybe then the conditions are in place to re-engage on two states.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  The department said in May that you hadn’t personally seen the evidence Israel says it has that Hamas was occupying the tower in Gaza – that they’d took down – that had news organizations including the AP in it.  What happens if there turns out to be no smoking gun?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Two things.  First, President Biden has been very clear Israel has the right to defend itself and it was on the receiving end of indiscriminate rocket attacks coming from Gaza going after Israeli civilians.  And &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So you were fine with that building being taken down?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Any country would defend itself and Israel has the right.  However, having said that, Israel as a democracy I think has an added burden to make sure it is doing everything possible to avoid civilian causalities.  And that’s what is expected of us; it’s expected of Israel.  We have our own experience with this, and I think one of the things that we found ourselves, speaking only for the United States, is that the more transparency you can provide, the more legitimacy you’re going to have.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So based on that, do you think that we’ll see clear evidence?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  All I can tell you is we’ve had information shared in intelligence channels, which I can’t, for obvious reasons, comment on.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Did you find it convincing?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I can’t comment on it.  But I do think from our own experience, the more transparency, the better.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  China.  Can we win an open-ended arms race with Beijing?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, we don’t want to be in an arms race with Beijing or anyone.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  We are.  We are.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  What we want – no, we’re in a very stiff competition.  Look, the relationship with China is both the most complicated and most consequential that we have.  There are adversarial aspects to it, there are competitive aspects, there are cooperative aspects.  And we have tremendous sources of strength when it comes to each one of those aspects.  We have our allies and partners, but most important, we have ourselves.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, what are the implications if Beijing is found to have been covering up a Wuhan lab leak?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We have to get to the bottom of what happened.  There’s accountability, but from my perspective the most important thing, and the most important reason we have to get to the bottom of this, is that’s the only way we’re going to be able to prevent the next pandemic, or at least do a better job in mitigating it.  What the government didn’t do in the early days and still hasn’t done is given us the transparency we need, the international community – access for inspectors and experts, the sharing of information in real time.  That has to happen.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So to get those answers, to do a proper investigation, you’re going to need – the U.S. is going to need access to the labs.  Will you demand that?  Will you put teeth on it?  Will you even go as far as sanctions on China if they keep inspectors out?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I think the international community is clear that we have to have – the international community has to have access, it has to have information, it has to have meaningful international &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So what’s the real pressure the U.S. will put on China for access to the lab?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  If China denies the information, denies the access, denies the transparency that’s needed, it is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And you kind of expect that?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, let’s see.  Because &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>That’s been the history.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Mike, at the end of the day it’s profoundly in China’s interest to do this as well, because, look, it suffered too in the outbreak of this pandemic.  It presumably has an interest as well, especially if it purports to be a responsible international actor, to do everything it can to provide all the information it has to make sure we can hopefully prevent this from happening again.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>The Trump administration had a number of executive orders cracking down on people who were tied to the Chinese Communist Party – we’re talking about export bans.  How are you thinking about that and will you be tougher?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Look, I think the Trump administration was right to look at that.  And we’re &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And to act on it?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  And to act on it.  And we’re reviewing all of that as we speak.  And for example, it’s very important that we not – American companies or individuals – aid and abet, for example, China’s ability to use surveillance technology to repress its own people, or to export that technology to allow other autocratic or authoritarian governments from doing the same thing.  I think that’s very important.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Last stop on the tour, Russia.  With these cyber attacks, President Putin is thumbing his nose at the U.S. – blatant disrespect.  What is the U.S. going to do about it?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, what we’re going to do about it is to do what President Biden has already done, which is to make very clear &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But it’s not working.  We’ve had our food supply threatened, we’ve had our energy supply threatened, now transportation threatened.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Look, there are – we would prefer to have a more stable, predictable relationship with Russia.  We’ve made that clear.  But we’ve made equally clear that if Russia chooses to act aggressively or recklessly toward us or toward our allies and partners, we’ll respond.</p>
<p>When it comes to these ransomware attacks, of course, we’ve already talked to the Russians about this.  One of the things we’re seeing is that criminal enterprises seem to be engaged in these attacks.  And it is an obligation on the part of any country, including Russia, if it has a criminal enterprise acting from its territory against anyone else, to do what’s necessary to stop it, to bring it to justice.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And yet, Mr. Secretary, Putin is clearly completely undeterred.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  One of the reasons that the President will be meeting with President Putin in a week’s time is not in spite of these aggressions, these attacks, it’s because of them, to tell him directly and clearly what he can expect from the United States if aggressive, reckless actions toward us continue.  Equally, though, to make clear that if Russia by its actions chooses a different course, we would prefer a more stable, predictable relationship.  There are things we can do together that would advance the security of our people, the Russian people, people around the world – strategic stability, arms control.  So we’re going to explore that.  We have to test the proposition, and the best way to do that is for the two presidents to meet face to face.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Are you optimistic that after that summit that there will be a, as you put it, “more stable” relationship?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  This is going to be a test of that proposition.  I can’t tell you whether I’m optimistic or not about the results of that test, but it’s important to do that.  And also, I don’t think we’re going to know after one meeting, but we’ll have some indications and we’ll see.  We’re prepared either way.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  What do you mean by prepared?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, as I said, we’re prepared if Russia chooses to continue reckless and aggressive action – we’re prepared to deal with that, as we have – on the other hand, if it chooses a different course, we’re prepared to engage.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
