<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 15:29:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Briefing with Senior Administration Officials Previewing Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Upcoming Travel to the People’s Republic of China</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-with-senior-administration-officials-previewing-deputy-secretary-shermans-upcoming-travel-to-the-peoples-republic-of-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 15:25:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261842</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hello, everyone.  We are here today to discuss the Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman’s travel to the People’s Republic of China or the PRC on July 25th through 26th, following her stops in Tokyo, Seoul, and Ulaanbaatar.  Today’s briefers are  and .  Today we will provide a brief preview of the deputy secretary’s planned discussions, which are part of ongoing U.S. efforts to hold candid exchanges with PRC officials to advance U.S. interests and values.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today’s call is on background and for your reporting purposes our briefers should be referred to as senior administration officials.  All contents of the call are embargoed until the conclusion of this call.  With that, I’ll hand it over to .</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, thanks very much, and thank you all for joining us.  The deputy secretary is going to be traveling to Tianjin tomorrow for discussions with the Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi and Vice Foreign Minister Xie Feng.  The deputy secretary’s travel to China follows a week of important engagements with allies and partners in Japan, we were in Seoul a little bit earlier, and right now we’re in Mongolia.  The deputy secretary used her meetings there to underscore the United States commitment to standing shoulder to shoulder with our allies and partners to address pressing global challenges, advance a free and open Indo-Pacific, and uphold and strengthen the rules-based international order.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’ve said we are prepared to engage Chinese officials when we believe those engagements will be substantive and constructive.  Those are the terms on which we agreed to this visit.  So Deputy Secretary Sherman’s meetings are a continuation of the discussions we had in Anchorage in March around setting the terms for the relationship and achieving a steady state of affairs between our countries.  We believe it’s important to maintain open lines of communication between high-level officials.  Frank and open discussion, even – perhaps especially – where we disagree, is critical to reducing the potential for misunderstandings between our countries, maintaining global peace and security, and making progress on important issues.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As Secretary Blinken has said, the U.S. relationship with China will be collaborative where it can be, competitive where it should be, and adversarial where it must be.  And we expect all dimensions of the relationship will be on the table for discussion during Wendy’s meetings.  You know as well as I do she’s a seasoned diplomat.  We’re going into these meetings with our eyes wide open.  The deputy secretary is going to represent the U.S. interests and values and those of our allies and partners.  We’re going to do it honestly and directly.  In Tianjin, she’s going to make clear while we welcome stiff and sustained competition with the PRC, everyone needs to play by the same rules and on the level – on a level playing field.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She’s going to underscore that we do not want that stiff and sustained competition to veer into conflict.  This is why the U.S. wants to ensure that there are guard rails and parameters in place to responsibly manage the relationship.  While I’m not going to preview Wendy’s full agenda, I think you can anticipate that she will take the opportunity to explain our concerns about many of Beijing&#8217;s actions, including those on which we’ve taken recent steps, both on our own and in – excuse me – coordination with our allies and partners. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And at the same time, there are important global challenges where the U.S. and China both have an interest and where we think it’s important to exchange views and explore potential areas for cooperation.  So we anticipate that this will also be a focus of these meetings. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before I turn it over to , I just want to say that I’m sure you’re all aware of the floods that have been going on this week in Hunan Province.  We’re very much aware of that as we head into Tianjin.  I would anticipate that the deputy secretary is going to express condolences to the Chinese for the loss of life and also concern for those who are missing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So with that, I’m going to turn it over to my colleague .</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, thanks, .  And thanks again, everybody, for joining us on a Saturday morning.  Your time, appreciate it very much.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let me just underscore a few points on why and how we are engaging Chinese officials in Tianjin.  As we said in advance of our conversations in Anchorage and as we’ve discussed consistently, we think it’s important for us to say directly to Chinese officials in private what we say in public.  It’s in our interests to be very clear to Beijing about where we stand and explain our concerns in detail.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The main purpose of this meeting is to have frank and honest exchanges about the relationship.  The goal isn’t to negotiate over specifics, but rather keep the channels of communication open at a senior level, and our philosophy is that we should not avoid hard topics just to be polite because that will only allow problems to fester.  As we’ve made clear in our actions and words, we believe it’s important to responsibly manage the relationship, as  said, even and especially when the relationship is challenging.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So let me also put this meeting into the context of the administration’s broader China policy effort.  Since President Biden took office, we’ve put a lot of focus on strengthening our own competitive hand vis-a-vis China through many actions that we’ve taken domestically, investing in ourselves at home.  We’ve also rallied our allies and partners, including to advance an affirmative vision of the rules-based international order.  And we’ve confronted China when they’ve acted against our interests and values while working to cooperate with China on areas like climate change and nonproliferation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We know we’re stronger when we work with our allies.  We know this makes us more effective when dealing with Beijing.  We aren’t seeking an anti-China coalition in our work with allies and partners, but rather trying to work together in a multilateral fashion to uphold the international rules-based order.  So when the deputy secretary sits down with her interlocutors, I anticipate very clearly that she will be not only representing the United States, but she will be standing up and advocating her positions that are shared around the world. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And across the three pillars of our approach to China policy – investing in ourselves at home, working with our allies and partners and through international institutions, and confronting China where we need to while cooperating where we can – we’re actively executing on our strategy to present that affirmative vision, demonstrate that democracies can and do best deliver results for our people and people around the world – a premise that President Biden is deeply invested in – and that we’re competing effectively with China.  With all of those actions underway, we’re entering this engagement from a position of strength and of solidarity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But this bilateral engagement is just one piece of the puzzle when it comes to our China policy.  We are doing many things at once.  We have a multifaceted approach to a multifaceted relationship.  We’re engaging at a senior level precisely because we are in a competitive relationship.  We want to maintain open dialogue so that we are able to – so that we are being responsible and not letting the competition veer into an unintended conflict.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even as we meet with our Chinese counterparts, we will also continue to hold China accountable.  These things are not mutually exclusive, and it should be clear that we are not afraid to impose costs for China’s behavior that undermines international norms.  We will do this simultaneously with our engagement.  For example, as you’ve all seen in just the last few weeks, we’ve taken actions on Beijing’s efforts to erode democracy in Hong Kong, human rights abuses in Xinjiang, its use of forced labor, and its malicious cyber activities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Historically, people, I think, have had a binary assumption that either we’re in a period of engagement with China or we’re in a period of confrontation – essentially, that the relationship goes up and down.  But that’s just not the case anymore.  This is a continuation of the steady state of affairs and it’s in that context that we see this meeting occurring.  So with that, I think we’re happy to take some questions.</span></p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Let’s go to the line of David Brunnstrom.</span></p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Mr. Brunnstrom, your line is open.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Thank you very much.  I wondered if you could give any comment on the sanctions China announced ahead of these talks and whether or not that’s helpful.  And can you also tell us whether the United States side will be warning China of the possibility of more sanctions, for instance, over Iran oil shipments or in response to the Microsoft hack, and whether that’s going to be any sort of leverage in the talks?</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Thanks, David.  Look, I would say a few things.  We’ve obviously seen China’s counter sanctions this week, which we think are just another instance of China targeting private citizens and others for actions that the U.S. Government is taking to uphold our interests and values.  Look, we remain fully committed to implementing all relevant U.S. sanctions authorities, and as we’ve said, to take actions that are consistent with our interests and values.  We think this kind of retaliation is really just an example of how Beijing punishes those who speak out and further illustrates China’s deteriorating climate and rising political risks on many different fronts.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the second part of your question, look, I think that trying to think about some of these things as leverage is certainly not how we’re thinking about this.  Again, we are acting in ways that are intended to protect our interests and values and those of our allies and partners.  We certainly will raise concerns where we have them about where we think Beijing may be acting inconsistently with UN Security Council resolutions or with other elements of international law.  I’m not going to get ahead of the secretary – of the deputy secretary’s points and agenda in terms of what she may raise, but I think that you certainly can anticipate that she will be raising concerns about where we believe Beijing is violating (inaudible).</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Yeah, so – right, I don’t think that the deputy secretary is going in thinking that those measures or those actions that the Chinese took are going to be leverage in these talks.  We are definitely going to be engaging with them, as we said, on substantive and constructive issues.  Thank you.</span></p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Let’s go to Demetri Sevastopulo.</span></p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Your line is open.  Go ahead.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Yeah, good morning.  Can you hear me?</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Yeah, we hear you.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Great, morning.  So my question is:  In the last six months, you’ve taken a range of actions towards China.  You’ve also done an awful lot with allies, particularly in Asia, also in Europe.  Can you point to a few examples of where you think U.S. policy towards China has actually caused China to do things differently over the last six months?</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  So I’m happy to point to a couple of things, Demetri, and thanks for the question.  I mean, number one is, as you rightly note, a huge part of our emphasis on our approach to China is working with allies and partners.  And I think there’s a few things I would note as context before getting to the second part of your question.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think a lot of our effort is really aimed at shaping the international environment around China, on building resilience among allies and partners to Beijing’s coercive and – and actions that are at odds with our collective interests and values and ensuring, as we said, that we can present an affirmative vision.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the things, though, I think that we’ve really seen is that these multilateral actions have really gotten Beijing’s attention, and in some cases I think has actually caused Beijing in many ways to take steps that actually are potentially counter to its own interests, where we saw Beijing impose its own counter sanctions on European officials, European parliamentarians after the multilateral actions imposed some Xinjiang sanctions back in March.  That certainly has given some pause to certain quarters in Europe about things like the comprehensive agreement on investment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think there’s other areas where we’ve also seen Beijing take some pretty assertive steps when we have acted in concert with allies and partners, and I think it’s a demonstration of the fact that those multilateral actions really get Beijing’s attention.  And so I think it is really that broad upholding of international norms and rules and principles as well as the shaping of the international environment around China that is really, again, having the potential I think in the long term to influence Beijing’s actions.  So I think that’s basically reflective of the approach that we’re taking and some of the ways I see that playing out.</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Yeah, and I think it’s really important to note here that it’s not just one action that we would be taking.  We’re talking about the accumulation of actions here showing China that this is – we’re redefining this relationship (inaudible) not going to be afraid to take steps when we see that our interests have to be defended.  And so I think that in the long run, you’re going to see a little bit more rather than pointing at a specific action in response to one of our actions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s really – what we’re showing is that we are going to continue doing this, that this – the relationship is stabilized in this manner, that we’re going to take consistent action when we have to.  And that’s going to result in modified behavior down the – in the future.</span></p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Let’s go to Francesco Fontemaggi.</span></p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Thank you, and before we open Mr. Fontemaggi’s line, if I may remind you, to ask a question, press 1 then 0 on your touchtone phone. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mr. Fontemaggi, your line is open.  Go ahead.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Hi, good morning.  Thank you.  As you said at the top to – you’ve said several times that you were prepared to engage when you believe these meetings would be substantive and constructive.  As David mentioned, there were these counter sanctions just in the past few days and a decision from China not to cooperate with the WHO inquiry on the COVID origins and several other actions by China.  What makes – what exactly makes you think that this is the right time to have constructive and substantive meetings?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And also, if I may, is this meeting from deputy secretary – is that to prepare any future meeting at the top level between the presidents?  Thank you.</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Yeah, I think this is not just about timing, ups and downs in the relationship like we defined it maybe in the past.  I think when we’re talking about timing here, we&#8217;re going to take advantage of opportunities if there are areas that are constructive.  I just mentioned a little bit earlier these very, very dangerous floods that are going on in Hunan.  I think that if you read what the Chinese are saying about these floods, it&#8217;s very apparent to them – they know that there are climate issues out there, there are these causes out there that they have to fix themselves if they&#8217;re going to – if they&#8217;re going to resolve some of these problems that affect all of their citizens, they&#8217;re going to have to join global movements.  And I think that there are opportunities for us to take advantage of what&#8217;s happening there where the Chinese people agree with the international community.  So I mean, that&#8217;s an example of how we can be constructive.</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thanks.  Yeah, I&#8217;ll just briefly – I think – I totally agree with .  I think I would just note, again, if we&#8217;re coming from the perspective that we are in stiff and sustained competition with China, that we need to establish ways to responsibly manage that competition and really manage the relationship for the long term.  And that requires an understanding that we can&#8217;t avoid talking when times are difficult, that we have to be able to engage at senior levels in order to have responsible management of the relationship.  And so I think that we&#8217;re not really seeing this from a framework of are we up, are we down, as I said.  I think that&#8217;s, as  noted, a sort of arcane way of understanding the relationship between the U.S. and China.  We just – we really believe that we&#8217;ve got to be able to have frank and open and honest conversations, even and particularly when we’re in difficult times.</span></p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">We&#8217;ll go to Colum Murphy.</span></p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your line is open.  Go ahead.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mr. Murphy, I&#8217;ve actually released you from the queue.  If you would press 1 then 0 again at this point, we&#8217;ll open your line. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mr. Murphy, your line is open.  Go ahead, please.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Great, thank you.  I just wanted to see if you could give some more guidance on the logistics of the events tomorrow and Monday.  Some of us are looking to go to Tianjin and we just want to see what is the timing of the different meetings, which – what&#8217;s the order.  Where will the delegation stay, for example?  Right now we have very little information.  I’m just wondering if you could elaborate a little bit more on the on-the-ground sort of proceedings over the next two days.  Thank you.</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah, some of those logistics formatting questions or format questions are still being decided.  I think you can understand this is not a typical meeting.  We’re in Tianjin, which is not in the capital, and so the Chinese themselves are doing some unprecedented things.  And we are getting information late, in some cases piecemeal, and we&#8217;re going to have to make adjustments.  So we&#8217;ll be in touch with all journalists who are thinking about heading out there to provide more information on how this is going to work. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But we&#8217;re in a little bit of uncharted territory because of COVID, and I think the Chinese side is struggling with the same kinds of things.  And so what we do know is that the meetings are going to take place on Monday, and it&#8217;ll likely be Xie Feng first and then Foreign Minister Wang Yi second.  But after that, we’re still gathering information on how this is going to work, especially the press arrangements, because again, this is a very – this is a very new thing.  Over.</span></p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">That concludes today&#8217;s briefing.  The embargo is now lifted.  Have a wonderful Saturday and thank you for joining.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hello, everyone.  We are here today to discuss the Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman’s travel to the People’s Republic of China or the PRC on July 25th through 26th, following her stops in Tokyo, Seoul, and Ulaanbaatar.  Today’s briefers are  and .  Today we will provide a brief preview of the deputy secretary’s planned discussions, which are part of ongoing U.S. efforts to hold candid exchanges with PRC officials to advance U.S. interests and values.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today’s call is on background and for your reporting purposes our briefers should be referred to as senior administration officials.  All contents of the call are embargoed until the conclusion of this call.  With that, I’ll hand it over to .</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, thanks very much, and thank you all for joining us.  The deputy secretary is going to be traveling to Tianjin tomorrow for discussions with the Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi and Vice Foreign Minister Xie Feng.  The deputy secretary’s travel to China follows a week of important engagements with allies and partners in Japan, we were in Seoul a little bit earlier, and right now we’re in Mongolia.  The deputy secretary used her meetings there to underscore the United States commitment to standing shoulder to shoulder with our allies and partners to address pressing global challenges, advance a free and open Indo-Pacific, and uphold and strengthen the rules-based international order.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’ve said we are prepared to engage Chinese officials when we believe those engagements will be substantive and constructive.  Those are the terms on which we agreed to this visit.  So Deputy Secretary Sherman’s meetings are a continuation of the discussions we had in Anchorage in March around setting the terms for the relationship and achieving a steady state of affairs between our countries.  We believe it’s important to maintain open lines of communication between high-level officials.  Frank and open discussion, even – perhaps especially – where we disagree, is critical to reducing the potential for misunderstandings between our countries, maintaining global peace and security, and making progress on important issues.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As Secretary Blinken has said, the U.S. relationship with China will be collaborative where it can be, competitive where it should be, and adversarial where it must be.  And we expect all dimensions of the relationship will be on the table for discussion during Wendy’s meetings.  You know as well as I do she’s a seasoned diplomat.  We’re going into these meetings with our eyes wide open.  The deputy secretary is going to represent the U.S. interests and values and those of our allies and partners.  We’re going to do it honestly and directly.  In Tianjin, she’s going to make clear while we welcome stiff and sustained competition with the PRC, everyone needs to play by the same rules and on the level – on a level playing field.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She’s going to underscore that we do not want that stiff and sustained competition to veer into conflict.  This is why the U.S. wants to ensure that there are guard rails and parameters in place to responsibly manage the relationship.  While I’m not going to preview Wendy’s full agenda, I think you can anticipate that she will take the opportunity to explain our concerns about many of Beijing&#8217;s actions, including those on which we’ve taken recent steps, both on our own and in – excuse me – coordination with our allies and partners. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And at the same time, there are important global challenges where the U.S. and China both have an interest and where we think it’s important to exchange views and explore potential areas for cooperation.  So we anticipate that this will also be a focus of these meetings. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before I turn it over to , I just want to say that I’m sure you’re all aware of the floods that have been going on this week in Hunan Province.  We’re very much aware of that as we head into Tianjin.  I would anticipate that the deputy secretary is going to express condolences to the Chinese for the loss of life and also concern for those who are missing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So with that, I’m going to turn it over to my colleague .</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, thanks, .  And thanks again, everybody, for joining us on a Saturday morning.  Your time, appreciate it very much.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let me just underscore a few points on why and how we are engaging Chinese officials in Tianjin.  As we said in advance of our conversations in Anchorage and as we’ve discussed consistently, we think it’s important for us to say directly to Chinese officials in private what we say in public.  It’s in our interests to be very clear to Beijing about where we stand and explain our concerns in detail.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The main purpose of this meeting is to have frank and honest exchanges about the relationship.  The goal isn’t to negotiate over specifics, but rather keep the channels of communication open at a senior level, and our philosophy is that we should not avoid hard topics just to be polite because that will only allow problems to fester.  As we’ve made clear in our actions and words, we believe it’s important to responsibly manage the relationship, as  said, even and especially when the relationship is challenging.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So let me also put this meeting into the context of the administration’s broader China policy effort.  Since President Biden took office, we’ve put a lot of focus on strengthening our own competitive hand vis-a-vis China through many actions that we’ve taken domestically, investing in ourselves at home.  We’ve also rallied our allies and partners, including to advance an affirmative vision of the rules-based international order.  And we’ve confronted China when they’ve acted against our interests and values while working to cooperate with China on areas like climate change and nonproliferation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We know we’re stronger when we work with our allies.  We know this makes us more effective when dealing with Beijing.  We aren’t seeking an anti-China coalition in our work with allies and partners, but rather trying to work together in a multilateral fashion to uphold the international rules-based order.  So when the deputy secretary sits down with her interlocutors, I anticipate very clearly that she will be not only representing the United States, but she will be standing up and advocating her positions that are shared around the world. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And across the three pillars of our approach to China policy – investing in ourselves at home, working with our allies and partners and through international institutions, and confronting China where we need to while cooperating where we can – we’re actively executing on our strategy to present that affirmative vision, demonstrate that democracies can and do best deliver results for our people and people around the world – a premise that President Biden is deeply invested in – and that we’re competing effectively with China.  With all of those actions underway, we’re entering this engagement from a position of strength and of solidarity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But this bilateral engagement is just one piece of the puzzle when it comes to our China policy.  We are doing many things at once.  We have a multifaceted approach to a multifaceted relationship.  We’re engaging at a senior level precisely because we are in a competitive relationship.  We want to maintain open dialogue so that we are able to – so that we are being responsible and not letting the competition veer into an unintended conflict.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even as we meet with our Chinese counterparts, we will also continue to hold China accountable.  These things are not mutually exclusive, and it should be clear that we are not afraid to impose costs for China’s behavior that undermines international norms.  We will do this simultaneously with our engagement.  For example, as you’ve all seen in just the last few weeks, we’ve taken actions on Beijing’s efforts to erode democracy in Hong Kong, human rights abuses in Xinjiang, its use of forced labor, and its malicious cyber activities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Historically, people, I think, have had a binary assumption that either we’re in a period of engagement with China or we’re in a period of confrontation – essentially, that the relationship goes up and down.  But that’s just not the case anymore.  This is a continuation of the steady state of affairs and it’s in that context that we see this meeting occurring.  So with that, I think we’re happy to take some questions.</span></p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Let’s go to the line of David Brunnstrom.</span></p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Mr. Brunnstrom, your line is open.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Thank you very much.  I wondered if you could give any comment on the sanctions China announced ahead of these talks and whether or not that’s helpful.  And can you also tell us whether the United States side will be warning China of the possibility of more sanctions, for instance, over Iran oil shipments or in response to the Microsoft hack, and whether that’s going to be any sort of leverage in the talks?</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Thanks, David.  Look, I would say a few things.  We’ve obviously seen China’s counter sanctions this week, which we think are just another instance of China targeting private citizens and others for actions that the U.S. Government is taking to uphold our interests and values.  Look, we remain fully committed to implementing all relevant U.S. sanctions authorities, and as we’ve said, to take actions that are consistent with our interests and values.  We think this kind of retaliation is really just an example of how Beijing punishes those who speak out and further illustrates China’s deteriorating climate and rising political risks on many different fronts.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the second part of your question, look, I think that trying to think about some of these things as leverage is certainly not how we’re thinking about this.  Again, we are acting in ways that are intended to protect our interests and values and those of our allies and partners.  We certainly will raise concerns where we have them about where we think Beijing may be acting inconsistently with UN Security Council resolutions or with other elements of international law.  I’m not going to get ahead of the secretary – of the deputy secretary’s points and agenda in terms of what she may raise, but I think that you certainly can anticipate that she will be raising concerns about where we believe Beijing is violating (inaudible).</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Yeah, so – right, I don’t think that the deputy secretary is going in thinking that those measures or those actions that the Chinese took are going to be leverage in these talks.  We are definitely going to be engaging with them, as we said, on substantive and constructive issues.  Thank you.</span></p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Let’s go to Demetri Sevastopulo.</span></p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Your line is open.  Go ahead.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Yeah, good morning.  Can you hear me?</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Yeah, we hear you.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Great, morning.  So my question is:  In the last six months, you’ve taken a range of actions towards China.  You’ve also done an awful lot with allies, particularly in Asia, also in Europe.  Can you point to a few examples of where you think U.S. policy towards China has actually caused China to do things differently over the last six months?</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  So I’m happy to point to a couple of things, Demetri, and thanks for the question.  I mean, number one is, as you rightly note, a huge part of our emphasis on our approach to China is working with allies and partners.  And I think there’s a few things I would note as context before getting to the second part of your question.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think a lot of our effort is really aimed at shaping the international environment around China, on building resilience among allies and partners to Beijing’s coercive and – and actions that are at odds with our collective interests and values and ensuring, as we said, that we can present an affirmative vision.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the things, though, I think that we’ve really seen is that these multilateral actions have really gotten Beijing’s attention, and in some cases I think has actually caused Beijing in many ways to take steps that actually are potentially counter to its own interests, where we saw Beijing impose its own counter sanctions on European officials, European parliamentarians after the multilateral actions imposed some Xinjiang sanctions back in March.  That certainly has given some pause to certain quarters in Europe about things like the comprehensive agreement on investment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think there’s other areas where we’ve also seen Beijing take some pretty assertive steps when we have acted in concert with allies and partners, and I think it’s a demonstration of the fact that those multilateral actions really get Beijing’s attention.  And so I think it is really that broad upholding of international norms and rules and principles as well as the shaping of the international environment around China that is really, again, having the potential I think in the long term to influence Beijing’s actions.  So I think that’s basically reflective of the approach that we’re taking and some of the ways I see that playing out.</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Yeah, and I think it’s really important to note here that it’s not just one action that we would be taking.  We’re talking about the accumulation of actions here showing China that this is – we’re redefining this relationship (inaudible) not going to be afraid to take steps when we see that our interests have to be defended.  And so I think that in the long run, you’re going to see a little bit more rather than pointing at a specific action in response to one of our actions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s really – what we’re showing is that we are going to continue doing this, that this – the relationship is stabilized in this manner, that we’re going to take consistent action when we have to.  And that’s going to result in modified behavior down the – in the future.</span></p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Let’s go to Francesco Fontemaggi.</span></p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Thank you, and before we open Mr. Fontemaggi’s line, if I may remind you, to ask a question, press 1 then 0 on your touchtone phone. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mr. Fontemaggi, your line is open.  Go ahead.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Hi, good morning.  Thank you.  As you said at the top to – you’ve said several times that you were prepared to engage when you believe these meetings would be substantive and constructive.  As David mentioned, there were these counter sanctions just in the past few days and a decision from China not to cooperate with the WHO inquiry on the COVID origins and several other actions by China.  What makes – what exactly makes you think that this is the right time to have constructive and substantive meetings?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And also, if I may, is this meeting from deputy secretary – is that to prepare any future meeting at the top level between the presidents?  Thank you.</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Yeah, I think this is not just about timing, ups and downs in the relationship like we defined it maybe in the past.  I think when we’re talking about timing here, we&#8217;re going to take advantage of opportunities if there are areas that are constructive.  I just mentioned a little bit earlier these very, very dangerous floods that are going on in Hunan.  I think that if you read what the Chinese are saying about these floods, it&#8217;s very apparent to them – they know that there are climate issues out there, there are these causes out there that they have to fix themselves if they&#8217;re going to – if they&#8217;re going to resolve some of these problems that affect all of their citizens, they&#8217;re going to have to join global movements.  And I think that there are opportunities for us to take advantage of what&#8217;s happening there where the Chinese people agree with the international community.  So I mean, that&#8217;s an example of how we can be constructive.</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thanks.  Yeah, I&#8217;ll just briefly – I think – I totally agree with .  I think I would just note, again, if we&#8217;re coming from the perspective that we are in stiff and sustained competition with China, that we need to establish ways to responsibly manage that competition and really manage the relationship for the long term.  And that requires an understanding that we can&#8217;t avoid talking when times are difficult, that we have to be able to engage at senior levels in order to have responsible management of the relationship.  And so I think that we&#8217;re not really seeing this from a framework of are we up, are we down, as I said.  I think that&#8217;s, as  noted, a sort of arcane way of understanding the relationship between the U.S. and China.  We just – we really believe that we&#8217;ve got to be able to have frank and open and honest conversations, even and particularly when we’re in difficult times.</span></p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">We&#8217;ll go to Colum Murphy.</span></p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your line is open.  Go ahead.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mr. Murphy, I&#8217;ve actually released you from the queue.  If you would press 1 then 0 again at this point, we&#8217;ll open your line. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mr. Murphy, your line is open.  Go ahead, please.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Great, thank you.  I just wanted to see if you could give some more guidance on the logistics of the events tomorrow and Monday.  Some of us are looking to go to Tianjin and we just want to see what is the timing of the different meetings, which – what&#8217;s the order.  Where will the delegation stay, for example?  Right now we have very little information.  I’m just wondering if you could elaborate a little bit more on the on-the-ground sort of proceedings over the next two days.  Thank you.</span></p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah, some of those logistics formatting questions or format questions are still being decided.  I think you can understand this is not a typical meeting.  We’re in Tianjin, which is not in the capital, and so the Chinese themselves are doing some unprecedented things.  And we are getting information late, in some cases piecemeal, and we&#8217;re going to have to make adjustments.  So we&#8217;ll be in touch with all journalists who are thinking about heading out there to provide more information on how this is going to work. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But we&#8217;re in a little bit of uncharted territory because of COVID, and I think the Chinese side is struggling with the same kinds of things.  And so what we do know is that the meetings are going to take place on Monday, and it&#8217;ll likely be Xie Feng first and then Foreign Minister Wang Yi second.  But after that, we’re still gathering information on how this is going to work, especially the press arrangements, because again, this is a very – this is a very new thing.  Over.</span></p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">That concludes today&#8217;s briefing.  The embargo is now lifted.  Have a wonderful Saturday and thank you for joining.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Acting Assistant Secretary of State Joey Hood Travels to Algeria, Morocco, and Kuwait</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/acting-assistant-secretary-of-state-joey-hood-travels-to-algeria-morocco-and-kuwait/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 12:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261838</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Acting Assistant Secretary of State for Near Eastern Affairs Joey Hood will visit Algeria, Morocco, and Kuwait, July 24-29.  Acting Assistant Secretary Hood will first be in Algeria where he will meet with Algerian leaders to discuss bilateral and regional issues, as well as announce an important cultural preservation project.  The Acting Assistant Secretary will then head to Morocco where he will meet with Moroccan government officials, local business leaders, and with civil society leaders.  He will also visit the American Legation Exhibit at the National Library of Rabat.  From there he will head to Kuwait where he will join the Secretary of State on his trip to the region.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For any questions, please contact </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEA-Press@state.gov</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and follow us on Twitter @StateDept_NEA.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Acting Assistant Secretary of State for Near Eastern Affairs Joey Hood will visit Algeria, Morocco, and Kuwait, July 24-29.  Acting Assistant Secretary Hood will first be in Algeria where he will meet with Algerian leaders to discuss bilateral and regional issues, as well as announce an important cultural preservation project.  The Acting Assistant Secretary will then head to Morocco where he will meet with Moroccan government officials, local business leaders, and with civil society leaders.  He will also visit the American Legation Exhibit at the National Library of Rabat.  From there he will head to Kuwait where he will join the Secretary of State on his trip to the region.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For any questions, please contact </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEA-Press@state.gov</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and follow us on Twitter @StateDept_NEA.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-Europe Communiqué on Afghanistan and Peace Efforts</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-europe-communique-on-afghanistan-and-peace-efforts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 20:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261726</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is the text of a communiqué issued by the United States of America, the European Union, France, Germany, Italy, NATO, Norway, and the United Kingdom.</p>
<p><em>Begin text. </em></p>
<p>The Special Representatives and Special Envoys of the United States of America, the European Union, France, Germany, Italy, NATO, Norway, and the United Kingdom met in Rome on 22 July 2021 to discuss the situation in Afghanistan and the developments in Afghanistan peace negotiations after the latest round of high-level talks in Doha on July 17-18, 2021.</p>
<p>We affirm that:</p>
<ol>
<li>Our countries and organizations are committed to a strong partnership with Afghanistan and will be closely monitoring ongoing developments in this new phase of transition with the withdrawal of international forces.</li>
<li>The people of Afghanistan have suffered for too long from conflict. We are deeply concerned about the high levels of violence, the Taliban’s military offensive, and the number of reported serious human rights abuses and violations alleged in communities most affected by the ongoing armed conflict across the country.</li>
<li>We call on all parties to reduce violence and protect civilians, respecting their obligations under international humanitarian law. We call on the Taliban to end their military offensive, and on both the Islamic Republic and the Taliban to engage meaningfully in the peace process. We reiterate the urgency of reaching a ceasefire to ensure the success of negotiations, and we acknowledge the sacrifices of the Afghan security forces.</li>
<li>We reaffirm that there is no military solution to the conflict in Afghanistan, we stand by UNSC resolution 2513 (2020), and we do not support any government in Afghanistan imposed through military force.</li>
<li>We express our full support to an inclusive Afghan-owned and Afghan-led peace process with full and meaningful participation of women that leads to a just and durable political settlement. We also highlight five elements of a final settlement that are most critical: (1) inclusive governance; (2) the right to elect political leaders; (3) protections for human rights, including rights of women, youth and minorities; (4) commitments on counter-terrorism, including to ensure that Afghanistan does not again serve as a safe haven for terrorists; and (5) adherence to international law, including international humanitarian law. We emphasize that international support to any future government will depend, at least in part, on adherence to these five elements.</li>
<li>We intend to maintain our support for Afghan institutions, including defense and security forces, to address the country’s urgent needs. We also reiterate that future assistance to Afghanistan is dependent on good governance and a commitment to the rule of law and human rights, including preservation of the gains made by women and girls over the past two decades, as well as the government taking meaningful steps to tackle corruption and to meeting commitments made at the November 2020 Geneva Conference.</li>
<li>We took due note of yesterday’s briefings by the representatives of the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan and the Taliban and welcome the talks held in Doha on July 17 and 18 between senior leaders of the two sides. We further welcome the declared commitment of the two sides to accelerate negotiations toward an inclusive political settlement and to meet again in the near future. We believe future meetings should focus on core issues that will be fundamental to reaching an inclusive political settlement.</li>
<li>We acknowledge that reaching a final political settlement, including on the Constitution, will likely take time. We urge the two sides to agree on a permanent and comprehensive ceasefire and on foundational principles for the future Afghan State and details of transitional governing arrangements until a final political settlement is reached. We emphasize that any transitional governing arrangements must be inclusive, respect the rights of all Afghans in line with Afghanistan’s international commitments and also uphold counter-terrorism commitments.</li>
<li>We welcome in particular the commitments made by the Taliban yesterday to inclusive governance, respecting human rights including the rights of women and minorities, to abide by international law, including international humanitarian law, and to upholding counter terrorism commitments. We also welcome their openness to negotiate a mechanism for representative government with the Islamic Republic negotiation team.</li>
<li>We call on the two parties to negotiate in good faith in order to reach a just and durable political settlement. To promote progress in the negotiations, we support any third-party facilitation or mediation welcomed by the two sides.</li>
<li>We seize this opportunity to reiterate appreciation to Qatar as host of the negotiations, and we commend it for bringing the parties together and for its overall contribution to the process. We also commend the United Nations for the essential and expanded role it is playing in support of the process.</li>
<li>We reiterate that the Taliban and the Islamic Republic must deliver on their commitments (1) to prevent the use of Afghan soil by al Qaeda, Da’esh or other terrorist groups from launching attacks against, or threatening the security of, any other country; and (2) not to host members of these groups nor to allow them to recruit, train, fundraise or transit through Afghanistan.</li>
<li>We urge the Taliban to reduce violence, uphold their commitments to protect Afghanistan’s infrastructure, protect civilians and cooperate on humanitarian assistance, particularly as the Afghan people suffer acutely from the effects of COVID-19 and drought, in addition to violence. We call on the Taliban to allow and facilitate, without preconditions and consistent with international humanitarian law, access for delivery of humanitarian aid, to areas under their control.</li>
<li>We believe that Afghanistan can contribute to regional and international stability and connectivity. We encourage Afghanistan’s neighbors to intensify their support to the Afghan people and to contribute to a lasting peace settlement and economic development in the interests of all.</li>
<li>We also call upon all parties to ensure the safety of foreign embassies and other diplomatic missions, multilateral agencies, media representatives, airports and non-governmental organizations and their Afghan and international staff. We particularly appreciate Turkey’s readiness and commitment to assist with airport security as needed.</li>
<li>We express our appreciation to Italy for organizing these consultations and agreed to set the date and venue of the next meeting through diplomatic channels.</li>
</ol>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is the text of a communiqué issued by the United States of America, the European Union, France, Germany, Italy, NATO, Norway, and the United Kingdom.</p>
<p><em>Begin text. </em></p>
<p>The Special Representatives and Special Envoys of the United States of America, the European Union, France, Germany, Italy, NATO, Norway, and the United Kingdom met in Rome on 22 July 2021 to discuss the situation in Afghanistan and the developments in Afghanistan peace negotiations after the latest round of high-level talks in Doha on July 17-18, 2021.</p>
<p>We affirm that:</p>
<ol>
<li>Our countries and organizations are committed to a strong partnership with Afghanistan and will be closely monitoring ongoing developments in this new phase of transition with the withdrawal of international forces.</li>
<li>The people of Afghanistan have suffered for too long from conflict. We are deeply concerned about the high levels of violence, the Taliban’s military offensive, and the number of reported serious human rights abuses and violations alleged in communities most affected by the ongoing armed conflict across the country.</li>
<li>We call on all parties to reduce violence and protect civilians, respecting their obligations under international humanitarian law. We call on the Taliban to end their military offensive, and on both the Islamic Republic and the Taliban to engage meaningfully in the peace process. We reiterate the urgency of reaching a ceasefire to ensure the success of negotiations, and we acknowledge the sacrifices of the Afghan security forces.</li>
<li>We reaffirm that there is no military solution to the conflict in Afghanistan, we stand by UNSC resolution 2513 (2020), and we do not support any government in Afghanistan imposed through military force.</li>
<li>We express our full support to an inclusive Afghan-owned and Afghan-led peace process with full and meaningful participation of women that leads to a just and durable political settlement. We also highlight five elements of a final settlement that are most critical: (1) inclusive governance; (2) the right to elect political leaders; (3) protections for human rights, including rights of women, youth and minorities; (4) commitments on counter-terrorism, including to ensure that Afghanistan does not again serve as a safe haven for terrorists; and (5) adherence to international law, including international humanitarian law. We emphasize that international support to any future government will depend, at least in part, on adherence to these five elements.</li>
<li>We intend to maintain our support for Afghan institutions, including defense and security forces, to address the country’s urgent needs. We also reiterate that future assistance to Afghanistan is dependent on good governance and a commitment to the rule of law and human rights, including preservation of the gains made by women and girls over the past two decades, as well as the government taking meaningful steps to tackle corruption and to meeting commitments made at the November 2020 Geneva Conference.</li>
<li>We took due note of yesterday’s briefings by the representatives of the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan and the Taliban and welcome the talks held in Doha on July 17 and 18 between senior leaders of the two sides. We further welcome the declared commitment of the two sides to accelerate negotiations toward an inclusive political settlement and to meet again in the near future. We believe future meetings should focus on core issues that will be fundamental to reaching an inclusive political settlement.</li>
<li>We acknowledge that reaching a final political settlement, including on the Constitution, will likely take time. We urge the two sides to agree on a permanent and comprehensive ceasefire and on foundational principles for the future Afghan State and details of transitional governing arrangements until a final political settlement is reached. We emphasize that any transitional governing arrangements must be inclusive, respect the rights of all Afghans in line with Afghanistan’s international commitments and also uphold counter-terrorism commitments.</li>
<li>We welcome in particular the commitments made by the Taliban yesterday to inclusive governance, respecting human rights including the rights of women and minorities, to abide by international law, including international humanitarian law, and to upholding counter terrorism commitments. We also welcome their openness to negotiate a mechanism for representative government with the Islamic Republic negotiation team.</li>
<li>We call on the two parties to negotiate in good faith in order to reach a just and durable political settlement. To promote progress in the negotiations, we support any third-party facilitation or mediation welcomed by the two sides.</li>
<li>We seize this opportunity to reiterate appreciation to Qatar as host of the negotiations, and we commend it for bringing the parties together and for its overall contribution to the process. We also commend the United Nations for the essential and expanded role it is playing in support of the process.</li>
<li>We reiterate that the Taliban and the Islamic Republic must deliver on their commitments (1) to prevent the use of Afghan soil by al Qaeda, Da’esh or other terrorist groups from launching attacks against, or threatening the security of, any other country; and (2) not to host members of these groups nor to allow them to recruit, train, fundraise or transit through Afghanistan.</li>
<li>We urge the Taliban to reduce violence, uphold their commitments to protect Afghanistan’s infrastructure, protect civilians and cooperate on humanitarian assistance, particularly as the Afghan people suffer acutely from the effects of COVID-19 and drought, in addition to violence. We call on the Taliban to allow and facilitate, without preconditions and consistent with international humanitarian law, access for delivery of humanitarian aid, to areas under their control.</li>
<li>We believe that Afghanistan can contribute to regional and international stability and connectivity. We encourage Afghanistan’s neighbors to intensify their support to the Afghan people and to contribute to a lasting peace settlement and economic development in the interests of all.</li>
<li>We also call upon all parties to ensure the safety of foreign embassies and other diplomatic missions, multilateral agencies, media representatives, airports and non-governmental organizations and their Afghan and international staff. We particularly appreciate Turkey’s readiness and commitment to assist with airport security as needed.</li>
<li>We express our appreciation to Italy for organizing these consultations and agreed to set the date and venue of the next meeting through diplomatic channels.</li>
</ol>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Announces Humanitarian Assistance for Iraq</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-announces-humanitarian-assistance-for-iraq/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 19:44:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261691</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is pleased to announce nearly $155 million in additional humanitarian assistance for the people of Iraq as well as Iraqi refugees in the region and generous communities hosting them. With this additional funding from the State Department and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), U.S. humanitarian support for Iraq amounts to more than $200 million to-date in Fiscal Year (FY) 2021. Since FY 2014, the United States has provided more than $3 billion in humanitarian assistance in Iraq and for Iraqis in the region.</p>
<p>This funding will provide critical shelter, essential healthcare, emergency food assistance, protection services such as gender-based violence response, and water, sanitation, and hygiene services throughout Iraq. U.S. funded programs will support Iraqis displaced by ISIS, many of whom also continue to face hardships from the COVID-19 pandemic by promoting access to civil documentation and legal services, improving the capacity of health care facilities, and increasing access to education and livelihood opportunities.</p>
<p>The United States remains the largest single donor of humanitarian assistance in Iraq and globally. We appreciate all donors who have stepped up and continue to encourage both existing and new donors to increase their support to help meet the needs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is pleased to announce nearly $155 million in additional humanitarian assistance for the people of Iraq as well as Iraqi refugees in the region and generous communities hosting them. With this additional funding from the State Department and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), U.S. humanitarian support for Iraq amounts to more than $200 million to-date in Fiscal Year (FY) 2021. Since FY 2014, the United States has provided more than $3 billion in humanitarian assistance in Iraq and for Iraqis in the region.</p>
<p>This funding will provide critical shelter, essential healthcare, emergency food assistance, protection services such as gender-based violence response, and water, sanitation, and hygiene services throughout Iraq. U.S. funded programs will support Iraqis displaced by ISIS, many of whom also continue to face hardships from the COVID-19 pandemic by promoting access to civil documentation and legal services, improving the capacity of health care facilities, and increasing access to education and livelihood opportunities.</p>
<p>The United States remains the largest single donor of humanitarian assistance in Iraq and globally. We appreciate all donors who have stepped up and continue to encourage both existing and new donors to increase their support to help meet the needs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken&#8217;s Meeting with Foreign Minister Hussein</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-foreign-minister-hussein/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 18:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Iraqi Foreign Minister Dr. Fuad Hussein today on the margins of the U.S.-Iraq Strategic Dialogue in Washington, D.C. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Hussein reviewed the Strategic Dialogue and reaffirmed the principles agreed upon by the two sides in the Strategic Framework Agreement (SFA). The Secretary encouraged the Government of Iraq to continue efforts to address the Iraqi people’s demands for equity and justice and expressed his support for Iraq’s anti-corruption and economic reform efforts, as well as for elections later this year. The Secretary reiterated that the United States remains committed to assisting the Government of Iraq to achieve a secure, stable, and prosperous future.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Iraqi Foreign Minister Dr. Fuad Hussein today on the margins of the U.S.-Iraq Strategic Dialogue in Washington, D.C. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Hussein reviewed the Strategic Dialogue and reaffirmed the principles agreed upon by the two sides in the Strategic Framework Agreement (SFA). The Secretary encouraged the Government of Iraq to continue efforts to address the Iraqi people’s demands for equity and justice and expressed his support for Iraq’s anti-corruption and economic reform efforts, as well as for elections later this year. The Secretary reiterated that the United States remains committed to assisting the Government of Iraq to achieve a secure, stable, and prosperous future.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman to Lead U.S. Delegation in Strategic Stability Dialogue with Russian Federation</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-sherman-to-lead-u-s-delegation-in-strategic-stability-dialogue-with-russian-federation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 18:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman will travel to Geneva, Switzerland to lead the U.S. delegation’s participation in a U.S.-Russia bilateral Strategic Stability Dialogue on July 28, 2021. She will be joined by Under Secretary of State for Arms Control and International Security Bonnie Jenkins, who will provide additional leadership for the delegation. This meeting follows up on a commitment made between President Biden and Russian President Putin to have a deliberate and robust dialogue between our two nations that will seek to lay the groundwork for future arms control and risk reduction measures.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman will travel to Geneva, Switzerland to lead the U.S. delegation’s participation in a U.S.-Russia bilateral Strategic Stability Dialogue on July 28, 2021. She will be joined by Under Secretary of State for Arms Control and International Security Bonnie Jenkins, who will provide additional leadership for the delegation. This meeting follows up on a commitment made between President Biden and Russian President Putin to have a deliberate and robust dialogue between our two nations that will seek to lay the groundwork for future arms control and risk reduction measures.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony Blinken to Highlight Value of International Education at the Department’s 12th Annual EducationUSA Forum</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-blinken-to-highlight-value-of-international-education-at-the-departments-12th-annual-educationusa-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 18:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261665</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony Blinken will highlight the value of international education to U.S. diplomacy, national security, economic prosperity, and U.S. leadership in research and innovation via pre-recorded video remarks at the 12th annual EducationUSA Forum on Monday, July 26, at 10 a.m. U.S. Secretary of Education Dr. Miguel Cardona will also address the Forum to highlight the Department of Education’s commitment to a renewed focus on the benefits of international education at home and abroad.</p>
<p>International students, numbering over a million for the fifth consecutive year in 2019-2020, contributed over $39 billion to the U.S. economy in 2020, and supported an estimated 415,000 U.S. jobs. With more than 4,000 U.S. colleges and universities, the United States offers international students world-class academic opportunities. In turn, international students enrich American classrooms and communities with diverse perspectives and develop ties with their American peers. These ties form the basis of continued American success in business and trade, science and innovation, and governmental relations.</p>
<p>Held virtually from July 26-30, the 2021 EducationUSA Forum will convene more than 2,000 international education professionals from accredited U.S. colleges and universities to explore best practices and strategies for maintaining and growing the United States as the top study destination for international students from around the globe. The 2021 EducationUSA Forum will feature over 30 virtual conference sessions on issues such as global student mobility trends, student recruitment strategies, best practices in diversifying the international student pipeline, and practical updates for virtual programming during COVID-19. At the Forum, the first in a new series of global marketing assets promoting study in the United States will be also be released.</p>
<p>EducationUSA is the U.S. Department of State’s global network of international student advising centers operating in more than 175 countries and territories to highlight U.S. higher education opportunities to students around the world. The network supports the Department’s mission to promote U.S. higher education and exchanges to international students to create and sustain mutual understanding with other countries, which is necessary in advancing U.S. foreign policy goals.</p>
<p>Members of the press can register for the event <a class="external-link" href="https://educationusaforum2021.vfairs.com/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">here</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> to watch the video as it is broadcast at the forum. The video and other releases throughout the event will also be posted on <a href="http://educationusa.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://educationusa.state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1627149136241000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGnOsx3TcEwjGtIfHXcgG9lfI5F6Q">educationusa.state.gov</a>. Please contact <a href="mailto:ECA-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ECA-Press@state.gov</a> with questions. Follow the conversation on Twitter using #EdUSAForum. Visit this <a href="https://educationusa.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MjMuNDM2MjE1MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2VkdWNhdGlvbnVzYS5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvIn0.ah4TE9A-yHEeNoVhK9oCbxpN_x7W3udcm62E6A5FCHM/s/1039202793/br/109824997536-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1627149136241000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEjueK9plV2RWiPOJWSvite7g8zeg">website</a> to learn more about EducationUSA and the 2021 EducationUSA Forum.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony Blinken will highlight the value of international education to U.S. diplomacy, national security, economic prosperity, and U.S. leadership in research and innovation via pre-recorded video remarks at the 12th annual EducationUSA Forum on Monday, July 26, at 10 a.m. U.S. Secretary of Education Dr. Miguel Cardona will also address the Forum to highlight the Department of Education’s commitment to a renewed focus on the benefits of international education at home and abroad.</p>
<p>International students, numbering over a million for the fifth consecutive year in 2019-2020, contributed over $39 billion to the U.S. economy in 2020, and supported an estimated 415,000 U.S. jobs. With more than 4,000 U.S. colleges and universities, the United States offers international students world-class academic opportunities. In turn, international students enrich American classrooms and communities with diverse perspectives and develop ties with their American peers. These ties form the basis of continued American success in business and trade, science and innovation, and governmental relations.</p>
<p>Held virtually from July 26-30, the 2021 EducationUSA Forum will convene more than 2,000 international education professionals from accredited U.S. colleges and universities to explore best practices and strategies for maintaining and growing the United States as the top study destination for international students from around the globe. The 2021 EducationUSA Forum will feature over 30 virtual conference sessions on issues such as global student mobility trends, student recruitment strategies, best practices in diversifying the international student pipeline, and practical updates for virtual programming during COVID-19. At the Forum, the first in a new series of global marketing assets promoting study in the United States will be also be released.</p>
<p>EducationUSA is the U.S. Department of State’s global network of international student advising centers operating in more than 175 countries and territories to highlight U.S. higher education opportunities to students around the world. The network supports the Department’s mission to promote U.S. higher education and exchanges to international students to create and sustain mutual understanding with other countries, which is necessary in advancing U.S. foreign policy goals.</p>
<p>Members of the press can register for the event <a class="external-link" href="https://educationusaforum2021.vfairs.com/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">here</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> to watch the video as it is broadcast at the forum. The video and other releases throughout the event will also be posted on <a href="http://educationusa.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://educationusa.state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1627149136241000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGnOsx3TcEwjGtIfHXcgG9lfI5F6Q">educationusa.state.gov</a>. Please contact <a href="mailto:ECA-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ECA-Press@state.gov</a> with questions. Follow the conversation on Twitter using #EdUSAForum. Visit this <a href="https://educationusa.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MjMuNDM2MjE1MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2VkdWNhdGlvbnVzYS5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvIn0.ah4TE9A-yHEeNoVhK9oCbxpN_x7W3udcm62E6A5FCHM/s/1039202793/br/109824997536-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1627149136241000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEjueK9plV2RWiPOJWSvite7g8zeg">website</a> to learn more about EducationUSA and the 2021 EducationUSA Forum.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Iraqi Foreign Minister Dr. Fuad Hussein Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-iraqi-foreign-minister-dr-fuad-hussein-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 16:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261632</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good morning, everyone.  It’s a particular pleasure to have Foreign Minister Hussein, my friend of many years, colleague of many years here at the State Department, with his delegation for the Strategic Dialogue with the United States and Iraq.</p>
<p>We are, of course, the closest of partners in the fight against ISIS, and we can take tremendous pride in the work we’ve done together to defeat ISIS and to make sure that it stays defeated.  But I think what today is demonstrating is that the partnership between the United States and Iraq is much broader and deeper than even the common fight against ISIS.</p>
<p>The United States is proud to be partnered with Iraq in meeting some of the most important challenges of our time, whether it’s the fight against the COVID-19 pandemic, dealing with climate change and making investments in renewable energy.  Whether it is as the leading provider of humanitarian assistance to Iraq, and building opportunity for Iraqis, this partnership has tremendous breadth as well as tremendous depth.</p>
<p>And, of course, the United States is proud to be leading international efforts to support Iraq’s elections in October, free and fair elections, so that the Iraqi people can have their voices heard and choose their leaders.</p>
<p>Most of all, we are proceeding together in partnership based on mutual respect and mutual interests, and the work we’re doing today is going to carry that forward.</p>
<p>So, Fuad, welcome.  It’s wonderful to have you here.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HUSSEIN:</strong>  Thank you very much.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) Thank you very much.  Thank you very much, my dear friend Tony, Tony Blinken, Secretary of State.  In fact, this relationship, this partnership goes back a long way to the joint work against ISIS, and building the political (inaudible) and – for Iraq.</p>
<p>Our presence here in Washington is to conduct the dialogue and the discussions with the United States under the leadership of the U.S. delegation under the honorable Secretary of State Tony Blinken, and I thank him for this invitation, and we hope that the outcome of this dialogue is to serve the interests of the two countries and the two people.</p>
<p>And the foundations of this dialogue are the basic principles that were mentioned: joint operation, mutual respect, and cooperation in various fields – military and security, economic, trade, also energy and all its different fields like clean energy, gas, fuel, electricity, as well as the health field and countering the pandemic – COVID-19 pandemic, and the work and cooperation on the field of education.</p>
<p>And with the efforts and operation of the Iraqi forces, of all its branches, the support of the Iraqi people and the cooperation of the international coalition, we were able to defeat the so-called Islamic State – that is, ISIS – and to eradicate it from its presence in Iraq.</p>
<p>However, ISIS the terrorist organization remains as a terrorist organization and as a military organization that depends on particular ideology.</p>
<p>There’s still terrorist activities for ISIS in Iraq.  A few days ago, there was a suicide operation in Sadr City that resulted in the martyrdom of tens of – number of the citizens as well as a larger number of injuries amongst the citizens.  So, these ISIS activities continue, are still present, and they represent a danger to the Iraqi society, to the regional society, and to the international society.</p>
<p>And because the terrorist organization ISIS is a local and active organization inside Iraq, but also a regional and international organization that depends on an international ideology, that requires international work and international cooperation.</p>
<p>And so, we need the cooperation with the international coalition and to work with the international coalition, under the leadership of the United States against ISIS, and to exchange information with the international coalition, the United States, and with Iraq to defeat Daesh.</p>
<p>Our relationships with the United States are not just military relationships, but they are vast and broad relationships. And in the future, we will have a much broader cooperation in all the fields that were mentioned, the strategic dialogues that depend and relies on pushing forward these efforts to improve the lives of people and to improve the future of Iraq.  And we thank the United States for helping and supporting Iraq in the Security Council to get a unanimous position to support Iraq, and send monitors to monitor the electoral efforts, which are very important for the future of Iraq, and future of the people of Iraq, and democracy in Iraq.</p>
<p>At the end, again, I reiterate my thanks to my dear friend and colleague, Secretary Tony Blinken, for receiving us.  And we anticipate to have deep discussions that will bring us to fruitful results for the good interest of the two countries.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HUSSEIN:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong><em>Shukran.</em>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HUSSEIN:  </strong><em>Shukran.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110010000" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good morning, everyone.  It’s a particular pleasure to have Foreign Minister Hussein, my friend of many years, colleague of many years here at the State Department, with his delegation for the Strategic Dialogue with the United States and Iraq.</p>
<p>We are, of course, the closest of partners in the fight against ISIS, and we can take tremendous pride in the work we’ve done together to defeat ISIS and to make sure that it stays defeated.  But I think what today is demonstrating is that the partnership between the United States and Iraq is much broader and deeper than even the common fight against ISIS.</p>
<p>The United States is proud to be partnered with Iraq in meeting some of the most important challenges of our time, whether it’s the fight against the COVID-19 pandemic, dealing with climate change and making investments in renewable energy.  Whether it is as the leading provider of humanitarian assistance to Iraq, and building opportunity for Iraqis, this partnership has tremendous breadth as well as tremendous depth.</p>
<p>And, of course, the United States is proud to be leading international efforts to support Iraq’s elections in October, free and fair elections, so that the Iraqi people can have their voices heard and choose their leaders.</p>
<p>Most of all, we are proceeding together in partnership based on mutual respect and mutual interests, and the work we’re doing today is going to carry that forward.</p>
<p>So, Fuad, welcome.  It’s wonderful to have you here.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HUSSEIN:</strong>  Thank you very much.</p>
<p>(Via interpreter) Thank you very much.  Thank you very much, my dear friend Tony, Tony Blinken, Secretary of State.  In fact, this relationship, this partnership goes back a long way to the joint work against ISIS, and building the political (inaudible) and – for Iraq.</p>
<p>Our presence here in Washington is to conduct the dialogue and the discussions with the United States under the leadership of the U.S. delegation under the honorable Secretary of State Tony Blinken, and I thank him for this invitation, and we hope that the outcome of this dialogue is to serve the interests of the two countries and the two people.</p>
<p>And the foundations of this dialogue are the basic principles that were mentioned: joint operation, mutual respect, and cooperation in various fields – military and security, economic, trade, also energy and all its different fields like clean energy, gas, fuel, electricity, as well as the health field and countering the pandemic – COVID-19 pandemic, and the work and cooperation on the field of education.</p>
<p>And with the efforts and operation of the Iraqi forces, of all its branches, the support of the Iraqi people and the cooperation of the international coalition, we were able to defeat the so-called Islamic State – that is, ISIS – and to eradicate it from its presence in Iraq.</p>
<p>However, ISIS the terrorist organization remains as a terrorist organization and as a military organization that depends on particular ideology.</p>
<p>There’s still terrorist activities for ISIS in Iraq.  A few days ago, there was a suicide operation in Sadr City that resulted in the martyrdom of tens of – number of the citizens as well as a larger number of injuries amongst the citizens.  So, these ISIS activities continue, are still present, and they represent a danger to the Iraqi society, to the regional society, and to the international society.</p>
<p>And because the terrorist organization ISIS is a local and active organization inside Iraq, but also a regional and international organization that depends on an international ideology, that requires international work and international cooperation.</p>
<p>And so, we need the cooperation with the international coalition and to work with the international coalition, under the leadership of the United States against ISIS, and to exchange information with the international coalition, the United States, and with Iraq to defeat Daesh.</p>
<p>Our relationships with the United States are not just military relationships, but they are vast and broad relationships. And in the future, we will have a much broader cooperation in all the fields that were mentioned, the strategic dialogues that depend and relies on pushing forward these efforts to improve the lives of people and to improve the future of Iraq.  And we thank the United States for helping and supporting Iraq in the Security Council to get a unanimous position to support Iraq, and send monitors to monitor the electoral efforts, which are very important for the future of Iraq, and future of the people of Iraq, and democracy in Iraq.</p>
<p>At the end, again, I reiterate my thanks to my dear friend and colleague, Secretary Tony Blinken, for receiving us.  And we anticipate to have deep discussions that will bring us to fruitful results for the good interest of the two countries.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HUSSEIN:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong><em>Shukran.</em>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER HUSSEIN:  </strong><em>Shukran.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110010000" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Mika Brzezinski and Willie Geist of MSNBC’s Morning Joe</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-mika-brzezinski-and-willie-geist-of-msnbcs-morning-joe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 15:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261601</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> As COVID-19 cases rise once again in America, health officials say the Delta variant is now the most dominant strain not only in the U.S., but across the world. This setback comes just weeks after the Biden administration pledged to lead the way in global vaccination efforts. Will the virus’s re-emergence at home slow down efforts to vaccinate the rest of the world?</p>
<p>Joining us now, U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken, and Tony, it’s great to have you back on the show and to speak with you. And I guess we’ll start right there. As we – as it pertains to the coronavirus, how will the United States collaborate on the world stage, lead on the world stage, when you have a rejection of the vaccine here at home that is creating a pandemic among the unvaccinated?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Mika, first, it’s great to see you and great to be with you too. Look, we are leading on both fronts – at home and around the world. And we have to do both because as long as this virus is out there anywhere replicating, we’re going to see more variants, and those variants are going to come back and bite us, as we’re already experiencing with Delta. And so as we’re pursuing every effort to get every American vaccinated, we’re also very much engaged in the world at the President’s direction.</p>
<p>And as you know, we had vaccines in our stockpile, 80 million that we’re making available to countries around the world. We started doing that about a month ago. Of the 80 million, 60 million have been distributed. And the President announced when he was in Europe at the G7 that the United States was going to purchase 500 million, a half a billion vaccines to distribute around the world – no strings attached – to countries around the world to make sure that we can do everything we can to win this race against variants.</p>
<p>The other thing that’s happening is because of our leadership, other countries are stepping up. The G7 countries, our European partners, Japan are also committing additional vaccines. And production is increasing. What we have to do is get to a place where we’re getting as many vaccines as we possibly can to as many countries, as many people as fast as we can. If we do that, we can get ahead of the variants and win the race.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> So I understand you’re announcing a trip where you will take this show on the road and this message on the road. I’d like to hear more about that and I’d like to push you a little bit on the pandemic among the unvaccinated here at home, which really appears to be based on disinformation. We’re hearing even Republican governors like Kay Ivey just fed up with the disinformation and with the choice of people to not vaccinate themselves, to not protect themselves from a virus that could kill them. Meanwhile, there is many countries around the world just hoping to get their hands on the vaccine.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, Mika, that’s right, and look, we know it. The numbers are very, very clear. Of the people hospitalized now or people dying from COVID-19 in the United States, 97, 98, 99 percent are unvaccinated. It’s as clear and stark as that. That’s the reality. And hopefully, as more and more people speak out about this, people will listen and take action. And this is not a partisan issue. It’s an American issue. We’re all in this together, and I hope everyone will do what is necessary to protect ourselves against COVID-19.</p>
<p>And yes, I’m going to India this week. This is such a critical country in the fight against COVID-19. The Indians stood up for us in the early days when we were having great challenges, helping to provide PPE, for example. We’ve now stood up for them as they have encountered wave after wave of COVID-19, including providing more than a quarter of a billion dollars of assistance to them. We have millions of vaccines ready to go to them when they finish their own legal process to bring them in. And India is the leading country when it comes to the production of vaccines.</p>
<p>Of course, they’re focused understandably on their own internal challenges now, but when that production engine gets fully going and can distribute again to the rest of the world, that’s going to make a big difference, too. So I’ll be talking to our Indian friends about that next week.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Will you be addressing in the weeks and months to come the disinformation from U.S. tech companies, perhaps even happening abroad, where companies like Facebook and others have so much information that is just flat wrong about COVID and is leading to deadly decisions on the part of people around the world?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Look, Mika, all we can do is ask everyone to step up to their responsibilities, to try to get accurate information out there to people who need it, whether that’s here at home or whether that’s around the world. And ultimately, because this is a global challenge, because no one is safe until everyone is safe, countries or groups that may engage in misinformation or disinformation are doing themselves ultimately a huge disservice.</p>
<p>And so what we can do, what we have to do, what we are doing, is making sure, one, that the right information gets out there, and two, the resources get out there, the vaccines get out there, the production’s out there. One of the other things we’re doing is investing now in production in different parts of the world – for example, in Africa. We need to make sure that we’re doing that both to get ahead of COVID-19, this pandemic, but also to set ourselves up for the next time. Because unfortunately, there will be a next time. But we have to make sure that we’re in a much better place around the world to prevent it, to see it, to mitigate it more effectively than we’re able to do this time.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> I want to move on to Cuba, which has seen protests over the past few weeks. And yesterday the White House announced new sanctions against Cuba’s defense minister and special forces brigade for the suppression of peaceful protests. What are those sanctions, and what happens if there is not the result the United States would like to see in reaction, in response to those sanctions?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, Mika, I think what we saw just a little over a week ago is quite extraordinary. Thousands of people, tens of thousands of people taking to the streets across Cuba – not just in Havana but in dozens of cities and towns across Cuba – to say they’re fed up – fed up with the repression, fed up with the lack of freedom, fed up with the fact that they don’t have food and medicines, that they have a government that is not providing for them, and making their voices heard. And I think it’s evidence of a government that – and a regime that certainly lacks confidence in itself when it has to try to stifle the voices of its own people.</p>
<p>The smartest thing the regime in Cuba can do is to listen to its own people instead of repress them. But unfortunately, they are – they continue to repress them, they took violent action against those who were speaking up. We went ahead and sanctioned the leaders of the military, the leaders of something called the Black Berets. They were on the front lines of taking violent action against people speaking out for their freedom, speaking out for their needs. We’ll continue to do that.</p>
<p>And also it’s very important that the Cuban people have an ability to communicate, and one of the things we’re very focused on now, working with the private sector, working with others, is doing everything we can to make sure that they have internet access so they can speak to one another, so they can have contact and communication with folks off the island. That is a very active effort.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> And is the regime responding, showing any signs of improvement, of responding to what the United States is requiring for the sanctions to either be pulled back or for more sanctions not to come their way?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> No. We haven’t seen that kind of response. The regime tends to double down in these situations. But again, this is not about us. This is about the Cuban people. And I think one of the big mistakes the regime makes is to try to point the finger at the United States, saying we’re responsible for these protests. We’re not. These are the Cuban people. They are speaking up. They are standing – they’re speaking out. They’re standing up. And a regime that doesn’t understand that and that has – lacks the confidence to allow the voices of its own people to be heard I think is making a very, very big mistake.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Let’s jump to Russia and the issue of cyberwarfare, which I think also then ends us up in China. (Laughter.) What is the United States prepared to do to make sure this doesn’t happen again? What’s next, when the next attack happens, to kind of send a message to Vladimir Putin that there’s a new sheriff in town?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, I think that message has been sent and, as necessary, will be sent again. The – President Biden addressed this directly with President Putin, both at the meeting in Geneva that I took part in as well as more recently on the phone. And one of the things that we’re seeing, as you know, is an increased use of so-called ransomware. And this is tremendously destructive. Overall, one-in-four Americans has been a victim of a cyber crime. About $40 billion lost on an annual basis. And ransomware in particular is increasingly dangerous. And what we’ve made clear to Russia, but to other countries around the world, is if you’re harboring individuals or organizations engaged in cyber crime, engaged in ransomware, that is unacceptable. And if you will not take action against them, we will.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Secretary Blinken, it’s Willie Geist. Good to see you this morning.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Hey, Willie.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> I want to ask you about Afghanistan. The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs, General Milley, said the other day that the Taliban has strategic momentum, that it may well over-run the country, though he didn’t concede that point just yet. So as the troops come home from Afghanistan, how should Americans be thinking about the mission there from our point of view? If it does become a training ground for terrorists again, if there does – some threat is posed to the United States, what will be the American reaction there?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b>Well, Willie, we’re determined that it not become a training ground for terrorism directed against the United States or our allies and partners. That’s exactly why we went there in the first place, which is important to remember. We were attacked on 9/11, we went to Afghanistan to get the folks who attacked us, to bring them to justice. Osama bin Laden was brought to justice 10 years ago, and the group, al-Qaida, responsible for those attacks has been dramatically diminished in terms of its capacity to attack anyone from Afghanistan. We’re going to make sure that we keep our eyes on that. If we see the threat re-emerging, we’re going to be in a position to take action against it. But that’s why we were there, and now we’re 20 years and a trillion dollars and thousands of Americans lost later in this – in that campaign. I think the reason we went there is what we have to keep the focus on, and we’ve largely succeeded in doing what we needed to do.</p>
<p>We do have deep concerns about the actions the Taliban is taking indicating that it may be trying to take the country by force, but were that to happen, Afghanistan would be a pariah state. It would not get the assistance that it’s looking for and that the Taliban says it wants if it has any responsibility for the country. It would not get the support from the international community that it says it wants. We’re actively engaged in diplomacy because there is no military solution to this conflict that’s been going on for more than 40 years in Afghanistan, and we’re working to try to bring that to an end.</p>
<p>But one other thing: We’re sustaining our support through our embassy, through other embassies for the Afghan people, and at the same time we’re working to make good on our commitment to those who helped us and put their lives on the line – interpreters, translators – they’re benefiting from a program called Special Immigrant Visa programs that allow them to seek visas to come to the United States. We are moving very, very rapidly ahead with that program.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>When you say “take action,” Mr. Secretary, is that airstrikes? Or can you see a world where American troops are back in Afghanistan?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b>Look, I don’t want to get into hypotheticals about where this might go in the future. What I can tell you, Willie, is that we’re going to make sure that we have the capacity to see if the terrorist threat from Afghanistan re-emerges and to be in a position to do something about it.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Mr. Secretary, a final question, and it’s not really a fun one, but I have to ask. We had a president for four years who openly admitted to getting dirt on political rivals from a foreign leader, meeting without notetakers with Vladimir Putin, having these meetings with Kim Jong-un, which were a joke at best. Geo-strategically, how much ground was lost during the Donald Trump presidency with his corrupt and undemocratic approach to foreign policy? Are we less secure, and if so, how much?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b>Well, Mika, happily, in my job, I don’t do politics. I’m focused on the future. But I can tell you this: Just a short while ago, the President traveled to Europe. He met with our G7 partners, with our NATO Allies, with our partners in the European Union, and then, of course, he met with Vladimir Putin. And he has asked us these first six months of the administration to focus first and foremost on revitalizing our relationships, our partnerships with allies, with partners. That’s exactly what we’ve done. And there was a very, very telling poll that came out during his trip. Across the democratic countries that we’ve been engaged with and that the President engaged with in Europe, on average, 75 percent of the people have confidence, trust in American leadership. That’s up from 17 percent a year ago. I think that speaks volumes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Secretary of State Antony Blinken, thank you so much for coming on the show this morning, and we look forward to hearing about the trip to India and the fight against COVID. Thank you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> As COVID-19 cases rise once again in America, health officials say the Delta variant is now the most dominant strain not only in the U.S., but across the world. This setback comes just weeks after the Biden administration pledged to lead the way in global vaccination efforts. Will the virus’s re-emergence at home slow down efforts to vaccinate the rest of the world?</p>
<p>Joining us now, U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken, and Tony, it’s great to have you back on the show and to speak with you. And I guess we’ll start right there. As we – as it pertains to the coronavirus, how will the United States collaborate on the world stage, lead on the world stage, when you have a rejection of the vaccine here at home that is creating a pandemic among the unvaccinated?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Mika, first, it’s great to see you and great to be with you too. Look, we are leading on both fronts – at home and around the world. And we have to do both because as long as this virus is out there anywhere replicating, we’re going to see more variants, and those variants are going to come back and bite us, as we’re already experiencing with Delta. And so as we’re pursuing every effort to get every American vaccinated, we’re also very much engaged in the world at the President’s direction.</p>
<p>And as you know, we had vaccines in our stockpile, 80 million that we’re making available to countries around the world. We started doing that about a month ago. Of the 80 million, 60 million have been distributed. And the President announced when he was in Europe at the G7 that the United States was going to purchase 500 million, a half a billion vaccines to distribute around the world – no strings attached – to countries around the world to make sure that we can do everything we can to win this race against variants.</p>
<p>The other thing that’s happening is because of our leadership, other countries are stepping up. The G7 countries, our European partners, Japan are also committing additional vaccines. And production is increasing. What we have to do is get to a place where we’re getting as many vaccines as we possibly can to as many countries, as many people as fast as we can. If we do that, we can get ahead of the variants and win the race.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> So I understand you’re announcing a trip where you will take this show on the road and this message on the road. I’d like to hear more about that and I’d like to push you a little bit on the pandemic among the unvaccinated here at home, which really appears to be based on disinformation. We’re hearing even Republican governors like Kay Ivey just fed up with the disinformation and with the choice of people to not vaccinate themselves, to not protect themselves from a virus that could kill them. Meanwhile, there is many countries around the world just hoping to get their hands on the vaccine.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, Mika, that’s right, and look, we know it. The numbers are very, very clear. Of the people hospitalized now or people dying from COVID-19 in the United States, 97, 98, 99 percent are unvaccinated. It’s as clear and stark as that. That’s the reality. And hopefully, as more and more people speak out about this, people will listen and take action. And this is not a partisan issue. It’s an American issue. We’re all in this together, and I hope everyone will do what is necessary to protect ourselves against COVID-19.</p>
<p>And yes, I’m going to India this week. This is such a critical country in the fight against COVID-19. The Indians stood up for us in the early days when we were having great challenges, helping to provide PPE, for example. We’ve now stood up for them as they have encountered wave after wave of COVID-19, including providing more than a quarter of a billion dollars of assistance to them. We have millions of vaccines ready to go to them when they finish their own legal process to bring them in. And India is the leading country when it comes to the production of vaccines.</p>
<p>Of course, they’re focused understandably on their own internal challenges now, but when that production engine gets fully going and can distribute again to the rest of the world, that’s going to make a big difference, too. So I’ll be talking to our Indian friends about that next week.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Will you be addressing in the weeks and months to come the disinformation from U.S. tech companies, perhaps even happening abroad, where companies like Facebook and others have so much information that is just flat wrong about COVID and is leading to deadly decisions on the part of people around the world?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Look, Mika, all we can do is ask everyone to step up to their responsibilities, to try to get accurate information out there to people who need it, whether that’s here at home or whether that’s around the world. And ultimately, because this is a global challenge, because no one is safe until everyone is safe, countries or groups that may engage in misinformation or disinformation are doing themselves ultimately a huge disservice.</p>
<p>And so what we can do, what we have to do, what we are doing, is making sure, one, that the right information gets out there, and two, the resources get out there, the vaccines get out there, the production’s out there. One of the other things we’re doing is investing now in production in different parts of the world – for example, in Africa. We need to make sure that we’re doing that both to get ahead of COVID-19, this pandemic, but also to set ourselves up for the next time. Because unfortunately, there will be a next time. But we have to make sure that we’re in a much better place around the world to prevent it, to see it, to mitigate it more effectively than we’re able to do this time.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> I want to move on to Cuba, which has seen protests over the past few weeks. And yesterday the White House announced new sanctions against Cuba’s defense minister and special forces brigade for the suppression of peaceful protests. What are those sanctions, and what happens if there is not the result the United States would like to see in reaction, in response to those sanctions?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, Mika, I think what we saw just a little over a week ago is quite extraordinary. Thousands of people, tens of thousands of people taking to the streets across Cuba – not just in Havana but in dozens of cities and towns across Cuba – to say they’re fed up – fed up with the repression, fed up with the lack of freedom, fed up with the fact that they don’t have food and medicines, that they have a government that is not providing for them, and making their voices heard. And I think it’s evidence of a government that – and a regime that certainly lacks confidence in itself when it has to try to stifle the voices of its own people.</p>
<p>The smartest thing the regime in Cuba can do is to listen to its own people instead of repress them. But unfortunately, they are – they continue to repress them, they took violent action against those who were speaking up. We went ahead and sanctioned the leaders of the military, the leaders of something called the Black Berets. They were on the front lines of taking violent action against people speaking out for their freedom, speaking out for their needs. We’ll continue to do that.</p>
<p>And also it’s very important that the Cuban people have an ability to communicate, and one of the things we’re very focused on now, working with the private sector, working with others, is doing everything we can to make sure that they have internet access so they can speak to one another, so they can have contact and communication with folks off the island. That is a very active effort.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> And is the regime responding, showing any signs of improvement, of responding to what the United States is requiring for the sanctions to either be pulled back or for more sanctions not to come their way?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> No. We haven’t seen that kind of response. The regime tends to double down in these situations. But again, this is not about us. This is about the Cuban people. And I think one of the big mistakes the regime makes is to try to point the finger at the United States, saying we’re responsible for these protests. We’re not. These are the Cuban people. They are speaking up. They are standing – they’re speaking out. They’re standing up. And a regime that doesn’t understand that and that has – lacks the confidence to allow the voices of its own people to be heard I think is making a very, very big mistake.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Let’s jump to Russia and the issue of cyberwarfare, which I think also then ends us up in China. (Laughter.) What is the United States prepared to do to make sure this doesn’t happen again? What’s next, when the next attack happens, to kind of send a message to Vladimir Putin that there’s a new sheriff in town?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, I think that message has been sent and, as necessary, will be sent again. The – President Biden addressed this directly with President Putin, both at the meeting in Geneva that I took part in as well as more recently on the phone. And one of the things that we’re seeing, as you know, is an increased use of so-called ransomware. And this is tremendously destructive. Overall, one-in-four Americans has been a victim of a cyber crime. About $40 billion lost on an annual basis. And ransomware in particular is increasingly dangerous. And what we’ve made clear to Russia, but to other countries around the world, is if you’re harboring individuals or organizations engaged in cyber crime, engaged in ransomware, that is unacceptable. And if you will not take action against them, we will.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> Secretary Blinken, it’s Willie Geist. Good to see you this morning.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Hey, Willie.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b> I want to ask you about Afghanistan. The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs, General Milley, said the other day that the Taliban has strategic momentum, that it may well over-run the country, though he didn’t concede that point just yet. So as the troops come home from Afghanistan, how should Americans be thinking about the mission there from our point of view? If it does become a training ground for terrorists again, if there does – some threat is posed to the United States, what will be the American reaction there?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b>Well, Willie, we’re determined that it not become a training ground for terrorism directed against the United States or our allies and partners. That’s exactly why we went there in the first place, which is important to remember. We were attacked on 9/11, we went to Afghanistan to get the folks who attacked us, to bring them to justice. Osama bin Laden was brought to justice 10 years ago, and the group, al-Qaida, responsible for those attacks has been dramatically diminished in terms of its capacity to attack anyone from Afghanistan. We’re going to make sure that we keep our eyes on that. If we see the threat re-emerging, we’re going to be in a position to take action against it. But that’s why we were there, and now we’re 20 years and a trillion dollars and thousands of Americans lost later in this – in that campaign. I think the reason we went there is what we have to keep the focus on, and we’ve largely succeeded in doing what we needed to do.</p>
<p>We do have deep concerns about the actions the Taliban is taking indicating that it may be trying to take the country by force, but were that to happen, Afghanistan would be a pariah state. It would not get the assistance that it’s looking for and that the Taliban says it wants if it has any responsibility for the country. It would not get the support from the international community that it says it wants. We’re actively engaged in diplomacy because there is no military solution to this conflict that’s been going on for more than 40 years in Afghanistan, and we’re working to try to bring that to an end.</p>
<p>But one other thing: We’re sustaining our support through our embassy, through other embassies for the Afghan people, and at the same time we’re working to make good on our commitment to those who helped us and put their lives on the line – interpreters, translators – they’re benefiting from a program called Special Immigrant Visa programs that allow them to seek visas to come to the United States. We are moving very, very rapidly ahead with that program.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>When you say “take action,” Mr. Secretary, is that airstrikes? Or can you see a world where American troops are back in Afghanistan?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b>Look, I don’t want to get into hypotheticals about where this might go in the future. What I can tell you, Willie, is that we’re going to make sure that we have the capacity to see if the terrorist threat from Afghanistan re-emerges and to be in a position to do something about it.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Mr. Secretary, a final question, and it’s not really a fun one, but I have to ask. We had a president for four years who openly admitted to getting dirt on political rivals from a foreign leader, meeting without notetakers with Vladimir Putin, having these meetings with Kim Jong-un, which were a joke at best. Geo-strategically, how much ground was lost during the Donald Trump presidency with his corrupt and undemocratic approach to foreign policy? Are we less secure, and if so, how much?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b>Well, Mika, happily, in my job, I don’t do politics. I’m focused on the future. But I can tell you this: Just a short while ago, the President traveled to Europe. He met with our G7 partners, with our NATO Allies, with our partners in the European Union, and then, of course, he met with Vladimir Putin. And he has asked us these first six months of the administration to focus first and foremost on revitalizing our relationships, our partnerships with allies, with partners. That’s exactly what we’ve done. And there was a very, very telling poll that came out during his trip. Across the democratic countries that we’ve been engaged with and that the President engaged with in Europe, on average, 75 percent of the people have confidence, trust in American leadership. That’s up from 17 percent a year ago. I think that speaks volumes.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION: </b>Secretary of State Antony Blinken, thank you so much for coming on the show this morning, and we look forward to hearing about the trip to India and the fight against COVID. Thank you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Michigan Governor Whitmer</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-michigan-governor-whitmer/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 13:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261572</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Governor Gretchen Whitmer last week about the case of U.S. citizen Danny Fenster, a journalist and Michigan native currently detained in Burma. Governor Whitmer expressed thanks for the State Department’s continued commitment to secure Fenster’s release. Secretary Blinken and Governor Whitmer also discussed Enbridge Energy’s Line 5, which crosses the U.S. border with Canada in Michigan and is the subject of litigation between the State of Michigan and Enbridge in U.S. domestic courts. Secretary Blinken noted that there is no formal bilateral process between the federal governments of the United States and Canada concerning Line 5.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Governor Gretchen Whitmer last week about the case of U.S. citizen Danny Fenster, a journalist and Michigan native currently detained in Burma. Governor Whitmer expressed thanks for the State Department’s continued commitment to secure Fenster’s release. Secretary Blinken and Governor Whitmer also discussed Enbridge Energy’s Line 5, which crosses the U.S. border with Canada in Michigan and is the subject of litigation between the State of Michigan and Enbridge in U.S. domestic courts. Secretary Blinken noted that there is no formal bilateral process between the federal governments of the United States and Canada concerning Line 5.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
