<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 15:30:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken On ABC’s This Week with George Stephanopoulos</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-on-abcs-this-week-with-george-stephanopoulos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 15:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245703</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Good morning, Mr. Secretary.  Welcome to This Week.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Thanks, George.  Great to be with you.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Let’s start with the ceasefire.  President Biden pushed it privately, welcomed it publicly.  Both sides are claiming a sort of victory right now, but has anything really changed?  What’s to prevent this cycle of violence from kicking up again, maybe very soon?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, first, George, it was critical to get to the ceasefire, and President Biden’s focus on relentless, determined, but quiet diplomacy is what got us to where we needed to be, which is to get the violence ended as quickly as possible, to stop more human suffering, and to at least put ourselves in position to make a turn, to make a pivot to building something more positive. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That has to start now with dealing with the grave humanitarian situation in Gaza, then reconstruction, rebuilding what’s been lost, and, critically, engaging both sides in trying to start to make real improvements in the lives of people so that Israelis and Palestinians can live with equal measures of security, of peace, and of dignity.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  You stress that word “equal” right there.  That seems to be a new emphasis for this administration.  We haven’t heard that a lot in the past, equal rights for Palestinians and Israelis.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, it’s vitally important that Palestinians feel hope and have opportunity and can live in security, just as it is for Israelis.  And there should be equal measures.  And in a democratic society, that is, I think, an obligation of the – of any government.  So ultimately, I think that that hope, that security, that dignity can – will be found in a Palestinian state. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But meanwhile, we have to do everything we can both to address the immediate situation, which is humanitarian, reconstruction in Gaza, starting to improve people’s lives in a concrete way, and ultimately get to a place where we can get negotiations and move towards something that brings a lasting resolution to the problem.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  You say you still want to work towards a two-state solution, but is that really still possible?  Is there anything constructive the United States can do?  It doesn’t seem like efforts have created much fruit in the past.  And – or is this new emphasis you’re putting on equal rights really the start of a longer-term shift?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  President Biden’s been very clear that he remains committed to a two-state solution.  Look, ultimately, it is the only way to ensure Israel’s future as a Jewish and democratic state, and of course, the only way to give the Palestinians the state to which they’re entitled.  That’s where we have to go.  But that, I don’t think, is something for – necessarily for today.  We have to start putting in place the conditions that would allow both sides to engage in a meaningful and positive way toward two states.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the first instance, we have to deal with making this turn from the violence – we got the ceasefire – and now deal with the humanitarian situation, deal with reconstruction, and deepen our existing engagement with Palestinians and with Israelis alike.  But the most &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  The President wants &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  I was going to say, George, the most important thing is this:  What I hope that everyone takes from this is that if there isn’t positive change, and particularly if we can’t find a way for – to help Palestinians live with more dignity and with more hope, the cycle’s likely to repeat itself, and that is in no one’s interest.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  You say you want rebuilding; you say you want reconstruction.  The President said he wants to do that without restocking Hamas – rebuilding Gaza without restocking Hamas.  How do you do that?  They’re in charge in Gaza.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Look, we’ve worked in the past and we can continue to work with trusted, independent parties that can help do the reconstruction and the development, not some quasi-governmental authority.  And the fact of the matter is Hamas has brought nothing but ruin to the Palestinian people: its gross mismanagement of Gaza while it’s been in charge, and of course, these indiscriminate rocket attacks on Israeli civilians, which have elicited the response that they did because Israel has a right to defend itself.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So I think what’s the real challenge here is to help the Palestinians, and particularly to help moderate Palestinians and the Palestinian Authority deliver better results for their people.  And of course, Israel has a profound role to play in that too.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  The President reiterated his strong support for Israel on Friday, but he’s coming under increased pressure from progressives.  Bernie Sanders has introduced a resolution of disapproval over a new arms sale to Israel.  Others like Rashida Tlaib and AOC say the U.S. should not be rubber-stamping arms sales to Israel when they use the weapons to abuse Palestinian rights.  What’s your response to that?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, happily, George, one of the things I don’t do in this job is I don’t do politics.  I focus on the policy.  So I’ll leave the politics to others.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But here’s what I can say:  We got to the result thanks to President Biden’s relentless focus on this quiet but, I think, effective diplomacy in getting to a ceasefire and stopping the violence in 11 days.  If you go back and look at previous crises, they’ve lasted a lot longer, but of course, every single day that these things go on, we see a tremendous loss in human life and in human suffering.  And we were determined to get – to bring that to an end.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to arms sales, two things.  First, the President’s been equally clear:  We are committed to giving Israel the means to defend itself, especially when it comes to these indiscriminate rocket attacks against civilians.  Any country would respond to that, and we – we’re committed to Israel’s defense.  At the same time, any arms sale is going to be done in full consultation with Congress.  We’re committed to that.  And we want to make sure that that process works effectively.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Your administration’s continuing to pursue nuclear negotiations with Iran, but 42 Republican senators have called on the President to end the negotiations, make it clear that sanctions will remain in place because of Iranian funding of Hamas.  Do you believe that Iran is funding Hamas?  And if they are, should the sanctions stay in place?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  George, Iran is engaged in a number of activities, including funding extremist groups, supporting terrorism more broadly, supporting very dangerous proxies that are taking destabilizing actions throughout the Middle East, proliferating weapons. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And two things on that.  One, an Iran with a nuclear weapon or with the capability to build one in very short order is going to act with even greater impunity in those areas, which just adds to the urgency of trying to put the nuclear problem back in the box that the nuclear agreement put it in.  And, of course, many of these actions are going forward now while the – and have gone forward over the last few years under the so-called maximum pressure being exerted by the previous administration, and clearly did not get the result that we all seek, which is to curb all of these activities. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But the first thing that we need to do is put the nuclear problem back in the box.  That’s why we’re committed to trying to see if Iran will come back into compliance with the nuclear agreement, the so-called JCPOA – that’s what we’re engaged in now – and then use that as a platform to build on and to try to deal with these other issues.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  The Iranians say the decision to raise – to lift some of the sanctions has already been made.  Is that true? </span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  We’re – we’ve been now over – we’re about to have our, I think, fifth round of discussions in Vienna with the Iranians.  And what these discussions and talks – indirect, as you know – have done is they’ve clarified what each side needs to do in order to come back into compliance.  So we know what sanctions would need to be lifted if they’re inconsistent with the nuclear agreement.  But as important and indeed more important, Iran, I think, knows what it needs to do to come back into compliance on the nuclear side.  And what we haven’t yet seen is whether Iran is ready and willing to make a decision to do what it has to do.  That’s the test and we don’t yet have an answer.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Finally, let’s talk about the North Korea nuclear program.  At his meeting with the South Korean prime minister on Friday, the President said he was prepared to re-engage with the North Koreans under the right conditions.  Right now, the best estimates are that the North Korean nuclear arsenal has doubled in recent years, about 45 weapons right now.  Does the United States have to accept that North Korea will remain a nuclear power?  Do we have to learn to live with a nuclear North Korea?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  We don’t and we shouldn’t, but let’s be honest:  This is a hard problem.  Previous administrations, Republican and Democrat alike, have tried to tackle it, and no one’s fully succeeded, to say the least.  In fact, the program has gotten more advanced and more dangerous over time.  And we’ve looked at different approaches that were taken, including basically doing nothing for nothing or trying to do – get everything for everything.  Neither has worked.  We engaged in an intensive review.  We looked at what every previous administration has done.  We consulted very closely with our allies and partners, starting with South Korea and Japan.  I was there with Secretary Austin.  We just had President Moon’s visit.  All of that as well as the view of experts on all sides was factored in.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And what President Biden determined was the best chance we have to achieve the objective of the total denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula is to engage diplomatically with North Korea on a deliberate, calibrated approach where we seek to make progress toward that goal.  I don’t think there’s going to be a grand bargain where this gets resolved in one fell swoop.  It’s got to be clearly calibrated diplomacy, clear steps from the North Koreans, and it moves forward in that way.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, we put that forward.  We’re waiting to see if Pyongyang actually wants to engage.  The ball’s in their court.  We’ve made clear we’re prepared to pursue this diplomatically even as the sanctions remain in place because North Korea continues to engage in activities that are clearly prohibited by the United Nations.  But we’re prepared to do the diplomacy.  The question is:  Is North Korea? </span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Secretary Blinken, thanks for your time this morning.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Thanks, George.  Great to be with you.  </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Good morning, Mr. Secretary.  Welcome to This Week.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Thanks, George.  Great to be with you.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Let’s start with the ceasefire.  President Biden pushed it privately, welcomed it publicly.  Both sides are claiming a sort of victory right now, but has anything really changed?  What’s to prevent this cycle of violence from kicking up again, maybe very soon?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, first, George, it was critical to get to the ceasefire, and President Biden’s focus on relentless, determined, but quiet diplomacy is what got us to where we needed to be, which is to get the violence ended as quickly as possible, to stop more human suffering, and to at least put ourselves in position to make a turn, to make a pivot to building something more positive. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That has to start now with dealing with the grave humanitarian situation in Gaza, then reconstruction, rebuilding what’s been lost, and, critically, engaging both sides in trying to start to make real improvements in the lives of people so that Israelis and Palestinians can live with equal measures of security, of peace, and of dignity.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  You stress that word “equal” right there.  That seems to be a new emphasis for this administration.  We haven’t heard that a lot in the past, equal rights for Palestinians and Israelis.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, it’s vitally important that Palestinians feel hope and have opportunity and can live in security, just as it is for Israelis.  And there should be equal measures.  And in a democratic society, that is, I think, an obligation of the – of any government.  So ultimately, I think that that hope, that security, that dignity can – will be found in a Palestinian state. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But meanwhile, we have to do everything we can both to address the immediate situation, which is humanitarian, reconstruction in Gaza, starting to improve people’s lives in a concrete way, and ultimately get to a place where we can get negotiations and move towards something that brings a lasting resolution to the problem.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  You say you still want to work towards a two-state solution, but is that really still possible?  Is there anything constructive the United States can do?  It doesn’t seem like efforts have created much fruit in the past.  And – or is this new emphasis you’re putting on equal rights really the start of a longer-term shift?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  President Biden’s been very clear that he remains committed to a two-state solution.  Look, ultimately, it is the only way to ensure Israel’s future as a Jewish and democratic state, and of course, the only way to give the Palestinians the state to which they’re entitled.  That’s where we have to go.  But that, I don’t think, is something for – necessarily for today.  We have to start putting in place the conditions that would allow both sides to engage in a meaningful and positive way toward two states.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the first instance, we have to deal with making this turn from the violence – we got the ceasefire – and now deal with the humanitarian situation, deal with reconstruction, and deepen our existing engagement with Palestinians and with Israelis alike.  But the most &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  The President wants &#8212;</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  I was going to say, George, the most important thing is this:  What I hope that everyone takes from this is that if there isn’t positive change, and particularly if we can’t find a way for – to help Palestinians live with more dignity and with more hope, the cycle’s likely to repeat itself, and that is in no one’s interest.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  You say you want rebuilding; you say you want reconstruction.  The President said he wants to do that without restocking Hamas – rebuilding Gaza without restocking Hamas.  How do you do that?  They’re in charge in Gaza.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Look, we’ve worked in the past and we can continue to work with trusted, independent parties that can help do the reconstruction and the development, not some quasi-governmental authority.  And the fact of the matter is Hamas has brought nothing but ruin to the Palestinian people: its gross mismanagement of Gaza while it’s been in charge, and of course, these indiscriminate rocket attacks on Israeli civilians, which have elicited the response that they did because Israel has a right to defend itself.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So I think what’s the real challenge here is to help the Palestinians, and particularly to help moderate Palestinians and the Palestinian Authority deliver better results for their people.  And of course, Israel has a profound role to play in that too.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  The President reiterated his strong support for Israel on Friday, but he’s coming under increased pressure from progressives.  Bernie Sanders has introduced a resolution of disapproval over a new arms sale to Israel.  Others like Rashida Tlaib and AOC say the U.S. should not be rubber-stamping arms sales to Israel when they use the weapons to abuse Palestinian rights.  What’s your response to that?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Well, happily, George, one of the things I don’t do in this job is I don’t do politics.  I focus on the policy.  So I’ll leave the politics to others.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But here’s what I can say:  We got to the result thanks to President Biden’s relentless focus on this quiet but, I think, effective diplomacy in getting to a ceasefire and stopping the violence in 11 days.  If you go back and look at previous crises, they’ve lasted a lot longer, but of course, every single day that these things go on, we see a tremendous loss in human life and in human suffering.  And we were determined to get – to bring that to an end.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to arms sales, two things.  First, the President’s been equally clear:  We are committed to giving Israel the means to defend itself, especially when it comes to these indiscriminate rocket attacks against civilians.  Any country would respond to that, and we – we’re committed to Israel’s defense.  At the same time, any arms sale is going to be done in full consultation with Congress.  We’re committed to that.  And we want to make sure that that process works effectively.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Your administration’s continuing to pursue nuclear negotiations with Iran, but 42 Republican senators have called on the President to end the negotiations, make it clear that sanctions will remain in place because of Iranian funding of Hamas.  Do you believe that Iran is funding Hamas?  And if they are, should the sanctions stay in place?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  George, Iran is engaged in a number of activities, including funding extremist groups, supporting terrorism more broadly, supporting very dangerous proxies that are taking destabilizing actions throughout the Middle East, proliferating weapons. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And two things on that.  One, an Iran with a nuclear weapon or with the capability to build one in very short order is going to act with even greater impunity in those areas, which just adds to the urgency of trying to put the nuclear problem back in the box that the nuclear agreement put it in.  And, of course, many of these actions are going forward now while the – and have gone forward over the last few years under the so-called maximum pressure being exerted by the previous administration, and clearly did not get the result that we all seek, which is to curb all of these activities. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But the first thing that we need to do is put the nuclear problem back in the box.  That’s why we’re committed to trying to see if Iran will come back into compliance with the nuclear agreement, the so-called JCPOA – that’s what we’re engaged in now – and then use that as a platform to build on and to try to deal with these other issues.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  The Iranians say the decision to raise – to lift some of the sanctions has already been made.  Is that true? </span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  We’re – we’ve been now over – we’re about to have our, I think, fifth round of discussions in Vienna with the Iranians.  And what these discussions and talks – indirect, as you know – have done is they’ve clarified what each side needs to do in order to come back into compliance.  So we know what sanctions would need to be lifted if they’re inconsistent with the nuclear agreement.  But as important and indeed more important, Iran, I think, knows what it needs to do to come back into compliance on the nuclear side.  And what we haven’t yet seen is whether Iran is ready and willing to make a decision to do what it has to do.  That’s the test and we don’t yet have an answer.</span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Finally, let’s talk about the North Korea nuclear program.  At his meeting with the South Korean prime minister on Friday, the President said he was prepared to re-engage with the North Koreans under the right conditions.  Right now, the best estimates are that the North Korean nuclear arsenal has doubled in recent years, about 45 weapons right now.  Does the United States have to accept that North Korea will remain a nuclear power?  Do we have to learn to live with a nuclear North Korea?</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  We don’t and we shouldn’t, but let’s be honest:  This is a hard problem.  Previous administrations, Republican and Democrat alike, have tried to tackle it, and no one’s fully succeeded, to say the least.  In fact, the program has gotten more advanced and more dangerous over time.  And we’ve looked at different approaches that were taken, including basically doing nothing for nothing or trying to do – get everything for everything.  Neither has worked.  We engaged in an intensive review.  We looked at what every previous administration has done.  We consulted very closely with our allies and partners, starting with South Korea and Japan.  I was there with Secretary Austin.  We just had President Moon’s visit.  All of that as well as the view of experts on all sides was factored in.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And what President Biden determined was the best chance we have to achieve the objective of the total denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula is to engage diplomatically with North Korea on a deliberate, calibrated approach where we seek to make progress toward that goal.  I don’t think there’s going to be a grand bargain where this gets resolved in one fell swoop.  It’s got to be clearly calibrated diplomacy, clear steps from the North Koreans, and it moves forward in that way.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, we put that forward.  We’re waiting to see if Pyongyang actually wants to engage.  The ball’s in their court.  We’ve made clear we’re prepared to pursue this diplomatically even as the sanctions remain in place because North Korea continues to engage in activities that are clearly prohibited by the United Nations.  But we’re prepared to do the diplomacy.  The question is:  Is North Korea? </span></p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Secretary Blinken, thanks for your time this morning.</span></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Thanks, George.  Great to be with you.  </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yemen National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/yemen-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 12:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I offer bests wishes to the people of Yemen on the occasion of your 31st National Unity Day.  The United States appreciates the Republic of Yemen Government’s ongoing commitments towards achieving peace in Yemen.</p>
<p>An inclusive and lasting resolution of this conflict is a top priority for the United States.  I look forward to the continued engagement between our countries and other partners to achieve peace, and I affirm our commitment to helping bring about a prosperous future for all Yemenis.  May you enjoy a celebratory National Unity Day.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I offer bests wishes to the people of Yemen on the occasion of your 31st National Unity Day.  The United States appreciates the Republic of Yemen Government’s ongoing commitments towards achieving peace in Yemen.</p>
<p>An inclusive and lasting resolution of this conflict is a top priority for the United States.  I look forward to the continued engagement between our countries and other partners to achieve peace, and I affirm our commitment to helping bring about a prosperous future for all Yemenis.  May you enjoy a celebratory National Unity Day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Turkish Foreign Minister Çavuşoğlu</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-turkish-foreign-minister-cavusoglu-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 23:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245642</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Turkish Foreign Minister Mevlüt Çavuşoğlu today. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Çavuşoğlu discussed the importance of cooperation between the United States and Turkey, including our shared interests in Syria and Afghanistan. The Secretary noted continuing U.S. support for talks between NATO Allies Turkey and Greece and emphasized the importance of promoting and protecting human rights and fundamental freedoms.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Turkish Foreign Minister Mevlüt Çavuşoğlu today. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Çavuşoğlu discussed the importance of cooperation between the United States and Turkey, including our shared interests in Syria and Afghanistan. The Secretary noted continuing U.S. support for talks between NATO Allies Turkey and Greece and emphasized the importance of promoting and protecting human rights and fundamental freedoms.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calling for a Civilian-Led Transition of Power to a Democratically Elected Government in Chad</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/calling-for-a-civilian-led-transition-of-power-to-a-democratically-elected-government-in-chad/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 23:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245639</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States supports the recommendations of the African Union Peace and Security Council regarding Chad, and we join the African Union and our international partners in calling for a peaceful, timely, and civilian-led transition of power to a democratically elected government before October 2022.</p>
<p>The Chadian people deserve an inclusive national dialogue where all stakeholders can come together to decide the future of their country. Chad’s political transition should include a new national constitution, a concrete plan and timeline for elections, and support for strong institutions such as a representative National Assembly, an independent judicial system, and a reformed National Independent Electoral Commission. A representative, democratically elected government is the best path to long-term prosperity and stability in Chad and the region.</p>
<p>The United States has long stood with the people of Chad in advocating for democratic, representative government, and we will continue to support the people of Chad, the African Union, and our international partners in advocating for a timely transition to elected, civilian government.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States supports the recommendations of the African Union Peace and Security Council regarding Chad, and we join the African Union and our international partners in calling for a peaceful, timely, and civilian-led transition of power to a democratically elected government before October 2022.</p>
<p>The Chadian people deserve an inclusive national dialogue where all stakeholders can come together to decide the future of their country. Chad’s political transition should include a new national constitution, a concrete plan and timeline for elections, and support for strong institutions such as a representative National Assembly, an independent judicial system, and a reformed National Independent Electoral Commission. A representative, democratically elected government is the best path to long-term prosperity and stability in Chad and the region.</p>
<p>The United States has long stood with the people of Chad in advocating for democratic, representative government, and we will continue to support the people of Chad, the African Union, and our international partners in advocating for a timely transition to elected, civilian government.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Palestinian Authority President Abbas</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-palestinian-authority-president-abbas-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 21:34:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas. The Secretary and President welcomed the ceasefire and discussed measures to ensure that it holds. The Secretary underscored the U.S. commitment to working with the Palestinian Authority and the United Nations to provide rapid humanitarian assistance and to marshal international support for Gaza and Gaza reconstruction efforts. The Secretary and President expressed their appreciation for Egypt’s mediation efforts and committed to retaining open lines of communication at all levels. The President welcomed Secretary Blinken&#8217;s planned travel to the region, where the Secretary will meet with Palestinian, Israeli, and regional counterparts to discuss relief efforts and working together to build better futures for Palestinians and Israelis.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas. The Secretary and President welcomed the ceasefire and discussed measures to ensure that it holds. The Secretary underscored the U.S. commitment to working with the Palestinian Authority and the United Nations to provide rapid humanitarian assistance and to marshal international support for Gaza and Gaza reconstruction efforts. The Secretary and President expressed their appreciation for Egypt’s mediation efforts and committed to retaining open lines of communication at all levels. The President welcomed Secretary Blinken&#8217;s planned travel to the region, where the Secretary will meet with Palestinian, Israeli, and regional counterparts to discuss relief efforts and working together to build better futures for Palestinians and Israelis.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inaugural U.S.-Lebanon Defense Resourcing Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/inaugural-u-s-lebanon-defense-resourcing-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 16:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245533</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State and the Lebanese Armed Forces held their inaugural Defense Resourcing Conference on May 21, 2021.  Senior Official for Arms Control and International Security C.S. Eliot Kang headed the U.S. delegation and Lebanese Armed Forces (LAF) Commander General Joseph Aoun headed the Lebanese delegation.  Other U.S. participants included Acting Assistant Secretary of Defense for International Security Affairs Mara Karlin, U.S. Ambassador to Lebanon Dorothy Shea, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Regional Security and Security Assistance Mira Resnick, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Levant Affairs Aimee Cutrona, and representatives from the Office of the Secretary of Defense and the Defense Security Cooperation Agency.</p>
<p>In this virtual conference, the delegations highlighted the strength of the U.S.-LAF partnership and discussed ways to deepen security cooperation.  Participants commemorated the completion of a non-binding five-year security assistance roadmap that aligns anticipated annual U.S. support to the LAF with shared priorities in counterterrorism, border security, and defense institution building, which will enable effective joint planning for future defense requirements.</p>
<p>The delegations discussed the deteriorating economic, political, and humanitarian conditions affecting the Lebanese people and military.  The U.S. Department of State renewed its commitment to the LAF by announcing $120 million in Foreign Military Financing (FMF) assistance to Lebanon for fiscal year 2021, subject to Congressional notification procedures, representing a $15 million increase over prior-year levels.  Lebanon is one of the largest recipients globally of U.S. Department of State security assistance.</p>
<p>The delegations also discussed ways to leverage the full range of authorities under U.S. law through which the United States can provide additional assistance to the LAF as it grapples with the economic crises in Lebanon.  Earlier this month, for instance, the U.S. Department of Defense notified Lebanon of the planned transfer of three Protector-class patrol boats to the Lebanese Navy, which, upon delivery in 2022, will enhance the Lebanese Navy’s ability to counter external and regional threats, and protect freedom of navigation and commerce in the maritime domain.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State looks forward to reviewing progress on the U.S.-LAF partnership at the next Defense Resourcing Conference in 2022.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State and the Lebanese Armed Forces held their inaugural Defense Resourcing Conference on May 21, 2021.  Senior Official for Arms Control and International Security C.S. Eliot Kang headed the U.S. delegation and Lebanese Armed Forces (LAF) Commander General Joseph Aoun headed the Lebanese delegation.  Other U.S. participants included Acting Assistant Secretary of Defense for International Security Affairs Mara Karlin, U.S. Ambassador to Lebanon Dorothy Shea, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Regional Security and Security Assistance Mira Resnick, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Levant Affairs Aimee Cutrona, and representatives from the Office of the Secretary of Defense and the Defense Security Cooperation Agency.</p>
<p>In this virtual conference, the delegations highlighted the strength of the U.S.-LAF partnership and discussed ways to deepen security cooperation.  Participants commemorated the completion of a non-binding five-year security assistance roadmap that aligns anticipated annual U.S. support to the LAF with shared priorities in counterterrorism, border security, and defense institution building, which will enable effective joint planning for future defense requirements.</p>
<p>The delegations discussed the deteriorating economic, political, and humanitarian conditions affecting the Lebanese people and military.  The U.S. Department of State renewed its commitment to the LAF by announcing $120 million in Foreign Military Financing (FMF) assistance to Lebanon for fiscal year 2021, subject to Congressional notification procedures, representing a $15 million increase over prior-year levels.  Lebanon is one of the largest recipients globally of U.S. Department of State security assistance.</p>
<p>The delegations also discussed ways to leverage the full range of authorities under U.S. law through which the United States can provide additional assistance to the LAF as it grapples with the economic crises in Lebanon.  Earlier this month, for instance, the U.S. Department of Defense notified Lebanon of the planned transfer of three Protector-class patrol boats to the Lebanese Navy, which, upon delivery in 2022, will enhance the Lebanese Navy’s ability to counter external and regional threats, and protect freedom of navigation and commerce in the maritime domain.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State looks forward to reviewing progress on the U.S.-LAF partnership at the next Defense Resourcing Conference in 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Seventh U.S.-Thailand Strategic Dialogue</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/seventh-u-s-thailand-strategic-dialogue/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 15:53:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245518</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Senior delegations representing the United States and Thailand met virtually on May 21, 2021, for the Seventh U.S.-Thailand Strategic Dialogue.  Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Atul Keshap led the U.S. delegation, and Permanent Secretary of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs Thani Thongphakdi led the Thai delegation.</p>
<p>The Strategic Dialogue is an integral part of the enduring U.S.-Thai relationship, which has spanned over two centuries and covers political, security, and economic cooperation.  The Dialogue addressed a wide variety of issues of mutual interest, including regional security, economic prosperity, health cooperation, and joint efforts to combat transnational crime.  Both sides reaffirmed the longstanding commitment to the U.S.-Thai defense alliance, which benefits both nations and supports peace and prosperity across the Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p>The two delegations explored ways to deepen cooperation in areas, including climate change and clean energy, business, technology, and people-to-people connections.  The United States reiterated its commitment to the people of Thailand in our fight against COVID-19, and thus far has provided nearly $30 million in health-related assistance to Thailand.  Both sides highlighted the importance of cooperation in regional forums including the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum, ASEAN, and the Mekong-U.S. Partnership.</p>
<p>The United States underscored the importance of protecting human rights and fundamental freedoms. The United States also expressed deep concern about the ongoing crisis in Burma.</p>
<p>The two sides agreed on the benefit of continued high-level engagements and looked forward to the next U.S.-Thailand Strategic Dialogue.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Senior delegations representing the United States and Thailand met virtually on May 21, 2021, for the Seventh U.S.-Thailand Strategic Dialogue.  Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Atul Keshap led the U.S. delegation, and Permanent Secretary of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs Thani Thongphakdi led the Thai delegation.</p>
<p>The Strategic Dialogue is an integral part of the enduring U.S.-Thai relationship, which has spanned over two centuries and covers political, security, and economic cooperation.  The Dialogue addressed a wide variety of issues of mutual interest, including regional security, economic prosperity, health cooperation, and joint efforts to combat transnational crime.  Both sides reaffirmed the longstanding commitment to the U.S.-Thai defense alliance, which benefits both nations and supports peace and prosperity across the Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p>The two delegations explored ways to deepen cooperation in areas, including climate change and clean energy, business, technology, and people-to-people connections.  The United States reiterated its commitment to the people of Thailand in our fight against COVID-19, and thus far has provided nearly $30 million in health-related assistance to Thailand.  Both sides highlighted the importance of cooperation in regional forums including the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum, ASEAN, and the Mekong-U.S. Partnership.</p>
<p>The United States underscored the importance of protecting human rights and fundamental freedoms. The United States also expressed deep concern about the ongoing crisis in Burma.</p>
<p>The two sides agreed on the benefit of continued high-level engagements and looked forward to the next U.S.-Thailand Strategic Dialogue.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Acting Assistant Secretary of State Joey Hood Visits Tunisia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/acting-assistant-secretary-of-state-joey-hood-visits-tunisia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 15:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245513</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Acting Assistant Secretary of State for Near Eastern Affairs Joey Hood visited Tunisia from May 17–20.  Acting Assistant Secretary Hood met with Tunisian State Secretary Mohamed Ali Nafti and Diplomatic Advisor to Prime Minister Mechichi, Elyes Ghariani, and underscored the United States government’s commitment to partnering with Tunisia to advance its democratic, economic, and security goals.  They also discussed regional issues of mutual importance, including support for the UN-led Libyan peace process.  Acting Assistant Secretary Hood also met with civil society and attended an event to celebrate the 75th anniversary of the Fulbright Program.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Acting Assistant Secretary of State for Near Eastern Affairs Joey Hood visited Tunisia from May 17–20.  Acting Assistant Secretary Hood met with Tunisian State Secretary Mohamed Ali Nafti and Diplomatic Advisor to Prime Minister Mechichi, Elyes Ghariani, and underscored the United States government’s commitment to partnering with Tunisia to advance its democratic, economic, and security goals.  They also discussed regional issues of mutual importance, including support for the UN-led Libyan peace process.  Acting Assistant Secretary Hood also met with civil society and attended an event to celebrate the 75th anniversary of the Fulbright Program.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Travel to Belgium, Turkey, Indonesia, Cambodia, Thailand, and Hawaii</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-travel-to-belgium-turkey-indonesia-cambodia-thailand-and-hawaii/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 14:29:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman will travel to Brussels, Ankara, Jakarta, Phnom Penh, Bangkok, and Honolulu May 25 to June 4.</p>
<p>In Brussels, the Deputy Secretary will meet with foreign counterparts representing Belgium, the EU, and NATO to discuss key policy priorities, including strengthening cooperation with allies and partners, supporting the global recovery from COVID-19, and countering the influence of challenging foreign actors. While in Brussels, Deputy Secretary Sherman will lead the first meeting of the U.S.-EU Dialogue on China with European Union External Action Service Secretary General Stefano Sannino.  The Deputy Secretary will then travel to Ankara to engage with government officials and civil society.  Deputy Secretary Sherman will underscore the importance of the U.S.-Turkey relationship as we work together with our NATO Ally to confront mutual challenges, and discuss areas of concern.</p>
<p>From Ankara, Deputy Secretary Sherman will travel to Southeast Asia, where she will reaffirm the United States’ commitment to ASEAN centrality and address a range of bilateral and regional issues, including efforts to urge the Burmese military to cease violence, release all those unjustly detained, and restore Burma to the path of democracy.  In Jakarta, she will meet Indonesian government officials to discuss the growing U.S.-Indonesia partnership and how the two countries can collaborate to address regional challenges.  While in Jakarta, she will also meet with officials from the ASEAN Secretariat and the ASEAN Committee of Permanent Representatives to discuss expanding and deepening the U.S.-ASEAN strategic partnership.  In Phnom Penh, the Deputy Secretary will hold a series of meetings.  In Bangkok, the Deputy Secretary will meet with Thai government officials to discuss U.S.-Thai security cooperation, expanding economic ties, promoting fundamental freedoms, Mekong regional issues, the crisis in Burma, and deepening cultural ties between the American and Thai people.</p>
<p>Finally, in Honolulu, Deputy Secretary Sherman will meet with officials at INDOPACOM to discuss U.S. strategy in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman will travel to Brussels, Ankara, Jakarta, Phnom Penh, Bangkok, and Honolulu May 25 to June 4.</p>
<p>In Brussels, the Deputy Secretary will meet with foreign counterparts representing Belgium, the EU, and NATO to discuss key policy priorities, including strengthening cooperation with allies and partners, supporting the global recovery from COVID-19, and countering the influence of challenging foreign actors. While in Brussels, Deputy Secretary Sherman will lead the first meeting of the U.S.-EU Dialogue on China with European Union External Action Service Secretary General Stefano Sannino.  The Deputy Secretary will then travel to Ankara to engage with government officials and civil society.  Deputy Secretary Sherman will underscore the importance of the U.S.-Turkey relationship as we work together with our NATO Ally to confront mutual challenges, and discuss areas of concern.</p>
<p>From Ankara, Deputy Secretary Sherman will travel to Southeast Asia, where she will reaffirm the United States’ commitment to ASEAN centrality and address a range of bilateral and regional issues, including efforts to urge the Burmese military to cease violence, release all those unjustly detained, and restore Burma to the path of democracy.  In Jakarta, she will meet Indonesian government officials to discuss the growing U.S.-Indonesia partnership and how the two countries can collaborate to address regional challenges.  While in Jakarta, she will also meet with officials from the ASEAN Secretariat and the ASEAN Committee of Permanent Representatives to discuss expanding and deepening the U.S.-ASEAN strategic partnership.  In Phnom Penh, the Deputy Secretary will hold a series of meetings.  In Bangkok, the Deputy Secretary will meet with Thai government officials to discuss U.S.-Thai security cooperation, expanding economic ties, promoting fundamental freedoms, Mekong regional issues, the crisis in Burma, and deepening cultural ties between the American and Thai people.</p>
<p>Finally, in Honolulu, Deputy Secretary Sherman will meet with officials at INDOPACOM to discuss U.S. strategy in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Calls with Israeli Foreign Minister Ashkenazi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-calls-with-israeli-foreign-minister-ashkenazi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 01:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Israeli Foreign Minister Gabi Ashkenazi this morning and again in the afternoon. During their afternoon conversation, the Secretary welcomed the Foreign Minister&#8217;s confirmation that the parties had agreed to a ceasefire. Both leaders expressed their appreciation for Egypt&#8217;s mediation efforts, and the Secretary noted that he would continue to remain in close touch with his Egyptian counterpart and other regional stakeholders. The Foreign Minister welcomed Secretary Blinken&#8217;s planned travel to the region, where the Secretary will meet with Israeli, Palestinian, and regional counterparts in the coming days to discuss recovery efforts and working together to build better futures for Israelis and Palestinians.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Israeli Foreign Minister Gabi Ashkenazi this morning and again in the afternoon. During their afternoon conversation, the Secretary welcomed the Foreign Minister&#8217;s confirmation that the parties had agreed to a ceasefire. Both leaders expressed their appreciation for Egypt&#8217;s mediation efforts, and the Secretary noted that he would continue to remain in close touch with his Egyptian counterpart and other regional stakeholders. The Foreign Minister welcomed Secretary Blinken&#8217;s planned travel to the region, where the Secretary will meet with Israeli, Palestinian, and regional counterparts in the coming days to discuss recovery efforts and working together to build better futures for Israelis and Palestinians.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
