<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 16:41:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Special Representative for the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK) Kim’s Trilateral Call with Republic of Korea (ROK) Special Representative Noh and Japan Director General Funakoshi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-representative-for-the-democratic-peoples-republic-of-korea-dprk-kims-trilateral-call-with-republic-of-korea-rok-special-representative-noh-and-japan-director-general-fun-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 16:41:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324111</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>In a March 14 trilateral call, U.S. Special Representative for the DPRK Sung Kim, Japanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs Director General for Asian and Oceanian Affairs Bureau Funakoshi Takehiro, and ROK Special Representative for Korean Peninsula Peace and Security Affairs Noh Kyu-duk discussed the DPRK’s February 26 and March 4 ballistic missile launches, which all three governments have concluded were tests of a new DPRK intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM) system.</p>
<p>Special Representative Kim strongly condemned the launches, which violated multiple UN Security Council resolutions and present a serious threat to international peace and security.  He also reaffirmed the U.S. commitment to the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, as well as its ironclad commitment to the defense of its allies, the ROK and Japan.</p>
<p>Special Representative Kim expressed concern that these ICBM launches represented a serious escalation by the DPRK and pose a significant risk to regional stability.  While noting that the door remains open to diplomacy, Special Representative Kim emphasized that the United States will take all necessary measures to ensure the security of the American homeland and our allies.  He called on the DPRK to cease its unlawful and destabilizing activities and instead engage in dialogue, underscoring the United States’ continued openness to meeting the DPRK without preconditions.  The three officials agreed to continue their close coordination.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>In a March 14 trilateral call, U.S. Special Representative for the DPRK Sung Kim, Japanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs Director General for Asian and Oceanian Affairs Bureau Funakoshi Takehiro, and ROK Special Representative for Korean Peninsula Peace and Security Affairs Noh Kyu-duk discussed the DPRK’s February 26 and March 4 ballistic missile launches, which all three governments have concluded were tests of a new DPRK intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM) system.</p>
<p>Special Representative Kim strongly condemned the launches, which violated multiple UN Security Council resolutions and present a serious threat to international peace and security.  He also reaffirmed the U.S. commitment to the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, as well as its ironclad commitment to the defense of its allies, the ROK and Japan.</p>
<p>Special Representative Kim expressed concern that these ICBM launches represented a serious escalation by the DPRK and pose a significant risk to regional stability.  While noting that the door remains open to diplomacy, Special Representative Kim emphasized that the United States will take all necessary measures to ensure the security of the American homeland and our allies.  He called on the DPRK to cease its unlawful and destabilizing activities and instead engage in dialogue, underscoring the United States’ continued openness to meeting the DPRK without preconditions.  The three officials agreed to continue their close coordination.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Robinson’s Travel to Beirut, Vienna, and Chisinau</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-for-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-robinsons-travel-to-beirut-vienna-and-chisinau/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 12:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=323912</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement (INL) Todd D. Robinson traveled to Beirut, Lebanon from March 9-11. While in Beirut, Assistant Secretary Robinson met with members of the Lebanese government and presided over a ceremony commemorating the handover of the Aramoun Training Academy, a U.S.-funded facility that will help strengthen and expand the training capability and professionalization of the Lebanese Internal Security Forces (ISF) and other partners. The Assistant Secretary also met with ISF leadership to highlight current U.S. support for the organization’s resilience and professionalization. He also met with female members of the ISF and the justice sector to highlight their contributions to civilian security and the rule of law in Lebanon.</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary Robinson is in Vienna, Austria from March 12-15. While in Vienna, he will lead the U.S. delegation to the 65th session of the United Nations Commission on Narcotic Drugs. As co-head of the U.S. delegation, he will meet with foreign partners to demonstrate U.S. solidarity and support for Ukraine as it faces Russia’s premeditated, unjustified, and unprovoked war. Assistant Secretary Robinson will also engage with partner and ally governments to drive global action and consensus to counter illicit narcotics and precursor chemicals contributing to the U.S. opioid epidemic.</p>
<p>Finally, Assistant Secretary Robinson will travel to Chisinau, Moldova from March 15-17 where he will meet with Moldovan government officials to highlight ongoing U.S. support for Moldova&#8217;s fight against corruption and its democratic reform agenda, as well as visit the Moldovan Police Academy. The Assistant Secretary will also discuss support for Moldovan authorities on the frontline of the humanitarian response to the crisis caused by Russia&#8217;s further invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:INL-PAPD@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">INL-PAPD@state.gov</a> or visit @StateINL on twitter.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement (INL) Todd D. Robinson traveled to Beirut, Lebanon from March 9-11. While in Beirut, Assistant Secretary Robinson met with members of the Lebanese government and presided over a ceremony commemorating the handover of the Aramoun Training Academy, a U.S.-funded facility that will help strengthen and expand the training capability and professionalization of the Lebanese Internal Security Forces (ISF) and other partners. The Assistant Secretary also met with ISF leadership to highlight current U.S. support for the organization’s resilience and professionalization. He also met with female members of the ISF and the justice sector to highlight their contributions to civilian security and the rule of law in Lebanon.</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary Robinson is in Vienna, Austria from March 12-15. While in Vienna, he will lead the U.S. delegation to the 65th session of the United Nations Commission on Narcotic Drugs. As co-head of the U.S. delegation, he will meet with foreign partners to demonstrate U.S. solidarity and support for Ukraine as it faces Russia’s premeditated, unjustified, and unprovoked war. Assistant Secretary Robinson will also engage with partner and ally governments to drive global action and consensus to counter illicit narcotics and precursor chemicals contributing to the U.S. opioid epidemic.</p>
<p>Finally, Assistant Secretary Robinson will travel to Chisinau, Moldova from March 15-17 where he will meet with Moldovan government officials to highlight ongoing U.S. support for Moldova&#8217;s fight against corruption and its democratic reform agenda, as well as visit the Moldovan Police Academy. The Assistant Secretary will also discuss support for Moldovan authorities on the frontline of the humanitarian response to the crisis caused by Russia&#8217;s further invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:INL-PAPD@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">INL-PAPD@state.gov</a> or visit @StateINL on twitter.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Iraqi Prime Minister Mustafa al-Kadhimi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-iraqi-prime-minister-mustafa-al-kadhimi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 10:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=323890</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke yesterday with Iraqi Prime Minister Mustafa al-Kadhimi. Secretary Blinken condemned the Iranian missile attacks near Erbil that violated Iraq’s sovereignty and expressed solidarity with the Iraqi people. The Secretary and the Prime Minister agreed the attack demonstrates the need for Iraqi unity and the urgency of forming a government accountable to the Iraqi people that protects Iraq’s territorial integrity. The Secretary conveyed the U.S. commitment to working with the Iraqi government and others in the region to hold Iran accountable.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke yesterday with Iraqi Prime Minister Mustafa al-Kadhimi. Secretary Blinken condemned the Iranian missile attacks near Erbil that violated Iraq’s sovereignty and expressed solidarity with the Iraqi people. The Secretary and the Prime Minister agreed the attack demonstrates the need for Iraqi unity and the urgency of forming a government accountable to the Iraqi people that protects Iraq’s territorial integrity. The Secretary conveyed the U.S. commitment to working with the Iraqi government and others in the region to hold Iran accountable.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken&#8217;s Call with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Kuleba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-ukrainian-foreign-minister-kuleba-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=323849</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke by phone today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to offer continued support to the people and government of Ukraine and to condemn the Russian Federation’s ongoing attacks on Ukrainian cities, which have caused increasing civilian deaths. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Kuleba discussed ongoing diplomatic efforts to stop Putin’s war of choice. The Secretary reiterated the United States’ steadfast solidarity with Ukraine in defense against the Kremlin’s continued brutal aggression.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke by phone today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to offer continued support to the people and government of Ukraine and to condemn the Russian Federation’s ongoing attacks on Ukrainian cities, which have caused increasing civilian deaths. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Kuleba discussed ongoing diplomatic efforts to stop Putin’s war of choice. The Secretary reiterated the United States’ steadfast solidarity with Ukraine in defense against the Kremlin’s continued brutal aggression.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iran’s Missile Strikes on the Kurdistan Region of Iraq</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/irans-missile-strikes-on-the-kurdistan-region-of-iraq/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 16:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=323821</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States strongly condemns the missile strikes on Erbil, Iraq last night that emanated from Iran. The strikes were an outrageous violation of Iraq’s sovereignty. No U.S. facilities were damaged or personnel injured, and we have no indications the attack was directed at the United States. Iran must immediately cease its attacks, respect Iraqi sovereignty, and halt its interference in Iraq’s internal affairs. The United States stands with our Iraqi partners, including in the Kurdistan Region, and will help our partners in the region defend themselves.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States strongly condemns the missile strikes on Erbil, Iraq last night that emanated from Iran. The strikes were an outrageous violation of Iraq’s sovereignty. No U.S. facilities were damaged or personnel injured, and we have no indications the attack was directed at the United States. Iran must immediately cease its attacks, respect Iraqi sovereignty, and halt its interference in Iraq’s internal affairs. The United States stands with our Iraqi partners, including in the Kurdistan Region, and will help our partners in the region defend themselves.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Wendy R. Sherman With Bret Baier of Fox News Sunday</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-wendy-r-sherman-with-bret-baier-of-fox-news-sunday/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 16:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=323818</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Joining us now live, Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman. Madam Secretary, welcome to Fox News Sunday.</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: Good to be with you, Bret.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Want to obviously talk a lot about Ukraine, but I want to start where I left off there with General Keane, and that is these 12 ballistic missiles fired on the U.S. consulate in Erbil, Iraq from inside Iran. Just in the past few minutes, Iran is now claiming responsibility for that attack. What is the reaction to that, and is there going to be a response?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: This was a very concerning attack, as General Keane pointed out. Indeed, we do not believe that the consulate was actually the target of this missile attack. We are very glad that our facilities are secure, that everybody’s accounted for, that no one has been hurt or killed. But all of that said, this is great concern. There will indeed be a statement, I’m sure, coming out shortly, as well as calls in. This was an attack on Iraq’s sovereignty, among other things, and of great concern to all of us.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Obviously &#8212;</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: We will be following this closely.</p>
<p>QUESTION: We have U.S. personnel there who work and live there, and as you mentioned, no casualties as of yet that we’ve heard of. But at the same time, the U.S. is closing in on this nuclear deal with Iran. Is that true? Is it close?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: Well, I think it’s close, and we would like all of the parties – including Russia, which has indicated it’s got some concerns – to bring this to a close. We are very concerned about what Iran is doing, but imagine these Iranians with a nuclear weapon. We need to get that off the table so we can address their malign behavior in the Middle East, and we will do all of the above, but first we’ve got to get this deal. And it is not yet closed.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Madam Secretary, you can understand the disconnect for the average American watching this happening. As we’re sitting at a table not only with the Iranians but the Russians in Vienna, we are getting fired upon by Iran. You’re saying the target wasn’t the U.S. consulate, but that’s where it ended up. Help people get – square this circle, because it doesn’t seem like a lot of people think that we should be doing that.</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: It’s hard to understand, I appreciate that, but here’s the deal: If Iran has a nuclear weapon, its ability to project power into the Middle East and to deter us, our allies and partners, is enormous. So President Biden believes very strongly, as does Secretary Blinken, as do I, that we need to make sure that Iran never obtains a nuclear weapon, and then we also need to deal with their malign behavior in the region. But first we’ve got to make sure that they cannot obtain a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Right. I just have two more quick questions.</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: Sure.</p>
<p>QUESTION: You think that this deal is as good as the 2015 deal? You were a part of that as well.</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: I think we don’t know yet. It is not closed; it is not finished. We are urging all parties to do what they need to, and there’s a lot of onus on Iran to decide whether in fact it wants to move forward or not, come into compliance and ensure that Iran never has a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Right. And regardless of whether the deal is reached or not, is there a plan to deal with Iran’s regional behavior, proxies, terrorism, fighting, these missiles, drones, whether there’s a deal with removing sanctions or not?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: Absolutely, very high priority, working with our partners and allies in the region to do exactly that.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Okay, and last thing. There is reporting that two Iranians belonging to the Qods Force have been plotting to assassinate former National Security Advisor John Bolton according to the Justice Department. And this is The Washington Examiner reporting that the department possess indictable evidence against the Iranians, but the Biden administration resisting publicly indicting the men for fear that it could derail their drive for the nuclear deal with Iran currently nearing completion in Vienna. Do you know that to be true?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: What I know to be true is that we have a responsibility to protect American citizens from harm. We do that every single day, and that is true of all present and past American officials, and that is our highest priority.</p>
<p>QUESTION: But nothing is being held back?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: Nothing is being held back. We are going to protect Americans wherever they are however we can.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Madam Secretary, now to Ukraine. These new strikes overnight in the west, just miles from the Polish border, the death toll now at 35, 135 wounded there. Nothing NATO or the U.S. has done so far has stopped Vladimir Putin. How does this end?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: Well, right now it looks like it ends very badly already for the Ukrainian people. I think we all spend every day just horrified at the suffering of the American* people. As your reporter on the ground discussed, it is just awful, particularly in Mariupol, where people are either going to starve to death or freeze to death or die because they don’t have their medicine. It is truly horrifying.</p>
<p>There are two objectives that we have. One is to support Ukraine in every way we can, and indeed, since the Biden administration began, we have put $1.2 billion forward in security assistance to help Ukraine defend itself against this horrible attack. And the second is to put enormous pressure on Vladimir Putin to try to change his calculus, to end this war, to get a ceasefire in the first instance, to get humanitarian corridors, and to end this invasion. That pressure is beginning to have some effect. We are seeing some signs of a willingness to have real, serious negotiations. But I have to say, as your reporter said, so far it appears that Vladimir Putin is intent on destroying Ukraine. We need to help Ukrainians in every way we can.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Madam Secretary, everyone is wary of World War III. President Biden mentioned that the other day. But on Capitol Hill, there are now more and more lawmakers seeming to say that they’re tired of giving Putin the upper hand here, at least publicly. Here’s Senator Mitt Romney:</p>
<p>SENATOR ROMNEY: “President Putin has actually said the things we’re doing are provocative. He’s already said that the sanctions we’ve put in place are like declaring war. He’s going to continue saying that, and we are fearful of provoking him. It’s time for him to be fearful of us.”</p>
<p>QUESTION: So is there a way to flip the script here?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: I think we’ve already started to flip that script, Bret. I think that $1.2 billion in security assistance – anti-tank, anti-armor, anti-aircraft – is really helping Ukraine to resist the onslaught of what your reporter said is a army of Russia where Putin very badly miscalculated how this war would go. It is nonetheless horrifying for the Ukrainian people, and so we want to support them in every way we possibly can. And we want to support everyone’s efforts coordinated with the United States to try to mediate and end this terrible, terrible situation.</p>
<p>QUESTION: You’re saying support them in every way, but the MiG-29 situation – these jets from Poland – really seemed to be a mixed message. Republicans are now talking about that openly, criticizing the administration. Here’s Senator Tom Cotton; take a listen.</p>
<p>SENATOR COTTON: “They’re saying on the one hand Ukraine is not effectively using its current aircraft and can’t effectively use this aircraft, so the gains would be very small. But on the other hand, Vladimir Putin is going to view this as such an escalation that he might strike the United States or strike NATO. Both of those things can’t be true.”</p>
<p>SENATOR GRAHAM: “The Ukrainians don’t need applause; they need jets.”</p>
<p>SENATOR ROMNEY: “They want MiGs; get them the MiGs.”</p>
<p>QUESTION: (Inaudible) say – if the Ukrainians say they do want these MiGs, whether we assess that they’re good or not for the battlefield, why not get them that?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: So look, if I were President Zelenskyy, I would want everything and anything I could possibly get, so I understand this. The Pentagon, however, made an assessment that trying to move these planes was very complicated, that backfilling them was virtually impossible, that what Ukrainians really needed were anti-aircraft, anti-tank, and anti-armor weapons, which is what we are supplying them in great measure and coordinating with other countries to do the same. So I understand the frustration.</p>
<p>And one of the things I think has been really terrific in this horrifying situation is there has been bipartisan support for Ukraine. I’m really grateful that Congress recently passed the legislation – provide an additional $200 million dollars in drawdown that Secretary Blinken signed out yesterday. So this is a bipartisan effort. At the Munich Security Conference, there was a strong bipartisan delegation in support of Ukraine. And there is that kind of support on Capitol Hill, which I think sends an important signal not only to Ukraine, but to Putin that he can’t divide America, he can’t divide NATO, he can’t divide Europe, he can’t divide the world. A hundred and forty-one countries signed up to a resolution at the UN General Assembly denouncing what Vladimir Putin is doing. This is one man’s choice to wage a premeditated, unjust, unprovoked war against a sovereign country. We can’t let it stand.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Quickly, has the Russia-China relationship suffered or strengthened as a result of this invasion?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: I think that’s an open question yet, Bret, to be perfectly honest. We saw Russia and China come closer together, certainly before the Olympics, putting out a long manifesto about their partnership and how they were going to move forward together. And at the same time, we’ve seen China pretty uncomfortable with an invasion of a sovereign country. China has – the People’s Republic of China has often said that sovereignty is key, territorial integrity is key, that countries should decide their own political future. We agree with those principles. We hope that China does as well.</p>
<p>In two weeks – in two weeks – Vladimir Putin undid 30 years of economic development. There was an international order that China and Russia both subscribed to that helped – both countries developed. For Russia, that is now gone. We’re seeing them be taken out of every organization. The President’s going to move forward with the Congress on removing them from most-favored nation status at the WTO, the World Trade Organization. I think the PRC is watching very closely, has to make some tough decisions.</p>
<p>QUESTION: But yet they’re sounding very bold, Madam Secretary. Just yesterday, China warned that any country supporting Taiwan militarily would face, quote, “the worst consequences,” adding no one, no force would be able to stop the Communist Party if it attacks Taiwan. That does not sound positive. So the last question I have for you: Has Russia’s invasion changed China’s calculus when it comes to Taiwan?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: I hope that China is looking very carefully at what’s happening. We have a united world with very grave and very consequential sanctions on Russia. We understand and support a “one China” policy, but we don’t believe that China, PRC, ought to take Taiwan by force, and we will do everything we can to deter that effort by the PRC. And I think they’re watching very closely. In fact, I think they made that statement, Bret, because they’ve seen what’s happened and they’re trying to go on the offense knowing that they ought to be on the defense.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Secretary Sherman, thank you. Thanks for your time this weekend.</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: Thank you.</p>
<p>*Ukrainian</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Joining us now live, Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman. Madam Secretary, welcome to Fox News Sunday.</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: Good to be with you, Bret.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Want to obviously talk a lot about Ukraine, but I want to start where I left off there with General Keane, and that is these 12 ballistic missiles fired on the U.S. consulate in Erbil, Iraq from inside Iran. Just in the past few minutes, Iran is now claiming responsibility for that attack. What is the reaction to that, and is there going to be a response?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: This was a very concerning attack, as General Keane pointed out. Indeed, we do not believe that the consulate was actually the target of this missile attack. We are very glad that our facilities are secure, that everybody’s accounted for, that no one has been hurt or killed. But all of that said, this is great concern. There will indeed be a statement, I’m sure, coming out shortly, as well as calls in. This was an attack on Iraq’s sovereignty, among other things, and of great concern to all of us.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Obviously &#8212;</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: We will be following this closely.</p>
<p>QUESTION: We have U.S. personnel there who work and live there, and as you mentioned, no casualties as of yet that we’ve heard of. But at the same time, the U.S. is closing in on this nuclear deal with Iran. Is that true? Is it close?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: Well, I think it’s close, and we would like all of the parties – including Russia, which has indicated it’s got some concerns – to bring this to a close. We are very concerned about what Iran is doing, but imagine these Iranians with a nuclear weapon. We need to get that off the table so we can address their malign behavior in the Middle East, and we will do all of the above, but first we’ve got to get this deal. And it is not yet closed.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Madam Secretary, you can understand the disconnect for the average American watching this happening. As we’re sitting at a table not only with the Iranians but the Russians in Vienna, we are getting fired upon by Iran. You’re saying the target wasn’t the U.S. consulate, but that’s where it ended up. Help people get – square this circle, because it doesn’t seem like a lot of people think that we should be doing that.</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: It’s hard to understand, I appreciate that, but here’s the deal: If Iran has a nuclear weapon, its ability to project power into the Middle East and to deter us, our allies and partners, is enormous. So President Biden believes very strongly, as does Secretary Blinken, as do I, that we need to make sure that Iran never obtains a nuclear weapon, and then we also need to deal with their malign behavior in the region. But first we’ve got to make sure that they cannot obtain a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Right. I just have two more quick questions.</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: Sure.</p>
<p>QUESTION: You think that this deal is as good as the 2015 deal? You were a part of that as well.</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: I think we don’t know yet. It is not closed; it is not finished. We are urging all parties to do what they need to, and there’s a lot of onus on Iran to decide whether in fact it wants to move forward or not, come into compliance and ensure that Iran never has a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Right. And regardless of whether the deal is reached or not, is there a plan to deal with Iran’s regional behavior, proxies, terrorism, fighting, these missiles, drones, whether there’s a deal with removing sanctions or not?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: Absolutely, very high priority, working with our partners and allies in the region to do exactly that.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Okay, and last thing. There is reporting that two Iranians belonging to the Qods Force have been plotting to assassinate former National Security Advisor John Bolton according to the Justice Department. And this is The Washington Examiner reporting that the department possess indictable evidence against the Iranians, but the Biden administration resisting publicly indicting the men for fear that it could derail their drive for the nuclear deal with Iran currently nearing completion in Vienna. Do you know that to be true?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: What I know to be true is that we have a responsibility to protect American citizens from harm. We do that every single day, and that is true of all present and past American officials, and that is our highest priority.</p>
<p>QUESTION: But nothing is being held back?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: Nothing is being held back. We are going to protect Americans wherever they are however we can.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Madam Secretary, now to Ukraine. These new strikes overnight in the west, just miles from the Polish border, the death toll now at 35, 135 wounded there. Nothing NATO or the U.S. has done so far has stopped Vladimir Putin. How does this end?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: Well, right now it looks like it ends very badly already for the Ukrainian people. I think we all spend every day just horrified at the suffering of the American* people. As your reporter on the ground discussed, it is just awful, particularly in Mariupol, where people are either going to starve to death or freeze to death or die because they don’t have their medicine. It is truly horrifying.</p>
<p>There are two objectives that we have. One is to support Ukraine in every way we can, and indeed, since the Biden administration began, we have put $1.2 billion forward in security assistance to help Ukraine defend itself against this horrible attack. And the second is to put enormous pressure on Vladimir Putin to try to change his calculus, to end this war, to get a ceasefire in the first instance, to get humanitarian corridors, and to end this invasion. That pressure is beginning to have some effect. We are seeing some signs of a willingness to have real, serious negotiations. But I have to say, as your reporter said, so far it appears that Vladimir Putin is intent on destroying Ukraine. We need to help Ukrainians in every way we can.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Madam Secretary, everyone is wary of World War III. President Biden mentioned that the other day. But on Capitol Hill, there are now more and more lawmakers seeming to say that they’re tired of giving Putin the upper hand here, at least publicly. Here’s Senator Mitt Romney:</p>
<p>SENATOR ROMNEY: “President Putin has actually said the things we’re doing are provocative. He’s already said that the sanctions we’ve put in place are like declaring war. He’s going to continue saying that, and we are fearful of provoking him. It’s time for him to be fearful of us.”</p>
<p>QUESTION: So is there a way to flip the script here?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: I think we’ve already started to flip that script, Bret. I think that $1.2 billion in security assistance – anti-tank, anti-armor, anti-aircraft – is really helping Ukraine to resist the onslaught of what your reporter said is a army of Russia where Putin very badly miscalculated how this war would go. It is nonetheless horrifying for the Ukrainian people, and so we want to support them in every way we possibly can. And we want to support everyone’s efforts coordinated with the United States to try to mediate and end this terrible, terrible situation.</p>
<p>QUESTION: You’re saying support them in every way, but the MiG-29 situation – these jets from Poland – really seemed to be a mixed message. Republicans are now talking about that openly, criticizing the administration. Here’s Senator Tom Cotton; take a listen.</p>
<p>SENATOR COTTON: “They’re saying on the one hand Ukraine is not effectively using its current aircraft and can’t effectively use this aircraft, so the gains would be very small. But on the other hand, Vladimir Putin is going to view this as such an escalation that he might strike the United States or strike NATO. Both of those things can’t be true.”</p>
<p>SENATOR GRAHAM: “The Ukrainians don’t need applause; they need jets.”</p>
<p>SENATOR ROMNEY: “They want MiGs; get them the MiGs.”</p>
<p>QUESTION: (Inaudible) say – if the Ukrainians say they do want these MiGs, whether we assess that they’re good or not for the battlefield, why not get them that?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: So look, if I were President Zelenskyy, I would want everything and anything I could possibly get, so I understand this. The Pentagon, however, made an assessment that trying to move these planes was very complicated, that backfilling them was virtually impossible, that what Ukrainians really needed were anti-aircraft, anti-tank, and anti-armor weapons, which is what we are supplying them in great measure and coordinating with other countries to do the same. So I understand the frustration.</p>
<p>And one of the things I think has been really terrific in this horrifying situation is there has been bipartisan support for Ukraine. I’m really grateful that Congress recently passed the legislation – provide an additional $200 million dollars in drawdown that Secretary Blinken signed out yesterday. So this is a bipartisan effort. At the Munich Security Conference, there was a strong bipartisan delegation in support of Ukraine. And there is that kind of support on Capitol Hill, which I think sends an important signal not only to Ukraine, but to Putin that he can’t divide America, he can’t divide NATO, he can’t divide Europe, he can’t divide the world. A hundred and forty-one countries signed up to a resolution at the UN General Assembly denouncing what Vladimir Putin is doing. This is one man’s choice to wage a premeditated, unjust, unprovoked war against a sovereign country. We can’t let it stand.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Quickly, has the Russia-China relationship suffered or strengthened as a result of this invasion?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: I think that’s an open question yet, Bret, to be perfectly honest. We saw Russia and China come closer together, certainly before the Olympics, putting out a long manifesto about their partnership and how they were going to move forward together. And at the same time, we’ve seen China pretty uncomfortable with an invasion of a sovereign country. China has – the People’s Republic of China has often said that sovereignty is key, territorial integrity is key, that countries should decide their own political future. We agree with those principles. We hope that China does as well.</p>
<p>In two weeks – in two weeks – Vladimir Putin undid 30 years of economic development. There was an international order that China and Russia both subscribed to that helped – both countries developed. For Russia, that is now gone. We’re seeing them be taken out of every organization. The President’s going to move forward with the Congress on removing them from most-favored nation status at the WTO, the World Trade Organization. I think the PRC is watching very closely, has to make some tough decisions.</p>
<p>QUESTION: But yet they’re sounding very bold, Madam Secretary. Just yesterday, China warned that any country supporting Taiwan militarily would face, quote, “the worst consequences,” adding no one, no force would be able to stop the Communist Party if it attacks Taiwan. That does not sound positive. So the last question I have for you: Has Russia’s invasion changed China’s calculus when it comes to Taiwan?</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: I hope that China is looking very carefully at what’s happening. We have a united world with very grave and very consequential sanctions on Russia. We understand and support a “one China” policy, but we don’t believe that China, PRC, ought to take Taiwan by force, and we will do everything we can to deter that effort by the PRC. And I think they’re watching very closely. In fact, I think they made that statement, Bret, because they’ve seen what’s happened and they’re trying to go on the offense knowing that they ought to be on the defense.</p>
<p>QUESTION: Secretary Sherman, thank you. Thanks for your time this weekend.</p>
<p>DEPUTY SECRETARY SHERMAN: Thank you.</p>
<p>*Ukrainian</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken to Deliver Remarks at the International Women of Courage Award Ceremony</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinken-to-deliver-remarks-at-the-international-women-of-courage-award-ceremony/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 15:08:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=323807</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will host and deliver remarks at the 16th annual International Women of Courage (IWOC) Award Ceremony at the U.S. Department of State at 10:00 a.m. on Monday, March 14, 2022. He will be joined by First Lady Jill Biden, U.S. Permanent Representative to the UN Linda Thomas-Greenfield, Assistant Secretary for Educational and Cultural Affairs Lee Satterfield, Senior Official for the Office of Global Women’s Issues Katrina Fotovat, and Special Envoy for Afghan Women, Girls, and Human Rights Rina Amiri, who will all deliver remarks. <a href="https://www.state.gov/2022-international-women-of-courage-award-recipients-announced/">Find additional information about the 2022 IWOC Award Ceremony</a>.</p>
<p>All remarks will be live-streamed on <a href="https://www.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.state.gov</a> and <a class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/statedept" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">www.youtube.com/statedept</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact the Office of Press Relations at <a href="mailto:PAPressDuty@state.gov">PAPressDuty@state.gov</a>.</p>
<div id="mail_footer"></div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will host and deliver remarks at the 16th annual International Women of Courage (IWOC) Award Ceremony at the U.S. Department of State at 10:00 a.m. on Monday, March 14, 2022. He will be joined by First Lady Jill Biden, U.S. Permanent Representative to the UN Linda Thomas-Greenfield, Assistant Secretary for Educational and Cultural Affairs Lee Satterfield, Senior Official for the Office of Global Women’s Issues Katrina Fotovat, and Special Envoy for Afghan Women, Girls, and Human Rights Rina Amiri, who will all deliver remarks. <a href="https://www.state.gov/2022-international-women-of-courage-award-recipients-announced/">Find additional information about the 2022 IWOC Award Ceremony</a>.</p>
<p>All remarks will be live-streamed on <a href="https://www.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.state.gov</a> and <a class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/statedept" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">www.youtube.com/statedept</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact the Office of Press Relations at <a href="mailto:PAPressDuty@state.gov">PAPressDuty@state.gov</a>.</p>
<div id="mail_footer"></div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Qatari Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Foreign Affairs Al-Thani</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-qatari-deputy-prime-minister-and-minister-of-foreign-affairs-al-thani-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 14:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=323795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke yesterday with Qatari Minister of Foreign Affairs Mohammed bin Abdulrahman Al-Thani. Secretary Blinken and the Foreign Minister discussed Russia’s unprovoked war on Ukraine and reaffirmed their support to the Ukrainian people. The Secretary also thanked the Foreign Minister for Qatar’s continued willingness to assist with the safe transit of vulnerable people from Afghanistan. The Secretary and Foreign Minister noted the significance of the 50-year anniversary on March 19 of diplomatic relations between the United States and Qatar and emphasized the strong bilateral partnership.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times new roman,times; font-size: medium;">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke yesterday with Qatari Minister of Foreign Affairs Mohammed bin Abdulrahman Al-Thani. Secretary Blinken and the Foreign Minister discussed Russia’s unprovoked war on Ukraine and reaffirmed their support to the Ukrainian people. The Secretary also thanked the Foreign Minister for Qatar’s continued willingness to assist with the safe transit of vulnerable people from Afghanistan. The Secretary and Foreign Minister noted the significance of the 50-year anniversary on March 19 of diplomatic relations between the United States and Qatar and emphasized the strong bilateral partnership.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>$200 Million in New Security Assistance for Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/200-million-in-new-security-assistance-for-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 22:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=323770</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The people of Ukraine are inspiring the world as they defend their country from Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified invasion of their country. The United States and our Allies and partners stand in solidarity with the people and government of Ukraine in the face of the Kremlin’s aggression.</p>
<p>Exercising the additional authority provided in the extension of the continuing resolution, I have immediately authorized today, pursuant to a delegation by the President, a fourth Presidential Drawdown of up to $200 million for additional military assistance for Ukraine’s defense. This package will include further defensive assistance to help Ukraine meet the armored, airborne, and other threats it is facing. This drawdown will bring the total security assistance provided by the United States to Ukraine to more than $1.2 billion since the beginning of the Administration.</p>
<p>We salute the armed forces of Ukraine and all Ukrainian citizens who are defending their country with great skill, iron will, and profound courage. America and its Allies support their efforts to defend their country and protect their fellow citizens, and urge Russia to recognize that force will never defeat Ukraine’s spirit. We are committed to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and will continue to provide Ukraine the support it needs.</p>
<p>We will also continue to provide humanitarian assistance to those in need and to back the people of Ukraine in their fight for their country through security and economic assistance. The international community is united and determined to hold Putin accountable.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The people of Ukraine are inspiring the world as they defend their country from Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified invasion of their country. The United States and our Allies and partners stand in solidarity with the people and government of Ukraine in the face of the Kremlin’s aggression.</p>
<p>Exercising the additional authority provided in the extension of the continuing resolution, I have immediately authorized today, pursuant to a delegation by the President, a fourth Presidential Drawdown of up to $200 million for additional military assistance for Ukraine’s defense. This package will include further defensive assistance to help Ukraine meet the armored, airborne, and other threats it is facing. This drawdown will bring the total security assistance provided by the United States to Ukraine to more than $1.2 billion since the beginning of the Administration.</p>
<p>We salute the armed forces of Ukraine and all Ukrainian citizens who are defending their country with great skill, iron will, and profound courage. America and its Allies support their efforts to defend their country and protect their fellow citizens, and urge Russia to recognize that force will never defeat Ukraine’s spirit. We are committed to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and will continue to provide Ukraine the support it needs.</p>
<p>We will also continue to provide humanitarian assistance to those in need and to back the people of Ukraine in their fight for their country through security and economic assistance. The international community is united and determined to hold Putin accountable.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eighth Annual U.S.-AUC High-Level Dialogue Joint Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/eighth-annual-u-s-auc-high-level-dialogue-joint-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 17:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=323754</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Government of the United States of America and the African Union Commission on the occasion of the U.S.-African Union High-Level Dialogue.</p>
<p>Begin Text:</p>
<p>The United States and African Union Commission (AUC) convened the eighth annual U.S.-AUC High-Level Dialogue on March 11 in Washington, D.C., led by Secretary of State Antony Blinken and AUC Head of Delegation Chairperson Moussa Faki Mahamat. The AUC and United States reaffirmed their strong commitment to collaboration, grounded in mutual interests and shared values, to address global issues including health security, climate change, inclusive economic growth, and peace, security, and governance. Secretary Blinken and Chairperson Moussa Faki signed a new Memorandum of Cooperation to advance the partnership between the United States and the Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (Africa CDC).</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken and Chairperson Moussa Faki discussed strengthening the U.S.-AUC partnership to focus on shared global concerns including ending the current COVID-19 pandemic and preparing for future health threats; partnering on climate change strategies addressing threats to global stability; and bolstering democracy and democratically elected governments on the continent.</p>
<p>Health: U.S. interagency officials and AU Commissioner for Health, Humanitarian Affairs, and Social Development Minata Samate Cessouma discussed health capacity building in Africa and operationalizing Africa CDC&#8217;s Regional Collaborating Centers. Ensuring strong systems and infrastructure, including National Public Health Institutes is vital to prevent, detect, and respondto future infectious disease threats and improve the health of our global citizens. Participants also discussed COVID-19 response efforts and highlighted U.S. investments in the health sector, including through PEPFAR and other programs.</p>
<p>It was discussed to build upon existing public health assets including those for combatting HIV, TB, and malaria, in response to the COVID-19 pandemic and other future disease threats. Participants acknowledged the importance of the operationalization of the Africa Medicines Agency (AMA).</p>
<p>Climate: Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica Medina underscored U.S. support for the AUC Africa Continental Climate Change and Resilient Development Strategy through U.S. programs including PREPARE, the President&#8217;s Emergency Plan for Adaptation and Resilience. U.S. and AUC officials discussed Africa’s priorities for COP27, which will be hosted by Africa in November 2022, especially just transitional and sustainable funding. The AU plays a leading role in advancing continental implementation of global climate commitments to keep the global temperature from rising beyond 1.5 degrees Celsius. Participants also discussed the nexus of climate and food security and food systems in the context of the AU’s theme on Nutrition and Food Security for 2022.</p>
<p>Economic Growth: Deputy Assistant Secretary Akunna Cook and AUC Commissioner for Economic Development, Tourism, Trade, Industry, and Minerals Albert Muchanga</p>
<p>led a strategic discussion on inclusive economic growth and investment opportunities. Noting the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on economies in the region, officials discussed the importance of spurring economic growth as a response to the pandemic. Officials reaffirmed U.S. support for the AfCFTA and other Agenda 2063 programs and projects to achieve sustainable economic development, build regional value chains, and increase both competitiveness and investment opportunities for mutual benefit. Participants discussed the importance of engaging with the private sector to increase trade and investment with Africa in pursuit of inclusive economic development, including by enhancing AGOA beyond its current framework.</p>
<p>Peace and Security: Special Assistant to the President and National Security Council Senior Director for Africa Dana Banks, Assistant Secretary of State for African Affairs Molly Phee, and AUC Commissioner for Political Affairs, Peace and Security Bankole Adeoye outlined the shared principles that underpin the U.S.-AUC security relationship. They discussed the importance of concrete action to address threats to democracy, including recent coups and military takeovers, lack of respect for constitutional term limits, and growing negative influence around the world.</p>
<p>Officials emphasized that these negative trends across the continent undermine the foundational principles of the AU, including the promotion of democratic ideals. U.S. and AU officials share the vision that the AU becomes the continental security guarantor, promoting peace and democracy through an operationalized and sustainable African Peace and Security Architecture (APSA) and African Governance Architecture. Additionally, the APSA provides a vital platform for preventing conflict, including in addressing the governance shortfalls fueling conflict and creating vulnerabilities exploited by terrorists, insurgencies, and international criminal networks. Participants affirmed their commitment to intensifying efforts to strengthen vital and inclusive democratic institutions and promote good governance as the most effective way to address the needs and aspirations of African citizens for a healthier, more peaceful, and more prosperous future.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Government of the United States of America and the African Union Commission on the occasion of the U.S.-African Union High-Level Dialogue.</p>
<p>Begin Text:</p>
<p>The United States and African Union Commission (AUC) convened the eighth annual U.S.-AUC High-Level Dialogue on March 11 in Washington, D.C., led by Secretary of State Antony Blinken and AUC Head of Delegation Chairperson Moussa Faki Mahamat. The AUC and United States reaffirmed their strong commitment to collaboration, grounded in mutual interests and shared values, to address global issues including health security, climate change, inclusive economic growth, and peace, security, and governance. Secretary Blinken and Chairperson Moussa Faki signed a new Memorandum of Cooperation to advance the partnership between the United States and the Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (Africa CDC).</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken and Chairperson Moussa Faki discussed strengthening the U.S.-AUC partnership to focus on shared global concerns including ending the current COVID-19 pandemic and preparing for future health threats; partnering on climate change strategies addressing threats to global stability; and bolstering democracy and democratically elected governments on the continent.</p>
<p>Health: U.S. interagency officials and AU Commissioner for Health, Humanitarian Affairs, and Social Development Minata Samate Cessouma discussed health capacity building in Africa and operationalizing Africa CDC&#8217;s Regional Collaborating Centers. Ensuring strong systems and infrastructure, including National Public Health Institutes is vital to prevent, detect, and respondto future infectious disease threats and improve the health of our global citizens. Participants also discussed COVID-19 response efforts and highlighted U.S. investments in the health sector, including through PEPFAR and other programs.</p>
<p>It was discussed to build upon existing public health assets including those for combatting HIV, TB, and malaria, in response to the COVID-19 pandemic and other future disease threats. Participants acknowledged the importance of the operationalization of the Africa Medicines Agency (AMA).</p>
<p>Climate: Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica Medina underscored U.S. support for the AUC Africa Continental Climate Change and Resilient Development Strategy through U.S. programs including PREPARE, the President&#8217;s Emergency Plan for Adaptation and Resilience. U.S. and AUC officials discussed Africa’s priorities for COP27, which will be hosted by Africa in November 2022, especially just transitional and sustainable funding. The AU plays a leading role in advancing continental implementation of global climate commitments to keep the global temperature from rising beyond 1.5 degrees Celsius. Participants also discussed the nexus of climate and food security and food systems in the context of the AU’s theme on Nutrition and Food Security for 2022.</p>
<p>Economic Growth: Deputy Assistant Secretary Akunna Cook and AUC Commissioner for Economic Development, Tourism, Trade, Industry, and Minerals Albert Muchanga</p>
<p>led a strategic discussion on inclusive economic growth and investment opportunities. Noting the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on economies in the region, officials discussed the importance of spurring economic growth as a response to the pandemic. Officials reaffirmed U.S. support for the AfCFTA and other Agenda 2063 programs and projects to achieve sustainable economic development, build regional value chains, and increase both competitiveness and investment opportunities for mutual benefit. Participants discussed the importance of engaging with the private sector to increase trade and investment with Africa in pursuit of inclusive economic development, including by enhancing AGOA beyond its current framework.</p>
<p>Peace and Security: Special Assistant to the President and National Security Council Senior Director for Africa Dana Banks, Assistant Secretary of State for African Affairs Molly Phee, and AUC Commissioner for Political Affairs, Peace and Security Bankole Adeoye outlined the shared principles that underpin the U.S.-AUC security relationship. They discussed the importance of concrete action to address threats to democracy, including recent coups and military takeovers, lack of respect for constitutional term limits, and growing negative influence around the world.</p>
<p>Officials emphasized that these negative trends across the continent undermine the foundational principles of the AU, including the promotion of democratic ideals. U.S. and AU officials share the vision that the AU becomes the continental security guarantor, promoting peace and democracy through an operationalized and sustainable African Peace and Security Architecture (APSA) and African Governance Architecture. Additionally, the APSA provides a vital platform for preventing conflict, including in addressing the governance shortfalls fueling conflict and creating vulnerabilities exploited by terrorists, insurgencies, and international criminal networks. Participants affirmed their commitment to intensifying efforts to strengthen vital and inclusive democratic institutions and promote good governance as the most effective way to address the needs and aspirations of African citizens for a healthier, more peaceful, and more prosperous future.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
