<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 20:04:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Travel to Belgium, Poland, Moldova, Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-belgium-poland-moldova-latvia-lithuania-and-estonia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 19:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319768</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Belgium, Poland, Moldova, Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia from March 3 to 8, 2022.  The trip continues extensive consultations and coordination with our NATO Allies and European partners about the Russian Federation’s continued premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken will begin his trip in Brussels, Belgium where he will participate in a NATO Foreign Ministerial, meet with EU counterparts, participate in a G7 Ministerial Meeting, and hold additional meetings with partners to discuss the global response to Russia’s invasion, including Allies’ and partners’ continued coordination on imposing massive consequences and severe economic costs on Russia.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Poland on March 5, where he will meet with Polish leaders, including Foreign Minister Zbigniew Rau, to discuss further security assistance in the face of Russia’s continued aggression and unprovoked attack on Ukraine.  He will also thank Poland for generously welcoming hundreds of thousands of displaced persons from Ukraine and discuss how the United States can augment humanitarian assistance efforts for those fleeing Putin’s war.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Chisinau, Moldova to meet with President Maia Sandu, Prime Minister Natalia Gavrilita, and Foreign Minister Nicu Popescu.  During his stop, the Secretary will discuss support for Moldova’s efforts to receive and assist refugees fleeing Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, as well as U.S. support for Moldova’s democracy, sovereignty, and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Vilnius, Lithuania on March 6 to meet with President Gitanas Nauseda, Prime Minister Ingrida Simonyte, and Foreign Minister Gabrielius Landsbergis. On March 7, the Secretary will travel to Riga, Latvia, to meet with President Egils Levits, Prime Minister Krisjanis Karins, and Foreign Minister Edgars Rinkevics. He will travel to Tallinn, Estonia, on March 8 to meet with President Alar Karis, Prime Minister Kaja Kallas, and Foreign Minister Eva-Maria Liimets. During all three stops, he will discuss joint efforts to support Ukraine, strengthen NATO’s deterrence and defense, promote democracy and human rights, and pursue deeper economic and energy cooperation with our Baltic Allies.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Belgium, Poland, Moldova, Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia from March 3 to 8, 2022.  The trip continues extensive consultations and coordination with our NATO Allies and European partners about the Russian Federation’s continued premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken will begin his trip in Brussels, Belgium where he will participate in a NATO Foreign Ministerial, meet with EU counterparts, participate in a G7 Ministerial Meeting, and hold additional meetings with partners to discuss the global response to Russia’s invasion, including Allies’ and partners’ continued coordination on imposing massive consequences and severe economic costs on Russia.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Poland on March 5, where he will meet with Polish leaders, including Foreign Minister Zbigniew Rau, to discuss further security assistance in the face of Russia’s continued aggression and unprovoked attack on Ukraine.  He will also thank Poland for generously welcoming hundreds of thousands of displaced persons from Ukraine and discuss how the United States can augment humanitarian assistance efforts for those fleeing Putin’s war.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Chisinau, Moldova to meet with President Maia Sandu, Prime Minister Natalia Gavrilita, and Foreign Minister Nicu Popescu.  During his stop, the Secretary will discuss support for Moldova’s efforts to receive and assist refugees fleeing Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, as well as U.S. support for Moldova’s democracy, sovereignty, and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Vilnius, Lithuania on March 6 to meet with President Gitanas Nauseda, Prime Minister Ingrida Simonyte, and Foreign Minister Gabrielius Landsbergis. On March 7, the Secretary will travel to Riga, Latvia, to meet with President Egils Levits, Prime Minister Krisjanis Karins, and Foreign Minister Edgars Rinkevics. He will travel to Tallinn, Estonia, on March 8 to meet with President Alar Karis, Prime Minister Kaja Kallas, and Foreign Minister Eva-Maria Liimets. During all three stops, he will discuss joint efforts to support Ukraine, strengthen NATO’s deterrence and defense, promote democracy and human rights, and pursue deeper economic and energy cooperation with our Baltic Allies.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Saudi Foreign Minister Prince Faisal bin Farhan Al Saud</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-saudi-foreign-minister-prince-faisal-bin-farhan-al-saud-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 17:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with the Foreign Minister of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, Prince Faisal bin Farhan Al Saud, about Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified attack against Ukraine, the importance of respecting the UN Charter’s principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity of states, and coordinating a strong international response in support of Ukrainian sovereignty.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with the Foreign Minister of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, Prince Faisal bin Farhan Al Saud, about Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified attack against Ukraine, the importance of respecting the UN Charter’s principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity of states, and coordinating a strong international response in support of Ukrainian sovereignty.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-Turkmenistan Annual Bilateral Consultations</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-turkmenistan-annual-bilateral-consultations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 17:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319608</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, virtual United States-Turkmenistan Annual Bilateral Consultations (ABCs) concluded after two days of productive discussions.  A senior U.S. delegation, led by Assistant Secretary of State Donald Lu, hosted Foreign Minister Rashid Meredov and the senior Turkmen delegation.</p>
<p>The ABCs began in 2009 so that our governments could discuss important policy issues. They continue to serve that important role, even as the global and regional situation have evolved.</p>
<p>During the consultations, the U.S. delegation reinforced support for the independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity of Turkmenistan and reiterated our shared commitment to peace, prosperity, and security in Central Asia through the C5+1 diplomatic platform.  The U.S. delegation reiterated the importance of condemning Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine and of maintaining solidarity with the people of Ukraine.  The delegations discussed a wide range of bilateral and regional issues including cooperation on strengthening border security, counternarcotics, and counterterrorism, as well as the need for progress on human rights, including freedom of religion or belief, labor issues, and education opportunities.  Both delegations also discussed their growing engagement on climate action, trade and business, women’s economic empowerment, and regional connectivity of energy resources.</p>
<p>The United States looks forward to strengthening our efforts with Turkmenistan in all of these important areas and deepening the friendship between our peoples.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, virtual United States-Turkmenistan Annual Bilateral Consultations (ABCs) concluded after two days of productive discussions.  A senior U.S. delegation, led by Assistant Secretary of State Donald Lu, hosted Foreign Minister Rashid Meredov and the senior Turkmen delegation.</p>
<p>The ABCs began in 2009 so that our governments could discuss important policy issues. They continue to serve that important role, even as the global and regional situation have evolved.</p>
<p>During the consultations, the U.S. delegation reinforced support for the independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity of Turkmenistan and reiterated our shared commitment to peace, prosperity, and security in Central Asia through the C5+1 diplomatic platform.  The U.S. delegation reiterated the importance of condemning Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine and of maintaining solidarity with the people of Ukraine.  The delegations discussed a wide range of bilateral and regional issues including cooperation on strengthening border security, counternarcotics, and counterterrorism, as well as the need for progress on human rights, including freedom of religion or belief, labor issues, and education opportunities.  Both delegations also discussed their growing engagement on climate action, trade and business, women’s economic empowerment, and regional connectivity of energy resources.</p>
<p>The United States looks forward to strengthening our efforts with Turkmenistan in all of these important areas and deepening the friendship between our peoples.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with Indonesian Foreign Minister Marsudi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-indonesian-foreign-minister-marsudi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 14:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319433</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Indonesian Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi.  The Deputy Secretary condemned Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine and thanked the Government of Indonesia for cosponsoring the UN General Assembly resolution on Ukraine.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Marsudi also emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Indonesia Strategic Partnership and discussed ways to ensure the success of the upcoming U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Indonesian Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi.  The Deputy Secretary condemned Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine and thanked the Government of Indonesia for cosponsoring the UN General Assembly resolution on Ukraine.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Marsudi also emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Indonesia Strategic Partnership and discussed ways to ensure the success of the upcoming U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Mexican Foreign Secretary Ebrard</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-mexican-foreign-secretary-ebrard-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 01:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Mexican Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard. Secretary Blinken noted Mexico’s strong statements in support of Ukraine and in defense of the UN Charter in its Security Council and General Assembly remarks and as a part of the OAS Joint Declaration in the wake of Russia’s premeditated and unprovoked invasion. The Secretary and Foreign Secretary reaffirmed both countries’ condemnation of Russia’s actions and called for Russia to cease all hostilities. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Ebrard also spoke about the renewed and vibrant U.S.-Mexico partnership and the advances in cooperation over the past year led by President Biden and President Lopez Obrador. Secretary Blinken reiterated his sincere appreciation for our strong partnership with Mexico as we work to advance democracy, economic prosperity, and security in North America and around the world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Mexican Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard. Secretary Blinken noted Mexico’s strong statements in support of Ukraine and in defense of the UN Charter in its Security Council and General Assembly remarks and as a part of the OAS Joint Declaration in the wake of Russia’s premeditated and unprovoked invasion. The Secretary and Foreign Secretary reaffirmed both countries’ condemnation of Russia’s actions and called for Russia to cease all hostilities. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Ebrard also spoke about the renewed and vibrant U.S.-Mexico partnership and the advances in cooperation over the past year led by President Biden and President Lopez Obrador. Secretary Blinken reiterated his sincere appreciation for our strong partnership with Mexico as we work to advance democracy, economic prosperity, and security in North America and around the world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ukraine’s Filing Against Russia at the International Court of Justice</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/ukraines-filing-against-russia-at-the-international-court-of-justice/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319299</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>On February 26, 2022, Ukraine filed an application at the International Court of Justice (ICJ) to initiate proceedings against the Russian Federation under the Convention on the Prevention and Punishment of the Crime of Genocide. Ukraine seeks to address Russia’s groundless claims that genocide has occurred in the Luhansk and Donetsk oblasts of Ukraine and establish that Russia has no lawful basis to take military action on the basis of those false claims. Ukraine has also requested the ICJ exercise its authority to indicate provisional measures to preserve Ukraine’s rights and limit the ongoing and irreparable harm to the Ukrainian people as well as Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity within its internationally recognized borders.</p>
<p>As the principal judicial organ of the United Nations, the ICJ has a vital role to play in the peaceful settlement of disputes. Ukraine also requested the Court call upon Russia to halt immediately all military actions in Ukraine pending the Court’s review. Today, in response to that request, the Court called on the Russian Federation to act in a manner that would allow any provisional measures ordered by the Court to have an actual impact. This is another clear indication that Russia must cease its military activities in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Considering the gravity of the crisis in Ukraine that has resulted from Russia’s unprovoked invasion, we trust the Court is taking into consideration the dire circumstances and rapidly unfolding events and hope that it will act with utmost urgency on Ukraine’s request for provisional measures.</p>
<p>Each day that Russia is unconstrained in its aggression is a day that brings more violence, suffering, death, and destruction in Ukraine. The United States stands with the people of Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>On February 26, 2022, Ukraine filed an application at the International Court of Justice (ICJ) to initiate proceedings against the Russian Federation under the Convention on the Prevention and Punishment of the Crime of Genocide. Ukraine seeks to address Russia’s groundless claims that genocide has occurred in the Luhansk and Donetsk oblasts of Ukraine and establish that Russia has no lawful basis to take military action on the basis of those false claims. Ukraine has also requested the ICJ exercise its authority to indicate provisional measures to preserve Ukraine’s rights and limit the ongoing and irreparable harm to the Ukrainian people as well as Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity within its internationally recognized borders.</p>
<p>As the principal judicial organ of the United Nations, the ICJ has a vital role to play in the peaceful settlement of disputes. Ukraine also requested the Court call upon Russia to halt immediately all military actions in Ukraine pending the Court’s review. Today, in response to that request, the Court called on the Russian Federation to act in a manner that would allow any provisional measures ordered by the Court to have an actual impact. This is another clear indication that Russia must cease its military activities in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Considering the gravity of the crisis in Ukraine that has resulted from Russia’s unprovoked invasion, we trust the Court is taking into consideration the dire circumstances and rapidly unfolding events and hope that it will act with utmost urgency on Ukraine’s request for provisional measures.</p>
<p>Each day that Russia is unconstrained in its aggression is a day that brings more violence, suffering, death, and destruction in Ukraine. The United States stands with the people of Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with Peruvian Foreign Minister Landa</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-peruvian-foreign-minister-landa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 23:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319290</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Peruvian Foreign Minister César Landa about our shared democratic values and opposition to Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. In addition to discussing opportunities to further strengthen Peru-U.S. relations, Deputy Secretary Sherman commended the Peruvian government for its leadership in condemning Russia’s actions, including its support of the February 25 Organization of American States’ joint declaration on Russia’s aggression. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Landa also discussed how Russia’s violation of international law and the territorial integrity and sovereignty of Ukraine undermines global stability and contradicts the values that bind our hemisphere. The Deputy Secretary congratulated the Foreign Minister on Peru’s designation as the host of APEC 2024 and welcomed the OECD council’s approval to open accession discussions for Peru.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Peruvian Foreign Minister César Landa about our shared democratic values and opposition to Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. In addition to discussing opportunities to further strengthen Peru-U.S. relations, Deputy Secretary Sherman commended the Peruvian government for its leadership in condemning Russia’s actions, including its support of the February 25 Organization of American States’ joint declaration on Russia’s aggression. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Landa also discussed how Russia’s violation of international law and the territorial integrity and sovereignty of Ukraine undermines global stability and contradicts the values that bind our hemisphere. The Deputy Secretary congratulated the Foreign Minister on Peru’s designation as the host of APEC 2024 and welcomed the OECD council’s approval to open accession discussions for Peru.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2022 International Narcotics Control Strategy Report Release</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/2022-international-narcotics-control-strategy-report-release/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 23:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State submitted the 2022 edition of the annual International Narcotics Control Strategy Report (INCSR) to Congress today. This two-volume, Congressionally-mandated report assesses foreign governments’ efforts to reduce illicit drug production, trafficking, and use as well as their work to counter drug trafficking-related money laundering. The INCSR was first published in 1986, and this edition covers calendar year 2021.</p>
<p>This year’s INCSR stresses that the opioid crisis remains a global challenge that requires urgent international action. Synthetic opioids, such as fentanyl, continue to claim far too many lives in the United States and represent a growing global threat. The report highlights not only increases in trafficking and abuse of fentanyl and other deadly synthetic opioids across the globe but also concerning levels of overseas production of cocaine, heroin, and methamphetamine. Reducing the global drug threat will require sustained political commitments from partner governments, supported by U.S. assistance, to target all the links in the supplier-to-consumer chain. This means curbing the production of illicit drugs, interdicting drug shipments, tackling illicit finance, and reducing drug demand everywhere.</p>
<p>Volume I of the INCSR, addressing Drugs and Chemical Control, provides an overview of 2021 drug control efforts undertaken by 63 countries. Volume II, Money Laundering, highlights the nature of drug trafficking-related money laundering – and specific vulnerabilities – in 80 countries and jurisdictions as well as these governments’ efforts to strengthen their anti-money laundering regimes.</p>
<p>The full text of INCSR Volumes I and II can be viewed at <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs-releases/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs-releases/</a>.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:INL-PAPD@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">INL-PAPD@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State submitted the 2022 edition of the annual International Narcotics Control Strategy Report (INCSR) to Congress today. This two-volume, Congressionally-mandated report assesses foreign governments’ efforts to reduce illicit drug production, trafficking, and use as well as their work to counter drug trafficking-related money laundering. The INCSR was first published in 1986, and this edition covers calendar year 2021.</p>
<p>This year’s INCSR stresses that the opioid crisis remains a global challenge that requires urgent international action. Synthetic opioids, such as fentanyl, continue to claim far too many lives in the United States and represent a growing global threat. The report highlights not only increases in trafficking and abuse of fentanyl and other deadly synthetic opioids across the globe but also concerning levels of overseas production of cocaine, heroin, and methamphetamine. Reducing the global drug threat will require sustained political commitments from partner governments, supported by U.S. assistance, to target all the links in the supplier-to-consumer chain. This means curbing the production of illicit drugs, interdicting drug shipments, tackling illicit finance, and reducing drug demand everywhere.</p>
<p>Volume I of the INCSR, addressing Drugs and Chemical Control, provides an overview of 2021 drug control efforts undertaken by 63 countries. Volume II, Money Laundering, highlights the nature of drug trafficking-related money laundering – and specific vulnerabilities – in 80 countries and jurisdictions as well as these governments’ efforts to strengthen their anti-money laundering regimes.</p>
<p>The full text of INCSR Volumes I and II can be viewed at <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs-releases/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs-releases/</a>.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:INL-PAPD@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">INL-PAPD@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Restarting the Direct Access Program for U.S.-Affiliated Iraqis (Iraqi P-2 Program)</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/restarting-the-direct-access-program-for-u-s-affiliated-iraqis-iraqi-p-2-program/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 23:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319280</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State is restarting the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program (USRAP) Direct Access Program for U.S.-Affiliated Iraqis (Iraqi P-2 Program). The United States is committed to ensuring those who sacrificed their own safety for our collective interests have an opportunity to seek refuge in the United States. This includes Iraqis who have served alongside U.S. service members.</p>
<p>After an extensive review, we have resumed case processing for a select number of Iraqi P-2 cases that had been previously suspended during our review of the program. In coordination with the Department of Homeland Security, we will continue to review and process all other existing Iraqi P-2 cases that can move forward as well as accept new applications to the program.</p>
<p>During our review of the Iraqi P-2 Program, we identified and resolved the issues that led to our suspension of the program in January of 2021. We are committed to ensuring that only bona fide and qualified Iraqis who supported U.S. efforts in Iraq are considered for this important humanitarian program.</p>
<p>All refugees undergo the highest level of security screening and vetting, including extensive interviews and the vetting of biographic and biometric information. Only after an applicant has cleared all security vetting can they be deemed eligible for admission to the United States. In the admission of refugees to the United States, the safety and security of the American people is our highest priority.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State is restarting the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program (USRAP) Direct Access Program for U.S.-Affiliated Iraqis (Iraqi P-2 Program). The United States is committed to ensuring those who sacrificed their own safety for our collective interests have an opportunity to seek refuge in the United States. This includes Iraqis who have served alongside U.S. service members.</p>
<p>After an extensive review, we have resumed case processing for a select number of Iraqi P-2 cases that had been previously suspended during our review of the program. In coordination with the Department of Homeland Security, we will continue to review and process all other existing Iraqi P-2 cases that can move forward as well as accept new applications to the program.</p>
<p>During our review of the Iraqi P-2 Program, we identified and resolved the issues that led to our suspension of the program in January of 2021. We are committed to ensuring that only bona fide and qualified Iraqis who supported U.S. efforts in Iraq are considered for this important humanitarian program.</p>
<p>All refugees undergo the highest level of security screening and vetting, including extensive interviews and the vetting of biographic and biometric information. Only after an applicant has cleared all security vetting can they be deemed eligible for admission to the United States. In the admission of refugees to the United States, the safety and security of the American people is our highest priority.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Romania Signs the Artemis Accords</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/romania-signs-the-artemis-accords/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 19:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319190</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>At a virtual ceremony, Romania became the 16th nation to sign the Artemis Accords. President and CEO of the Romanian Space Agency Marius-Ioan Piso signed the Accords on behalf of Romania. His actions were witnessed and welcomed by NASA Administrator Bill Nelson, U.S. Embassy in Romania Chargé d’affaires, a.i. David Muniz, and Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Jennifer R. Littlejohn.</p>
<p>The Artemis Accords are a set of nonbinding commitments, grounded in the Outer Space Treaty of 1967, to facilitate the peaceful and safe exploration of outer space.  The Artemis Accords lay out certain principles to guide civil space actors, among them: peaceful purposes, transparency, interoperability, commitment to emergency assistance, registration of space objects, release of scientific data, deconfliction of activities, protection of space heritage, and mitigation of orbital debris, including spacecraft disposal.</p>
<p>The other signatories of the Artemis Accords are Australia, Brazil, Canada, Israel, Italy, Japan, the Republic of Korea, Luxembourg, Mexico, New Zealand, Poland, Ukraine, United Arab Emirates, United Kingdom, and the United States.</p>
<p>For more information, contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov</a>.</p>
<div id="m_2794387698254320110mail_footer"></div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>At a virtual ceremony, Romania became the 16th nation to sign the Artemis Accords. President and CEO of the Romanian Space Agency Marius-Ioan Piso signed the Accords on behalf of Romania. His actions were witnessed and welcomed by NASA Administrator Bill Nelson, U.S. Embassy in Romania Chargé d’affaires, a.i. David Muniz, and Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Jennifer R. Littlejohn.</p>
<p>The Artemis Accords are a set of nonbinding commitments, grounded in the Outer Space Treaty of 1967, to facilitate the peaceful and safe exploration of outer space.  The Artemis Accords lay out certain principles to guide civil space actors, among them: peaceful purposes, transparency, interoperability, commitment to emergency assistance, registration of space objects, release of scientific data, deconfliction of activities, protection of space heritage, and mitigation of orbital debris, including spacecraft disposal.</p>
<p>The other signatories of the Artemis Accords are Australia, Brazil, Canada, Israel, Italy, Japan, the Republic of Korea, Luxembourg, Mexico, New Zealand, Poland, Ukraine, United Arab Emirates, United Kingdom, and the United States.</p>
<p>For more information, contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov</a>.</p>
<div id="m_2794387698254320110mail_footer"></div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
