<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 14:09:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Department of State Offers Reward for Information to Bring Three Irish Transnational Criminals to Justice</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/department-of-state-offers-reward-for-information-to-bring-three-irish-transnational-criminals-to-justice/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 12:27:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333527</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State is announcing rewards of up to $5 million for information leading to each of the arrests and/or convictions of Irish transnational organized criminal Christopher Vincent Kinahan and his two sons, Daniel Joseph Kinahan and Christopher Kinahan, Jr.<u>,</u> for participating in, or conspiring to participate in, transnational organized crime.  After initially distributing South American cocaine and heroin in Ireland, the Kinahans later expanded their narcotics trafficking organization to include the United Kingdom and then throughout mainland Europe.  In addition to narcotics trafficking, the Kinahans have engaged in money laundering, firearms trafficking, and murder.</p>
<p>Today’s reward offer announcement complements the Department of Treasury’s announcement of sanctions against the Kinahans pursuant to Executive Order 14059, <i>Imposing Sanctions on Foreign Persons Involved in the Global Illicit Drug Trade. </i>The reward is offered jointly with the An Garda Síochana (AGS) in Ireland and the National Crime Agency (NCA) in the United Kingdom. Together with the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA), these agencies will work to combat drug trafficking and transnational crime by the Kinahan Transnational Criminal Organization wherever it exists.</p>
<p>This reward is offered under the Department of State’s Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program (TOCRP).  The TOCRP and Narcot<wbr />ics Rewards Program (NRP) have helped bring more than 75 transnational criminals and major narcotics traffickers to justice since the inception of the NRP in 1986.  The Department has paid more than $135 million in rewards under these programs for information leading to apprehensions and convictions.</p>
<p>The Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs manages the TOCRP in close coordination with federal law enforcement partners and other U.S. government agencies.  These actions demonstrate the Department’s commitment to supporting law enforcement efforts to bring transnational criminals to justice.</p>
<p>For more information on the individuals listed above and the NRP and TOCRP, please see <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs/inl-rewards-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTIuNTYyNzY2NzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1LW9mLWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtbmFyY290aWNzLWFuZC1sYXctZW5mb3JjZW1lbnQtYWZmYWlycy9pbmwtcmV3YXJkcy1wcm9ncmFtLyJ9.-l-2wo-ZLZhu_S-zmvLRUYEzCtyH10ouiqRa58kBYkE/s/2171565732/br/129667581271-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649852470627000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3el3fUnkbevB9e2kONcuIA">https://www.state.gov/<wbr />bureau-of-international-<wbr />narcotics-and-law-enforcement-<wbr />affairs/inl-rewards-program/</a><u>.</u></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State is announcing rewards of up to $5 million for information leading to each of the arrests and/or convictions of Irish transnational organized criminal Christopher Vincent Kinahan and his two sons, Daniel Joseph Kinahan and Christopher Kinahan, Jr.<u>,</u> for participating in, or conspiring to participate in, transnational organized crime.  After initially distributing South American cocaine and heroin in Ireland, the Kinahans later expanded their narcotics trafficking organization to include the United Kingdom and then throughout mainland Europe.  In addition to narcotics trafficking, the Kinahans have engaged in money laundering, firearms trafficking, and murder.</p>
<p>Today’s reward offer announcement complements the Department of Treasury’s announcement of sanctions against the Kinahans pursuant to Executive Order 14059, <i>Imposing Sanctions on Foreign Persons Involved in the Global Illicit Drug Trade. </i>The reward is offered jointly with the An Garda Síochana (AGS) in Ireland and the National Crime Agency (NCA) in the United Kingdom. Together with the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA), these agencies will work to combat drug trafficking and transnational crime by the Kinahan Transnational Criminal Organization wherever it exists.</p>
<p>This reward is offered under the Department of State’s Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program (TOCRP).  The TOCRP and Narcot<wbr />ics Rewards Program (NRP) have helped bring more than 75 transnational criminals and major narcotics traffickers to justice since the inception of the NRP in 1986.  The Department has paid more than $135 million in rewards under these programs for information leading to apprehensions and convictions.</p>
<p>The Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs manages the TOCRP in close coordination with federal law enforcement partners and other U.S. government agencies.  These actions demonstrate the Department’s commitment to supporting law enforcement efforts to bring transnational criminals to justice.</p>
<p>For more information on the individuals listed above and the NRP and TOCRP, please see <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureau-of-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-affairs/inl-rewards-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTIuNTYyNzY2NzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1LW9mLWludGVybmF0aW9uYWwtbmFyY290aWNzLWFuZC1sYXctZW5mb3JjZW1lbnQtYWZmYWlycy9pbmwtcmV3YXJkcy1wcm9ncmFtLyJ9.-l-2wo-ZLZhu_S-zmvLRUYEzCtyH10ouiqRa58kBYkE/s/2171565732/br/129667581271-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649852470627000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3el3fUnkbevB9e2kONcuIA">https://www.state.gov/<wbr />bureau-of-international-<wbr />narcotics-and-law-enforcement-<wbr />affairs/inl-rewards-program/</a><u>.</u></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fourth Annual U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/fourth-annual-u-s-india-22-ministerial-dialogue/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 04:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333498</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and India on the occasion of the Fourth Annual U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue in 2022.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken and Secretary of Defense Lloyd J. Austin III welcomed Minister of Defence Rajnath Singh and Minister of External Affairs Dr. S. Jaishankar to Washington, D.C., on April 11, 2022, for the fourth U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue. The Dialogue was preceded by a virtual meeting between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and President Joseph Biden.</p>
<p>As natural and trusted partners celebrating 75 years of diplomatic relations between the United States and independent India, with a shared commitment to democracy and pluralism, a multifaceted bilateral agenda, and growing convergence of strategic interests, both countries seek to continue to promote a resilient, rules-based international order that safeguards sovereignty and territorial integrity, upholds democratic values, and promotes peace and prosperity for all.</p>
<p>Building upon the September 2021 meeting between President Biden and Prime Minister Modi, and their respective participation in Summits related to COVID-19, climate, infrastructure and supply chain resilience, the Ministers reaffirmed the importance of the U.S.-India Comprehensive Global Strategic Partnership to international peace and security.</p>
<p><em>Global Partnership and Indo-Pacific Cooperation</em></p>
<p>The Ministers reviewed mutual efforts to respond to the worsening humanitarian crisis in Ukraine and assessed its broader implications. They urged an immediate cessation of hostilities. The Ministers unequivocally condemned civilian deaths.  They underscored that the contemporary global order has been built on the UN Charter, respect for international law, and the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states.</p>
<p>Recalling the inaugural virtual Quad Leaders’ Summit in March 2021, the in-person Quad Leaders’ Summit in September 2021 in Washington, the February 2022 Quad Foreign Ministers’ meeting in Melbourne, and looking forward to the next Quad Leaders’ Summit in Tokyo in 2022, the Ministers reaffirmed their commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific in which the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states are respected, and countries are free from military, economic, and political coercion. They further reaffirmed their dedication to promoting regional stability and prosperity, with an inclusive regional architecture, abiding by the rule of law, the freedom of navigation and overflight, peaceful resolution of disputes, and ASEAN centrality. They also reiterated the importance of adherence to international law to meet challenges to the rules-based order, including in the South China Sea.</p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the progress made in the last year on developing a positive and constructive agenda for the Quad to deliver peace and prosperity to the region in pursuance of their shared vision for a free, open, and inclusive Indo-Pacific. The Ministers reiterated their commitment to the take forward the initiatives announced by the Leaders, to empower the Quad as a force for global good for the Indo-Pacific region and welcomed ongoing discussions in the Quad Working Groups on vaccines, climate change, infrastructure, space, cyber security, and critical and emerging technologies for delivering practical and tangible benefits to the region.</p>
<p>Welcoming the remarkable progress made under the Quad Vaccine Partnership to augment the manufacturing capacity of the Biological E facility in India, supported by the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC), the Ministers committed to expedite delivery of the first batch of vaccines to countries of the Indo-Pacific and beyond and to diversify the basket of vaccines in the context of changes in the global demand and supply landscape.</p>
<p>Following up on the October 2021 virtual meeting of the Foreign Ministers of India, Israel, the United Arab Emirates, and the United States, the Ministers welcomed the opportunity to enhance engagement in this forum on shared priorities such as food security, clean energy, waste management, and infrastructure development.</p>
<p>The United States congratulated India for its significant contributions as a member of the United Nations Security Council (UNSC) for the term 2021-2022. In this context, the United States expressed its appreciation for India’s leadership as the Chair of the three Committees of the Security Council: the 1988 Taliban Sanctions Committee, the 1970 Libya Sanctions Committee and the 1373 Counter Terrorism Committee.</p>
<p>The Ministers reiterated their commitment to work together in close coordination at the UNSC and in international organizations. The United States reaffirmed its continued support for India’s permanent membership in a reformed UNSC and for India’s entry to the Nuclear Suppliers’ Group.</p>
<p>Considering growing national security threats from both state and non-state malicious cyber actors, the Ministers recognized the importance of an open, interoperable, secure, and reliable Internet and stable cyberspace.  Both sides reaffirmed the 2021 reports of the UN Open Ended Working Group and the UN Group of Governmental Experts, which articulate a framework of responsible state behavior in cyberspace and committed to work together in future multilateral negotiations to encourage States to implement the framework. They confirmed their intent to work closely as part of ongoing efforts to counter the use of information communications technologies for criminal purposes.</p>
<p>Acknowledging India’s distinguished history of leading peacekeeping missions, the United States welcomed India’s commitment to participate in multilateral peacekeeping training in 2022, expand joint-capacity building efforts with third-country partners, and launch a new joint National Investigation Officers Training of Trainers course in partnership with the United Nations.</p>
<p>The Ministers called on the Taliban to abide by UNSC Resolution 2593 (2021), which demands that Afghan territory must never again be used to threaten or attack any country or to shelter or train terrorists, or to plan or finance terrorist attacks.  The Ministers urged the Taliban to adhere to these and all other commitments; respect the human rights of all Afghans, including women, children, and members of minority groups; and uphold freedom of travel. They also emphasized the importance of an inclusive Afghan government and unhindered access for the United Nations and its implementing partners to deliver humanitarian assistance. The Ministers recommitted to close consultations on Afghanistan to help facilitate an inclusive and peaceful future for all Afghans.</p>
<p>The Ministers called for the cessation of violence in Myanmar, the release of all those arbitrarily detained, and a swift return to the path of democracy and inclusive governance. They also called for urgent implementation of the ASEAN Five Point Consensus.</p>
<p>The Ministers recalled U.S. and Indian initiatives announced during the first Summit for Democracy and looked forward to further cooperation in the current Year of Action ahead of the next Summit.</p>
<p>Leveraging the recently extended U.S.-India Statement of Guiding Principles on Triangular Cooperation for Global Development, the Ministers called for greater cooperation to address global development challenges around the world, including in Asia and Africa.  In this regard, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and India’s Development Partnership Administration (DPA) have decided to expand triangular development activity with third countries.  In addition, the Ministers looked forward to continuing discussions on the establishment of the U.S.-India Gandhi-King Development Foundation.</p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the 2021 Indo-Pacific Business Forum, co-hosted by the United States and India, and convened for the first time in South Asia. They affirmed their interest in expanding efforts to promote sustainable and durable infrastructure across the Indo-Pacific and affirmed they would remain engaged through the Blue Dot Network and Build Back Better World (B3W) Initiative. The United States appreciated the opportunity for USAID to co-chair the Coalition for Disaster Resilient Infrastructure (CDRI)’s Governing Council.  Both sides reaffirmed plans to collaborate through CDRI in supporting countries most impacted by natural disasters, including those resulting from climate change.</p>
<p>The United States welcomed India’s announcement at COP26 to intensify its climate action including its long-term vision to achieve net-zero emissions by 2070.  Both sides looked forward to further cooperation to support negotiations on ocean plastic pollution launched by the UN Environment Assembly (UNEA 5.2) in February 2022. India welcomed the United States’ signing of the Framework Agreement of the International Solar Alliance (ISA) and looked forward to supporting projects to expand the availability of reliable and affordable solar power including the $500 million investment by the DFC in First Solar’s facility to produce solar panels in India.</p>
<p>The United States conveyed its full support to India’s upcoming G20 Presidency from December 2022 to November 2023.  In this context, the Ministers reiterated their commitment to work closely on international security, social, and economic issues of global interest and impact.</p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the March 21, 2022, Foreign Office Consultations, and affirmed that closer regional and multilateral coordination was integral to the bilateral Comprehensive Global Strategic Partnership. <em> </em>The Ministers look forward to reconvening the Global Issues Forum to further exchange perspectives on issues of mutual interest.</p>
<p><em>Mutual Prosperity, Innovation, and Resilient Supply Chains</em></p>
<p>The Ministers underlined the importance of strengthening the commercial and economic pillar of the U.S.-India partnership to advance economic growth and deliver mutual prosperity for both countries. They applauded the rebound in bilateral trade between the two countries over the last year, surpassing $113 billion in goods. They welcomed the 12<sup>th</sup> Ministerial-level meeting of the U.S.-India Trade Policy Forum (TPF) and the renewal of Working Group discussions to expand bilateral trade, remove market access barriers, and improve ease of business.  They looked forward to both sides developing action plans that identify and prioritize the resolution of specific trade concerns to build on the progress made during the last TPF Ministerial meeting.</p>
<p>The Ministers reiterated the importance of a transparent and predictable business environment to facilitate private-sector investment. They looked forward to reconvening the U.S.-India Commercial Dialogue and the CEO Forum this year to enhance economic cooperation, boost commercial ties, and develop private-sector recommendations for both governments. The Ministers appreciated the discussions held during the eighth ministerial-level US-India Economic and Financial Partnership meeting in October 2021, which focused on continued cooperation on a range of subjects including financial regulatory and technical collaboration, multilateral engagement, climate finance, and anti-money laundering and combating the financing of terrorism. The United States appreciated recent economic reform initiatives in India, which help improve the ease of doing business, and efforts to accelerate the start-up and innovation sector.</p>
<p>The Ministers reaffirmed the vital role of secure, resilient, reliable, and diverse supply chains for Critical and Emerging Technologies (CET), and the need to enable regional and global innovation.  The Ministers decided to put in place a framework to advance cooperation in CET such as advanced communication technology, artificial intelligence, quantum science, STEM, semi-conductors and biotechnology.</p>
<p>The Ministers noted the substantial progress in negotiations for an Investment Incentive Agreement (IIA) between the Governments of India and the United States, which provides a framework for DFC to continue to expand its investment in India – for private sector-led projects in critical areas such as renewable energy, agriculture, healthcare, and SME financing. The Ministers encouraged negotiators to resolve remaining issues so that the IIA may be concluded as soon as possible.</p>
<p><em>Climate, Environment, and Clean Energy</em></p>
<p>The Ministers commended ongoing engagement under the two main tracks of the U.S.-India Climate and Clean Energy Agenda 2030 Partnership – the Climate Action and Finance Mobilization Dialogue (CAFMD) and the Strategic Clean Energy Partnership (SCEP) – to explore and identify low carbon pathways to develop and undertake joint research and development projects, mobilize finance, develop and promote green technologies, and enhance technical collaboration aimed at building on complementarities for facilitating energy transition. To this end, the Ministers affirmed the intent to work together for the exchange of best practices and development of technology transfer to enable the affordable deployment of clean and emerging energy technologies, including commercialization and scaling up of battery storage, offshore wind, green hydrogen, and rooftop solar technology in India.</p>
<p>Both sides welcomed the expanding cooperation between the energy sectors of both countries. Recognizing that access to energy must be affordable and reliable, they committed to work together bilaterally and at the global level towards these objectives. Noting that volatility in energy markets could threaten orderly and predictable global energy transition they welcomed initiatives taken by both countries to stabilize prices, including through the coordinated release from strategic petroleum reserves.</p>
<p>The Ministers expressed satisfaction on the progress made on different collaborative initiatives under the U.S.-India Civil Nuclear Energy Working Group and the Global Centre for Nuclear Energy Partnership Joint Working Group.  The Ministers noted ongoing negotiations between the Nuclear Power Corporation of India Limited (NPCIL) and Westinghouse Electric Company (WEC) for the construction of six nuclear reactors in India. They welcomed progress through consultations between the U.S. Department of Energy and India’s Department of Atomic Energy for facilitating opportunities for WEC to develop a techno-commercial offer for the Kovvada nuclear project. They also noted the ongoing discussion on developing next generation small modular reactor technologies in a collaborative mode for the domestic market as well as for export.</p>
<p>The Ministers also recognized the efforts of USAID and other U.S. agencies to support and augment production of clean and accessible energy and engage with private sector through its initiatives such as South Asia Regional Energy Partnership, Flexible Resources Initiative, and Smart Grid Knowledge Center.</p>
<p><em>Science, Technology, Cybersecurity, and Space</em></p>
<p>Reflecting on the positive science and technology cooperation between the two countries, the Ministers welcomed the announcement of a Joint Commission Meeting on Science and Technology in 2022, to discuss future science and technology collaboration.</p>
<p>The Ministers applauded the recent and upcoming meetings of the U.S.-India Cyber Dialogue and the Information and Communication Technology (ICT) Working Group to deepen cybersecurity cooperation. They strongly condemned ransomware and other cyber-related crimes and recognized the need to bolster protection of critical networks and infrastructure.</p>
<p>Recalling their countries’ strong tradition of space exploration and endeavors, the Ministers announced the conclusion of a Memorandum of Understanding on Space Situational Awareness and pledged to expand bilateral space cooperation, acknowledging the pivotal role international cooperation plays in the long-term sustainability and safety of the outer-space environment. They applauded the ongoing development of the NASA-ISRO Synthetic Aperture Radar (NISAR) satellite, planned for launch from India in 2023.  The NISAR mission will collect data vital to tackling the climate crisis. The Ministers also looked forward to the convening of the next India-U.S. Civil Space Joint Working Group in 2022.</p>
<p>The Ministers expressed appreciation for the continued cooperation between the U.S. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) and India’s Ministry of Earth Science (MoES) and ISRO in areas such as ocean and fisheries science, meteorology, and earth observation to better understand climate change and save lives through improved weather and ocean modeling and information sharing.  In support of climate and disaster resilience goals, the United States and India are driving advancements in climate and monsoon prediction and forecasting through collaborative work in the Indian Ocean.  As part of that work, MoES recently launched a joint data portal providing near-real-time public data from the NOAA Research Moored Array for African-Asian-Australian Monsoon Analysis and Prediction (RAMA) and the MoES Ocean Moored Buoy Network for the Northern Indian Ocean (OMNI).  The data supports improved monsoon prediction capabilities and sub-seasonal weather forecasting including for the United States, whose weather and atmosphere are impacted by systems that develop in the Indian Ocean. The Ministers also welcomed expansion of collaboration between NOAA and MoES under EKAMSAT program (Enhancing Knowledge of the Arabian Sea Marine Environment through Science and Advanced Technology).</p>
<p><em>Global Health</em></p>
<p>The Ministers recognized the pivotal role of the U.S.-India partnership in combating the COVID-19 pandemic and other contemporary global health challenges.  They welcomed joint U.S.-India leadership under the COVID-19 Global Action Plan to get shots in arms, diversify and secure global supply chains, build capacity for health care workers, and scientific cooperation.  They appreciated U.S.-India collaboration in vaccine R&amp;D and production including the Janssen and Corbevax vaccines being manufactured by Biological E., and the Novovax vaccines by Serum Institute of India, and expressed appreciation that due to efforts to increase manufacturing, safe, effective, and affordable COVID vaccines are readily available to third countries, further strengthening global vaccination efforts. The Ministers reaffirmed their commitment to facilitate joint research and information sharing, and work together to address barriers to pandemic-related vaccines and medical production so that global supply chains for vaccines are more resilient, stable, and predictable.</p>
<p>Recalling the recent U.S.-India Health Dialogue, the Ministers commended our ongoing collaboration on biomedical research, strengthening regulatory procedures and pandemic preparedness. The Ministers welcomed the signing of an overarching Memorandum of Understanding between India’s Ministry of Health and Family Welfare (MoHFW) and the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (DHHS) to work together to strengthen public health preparedness and response by expanding training on disease surveillance, improve response to and containment of outbreaks, strengthen laboratory networks and diagnostics, enhance pan-respiratory disease surveillance, develop sub-national emergency operation centers, and integrate a “One Health” approach into all public health initiatives.</p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the renewal of our joint commitment to undertake collaborative research on infectious diseases of global health significance and conclude a Memorandum of Understanding to continue joint support for an Indo-U.S. International Centre for Excellence in Research between the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID) of National Institutes of Health (NIH) and the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR).</p>
<p>The Ministers also welcomed the launch of ICMR-NIH Clinical Research Fellowship program, under which clinicians from both sides can come to conduct research in laboratories in India and the United States. The Ministers welcomed a new regulatory partnership in furtherance of shrimp safety between the Food and Drug Administration and Marine Product Export Development Authority (MPEDA), and reaffirmed plans to finalize a Memorandum of Understanding to undertake further research on diabetes between the U.S. National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases and ICMR.</p>
<p>The Ministers looked forward to expansion of the USAID-supported COVID-19 Learning Exchange virtual platform, to include programs for more population groups and allow cities and health officials to share best practices to improve routine immunization, strengthen urban health, and launch an interactive web-based platform to enhance knowledge management and operational reach.</p>
<p><em>Defense and Security</em></p>
<p>The Ministers commended the significant and continuing progress in the U.S.-India Major Defense Partnership.  Drawing on the momentum from the U.S.-India Defense Policy Group meeting in October 2021, they reaffirmed their ambitions for building an advanced and comprehensive defense partnership in which the U.S. and Indian militaries coordinate closely together across all domains.</p>
<p>The Ministers acknowledged the importance of deepening collaboration in science and technology in the U.S.-India Joint Technical Group (JTG), and in evolving new defense domains, including space, artificial intelligence (AI), and cyber.  The Ministers underscored the importance of cooperation in space and welcomed plans to conduct an inaugural Defense Space Dialogue in 2022. They welcomed the second Defense Cyber Dialogue held in 2021 and look forward to the next round this year.  They decided to hold an inaugural AI Dialogue this year to harness opportunities for joint innovation and cooperation in new domains.  The Ministers also discussed additional training opportunities for our respective militaries, and the United States welcomed enhanced Indian participation in advanced courses across these emerging domains.</p>
<p>As information-sharing forms an important pillar of the U.S.-India defense cooperation, the Ministers underlined the importance of building a comprehensive framework under which our militaries are equipped to exchange information in real time across domains.  The Ministers welcomed progress made toward full implementation of the Basic Exchange and Cooperation Agreement (BECA) to support the exchange of geospatial information. The Ministers noted that information exchange and placement of liaison officers in each other’s military organizations will spur joint service cooperation between our militaries to support integrated and multi-domain cooperation.</p>
<p>Acknowledging that our navies have been a driving force in advancing the United States and India’s shared interests in the Indian Ocean Region and the wider Indo-Pacific, the Ministers discussed opportunities to further advance and deepen maritime cooperation, including in underwater domain awareness.</p>
<p>The United States also welcomed India’s decision to join the Combined Maritime Forces Task Force as an Associate Partner to expand multilateral cooperation in the Indian Ocean. The Ministers lauded the 2022 Indo-Pacific Military Health Exchange, which India and the United States co-hosted to bring together experts from 38 countries to discuss challenges and solutions to military medical issues. Both sides look forward to India’s co-hosting of the Indo-Pacific Armies Chiefs Conference (IPACC) and Indo-Pacific Armies Management Seminar (IPAMS) in 2023.</p>
<p>In support of the Indian military’s expanding operational reach and emerging opportunities for cooperation in the Indian Ocean and the wider region, the Ministers welcomed regular bilateral logistics operations such as replenishments at sea, air-to-air and ground-refueling and committed to increasing such cooperation, including through the Logistics Exchange Memorandum of Agreement (LEMOA).</p>
<p>Both sides reaffirmed the importance of regular bilateral and multilateral exercises, including the MALABAR exercise with inclusion of Australia, the tri-service TIGER TRIUMPH exercise, the multilateral MILAN naval exercise, the bilateral YUDH ABHYAS and VAJRA PRAHAR Army exercises, the bilateral COPE India air exercise, and Indian participation in RED FLAG. They supported increasing the scope and complexity of these exercises. They looked forward to deepening cooperation between the Special Forces of both countries.</p>
<p>Recognizing the importance of building robust private industry collaboration, the Ministers welcomed ongoing projects under the auspices of the U.S.-India Defense Technology and Trade Initiative (DTTI), including a project agreement to co-develop Air-Launched UAVs.  They called on both sides to consider additional DTTI projects, such as a counter-unmanned aerial systems (UAS) system and an Intelligence, Surveillance, Target Acquisition and Reconnaissance (ISTAR) platform.  They also lauded the rapid growth in bilateral defense trade over the past decade.</p>
<p>Seeking trusted and resilient defense supply chains, the Ministers welcomed the progress made towards implementation of the Industrial Security Agreement to facilitate collaboration on cutting edge defense technologies between industries. Both sides would explore and further promote the means to encourage reciprocal participation of U.S. and Indian vendors in each other’s defense supply chains. Acknowledging India’s focus on developing its domestic capabilities and helping to ensure reliable defense supplies, the Ministers committed to work closely across their respective governments on co-production, co-development, cooperative testing of advanced systems, investment promotion, and the development of Maintenance Repair and Overhaul (MRO) facilities in India. To further enhance defense industrial cooperation in the naval sector, both sides agreed to explore possibilities of utilizing the Indian shipyards for repair and maintenance of ships of the U.S. Maritime Sealift Command (MSC) to support mid-voyage repair of U.S. Naval ships.</p>
<p><em>Counterterrorism and Counter Narcotics</em></p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the convening of the 18th Meeting of the India-U.S. Joint Working Group on Counter Terrorism and the 4th Session of the India-U.S. Designations Dialogue in October 2021.  The Ministers strongly condemned any use of terrorist proxies and cross-border terrorism in all its forms and called for the perpetrators of the 26/11 Mumbai attack, and Pathankot attack, to be brought to justice.  They called for concerted action against all terrorist groups, including groups proscribed by the UNSC 1267 Sanctions Committee, such as al-Qa’ida, ISIS/Daesh, Lashkar-e-Tayyiba (LeT), and Jaish-e-Mohammad (JeM), and Hizb ul Mujahideen. The Ministers called on Pakistan to take immediate, sustained, and irreversible action to ensure that no territory under its control is used for terrorist attacks.  The Ministers committed to continued exchange of information about sanctions and designations against terror groups and individuals, countering violent radicalism, use of the Internet for terrorist purposes, and cross-border movement of terrorists.  The Ministers also emphasized the importance of upholding international standards on anti-money laundering and combating the financing of terrorism by all countries, consistent with FATF recommendations.</p>
<p>The Ministers also reaffirmed their support for the early adoption of a UN Comprehensive Convention on International Terrorism (CCIT) that advances and strengthens the framework for global cooperation and reinforces that no cause or grievance justifies terrorism.</p>
<p>Both sides looked forward to the next U.S.-India Counter Narcotics Working Group meeting in 2022 and enhancing cooperation through a bilateral Counter-Narcotics Framework to combat drug trafficking, illicit narcotics production, and precursor chemical supply chains.</p>
<p>Building upon the recent Senior Officials Meeting between the U.S. Department of Homeland Security and India’s Ministry of Home Affairs, both sides looked forward to reconvening a Ministerial meeting of the U.S.-India Homeland Security Dialogue in 2022.</p>
<p><em>Education and People-to-People Ties</em></p>
<p>Lauding the vibrant educational linkages between India and the United States, the Ministers reiterated their support to further strengthen cooperation in the field of education and skill development through joint collaborations and promote student and scholar mobility to build people-to-people linkages between the two countries.  In this regard, the ministers announced the intent to establish a new U.S.-India Education and Skills Development Working Group.  The Ministers also appreciated the contribution of the Fulbright-Nehru program in furthering the exchange of outstanding academics and professionals between both countries and the special role the four million strong Indian-American diaspora play in deepening U.S.-India relations.</p>
<p>Welcoming the resumption of regular air travel between the two countries and expressing hope that this would encourage tourism and business travel, the Ministers acknowledged that the movement of skilled professionals, students, entrepreneurs, investors, and business travelers between our countries plays an important role in catalyzing innovation and economic opportunity.  India welcomed the waiver, through December 31, 2022, of in-person visa interviews for applicants that were previously issued any type of visa and are now applying for certain nonimmigrant visa classifications, which include those for Persons in Specialty Occupation, Academic and Vocational Students, and Intracompany Transferees.  The Ministers underlined the importance of continued engagement on visa issues, welcomed the December 2021 meeting of the bilateral Consular Dialogue, and resolved to continue efforts to facilitate the reciprocal movement of professionals, businesspersons, skilled workers, experts, and scientific personnel.</p>
<p>The Ministers also acknowledged the importance of continued discussions on a Social Security Totalization Agreement and welcomed the opportunity to further engage on pursuing such an agreement.</p>
<p>Both sides looked forward to commencing a dialogue on contemporary issues related to women in the context of people to people linkages.</p>
<p>Recognizing the importance of protecting cultural heritage, the Ministers committed to work toward negotiating a Memorandum of Understanding that will deepen cooperation in this area and assist authorities in combatting the trade in cultural artifacts and facilitating their repatriation.</p>
<p>The United States thanked India for its support for the Defense POW/MIA Accounting Agency (DPAA) missions in India. The Ministers reiterated their commitment to future DPAA‎ missions.</p>
<p>India looks forward to hosting the next 2+2 Ministerial.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and India on the occasion of the Fourth Annual U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue in 2022.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken and Secretary of Defense Lloyd J. Austin III welcomed Minister of Defence Rajnath Singh and Minister of External Affairs Dr. S. Jaishankar to Washington, D.C., on April 11, 2022, for the fourth U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue. The Dialogue was preceded by a virtual meeting between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and President Joseph Biden.</p>
<p>As natural and trusted partners celebrating 75 years of diplomatic relations between the United States and independent India, with a shared commitment to democracy and pluralism, a multifaceted bilateral agenda, and growing convergence of strategic interests, both countries seek to continue to promote a resilient, rules-based international order that safeguards sovereignty and territorial integrity, upholds democratic values, and promotes peace and prosperity for all.</p>
<p>Building upon the September 2021 meeting between President Biden and Prime Minister Modi, and their respective participation in Summits related to COVID-19, climate, infrastructure and supply chain resilience, the Ministers reaffirmed the importance of the U.S.-India Comprehensive Global Strategic Partnership to international peace and security.</p>
<p><em>Global Partnership and Indo-Pacific Cooperation</em></p>
<p>The Ministers reviewed mutual efforts to respond to the worsening humanitarian crisis in Ukraine and assessed its broader implications. They urged an immediate cessation of hostilities. The Ministers unequivocally condemned civilian deaths.  They underscored that the contemporary global order has been built on the UN Charter, respect for international law, and the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states.</p>
<p>Recalling the inaugural virtual Quad Leaders’ Summit in March 2021, the in-person Quad Leaders’ Summit in September 2021 in Washington, the February 2022 Quad Foreign Ministers’ meeting in Melbourne, and looking forward to the next Quad Leaders’ Summit in Tokyo in 2022, the Ministers reaffirmed their commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific in which the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states are respected, and countries are free from military, economic, and political coercion. They further reaffirmed their dedication to promoting regional stability and prosperity, with an inclusive regional architecture, abiding by the rule of law, the freedom of navigation and overflight, peaceful resolution of disputes, and ASEAN centrality. They also reiterated the importance of adherence to international law to meet challenges to the rules-based order, including in the South China Sea.</p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the progress made in the last year on developing a positive and constructive agenda for the Quad to deliver peace and prosperity to the region in pursuance of their shared vision for a free, open, and inclusive Indo-Pacific. The Ministers reiterated their commitment to the take forward the initiatives announced by the Leaders, to empower the Quad as a force for global good for the Indo-Pacific region and welcomed ongoing discussions in the Quad Working Groups on vaccines, climate change, infrastructure, space, cyber security, and critical and emerging technologies for delivering practical and tangible benefits to the region.</p>
<p>Welcoming the remarkable progress made under the Quad Vaccine Partnership to augment the manufacturing capacity of the Biological E facility in India, supported by the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC), the Ministers committed to expedite delivery of the first batch of vaccines to countries of the Indo-Pacific and beyond and to diversify the basket of vaccines in the context of changes in the global demand and supply landscape.</p>
<p>Following up on the October 2021 virtual meeting of the Foreign Ministers of India, Israel, the United Arab Emirates, and the United States, the Ministers welcomed the opportunity to enhance engagement in this forum on shared priorities such as food security, clean energy, waste management, and infrastructure development.</p>
<p>The United States congratulated India for its significant contributions as a member of the United Nations Security Council (UNSC) for the term 2021-2022. In this context, the United States expressed its appreciation for India’s leadership as the Chair of the three Committees of the Security Council: the 1988 Taliban Sanctions Committee, the 1970 Libya Sanctions Committee and the 1373 Counter Terrorism Committee.</p>
<p>The Ministers reiterated their commitment to work together in close coordination at the UNSC and in international organizations. The United States reaffirmed its continued support for India’s permanent membership in a reformed UNSC and for India’s entry to the Nuclear Suppliers’ Group.</p>
<p>Considering growing national security threats from both state and non-state malicious cyber actors, the Ministers recognized the importance of an open, interoperable, secure, and reliable Internet and stable cyberspace.  Both sides reaffirmed the 2021 reports of the UN Open Ended Working Group and the UN Group of Governmental Experts, which articulate a framework of responsible state behavior in cyberspace and committed to work together in future multilateral negotiations to encourage States to implement the framework. They confirmed their intent to work closely as part of ongoing efforts to counter the use of information communications technologies for criminal purposes.</p>
<p>Acknowledging India’s distinguished history of leading peacekeeping missions, the United States welcomed India’s commitment to participate in multilateral peacekeeping training in 2022, expand joint-capacity building efforts with third-country partners, and launch a new joint National Investigation Officers Training of Trainers course in partnership with the United Nations.</p>
<p>The Ministers called on the Taliban to abide by UNSC Resolution 2593 (2021), which demands that Afghan territory must never again be used to threaten or attack any country or to shelter or train terrorists, or to plan or finance terrorist attacks.  The Ministers urged the Taliban to adhere to these and all other commitments; respect the human rights of all Afghans, including women, children, and members of minority groups; and uphold freedom of travel. They also emphasized the importance of an inclusive Afghan government and unhindered access for the United Nations and its implementing partners to deliver humanitarian assistance. The Ministers recommitted to close consultations on Afghanistan to help facilitate an inclusive and peaceful future for all Afghans.</p>
<p>The Ministers called for the cessation of violence in Myanmar, the release of all those arbitrarily detained, and a swift return to the path of democracy and inclusive governance. They also called for urgent implementation of the ASEAN Five Point Consensus.</p>
<p>The Ministers recalled U.S. and Indian initiatives announced during the first Summit for Democracy and looked forward to further cooperation in the current Year of Action ahead of the next Summit.</p>
<p>Leveraging the recently extended U.S.-India Statement of Guiding Principles on Triangular Cooperation for Global Development, the Ministers called for greater cooperation to address global development challenges around the world, including in Asia and Africa.  In this regard, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and India’s Development Partnership Administration (DPA) have decided to expand triangular development activity with third countries.  In addition, the Ministers looked forward to continuing discussions on the establishment of the U.S.-India Gandhi-King Development Foundation.</p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the 2021 Indo-Pacific Business Forum, co-hosted by the United States and India, and convened for the first time in South Asia. They affirmed their interest in expanding efforts to promote sustainable and durable infrastructure across the Indo-Pacific and affirmed they would remain engaged through the Blue Dot Network and Build Back Better World (B3W) Initiative. The United States appreciated the opportunity for USAID to co-chair the Coalition for Disaster Resilient Infrastructure (CDRI)’s Governing Council.  Both sides reaffirmed plans to collaborate through CDRI in supporting countries most impacted by natural disasters, including those resulting from climate change.</p>
<p>The United States welcomed India’s announcement at COP26 to intensify its climate action including its long-term vision to achieve net-zero emissions by 2070.  Both sides looked forward to further cooperation to support negotiations on ocean plastic pollution launched by the UN Environment Assembly (UNEA 5.2) in February 2022. India welcomed the United States’ signing of the Framework Agreement of the International Solar Alliance (ISA) and looked forward to supporting projects to expand the availability of reliable and affordable solar power including the $500 million investment by the DFC in First Solar’s facility to produce solar panels in India.</p>
<p>The United States conveyed its full support to India’s upcoming G20 Presidency from December 2022 to November 2023.  In this context, the Ministers reiterated their commitment to work closely on international security, social, and economic issues of global interest and impact.</p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the March 21, 2022, Foreign Office Consultations, and affirmed that closer regional and multilateral coordination was integral to the bilateral Comprehensive Global Strategic Partnership. <em> </em>The Ministers look forward to reconvening the Global Issues Forum to further exchange perspectives on issues of mutual interest.</p>
<p><em>Mutual Prosperity, Innovation, and Resilient Supply Chains</em></p>
<p>The Ministers underlined the importance of strengthening the commercial and economic pillar of the U.S.-India partnership to advance economic growth and deliver mutual prosperity for both countries. They applauded the rebound in bilateral trade between the two countries over the last year, surpassing $113 billion in goods. They welcomed the 12<sup>th</sup> Ministerial-level meeting of the U.S.-India Trade Policy Forum (TPF) and the renewal of Working Group discussions to expand bilateral trade, remove market access barriers, and improve ease of business.  They looked forward to both sides developing action plans that identify and prioritize the resolution of specific trade concerns to build on the progress made during the last TPF Ministerial meeting.</p>
<p>The Ministers reiterated the importance of a transparent and predictable business environment to facilitate private-sector investment. They looked forward to reconvening the U.S.-India Commercial Dialogue and the CEO Forum this year to enhance economic cooperation, boost commercial ties, and develop private-sector recommendations for both governments. The Ministers appreciated the discussions held during the eighth ministerial-level US-India Economic and Financial Partnership meeting in October 2021, which focused on continued cooperation on a range of subjects including financial regulatory and technical collaboration, multilateral engagement, climate finance, and anti-money laundering and combating the financing of terrorism. The United States appreciated recent economic reform initiatives in India, which help improve the ease of doing business, and efforts to accelerate the start-up and innovation sector.</p>
<p>The Ministers reaffirmed the vital role of secure, resilient, reliable, and diverse supply chains for Critical and Emerging Technologies (CET), and the need to enable regional and global innovation.  The Ministers decided to put in place a framework to advance cooperation in CET such as advanced communication technology, artificial intelligence, quantum science, STEM, semi-conductors and biotechnology.</p>
<p>The Ministers noted the substantial progress in negotiations for an Investment Incentive Agreement (IIA) between the Governments of India and the United States, which provides a framework for DFC to continue to expand its investment in India – for private sector-led projects in critical areas such as renewable energy, agriculture, healthcare, and SME financing. The Ministers encouraged negotiators to resolve remaining issues so that the IIA may be concluded as soon as possible.</p>
<p><em>Climate, Environment, and Clean Energy</em></p>
<p>The Ministers commended ongoing engagement under the two main tracks of the U.S.-India Climate and Clean Energy Agenda 2030 Partnership – the Climate Action and Finance Mobilization Dialogue (CAFMD) and the Strategic Clean Energy Partnership (SCEP) – to explore and identify low carbon pathways to develop and undertake joint research and development projects, mobilize finance, develop and promote green technologies, and enhance technical collaboration aimed at building on complementarities for facilitating energy transition. To this end, the Ministers affirmed the intent to work together for the exchange of best practices and development of technology transfer to enable the affordable deployment of clean and emerging energy technologies, including commercialization and scaling up of battery storage, offshore wind, green hydrogen, and rooftop solar technology in India.</p>
<p>Both sides welcomed the expanding cooperation between the energy sectors of both countries. Recognizing that access to energy must be affordable and reliable, they committed to work together bilaterally and at the global level towards these objectives. Noting that volatility in energy markets could threaten orderly and predictable global energy transition they welcomed initiatives taken by both countries to stabilize prices, including through the coordinated release from strategic petroleum reserves.</p>
<p>The Ministers expressed satisfaction on the progress made on different collaborative initiatives under the U.S.-India Civil Nuclear Energy Working Group and the Global Centre for Nuclear Energy Partnership Joint Working Group.  The Ministers noted ongoing negotiations between the Nuclear Power Corporation of India Limited (NPCIL) and Westinghouse Electric Company (WEC) for the construction of six nuclear reactors in India. They welcomed progress through consultations between the U.S. Department of Energy and India’s Department of Atomic Energy for facilitating opportunities for WEC to develop a techno-commercial offer for the Kovvada nuclear project. They also noted the ongoing discussion on developing next generation small modular reactor technologies in a collaborative mode for the domestic market as well as for export.</p>
<p>The Ministers also recognized the efforts of USAID and other U.S. agencies to support and augment production of clean and accessible energy and engage with private sector through its initiatives such as South Asia Regional Energy Partnership, Flexible Resources Initiative, and Smart Grid Knowledge Center.</p>
<p><em>Science, Technology, Cybersecurity, and Space</em></p>
<p>Reflecting on the positive science and technology cooperation between the two countries, the Ministers welcomed the announcement of a Joint Commission Meeting on Science and Technology in 2022, to discuss future science and technology collaboration.</p>
<p>The Ministers applauded the recent and upcoming meetings of the U.S.-India Cyber Dialogue and the Information and Communication Technology (ICT) Working Group to deepen cybersecurity cooperation. They strongly condemned ransomware and other cyber-related crimes and recognized the need to bolster protection of critical networks and infrastructure.</p>
<p>Recalling their countries’ strong tradition of space exploration and endeavors, the Ministers announced the conclusion of a Memorandum of Understanding on Space Situational Awareness and pledged to expand bilateral space cooperation, acknowledging the pivotal role international cooperation plays in the long-term sustainability and safety of the outer-space environment. They applauded the ongoing development of the NASA-ISRO Synthetic Aperture Radar (NISAR) satellite, planned for launch from India in 2023.  The NISAR mission will collect data vital to tackling the climate crisis. The Ministers also looked forward to the convening of the next India-U.S. Civil Space Joint Working Group in 2022.</p>
<p>The Ministers expressed appreciation for the continued cooperation between the U.S. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) and India’s Ministry of Earth Science (MoES) and ISRO in areas such as ocean and fisheries science, meteorology, and earth observation to better understand climate change and save lives through improved weather and ocean modeling and information sharing.  In support of climate and disaster resilience goals, the United States and India are driving advancements in climate and monsoon prediction and forecasting through collaborative work in the Indian Ocean.  As part of that work, MoES recently launched a joint data portal providing near-real-time public data from the NOAA Research Moored Array for African-Asian-Australian Monsoon Analysis and Prediction (RAMA) and the MoES Ocean Moored Buoy Network for the Northern Indian Ocean (OMNI).  The data supports improved monsoon prediction capabilities and sub-seasonal weather forecasting including for the United States, whose weather and atmosphere are impacted by systems that develop in the Indian Ocean. The Ministers also welcomed expansion of collaboration between NOAA and MoES under EKAMSAT program (Enhancing Knowledge of the Arabian Sea Marine Environment through Science and Advanced Technology).</p>
<p><em>Global Health</em></p>
<p>The Ministers recognized the pivotal role of the U.S.-India partnership in combating the COVID-19 pandemic and other contemporary global health challenges.  They welcomed joint U.S.-India leadership under the COVID-19 Global Action Plan to get shots in arms, diversify and secure global supply chains, build capacity for health care workers, and scientific cooperation.  They appreciated U.S.-India collaboration in vaccine R&amp;D and production including the Janssen and Corbevax vaccines being manufactured by Biological E., and the Novovax vaccines by Serum Institute of India, and expressed appreciation that due to efforts to increase manufacturing, safe, effective, and affordable COVID vaccines are readily available to third countries, further strengthening global vaccination efforts. The Ministers reaffirmed their commitment to facilitate joint research and information sharing, and work together to address barriers to pandemic-related vaccines and medical production so that global supply chains for vaccines are more resilient, stable, and predictable.</p>
<p>Recalling the recent U.S.-India Health Dialogue, the Ministers commended our ongoing collaboration on biomedical research, strengthening regulatory procedures and pandemic preparedness. The Ministers welcomed the signing of an overarching Memorandum of Understanding between India’s Ministry of Health and Family Welfare (MoHFW) and the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (DHHS) to work together to strengthen public health preparedness and response by expanding training on disease surveillance, improve response to and containment of outbreaks, strengthen laboratory networks and diagnostics, enhance pan-respiratory disease surveillance, develop sub-national emergency operation centers, and integrate a “One Health” approach into all public health initiatives.</p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the renewal of our joint commitment to undertake collaborative research on infectious diseases of global health significance and conclude a Memorandum of Understanding to continue joint support for an Indo-U.S. International Centre for Excellence in Research between the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID) of National Institutes of Health (NIH) and the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR).</p>
<p>The Ministers also welcomed the launch of ICMR-NIH Clinical Research Fellowship program, under which clinicians from both sides can come to conduct research in laboratories in India and the United States. The Ministers welcomed a new regulatory partnership in furtherance of shrimp safety between the Food and Drug Administration and Marine Product Export Development Authority (MPEDA), and reaffirmed plans to finalize a Memorandum of Understanding to undertake further research on diabetes between the U.S. National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases and ICMR.</p>
<p>The Ministers looked forward to expansion of the USAID-supported COVID-19 Learning Exchange virtual platform, to include programs for more population groups and allow cities and health officials to share best practices to improve routine immunization, strengthen urban health, and launch an interactive web-based platform to enhance knowledge management and operational reach.</p>
<p><em>Defense and Security</em></p>
<p>The Ministers commended the significant and continuing progress in the U.S.-India Major Defense Partnership.  Drawing on the momentum from the U.S.-India Defense Policy Group meeting in October 2021, they reaffirmed their ambitions for building an advanced and comprehensive defense partnership in which the U.S. and Indian militaries coordinate closely together across all domains.</p>
<p>The Ministers acknowledged the importance of deepening collaboration in science and technology in the U.S.-India Joint Technical Group (JTG), and in evolving new defense domains, including space, artificial intelligence (AI), and cyber.  The Ministers underscored the importance of cooperation in space and welcomed plans to conduct an inaugural Defense Space Dialogue in 2022. They welcomed the second Defense Cyber Dialogue held in 2021 and look forward to the next round this year.  They decided to hold an inaugural AI Dialogue this year to harness opportunities for joint innovation and cooperation in new domains.  The Ministers also discussed additional training opportunities for our respective militaries, and the United States welcomed enhanced Indian participation in advanced courses across these emerging domains.</p>
<p>As information-sharing forms an important pillar of the U.S.-India defense cooperation, the Ministers underlined the importance of building a comprehensive framework under which our militaries are equipped to exchange information in real time across domains.  The Ministers welcomed progress made toward full implementation of the Basic Exchange and Cooperation Agreement (BECA) to support the exchange of geospatial information. The Ministers noted that information exchange and placement of liaison officers in each other’s military organizations will spur joint service cooperation between our militaries to support integrated and multi-domain cooperation.</p>
<p>Acknowledging that our navies have been a driving force in advancing the United States and India’s shared interests in the Indian Ocean Region and the wider Indo-Pacific, the Ministers discussed opportunities to further advance and deepen maritime cooperation, including in underwater domain awareness.</p>
<p>The United States also welcomed India’s decision to join the Combined Maritime Forces Task Force as an Associate Partner to expand multilateral cooperation in the Indian Ocean. The Ministers lauded the 2022 Indo-Pacific Military Health Exchange, which India and the United States co-hosted to bring together experts from 38 countries to discuss challenges and solutions to military medical issues. Both sides look forward to India’s co-hosting of the Indo-Pacific Armies Chiefs Conference (IPACC) and Indo-Pacific Armies Management Seminar (IPAMS) in 2023.</p>
<p>In support of the Indian military’s expanding operational reach and emerging opportunities for cooperation in the Indian Ocean and the wider region, the Ministers welcomed regular bilateral logistics operations such as replenishments at sea, air-to-air and ground-refueling and committed to increasing such cooperation, including through the Logistics Exchange Memorandum of Agreement (LEMOA).</p>
<p>Both sides reaffirmed the importance of regular bilateral and multilateral exercises, including the MALABAR exercise with inclusion of Australia, the tri-service TIGER TRIUMPH exercise, the multilateral MILAN naval exercise, the bilateral YUDH ABHYAS and VAJRA PRAHAR Army exercises, the bilateral COPE India air exercise, and Indian participation in RED FLAG. They supported increasing the scope and complexity of these exercises. They looked forward to deepening cooperation between the Special Forces of both countries.</p>
<p>Recognizing the importance of building robust private industry collaboration, the Ministers welcomed ongoing projects under the auspices of the U.S.-India Defense Technology and Trade Initiative (DTTI), including a project agreement to co-develop Air-Launched UAVs.  They called on both sides to consider additional DTTI projects, such as a counter-unmanned aerial systems (UAS) system and an Intelligence, Surveillance, Target Acquisition and Reconnaissance (ISTAR) platform.  They also lauded the rapid growth in bilateral defense trade over the past decade.</p>
<p>Seeking trusted and resilient defense supply chains, the Ministers welcomed the progress made towards implementation of the Industrial Security Agreement to facilitate collaboration on cutting edge defense technologies between industries. Both sides would explore and further promote the means to encourage reciprocal participation of U.S. and Indian vendors in each other’s defense supply chains. Acknowledging India’s focus on developing its domestic capabilities and helping to ensure reliable defense supplies, the Ministers committed to work closely across their respective governments on co-production, co-development, cooperative testing of advanced systems, investment promotion, and the development of Maintenance Repair and Overhaul (MRO) facilities in India. To further enhance defense industrial cooperation in the naval sector, both sides agreed to explore possibilities of utilizing the Indian shipyards for repair and maintenance of ships of the U.S. Maritime Sealift Command (MSC) to support mid-voyage repair of U.S. Naval ships.</p>
<p><em>Counterterrorism and Counter Narcotics</em></p>
<p>The Ministers welcomed the convening of the 18th Meeting of the India-U.S. Joint Working Group on Counter Terrorism and the 4th Session of the India-U.S. Designations Dialogue in October 2021.  The Ministers strongly condemned any use of terrorist proxies and cross-border terrorism in all its forms and called for the perpetrators of the 26/11 Mumbai attack, and Pathankot attack, to be brought to justice.  They called for concerted action against all terrorist groups, including groups proscribed by the UNSC 1267 Sanctions Committee, such as al-Qa’ida, ISIS/Daesh, Lashkar-e-Tayyiba (LeT), and Jaish-e-Mohammad (JeM), and Hizb ul Mujahideen. The Ministers called on Pakistan to take immediate, sustained, and irreversible action to ensure that no territory under its control is used for terrorist attacks.  The Ministers committed to continued exchange of information about sanctions and designations against terror groups and individuals, countering violent radicalism, use of the Internet for terrorist purposes, and cross-border movement of terrorists.  The Ministers also emphasized the importance of upholding international standards on anti-money laundering and combating the financing of terrorism by all countries, consistent with FATF recommendations.</p>
<p>The Ministers also reaffirmed their support for the early adoption of a UN Comprehensive Convention on International Terrorism (CCIT) that advances and strengthens the framework for global cooperation and reinforces that no cause or grievance justifies terrorism.</p>
<p>Both sides looked forward to the next U.S.-India Counter Narcotics Working Group meeting in 2022 and enhancing cooperation through a bilateral Counter-Narcotics Framework to combat drug trafficking, illicit narcotics production, and precursor chemical supply chains.</p>
<p>Building upon the recent Senior Officials Meeting between the U.S. Department of Homeland Security and India’s Ministry of Home Affairs, both sides looked forward to reconvening a Ministerial meeting of the U.S.-India Homeland Security Dialogue in 2022.</p>
<p><em>Education and People-to-People Ties</em></p>
<p>Lauding the vibrant educational linkages between India and the United States, the Ministers reiterated their support to further strengthen cooperation in the field of education and skill development through joint collaborations and promote student and scholar mobility to build people-to-people linkages between the two countries.  In this regard, the ministers announced the intent to establish a new U.S.-India Education and Skills Development Working Group.  The Ministers also appreciated the contribution of the Fulbright-Nehru program in furthering the exchange of outstanding academics and professionals between both countries and the special role the four million strong Indian-American diaspora play in deepening U.S.-India relations.</p>
<p>Welcoming the resumption of regular air travel between the two countries and expressing hope that this would encourage tourism and business travel, the Ministers acknowledged that the movement of skilled professionals, students, entrepreneurs, investors, and business travelers between our countries plays an important role in catalyzing innovation and economic opportunity.  India welcomed the waiver, through December 31, 2022, of in-person visa interviews for applicants that were previously issued any type of visa and are now applying for certain nonimmigrant visa classifications, which include those for Persons in Specialty Occupation, Academic and Vocational Students, and Intracompany Transferees.  The Ministers underlined the importance of continued engagement on visa issues, welcomed the December 2021 meeting of the bilateral Consular Dialogue, and resolved to continue efforts to facilitate the reciprocal movement of professionals, businesspersons, skilled workers, experts, and scientific personnel.</p>
<p>The Ministers also acknowledged the importance of continued discussions on a Social Security Totalization Agreement and welcomed the opportunity to further engage on pursuing such an agreement.</p>
<p>Both sides looked forward to commencing a dialogue on contemporary issues related to women in the context of people to people linkages.</p>
<p>Recognizing the importance of protecting cultural heritage, the Ministers committed to work toward negotiating a Memorandum of Understanding that will deepen cooperation in this area and assist authorities in combatting the trade in cultural artifacts and facilitating their repatriation.</p>
<p>The United States thanked India for its support for the Defense POW/MIA Accounting Agency (DPAA) missions in India. The Ministers reiterated their commitment to future DPAA‎ missions.</p>
<p>India looks forward to hosting the next 2+2 Ministerial.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken to Release the 2021 Human Rights Report</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinken-to-release-the-2021-human-rights-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 22:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333474</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will deliver on-camera remarks on the release of the 2021 <em>Country Reports on Human Rights Practices</em> at 1:30 p.m. on April 12, 2022, in the Press Briefing Room at the U.S. Department of State.</p>
<p>Acting Assistant Secretary Lisa Peterson of the Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor will take questions in the Briefing Room immediately following Secretary Blinken’s remarks.</p>
<p>Promoting respect for human rights and defending fundamental freedoms are central to who we are as a country.  The United States will continue to support those around the world struggling for human dignity and liberty.  Required by U.S. law, the 2021 <em>Country Reports on Human Rights Practices</em> document the status of human rights and worker rights in 198 countries and territories.</p>
<p>Instructions for embargoed access to the country reports will be sent to members of the press on Tuesday, April 12, 2022, at 11:30 a.m.  The entire report is EMBARGOED until the start of the press briefing.  The reports will be available to the public on <a href="http://www.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649802087589000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0H1BNk_fd4WhRT_8rjMo78">www.state.gov</a> following the Secretary’s remarks.</p>
<p>This event will be open press and will be livestreamed on <a href="http://state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTEuNTYyNjAwNTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdiJ9.ya4oUMIxSPBHAhtYZFd4wQYXJX0NhWFVz315RFquEyY/s/1006560560/br/129653753587-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649802087589000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3xKRnhPNC3mQ2snFpmB-Ht">www.state.gov</a>.</p>
<p>Please submit any media inquiries via the web form located on the ‘<a href="https://www.state.gov/information-for-journalists" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Flnks.gd%252Fl%252FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMjEuNTUxOTc2NzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvaW5mb3JtYXRpb24tZm9yLWpvdXJuYWxpc3RzIn0.0JDkrtKqDygYaKa4ZcEB8fH4QH_mh0fYakzMa9bcuZw%252Fs%252F402704355%252Fbr%252F128389640856-l%26data%3D04%257C01%257CKershnerAE%2540state.gov%257C4196672b13804d52865308da19991ae4%257C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%257C0%257C0%257C637850442615620186%257CUnknown%257CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%253D%257C3000%26sdata%3DqaT%252Bjk%252FHjiRyigJ4RXVLNpBrqPghQ3Ftp4Z2uGll5uA%253D%26reserved%3D0&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649802087589000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0eom_w3wCm9mqB2pJYvCXU">Information for Journalists</a>’ page on <a href="http://state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTEuNTYyNjAwNTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdiJ9.GA1ccatY94QKBAbq6E3P9zYzcDa1xJvpI7p6fqea3z4/s/1006560560/br/129653753587-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649802087589000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0tO3ZHeCBrb31jAmdv_GeY">www.state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will deliver on-camera remarks on the release of the 2021 <em>Country Reports on Human Rights Practices</em> at 1:30 p.m. on April 12, 2022, in the Press Briefing Room at the U.S. Department of State.</p>
<p>Acting Assistant Secretary Lisa Peterson of the Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor will take questions in the Briefing Room immediately following Secretary Blinken’s remarks.</p>
<p>Promoting respect for human rights and defending fundamental freedoms are central to who we are as a country.  The United States will continue to support those around the world struggling for human dignity and liberty.  Required by U.S. law, the 2021 <em>Country Reports on Human Rights Practices</em> document the status of human rights and worker rights in 198 countries and territories.</p>
<p>Instructions for embargoed access to the country reports will be sent to members of the press on Tuesday, April 12, 2022, at 11:30 a.m.  The entire report is EMBARGOED until the start of the press briefing.  The reports will be available to the public on <a href="http://www.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649802087589000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0H1BNk_fd4WhRT_8rjMo78">www.state.gov</a> following the Secretary’s remarks.</p>
<p>This event will be open press and will be livestreamed on <a href="http://state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTEuNTYyNjAwNTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdiJ9.ya4oUMIxSPBHAhtYZFd4wQYXJX0NhWFVz315RFquEyY/s/1006560560/br/129653753587-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649802087589000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3xKRnhPNC3mQ2snFpmB-Ht">www.state.gov</a>.</p>
<p>Please submit any media inquiries via the web form located on the ‘<a href="https://www.state.gov/information-for-journalists" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Flnks.gd%252Fl%252FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMjEuNTUxOTc2NzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvaW5mb3JtYXRpb24tZm9yLWpvdXJuYWxpc3RzIn0.0JDkrtKqDygYaKa4ZcEB8fH4QH_mh0fYakzMa9bcuZw%252Fs%252F402704355%252Fbr%252F128389640856-l%26data%3D04%257C01%257CKershnerAE%2540state.gov%257C4196672b13804d52865308da19991ae4%257C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%257C0%257C0%257C637850442615620186%257CUnknown%257CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%253D%257C3000%26sdata%3DqaT%252Bjk%252FHjiRyigJ4RXVLNpBrqPghQ3Ftp4Z2uGll5uA%253D%26reserved%3D0&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649802087589000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0eom_w3wCm9mqB2pJYvCXU">Information for Journalists</a>’ page on <a href="http://state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTEuNTYyNjAwNTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdiJ9.GA1ccatY94QKBAbq6E3P9zYzcDa1xJvpI7p6fqea3z4/s/1006560560/br/129653753587-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649802087589000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0tO3ZHeCBrb31jAmdv_GeY">www.state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin, Indian Minister of External Affairs Dr. S. Jaishankar and Indian Minister of Defense Rajnath Singh Opening Remarks at the U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-secretary-of-defense-lloyd-austin-indian-minister-of-external-affairs-dr-s-jaishankar-and-indian-minister-of-defense-rajnath-singh-opening-remarks-at-the-u-s-india-22/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Lloyd Austin, Secretary of Defense, Dr. S. Jaishankar, Indian Minister of External Affairs, Rajnath Singh, Indian Minister of Defense]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 21:07:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333436</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Lloyd Austin, Secretary of Defense</p>
<p>Dr. S. Jaishankar, Indian Minister of External Affairs</p>
<p>Rajnath Singh, Indian Minister of Defense</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b> Well, good afternoon, everyone.  Minister Jaishankar, Minister Singh, I am honored to be able to host you here at the State Department for the fourth 2+2 U.S.-India foreign and defense ministerial, alongside my friend and colleague the Secretary of Defense, Lloyd Austin.</p>
<p>As President Biden said when he hosted Prime Minister Modi in September of 2021, the relationship between the oldest and biggest democracies in the world is destined to be stronger, closer, more meaningful.  And those were sentiments that I believe both the President and Prime Minister reiterated today when they spoke via videoconference.</p>
<p>These 2+2 meetings have already played a key role in strengthening our bilateral relationship.  This is the core whole-of-government dialogue in our strategic partnership framework.  Today’s discussions will build upon the previous productive meetings that we’ve had.</p>
<p>This is a momentous moment in global affairs, and I think as a result this partnership is even more consequential and more vital.  Today we’ll discuss pressing issues, shared global challenges, including Russia’s war against Ukraine, ending the COVID-19 pandemic, the climate crisis, upholding a free, open, democratic, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region where the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states is assured.  We’ll also talk about improving our counterterrorism cooperation and strengthening the bonds between our higher education institutions.  So, this covers a wide range of different aspects in our relationship.  And I’m also looking forward to talking about our defense and security cooperation in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>Finally, we’ll have an opportunity to sign the Space Situational Awareness Agreement a little bit later today.  This is a demonstration of our growing technology partnership which we believe has virtually limitless potential for exploration, for discovery, for achievement, to the benefit of people in both of our countries and indeed around the world.</p>
<p>This year, as has been noted, marks India’s 75th year of independence, 75 years of our own relationship.  We look very much forward to continuing to build a stronger future for both of our countries, both of our peoples through our defense and security cooperation, through our deeply connected economies, through our shared values and common bonds, and to do so for many, many decades to come.</p>
<p>With that, it’s a pleasure to turn over the microphone to my friend, Minister Jaishankar.</p>
<p><b>MINISTER JAISHANKAR: </b> Thank you.  My senior colleague, Defense Minister Rajnath Singh-ji, Secretary of State Blinken, Secretary of Defense Austin, it’s a great pleasure to participate in the fourth India-U.S. 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue.  This morning we have had separate meetings with our State and Defense counterparts respectively.  We have of course benefitted from the guidance provided by Prime Minister Modi and President Biden through the virtual summit, at which we were all present.</p>
<p>The 2+2 format is intended to promote a more integrated approach to our partnership, and this has become increasingly relevant as the scope and intensity of our engagement steadily increases.  We can truly assert that there’s virtually no domain on which we are not cooperating with each other.  The nature of our opportunities and challenges are such that they are more effectively addressed through a cross-cutting dialogue.</p>
<p>As we meet for the fourth time, we can take satisfaction at the extent of progress that we have made, whether it is a $160 billion trade account, our 200,000 students, our highest recorded investment levels, or our rapidly growing energy trade.  The yardsticks to measure our growing closeness tell their own story.  The defense minister would be similarly highlighting the transformation in that domain.</p>
<p>Our collaboration has grown well beyond its bilateral scope and now has a visible impact on global issues, as well.  It could be addressing the COVID challenge, taking climate action, ensuring maritime security, or promoting critical technologies.  What India and the U.S. do together will make a difference.</p>
<p>A significant focus of our engagement pertains to the Indo-Pacific.  We have seen, particularly over the last year, both an elevation and an intensification of the Quad.  Our achievements in this regard have a larger resonance.</p>
<p>Today we will be reviewing all these matters and more.  We will also be discussing contemporary developments, including, obviously, Ukraine; also, Afghanistan, the Gulf, and the Indian subcontinent.  I thank Secretary Blinken and Secretary Austin for receiving us today, and look forward to our talks.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY AUSTIN:</b>  Okay.  Secretary Blinken, Minister Singh, Minister Jaishankar, it is a privilege to be here with you today for the fourth U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue.  It’s been nearly two decades since we signed our first defense framework, and we’ve built a partnership that is now a cornerstone of security in the Indo-Pacific.  Today, we are positioning the U.S. and Indian militaries to operate and coordinate closely together across all domains and increasingly across the wider Indo-Pacific, all in support of the rule of law, freedom of the seas, and regional peace and security.</p>
<p>Those are vital principles, and now, more than ever, democracies must stand together to defend the values that we all share.  We all understand the challenges that we face in the Indo-Pacific.  The People’s Republic of China is seeking to refashion the region and the international system more broadly in ways that serve its authoritarian interests.  But as we operationalize our defense agreements and take our cooperation to the next level, I believe that we can sustain and strengthen a favorable balance of power in the region.</p>
<p>So, I’m looking forward to discussing a range of bilateral defense priorities, including deeper information sharing and industrial cooperation.  All this will help to ensure that our militaries are ready to meet any challenge.</p>
<p>Now, a strong U.S.-Indian partnership is a critical building block in a more resilient, regional security architecture, and so today’s 2+2 is an opportunity to discuss ways to strengthen our cooperation with like-minded partners from East and Southeast Asia to Europe and beyond.</p>
<p>So, we’ve got an ambitious agenda today.  It reflects our combined vision for our partnership and our shared conviction that we can shape the course of history for the better and preserve a free and open Indo-Pacific at peace with itself and the world.</p>
<p>Ministers, I know that you’ve had a long trip to Washington and thank you for making it here for this important dialogue.  I am truly grateful for your vision, your commitment, and your leadership, as we work together to build one of the most consequential partnerships of our time.</p>
<p>Thank you, and I’ll now turn it over to Minister Singh.</p>
<p><b>MINISTER SINGH:</b>  Excellencies; Mr. Antony Blinken; Mr. Lloyd Austin, Secretary of Defense; my esteemed colleague, Dr. Jaishankar-ji; distinguished members of delegations:  Thank you, Secretary Blinken and to Secretary Austin, for your (inaudible) in Washington, D.C.  India places the highest priority upon the strategic partnership with USA.  (Inaudible) and for ensuring peace and sustained economic growth in our region.  Major defense partnership is one of the most important pillars of India-U.S. strategic relations.</p>
<p>As the largest country and the center to Indian Ocean, and as a democracy, India has critical roles to play in the Indian Ocean region and in the wider Indo-Pacific following the Act East and the Neighborhood First policy.  India played preeminent role in the region, from the tsunami in 2004 and during the COVID pandemic.  We have signed eight different defense-related agreements between our two countries in last few years, including a Space Situational Awareness Agreement for unclassified domain, which is being signed today.</p>
<p>Despite the pandemic, India-USA military engagements increased with higher capability in communication, closer information sharing, and enhanced mutual logistic support. This is a reflection of our – the growing depth and scale of our defense partnership.</p>
<p>In a decade, our defense suppliers from USA rose from negligible to a cumulative around of over $20 billion U.S.  We look forward to U.S. companies investing in India and support the Make In India program.</p>
<p>We look forward to further enhancing the depth and the scope of our defense cooperation to give effect to our shared vision of a free, open, inclusive, and a rules-bound Indo-Pacific and the Indian Ocean region.</p>
<p>We are working with the U.S. to double up capabilities across conventional and emerging defense domains.  We have made good progress in a number of defense cooperation activities since the visit of Secretary Austin to India in March 2021.  I look forward to discussing some of these and the way forward.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you very much, colleagues, and I think we’ll allow our colleagues from the press to exit.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Lloyd Austin, Secretary of Defense</p>
<p>Dr. S. Jaishankar, Indian Minister of External Affairs</p>
<p>Rajnath Singh, Indian Minister of Defense</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </b> Well, good afternoon, everyone.  Minister Jaishankar, Minister Singh, I am honored to be able to host you here at the State Department for the fourth 2+2 U.S.-India foreign and defense ministerial, alongside my friend and colleague the Secretary of Defense, Lloyd Austin.</p>
<p>As President Biden said when he hosted Prime Minister Modi in September of 2021, the relationship between the oldest and biggest democracies in the world is destined to be stronger, closer, more meaningful.  And those were sentiments that I believe both the President and Prime Minister reiterated today when they spoke via videoconference.</p>
<p>These 2+2 meetings have already played a key role in strengthening our bilateral relationship.  This is the core whole-of-government dialogue in our strategic partnership framework.  Today’s discussions will build upon the previous productive meetings that we’ve had.</p>
<p>This is a momentous moment in global affairs, and I think as a result this partnership is even more consequential and more vital.  Today we’ll discuss pressing issues, shared global challenges, including Russia’s war against Ukraine, ending the COVID-19 pandemic, the climate crisis, upholding a free, open, democratic, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region where the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states is assured.  We’ll also talk about improving our counterterrorism cooperation and strengthening the bonds between our higher education institutions.  So, this covers a wide range of different aspects in our relationship.  And I’m also looking forward to talking about our defense and security cooperation in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>Finally, we’ll have an opportunity to sign the Space Situational Awareness Agreement a little bit later today.  This is a demonstration of our growing technology partnership which we believe has virtually limitless potential for exploration, for discovery, for achievement, to the benefit of people in both of our countries and indeed around the world.</p>
<p>This year, as has been noted, marks India’s 75th year of independence, 75 years of our own relationship.  We look very much forward to continuing to build a stronger future for both of our countries, both of our peoples through our defense and security cooperation, through our deeply connected economies, through our shared values and common bonds, and to do so for many, many decades to come.</p>
<p>With that, it’s a pleasure to turn over the microphone to my friend, Minister Jaishankar.</p>
<p><b>MINISTER JAISHANKAR: </b> Thank you.  My senior colleague, Defense Minister Rajnath Singh-ji, Secretary of State Blinken, Secretary of Defense Austin, it’s a great pleasure to participate in the fourth India-U.S. 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue.  This morning we have had separate meetings with our State and Defense counterparts respectively.  We have of course benefitted from the guidance provided by Prime Minister Modi and President Biden through the virtual summit, at which we were all present.</p>
<p>The 2+2 format is intended to promote a more integrated approach to our partnership, and this has become increasingly relevant as the scope and intensity of our engagement steadily increases.  We can truly assert that there’s virtually no domain on which we are not cooperating with each other.  The nature of our opportunities and challenges are such that they are more effectively addressed through a cross-cutting dialogue.</p>
<p>As we meet for the fourth time, we can take satisfaction at the extent of progress that we have made, whether it is a $160 billion trade account, our 200,000 students, our highest recorded investment levels, or our rapidly growing energy trade.  The yardsticks to measure our growing closeness tell their own story.  The defense minister would be similarly highlighting the transformation in that domain.</p>
<p>Our collaboration has grown well beyond its bilateral scope and now has a visible impact on global issues, as well.  It could be addressing the COVID challenge, taking climate action, ensuring maritime security, or promoting critical technologies.  What India and the U.S. do together will make a difference.</p>
<p>A significant focus of our engagement pertains to the Indo-Pacific.  We have seen, particularly over the last year, both an elevation and an intensification of the Quad.  Our achievements in this regard have a larger resonance.</p>
<p>Today we will be reviewing all these matters and more.  We will also be discussing contemporary developments, including, obviously, Ukraine; also, Afghanistan, the Gulf, and the Indian subcontinent.  I thank Secretary Blinken and Secretary Austin for receiving us today, and look forward to our talks.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY AUSTIN:</b>  Okay.  Secretary Blinken, Minister Singh, Minister Jaishankar, it is a privilege to be here with you today for the fourth U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue.  It’s been nearly two decades since we signed our first defense framework, and we’ve built a partnership that is now a cornerstone of security in the Indo-Pacific.  Today, we are positioning the U.S. and Indian militaries to operate and coordinate closely together across all domains and increasingly across the wider Indo-Pacific, all in support of the rule of law, freedom of the seas, and regional peace and security.</p>
<p>Those are vital principles, and now, more than ever, democracies must stand together to defend the values that we all share.  We all understand the challenges that we face in the Indo-Pacific.  The People’s Republic of China is seeking to refashion the region and the international system more broadly in ways that serve its authoritarian interests.  But as we operationalize our defense agreements and take our cooperation to the next level, I believe that we can sustain and strengthen a favorable balance of power in the region.</p>
<p>So, I’m looking forward to discussing a range of bilateral defense priorities, including deeper information sharing and industrial cooperation.  All this will help to ensure that our militaries are ready to meet any challenge.</p>
<p>Now, a strong U.S.-Indian partnership is a critical building block in a more resilient, regional security architecture, and so today’s 2+2 is an opportunity to discuss ways to strengthen our cooperation with like-minded partners from East and Southeast Asia to Europe and beyond.</p>
<p>So, we’ve got an ambitious agenda today.  It reflects our combined vision for our partnership and our shared conviction that we can shape the course of history for the better and preserve a free and open Indo-Pacific at peace with itself and the world.</p>
<p>Ministers, I know that you’ve had a long trip to Washington and thank you for making it here for this important dialogue.  I am truly grateful for your vision, your commitment, and your leadership, as we work together to build one of the most consequential partnerships of our time.</p>
<p>Thank you, and I’ll now turn it over to Minister Singh.</p>
<p><b>MINISTER SINGH:</b>  Excellencies; Mr. Antony Blinken; Mr. Lloyd Austin, Secretary of Defense; my esteemed colleague, Dr. Jaishankar-ji; distinguished members of delegations:  Thank you, Secretary Blinken and to Secretary Austin, for your (inaudible) in Washington, D.C.  India places the highest priority upon the strategic partnership with USA.  (Inaudible) and for ensuring peace and sustained economic growth in our region.  Major defense partnership is one of the most important pillars of India-U.S. strategic relations.</p>
<p>As the largest country and the center to Indian Ocean, and as a democracy, India has critical roles to play in the Indian Ocean region and in the wider Indo-Pacific following the Act East and the Neighborhood First policy.  India played preeminent role in the region, from the tsunami in 2004 and during the COVID pandemic.  We have signed eight different defense-related agreements between our two countries in last few years, including a Space Situational Awareness Agreement for unclassified domain, which is being signed today.</p>
<p>Despite the pandemic, India-USA military engagements increased with higher capability in communication, closer information sharing, and enhanced mutual logistic support. This is a reflection of our – the growing depth and scale of our defense partnership.</p>
<p>In a decade, our defense suppliers from USA rose from negligible to a cumulative around of over $20 billion U.S.  We look forward to U.S. companies investing in India and support the Make In India program.</p>
<p>We look forward to further enhancing the depth and the scope of our defense cooperation to give effect to our shared vision of a free, open, inclusive, and a rules-bound Indo-Pacific and the Indian Ocean region.</p>
<p>We are working with the U.S. to double up capabilities across conventional and emerging defense domains.  We have made good progress in a number of defense cooperation activities since the visit of Secretary Austin to India in March 2021.  I look forward to discussing some of these and the way forward.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you very much, colleagues, and I think we’ll allow our colleagues from the press to exit.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary Noyes Travel to Moldova and Poland</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-noyes-travel-to-moldova-and-poland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 19:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333391</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM) Julieta Valls Noyes will travel to Chisinau, Moldova and Warsaw, Poland April 12-15.</p>
<p>In Chisinau, Assistant Secretary Noyes will meet with government officials to recognize Moldova’s role in hosting tens of thousands of refugees who have fled Ukraine due to Russia’s unprovoked invasion. She will also visit a refugee hosting center to meet with refugees as well as humanitarian organization staff and volunteers assisting them.</p>
<p>In Warsaw, she will meet with Polish and UN officials to discuss the ongoing humanitarian crisis response. Assistant Secretary Noyes will also meet with NGOs delivering critical humanitarian assistance for refugees in Poland.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM) Julieta Valls Noyes will travel to Chisinau, Moldova and Warsaw, Poland April 12-15.</p>
<p>In Chisinau, Assistant Secretary Noyes will meet with government officials to recognize Moldova’s role in hosting tens of thousands of refugees who have fled Ukraine due to Russia’s unprovoked invasion. She will also visit a refugee hosting center to meet with refugees as well as humanitarian organization staff and volunteers assisting them.</p>
<p>In Warsaw, she will meet with Polish and UN officials to discuss the ongoing humanitarian crisis response. Assistant Secretary Noyes will also meet with NGOs delivering critical humanitarian assistance for refugees in Poland.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with UK Minister for Europe and North America Cleverly</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-uk-minister-for-europe-and-north-america-cleverly/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 17:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333354</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with UK Minister of State for Europe and North America James Cleverly today in Washington. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Minister Cleverly continued close U.S.-UK coordination to hold the Kremlin accountable for its brutal atrocities in Putin’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine. The Deputy Secretary and Minister Cleverly also discussed bilateral cooperation to support South Caucasus peace and reconciliation efforts.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with UK Minister of State for Europe and North America James Cleverly today in Washington. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Minister Cleverly continued close U.S.-UK coordination to hold the Kremlin accountable for its brutal atrocities in Putin’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine. The Deputy Secretary and Minister Cleverly also discussed bilateral cooperation to support South Caucasus peace and reconciliation efforts.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Burma New Year 2022 – Thingyan Festival</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/burma-new-year-2022-thingyan-festival/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 13:28:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333281</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I extend best wishes to the people of Burma on the occasion of Burma’s New Year, Thingyan.</p>
<p>Thingyan is an opportunity to wash away the previous year’s tribulations. Since the military coup, the people of Burma have endured unimaginable suffering and shown incredible courage and resilience in opposition to the military regime. The United States will continue to stand by the people of Burma and to promote accountability in connection with the coup and the violence perpetrated by the regime. The United States is unwavering in its commitment to help restore Burma’s path to inclusive democracy and achieve lasting peace.</p>
<p>In these difficult times, please accept our warmest regards for the people of Burma.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I extend best wishes to the people of Burma on the occasion of Burma’s New Year, Thingyan.</p>
<p>Thingyan is an opportunity to wash away the previous year’s tribulations. Since the military coup, the people of Burma have endured unimaginable suffering and shown incredible courage and resilience in opposition to the military regime. The United States will continue to stand by the people of Burma and to promote accountability in connection with the coup and the violence perpetrated by the regime. The United States is unwavering in its commitment to help restore Burma’s path to inclusive democracy and achieve lasting peace.</p>
<p>In these difficult times, please accept our warmest regards for the people of Burma.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Violence and Threats to Free Speech in El Salvador</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/violence-and-threats-to-free-speech-in-el-salvador/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 13:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333213</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States government is concerned about violence in El Salvador and the passage and implementation of the April 5 Criminal Code amendment by the Legislative Assembly criminalizing reporting on certain gang activities. The law lends itself to attempts to censor the media, prevent reporting on corruption and other matters of public interest, and silence critics of the Salvadoran government.</p>
<p>Journalists must have the freedom to do their jobs without fear of violence, threats, or unjust detention.</p>
<p>We continue to support El Salvador in its efforts to reduce the proliferation of gangs. Since 2008, we have invested $411 million to improve citizen security and help the Salvadoran government combat gang violence. Examples include the construction of a state-of-the-art forensics lab in Nuevo Cuscatlan, and assistance to reclaim and renovate public spaces such as Parque Cuscatlan.</p>
<p>We are deeply concerned by the spike in violence and homicides committed by the MS-13 and the Barrio 18 gangs in El Salvador on March 25, 26, and 27.</p>
<p>Gangs pose a threat to the national security of El Salvador and the United States. We urge El Salvador to address this threat while also protecting vital civil liberties, including freedom of the press, due process, and freedom of speech.</p>
<p>Now more than ever it is essential to extradite gang leaders to face justice in the United States.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States government is concerned about violence in El Salvador and the passage and implementation of the April 5 Criminal Code amendment by the Legislative Assembly criminalizing reporting on certain gang activities. The law lends itself to attempts to censor the media, prevent reporting on corruption and other matters of public interest, and silence critics of the Salvadoran government.</p>
<p>Journalists must have the freedom to do their jobs without fear of violence, threats, or unjust detention.</p>
<p>We continue to support El Salvador in its efforts to reduce the proliferation of gangs. Since 2008, we have invested $411 million to improve citizen security and help the Salvadoran government combat gang violence. Examples include the construction of a state-of-the-art forensics lab in Nuevo Cuscatlan, and assistance to reclaim and renovate public spaces such as Parque Cuscatlan.</p>
<p>We are deeply concerned by the spike in violence and homicides committed by the MS-13 and the Barrio 18 gangs in El Salvador on March 25, 26, and 27.</p>
<p>Gangs pose a threat to the national security of El Salvador and the United States. We urge El Salvador to address this threat while also protecting vital civil liberties, including freedom of the press, due process, and freedom of speech.</p>
<p>Now more than ever it is essential to extradite gang leaders to face justice in the United States.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing – April 8, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-april-8-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 20:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=333088</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:02 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Good afternoon and Happy Friday, everyone. I have one update at the top, and then I’ll start with taking your questions. I<a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia"></a> would like to start off by addressing the missile strike by Russia’s forces that reportedly killed at least 50 civilians and injured many more at the Kramatorsk railway station in eastern Ukraine, where thousands of civilians were on a platform waiting to be evacuated. I want to express our deep condolences to the families of those killed or injured, and to the people of Ukraine who continue to suffer terribly from the Russian Government’s unprovoked, unjustified, and brutal war.</p>
<p>We are horrified by this latest atrocity, but we can no longer be surprised by the Kremlin’s repugnant disregard for human life. This is just yet another example of the Russian Government’s unjustified, brutal war sowing senseless death and destruction in Ukraine, and unraveling the fabric of normal life on schools, on homes, on hospitals, and on workplaces. Civilians are killed when they stay in their homes, and they’re killed when they tried to leave. Actions like these demonstrate why Russia did not belong on the UN Human Rights Council, and they also reinforced the U.S. assessment that members of Russian – Russia’s forces are committing war crimes in Ukraine.</p>
<p>This tragedy has also further increased our resolve to do everything we can to assist those investigating potential war crimes, see those responsible held accountable for atrocities, and support the people of Ukraine in their just cause: the defense of their country, their democracy, and their free and sovereign future.</p>
<p>Let’s first go to the line of Cindy Saine, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yes, thank you. Jalina, Prime Minister – Pakistani Prime Minister Imran Khan just spoke to the nation, and he has renewed allegations that the U.S. encouraged the no-confidence vote, saying that he has a cable to prove it. Could you please comment? And thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Cindy. <a id="post-333088-Pakistan"></a>Let me just say very bluntly there is absolutely no truth to these allegations. Of course, we continue to follow these developments, and we respect and support Pakistan’s constitutional process and rule of law. But again, these allegations are absolutely not true.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> And next we’ll go to the line of Endale Getahun with KETO FM International. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you so much. Good morning. Good morning, everyone, and a Happy Friday. Thank you for taking my call. I am asking regarding the situation, as you know, that’s in East Africa, Ethiopia. I don’t know if you know, but there was – a meeting took place between the second in command on Ethiopian military and Eritrean. And so do you know any information or have you heard on – or do you want to comment on regarding the general who visited Eritrea with the state – given the statements on state media and Ethiopian TV that they are preparing to do a second phase there to invade Tigray, as we speak? Do you have any comment on that?</p>
<p>The second one I have: Have you seen the Human Rights and Amnesty International released about the (inaudible) was taken based on their statements, ethnic cleansing and what have you, on – for the neighboring state, for Amhara militants or vigilantes, and they were – and western Tigray, which is still occupied by Eritreans and by the – with the Amhara? So what is your comments on that statement and also on the general, the second in command in Ethiopia, that made the statements on they are heading to the second phase, even as there’s a ceasefire according to Ethiopian Government, and also on the human – that was my question, but if you have any comments on World Food Program. They’re still having issues for delivering food. Only 26 trucks head on to Tigray. What’s your comment on that too? And thank you so much, appreciate it.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you for all of those robust questions. <a id="post-333088-Ethiopia"></a>I’ll do my best to give you an overview of what we have from here. I’ll just start off by saying that we certainly welcome the humanitarian truce in Tigray.</p>
<p>Second, to your question on the joint Human Rights report and Amnesty International report, we’re certainly aware of these reports on ethnically motivated atrocities committed by Amhara authorities in the western Tigray and in Ethiopia, and we also reiterate our grave concerns over findings in this report, which we will carefully review. In fact, we have some principals in the building, including Under Secretary Zeya, who is our Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy and Human Rights, along with our Ambassador-at-Large for Global Criminal Justice Beth Van Schaack, and a couple other principals in our department are actually meeting with representatives of Human Rights Watch and Amnesty International today to hear more about this report.</p>
<p>I’ll also say that the U.S. has consistently called out human rights abuses by all armed actors in this conflict, and we will continue to do this. Victims deserve justice, and those responsible for these abuses must be held accountable through transparent and inclusive processes.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to Laura Kelly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. Secretary Blinken on I believe it was March 23rd said that the State Department determined the Russians had committed war crimes in Ukraine. When do you intend to release those assessments of specific determinations of war crimes?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks, Laura. <a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia2"></a>Well, we certainly don’t have a timeline for this. But I’ll say that we continue to investigate Russia’s ongoing and unprovoked, unjustified war against Ukraine. But we have no – nothing to preview as far as timelines.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Eunjong Cho, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina, for taking my question. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Great. The nominee for ambassador to South Korea, Ambassador Phillip Goldberg, at the Senate nomination hearing yesterday said comprehensive, verifiable, irreversible denuclearization are goals in – when it comes to North Korea. So is comprehensible, verifiable, irreversible denuclearization the Biden administration’s official term for describing the goal in negotiations with North Korea? Is the Biden administration officially replacing “complete” with “comprehensive” in defining this goal?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks for your question, Eunjong. <a id="post-333088-Koreas"></a>We have no change – the Biden-Harris administration has no change in our policy, and we continue to urge the DPRK to refrain from further destabilizing activities and of course instead choose to engage in serious and sustained dialogue.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Jenny Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for calling on me. The Ukrainian foreign minister just called for Russia to be expelled from the OSCE, saying that if the OSCE lacks an appropriate suspension mechanism, then they should set up a process to get them out. Does the U.S. support suspending Russia from the OSCE or creating a mechanism to do so?</p>
<p>And then secondly, do you have an update on the American citizens detained in Russia? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks, Jenny. <a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia3"></a>To your first question on the OSCE, I’m learning about that in real time so we don’t have anything to respond to at the moment.</p>
<p>But what I will say about – to your second question, of course, is our top priority is and has always been the safety and the security of Americans overseas, and we continue to engage the Russian Government on cases of Americans who are currently detained.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Conor Finnegan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey, Jalina. Two questions on – just following up on what you said at the top about the strike on the train station in Kramatorsk. First, you said it reinforces the assessment that Russia is committing war crimes. Are you calling this strike a war crime?</p>
<p>And then second, you attributed it to Russia. The Kremlin has obviously denied responsibility. Just wondering if you will respond to their denial. Any more information you can provide on why you are attributing it to them? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Conor. I’ll say, to your question on the war crime question, assessing individual criminal liability in specific cases is the responsibility of courts as well as other investigatory bodies. But as the Secretary, Secretary Blinken, has said, those responsible for war crimes and other atrocities committed in Ukraine will be held to account. We won’t make any public comments on our war crimes assessment of specific acts or reports, nor discuss any information that’s reviewed at this time.</p>
<p>And then to your second question on a response – yeah, we just don’t have a response to give at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Joseph Akbush.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for this. Two questions. One, is there any comment on the two attacks which targeted U.S. servicemembers in Syria and Iraq over the last two days, I guess? And on that note, any updates to the Vienna talks?</p>
<p>And then my second question is on Ukraine. And are there still – is the U.S. still concerned about China providing military support to Russia or circumventing international sanctions? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Joseph. So for your first question, I would have to refer you to the DOD. To your second question on any updates in – on <a id="post-333088-Iran"></a>the status of talks and Iran, we don’t have any updates to share at this time other than it’s obviously been a significant process, but an agreement is neither imminent nor certain at this time.</p>
<p>And to your last question on <a id="post-333088-ChinaRussiaUkraine"></a>Chinese military to assist the Russians, I think we’ve been pretty clear on our stance when it comes to any support in this activity, and that hasn’t changed at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s take our last question from Elizabeth Hagedorn.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. One follow-up for you on Iran. Can you say whether the Biden administration shares General Milley’s view that the IRGC’s Qods Force specifically should remain on the U.S. list of terror organizations?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Elizabeth. <a id="post-333088-Iran2"></a>I’d say that the President shares the chairman’s view that IRGC Qods Forces are terrorists, and beyond that we aren’t going to comment on any of the topics in the nuclear talks. But what I would say is out of the 107 Biden administration designations in relation to Iran, 86 have specifically targeted the IRGC-related persons as well as affiliates.</p>
<p>Thank you all so much for joining today. That concludes today’s press briefing, and I hope you have a good weekend ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:19 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:02 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Good afternoon and Happy Friday, everyone. I have one update at the top, and then I’ll start with taking your questions. I<a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia"></a> would like to start off by addressing the missile strike by Russia’s forces that reportedly killed at least 50 civilians and injured many more at the Kramatorsk railway station in eastern Ukraine, where thousands of civilians were on a platform waiting to be evacuated. I want to express our deep condolences to the families of those killed or injured, and to the people of Ukraine who continue to suffer terribly from the Russian Government’s unprovoked, unjustified, and brutal war.</p>
<p>We are horrified by this latest atrocity, but we can no longer be surprised by the Kremlin’s repugnant disregard for human life. This is just yet another example of the Russian Government’s unjustified, brutal war sowing senseless death and destruction in Ukraine, and unraveling the fabric of normal life on schools, on homes, on hospitals, and on workplaces. Civilians are killed when they stay in their homes, and they’re killed when they tried to leave. Actions like these demonstrate why Russia did not belong on the UN Human Rights Council, and they also reinforced the U.S. assessment that members of Russian – Russia’s forces are committing war crimes in Ukraine.</p>
<p>This tragedy has also further increased our resolve to do everything we can to assist those investigating potential war crimes, see those responsible held accountable for atrocities, and support the people of Ukraine in their just cause: the defense of their country, their democracy, and their free and sovereign future.</p>
<p>Let’s first go to the line of Cindy Saine, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yes, thank you. Jalina, Prime Minister – Pakistani Prime Minister Imran Khan just spoke to the nation, and he has renewed allegations that the U.S. encouraged the no-confidence vote, saying that he has a cable to prove it. Could you please comment? And thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Cindy. <a id="post-333088-Pakistan"></a>Let me just say very bluntly there is absolutely no truth to these allegations. Of course, we continue to follow these developments, and we respect and support Pakistan’s constitutional process and rule of law. But again, these allegations are absolutely not true.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> And next we’ll go to the line of Endale Getahun with KETO FM International. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you so much. Good morning. Good morning, everyone, and a Happy Friday. Thank you for taking my call. I am asking regarding the situation, as you know, that’s in East Africa, Ethiopia. I don’t know if you know, but there was – a meeting took place between the second in command on Ethiopian military and Eritrean. And so do you know any information or have you heard on – or do you want to comment on regarding the general who visited Eritrea with the state – given the statements on state media and Ethiopian TV that they are preparing to do a second phase there to invade Tigray, as we speak? Do you have any comment on that?</p>
<p>The second one I have: Have you seen the Human Rights and Amnesty International released about the (inaudible) was taken based on their statements, ethnic cleansing and what have you, on – for the neighboring state, for Amhara militants or vigilantes, and they were – and western Tigray, which is still occupied by Eritreans and by the – with the Amhara? So what is your comments on that statement and also on the general, the second in command in Ethiopia, that made the statements on they are heading to the second phase, even as there’s a ceasefire according to Ethiopian Government, and also on the human – that was my question, but if you have any comments on World Food Program. They’re still having issues for delivering food. Only 26 trucks head on to Tigray. What’s your comment on that too? And thank you so much, appreciate it.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you for all of those robust questions. <a id="post-333088-Ethiopia"></a>I’ll do my best to give you an overview of what we have from here. I’ll just start off by saying that we certainly welcome the humanitarian truce in Tigray.</p>
<p>Second, to your question on the joint Human Rights report and Amnesty International report, we’re certainly aware of these reports on ethnically motivated atrocities committed by Amhara authorities in the western Tigray and in Ethiopia, and we also reiterate our grave concerns over findings in this report, which we will carefully review. In fact, we have some principals in the building, including Under Secretary Zeya, who is our Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy and Human Rights, along with our Ambassador-at-Large for Global Criminal Justice Beth Van Schaack, and a couple other principals in our department are actually meeting with representatives of Human Rights Watch and Amnesty International today to hear more about this report.</p>
<p>I’ll also say that the U.S. has consistently called out human rights abuses by all armed actors in this conflict, and we will continue to do this. Victims deserve justice, and those responsible for these abuses must be held accountable through transparent and inclusive processes.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to Laura Kelly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. Secretary Blinken on I believe it was March 23rd said that the State Department determined the Russians had committed war crimes in Ukraine. When do you intend to release those assessments of specific determinations of war crimes?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks, Laura. <a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia2"></a>Well, we certainly don’t have a timeline for this. But I’ll say that we continue to investigate Russia’s ongoing and unprovoked, unjustified war against Ukraine. But we have no – nothing to preview as far as timelines.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Eunjong Cho, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina, for taking my question. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Great. The nominee for ambassador to South Korea, Ambassador Phillip Goldberg, at the Senate nomination hearing yesterday said comprehensive, verifiable, irreversible denuclearization are goals in – when it comes to North Korea. So is comprehensible, verifiable, irreversible denuclearization the Biden administration’s official term for describing the goal in negotiations with North Korea? Is the Biden administration officially replacing “complete” with “comprehensive” in defining this goal?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks for your question, Eunjong. <a id="post-333088-Koreas"></a>We have no change – the Biden-Harris administration has no change in our policy, and we continue to urge the DPRK to refrain from further destabilizing activities and of course instead choose to engage in serious and sustained dialogue.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Jenny Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for calling on me. The Ukrainian foreign minister just called for Russia to be expelled from the OSCE, saying that if the OSCE lacks an appropriate suspension mechanism, then they should set up a process to get them out. Does the U.S. support suspending Russia from the OSCE or creating a mechanism to do so?</p>
<p>And then secondly, do you have an update on the American citizens detained in Russia? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong> Thanks, Jenny. <a id="post-333088-UkraineRussia3"></a>To your first question on the OSCE, I’m learning about that in real time so we don’t have anything to respond to at the moment.</p>
<p>But what I will say about – to your second question, of course, is our top priority is and has always been the safety and the security of Americans overseas, and we continue to engage the Russian Government on cases of Americans who are currently detained.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Conor Finnegan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey, Jalina. Two questions on – just following up on what you said at the top about the strike on the train station in Kramatorsk. First, you said it reinforces the assessment that Russia is committing war crimes. Are you calling this strike a war crime?</p>
<p>And then second, you attributed it to Russia. The Kremlin has obviously denied responsibility. Just wondering if you will respond to their denial. Any more information you can provide on why you are attributing it to them? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Conor. I’ll say, to your question on the war crime question, assessing individual criminal liability in specific cases is the responsibility of courts as well as other investigatory bodies. But as the Secretary, Secretary Blinken, has said, those responsible for war crimes and other atrocities committed in Ukraine will be held to account. We won’t make any public comments on our war crimes assessment of specific acts or reports, nor discuss any information that’s reviewed at this time.</p>
<p>And then to your second question on a response – yeah, we just don’t have a response to give at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go over to Joseph Akbush.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for this. Two questions. One, is there any comment on the two attacks which targeted U.S. servicemembers in Syria and Iraq over the last two days, I guess? And on that note, any updates to the Vienna talks?</p>
<p>And then my second question is on Ukraine. And are there still – is the U.S. still concerned about China providing military support to Russia or circumventing international sanctions? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Joseph. So for your first question, I would have to refer you to the DOD. To your second question on any updates in – on <a id="post-333088-Iran"></a>the status of talks and Iran, we don’t have any updates to share at this time other than it’s obviously been a significant process, but an agreement is neither imminent nor certain at this time.</p>
<p>And to your last question on <a id="post-333088-ChinaRussiaUkraine"></a>Chinese military to assist the Russians, I think we’ve been pretty clear on our stance when it comes to any support in this activity, and that hasn’t changed at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s take our last question from Elizabeth Hagedorn.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. One follow-up for you on Iran. Can you say whether the Biden administration shares General Milley’s view that the IRGC’s Qods Force specifically should remain on the U.S. list of terror organizations?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Elizabeth. <a id="post-333088-Iran2"></a>I’d say that the President shares the chairman’s view that IRGC Qods Forces are terrorists, and beyond that we aren’t going to comment on any of the topics in the nuclear talks. But what I would say is out of the 107 Biden administration designations in relation to Iran, 86 have specifically targeted the IRGC-related persons as well as affiliates.</p>
<p>Thank you all so much for joining today. That concludes today’s press briefing, and I hope you have a good weekend ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:19 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate Kerry and Assistant Secretary Medina’s Travel to Palau</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-presidential-envoy-for-climate-kerry-and-assistant-secretary-medinas-travel-to-palau/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 20:10:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333074</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Palau April 12-15 to lead the U.S. delegation to the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>, co-hosted by the United States and the Republic of Palau.  He will be joined by Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica Medina, who will travel to Palau April 10-16.</p>
<p>The Our Ocean Conference, taking place April 13-14, will focus on combating climate change, promoting sustainable fisheries, creating sustainable blue economies, advancing marine protected areas, achieving a safe and secure ocean, and confronting marine pollution.  The importance of ocean-based climate solutions and the centrality of a healthy ocean to small island developing states – and all places where the ocean is a primary source of sustenance – will be cross-cutting themes.</p>
<p>At the conference, Secretary Kerry and Assistant Secretary Medina will engage with government counterparts, private sector actors, and civil society partners to advance efforts related to ocean conservation and the climate crisis.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, contact <a href="mailto:ClimateComms@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ClimateComms@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Palau April 12-15 to lead the U.S. delegation to the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>, co-hosted by the United States and the Republic of Palau.  He will be joined by Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica Medina, who will travel to Palau April 10-16.</p>
<p>The Our Ocean Conference, taking place April 13-14, will focus on combating climate change, promoting sustainable fisheries, creating sustainable blue economies, advancing marine protected areas, achieving a safe and secure ocean, and confronting marine pollution.  The importance of ocean-based climate solutions and the centrality of a healthy ocean to small island developing states – and all places where the ocean is a primary source of sustenance – will be cross-cutting themes.</p>
<p>At the conference, Secretary Kerry and Assistant Secretary Medina will engage with government counterparts, private sector actors, and civil society partners to advance efforts related to ocean conservation and the climate crisis.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, contact <a href="mailto:ClimateComms@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ClimateComms@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
