<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 17:21:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>United States Welcomes Actions by Armenia and Azerbaijan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-welcomes-actions-by-armenia-and-azerbaijan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 17:21:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States welcomes the release by Azerbaijan of 15 Armenian detainees and their return to their families in Armenia. We also welcome Armenia’s decision to provide Azerbaijan with important information that will facilitate humanitarian demining and avoid future casualties. We are grateful to Prime Minister Irakli Garibashvili and the Government of Georgia for the essential role Georgia played in facilitating these steps, which bring the people of the region closer to the peaceful and prosperous future they deserve.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States is pleased to support these steps and hopes they will lay the groundwork for additional cooperation. We continue to call for the return of all detainees and stand ready to assist the countries of the region in their efforts to continue cooperation and resolve outstanding issues between them. We also continue to urge Armenia and Azerbaijan to reengage in substantive negotiations under the auspices of the OSCE Minsk Group Co-Chairs to negotiate a comprehensive political settlement to the conflict.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States welcomes the release by Azerbaijan of 15 Armenian detainees and their return to their families in Armenia. We also welcome Armenia’s decision to provide Azerbaijan with important information that will facilitate humanitarian demining and avoid future casualties. We are grateful to Prime Minister Irakli Garibashvili and the Government of Georgia for the essential role Georgia played in facilitating these steps, which bring the people of the region closer to the peaceful and prosperous future they deserve.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States is pleased to support these steps and hopes they will lay the groundwork for additional cooperation. We continue to call for the return of all detainees and stand ready to assist the countries of the region in their efforts to continue cooperation and resolve outstanding issues between them. We also continue to urge Armenia and Azerbaijan to reengage in substantive negotiations under the auspices of the OSCE Minsk Group Co-Chairs to negotiate a comprehensive political settlement to the conflict.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russia National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/russia-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 04:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251457</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the citizens of Russia as you celebrate Russia Day.  This holiday marks the significant step Russia made on June 12, 1991, when it held its first free, open, and fair elections, and adopted the Declaration of Russian State Sovereignty.  This important document recognized the democratic aspirations and sovereignty of the peoples of Russia and guaranteed their rights and equal protections under the rule of law, and their right to life and dignity, honoring their centuries of history, culture, and traditions.</p>
<p>I take this opportunity to reaffirm the United States’ desire for constructive engagement with the government of the Russian Federation in the interest of promoting a more stable and predictable bilateral relationship.  Likewise, we remain steadfastly committed to supporting the Russian people as they continue to build on the aspirations outlined in the Declaration of Russian State Sovereignty and their desire to work together with the international community and cooperate peacefully on matters of global concern.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the citizens of Russia as you celebrate Russia Day.  This holiday marks the significant step Russia made on June 12, 1991, when it held its first free, open, and fair elections, and adopted the Declaration of Russian State Sovereignty.  This important document recognized the democratic aspirations and sovereignty of the peoples of Russia and guaranteed their rights and equal protections under the rule of law, and their right to life and dignity, honoring their centuries of history, culture, and traditions.</p>
<p>I take this opportunity to reaffirm the United States’ desire for constructive engagement with the government of the Russian Federation in the interest of promoting a more stable and predictable bilateral relationship.  Likewise, we remain steadfastly committed to supporting the Russian people as they continue to build on the aspirations outlined in the Declaration of Russian State Sovereignty and their desire to work together with the international community and cooperate peacefully on matters of global concern.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On the Occasion of the Official Birthday of Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/on-the-occasion-of-the-official-birthday-of-her-majesty-queen-elizabeth-ii/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251448</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I offer my best wishes to Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II and to the people of the United Kingdom as you celebrate Her Majesty’s birthday.</p>
<p>Queen Elizabeth’s lifetime of leadership and dedication to service is an example for all nations.  Under her stewardship, the United Kingdom has withstood great challenges and enjoyed longstanding stability.  Throughout her reign, the United States has partnered with the United Kingdom to advance globally the democratic freedoms and values that lie at the heart of our mutual prosperity and security.</p>
<p>As host of both the G7 and the United Nations Climate Change Conference, this is a historic year of leadership for the United Kingdom.  We look forward to continuing to partner with the United Kingdom bilaterally and multilaterally to address the most urgent global challenges: ending and recovering from the COVID-19 pandemic, addressing the threat of climate change, and defending democratic values and open societies.</p>
<p>On this special day, I wish Her Majesty the Queen and the British people a year of health, peace, prosperity, and happiness.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I offer my best wishes to Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II and to the people of the United Kingdom as you celebrate Her Majesty’s birthday.</p>
<p>Queen Elizabeth’s lifetime of leadership and dedication to service is an example for all nations.  Under her stewardship, the United Kingdom has withstood great challenges and enjoyed longstanding stability.  Throughout her reign, the United States has partnered with the United Kingdom to advance globally the democratic freedoms and values that lie at the heart of our mutual prosperity and security.</p>
<p>As host of both the G7 and the United Nations Climate Change Conference, this is a historic year of leadership for the United Kingdom.  We look forward to continuing to partner with the United Kingdom bilaterally and multilaterally to address the most urgent global challenges: ending and recovering from the COVID-19 pandemic, addressing the threat of climate change, and defending democratic values and open societies.</p>
<p>On this special day, I wish Her Majesty the Queen and the British people a year of health, peace, prosperity, and happiness.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>World Day Against Child Labor</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/world-day-against-child-labor/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 23:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251488</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Child labor harms the physical and mental development of children, depriving them of their childhood, their potential, and their dignity. For their future and for the world’s future, we must do more to combat child labor and protect children from this scourge. June 12 is the World Day Against Child Labor, and 2021 is the International Year for the Elimination of Child Labor. We pledge to renew our commitment to end child labor and call upon our international partners to do the same.</p>
<p>Last year, the Convention on the Elimination of the Worst Forms of Child Labor became the first convention ratified by every member of the International Labor Organization (ILO). The world agrees: Children should not be subjected to hazardous work or criminal exploitation. We have been making progress to protect children from exploitation. Since 2000, the number of children involved in child labor around the world steadily decreased. The ILO and UNICEF’s latest estimate, however, shows the first increase in child labor in two decades – the world’s progress combating child labor becoming another victim of the global pandemic. We must collectively do more.</p>
<p>The United States’ trade agreements, trade preference programs, and finance programs are conditioned on governments taking steps to enforce child labor and other labor laws. The Department of State continues to monitor and report on child labor in our annual Human Rights Report and Trafficking in Persons Report, and we contribute to the Department of Labor’s annual Findings on the Worst Forms of Child Labor, the most comprehensive global report on this subject. The United States is committed to continuing its fight to end these practices and protect children around the world.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Child labor harms the physical and mental development of children, depriving them of their childhood, their potential, and their dignity. For their future and for the world’s future, we must do more to combat child labor and protect children from this scourge. June 12 is the World Day Against Child Labor, and 2021 is the International Year for the Elimination of Child Labor. We pledge to renew our commitment to end child labor and call upon our international partners to do the same.</p>
<p>Last year, the Convention on the Elimination of the Worst Forms of Child Labor became the first convention ratified by every member of the International Labor Organization (ILO). The world agrees: Children should not be subjected to hazardous work or criminal exploitation. We have been making progress to protect children from exploitation. Since 2000, the number of children involved in child labor around the world steadily decreased. The ILO and UNICEF’s latest estimate, however, shows the first increase in child labor in two decades – the world’s progress combating child labor becoming another victim of the global pandemic. We must collectively do more.</p>
<p>The United States’ trade agreements, trade preference programs, and finance programs are conditioned on governments taking steps to enforce child labor and other labor laws. The Department of State continues to monitor and report on child labor in our annual Human Rights Report and Trafficking in Persons Report, and we contribute to the Department of Labor’s annual Findings on the Worst Forms of Child Labor, the most comprehensive global report on this subject. The United States is committed to continuing its fight to end these practices and protect children around the world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Argentina Foreign Minister Solá</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-argentina-foreign-minister-sola/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 21:33:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Argentine Foreign Minister Felipe Solá to discuss the importance of bilateral, regional, and international efforts to promote democracy and human rights in Nicaragua. He highlighted our concerns regarding President Ortega’s arbitrary arrests of presidential candidates and attacks on independent media and civil society. The Secretary emphasized our desire to continue building upon the history of cooperation between the United States and Argentina in the promotion of human rights and democracy.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Argentine Foreign Minister Felipe Solá to discuss the importance of bilateral, regional, and international efforts to promote democracy and human rights in Nicaragua. He highlighted our concerns regarding President Ortega’s arbitrary arrests of presidential candidates and attacks on independent media and civil society. The Secretary emphasized our desire to continue building upon the history of cooperation between the United States and Argentina in the promotion of human rights and democracy.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; June 11, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-june-11-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 21:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=251411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:00 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Good afternoon and Happy Friday, everyone. Thank you for joining today’s State Department press briefing. I have one quick announcement to make at the top and then we will resume taking your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-UNITEDNATIONS"></a> The United States congratulates Albania, Brazil, Gabon, Ghana, and the United Arab Emirates on their election as non-permanent members of the UN Security Council for the 2022 to 2023 term.</p>
<p>We look forward to a strong and productive partnership with incoming members to address issues fundamental to the maintenance of international peace and security.</p>
<p>And with that, we’ll give it a few minutes to wait for the queue.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jennifer Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The embassy in Kabul announced today it was suspending all visa operations as of Sunday, and I was wondering if this applies to Afghan SIV applicants, and if so, whether the State Department will take any special considerations or do anything in order to ensure that these applicants are still processed in an expedient manner. Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-AFGHANISTAN"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks for your question, Jennifer. So due to COVID-19 conditions, the embassy in Kabul will, of course, temporarily be suspending visa interviews effective June 13th. And the team in Washington will actually continue processing applications at the chief-of-mission stage, but we’ll resume processing for qualified SIV applicants in Kabul, of course, as soon as it&#8217;s safe to do so. But again, just to continue to underscore, Secretary Blinken has said before, we&#8217;re withdrawing our forces from Afghanistan, but of course, we&#8217;re not withdrawing from Afghanistan. And, of course, while troops are planned to leave there in September, the United States will maintain a robust diplomatic presence throughout the U.S. embassy, and our teams in the consular section in Kabul and Washington will continue to process qualified SIV applications, of course, as expeditiously as possible.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s go to Said Arikat.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Inaudible) authority to close down the Palestinian Union of Health Workers Committee office in Ramallah, and they are predicting from – it could result in some catastrophic situation, especially with the medical situation being as bad as it is in the occupied territories. And just to follow up on yesterday&#8217;s Ms. Gayle Smith presentation on the 500 million vaccines, how would you distribute these vaccines if you decide to in a place like Gaza, where you don&#8217;t have any relations, it is actually besieged by Israel and Egypt? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-COVIDRESPONSE"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Said. I&#8217;ll take your second question first. I won&#8217;t get into the details of the how with the distribution, but I&#8217;ll continue to underscore that U.S. has received requests for vaccines from countries all over the world. And in fact, we&#8217;re sharing 25 million vaccine doses with recipients that include Mexico, Canada, the Republic of Korea, West Bank, and Gaza. And, of course, additionally U.S. is also purchasing 500 million doses of Pfizer vaccines and donating them to 92 low and lower-middle-income countries as well as economies defined by Gavi’s COVAX advanced market commitment, and to eight additional countries in the African Union.</p>
<p>To answer your first questions, we, of course, encourage all sides to refrain from steps that would exacerbate tensions.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s go to Laura Kelly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Oh, hi. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Yes, I can hear you, Laura.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, thank you. Can you talk about some of the most important topics of the meeting between President Biden and President Erdogan on Monday? Will you – how will you address concerns over significant human rights issues in Turkey? And do you have a reaction to the Taliban rejecting Turkey’s offer to provide search security to the Kabul airport?</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-TURKEYAFGHANISTAN"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Laura. So to touch on your last part, so U.S. officials, of course, have been meeting with Turkish officials as a part of our ongoing consultations with our friends in Afghanistan on the withdraw of troops from the U.S., and coalition of troops from the Afghanistan. Of course, we’ll continue to ensure the safety and security of U.S. diplomats and personnel. But to your first question, I have nothing to read out. I won&#8217;t get ahead of the President, and would refer you to the White House for that.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s go to Casey O&#8217;Neill.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Happy Friday. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Yes. Happy Friday. I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Awesome, thank you. So actually, I wanted to turn, if we could, to Myanmar. So earlier today, actually just a little while ago, UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Bachelet issued a statement essentially warning of the imminent further deterioration of the situation on the ground in Myanmar. And I was just wondering if you could provide us any sense of actions that the Biden administration are taking to one, hold the junta accountable for their various human rights – numerous – excuse me – human rights violations; and two, if there’s a specific point person within the administration that’s dealing with Myanmar. Of course, we’ve seen Ambassador Feltman. He is the point person – the special envoy for the Horn. We’ve seen other special envoys. So just wondering who exactly within the administration – within the State Department is kind of the point person on this crisis. Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-BURMA"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Well, I’ll take this – your – the second part of your question first. So we don’t have any personnel announcements to make, but what I can say at large is that we remain deeply concerned about the situation on the ground in Burma. And, of course, the military regime has shown no respect for the rule of law or the will of the people of Burma, which we are primarily concerned about. The regime’s actions, such as killing hundreds including dozens of children and unjustly detaining thousands of people, have shown little regard for justice. And again, we will continue to uplift the people of Burma, and the United States, of course, urges all countries to speak in one voice against the regime’s violence as well as the suffering of all of the people.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Simon Lewis.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi, thanks, Jalina. I have another follow-up from Gayle Smith’s comments yesterday at the press briefing. So regarding the 500 million Pfizer vaccines that the President has pledged to – from the U.S. – Ms. Smith said that those vaccines – those doses would be bought with already appropriated funds. So that – I’m taking that to mean that that’s coming out of the 4 billion dollars that the administration had already promised to COVAX. Could you just clarify when those original – originally the President announced 2 billion and then another 2 billion that would – U.S. would give to COVAX – sort of the understanding at the time was that was cash that would go to COVAX rather than the value of donated vaccines. So is that a change – has that been kind of recategorized now as $4 billion worth of vaccines basically – or I think the estimate for the vaccine donation is 3.5 billion.</p>
<p>And secondly, related to that, Gayle Smith was talking about aiming for global coverage with these vaccine donations but also focusing on countries where there are surges and also being responsive to other countries’ request. Does that put the U.S. at odds with COVAX stated goals – stated goal of COVAX which is giving vaccines to all countries – giving all countries equal access to vaccines. It seems that you’re focus on targeting countries, with surges and also some strategic partners and neighbors, is at odds with what COVAX is trying to do. Thanks.</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-COVIDRESPONSE2"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Simon, if you’re still here on the line, I’ll briefly touch on your first one and ask you to clarify your second one. I would kind of reiterate Coordinator Smith’s comments yesterday where she didn’t go into too much detail about the numbers, but then just to kind of reiterate what we said before, I believe, when Said was on the line, is that, of course, the U.S. is purchasing the 500 million doses of Pfizer vaccines and, of course, donating them to 92 low and lower-middle-income countries as it stands. But if you’re still on the line, if you could just briefly clarify your second question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah. Yeah, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Yeah, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah. Okay. Yeah, so the third question was just to clarify that those – the funds to pay for those vaccines is coming out of the already pledged $4 billion to COVAX, right? And the second question is: Is there some difference in the way that the U.S. is – wants to distribute these vaccines from COVAX’s sort of stated goal of giving all countries equal access to vaccines, whereas the U.S. has sort of saying we want to target countries where there are surges and we’re responding to requests from other countries. I guess we’ve seen vaccines go to South Korea and Mexico, so it seems that there are strategic interests at play in the distribution, which – is that at odds with COVAX’s criteria for distributing vaccines?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Well, I mean what I’ll say to that is that the United States has decided in coordination with COVAX where the vaccines will go. And, of course, like – as I’ve said before too, the 92 COVAX recipients but eight additional African Union Countries. And these countries were actually defined by COVAX due to their limited resources and a limited ability to purchase those vaccines outright. And I will leave it at that, thank you.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Roman Gressier – I apologize if I’m mispronouncing your last name – El Faro.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, that’s great, thank you. Could you please confirm that the State Department has submitted formal extradition requests for three of the 14 MS-13 leaders that the Justice Department charged with terrorism offenses in January? And if you can, why those three? Will you also submit some more requests, diplomatic requests, for the remaining?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So for the first part of your question, I’m going to have to refer you to the DOJ. For the second – your second question on diplomatic requests, we’ll actually have to take that back for you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Let’s go to Soyoung Kim.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just a question about North Korea G7 summit. I know there was no planned meetings, but will there be any pull-aside meetings between U.S., South Korea, and Japan to discuss North Korean issues during the G7 Summit?</p>
<p>And my follow-up question is I believe that President Biden will have his first in-person meeting with Russian President Putin next week in Switzerland. As Russia has a closer relationship with North Korea, do you think the two leaders will discuss cooperation for engaging with North Korea? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-DPRKRUSSIA"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So to your first question, I certainly won’t get ahead of the summit. And for your second question on leaders of the DPRK and Russia, I’d have to refer you to their governments to answer that.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Yangsoon Kim.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I want to ask about the phone call between the Secretary Blinken and the Chinese Yang. And you guys said that you discussed about the Biden administration’s comprehensive North Korea review. What was the response from the China?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> If I still have you, do you mind repeating your question, please?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes. I asked about the discussion between the Blinken and the Chinese Yang that discussed about the North Korean policy review. And what was the Chinese response about the Biden administration’s North Korean policy review?</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-DPRKCHINA"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So I would point you to our readout on Secretary Blinken’s call. We have that on our website. But just in sum, obviously, what they discussed was our comprehensive DPRK policy review which focused on the need for the United States as well as the PRC to work together for denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Elizabeth Hagedorn.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thank you. Can you give us an update on whether the indirect talks to bring home Americans detained in Iran are still active? And then given that several G7 member countries have dual citizens held in Iran, is Tehran’s prisoner-taking and a global strategy to deter it something that Secretary Blinken is discussing with leaders at this weekend’s summit? Thanks.</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-IRAN"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So to the first part of your question, we continue to call for the return of all U.S. citizens who are unjustly detained – of course, those who are in Iran and those who are unjustly detained in countries all over the world. And if I still have you, do you mind repeating your second question?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sure. Is the issue of hostage-taking in Iran an issue that Secretary Blinken plans on raising with leaders of the G7?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So I won’t get ahead of the Secretary’s meetings. And if we obviously have a readout, we will be sure to share the outcome of those meetings as well. Thanks.</p>
<p>We’ll take this last question from Kurdistan 24, Laurie Mylroie. I apologize if I said your last name wrong.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, I do. I’m sorry, I was on mute. I’m muted.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Do we still have Laurie?</p>
<p>(Interruption.)</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>This is Laurie Mylroie. Can you hear me now?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Yes, I can hear you, Laurie.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. My question concerns the <em>Washington Post</em> report that Russia has supplied Iran with advanced satellites that provide better surveillance capabilities. Does that change – how do you regard that and does that change your attitude towards the JCPOA negotiations?</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-RUSSIAIRAN"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Laurie, I believe she – I think if you’re still on the line it sounds like you completed your question. So what I’ll say is that we’re aware of and of course following these media reports about Russia potentially providing Iran with an advanced satellite system. Outside of that, we have nothing further to announce at this point. We don’t have any responses or any potential responses, if you will.</p>
<p>Thank you all for joining today. That concludes today’s daily press briefing.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:23 p.m.)</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:00 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Good afternoon and Happy Friday, everyone. Thank you for joining today’s State Department press briefing. I have one quick announcement to make at the top and then we will resume taking your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-UNITEDNATIONS"></a> The United States congratulates Albania, Brazil, Gabon, Ghana, and the United Arab Emirates on their election as non-permanent members of the UN Security Council for the 2022 to 2023 term.</p>
<p>We look forward to a strong and productive partnership with incoming members to address issues fundamental to the maintenance of international peace and security.</p>
<p>And with that, we’ll give it a few minutes to wait for the queue.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Jennifer Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The embassy in Kabul announced today it was suspending all visa operations as of Sunday, and I was wondering if this applies to Afghan SIV applicants, and if so, whether the State Department will take any special considerations or do anything in order to ensure that these applicants are still processed in an expedient manner. Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-AFGHANISTAN"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks for your question, Jennifer. So due to COVID-19 conditions, the embassy in Kabul will, of course, temporarily be suspending visa interviews effective June 13th. And the team in Washington will actually continue processing applications at the chief-of-mission stage, but we’ll resume processing for qualified SIV applicants in Kabul, of course, as soon as it&#8217;s safe to do so. But again, just to continue to underscore, Secretary Blinken has said before, we&#8217;re withdrawing our forces from Afghanistan, but of course, we&#8217;re not withdrawing from Afghanistan. And, of course, while troops are planned to leave there in September, the United States will maintain a robust diplomatic presence throughout the U.S. embassy, and our teams in the consular section in Kabul and Washington will continue to process qualified SIV applications, of course, as expeditiously as possible.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s go to Said Arikat.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Inaudible) authority to close down the Palestinian Union of Health Workers Committee office in Ramallah, and they are predicting from – it could result in some catastrophic situation, especially with the medical situation being as bad as it is in the occupied territories. And just to follow up on yesterday&#8217;s Ms. Gayle Smith presentation on the 500 million vaccines, how would you distribute these vaccines if you decide to in a place like Gaza, where you don&#8217;t have any relations, it is actually besieged by Israel and Egypt? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-COVIDRESPONSE"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Said. I&#8217;ll take your second question first. I won&#8217;t get into the details of the how with the distribution, but I&#8217;ll continue to underscore that U.S. has received requests for vaccines from countries all over the world. And in fact, we&#8217;re sharing 25 million vaccine doses with recipients that include Mexico, Canada, the Republic of Korea, West Bank, and Gaza. And, of course, additionally U.S. is also purchasing 500 million doses of Pfizer vaccines and donating them to 92 low and lower-middle-income countries as well as economies defined by Gavi’s COVAX advanced market commitment, and to eight additional countries in the African Union.</p>
<p>To answer your first questions, we, of course, encourage all sides to refrain from steps that would exacerbate tensions.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s go to Laura Kelly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Oh, hi. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Yes, I can hear you, Laura.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, thank you. Can you talk about some of the most important topics of the meeting between President Biden and President Erdogan on Monday? Will you – how will you address concerns over significant human rights issues in Turkey? And do you have a reaction to the Taliban rejecting Turkey’s offer to provide search security to the Kabul airport?</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-TURKEYAFGHANISTAN"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Laura. So to touch on your last part, so U.S. officials, of course, have been meeting with Turkish officials as a part of our ongoing consultations with our friends in Afghanistan on the withdraw of troops from the U.S., and coalition of troops from the Afghanistan. Of course, we’ll continue to ensure the safety and security of U.S. diplomats and personnel. But to your first question, I have nothing to read out. I won&#8217;t get ahead of the President, and would refer you to the White House for that.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s go to Casey O&#8217;Neill.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Happy Friday. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Yes. Happy Friday. I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Awesome, thank you. So actually, I wanted to turn, if we could, to Myanmar. So earlier today, actually just a little while ago, UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Bachelet issued a statement essentially warning of the imminent further deterioration of the situation on the ground in Myanmar. And I was just wondering if you could provide us any sense of actions that the Biden administration are taking to one, hold the junta accountable for their various human rights – numerous – excuse me – human rights violations; and two, if there’s a specific point person within the administration that’s dealing with Myanmar. Of course, we’ve seen Ambassador Feltman. He is the point person – the special envoy for the Horn. We’ve seen other special envoys. So just wondering who exactly within the administration – within the State Department is kind of the point person on this crisis. Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-BURMA"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Well, I’ll take this – your – the second part of your question first. So we don’t have any personnel announcements to make, but what I can say at large is that we remain deeply concerned about the situation on the ground in Burma. And, of course, the military regime has shown no respect for the rule of law or the will of the people of Burma, which we are primarily concerned about. The regime’s actions, such as killing hundreds including dozens of children and unjustly detaining thousands of people, have shown little regard for justice. And again, we will continue to uplift the people of Burma, and the United States, of course, urges all countries to speak in one voice against the regime’s violence as well as the suffering of all of the people.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Simon Lewis.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi, thanks, Jalina. I have another follow-up from Gayle Smith’s comments yesterday at the press briefing. So regarding the 500 million Pfizer vaccines that the President has pledged to – from the U.S. – Ms. Smith said that those vaccines – those doses would be bought with already appropriated funds. So that – I’m taking that to mean that that’s coming out of the 4 billion dollars that the administration had already promised to COVAX. Could you just clarify when those original – originally the President announced 2 billion and then another 2 billion that would – U.S. would give to COVAX – sort of the understanding at the time was that was cash that would go to COVAX rather than the value of donated vaccines. So is that a change – has that been kind of recategorized now as $4 billion worth of vaccines basically – or I think the estimate for the vaccine donation is 3.5 billion.</p>
<p>And secondly, related to that, Gayle Smith was talking about aiming for global coverage with these vaccine donations but also focusing on countries where there are surges and also being responsive to other countries’ request. Does that put the U.S. at odds with COVAX stated goals – stated goal of COVAX which is giving vaccines to all countries – giving all countries equal access to vaccines. It seems that you’re focus on targeting countries, with surges and also some strategic partners and neighbors, is at odds with what COVAX is trying to do. Thanks.</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-COVIDRESPONSE2"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Simon, if you’re still here on the line, I’ll briefly touch on your first one and ask you to clarify your second one. I would kind of reiterate Coordinator Smith’s comments yesterday where she didn’t go into too much detail about the numbers, but then just to kind of reiterate what we said before, I believe, when Said was on the line, is that, of course, the U.S. is purchasing the 500 million doses of Pfizer vaccines and, of course, donating them to 92 low and lower-middle-income countries as it stands. But if you’re still on the line, if you could just briefly clarify your second question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah. Yeah, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Yeah, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah. Okay. Yeah, so the third question was just to clarify that those – the funds to pay for those vaccines is coming out of the already pledged $4 billion to COVAX, right? And the second question is: Is there some difference in the way that the U.S. is – wants to distribute these vaccines from COVAX’s sort of stated goal of giving all countries equal access to vaccines, whereas the U.S. has sort of saying we want to target countries where there are surges and we’re responding to requests from other countries. I guess we’ve seen vaccines go to South Korea and Mexico, so it seems that there are strategic interests at play in the distribution, which – is that at odds with COVAX’s criteria for distributing vaccines?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Well, I mean what I’ll say to that is that the United States has decided in coordination with COVAX where the vaccines will go. And, of course, like – as I’ve said before too, the 92 COVAX recipients but eight additional African Union Countries. And these countries were actually defined by COVAX due to their limited resources and a limited ability to purchase those vaccines outright. And I will leave it at that, thank you.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Roman Gressier – I apologize if I’m mispronouncing your last name – El Faro.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, that’s great, thank you. Could you please confirm that the State Department has submitted formal extradition requests for three of the 14 MS-13 leaders that the Justice Department charged with terrorism offenses in January? And if you can, why those three? Will you also submit some more requests, diplomatic requests, for the remaining?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So for the first part of your question, I’m going to have to refer you to the DOJ. For the second – your second question on diplomatic requests, we’ll actually have to take that back for you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Let’s go to Soyoung Kim.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just a question about North Korea G7 summit. I know there was no planned meetings, but will there be any pull-aside meetings between U.S., South Korea, and Japan to discuss North Korean issues during the G7 Summit?</p>
<p>And my follow-up question is I believe that President Biden will have his first in-person meeting with Russian President Putin next week in Switzerland. As Russia has a closer relationship with North Korea, do you think the two leaders will discuss cooperation for engaging with North Korea? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-DPRKRUSSIA"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So to your first question, I certainly won’t get ahead of the summit. And for your second question on leaders of the DPRK and Russia, I’d have to refer you to their governments to answer that.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Yangsoon Kim.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I want to ask about the phone call between the Secretary Blinken and the Chinese Yang. And you guys said that you discussed about the Biden administration’s comprehensive North Korea review. What was the response from the China?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> If I still have you, do you mind repeating your question, please?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes. I asked about the discussion between the Blinken and the Chinese Yang that discussed about the North Korean policy review. And what was the Chinese response about the Biden administration’s North Korean policy review?</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-DPRKCHINA"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So I would point you to our readout on Secretary Blinken’s call. We have that on our website. But just in sum, obviously, what they discussed was our comprehensive DPRK policy review which focused on the need for the United States as well as the PRC to work together for denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Elizabeth Hagedorn.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thank you. Can you give us an update on whether the indirect talks to bring home Americans detained in Iran are still active? And then given that several G7 member countries have dual citizens held in Iran, is Tehran’s prisoner-taking and a global strategy to deter it something that Secretary Blinken is discussing with leaders at this weekend’s summit? Thanks.</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-IRAN"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So to the first part of your question, we continue to call for the return of all U.S. citizens who are unjustly detained – of course, those who are in Iran and those who are unjustly detained in countries all over the world. And if I still have you, do you mind repeating your second question?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sure. Is the issue of hostage-taking in Iran an issue that Secretary Blinken plans on raising with leaders of the G7?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So I won’t get ahead of the Secretary’s meetings. And if we obviously have a readout, we will be sure to share the outcome of those meetings as well. Thanks.</p>
<p>We’ll take this last question from Kurdistan 24, Laurie Mylroie. I apologize if I said your last name wrong.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, I do. I’m sorry, I was on mute. I’m muted.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Do we still have Laurie?</p>
<p>(Interruption.)</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>This is Laurie Mylroie. Can you hear me now?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Yes, I can hear you, Laurie.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. My question concerns the <em>Washington Post</em> report that Russia has supplied Iran with advanced satellites that provide better surveillance capabilities. Does that change – how do you regard that and does that change your attitude towards the JCPOA negotiations?</p>
<p><a id="post-251411-RUSSIAIRAN"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Laurie, I believe she – I think if you’re still on the line it sounds like you completed your question. So what I’ll say is that we’re aware of and of course following these media reports about Russia potentially providing Iran with an advanced satellite system. Outside of that, we have nothing further to announce at this point. We don’t have any responses or any potential responses, if you will.</p>
<p>Thank you all for joining today. That concludes today’s daily press briefing.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:23 p.m.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elections in Ethiopia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/elections-in-ethiopia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 17:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>On June 21, many Ethiopians will be able to cast ballots in elections, an important exercise of their civil and political rights.</p>
<p>These elections should not be seen as a singular event but rather as part of a democratic political process that involves dialogue, cooperation, and compromise.  To that end, we urge the Government of Ethiopia and all Ethiopians to commit to an inclusive, post-election political dialogue to determine a path forward to strengthen the country’s democracy and national unity.</p>
<p>We recognize the efforts that the National Electoral Board of Ethiopia (NEBE) and its staff have made to prepare for these elections at a time when so many Ethiopians are suffering and dying from violence and acute food insecurity caused by conflict.</p>
<p>We urge politicians and community leaders to reject violence and to refrain from inciting others.  All political actors and community leaders should seek to resolve grievances through negotiation, dialogue, and recognized non-violent dispute resolution mechanisms.</p>
<p>The United States continues to urge Ethiopia’s leaders to support a free media and an active civil society.  We urge the government to respect the right of citizens to freedom of expression, peaceful assembly, and association, and to reject the use of Internet shutdowns or network restrictions.</p>
<p>The United States is gravely concerned about the environment under which these upcoming elections are to be held.  The detention of opposition politicians, harassment of independent media, partisan activities by local and regional governments, and the many interethnic and inter-communal conflicts across Ethiopia are obstacles to a free and fair electoral process and whether Ethiopians would perceive them as credible.  The exclusion of large segments of the electorate from this contest due to security issues and internal displacement is particularly troubling.</p>
<p>The hardening of regional and ethnic divisions in multiple parts of Ethiopia threaten the country’s unity and territorial integrity.  The period following these elections will be a critical moment for Ethiopians to come together to confront these divisions.  The United States stands ready to help Ethiopia address these challenges and find a path to a brighter future.  We stand with all Ethiopians working toward a peaceful, democratic, and secure future for the country.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>On June 21, many Ethiopians will be able to cast ballots in elections, an important exercise of their civil and political rights.</p>
<p>These elections should not be seen as a singular event but rather as part of a democratic political process that involves dialogue, cooperation, and compromise.  To that end, we urge the Government of Ethiopia and all Ethiopians to commit to an inclusive, post-election political dialogue to determine a path forward to strengthen the country’s democracy and national unity.</p>
<p>We recognize the efforts that the National Electoral Board of Ethiopia (NEBE) and its staff have made to prepare for these elections at a time when so many Ethiopians are suffering and dying from violence and acute food insecurity caused by conflict.</p>
<p>We urge politicians and community leaders to reject violence and to refrain from inciting others.  All political actors and community leaders should seek to resolve grievances through negotiation, dialogue, and recognized non-violent dispute resolution mechanisms.</p>
<p>The United States continues to urge Ethiopia’s leaders to support a free media and an active civil society.  We urge the government to respect the right of citizens to freedom of expression, peaceful assembly, and association, and to reject the use of Internet shutdowns or network restrictions.</p>
<p>The United States is gravely concerned about the environment under which these upcoming elections are to be held.  The detention of opposition politicians, harassment of independent media, partisan activities by local and regional governments, and the many interethnic and inter-communal conflicts across Ethiopia are obstacles to a free and fair electoral process and whether Ethiopians would perceive them as credible.  The exclusion of large segments of the electorate from this contest due to security issues and internal displacement is particularly troubling.</p>
<p>The hardening of regional and ethnic divisions in multiple parts of Ethiopia threaten the country’s unity and territorial integrity.  The period following these elections will be a critical moment for Ethiopians to come together to confront these divisions.  The United States stands ready to help Ethiopia address these challenges and find a path to a brighter future.  We stand with all Ethiopians working toward a peaceful, democratic, and secure future for the country.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Presidential Election in Mongolia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/presidential-election-in-mongolia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 16:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251283</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States congratulates the people and government of Mongolia for their successful presidential election on June 9, the eighth such election since Mongolia’s peaceful democratic revolution in 1990. We commend Mongolia for its commitment to democracy, and we are proud to be Mongolia’s “third neighbor” and strategic partner. We look forward to working with President-elect Khurelsukh to continue building on that partnership and strengthening our shared democratic values and Mongolia’s sovereignty and independence.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States congratulates the people and government of Mongolia for their successful presidential election on June 9, the eighth such election since Mongolia’s peaceful democratic revolution in 1990. We commend Mongolia for its commitment to democracy, and we are proud to be Mongolia’s “third neighbor” and strategic partner. We look forward to working with President-elect Khurelsukh to continue building on that partnership and strengthening our shared democratic values and Mongolia’s sovereignty and independence.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States and the Republic of Palau Partner on Our Ocean Conference 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-and-the-republic-of-palau-partner-on-our-ocean-conference-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 15:32:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On the occasion of World Ocean Week, the United States is pleased to announce it will partner with Palau on the next Our Ocean Conference, planned for early 2022 in Koror, Palau.</p>
<p>All life on this planet depends on a healthy ocean.  It regulates our climate and weather, generates half our oxygen, and provides food and livelihoods for billions of people.  The Our Ocean Conference is a pivotal moment to spur global ocean action.  It is critical to work together with partners around the globe to mobilize commitments to advance sustainable fishing, promote marine protected areas, combat ocean plastic pollution, support maritime security, foster a blue economy, and create an ocean resilient to climate impacts.</p>
<p>It is important to note that the climate crisis is an ocean crisis.  Greenhouse gas pollution is having profound and dire impacts on the ocean.  To protect the ocean, we as a global community must keep the goals of the Paris Agreement within reach.  The ocean plays a vital role in our efforts to tackle the climate crisis, from reducing shipping emissions, to scaling up offshore renewable energy, to protecting and restoring coastal ecosystems that store carbon and protect coastlines – hence preserving resources that provide us life and livelihoods.</p>
<p>We look forward to working together with countries and other partners worldwide to ensure that the seventh Our Ocean Conference carries forward the momentum on “ocean and climate action” after November’s U.N. climate conference (COP26) and brings forward meaningful and actionable commitments to create a future that protects our ocean, our planet, and our people.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On the occasion of World Ocean Week, the United States is pleased to announce it will partner with Palau on the next Our Ocean Conference, planned for early 2022 in Koror, Palau.</p>
<p>All life on this planet depends on a healthy ocean.  It regulates our climate and weather, generates half our oxygen, and provides food and livelihoods for billions of people.  The Our Ocean Conference is a pivotal moment to spur global ocean action.  It is critical to work together with partners around the globe to mobilize commitments to advance sustainable fishing, promote marine protected areas, combat ocean plastic pollution, support maritime security, foster a blue economy, and create an ocean resilient to climate impacts.</p>
<p>It is important to note that the climate crisis is an ocean crisis.  Greenhouse gas pollution is having profound and dire impacts on the ocean.  To protect the ocean, we as a global community must keep the goals of the Paris Agreement within reach.  The ocean plays a vital role in our efforts to tackle the climate crisis, from reducing shipping emissions, to scaling up offshore renewable energy, to protecting and restoring coastal ecosystems that store carbon and protect coastlines – hence preserving resources that provide us life and livelihoods.</p>
<p>We look forward to working together with countries and other partners worldwide to ensure that the seventh Our Ocean Conference carries forward the momentum on “ocean and climate action” after November’s U.N. climate conference (COP26) and brings forward meaningful and actionable commitments to create a future that protects our ocean, our planet, and our people.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Spanish Foreign Minister González Laya</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-spanish-foreign-minister-gonzalez-laya-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 14:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=251260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Spanish Foreign Minister Arancha González Laya to reaffirm the strong U.S.-Spain alliance, friendship, and Transatlantic relationship.  Secretary Blinken emphasized the U.S. commitment to migration conducted through regular channels and in a safe, orderly, and humane manner.  The Secretary also reiterated U.S. support for NATO, including an increase to common funding, and highlighted our commitment to working with the EU and other partners to address shared challenges, including in the Middle East, Venezuela, and Nicaragua.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Spanish Foreign Minister Arancha González Laya to reaffirm the strong U.S.-Spain alliance, friendship, and Transatlantic relationship.  Secretary Blinken emphasized the U.S. commitment to migration conducted through regular channels and in a safe, orderly, and humane manner.  The Secretary also reiterated U.S. support for NATO, including an increase to common funding, and highlighted our commitment to working with the EU and other partners to address shared challenges, including in the Middle East, Venezuela, and Nicaragua.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
