<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:04:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Executive Vice President and Head of International Affairs at the U.S. Chamber of Commerce Myron Brillant At the CEO Summit of the Americas</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-executive-vice-president-and-head-of-international-affairs-at-the-u-s-chamber-of-commerce-myron-brillant-at-the-ceo-summit-of-the-americas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350742</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Los Angeles, California</p>
<p> InterContinental Hotel</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Well, Mr. Secretary, first off let me just say thank you for being here with us today.  And I just want to acknowledge upfront the strong partnership that we’ve had with the State Department in putting together the 4th annual Summit of the Americas.  And I want to give a shoutout to Jose Fernandez, the under secretary of state, and to Assistant Secretary Brian Nichols, but to your entire team &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>&#8212; because this is going to be, I know, a crazy week for the State Department.  And I want to begin by just acknowledging how complex and challenging a time it is for the U.S. Government, for the world community – the conflict in Europe, obviously the challenges with the U.S.-China relationship, and more broadly the issues you’re grappling with. So the fact that you’re here today at this summit, we very much greatly appreciate.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thanks, Myron.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>I want to ask you, Mr. Secretary, at the outset:  As you look at this Summit of Americas, and not just the CEO summit of it but the broader summit that President Biden and you are engaging with all these leaders from the region, tell us what’s important about it as you look at the foreign policy agenda, the administration, you think about it regionally, you think about it globally.  How does this summit fit into it?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, first, Myron, thank you.  Thank you for this partnership on our end, too.  We can’t do it without you.  We’ve had a partnership in so many ways with the Chamber across so many issues.  I think it’s especially important in our own hemisphere, so I’m grateful for everything that you’ve done and that the Chamber has done to be such an important presence here at the summit over the next three days.  Hugely, hugely, important.</p>
<p>And this is a critical moment for us.  On one level, it’s pretty simple, and it’s obvious but it’s no more – no less important for being obvious.  No other region in the world has the same direct impact on the lives and livelihoods of Americans than the hemisphere that we share.  It’s as simple as that.  So to some extent as goes the hemisphere, so go we.  And so we have a real stake in making sure that, together, we get this right.  And again, to state the obvious, this is a time of incredible challenge for all of us.  We’ve had a confluence of almost perfect storm events over the last few years that have had a profound effect here in the Americas: COVID, climate, some – a democratic deficit, migration, and of course the daily and changing impact of technologies on the lives of everyone.  You put all that together, we’ve lost 2.7 million lives &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>&#8212; from COVID in our hemisphere.  Our hemisphere has suffered the most from COVID.  At the same time, it’s 30 percent of global GDP.  If we get our act together and mobilize that effectively, there is so much we can do.  The leaders have not met in more than four years.  It’s time.</p>
<p>But to your point, and this is what I find so vital about this summit, as important as the government-to-government work is, that is far from the sum and substance of this gathering.  We have the business community, we have civil society, we have young people, we have all the different stakeholders in our hemisphere.  And if these three days, four days can galvanize some collective action together and then we can take that from the summit, I think we’ll have done a good thing.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Well, Mr. Secretary, thank you for framing it in the context of all the things that this region has to think about – the pandemic, the return to health and the return to stronger economies.  You have an economic plan that you want to talk about at this summit.  Can you give us a preview about what that economic plan looks like and a little bit about how the private sector will play into that economic plan?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, first, never get ahead of your boss, so the President &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Just a little bit of a &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Just a little bit.  The President’s going to be speaking to this later today, and I’m very excited about that.  It dovetails with a number of things that we’re doing here.  First, we have – with our partners throughout the region, we have a number of areas and issues that we’re trying to drive together.  There’s going to be a lengthy summit declaration that you’ll see that actually focuses in our work together on a number of areas, and the President’s economic plan dovetails with those areas.</p>
<p>So for example, we need to build greater health resilience in our hemisphere in two ways: we need to be better prepared to manage a future pandemic, but also in the daily lives of people.  We need to be able to provide better basic health services.  There are huge disparities.  One of the great things coming out of the summit – and this is where the private sector also is critical – is we have a commitment over the next couple of years to train 500,000 health professionals, generalists and specialists.  That’s going to make a huge difference if they are effectively deployed throughout our hemisphere in raising the basic level of health services.  That’s one, but the president’s going to address some of that.</p>
<p>Second, on the climate and energy agenda, there are huge needs but also huge opportunities to come together in a way that actually is beneficial to our economies and also beneficial to climate, beneficial to our energy security and infrastructure development.  He will speak to that.  We have to do more and we will do more in a positive way to bridge digital divides that exist within our countries, but also within the hemisphere itself.  Facilitating digital trade, doing it in a way that’s secure, that upholds basic democratic principles, but that also is much more inclusive so that we bridge some of these divides.  That’s going to be a big part of it.</p>
<p>But also – and this is really imperative and this is, again, where our partnership with the private sector is so important – we have to find ways together and make good on commitments together to create an environment in which business can really work effectively.</p>
<p>So we know there remain huge challenges when it comes to everything from regulatory frameworks to corruption.  It is vital that all of our partners – and we – work together to deal with these.  Because, for example, as we’ve discussed, there’s a lot of capital out there.  But it’s not going to be deployed if the environment in which you want to deploy it is simply too risky and too complicated.</p>
<p>We have these conversations all the time with our counterparts.  Hearing it from us is one thing; I think hearing it from the business community directly, that’s important too.  So the President’s going to address all that.</p>
<p>There are huge infrastructure demands throughout the world; there are huge infrastructure demands in our hemisphere.  How do we facilitate making sure that the government is playing its part in helping to support viable projects, in helping to mobilize capital?  All of that will be there.  I don’t want to get too far ahead of where he’s going to be; stay tuned.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Always smart not to get ahead of POTUS, of the President, your boss.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yes, it’s a good rule.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Look, you talked about energy security, you talked about the digital transformation, you talked about digital trade – all these are important areas for business to be in partnership with government, and not just our government but governments around the region.  How receptive is the message being heard in the region?  Now, I know you’re going to begin your bilaterals over the next couple days, you’ll have the big summit – do you see government leaders across the region understanding that this is a critical moment to come together?  Because we see quite a bit of change politically in the region, and I wonder how that factors into what you’re trying to achieve.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, look.  One of the, I think, strengths, in a sense, of our region, is – look, there are political differences.  We have democratic governments of the left, of the right, and of the center.  But despite what political differences there are, if the fundamentals are there, we’re going to be able to work very, very effectively together.  And whether it’s of the left, the right, or the center, there’s a common challenge for every single democracy in our hemisphere, and that’s to actually deliver concrete results for people.  One of the reasons you may see changes in governance is simply because people have lost faith in the – whatever the current existing administration is in a given country, whether it’s left, right, or center, in its ability to deliver practical things, concrete things.</p>
<p>So my sense, Myron, is in our conversations, governments are very motivated to figure out how do we actually deliver.  And it’s partly because it’s the right and necessary thing to do.  It’s probably the politically self-preservation thing to do as well.</p>
<p>So I think we have to work with that, work with partners, and find ways together to support change that creates the right environment – again, to, among other things, mobilize capital throughout the hemisphere.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Well, all those are very important principles and issues to think about.  One thing that you’ve talked about but I want to get a little deeper on is the rule of law &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yep.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  For business leaders, rule of law is fundamental.  We need certainty, we need transparency, we need accountability, and by the way, we want to be accountable also to the system.  Talk to me about the Alliance for Development in Democracy.  You have this pathway with a couple of countries in the region.  I’m sure you want to expand that to others.  How does that fit into this narrative, and how does it link up to the business community in terms of us working with you?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So I think this is a terrific initiative and it brings together, as you know, Costa Rica, the Dominican Republic, Panama.  In fact, I had my counterparts from those countries in Washington three or four months ago for a meeting of this alliance.  And we’re focused on very practical things like: how do we make governance work better for people, how do we make sure it’s inclusive, and how do we make sure that it does exactly what we’re talking about, it creates a better environment for, among other things, investment?</p>
<p>So one of the things we talked about is using some of the digital tools that have been developed to make sure governments adopt them.  That’s a way of combatting corruption, which is one of the single biggest challenges we face not only in the hemisphere, but around the world.  It cuts through red tape, so that also helps create a better business environment.  These are the kinds of initiatives that, in a very practical way, we’re trying to bring together.  And if we can demonstrate among a small number of countries that this works, I expect that’ll expand to others as well.</p>
<p><strong>BRILLIANT:</strong>  What does success look like at the end of this summit?  After our CEO summit, after your summit that the President leads, what does success look like, and how do we go forward and make sure that whatever is discussed here, we take into action?  And here, you can challenge the private sector.  We need to play a role.  But what does success look like?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Look, I think the private sector’s a critical partner on virtually everything that we’re doing.  And in fact, one of the greatest strengths we bring to the table is our ability to work together with the private sector in ways that other countries don’t or can’t.  So we want to see that mobilized to the greatest extent possible.</p>
<p>I think when it comes to the issues we’ve talked about, when it comes to basic good governance, when it comes to transparency, when it comes to rule of law, when it comes to combatting corruption, I think that’s something that the private sector rightly should and must insist on.  And hearing it directly from the private sector makes a big difference.  Certainly our partners hear it from us, and of course we have to deal with our own challenges, as we are.</p>
<p>But what does success look like?  It’s two things.  Yes, it’s what gets agreed at this – at the summit.  There’ll be important commitments; there’ll be important initiatives; there’ll be important declarations of intent.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Right.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>But three days is not 365 days.  This has to be done over 365 days.  We have to hold ourselves accountable to what is agreed here, the commitments that all of us make to try to move forward, and then really see where we are at every step along the way.  Are we delivering on that intent?  We’re not going to know that right away.  So look, I think we’ll have important – the lingo that we use – deliverables.  We’ll have good deliverables.  But the deliverables are only as good as their implementation.  They’re only as good as the sustained commitment to getting them done.</p>
<p>So maybe we should come back together in Los Angeles in a year’s time and see how we’re doing.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT: </strong> Los Angeles or others?  Well, this is the City of Angels, so I shouldn’t say other cities.  But we’ve got a lot of great cities in this country that would be happy to have this forum.</p>
<p>Look, I know you have limited time, and I want to ask you just sort of what should we be thinking about?  What should the business community be thinking about?  You’ve mentioned the big issues.  But what is it that we all need to be thinking about to drive home success?  Underscoring everything you just said.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> So for me, it’s a pretty simple proposition.  Not a single one of the issues that we’re working on and that are actually having an impact on the lives of people in every country in this hemisphere – not a single one can we effectively deal with alone.  And by alone, I mean no single government can do it and no – and even a group of governments can’t do it because we need to have partnerships with the private sector, with civil society, with other major stakeholders.  Climate, COVID, emerging technology, migration, all of these things defy unilateral solutions, either unilateral, again, on the part of a single government or unilateral on the part of a single stakeholder.</p>
<p>So it’s in a sense as basic as that.  If we can’t find ways to effectively partner, we’re not going to meet these challenges.  If we don’t meet these challenges, we’re not going to be responsive to our citizens.  And if we’re not responsive to our citizens, they’ll let us know.</p>
<p>So we need to get this right, but last thing I’ll say is this, and I think you’ll hear this from the President this afternoon because he is the eternal optimist and it’s an occupational requirement.  (Laughter.)  There’s huge opportunity here.  You all know this better than anyone.  You can see it, you can feel it, and you’re doing it.  The Vice President, with the call to action for investment in the Northern Triangle countries, that’s been a remarkable success – $3.2 billion in new investments generated just in the space of about a year.</p>
<p>So the opportunity is there.  The question is: How do we effectively work together to seize it?  And here, Myron, with the Chamber, hearing from you, talk – working with you, engaging with you so that we understand from the perspective of the business community what’s needed, and then we can use what influence we have to try to create – help create that environment.  That’s hugely important.</p>
<p>We’ll share the same with you, and I think if we’re working together, we’re going to get a lot done.  You take a step at a time, it doesn’t feel like you’re traveling too far.  As I say, in a year’s time, maybe we’ll see that we’ve actually covered a little bit of distance.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Well, one thing, and I know we have to run, is – I would add to the agenda is food security.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> Yeah.  Absolutely.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  We talked about energy security, rule of law, governance – all of these are important.  I think also at this time, with what’s happening in Europe, we have to work together on the food security issue.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> And I’m really glad you raised that.  And I know we’re over time, but let me say a quick word about that because it’s hugely important.  We have a, here again, historic food insecurity crisis that is global in nature.  Three years ago there were roughly 100 million people around the world who were considered severely food insecure.  That went up to about 160 million people last year.  Now, with Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, we’re adding another 40 million people to those who are severely food insecure around the world, so about 200 million people.  This is reaching historic proportions.</p>
<p>And here, too, we know we’ve had a perfect storm.  This has been the result of COVID.  It’s been the result of climate change.  And now it’s the result of conflict.  So we obviously have to deal with the underlying conditions one way or another.  But that’s going to take time.</p>
<p>In the meantime, what we’ve done is we’ve tried to bring countries together around the world to deal with the immediate challenge as well as the long-term challenge.  We have the presidency of the UN Security Council in the month of May.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT: </strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> Rotating presidency.  We decided to dedicate that presidency to focusing on food insecurity.  I went up to New York, spent a couple of days there.  We had about 40 countries together coming together on this, 40 foreign ministers, the Security Council itself, looking at the resources we need to put right now into the organizations that are helping deal with those who are food insecure – World Food Program, Food and Agricultural Organization, and others.  We looked at what can be done, and the President has done it, to generate, for example, the production of more fertilizer, half a billion dollars from the United States, to make sure that are folks are producing more.  If you don’t have the fertilizer on the market, crop yields go down, prices go up.  So we’ve got – we’re doing that.  Janet Yellen, our Secretary of the Treasury, is mobilizing the international financial institutions to help alleviate some of the financial burdens on countries that are dealing with this.</p>
<p>And at the same time, of course, we’re working, for example, to get wheat out of Ukraine.  There are 25 million tons of wheat that are sitting in silos at the ports in Odessa.  There’s 84, 85 ships filled with grain that can’t get out because of the Russian blockade.  We’re working to see that that gets lifted with the United Nations.  And we’re also working at other ways to get grain and other goods out of Ukraine so that they can get on to markets, people can have food, prices can go down.  All of this coming together.</p>
<p>But it takes continued action.  So we’re going to be working, for example, with the G7 countries to make sure that we are getting sustained action on this.  We had a – there, too, in New York at the UN, now more than 80 countries have signed on to a call to action that has specific things that each of us need to do to address this crisis.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Well, I know we’re running up against the clock, and I know that you’ve got staff that’s ready to pull me.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> We’ve literally run against the &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  And I would simply say, look, it may not be a fun job right now, but it’s certainly an interesting job, and we are so grateful for your leadership and for the President’s leadership at this critical time.  And I would just simply hope that you’re getting a little bit of a break periodically from your busy schedule.  But thank you so much for being at this summit and for offering your perspectives.  And very much appreciate the partnership that you expressed about the private sector and the Chamber in particular.</p>
<p>So please give him a round of applause.  Thank you very much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>Thanks.  Thank you.  Appreciate it.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Los Angeles, California</p>
<p> InterContinental Hotel</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Well, Mr. Secretary, first off let me just say thank you for being here with us today.  And I just want to acknowledge upfront the strong partnership that we’ve had with the State Department in putting together the 4th annual Summit of the Americas.  And I want to give a shoutout to Jose Fernandez, the under secretary of state, and to Assistant Secretary Brian Nichols, but to your entire team &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>&#8212; because this is going to be, I know, a crazy week for the State Department.  And I want to begin by just acknowledging how complex and challenging a time it is for the U.S. Government, for the world community – the conflict in Europe, obviously the challenges with the U.S.-China relationship, and more broadly the issues you’re grappling with. So the fact that you’re here today at this summit, we very much greatly appreciate.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thanks, Myron.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>I want to ask you, Mr. Secretary, at the outset:  As you look at this Summit of Americas, and not just the CEO summit of it but the broader summit that President Biden and you are engaging with all these leaders from the region, tell us what’s important about it as you look at the foreign policy agenda, the administration, you think about it regionally, you think about it globally.  How does this summit fit into it?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, first, Myron, thank you.  Thank you for this partnership on our end, too.  We can’t do it without you.  We’ve had a partnership in so many ways with the Chamber across so many issues.  I think it’s especially important in our own hemisphere, so I’m grateful for everything that you’ve done and that the Chamber has done to be such an important presence here at the summit over the next three days.  Hugely, hugely, important.</p>
<p>And this is a critical moment for us.  On one level, it’s pretty simple, and it’s obvious but it’s no more – no less important for being obvious.  No other region in the world has the same direct impact on the lives and livelihoods of Americans than the hemisphere that we share.  It’s as simple as that.  So to some extent as goes the hemisphere, so go we.  And so we have a real stake in making sure that, together, we get this right.  And again, to state the obvious, this is a time of incredible challenge for all of us.  We’ve had a confluence of almost perfect storm events over the last few years that have had a profound effect here in the Americas: COVID, climate, some – a democratic deficit, migration, and of course the daily and changing impact of technologies on the lives of everyone.  You put all that together, we’ve lost 2.7 million lives &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>&#8212; from COVID in our hemisphere.  Our hemisphere has suffered the most from COVID.  At the same time, it’s 30 percent of global GDP.  If we get our act together and mobilize that effectively, there is so much we can do.  The leaders have not met in more than four years.  It’s time.</p>
<p>But to your point, and this is what I find so vital about this summit, as important as the government-to-government work is, that is far from the sum and substance of this gathering.  We have the business community, we have civil society, we have young people, we have all the different stakeholders in our hemisphere.  And if these three days, four days can galvanize some collective action together and then we can take that from the summit, I think we’ll have done a good thing.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Well, Mr. Secretary, thank you for framing it in the context of all the things that this region has to think about – the pandemic, the return to health and the return to stronger economies.  You have an economic plan that you want to talk about at this summit.  Can you give us a preview about what that economic plan looks like and a little bit about how the private sector will play into that economic plan?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, first, never get ahead of your boss, so the President &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Just a little bit of a &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Just a little bit.  The President’s going to be speaking to this later today, and I’m very excited about that.  It dovetails with a number of things that we’re doing here.  First, we have – with our partners throughout the region, we have a number of areas and issues that we’re trying to drive together.  There’s going to be a lengthy summit declaration that you’ll see that actually focuses in our work together on a number of areas, and the President’s economic plan dovetails with those areas.</p>
<p>So for example, we need to build greater health resilience in our hemisphere in two ways: we need to be better prepared to manage a future pandemic, but also in the daily lives of people.  We need to be able to provide better basic health services.  There are huge disparities.  One of the great things coming out of the summit – and this is where the private sector also is critical – is we have a commitment over the next couple of years to train 500,000 health professionals, generalists and specialists.  That’s going to make a huge difference if they are effectively deployed throughout our hemisphere in raising the basic level of health services.  That’s one, but the president’s going to address some of that.</p>
<p>Second, on the climate and energy agenda, there are huge needs but also huge opportunities to come together in a way that actually is beneficial to our economies and also beneficial to climate, beneficial to our energy security and infrastructure development.  He will speak to that.  We have to do more and we will do more in a positive way to bridge digital divides that exist within our countries, but also within the hemisphere itself.  Facilitating digital trade, doing it in a way that’s secure, that upholds basic democratic principles, but that also is much more inclusive so that we bridge some of these divides.  That’s going to be a big part of it.</p>
<p>But also – and this is really imperative and this is, again, where our partnership with the private sector is so important – we have to find ways together and make good on commitments together to create an environment in which business can really work effectively.</p>
<p>So we know there remain huge challenges when it comes to everything from regulatory frameworks to corruption.  It is vital that all of our partners – and we – work together to deal with these.  Because, for example, as we’ve discussed, there’s a lot of capital out there.  But it’s not going to be deployed if the environment in which you want to deploy it is simply too risky and too complicated.</p>
<p>We have these conversations all the time with our counterparts.  Hearing it from us is one thing; I think hearing it from the business community directly, that’s important too.  So the President’s going to address all that.</p>
<p>There are huge infrastructure demands throughout the world; there are huge infrastructure demands in our hemisphere.  How do we facilitate making sure that the government is playing its part in helping to support viable projects, in helping to mobilize capital?  All of that will be there.  I don’t want to get too far ahead of where he’s going to be; stay tuned.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Always smart not to get ahead of POTUS, of the President, your boss.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yes, it’s a good rule.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Look, you talked about energy security, you talked about the digital transformation, you talked about digital trade – all these are important areas for business to be in partnership with government, and not just our government but governments around the region.  How receptive is the message being heard in the region?  Now, I know you’re going to begin your bilaterals over the next couple days, you’ll have the big summit – do you see government leaders across the region understanding that this is a critical moment to come together?  Because we see quite a bit of change politically in the region, and I wonder how that factors into what you’re trying to achieve.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, look.  One of the, I think, strengths, in a sense, of our region, is – look, there are political differences.  We have democratic governments of the left, of the right, and of the center.  But despite what political differences there are, if the fundamentals are there, we’re going to be able to work very, very effectively together.  And whether it’s of the left, the right, or the center, there’s a common challenge for every single democracy in our hemisphere, and that’s to actually deliver concrete results for people.  One of the reasons you may see changes in governance is simply because people have lost faith in the – whatever the current existing administration is in a given country, whether it’s left, right, or center, in its ability to deliver practical things, concrete things.</p>
<p>So my sense, Myron, is in our conversations, governments are very motivated to figure out how do we actually deliver.  And it’s partly because it’s the right and necessary thing to do.  It’s probably the politically self-preservation thing to do as well.</p>
<p>So I think we have to work with that, work with partners, and find ways together to support change that creates the right environment – again, to, among other things, mobilize capital throughout the hemisphere.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Well, all those are very important principles and issues to think about.  One thing that you’ve talked about but I want to get a little deeper on is the rule of law &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yep.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  For business leaders, rule of law is fundamental.  We need certainty, we need transparency, we need accountability, and by the way, we want to be accountable also to the system.  Talk to me about the Alliance for Development in Democracy.  You have this pathway with a couple of countries in the region.  I’m sure you want to expand that to others.  How does that fit into this narrative, and how does it link up to the business community in terms of us working with you?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So I think this is a terrific initiative and it brings together, as you know, Costa Rica, the Dominican Republic, Panama.  In fact, I had my counterparts from those countries in Washington three or four months ago for a meeting of this alliance.  And we’re focused on very practical things like: how do we make governance work better for people, how do we make sure it’s inclusive, and how do we make sure that it does exactly what we’re talking about, it creates a better environment for, among other things, investment?</p>
<p>So one of the things we talked about is using some of the digital tools that have been developed to make sure governments adopt them.  That’s a way of combatting corruption, which is one of the single biggest challenges we face not only in the hemisphere, but around the world.  It cuts through red tape, so that also helps create a better business environment.  These are the kinds of initiatives that, in a very practical way, we’re trying to bring together.  And if we can demonstrate among a small number of countries that this works, I expect that’ll expand to others as well.</p>
<p><strong>BRILLIANT:</strong>  What does success look like at the end of this summit?  After our CEO summit, after your summit that the President leads, what does success look like, and how do we go forward and make sure that whatever is discussed here, we take into action?  And here, you can challenge the private sector.  We need to play a role.  But what does success look like?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Look, I think the private sector’s a critical partner on virtually everything that we’re doing.  And in fact, one of the greatest strengths we bring to the table is our ability to work together with the private sector in ways that other countries don’t or can’t.  So we want to see that mobilized to the greatest extent possible.</p>
<p>I think when it comes to the issues we’ve talked about, when it comes to basic good governance, when it comes to transparency, when it comes to rule of law, when it comes to combatting corruption, I think that’s something that the private sector rightly should and must insist on.  And hearing it directly from the private sector makes a big difference.  Certainly our partners hear it from us, and of course we have to deal with our own challenges, as we are.</p>
<p>But what does success look like?  It’s two things.  Yes, it’s what gets agreed at this – at the summit.  There’ll be important commitments; there’ll be important initiatives; there’ll be important declarations of intent.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:  </strong>Right.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>But three days is not 365 days.  This has to be done over 365 days.  We have to hold ourselves accountable to what is agreed here, the commitments that all of us make to try to move forward, and then really see where we are at every step along the way.  Are we delivering on that intent?  We’re not going to know that right away.  So look, I think we’ll have important – the lingo that we use – deliverables.  We’ll have good deliverables.  But the deliverables are only as good as their implementation.  They’re only as good as the sustained commitment to getting them done.</p>
<p>So maybe we should come back together in Los Angeles in a year’s time and see how we’re doing.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT: </strong> Los Angeles or others?  Well, this is the City of Angels, so I shouldn’t say other cities.  But we’ve got a lot of great cities in this country that would be happy to have this forum.</p>
<p>Look, I know you have limited time, and I want to ask you just sort of what should we be thinking about?  What should the business community be thinking about?  You’ve mentioned the big issues.  But what is it that we all need to be thinking about to drive home success?  Underscoring everything you just said.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> So for me, it’s a pretty simple proposition.  Not a single one of the issues that we’re working on and that are actually having an impact on the lives of people in every country in this hemisphere – not a single one can we effectively deal with alone.  And by alone, I mean no single government can do it and no – and even a group of governments can’t do it because we need to have partnerships with the private sector, with civil society, with other major stakeholders.  Climate, COVID, emerging technology, migration, all of these things defy unilateral solutions, either unilateral, again, on the part of a single government or unilateral on the part of a single stakeholder.</p>
<p>So it’s in a sense as basic as that.  If we can’t find ways to effectively partner, we’re not going to meet these challenges.  If we don’t meet these challenges, we’re not going to be responsive to our citizens.  And if we’re not responsive to our citizens, they’ll let us know.</p>
<p>So we need to get this right, but last thing I’ll say is this, and I think you’ll hear this from the President this afternoon because he is the eternal optimist and it’s an occupational requirement.  (Laughter.)  There’s huge opportunity here.  You all know this better than anyone.  You can see it, you can feel it, and you’re doing it.  The Vice President, with the call to action for investment in the Northern Triangle countries, that’s been a remarkable success – $3.2 billion in new investments generated just in the space of about a year.</p>
<p>So the opportunity is there.  The question is: How do we effectively work together to seize it?  And here, Myron, with the Chamber, hearing from you, talk – working with you, engaging with you so that we understand from the perspective of the business community what’s needed, and then we can use what influence we have to try to create – help create that environment.  That’s hugely important.</p>
<p>We’ll share the same with you, and I think if we’re working together, we’re going to get a lot done.  You take a step at a time, it doesn’t feel like you’re traveling too far.  As I say, in a year’s time, maybe we’ll see that we’ve actually covered a little bit of distance.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Well, one thing, and I know we have to run, is – I would add to the agenda is food security.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> Yeah.  Absolutely.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  We talked about energy security, rule of law, governance – all of these are important.  I think also at this time, with what’s happening in Europe, we have to work together on the food security issue.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> And I’m really glad you raised that.  And I know we’re over time, but let me say a quick word about that because it’s hugely important.  We have a, here again, historic food insecurity crisis that is global in nature.  Three years ago there were roughly 100 million people around the world who were considered severely food insecure.  That went up to about 160 million people last year.  Now, with Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, we’re adding another 40 million people to those who are severely food insecure around the world, so about 200 million people.  This is reaching historic proportions.</p>
<p>And here, too, we know we’ve had a perfect storm.  This has been the result of COVID.  It’s been the result of climate change.  And now it’s the result of conflict.  So we obviously have to deal with the underlying conditions one way or another.  But that’s going to take time.</p>
<p>In the meantime, what we’ve done is we’ve tried to bring countries together around the world to deal with the immediate challenge as well as the long-term challenge.  We have the presidency of the UN Security Council in the month of May.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT: </strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> Rotating presidency.  We decided to dedicate that presidency to focusing on food insecurity.  I went up to New York, spent a couple of days there.  We had about 40 countries together coming together on this, 40 foreign ministers, the Security Council itself, looking at the resources we need to put right now into the organizations that are helping deal with those who are food insecure – World Food Program, Food and Agricultural Organization, and others.  We looked at what can be done, and the President has done it, to generate, for example, the production of more fertilizer, half a billion dollars from the United States, to make sure that are folks are producing more.  If you don’t have the fertilizer on the market, crop yields go down, prices go up.  So we’ve got – we’re doing that.  Janet Yellen, our Secretary of the Treasury, is mobilizing the international financial institutions to help alleviate some of the financial burdens on countries that are dealing with this.</p>
<p>And at the same time, of course, we’re working, for example, to get wheat out of Ukraine.  There are 25 million tons of wheat that are sitting in silos at the ports in Odessa.  There’s 84, 85 ships filled with grain that can’t get out because of the Russian blockade.  We’re working to see that that gets lifted with the United Nations.  And we’re also working at other ways to get grain and other goods out of Ukraine so that they can get on to markets, people can have food, prices can go down.  All of this coming together.</p>
<p>But it takes continued action.  So we’re going to be working, for example, with the G7 countries to make sure that we are getting sustained action on this.  We had a – there, too, in New York at the UN, now more than 80 countries have signed on to a call to action that has specific things that each of us need to do to address this crisis.</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  Well, I know we’re running up against the clock, and I know that you’ve got staff that’s ready to pull me.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> We’ve literally run against the &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR BRILLIANT:</strong>  And I would simply say, look, it may not be a fun job right now, but it’s certainly an interesting job, and we are so grateful for your leadership and for the President’s leadership at this critical time.  And I would just simply hope that you’re getting a little bit of a break periodically from your busy schedule.  But thank you so much for being at this summit and for offering your perspectives.  And very much appreciate the partnership that you expressed about the private sector and the Chamber in particular.</p>
<p>So please give him a round of applause.  Thank you very much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>Thanks.  Thank you.  Appreciate it.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States Establishes Complementary Mechanisms to Bolster Resiliency of the Hemisphere’s Health Economies and Ecosystems</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-establishes-complementary-mechanisms-to-bolster-resiliency-of-the-hemispheres-health-economies-and-ecosystems/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 18:57:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350749</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Department of Commerce, with the support of the U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services, announces annual multisectoral forum Americas RISE for Health. U.S. Department of State announces government-only Economy and Health Dialogue of the Americas. Together the two mechanisms will bolster resiliency of the hemisphere’s health economies and ecosystems.</p>
<p>Today on the eve of the Ninth Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles, Deputy Secretary of Commerce Don Graves and Under Secretary of State for Economic Affairs Growth, Energy, and the Environment Jose W. Fernandez announced the United States will establish complementary mechanisms to bolster resiliency of the hemisphere’s health economies and ecosystems. This announcement represents a first of its kind effort that will focus the region’s governments, private sector and civil society on shared challenges and opportunities to build resilient, inclusive, sustainable, equitable health economies and ecosystems.</p>
<p>Americas RISE for Health, convened by the U.S. Department of Commerce, with the support of the U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services, will harness the collective strengths of the region’s private sector and civil society and partner with the region’s governments to build the hemisphere’s supply chains back to be more resilient, enable digital health solutions to reach underserved populations, accelerate regulatory improvements, reduce trade and investment barriers to health financing, create ethical environments so health economies can thrive, and address other areas of need.</p>
<p>Economy and Health Dialogue of the Americas (EHA), convened by the U.S. Department of State, will establish a series of official sector-only convenings to increase political will and commitments across health and economy sectors necessary to strengthen public health systems in the Americas by initiating collaboration among countries in the region through ministries of foreign affairs, health, economy, trade and with regional expert organizations. The EHA will support the region’s governments to coordinate on pandemic prevention, preparedness, and response; identify and leverage best practices in the public sector to include health gap assessments, sustainable health budgeting, and effective service delivery to support economic resilience and recovery; promote anti-corruption practices to increase efficiency; and build more resilient health systems. Working in coordination with the Americas Business Dialogue, the EHA provides a government and member state-only platform to enable governments to assess country-specific concrete actions towards policy reform that would enable greater private sector and civil society participation in the region’s health economies, and investment opportunities.</p>
<p>Coordinating these two mechanisms will link governments with civil and private stakeholders to help meet the Biden-Harris Administration’s objectives of building a resilient hemisphere and bolstering economic resilience and opportunity in the Americas.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact: <a href="mailto:E_Communications@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="NotApplicable" data-linkindex="0">E_Communications@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Department of Commerce, with the support of the U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services, announces annual multisectoral forum Americas RISE for Health. U.S. Department of State announces government-only Economy and Health Dialogue of the Americas. Together the two mechanisms will bolster resiliency of the hemisphere’s health economies and ecosystems.</p>
<p>Today on the eve of the Ninth Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles, Deputy Secretary of Commerce Don Graves and Under Secretary of State for Economic Affairs Growth, Energy, and the Environment Jose W. Fernandez announced the United States will establish complementary mechanisms to bolster resiliency of the hemisphere’s health economies and ecosystems. This announcement represents a first of its kind effort that will focus the region’s governments, private sector and civil society on shared challenges and opportunities to build resilient, inclusive, sustainable, equitable health economies and ecosystems.</p>
<p>Americas RISE for Health, convened by the U.S. Department of Commerce, with the support of the U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services, will harness the collective strengths of the region’s private sector and civil society and partner with the region’s governments to build the hemisphere’s supply chains back to be more resilient, enable digital health solutions to reach underserved populations, accelerate regulatory improvements, reduce trade and investment barriers to health financing, create ethical environments so health economies can thrive, and address other areas of need.</p>
<p>Economy and Health Dialogue of the Americas (EHA), convened by the U.S. Department of State, will establish a series of official sector-only convenings to increase political will and commitments across health and economy sectors necessary to strengthen public health systems in the Americas by initiating collaboration among countries in the region through ministries of foreign affairs, health, economy, trade and with regional expert organizations. The EHA will support the region’s governments to coordinate on pandemic prevention, preparedness, and response; identify and leverage best practices in the public sector to include health gap assessments, sustainable health budgeting, and effective service delivery to support economic resilience and recovery; promote anti-corruption practices to increase efficiency; and build more resilient health systems. Working in coordination with the Americas Business Dialogue, the EHA provides a government and member state-only platform to enable governments to assess country-specific concrete actions towards policy reform that would enable greater private sector and civil society participation in the region’s health economies, and investment opportunities.</p>
<p>Coordinating these two mechanisms will link governments with civil and private stakeholders to help meet the Biden-Harris Administration’s objectives of building a resilient hemisphere and bolstering economic resilience and opportunity in the Americas.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact: <a href="mailto:E_Communications@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="NotApplicable" data-linkindex="0">E_Communications@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the Republic of Korea-U.S.-Japan Trilateral Vice Foreign Ministerial Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-the-republic-of-korea-u-s-japan-trilateral-vice-foreign-ministerial-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 16:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350669</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is the joint statement released by the Vice Foreign Ministers of the Republic of Korea and Japan and the Deputy Secretary of State of the United States.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin Text.</em></p>
<p>Republic of Korea (ROK) First Vice Foreign Minister Cho Hyundong, U.S. Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman, and Japan Vice Foreign Minister Mori Takeo met today in Seoul to discuss how our three countries will work together to address the challenges of the 21st Century for the benefit of the region and the world.</p>
<p>The Vice Foreign Ministers and the Deputy Secretary strongly condemned the repeated unlawful ballistic missile launches by the DPRK. They reaffirmed the outcomes of the May 27 Minister-level trilateral joint statement and committed to advance trilateral security cooperation to curb threats from the DPRK. The Deputy Secretary reaffirmed the United States’ steadfast commitments to the defense of the Republic of Korea and Japan, including extended deterrence. The Vice Ministers and the Deputy Secretary urged the DPRK to abide by its obligations under relevant UNSC resolutions and immediately cease actions that violate international law, escalate tensions, destabilize the region, or endanger global peace and security, and instead engage in dialogue toward the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. They stressed that a path to serious and sustained dialogue remains open and urged the DPRK to return to negotiations, while also expressing their hope that the DPRK will respond positively to international offers of assistance to fight against COVID-19. They reaffirmed the importance of achieving a swift resolution to the abductions issue.</p>
<p>The Vice Foreign Ministers and the Deputy Secretary discussed a range of pressing regional and global issues, including our joint efforts to support Ukraine, restore Myanmar to a democratic path, bolster engagement with ASEAN and within ASEAN-led architecture, enhance cooperation with Pacific Island countries, strengthen economic and energy security, prioritize women’s empowerment and workforce development, uphold international law, and promote a free and open Indo-Pacific, which is inclusive.</p>
<p>ROK-U.S.-Japan trilateral cooperation, grounded in our shared values, demonstrates that democracies can build a better future for their people, and the Vice Foreign Ministers and the Deputy Secretary decided to meet in Tokyo to continue their regular trilateral consultations as we advance our shared efforts.</p>
<p align="left"><em>End Text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is the joint statement released by the Vice Foreign Ministers of the Republic of Korea and Japan and the Deputy Secretary of State of the United States.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin Text.</em></p>
<p>Republic of Korea (ROK) First Vice Foreign Minister Cho Hyundong, U.S. Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman, and Japan Vice Foreign Minister Mori Takeo met today in Seoul to discuss how our three countries will work together to address the challenges of the 21st Century for the benefit of the region and the world.</p>
<p>The Vice Foreign Ministers and the Deputy Secretary strongly condemned the repeated unlawful ballistic missile launches by the DPRK. They reaffirmed the outcomes of the May 27 Minister-level trilateral joint statement and committed to advance trilateral security cooperation to curb threats from the DPRK. The Deputy Secretary reaffirmed the United States’ steadfast commitments to the defense of the Republic of Korea and Japan, including extended deterrence. The Vice Ministers and the Deputy Secretary urged the DPRK to abide by its obligations under relevant UNSC resolutions and immediately cease actions that violate international law, escalate tensions, destabilize the region, or endanger global peace and security, and instead engage in dialogue toward the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. They stressed that a path to serious and sustained dialogue remains open and urged the DPRK to return to negotiations, while also expressing their hope that the DPRK will respond positively to international offers of assistance to fight against COVID-19. They reaffirmed the importance of achieving a swift resolution to the abductions issue.</p>
<p>The Vice Foreign Ministers and the Deputy Secretary discussed a range of pressing regional and global issues, including our joint efforts to support Ukraine, restore Myanmar to a democratic path, bolster engagement with ASEAN and within ASEAN-led architecture, enhance cooperation with Pacific Island countries, strengthen economic and energy security, prioritize women’s empowerment and workforce development, uphold international law, and promote a free and open Indo-Pacific, which is inclusive.</p>
<p>ROK-U.S.-Japan trilateral cooperation, grounded in our shared values, demonstrates that democracies can build a better future for their people, and the Vice Foreign Ministers and the Deputy Secretary decided to meet in Tokyo to continue their regular trilateral consultations as we advance our shared efforts.</p>
<p align="left"><em>End Text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on Limited Resumption of Arctic Council Cooperation</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-limited-resumption-of-arctic-council-cooperation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 14:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350548</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The governments of Canada, the Kingdom of Denmark, Finland, Iceland, Norway, Sweden, and the United States have issued the following joint statement.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>In response to Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine, a flagrant violation of the principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity, based on international law, the other Arctic Council founding states – Canada, Finland, Iceland, the Kingdom of Denmark, Norway, Sweden, and the United States – on March 3 announced a pause in their participation in the Arctic Council. Since March 3, representatives from these States have examined modalities to allow a resumption of the work in the Arctic Council.</p>
<p>We remain convinced of the enduring value of the Arctic Council for circumpolar cooperation and reiterate our support for this forum and its important work.</p>
<p>We intend to implement a limited resumption of our work in the Arctic Council, in projects that do not involve the participation of the Russian Federation. These projects, contained in the workplan approved by all eight Arctic States at the Reykjavik ministerial, are a vital component of our responsibility to the people of the Arctic, including Indigenous Peoples.</p>
<p>We continue to examine additional modalities to allow us to further continue the Council’s important work.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The governments of Canada, the Kingdom of Denmark, Finland, Iceland, Norway, Sweden, and the United States have issued the following joint statement.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>In response to Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine, a flagrant violation of the principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity, based on international law, the other Arctic Council founding states – Canada, Finland, Iceland, the Kingdom of Denmark, Norway, Sweden, and the United States – on March 3 announced a pause in their participation in the Arctic Council. Since March 3, representatives from these States have examined modalities to allow a resumption of the work in the Arctic Council.</p>
<p>We remain convinced of the enduring value of the Arctic Council for circumpolar cooperation and reiterate our support for this forum and its important work.</p>
<p>We intend to implement a limited resumption of our work in the Arctic Council, in projects that do not involve the participation of the Russian Federation. These projects, contained in the workplan approved by all eight Arctic States at the Reykjavik ministerial, are a vital component of our responsibility to the people of the Arctic, including Indigenous Peoples.</p>
<p>We continue to examine additional modalities to allow us to further continue the Council’s important work.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Support for International Joint Commission Recommendations to Address Transboundary Pollution from Mining</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/support-for-international-joint-commission-recommendations-to-address-transboundary-pollution-from-mining/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 13:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On June 7, representatives from the Department of State, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, and U.S. Geological Survey met with Council members from the six governments of the transboundary Ktunaxa Nation, including the four Ktunaxa First Nation Governments of Yaq̓it ʔa·knuqⱡi’it First Nation (Tobacco Plains), ʔakisq̓nuk̓ First Nation, Yaqan Nuʔkiy (Lower Kootenay) and ʔaq̓am, the Kootenai Tribe of Idaho, and the Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes, in Bonners Ferry, Idaho, to discuss addressing pollution from mining in British Columbia that affects the United States and Canada.</p>
<p>The meeting underscored the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to strengthening Nation-to-Nation relationships by listening to Tribal priorities and respecting Tribal sovereignty.  During the meeting, the Department reaffirmed the Administration’s support for a joint reference to the International Joint Commission (IJC) under the Boundary Waters Treaty of 1909 for the Kootenai Basin regarding the transboundary impacts of mining.  A joint reference would respond to the need for impartial recommendations and transparent communication, build trust, and forge a common understanding of this issue among local, Indigenous, state, provincial, and federal governments as well as stakeholders and the public in both countries.</p>
<p>Support for a joint IJC reference reflects the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to protect public health; conserve our lands, waters, and biodiversity; and deliver environmental justice to communities overburdened by pollution.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On June 7, representatives from the Department of State, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, and U.S. Geological Survey met with Council members from the six governments of the transboundary Ktunaxa Nation, including the four Ktunaxa First Nation Governments of Yaq̓it ʔa·knuqⱡi’it First Nation (Tobacco Plains), ʔakisq̓nuk̓ First Nation, Yaqan Nuʔkiy (Lower Kootenay) and ʔaq̓am, the Kootenai Tribe of Idaho, and the Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes, in Bonners Ferry, Idaho, to discuss addressing pollution from mining in British Columbia that affects the United States and Canada.</p>
<p>The meeting underscored the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to strengthening Nation-to-Nation relationships by listening to Tribal priorities and respecting Tribal sovereignty.  During the meeting, the Department reaffirmed the Administration’s support for a joint reference to the International Joint Commission (IJC) under the Boundary Waters Treaty of 1909 for the Kootenai Basin regarding the transboundary impacts of mining.  A joint reference would respond to the need for impartial recommendations and transparent communication, build trust, and forge a common understanding of this issue among local, Indigenous, state, provincial, and federal governments as well as stakeholders and the public in both countries.</p>
<p>Support for a joint IJC reference reflects the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to protect public health; conserve our lands, waters, and biodiversity; and deliver environmental justice to communities overburdened by pollution.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meetings with Republic of Korea Minister of Unification Kwon and Vice Minister Kim</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meetings-with-republic-of-korea-minister-of-unification-kwon-and-vice-minister-kim/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 12:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350520</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met separately with Republic of Korea (ROK) Minister of Unification Kwon Young-se and Vice Minister of Unification Kim Ki-woong on June 8 and condemned the DPRK’s ballistic missile launches as a violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions and as deeply destabilizing to the region.  The Deputy Secretary underscored the importance of close cooperation between and among the United States, the ROK, and Japan to achieve the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>The Deputy Secretary, Minister, and Vice Minister also expressed concern about the impact of the DPRK’s COVID-19 outbreak on the North Korean people.  Deputy Secretary Sherman expressed support for efforts to prevent the spread of COVID-19 in the DPRK, including inter-Korean cooperation efforts.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met separately with Republic of Korea (ROK) Minister of Unification Kwon Young-se and Vice Minister of Unification Kim Ki-woong on June 8 and condemned the DPRK’s ballistic missile launches as a violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions and as deeply destabilizing to the region.  The Deputy Secretary underscored the importance of close cooperation between and among the United States, the ROK, and Japan to achieve the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>The Deputy Secretary, Minister, and Vice Minister also expressed concern about the impact of the DPRK’s COVID-19 outbreak on the North Korean people.  Deputy Secretary Sherman expressed support for efforts to prevent the spread of COVID-19 in the DPRK, including inter-Korean cooperation efforts.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Japanese Vice Foreign Minister Mori</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-japanese-vice-foreign-minister-mori-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 12:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with Japanese Vice Foreign Minister Mori Takeo in Seoul.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Vice Foreign Minister Mori emphasized the enduring importance of the U.S.-Japan Alliance to uphold an inclusive, free, and open Indo-Pacific.  The Deputy Secretary and Vice Foreign Minister discussed deepening U.S.-Japan economic cooperation, including plans for a ministerial-level Economic Policy Consultative Committee (EPCC) meeting in July and the importance of strengthening supply chain resiliency in high-tech sectors.  The Deputy Secretary and Vice Foreign Minister condemned DPRK missile launches and emphasized the importance of trilateral U.S.-Japan-ROK cooperation to tackle the most pressing regional and global challenges of the 21<sup>st</sup> Century.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with Japanese Vice Foreign Minister Mori Takeo in Seoul.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Vice Foreign Minister Mori emphasized the enduring importance of the U.S.-Japan Alliance to uphold an inclusive, free, and open Indo-Pacific.  The Deputy Secretary and Vice Foreign Minister discussed deepening U.S.-Japan economic cooperation, including plans for a ministerial-level Economic Policy Consultative Committee (EPCC) meeting in July and the importance of strengthening supply chain resiliency in high-tech sectors.  The Deputy Secretary and Vice Foreign Minister condemned DPRK missile launches and emphasized the importance of trilateral U.S.-Japan-ROK cooperation to tackle the most pressing regional and global challenges of the 21<sup>st</sup> Century.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Panel Discussion at the Media Summit of Americas Session: “A Commitment to Journalistic Freedom”</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-panel-discussion-at-the-media-summit-of-americas-session-a-commitment-to-journalistic-freedom/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 11:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350506</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Los Angeles, California Location</p>
<p>Herald Examiner Building</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you very much.  Well, good evening, everyone, and it is wonderful to be in Los Angeles, and particularly wonderful to be here in this extraordinary building.  And I want to start by saying thank you, thank you, thank you to Arizona State’s Cronkite School of Journalism, to USC’s Annenberg School of Journalism, to the Equis Institute, for partnering with us and putting this event together; and also, as important – more important, even – for their leadership in promoting independent journalism and civic participation, and for training rising generations of media professionals.</p>
<p>To the journalists and civil society leaders from across the hemisphere who made the journey to Los Angeles: welcome.  We’re so grateful to have you here – and especially grateful for the crucial work that you do every single day.</p>
<p>Finally, to any of the J-school students in the audience, we are heartened by the path that you’re taking.  Now, I say that with some degree of modest authority, as a one-time aspiring journalist myself.  Now, I’m old enough that when I briefly practiced the profession, I did it on something called a typewriter.  You can look it up.  You’ll find it somewhere on the internet.  But take it from someone who never fully realized that aspiration – it is a challenging path.  I suspect you know that already.  But I couldn’t be more inspired to see rising journalists here, and I’m really looking forward to reading your bylines and hearing you and seeing you in the media over the years ahead.</p>
<p>So starting tomorrow, the Ninth Summit of the Americas is going to bring together governments, civil society, youth, the private sector, and citizens from across our hemisphere to try to see how, together, we can tackle the fundamental problems that our societies face and do a better job at delivering for our people.  That is the mission that we set for ourselves.</p>
<p>In every country in the hemisphere, for every goal that we want to achieve, for every problem affecting the lives of our people, a free, independent press is essential.</p>
<p>We see that in the reporting around the hemisphere and the world – including by some people who are here today – whether that’s digging into the toughest topics, like corruption or abuses by security services; or lifting up the stories of grassroots leaders who are finding solutions to complex problems, like the youth activists in small island states who are helping their communities adapt to rising seas and other changes that are brought on by climate change.</p>
<p>Reporting on issues like these shows how a free, independent press is quite literally a cornerstone of healthy democracies.  And at its core is an idea, the idea that accurate information is a public good – one that helps people understand the events and forces shaping their lives; spotlights problems and solutions that they otherwise might not see; and, fundamentally, empowers citizens to engage meaningfully in their communities, their countries, and the world.  In democracies, we often look to the media to provide this public good.</p>
<p>It’s also the reason it’s so important that governments like ours are open to scrutiny, to questions from the media – even when occasionally it’s not the most comfortable thing to do.  And you can take that from me as well.</p>
<p>When I had the honor of becoming Secretary of State, one of the very first things I did was to reinstate the daily press briefing at the State Department.  And our spokesperson, Ned Price, is here with us today.  It’s why, wherever I travel around the world, I make a point of holding press conferences where I take questions from local media as well as with some of the media colleagues who travel with us around the world.  It’s why I’ll take questions from you when I get done with these remarks.</p>
<p>Yet today, we see that the right to freedom of expression, including freedom of the press, faces profound challenges in our own hemisphere and around the world.  Challenges that, if left unaddressed, could threaten the foundations of our democracies.</p>
<p>So what I’d like to do in this time that I have now is to highlight three of the challenges that we see, and what the United States is doing – together with journalists, media organizations, NGOs, multilateral organizations, philanthropies, the private sector, and other governments – what we’re all trying to do to tackle them.</p>
<p>The first challenge – this will not be news to anyone – is disinformation.  Many speakers today have highlighted how governments and non-state actors are seizing on vulnerabilities in our media ecosystem to create, to disseminate, to amplify false or misleading information.  We’ve seen how these falsehoods can polarize communities, poison the public square, undermine people’s trust in health systems, government institutions, in democracy itself.</p>
<p>Today, the United States is launching the first hub of the Digital Communication Network of the Americas.  Since creating the DCN in 2015, we’ve actually helped build a network of more than 8,000 journalists, educators, communicators and new media professionals, public officials and others around the world, who are working to combat state-sponsored disinformation and propaganda.</p>
<p>The network does this by developing and sharing evidence-based tools to help local actors provide people with accurate information.</p>
<p>Take one example, the pandemic.  We’ve seen governments and other actors intentionally spread false narratives about COVID-19’s origin, its transmission, and treatments in an effort to stoke fear, to sow doubt, including about safe and effective vaccines, to erode trust in democracy itself – including deliberately targeting Spanish-language social media in this region.</p>
<p>The spread, the reach of disinformation online is, quite simply, staggering.  One study that measured social media traffic over a 90-day period of the pandemic found that the entire World Health Organization COVID-19 site received only 25,000 social media engagements, compared to 2.1 million hits – million hits – for a single false story claiming that the coronavirus is a bioweapon stolen from Canada.  That’s wrong, by the way.</p>
<p>In response, DCN has connected investigative journalists, data scientists, public health officials to share effective strategies on disseminating accurate information about COVID-19 and debunking harmful myths on social media.</p>
<p>The strength of DCN is in the diversity and flatness of the network that’s been created.  It doesn’t try to prescribe one single solution, but what it does is it makes it easier for participants to learn from one another’s responses – whether through webinars or trainings, online learning hubs or research exchanges, even games and apps.  The new Americas chapter will complement DCN hubs in Africa and Europe, further broadening our network of partners and the ideas that they bring to the table.</p>
<p>Even as we take steps to counter disinformation, we have to always guard against measures that give governments overly broad powers to criminalize, to censor, or otherwise quash freedom of expression, as we’ve seen in the rash of so-called “fake news” laws passed by governments, some of which have been abused to harass or lock up journalists whose critical reporting the governments didn’t like.</p>
<p>This brings me to a second challenge: the ongoing threats, harassment, the violence faced by media workers across the region.</p>
<p>You all know this, because many of you are living it.</p>
<p>At least 17 journalists have been killed in this hemisphere in this year, according to the UNESCO observatory of killed journalists, including – most recently – Yesenia Mollinedo and Sheila Johana Garcia, the director and a reporter of the news website El Veraz, in Veracruz, Mexico, shot to death on May the 9th.</p>
<p>No region in the world is more dangerous for journalists.</p>
<p>Crimes like these persist in no small part because the people who order them and carry them out are so rarely held accountable.  That sends a message that these attacks can continue with impunity.</p>
<p>Repressive officials are also using new technologies to monitor journalists, to surveil their private communications – a practice unearthed, fittingly enough, through very dogged reporting.</p>
<p>Governments are using sweeping legislation to quash free expression, as we saw in the recent slate of amendments adopted by El Salvador in March and in April of this year.</p>
<p>In Cuba, Nicaragua, Venezuela, the simple act of carrying out investigative journalism is a crime.</p>
<p>In Nicaragua, journalists and political opposition candidates Miguel Mora and Miguel Mendoza, newspaper publisher Juan Lorenzo Holmann are currently unjustly imprisoned, after being sentenced under abusive legislation in trials that lacked basic due process.  Dozens of independent journalists have fled the country due to persecution and threats, including Anibal Toruno, Luis Chavarria Galeano, Jackson Orozco, who are with us this week at the summit.</p>
<p>In Cuba, independent journalists are subjected to systemic abuses, including house arrest for days, weeks at a time, beatings, forced exile.</p>
<p>When individual journalists are attacked, when they’re persecuted, when they’re imprisoned, when they’re targeted in any other way, the chilling effects reach far beyond the immediate victims.  Sometimes this can lead to the shuttering of a publication.  Other times, it can lead other reporters to self-censor or to leave the profession entirely.</p>
<p>So here’s some of the things that we’re trying to do about that.</p>
<p>The United States is working across the region to strengthen the rule of law, investing in training judges and prosecutors to investigate and prosecute such attacks, as well as those on human rights defenders and other civil society leaders.</p>
<p>We consistently speak up and speak out about attacks on journalists, in every country, in public and in private.  We document governments’ efforts to curtail freedom of expression in our annual human rights report.</p>
<p>We’re deepening our engagement with multilateral bodies that advocate for freedom of expression and the safety of journalists around the world, using our seat at the table to try to make them even more effective.  One of the reasons that it was so important for the United States to come back into these international organizations was to be able to assert some of this leadership at these tables.  And we’re helping to stand up new bodies to address emerging threats.</p>
<p>We’re very proud to join the new OAS Group of Friends of Freedom of Expression and Journalism and we welcome the creation of the OAS’s new Center for Media Integrity.  Luis, thank you for your leadership on this.  It’s very, very important.  And we’re deepening our engagement in the Media Freedom Coalition.</p>
<p>We’re also doing some very practical things that we hope will make a difference.  For example, increasing support for journalists who are facing threats of harassment.  USAID will provide up to $9 million to support a global Defamation Defense Fund for Journalists, which will offer liability coverage for journalists and news organizations targeted with unjust litigation.  This is one of the tools that repressive governments use.  They try to turn and distort the law against journalists by going after them with lawsuits that they can’t afford to defend.  We will help make sure that they can defend themselves.</p>
<p>The State Department is investing up to $3.5 million to launch a Journalism Protection Platform that will provide at-risk media professionals with physical and digital security training, psychosocial care, and other assistance when they are in one way or another under attack.</p>
<p>Third, we’re working to make independent media more sustainable.  Put simply: we will not have a vibrant, independent press if more and more outlets are shutting down because they can’t find a viable business model.</p>
<p>The United States is working with business groups, with the private sector, to help independent media become more financially sustainable.  We’re providing direct financial assistance to at-risk outlets.  We’ve committed $30 million to the International Fund for Public Interest Media, which will focus on assisting media in resource-poor and unstable settings, and $5 million to improve the financial viability of independent media outlets.</p>
<p>We’re also encouraging other countries to engage in similar means of support.  We had, as some of you know, a Summit for Democracy that President Biden convened last year.  One of the main areas of focus of the summit was finding ways collectively to provide support to independent media.</p>
<p>In my own judgment, it’s hard to think of a smarter investment in our democracies – given the incredibly brave and innovative work that journalists are doing throughout our region.</p>
<p>Journalists like Catherine Calderon, who many of you heard from, I think, earlier today.  Back in 2015, she was an activist.  She was helping to organize demonstrations against corruption in Honduras.  She kept running into Jennifer Avila, a journalist who was covering the protests.  The more they talked, the more they saw a similar gap: For all the ways Hondurans were hurt by corruption in their everyday lives, no media outlet was conducting independent, rigorous reporting on the problem.</p>
<p>That, of course, was no accident.  For years, Honduran activists and reporters who have tried to document corruption – and in particular, women – have been silenced through harassment, through threats, through discrimination, through violence.</p>
<p>So Catherine and Jennifer decided to launch a media outlet that would close that gap, and it was called <i>Contracorriente</i>, or counter current.  Since 2015, <i>Counter Current</i> has flourished.  It’s unearthed corruption at the highest levels of government, the military, the police, and it’s led to high-profile resignations and even prosecutions.  Reflecting on the founding of <i>Counter Current</i>, Catherine said, and I quote, “Now, more than ever, I feel it was necessary.  We had to exist…to be a space where we have the possibility of doing journalism…without being silent.”</p>
<p>The same is true for free, independent press across the hemisphere: It has to exist, now more than ever, for the well-being of our people, for the well-being of our communities, for the well-being of our democracies.</p>
<p>The United States is committed to being a partner not only in protecting this space but expanding it.  Thanks very much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  I want to know how you justify the invitation to Dr. Ariel Henry from Haiti when he is ruling with no mandate in contravention of the nation’s constitution, and then he’s been implicated in, I think you would admit, very serious crimes, including the murder of a Haitian journalist just this February by the Haitian police.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So we’ll have plenty of opportunity, I think, in the days ahead to talk about the summit, the participation in the summit, who’s here, who’s not.  In Haiti, we continue to work for a transition that leads to appropriate elections that are supported by all the Haitian people.  We continue to work to deal with gang violence that is afflicting the country and is doing terrible damage to the Haitian people.  We continue to work to try to find ways to support the Haitian people, who have borne more than their share of trouble in the last years, both human and naturally made.</p>
<p>So in all of these ways we’re working, including with partners in our hemisphere, to try to support the Haitian people.  But we want to see them have a truly representative government, and that goes down the path of getting to new elections in the coming time.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But Prime Minister Henry is refusing to negotiate with civil society.  Again, he is actually governing with no constitutional mandate.  His government has been implicated in many different crimes, including potentially the murder of the past president.  You yourself have said in your speech here today and in previous statements that countries like Venezuela, Cuba, Nicaragua, that you mentioned are being excluded from the Summit of the Americas because you deem them to not be democratic.</p>
<p>But how can you use that as your justification when you have the so-called prime minister of Haiti, who is ruling under no sort of democratic mandate here, despite the fact that this is well-known in terms of the repression of journalists, the repression of protesters, and his previous involvement in the coup against President Aristide that <i>The New York Times</i> has at least alleged the United States Government was supportive of?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Again, we, like many other countries, are determined to get into the facts of what happened in Haiti, including the assassination of the previous prime minister.  We’re determined to find the facts wherever they lead and to whomever they lead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  What about (inaudible)?</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Okay, and now – well, now we would like to get started on our conversation that we have planned here today.</p>
<p>S<b>ECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:  </b>Yes, I’m excited to get started on this, and I think everyone will enjoy it as well.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  (Off-mike.)</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  And we’ll have more time, of course, to answer these questions after the discussion that &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We’ll be happy to follow up with these questions.</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  For sure.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But Secretary Blinken, what about Shireen Abu Akleh &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you, all.  We really want our panel (inaudible).</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  &#8212; who was murdered by Israeli forces, right?  CNN just agreed to this.  These are your two greatest allies in the Middle East, Saudi Arabia and Israel.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Again &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  They have murdered American journalists and there have been absolutely no repercussions, and you’re sitting up here talking about the freedom of press and democracy.  The United States is denying sovereignty to tens of millions of people around the globe with draconian sanctions for electing leaders that you do not like.  Why is there no accountability for Israel or Saudi Arabia for murdering journalists?  It is one of the most dangerous places in the world to be a journalist in Palestine.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I deplore the loss of Shireen.  She was a remarkable journalist, an American citizen, as you well know.  And there too we are determined to follow the facts and get to the truth of what happened to her.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  The facts are established, Secretary Blinken.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  No, they have not yet been – no, they have – I’m sorry, with respect, they have not yet been established.  We are looking for &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Yes, they have.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  No, they have not.  We are looking for an independent, credible investigation.  When that investigation happens, we will follow the facts wherever they lead.  It’s as straightforward as that.  That has not yet happened, but it’s something that we very much want to see happen.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  And we’ll have time after the panel, of course, to talk more about this.  But Madison, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Yes, so thanks for joining us here tonight.  I’m super honored and excited to be here.  Now, one thing you mention in your remarks which I want to talk about a little more is the safety issues in journalism.  Journalists in countries, including democracies, put their safety and lives on the line in order to do their job.  And I know you talk about it a little bit in your remarks what the U.S. is doing, but what more do you think needs to be done to help ensure their safety?</p>
<p>And to the other journalists up here, is that something that kind of worries you guys entering this workforce?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, I think especially for reporters who are working in areas of conflict or working on societies where governments are engaged in repressive actions, the risk of doing the job is acute.  And as I mentioned, in our own hemisphere just in this year, a year that is only half over, 17 journalists at least have been killed, as documented by UNESCO.  So this is something that we take very, very seriously.</p>
<p>And a number of things I mentioned go directly at trying to help give journalists, especially in independent media where the resources may not be the same as for major media organizations, some tools to more effectively protect themselves faced with these dangers.  And it goes from everything to having the right tools to deal with their cyber security, to deal with their physical security, and also to deal with their legal and economic security.  All of these things are very practical programs that we’re working on, that we’re putting in place.  And not only are we doing it, we’re trying to do it with other countries around the world.  As I mentioned, at the Summit for Democracy that President Biden convened last year, this was one of the lines of effort that we put into place.</p>
<p>It’s also really important that we provide support for NGOs and other groups that are engaged in this kind of work in helping journalists, but we want to make sure as well that we’re hearing from people so that we understand exactly what they’re facing and maybe how we can be more helpful in helping them face it.</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Yeah, and do one of you guys want to answer?  Yeah.</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:  </b>I think part of why I love doing this is because it’s always new every single day.  You don’t know what you’re going to get yourself into, but that comes with a lot of safety issues.  Granted, I’m a journalist right now in Illinois.  It’s not somewhere where there’s a ton of conflict in terms of places abroad like we’ve seen.  There’s a lot of emotion when it comes to that.  But I think it fuels me more than anything to keep on going, and I just hope tonight we can kind of come to a consensus and find solutions and push the conversation forward to make sure that people feel welcomed to start in this path and keep it going.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  But is this something – as you’re thinking about and are engaged in careers, is this something that you’re actually thinking about that’s a concern, that is a &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MS BAITTO:</b>  Definitely.</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Oh yeah, definitely.  Even here in the U.S. when there has been different protests in the last several years, you see videos surface of stuff that happens to journalists.  So me seeing that as someone who’s entering this career field, that’s something that scares me.  You can go out and cover something, emotions are high, and something can happen here and abroad.</p>
<p><b>MS VILLALOBOS:  </b>There was something in your remarks that stuck out to me because there was a student at Cronkite that was part of her grad program.  She was trying to see if there are some courses that we could put into place about teaching safety to journalists, how to defend yourself when you’re out there, or even just teaching things that might not be common sense to everyone about keeping yourself safe.  And just hearing that in your remarks, seeing that we may be doing things like that on a national level, it just really resonated with me.  And I think that that’s a great idea.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, it’s kind of an extraordinary observation and comment because the idea that that would have been part, for example, of a journalism school curriculum 25 or 30 years ago, probably not.  So in many ways it’s a sad commentary, but it’s also, I think, a commentary on the fact that at least in different ways we’re trying to step up to this problem.</p>
<p>And I certainly hope that it doesn’t have the chilling effect that it’s designed to have, but that takes incredible courage.  It takes determination.  But what I found is a common denominator in the many years that I’ve been either a journalist myself for a brief period of time or working with journalists is an almost unquenchable desire to get at the truth, to get at the facts, including our two friends who raised questions just a few minutes ago.</p>
<p>That’s what we need.  We need to continue.  We need to be held accountable, but we also need to make sure that the structures, the protections are in place to allow people to do their jobs without fear of retribution of whatever kind.  And yes, the only way this should really happen is for our friends in the press to be yelling at me, not to have other people yelling at them.</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Of course.</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  And one thing that I think is significant, you wanted to kind of get into the journalism field and have had practice in it.  Do you think, when you had the idea to possibly go forward with this, was there – as a – was it as pervasive back then to be scared and to have some apprehensions in possibly becoming a journalist?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  It really depended what you were doing.  I had a good friend when I started out; we were on our college newspaper together, and then after school he went into reporting professionally and he wound up going to Central America in the 1980s.  So that was a challenging time, and that was not without its own kind of dangers.  Other reporters famously were in Asia and other places in times of – in places of conflict.</p>
<p>So I think there’s been a long history of reporters obviously being in places of conflict.  I think what’s changed in a sense is that the terrain of conflict has broadened out, and the kind of practices that some governments and others engage in has changed to make it more challenging for journalists in a broader variety of places than before.</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Yeah, and one thing I’ve noticed is as generations go on, I feel like there’s been a loss of trust in media.  I was actually talking to my grandfather about this the other day, and he said when he was growing up, he would watch the news, he would listen to Walter Cronkite, and you just trusted.  You had this trust.  But now I feel like we’ve lost so much trust as journalists, and I think in the past few years we’ve definitely seen people in power say things about the media and it obviously – other people start to believe that too.  So how can we rebuild that trust to get it to where it was once or even better?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  It’s one of the $64,000 questions and I’m not &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Yeah.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  &#8212; sure that there’s a good answer.  But you’re exactly right, and the Walter Cronkite example is a good one.  When I started out as a reporter after college – this is in the mid-1980s, just to situate in time – as a practical matter, most Americans got their news from one of the three networks at night: ABC, CBS, NBC.  There was a little bit of talk radio.  There was obviously no internet, no social media.  And there were these curators of the news at the networks and at the major newspapers – the <i>Times</i>, had the <i>L.A. Times</i> out here, <i>The</i> <i>Washington Post</i>, <i>The</i> <i>Wall Street Journal</i> – and that was where a lot of people got their information.  And of course, there was vitally important local media, which I’ll come to in a minute.  But you had these relatively small number of people who, in effect, edited the news that you consumed.</p>
<p>And in many ways, I think there was an expectation – I certainly had it – that the democratization of information that we’ve seen over the last 25 years would actually be a good thing, because there’s something that isn’t – doesn’t quite sit right with a small handful of organizations having such a dominant role in shaping the information that most people receive.  But we’ve also seen some of the downside of that, to state the obvious, and it’s very well known to just about everyone in this room.  We’ve lost these trusted mediators, trusted curators.  Now everyone is a publisher.  Some claim they’re not publishers, but that’s another matter.  And as a result, we have an incredible ecosystem of information that people, myself included, have a real hard time deciphering, and finding sources that are genuinely trusted is something that is increasingly a challenge for people.</p>
<p>So whether we can recapture that in some fashion, I don’t know.  Now, one of the things that we’ve tried to do is to help give people some of the tools to have digital literacy, to be able to separate the wheat from the chaff, to try to make their own judgments about the news and information that they’re consuming and not simply to take it at face value.  But this, of course, gets into all sorts of other complicated complications about where people go to look for their information, and the fact that we’re all, in effect, relegated to silos of our own choosing.  There’s a tremendous amount of self-selection, and we are all constantly looking for affirmation of the views that we bring to the table to begin with.  That also doesn’t make for the most healthy ecosystem.</p>
<p>So there’s a lot that goes into this, and ultimately, it ideally starts with the individual consumer to somehow demand that that kind of trusted information be what is – what’s out there on the market.  But there’s a lot that we could talk about.</p>
<p>But let me ask the three of you:  So how do you see this?  As people who are going into this field now at a time when trust for most institutions has been on a downward slope, including the media, how does that make you feel about the profession, and what would you want to do about it?</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  So I’ve been working for two years, now that I graduated – I was the first class to graduate during the pandemic – and I started journalism school 2016, when I think that’s the year we saw a huge shift in trusting the media.  And so this is all I’ve ever known.  I’ve only known that people don’t like us and that they don’t trust us, right?  I mean, there’s – the majority of us – people realize what we’re doing and I think so, but there’s bad actors there that totally might not really get behind what we’re doing.</p>
<p>But I think if I have been able to navigate how to ethically and factually report during this tough time, I’m ready to be thrown whatever is ahead.  But just to be frank, I think we talk about the future of journalism and there’s a lot of responsibility put on the new generation, as we should, right, because we’re the ones on the front lines – the next ones.  But if you guys don’t have the answers, we definitely don’t either, right?  But I think together we can find them.</p>
<p>But it’s going to be a give and take.  It’s going to take some time.  It’s going to take a lot of time, and it needs to start with education.  It needs to start with media literacy.  People need to understand how to transparently obtain a news outlet where they should go, where shouldn’t they go; what is factual, what is not; how do you figure that out on your own computer, on Facebook, on all these different outlets; and, honestly, to lead with compassion.  I think a lot of us as journalists and some of the ones that have been veterans and have had great, long careers get desensitized, as they should.  And I’m sure one day I will, too.  But I still have a lot of feelings towards everyone that I interview and all the stories that I tell, and I hope I don’t lose that because I think when you do, you lose humanity and what we really are here to do is – and it’s just give a voice to people that are – that don’t have a platform.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Yeah, well, that’s a wonderful way to look at it.  I think it’s a wonderful motivation.  I hope you don’t lose sight of that.  But here’s the hard truth:  We’re looking to you &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  Of course.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  &#8212; and to your generation for the answers.  We &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  We’ll get there.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  You’re the ones who need to figure this out.  We’ll try our best.</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  Yes, yes.</p>
<p><b>MS VILALOBOS:</b>  One of the points that you brought up earlier was about information overload, and that was actually one of the points that was brought up in a panel here earlier.  How do you personally sift through your social media feed and everything?  And I’m sure sometimes your own face pops up on there.  How do you handle that?  How do you find what you think is the sources that you want to trust and things like that, and how can – if you’re handling that, how can the public handle that as well?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  It’s the single biggest challenge that I think anyone in government faces, and it’s a challenge that I’ve seen evolve again over the last almost 30 years that I’ve been doing this.  When you had just a relatively limited number of sources of information 25 or 30 years ago, not only could you manage your day, but the pressure to respond was much less acute than it is now, than it’s been for the last decade or so.  There was a cushion, there was a gap in news emerging and then it really getting into the bloodstream of your community or your country.</p>
<p>Now it’s instantaneous.  It’s an intravenous feed, and that puts incredible pressure on people who are actually in government to react, to respond, to do something immediately.  Having the discipline to try to take a little bit of distance – to not just jump at a report that concludes X, because maybe it’s not conclusive; to actually have the distance and the remove to say no, we need to get to the facts, and even if there’s tremendous pressure to respond to what seem to be the facts – that’s not easy.</p>
<p>When I worked for President Obama, one of the, I think, thoughts that he had about this was that his job in a sense was to be something of a circuit breaker and to try to create that distance that no longer really exists, that moment of reflection, of deliberation, of trying to understand what the facts are before you simply reflexively respond because there’s pressure to do it and because you’re perceived as somehow weak or feckless if you’re not responding immediately.  That’s not an easy thing to do, but I think it is incumbent upon those of us who are in government or positions of public responsibility to at least try to do that.</p>
<p>And I think the challenge that media faces between – it’s a perennial challenge, but it’s gotten worse because of the immediacy of information.  The challenge between getting it right and getting it fast – there’s a huge responsibility that comes with that, too.  And that’s a responsibility you’re increasingly going to have to face in your careers, because the pressure on you to get it immediately – even if maybe you’re not getting it right, right away – is pretty intense.</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Yeah.  And then going on to like another topic, people these days with social media – anyone can be a journalist.  Anyone can get their phone, livestream something, post a picture that could be taken out of context and post it somewhere, and then people start to believe that this is true and then you have the spread of fake news.  But another issue with fake news I think we’re seeing a lot is people will see something that could be factual, but it doesn’t align with their preconceived ideas and this other thing that is actually fake does, and they call that fake news, and that spreads.  And that’s another issue with social media.  Do you feel that there needs to be any more regulation with social media?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, one of the things I’m going to try not to do is to delve into anything that smacks of politics or &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Yes.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Because, happily, my job lets me stay out of that.  But I think we’re – clearly this is a fundamental debate that we’re having, and now to get the – how to find where the right balance is is incredibly, incredibly challenging.</p>
<p>You mentioned as well, and these – a lot of these things join together – having the appropriate literacy to try to pull apart the information from the disinformation, the real from the fake, that’s something that needs to start really, really early.  One of the things we’ve seen, for example, is that as we rightly devote a lot of resources, for example, to STEM education or STEAM education in our countries, well, usually they’re finite budgets.  And when you look at budgets in schools, one place that the money that goes to STEAM or STEM often comes from is civics.  But if we’re not teaching civics, we’re not teaching the foundations that you need for something like digital literacy.  And that creates a problem very early on that just builds and builds and builds, and then if you don’t have a citizenry that has the tools to be able to deal with this information system, it makes it very, very challenging to deal with.</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  One thing that I’m a little curious with, just checking your Twitter, there’s been about more than a dozen tweets put on in the last 24 hours.  Clearly you’re not the social media influencer behind all of them, but what &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  (Laughter.)  Every single one.</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  Every single one, word for word.  But what is the process in which your team or one person, whatever it is, what is kind of the process that a tweet has to go through or any social media content has to go through when it has your name on it?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Yeah, it’s a great question and one that I and we take very seriously, because if I’m putting something out, then I’m simply here as a representative of the United States Government, so anything that we put out is supposed to be – to represent the government, to be reflective of it, to be reflective of our policies, and I’m simply a vehicle for doing that.</p>
<p>So we have a very carefully married-up operation between the folks on our communications team, the folks on our policy team, myself and other colleagues depending on what the subject is, and they need to know and understand each other in – almost intimately, because we have to make sure that whatever is going out under the State Department banner, whether it’s in my name or anyone else’s name, is an accurate reflection of the policies of our government and the President.</p>
<p>So a lot of care goes into that.  We don’t always get it 100 percent right, but we work at it every day.</p>
<p><b>MS VILALOBOS:</b>  And this social media topic, I think that it’s interesting.  We as journalists are always writing headlines, writing topics, things like that.  This era of clickbait culture and at-times sensational journalism, I think this is more of a – not so much a question as an idea.  This is just taking over, and I think that – I think that just the – there’s so many things that can go wrong when there is more drive for engagement in the headline rather than actual content in that headline.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, this goes to something we were talking about, and I was talking about a little bit earlier – is that there is a race to survive too.  The economics of this business are increasingly challenged, increasingly complicated.  That’s especially true, of course, in print media.  And so even social media, the clickbait phenomenon is part of – is partly making sure you get as many eyeballs as you can on something and then maybe drive the advertising revenues or drive your – so what used to be called readership.  So all that pieces together.</p>
<p>One of the reasons we’re trying to look for ways to build support for independent media is to help take some of that pressure off, and at least create a space where journalism is not motivated by that necessity.</p>
<p>Now, having said that, I often thought it would be really great fun writing headlines for tabloids.  (Laughter.)  That just sounds like a great job.  And just to date myself, again, one of the – I think the greatest – and I know I shouldn’t comment on individual publications, but I always thought growing up that the headline writers for the <i>New York Post</i> have one of the best jobs in the business.  (Laughter.)  Because the inventiveness of those headlines are incredible, and there’s just one that stuck with me from many, many years ago, back in the days of the Soviet Union.  One of the leaders of the Soviet Union passed away and the headline in the <i>New York Post</i> the next day was “Red Head Dead.”  (Laughter.)  That’s pretty good.</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  And I think for everyone we were really able to really talk about hopefully a good idea of where the future of journalism is going and hopefully inspires others.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, let me &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Thank you for joining us.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  No, let me just say to the three of you, first of all, it’s really inspiring to be with you.  It’s inspiring to see others out here, both colleagues who are engaged in the profession today, people who are just joining it.  I am so glad that you’re doing this, as I’m dead-serious about the proposition that this lies at the heart of our democracies.  And as goes journalism, as goes a free media, so go our democracies.</p>
<p>So what you’re doing is incredibly important.  It’s also incredibly challenging.  It goes to, I think, what you were saying about, first of all, trying to find the humanity that’s usually at the heart of things – to remember that, ultimately, you’re reporting on, writing about real people, complicated, imperfect as human beings are, to try to reflect that.  I know how hard it is too, because having been on both sides of this – when you’re in government and you’re in a room with 10 people and you’re talking about a policy, and then if you ask the 10 people in the room who said what and what were the conclusions, you’d probably get 10 different answers from people who were actually in the room.  You’re not in the room and you’re trying to figure out what was said in the room.</p>
<p>It’s incredibly hard, but it’s incredibly, incredibly powerful and incredibly necessary.  And I think having that drive to try to learn about something, to understand it, to know it, and then to be able to communicate it to your fellow citizens is a wonderful thing.  So it’s great to see all of you going into it.  Thanks.</p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Los Angeles, California Location</p>
<p>Herald Examiner Building</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you very much.  Well, good evening, everyone, and it is wonderful to be in Los Angeles, and particularly wonderful to be here in this extraordinary building.  And I want to start by saying thank you, thank you, thank you to Arizona State’s Cronkite School of Journalism, to USC’s Annenberg School of Journalism, to the Equis Institute, for partnering with us and putting this event together; and also, as important – more important, even – for their leadership in promoting independent journalism and civic participation, and for training rising generations of media professionals.</p>
<p>To the journalists and civil society leaders from across the hemisphere who made the journey to Los Angeles: welcome.  We’re so grateful to have you here – and especially grateful for the crucial work that you do every single day.</p>
<p>Finally, to any of the J-school students in the audience, we are heartened by the path that you’re taking.  Now, I say that with some degree of modest authority, as a one-time aspiring journalist myself.  Now, I’m old enough that when I briefly practiced the profession, I did it on something called a typewriter.  You can look it up.  You’ll find it somewhere on the internet.  But take it from someone who never fully realized that aspiration – it is a challenging path.  I suspect you know that already.  But I couldn’t be more inspired to see rising journalists here, and I’m really looking forward to reading your bylines and hearing you and seeing you in the media over the years ahead.</p>
<p>So starting tomorrow, the Ninth Summit of the Americas is going to bring together governments, civil society, youth, the private sector, and citizens from across our hemisphere to try to see how, together, we can tackle the fundamental problems that our societies face and do a better job at delivering for our people.  That is the mission that we set for ourselves.</p>
<p>In every country in the hemisphere, for every goal that we want to achieve, for every problem affecting the lives of our people, a free, independent press is essential.</p>
<p>We see that in the reporting around the hemisphere and the world – including by some people who are here today – whether that’s digging into the toughest topics, like corruption or abuses by security services; or lifting up the stories of grassroots leaders who are finding solutions to complex problems, like the youth activists in small island states who are helping their communities adapt to rising seas and other changes that are brought on by climate change.</p>
<p>Reporting on issues like these shows how a free, independent press is quite literally a cornerstone of healthy democracies.  And at its core is an idea, the idea that accurate information is a public good – one that helps people understand the events and forces shaping their lives; spotlights problems and solutions that they otherwise might not see; and, fundamentally, empowers citizens to engage meaningfully in their communities, their countries, and the world.  In democracies, we often look to the media to provide this public good.</p>
<p>It’s also the reason it’s so important that governments like ours are open to scrutiny, to questions from the media – even when occasionally it’s not the most comfortable thing to do.  And you can take that from me as well.</p>
<p>When I had the honor of becoming Secretary of State, one of the very first things I did was to reinstate the daily press briefing at the State Department.  And our spokesperson, Ned Price, is here with us today.  It’s why, wherever I travel around the world, I make a point of holding press conferences where I take questions from local media as well as with some of the media colleagues who travel with us around the world.  It’s why I’ll take questions from you when I get done with these remarks.</p>
<p>Yet today, we see that the right to freedom of expression, including freedom of the press, faces profound challenges in our own hemisphere and around the world.  Challenges that, if left unaddressed, could threaten the foundations of our democracies.</p>
<p>So what I’d like to do in this time that I have now is to highlight three of the challenges that we see, and what the United States is doing – together with journalists, media organizations, NGOs, multilateral organizations, philanthropies, the private sector, and other governments – what we’re all trying to do to tackle them.</p>
<p>The first challenge – this will not be news to anyone – is disinformation.  Many speakers today have highlighted how governments and non-state actors are seizing on vulnerabilities in our media ecosystem to create, to disseminate, to amplify false or misleading information.  We’ve seen how these falsehoods can polarize communities, poison the public square, undermine people’s trust in health systems, government institutions, in democracy itself.</p>
<p>Today, the United States is launching the first hub of the Digital Communication Network of the Americas.  Since creating the DCN in 2015, we’ve actually helped build a network of more than 8,000 journalists, educators, communicators and new media professionals, public officials and others around the world, who are working to combat state-sponsored disinformation and propaganda.</p>
<p>The network does this by developing and sharing evidence-based tools to help local actors provide people with accurate information.</p>
<p>Take one example, the pandemic.  We’ve seen governments and other actors intentionally spread false narratives about COVID-19’s origin, its transmission, and treatments in an effort to stoke fear, to sow doubt, including about safe and effective vaccines, to erode trust in democracy itself – including deliberately targeting Spanish-language social media in this region.</p>
<p>The spread, the reach of disinformation online is, quite simply, staggering.  One study that measured social media traffic over a 90-day period of the pandemic found that the entire World Health Organization COVID-19 site received only 25,000 social media engagements, compared to 2.1 million hits – million hits – for a single false story claiming that the coronavirus is a bioweapon stolen from Canada.  That’s wrong, by the way.</p>
<p>In response, DCN has connected investigative journalists, data scientists, public health officials to share effective strategies on disseminating accurate information about COVID-19 and debunking harmful myths on social media.</p>
<p>The strength of DCN is in the diversity and flatness of the network that’s been created.  It doesn’t try to prescribe one single solution, but what it does is it makes it easier for participants to learn from one another’s responses – whether through webinars or trainings, online learning hubs or research exchanges, even games and apps.  The new Americas chapter will complement DCN hubs in Africa and Europe, further broadening our network of partners and the ideas that they bring to the table.</p>
<p>Even as we take steps to counter disinformation, we have to always guard against measures that give governments overly broad powers to criminalize, to censor, or otherwise quash freedom of expression, as we’ve seen in the rash of so-called “fake news” laws passed by governments, some of which have been abused to harass or lock up journalists whose critical reporting the governments didn’t like.</p>
<p>This brings me to a second challenge: the ongoing threats, harassment, the violence faced by media workers across the region.</p>
<p>You all know this, because many of you are living it.</p>
<p>At least 17 journalists have been killed in this hemisphere in this year, according to the UNESCO observatory of killed journalists, including – most recently – Yesenia Mollinedo and Sheila Johana Garcia, the director and a reporter of the news website El Veraz, in Veracruz, Mexico, shot to death on May the 9th.</p>
<p>No region in the world is more dangerous for journalists.</p>
<p>Crimes like these persist in no small part because the people who order them and carry them out are so rarely held accountable.  That sends a message that these attacks can continue with impunity.</p>
<p>Repressive officials are also using new technologies to monitor journalists, to surveil their private communications – a practice unearthed, fittingly enough, through very dogged reporting.</p>
<p>Governments are using sweeping legislation to quash free expression, as we saw in the recent slate of amendments adopted by El Salvador in March and in April of this year.</p>
<p>In Cuba, Nicaragua, Venezuela, the simple act of carrying out investigative journalism is a crime.</p>
<p>In Nicaragua, journalists and political opposition candidates Miguel Mora and Miguel Mendoza, newspaper publisher Juan Lorenzo Holmann are currently unjustly imprisoned, after being sentenced under abusive legislation in trials that lacked basic due process.  Dozens of independent journalists have fled the country due to persecution and threats, including Anibal Toruno, Luis Chavarria Galeano, Jackson Orozco, who are with us this week at the summit.</p>
<p>In Cuba, independent journalists are subjected to systemic abuses, including house arrest for days, weeks at a time, beatings, forced exile.</p>
<p>When individual journalists are attacked, when they’re persecuted, when they’re imprisoned, when they’re targeted in any other way, the chilling effects reach far beyond the immediate victims.  Sometimes this can lead to the shuttering of a publication.  Other times, it can lead other reporters to self-censor or to leave the profession entirely.</p>
<p>So here’s some of the things that we’re trying to do about that.</p>
<p>The United States is working across the region to strengthen the rule of law, investing in training judges and prosecutors to investigate and prosecute such attacks, as well as those on human rights defenders and other civil society leaders.</p>
<p>We consistently speak up and speak out about attacks on journalists, in every country, in public and in private.  We document governments’ efforts to curtail freedom of expression in our annual human rights report.</p>
<p>We’re deepening our engagement with multilateral bodies that advocate for freedom of expression and the safety of journalists around the world, using our seat at the table to try to make them even more effective.  One of the reasons that it was so important for the United States to come back into these international organizations was to be able to assert some of this leadership at these tables.  And we’re helping to stand up new bodies to address emerging threats.</p>
<p>We’re very proud to join the new OAS Group of Friends of Freedom of Expression and Journalism and we welcome the creation of the OAS’s new Center for Media Integrity.  Luis, thank you for your leadership on this.  It’s very, very important.  And we’re deepening our engagement in the Media Freedom Coalition.</p>
<p>We’re also doing some very practical things that we hope will make a difference.  For example, increasing support for journalists who are facing threats of harassment.  USAID will provide up to $9 million to support a global Defamation Defense Fund for Journalists, which will offer liability coverage for journalists and news organizations targeted with unjust litigation.  This is one of the tools that repressive governments use.  They try to turn and distort the law against journalists by going after them with lawsuits that they can’t afford to defend.  We will help make sure that they can defend themselves.</p>
<p>The State Department is investing up to $3.5 million to launch a Journalism Protection Platform that will provide at-risk media professionals with physical and digital security training, psychosocial care, and other assistance when they are in one way or another under attack.</p>
<p>Third, we’re working to make independent media more sustainable.  Put simply: we will not have a vibrant, independent press if more and more outlets are shutting down because they can’t find a viable business model.</p>
<p>The United States is working with business groups, with the private sector, to help independent media become more financially sustainable.  We’re providing direct financial assistance to at-risk outlets.  We’ve committed $30 million to the International Fund for Public Interest Media, which will focus on assisting media in resource-poor and unstable settings, and $5 million to improve the financial viability of independent media outlets.</p>
<p>We’re also encouraging other countries to engage in similar means of support.  We had, as some of you know, a Summit for Democracy that President Biden convened last year.  One of the main areas of focus of the summit was finding ways collectively to provide support to independent media.</p>
<p>In my own judgment, it’s hard to think of a smarter investment in our democracies – given the incredibly brave and innovative work that journalists are doing throughout our region.</p>
<p>Journalists like Catherine Calderon, who many of you heard from, I think, earlier today.  Back in 2015, she was an activist.  She was helping to organize demonstrations against corruption in Honduras.  She kept running into Jennifer Avila, a journalist who was covering the protests.  The more they talked, the more they saw a similar gap: For all the ways Hondurans were hurt by corruption in their everyday lives, no media outlet was conducting independent, rigorous reporting on the problem.</p>
<p>That, of course, was no accident.  For years, Honduran activists and reporters who have tried to document corruption – and in particular, women – have been silenced through harassment, through threats, through discrimination, through violence.</p>
<p>So Catherine and Jennifer decided to launch a media outlet that would close that gap, and it was called <i>Contracorriente</i>, or counter current.  Since 2015, <i>Counter Current</i> has flourished.  It’s unearthed corruption at the highest levels of government, the military, the police, and it’s led to high-profile resignations and even prosecutions.  Reflecting on the founding of <i>Counter Current</i>, Catherine said, and I quote, “Now, more than ever, I feel it was necessary.  We had to exist…to be a space where we have the possibility of doing journalism…without being silent.”</p>
<p>The same is true for free, independent press across the hemisphere: It has to exist, now more than ever, for the well-being of our people, for the well-being of our communities, for the well-being of our democracies.</p>
<p>The United States is committed to being a partner not only in protecting this space but expanding it.  Thanks very much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  I want to know how you justify the invitation to Dr. Ariel Henry from Haiti when he is ruling with no mandate in contravention of the nation’s constitution, and then he’s been implicated in, I think you would admit, very serious crimes, including the murder of a Haitian journalist just this February by the Haitian police.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So we’ll have plenty of opportunity, I think, in the days ahead to talk about the summit, the participation in the summit, who’s here, who’s not.  In Haiti, we continue to work for a transition that leads to appropriate elections that are supported by all the Haitian people.  We continue to work to deal with gang violence that is afflicting the country and is doing terrible damage to the Haitian people.  We continue to work to try to find ways to support the Haitian people, who have borne more than their share of trouble in the last years, both human and naturally made.</p>
<p>So in all of these ways we’re working, including with partners in our hemisphere, to try to support the Haitian people.  But we want to see them have a truly representative government, and that goes down the path of getting to new elections in the coming time.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But Prime Minister Henry is refusing to negotiate with civil society.  Again, he is actually governing with no constitutional mandate.  His government has been implicated in many different crimes, including potentially the murder of the past president.  You yourself have said in your speech here today and in previous statements that countries like Venezuela, Cuba, Nicaragua, that you mentioned are being excluded from the Summit of the Americas because you deem them to not be democratic.</p>
<p>But how can you use that as your justification when you have the so-called prime minister of Haiti, who is ruling under no sort of democratic mandate here, despite the fact that this is well-known in terms of the repression of journalists, the repression of protesters, and his previous involvement in the coup against President Aristide that <i>The New York Times</i> has at least alleged the United States Government was supportive of?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Again, we, like many other countries, are determined to get into the facts of what happened in Haiti, including the assassination of the previous prime minister.  We’re determined to find the facts wherever they lead and to whomever they lead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  What about (inaudible)?</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Okay, and now – well, now we would like to get started on our conversation that we have planned here today.</p>
<p>S<b>ECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:  </b>Yes, I’m excited to get started on this, and I think everyone will enjoy it as well.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  (Off-mike.)</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  And we’ll have more time, of course, to answer these questions after the discussion that &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We’ll be happy to follow up with these questions.</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  For sure.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But Secretary Blinken, what about Shireen Abu Akleh &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you, all.  We really want our panel (inaudible).</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  &#8212; who was murdered by Israeli forces, right?  CNN just agreed to this.  These are your two greatest allies in the Middle East, Saudi Arabia and Israel.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Again &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  They have murdered American journalists and there have been absolutely no repercussions, and you’re sitting up here talking about the freedom of press and democracy.  The United States is denying sovereignty to tens of millions of people around the globe with draconian sanctions for electing leaders that you do not like.  Why is there no accountability for Israel or Saudi Arabia for murdering journalists?  It is one of the most dangerous places in the world to be a journalist in Palestine.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I deplore the loss of Shireen.  She was a remarkable journalist, an American citizen, as you well know.  And there too we are determined to follow the facts and get to the truth of what happened to her.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  The facts are established, Secretary Blinken.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  No, they have not yet been – no, they have – I’m sorry, with respect, they have not yet been established.  We are looking for &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Yes, they have.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  No, they have not.  We are looking for an independent, credible investigation.  When that investigation happens, we will follow the facts wherever they lead.  It’s as straightforward as that.  That has not yet happened, but it’s something that we very much want to see happen.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  And we’ll have time after the panel, of course, to talk more about this.  But Madison, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Yes, so thanks for joining us here tonight.  I’m super honored and excited to be here.  Now, one thing you mention in your remarks which I want to talk about a little more is the safety issues in journalism.  Journalists in countries, including democracies, put their safety and lives on the line in order to do their job.  And I know you talk about it a little bit in your remarks what the U.S. is doing, but what more do you think needs to be done to help ensure their safety?</p>
<p>And to the other journalists up here, is that something that kind of worries you guys entering this workforce?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, I think especially for reporters who are working in areas of conflict or working on societies where governments are engaged in repressive actions, the risk of doing the job is acute.  And as I mentioned, in our own hemisphere just in this year, a year that is only half over, 17 journalists at least have been killed, as documented by UNESCO.  So this is something that we take very, very seriously.</p>
<p>And a number of things I mentioned go directly at trying to help give journalists, especially in independent media where the resources may not be the same as for major media organizations, some tools to more effectively protect themselves faced with these dangers.  And it goes from everything to having the right tools to deal with their cyber security, to deal with their physical security, and also to deal with their legal and economic security.  All of these things are very practical programs that we’re working on, that we’re putting in place.  And not only are we doing it, we’re trying to do it with other countries around the world.  As I mentioned, at the Summit for Democracy that President Biden convened last year, this was one of the lines of effort that we put into place.</p>
<p>It’s also really important that we provide support for NGOs and other groups that are engaged in this kind of work in helping journalists, but we want to make sure as well that we’re hearing from people so that we understand exactly what they’re facing and maybe how we can be more helpful in helping them face it.</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Yeah, and do one of you guys want to answer?  Yeah.</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:  </b>I think part of why I love doing this is because it’s always new every single day.  You don’t know what you’re going to get yourself into, but that comes with a lot of safety issues.  Granted, I’m a journalist right now in Illinois.  It’s not somewhere where there’s a ton of conflict in terms of places abroad like we’ve seen.  There’s a lot of emotion when it comes to that.  But I think it fuels me more than anything to keep on going, and I just hope tonight we can kind of come to a consensus and find solutions and push the conversation forward to make sure that people feel welcomed to start in this path and keep it going.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  But is this something – as you’re thinking about and are engaged in careers, is this something that you’re actually thinking about that’s a concern, that is a &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MS BAITTO:</b>  Definitely.</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Oh yeah, definitely.  Even here in the U.S. when there has been different protests in the last several years, you see videos surface of stuff that happens to journalists.  So me seeing that as someone who’s entering this career field, that’s something that scares me.  You can go out and cover something, emotions are high, and something can happen here and abroad.</p>
<p><b>MS VILLALOBOS:  </b>There was something in your remarks that stuck out to me because there was a student at Cronkite that was part of her grad program.  She was trying to see if there are some courses that we could put into place about teaching safety to journalists, how to defend yourself when you’re out there, or even just teaching things that might not be common sense to everyone about keeping yourself safe.  And just hearing that in your remarks, seeing that we may be doing things like that on a national level, it just really resonated with me.  And I think that that’s a great idea.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, it’s kind of an extraordinary observation and comment because the idea that that would have been part, for example, of a journalism school curriculum 25 or 30 years ago, probably not.  So in many ways it’s a sad commentary, but it’s also, I think, a commentary on the fact that at least in different ways we’re trying to step up to this problem.</p>
<p>And I certainly hope that it doesn’t have the chilling effect that it’s designed to have, but that takes incredible courage.  It takes determination.  But what I found is a common denominator in the many years that I’ve been either a journalist myself for a brief period of time or working with journalists is an almost unquenchable desire to get at the truth, to get at the facts, including our two friends who raised questions just a few minutes ago.</p>
<p>That’s what we need.  We need to continue.  We need to be held accountable, but we also need to make sure that the structures, the protections are in place to allow people to do their jobs without fear of retribution of whatever kind.  And yes, the only way this should really happen is for our friends in the press to be yelling at me, not to have other people yelling at them.</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Of course.</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  And one thing that I think is significant, you wanted to kind of get into the journalism field and have had practice in it.  Do you think, when you had the idea to possibly go forward with this, was there – as a – was it as pervasive back then to be scared and to have some apprehensions in possibly becoming a journalist?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  It really depended what you were doing.  I had a good friend when I started out; we were on our college newspaper together, and then after school he went into reporting professionally and he wound up going to Central America in the 1980s.  So that was a challenging time, and that was not without its own kind of dangers.  Other reporters famously were in Asia and other places in times of – in places of conflict.</p>
<p>So I think there’s been a long history of reporters obviously being in places of conflict.  I think what’s changed in a sense is that the terrain of conflict has broadened out, and the kind of practices that some governments and others engage in has changed to make it more challenging for journalists in a broader variety of places than before.</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Yeah, and one thing I’ve noticed is as generations go on, I feel like there’s been a loss of trust in media.  I was actually talking to my grandfather about this the other day, and he said when he was growing up, he would watch the news, he would listen to Walter Cronkite, and you just trusted.  You had this trust.  But now I feel like we’ve lost so much trust as journalists, and I think in the past few years we’ve definitely seen people in power say things about the media and it obviously – other people start to believe that too.  So how can we rebuild that trust to get it to where it was once or even better?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  It’s one of the $64,000 questions and I’m not &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Yeah.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  &#8212; sure that there’s a good answer.  But you’re exactly right, and the Walter Cronkite example is a good one.  When I started out as a reporter after college – this is in the mid-1980s, just to situate in time – as a practical matter, most Americans got their news from one of the three networks at night: ABC, CBS, NBC.  There was a little bit of talk radio.  There was obviously no internet, no social media.  And there were these curators of the news at the networks and at the major newspapers – the <i>Times</i>, had the <i>L.A. Times</i> out here, <i>The</i> <i>Washington Post</i>, <i>The</i> <i>Wall Street Journal</i> – and that was where a lot of people got their information.  And of course, there was vitally important local media, which I’ll come to in a minute.  But you had these relatively small number of people who, in effect, edited the news that you consumed.</p>
<p>And in many ways, I think there was an expectation – I certainly had it – that the democratization of information that we’ve seen over the last 25 years would actually be a good thing, because there’s something that isn’t – doesn’t quite sit right with a small handful of organizations having such a dominant role in shaping the information that most people receive.  But we’ve also seen some of the downside of that, to state the obvious, and it’s very well known to just about everyone in this room.  We’ve lost these trusted mediators, trusted curators.  Now everyone is a publisher.  Some claim they’re not publishers, but that’s another matter.  And as a result, we have an incredible ecosystem of information that people, myself included, have a real hard time deciphering, and finding sources that are genuinely trusted is something that is increasingly a challenge for people.</p>
<p>So whether we can recapture that in some fashion, I don’t know.  Now, one of the things that we’ve tried to do is to help give people some of the tools to have digital literacy, to be able to separate the wheat from the chaff, to try to make their own judgments about the news and information that they’re consuming and not simply to take it at face value.  But this, of course, gets into all sorts of other complicated complications about where people go to look for their information, and the fact that we’re all, in effect, relegated to silos of our own choosing.  There’s a tremendous amount of self-selection, and we are all constantly looking for affirmation of the views that we bring to the table to begin with.  That also doesn’t make for the most healthy ecosystem.</p>
<p>So there’s a lot that goes into this, and ultimately, it ideally starts with the individual consumer to somehow demand that that kind of trusted information be what is – what’s out there on the market.  But there’s a lot that we could talk about.</p>
<p>But let me ask the three of you:  So how do you see this?  As people who are going into this field now at a time when trust for most institutions has been on a downward slope, including the media, how does that make you feel about the profession, and what would you want to do about it?</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  So I’ve been working for two years, now that I graduated – I was the first class to graduate during the pandemic – and I started journalism school 2016, when I think that’s the year we saw a huge shift in trusting the media.  And so this is all I’ve ever known.  I’ve only known that people don’t like us and that they don’t trust us, right?  I mean, there’s – the majority of us – people realize what we’re doing and I think so, but there’s bad actors there that totally might not really get behind what we’re doing.</p>
<p>But I think if I have been able to navigate how to ethically and factually report during this tough time, I’m ready to be thrown whatever is ahead.  But just to be frank, I think we talk about the future of journalism and there’s a lot of responsibility put on the new generation, as we should, right, because we’re the ones on the front lines – the next ones.  But if you guys don’t have the answers, we definitely don’t either, right?  But I think together we can find them.</p>
<p>But it’s going to be a give and take.  It’s going to take some time.  It’s going to take a lot of time, and it needs to start with education.  It needs to start with media literacy.  People need to understand how to transparently obtain a news outlet where they should go, where shouldn’t they go; what is factual, what is not; how do you figure that out on your own computer, on Facebook, on all these different outlets; and, honestly, to lead with compassion.  I think a lot of us as journalists and some of the ones that have been veterans and have had great, long careers get desensitized, as they should.  And I’m sure one day I will, too.  But I still have a lot of feelings towards everyone that I interview and all the stories that I tell, and I hope I don’t lose that because I think when you do, you lose humanity and what we really are here to do is – and it’s just give a voice to people that are – that don’t have a platform.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Yeah, well, that’s a wonderful way to look at it.  I think it’s a wonderful motivation.  I hope you don’t lose sight of that.  But here’s the hard truth:  We’re looking to you &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  Of course.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  &#8212; and to your generation for the answers.  We &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  We’ll get there.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  You’re the ones who need to figure this out.  We’ll try our best.</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  Yes, yes.</p>
<p><b>MS VILALOBOS:</b>  One of the points that you brought up earlier was about information overload, and that was actually one of the points that was brought up in a panel here earlier.  How do you personally sift through your social media feed and everything?  And I’m sure sometimes your own face pops up on there.  How do you handle that?  How do you find what you think is the sources that you want to trust and things like that, and how can – if you’re handling that, how can the public handle that as well?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  It’s the single biggest challenge that I think anyone in government faces, and it’s a challenge that I’ve seen evolve again over the last almost 30 years that I’ve been doing this.  When you had just a relatively limited number of sources of information 25 or 30 years ago, not only could you manage your day, but the pressure to respond was much less acute than it is now, than it’s been for the last decade or so.  There was a cushion, there was a gap in news emerging and then it really getting into the bloodstream of your community or your country.</p>
<p>Now it’s instantaneous.  It’s an intravenous feed, and that puts incredible pressure on people who are actually in government to react, to respond, to do something immediately.  Having the discipline to try to take a little bit of distance – to not just jump at a report that concludes X, because maybe it’s not conclusive; to actually have the distance and the remove to say no, we need to get to the facts, and even if there’s tremendous pressure to respond to what seem to be the facts – that’s not easy.</p>
<p>When I worked for President Obama, one of the, I think, thoughts that he had about this was that his job in a sense was to be something of a circuit breaker and to try to create that distance that no longer really exists, that moment of reflection, of deliberation, of trying to understand what the facts are before you simply reflexively respond because there’s pressure to do it and because you’re perceived as somehow weak or feckless if you’re not responding immediately.  That’s not an easy thing to do, but I think it is incumbent upon those of us who are in government or positions of public responsibility to at least try to do that.</p>
<p>And I think the challenge that media faces between – it’s a perennial challenge, but it’s gotten worse because of the immediacy of information.  The challenge between getting it right and getting it fast – there’s a huge responsibility that comes with that, too.  And that’s a responsibility you’re increasingly going to have to face in your careers, because the pressure on you to get it immediately – even if maybe you’re not getting it right, right away – is pretty intense.</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Yeah.  And then going on to like another topic, people these days with social media – anyone can be a journalist.  Anyone can get their phone, livestream something, post a picture that could be taken out of context and post it somewhere, and then people start to believe that this is true and then you have the spread of fake news.  But another issue with fake news I think we’re seeing a lot is people will see something that could be factual, but it doesn’t align with their preconceived ideas and this other thing that is actually fake does, and they call that fake news, and that spreads.  And that’s another issue with social media.  Do you feel that there needs to be any more regulation with social media?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, one of the things I’m going to try not to do is to delve into anything that smacks of politics or &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Yes.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Because, happily, my job lets me stay out of that.  But I think we’re – clearly this is a fundamental debate that we’re having, and now to get the – how to find where the right balance is is incredibly, incredibly challenging.</p>
<p>You mentioned as well, and these – a lot of these things join together – having the appropriate literacy to try to pull apart the information from the disinformation, the real from the fake, that’s something that needs to start really, really early.  One of the things we’ve seen, for example, is that as we rightly devote a lot of resources, for example, to STEM education or STEAM education in our countries, well, usually they’re finite budgets.  And when you look at budgets in schools, one place that the money that goes to STEAM or STEM often comes from is civics.  But if we’re not teaching civics, we’re not teaching the foundations that you need for something like digital literacy.  And that creates a problem very early on that just builds and builds and builds, and then if you don’t have a citizenry that has the tools to be able to deal with this information system, it makes it very, very challenging to deal with.</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  One thing that I’m a little curious with, just checking your Twitter, there’s been about more than a dozen tweets put on in the last 24 hours.  Clearly you’re not the social media influencer behind all of them, but what &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  (Laughter.)  Every single one.</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  Every single one, word for word.  But what is the process in which your team or one person, whatever it is, what is kind of the process that a tweet has to go through or any social media content has to go through when it has your name on it?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Yeah, it’s a great question and one that I and we take very seriously, because if I’m putting something out, then I’m simply here as a representative of the United States Government, so anything that we put out is supposed to be – to represent the government, to be reflective of it, to be reflective of our policies, and I’m simply a vehicle for doing that.</p>
<p>So we have a very carefully married-up operation between the folks on our communications team, the folks on our policy team, myself and other colleagues depending on what the subject is, and they need to know and understand each other in – almost intimately, because we have to make sure that whatever is going out under the State Department banner, whether it’s in my name or anyone else’s name, is an accurate reflection of the policies of our government and the President.</p>
<p>So a lot of care goes into that.  We don’t always get it 100 percent right, but we work at it every day.</p>
<p><b>MS VILALOBOS:</b>  And this social media topic, I think that it’s interesting.  We as journalists are always writing headlines, writing topics, things like that.  This era of clickbait culture and at-times sensational journalism, I think this is more of a – not so much a question as an idea.  This is just taking over, and I think that – I think that just the – there’s so many things that can go wrong when there is more drive for engagement in the headline rather than actual content in that headline.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, this goes to something we were talking about, and I was talking about a little bit earlier – is that there is a race to survive too.  The economics of this business are increasingly challenged, increasingly complicated.  That’s especially true, of course, in print media.  And so even social media, the clickbait phenomenon is part of – is partly making sure you get as many eyeballs as you can on something and then maybe drive the advertising revenues or drive your – so what used to be called readership.  So all that pieces together.</p>
<p>One of the reasons we’re trying to look for ways to build support for independent media is to help take some of that pressure off, and at least create a space where journalism is not motivated by that necessity.</p>
<p>Now, having said that, I often thought it would be really great fun writing headlines for tabloids.  (Laughter.)  That just sounds like a great job.  And just to date myself, again, one of the – I think the greatest – and I know I shouldn’t comment on individual publications, but I always thought growing up that the headline writers for the <i>New York Post</i> have one of the best jobs in the business.  (Laughter.)  Because the inventiveness of those headlines are incredible, and there’s just one that stuck with me from many, many years ago, back in the days of the Soviet Union.  One of the leaders of the Soviet Union passed away and the headline in the <i>New York Post</i> the next day was “Red Head Dead.”  (Laughter.)  That’s pretty good.</p>
<p><b>MS BAIETTO:</b>  And I think for everyone we were really able to really talk about hopefully a good idea of where the future of journalism is going and hopefully inspires others.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, let me &#8212;</p>
<p><b>MS THOMAS:</b>  Thank you for joining us.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  No, let me just say to the three of you, first of all, it’s really inspiring to be with you.  It’s inspiring to see others out here, both colleagues who are engaged in the profession today, people who are just joining it.  I am so glad that you’re doing this, as I’m dead-serious about the proposition that this lies at the heart of our democracies.  And as goes journalism, as goes a free media, so go our democracies.</p>
<p>So what you’re doing is incredibly important.  It’s also incredibly challenging.  It goes to, I think, what you were saying about, first of all, trying to find the humanity that’s usually at the heart of things – to remember that, ultimately, you’re reporting on, writing about real people, complicated, imperfect as human beings are, to try to reflect that.  I know how hard it is too, because having been on both sides of this – when you’re in government and you’re in a room with 10 people and you’re talking about a policy, and then if you ask the 10 people in the room who said what and what were the conclusions, you’d probably get 10 different answers from people who were actually in the room.  You’re not in the room and you’re trying to figure out what was said in the room.</p>
<p>It’s incredibly hard, but it’s incredibly, incredibly powerful and incredibly necessary.  And I think having that drive to try to learn about something, to understand it, to know it, and then to be able to communicate it to your fellow citizens is a wonderful thing.  So it’s great to see all of you going into it.  Thanks.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary McKeon’s Travel to Paris and Frankfurt</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-mckeons-travel-to-paris-and-frankfurt/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 01:25:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brian P. McKeon will travel to Paris, France, from June 8 to 10 to lead the U.S. delegation to the 61st annual Ministerial Council Meeting of the Organization for Economic Development and Cooperation (OECD).  While in Paris, Deputy Secretary McKeon will meet with OECD Secretary General Matthias Corman and officials from OECD member countries.  The Deputy Secretary and the Secretary General will discuss the OECD’s key role in driving progress to meet shared challenges, including the climate crisis, inclusive economic recovery, and support for Ukraine’s recovery and reconstruction.  He will participate in Ministerial Council Meeting working sessions, including on Africa and on the economic and other consequences of Russia’s aggression in Ukraine.  Deputy Secretary McKeon will also visit Frankfurt, Germany, for internal meetings at the U.S. Consulate General.</p>
<p>The Deputy Secretary’s participation in the OECD Ministerial Council Meeting will underscore our support for the OECD as the premiere venue for market-oriented democracies to come together to develop solutions for economic challenges.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000000" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brian P. McKeon will travel to Paris, France, from June 8 to 10 to lead the U.S. delegation to the 61st annual Ministerial Council Meeting of the Organization for Economic Development and Cooperation (OECD).  While in Paris, Deputy Secretary McKeon will meet with OECD Secretary General Matthias Corman and officials from OECD member countries.  The Deputy Secretary and the Secretary General will discuss the OECD’s key role in driving progress to meet shared challenges, including the climate crisis, inclusive economic recovery, and support for Ukraine’s recovery and reconstruction.  He will participate in Ministerial Council Meeting working sessions, including on Africa and on the economic and other consequences of Russia’s aggression in Ukraine.  Deputy Secretary McKeon will also visit Frankfurt, Germany, for internal meetings at the U.S. Consulate General.</p>
<p>The Deputy Secretary’s participation in the OECD Ministerial Council Meeting will underscore our support for the OECD as the premiere venue for market-oriented democracies to come together to develop solutions for economic challenges.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000000" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Ukrainian Deputy Foreign Minister Senik</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-ukrainian-deputy-foreign-minister-senik/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 01:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=350406</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with Ukrainian Deputy Foreign Minister Dmytro Senik in Seoul.  The Deputy Secretary emphasized the United States’ robust, continued support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Russia’s unprovoked aggression.  The Deputy Secretary provided an update on U.S. assistance to Ukraine, including security, humanitarian, and economic assistance, as well as budgetary support and aid for long-term efforts.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Deputy Foreign Minister Senik also discussed the impact of Russia’s brutal war of aggression on global food security and our commitment to getting Ukraine’s grain to international markets.</p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today with Ukrainian Deputy Foreign Minister Dmytro Senik in Seoul.  The Deputy Secretary emphasized the United States’ robust, continued support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Russia’s unprovoked aggression.  The Deputy Secretary provided an update on U.S. assistance to Ukraine, including security, humanitarian, and economic assistance, as well as budgetary support and aid for long-term efforts.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Deputy Foreign Minister Senik also discussed the impact of Russia’s brutal war of aggression on global food security and our commitment to getting Ukraine’s grain to international markets.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
