<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 19:25:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Joint Statement of the United States and Germany on Support for Ukraine, European Energy Security, and our Climate Goals</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-of-the-united-states-and-germany-on-support-for-ukraine-european-energy-security-and-our-climate-goals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 19:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261045</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and Germany.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The United States and Germany are steadfast in their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, independence, and chosen European path. We recommit ourselves today to push back against Russian aggression and malign activities in Ukraine and beyond. The United States pledges to support Germany’s and France’s efforts to bring peace to eastern Ukraine via the Normandy Format. Germany will intensify its efforts within the Normandy Format to facilitate the implementation of the Minsk agreements. The United States and Germany affirm their commitment to tackling the climate crisis and taking decisive action to reduce emissions in the 2020s to keep a 1.5-degree Celsius temperature limit within reach.</p>
<p>The United States and Germany are united in their determination to hold Russia to account for its aggression and malign activities by imposing costs via sanctions and other tools. We commit to working together via the newly established U.S.-EU High Level Dialogue on Russia, and via bilateral channels, to ensure the United States and the EU remain prepared, including with appropriate tools and mechanisms, to respond together to Russian aggression and malign activities, including Russian efforts to use energy as a weapon. Should Russia attempt to use energy as a weapon or commit further aggressive acts against Ukraine, Germany will take action at the national level and press for effective measures at the European level, including sanctions, to limit Russian export capabilities to Europe in the energy sector, including gas, and/or in other economically relevant sectors. This commitment is designed to ensure that Russia will not misuse any pipeline, including Nord Stream 2, to achieve aggressive political ends by using energy as a weapon.</p>
<p>We support the energy security of Ukraine and Central and Eastern Europe, including the key principles enshrined in the EU’s Third Energy Package of diversity and security of supply. Germany underscores that it will abide by both the letter and the spirit of the Third Energy Package with respect to Nord Stream 2 under German jurisdiction to ensure unbundling and third-party access. This includes an assessment of any risks posed by certification of the project operator to the security of energy supply of the EU.</p>
<p>The United States and Germany are united in their belief that it is in Ukraine’s and Europe’s interest for gas transit via Ukraine to continue beyond 2024. In line with this belief, Germany commits to utilize all available leverage to facilitate an extension of up to 10 years to Ukraine’s gas transit agreement with Russia, including appointing a special envoy to support those negotiations, to begin as soon as possible and no later than September 1. The United States commits to fully support these efforts.</p>
<p>The United States and Germany are resolute in their commitment to the fight against climate change and ensuring the success of the Paris Agreement by reducing our own emissions in line with net-zero by 2050 at the latest, encouraging the strengthening of climate ambition of other major economies, and collaborating on the policies and technologies to accelerate the global net-zero transition. That is why we have launched the U.S.-Germany Climate and Energy Partnership . The Partnership will foster U.S.-Germany collaboration on developing actionable roadmaps to reach our ambitious emission reduction targets; coordinating our domestic policies and priorities in sectoral decarbonization initiatives and multilateral fora; mobilizing investment in energy transition; and developing, demonstrating, and scaling critical energy technologies such as renewable energy and storage, hydrogen, energy efficiency, and electric mobility.</p>
<p>As part of the U.S.-Germany Climate and Energy Partnership, we have decided to establish a pillar to support the energy transitions in emerging economies. This pillar will include a focus on supporting Ukraine and other countries in Central and Eastern Europe. These efforts will not only contribute to the fight against climate change but will support European energy security by reducing demand for Russian energy.</p>
<p>In line with these efforts, Germany commits to establish and administer a Green Fund for Ukraine to support Ukraine’s energy transition, energy efficiency, and energy security. Germany and the United States will endeavor to promote and support investments of at least $1 billion in the Green Fund for Ukraine, including from third parties such as private-sector entities. Germany will provide an initial donation to the fund of at least $175 million and will work toward extending its commitments in the coming budget years. The fund will promote the use of renewable energy; facilitate the development of hydrogen; increase energy efficiency; accelerate the transition from coal; and foster carbon neutrality. The United States plans to support the initiative via technical assistance and policy support consistent with the objectives of the fund, in addition to programs supporting market integration, regulatory reform, and renewables development in Ukraine’s energy sector.</p>
<p>In addition, Germany will continue to support bilateral energy projects with Ukraine, especially in the field of renewables and energy efficiency, as well as coal transition support, including the appointment of a special envoy with dedicated funding of $70 million. Germany is also ready to launch a Ukraine Resilience Package to support Ukraine’s energy security. This will include efforts to safeguard and increase the capacity for reverse flows of gas to Ukraine, with the aim of shielding Ukraine completely from potential future attempts by Russia to cut gas supplies to the country. It will also include technical assistance for Ukraine’s integration into the European electricity grid, building on and in coordination with the ongoing work by the EU and the U.S. Agency for International Development. In addition, Germany will facilitate Ukraine’s inclusion in Germany’s Cyber Capacity Building Facility, support efforts to reform Ukraine’s energy sector, and assist with identifying options to modernize Ukraine’s gas transmission systems.</p>
<p>The United States and Germany express their strong support for the Three Seas Initiative and its efforts to strengthen infrastructure connectivity and energy security in Central and Eastern Europe. Germany commits to expand its engagement with the initiative with an eye toward financially supporting projects of the Three Seas Initiative in the fields of regional energy security and renewable energy. In addition, Germany will support projects of common interest in the energy sector via the EU Budget, with contributions of up to $1.77 billion in 2021-2027. The United States remains committed to investing in the Three Seas Initiative and continues to encourage concrete investments by members and others.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and Germany.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The United States and Germany are steadfast in their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, independence, and chosen European path. We recommit ourselves today to push back against Russian aggression and malign activities in Ukraine and beyond. The United States pledges to support Germany’s and France’s efforts to bring peace to eastern Ukraine via the Normandy Format. Germany will intensify its efforts within the Normandy Format to facilitate the implementation of the Minsk agreements. The United States and Germany affirm their commitment to tackling the climate crisis and taking decisive action to reduce emissions in the 2020s to keep a 1.5-degree Celsius temperature limit within reach.</p>
<p>The United States and Germany are united in their determination to hold Russia to account for its aggression and malign activities by imposing costs via sanctions and other tools. We commit to working together via the newly established U.S.-EU High Level Dialogue on Russia, and via bilateral channels, to ensure the United States and the EU remain prepared, including with appropriate tools and mechanisms, to respond together to Russian aggression and malign activities, including Russian efforts to use energy as a weapon. Should Russia attempt to use energy as a weapon or commit further aggressive acts against Ukraine, Germany will take action at the national level and press for effective measures at the European level, including sanctions, to limit Russian export capabilities to Europe in the energy sector, including gas, and/or in other economically relevant sectors. This commitment is designed to ensure that Russia will not misuse any pipeline, including Nord Stream 2, to achieve aggressive political ends by using energy as a weapon.</p>
<p>We support the energy security of Ukraine and Central and Eastern Europe, including the key principles enshrined in the EU’s Third Energy Package of diversity and security of supply. Germany underscores that it will abide by both the letter and the spirit of the Third Energy Package with respect to Nord Stream 2 under German jurisdiction to ensure unbundling and third-party access. This includes an assessment of any risks posed by certification of the project operator to the security of energy supply of the EU.</p>
<p>The United States and Germany are united in their belief that it is in Ukraine’s and Europe’s interest for gas transit via Ukraine to continue beyond 2024. In line with this belief, Germany commits to utilize all available leverage to facilitate an extension of up to 10 years to Ukraine’s gas transit agreement with Russia, including appointing a special envoy to support those negotiations, to begin as soon as possible and no later than September 1. The United States commits to fully support these efforts.</p>
<p>The United States and Germany are resolute in their commitment to the fight against climate change and ensuring the success of the Paris Agreement by reducing our own emissions in line with net-zero by 2050 at the latest, encouraging the strengthening of climate ambition of other major economies, and collaborating on the policies and technologies to accelerate the global net-zero transition. That is why we have launched the U.S.-Germany Climate and Energy Partnership . The Partnership will foster U.S.-Germany collaboration on developing actionable roadmaps to reach our ambitious emission reduction targets; coordinating our domestic policies and priorities in sectoral decarbonization initiatives and multilateral fora; mobilizing investment in energy transition; and developing, demonstrating, and scaling critical energy technologies such as renewable energy and storage, hydrogen, energy efficiency, and electric mobility.</p>
<p>As part of the U.S.-Germany Climate and Energy Partnership, we have decided to establish a pillar to support the energy transitions in emerging economies. This pillar will include a focus on supporting Ukraine and other countries in Central and Eastern Europe. These efforts will not only contribute to the fight against climate change but will support European energy security by reducing demand for Russian energy.</p>
<p>In line with these efforts, Germany commits to establish and administer a Green Fund for Ukraine to support Ukraine’s energy transition, energy efficiency, and energy security. Germany and the United States will endeavor to promote and support investments of at least $1 billion in the Green Fund for Ukraine, including from third parties such as private-sector entities. Germany will provide an initial donation to the fund of at least $175 million and will work toward extending its commitments in the coming budget years. The fund will promote the use of renewable energy; facilitate the development of hydrogen; increase energy efficiency; accelerate the transition from coal; and foster carbon neutrality. The United States plans to support the initiative via technical assistance and policy support consistent with the objectives of the fund, in addition to programs supporting market integration, regulatory reform, and renewables development in Ukraine’s energy sector.</p>
<p>In addition, Germany will continue to support bilateral energy projects with Ukraine, especially in the field of renewables and energy efficiency, as well as coal transition support, including the appointment of a special envoy with dedicated funding of $70 million. Germany is also ready to launch a Ukraine Resilience Package to support Ukraine’s energy security. This will include efforts to safeguard and increase the capacity for reverse flows of gas to Ukraine, with the aim of shielding Ukraine completely from potential future attempts by Russia to cut gas supplies to the country. It will also include technical assistance for Ukraine’s integration into the European electricity grid, building on and in coordination with the ongoing work by the EU and the U.S. Agency for International Development. In addition, Germany will facilitate Ukraine’s inclusion in Germany’s Cyber Capacity Building Facility, support efforts to reform Ukraine’s energy sector, and assist with identifying options to modernize Ukraine’s gas transmission systems.</p>
<p>The United States and Germany express their strong support for the Three Seas Initiative and its efforts to strengthen infrastructure connectivity and energy security in Central and Eastern Europe. Germany commits to expand its engagement with the initiative with an eye toward financially supporting projects of the Three Seas Initiative in the fields of regional energy security and renewable energy. In addition, Germany will support projects of common interest in the energy sector via the EU Budget, with contributions of up to $1.77 billion in 2021-2027. The United States remains committed to investing in the Three Seas Initiative and continues to encourage concrete investments by members and others.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2021 Investment Climate Statements Released</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/2021-investment-climate-statements-released/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 15:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260931</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today the Department of State released the 2021 Investment Climate Statements, which analyze the investment climates of more than 170 countries and economies that are current or potential markets for U.S. companies. The reports provide up-to-date information gathered by our economic officers in embassies and consulates around the world – helping U.S. companies make informed business decisions. They also serve as a reference in working with partner governments to create enabling environments that are not only economically sound but also adhere to high standards, like protecting the environment and respecting human rights, including worker rights. Readers can also access points of contact within each U.S. mission for additional follow-up and consultation.</p>
<p>The reports cover topics including: Openness to Investment, Legal and Regulatory Systems, Protection of Real and Intellectual Property Rights, Financial Sector, State-Owned Enterprises, Responsible Business Conduct, and Corruption.</p>
<p>Our posts overseas are working daily to address many of the barriers to U.S. investment highlighted by the Investment Climate Statements. Addressing these barriers can create opportunities for U.S. businesses and support their growth and expansion in the United States and in partner countries.</p>
<p>The reports can be viewed at the following link: <a href="https://www.state.gov/investment-climate-statements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MjEuNDM1MDAxNTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvaW52ZXN0bWVudC1jbGltYXRlLXN0YXRlbWVudHMvIn0.EeplJbZ3QPalW83Bp61BtwChcrox_x_Gb_c2sCXmtoI/s/1039202793/br/109682275679-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1626967329646000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE71M3abyhI9iY0qCqE5iOGRu42XA">https://www.state.gov/<wbr />investment-climate-statements/</a><wbr />.</p>
<p>The Investment Climate Statements also form a chapter of the Department of Commerce&#8217;s Country Commercial Guides and can be read together with those guides for a broad description of the investment and business environments in foreign economies (<a class="external-link" href="https://www.trade.gov/ccg-landing-page" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://www.trade.gov/ccg-landing-page</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>).</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today the Department of State released the 2021 Investment Climate Statements, which analyze the investment climates of more than 170 countries and economies that are current or potential markets for U.S. companies. The reports provide up-to-date information gathered by our economic officers in embassies and consulates around the world – helping U.S. companies make informed business decisions. They also serve as a reference in working with partner governments to create enabling environments that are not only economically sound but also adhere to high standards, like protecting the environment and respecting human rights, including worker rights. Readers can also access points of contact within each U.S. mission for additional follow-up and consultation.</p>
<p>The reports cover topics including: Openness to Investment, Legal and Regulatory Systems, Protection of Real and Intellectual Property Rights, Financial Sector, State-Owned Enterprises, Responsible Business Conduct, and Corruption.</p>
<p>Our posts overseas are working daily to address many of the barriers to U.S. investment highlighted by the Investment Climate Statements. Addressing these barriers can create opportunities for U.S. businesses and support their growth and expansion in the United States and in partner countries.</p>
<p>The reports can be viewed at the following link: <a href="https://www.state.gov/investment-climate-statements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MjEuNDM1MDAxNTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvaW52ZXN0bWVudC1jbGltYXRlLXN0YXRlbWVudHMvIn0.EeplJbZ3QPalW83Bp61BtwChcrox_x_Gb_c2sCXmtoI/s/1039202793/br/109682275679-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1626967329646000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE71M3abyhI9iY0qCqE5iOGRu42XA">https://www.state.gov/<wbr />investment-climate-statements/</a><wbr />.</p>
<p>The Investment Climate Statements also form a chapter of the Department of Commerce&#8217;s Country Commercial Guides and can be read together with those guides for a broad description of the investment and business environments in foreign economies (<a class="external-link" href="https://www.trade.gov/ccg-landing-page" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://www.trade.gov/ccg-landing-page</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Counselor Chollet’s Trip to Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/counselor-chollets-trip-to-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 12:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Open Sans',sans-serif; color: #222222;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p style="background: white; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; widows: 2; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-thickness: initial; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: 'Open Sans',sans-serif; color: #222222;">Counselor of the Department Derek Chollet met with Ukrainian Prime Minister Denys Shmyhal, Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba, Head of Presidential Office Andriy Yermak, and Deputy Foreign Minister Yevhenii Yenin in Kyiv, Ukraine, on July 20-21. The Counselor and the senior Ukrainian officials discussed our shared concerns about the Nord Stream 2 pipeline and U.S. commitments to ensure Russia cannot use energy as a coercive tool against Ukraine or any other country in Europe. Counselor Chollet reiterated our support for Ukraine’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, and Euro-Atlantic aspirations. The Counselor addressed Ukraine’s efforts to advance economic and rule of law reforms, with an emphasis on strengthening corporate governance and bolstering anti-corruption institutions.</span></p>
<p style="background: white; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; widows: 2; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-thickness: initial; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: 'Open Sans',sans-serif; color: #222222;">Counselor Chollet also met with energy sector and corporate governance leaders to discuss Ukraine’s prosperity and energy security.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Open Sans',sans-serif; color: #222222;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p style="background: white; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; widows: 2; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-thickness: initial; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: 'Open Sans',sans-serif; color: #222222;">Counselor of the Department Derek Chollet met with Ukrainian Prime Minister Denys Shmyhal, Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba, Head of Presidential Office Andriy Yermak, and Deputy Foreign Minister Yevhenii Yenin in Kyiv, Ukraine, on July 20-21. The Counselor and the senior Ukrainian officials discussed our shared concerns about the Nord Stream 2 pipeline and U.S. commitments to ensure Russia cannot use energy as a coercive tool against Ukraine or any other country in Europe. Counselor Chollet reiterated our support for Ukraine’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, and Euro-Atlantic aspirations. The Counselor addressed Ukraine’s efforts to advance economic and rule of law reforms, with an emphasis on strengthening corporate governance and bolstering anti-corruption institutions.</span></p>
<p style="background: white; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; widows: 2; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-thickness: initial; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: 'Open Sans',sans-serif; color: #222222;">Counselor Chollet also met with energy sector and corporate governance leaders to discuss Ukraine’s prosperity and energy security.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Japanese Defense Minister Kishi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-japanese-defense-minister-kishi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 12:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260886</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Japanese Defense Minister Kishi today in Tokyo. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Defense Minister Kishi reaffirmed that the U.S.-Japan Alliance remains the cornerstone of peace, security, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region. Deputy Secretary Sherman highlighted the United States’ unwavering commitment to the defense of Japan.</p>
<p>The Deputy Secretary and the Defense Minister underscored the importance of peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait and highlighted their shared commitment to working toward the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, including through trilateral cooperation among the United States, Japan, and the Republic of Korea.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Japanese Defense Minister Kishi today in Tokyo. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Defense Minister Kishi reaffirmed that the U.S.-Japan Alliance remains the cornerstone of peace, security, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region. Deputy Secretary Sherman highlighted the United States’ unwavering commitment to the defense of Japan.</p>
<p>The Deputy Secretary and the Defense Minister underscored the importance of peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait and highlighted their shared commitment to working toward the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, including through trilateral cooperation among the United States, Japan, and the Republic of Korea.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Travel to the People’s Republic of China and Oman</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-travel-to-the-peoples-republic-of-china-and-oman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 11:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260876</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #222222;">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman will travel to the People’s Republic of China (PRC) July 25-26 and to Oman July 27.</span></p>
<p>In the PRC, the Deputy Secretary will travel to Tianjin to meet with PRC officials, including State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi.  These discussions are part of ongoing U.S. efforts to hold candid exchanges with PRC officials to advance U.S. interests and values and to responsibly manage the relationship. The Deputy Secretary will discuss areas where we have serious concerns about PRC actions, as well as areas where our interests align.</p>
<p>In Oman, the Deputy Secretary will meet with Deputy Foreign Minister Sheikh Khalifa Al Harthy to discuss advancing peace and security in the region and our shared commitment to bolstering the U.S.- Oman bilateral relationship.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #222222;">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman will travel to the People’s Republic of China (PRC) July 25-26 and to Oman July 27.</span></p>
<p>In the PRC, the Deputy Secretary will travel to Tianjin to meet with PRC officials, including State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi.  These discussions are part of ongoing U.S. efforts to hold candid exchanges with PRC officials to advance U.S. interests and values and to responsibly manage the relationship. The Deputy Secretary will discuss areas where we have serious concerns about PRC actions, as well as areas where our interests align.</p>
<p>In Oman, the Deputy Secretary will meet with Deputy Foreign Minister Sheikh Khalifa Al Harthy to discuss advancing peace and security in the region and our shared commitment to bolstering the U.S.- Oman bilateral relationship.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Belgium National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/belgium-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 04:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260828</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I send my warm wishes to the people of the Kingdom of Belgium as you observe your National Day.</p>
<p>The United States and Belgium have a long and proud history of cooperation, and our close alliance is based on a shared commitment to democracy and human rights.  We fought side by side in two world wars to defend our shared values.  As founding members of NATO, we established the cornerstone of peace, prosperity, and stability the Transatlantic community has enjoyed since then.</p>
<p>The people of the United States mourn with you after the devastating loss of life and destruction from the recent floods.  We trust that Belgium will rebuild and persevere as it has done in the past.  Such perseverance has been evident as we face a global pandemic and continue to stand together.  The fruits of our scientific cooperation have benefited the world.  We are committed to using that same ingenuity in new avenues of partnership, such as working together to combat the climate crisis by reducing greenhouse gas emissions and developing green infrastructure.</p>
<p>I look forward to creating a more secure and prosperous future for our citizens in the coming year.  Best wishes to the people of Belgium on the occasion of your National Day.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I send my warm wishes to the people of the Kingdom of Belgium as you observe your National Day.</p>
<p>The United States and Belgium have a long and proud history of cooperation, and our close alliance is based on a shared commitment to democracy and human rights.  We fought side by side in two world wars to defend our shared values.  As founding members of NATO, we established the cornerstone of peace, prosperity, and stability the Transatlantic community has enjoyed since then.</p>
<p>The people of the United States mourn with you after the devastating loss of life and destruction from the recent floods.  We trust that Belgium will rebuild and persevere as it has done in the past.  Such perseverance has been evident as we face a global pandemic and continue to stand together.  The fruits of our scientific cooperation have benefited the world.  We are committed to using that same ingenuity in new avenues of partnership, such as working together to combat the climate crisis by reducing greenhouse gas emissions and developing green infrastructure.</p>
<p>I look forward to creating a more secure and prosperous future for our citizens in the coming year.  Best wishes to the people of Belgium on the occasion of your National Day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Announcement of a Unity Government in Haiti</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/announcement-of-a-unity-government-in-haiti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 02:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260846</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes efforts by Haiti’s political leadership to come together in choosing an interim Prime Minister and a unity cabinet to chart a path forward in the wake of the heinous assassination of Jovenel Moïse.  The formation of this interim government is a positive and necessary step to respond to the Haitian people’s needs and begin restoring Haiti’s democratic institutions.</p>
<p>The United States, together with the international community, urges Haiti’s political and civil society leaders to continue to work together to advance a broad and inclusive dialogue that responds to the needs of the Haitian people and lays the groundwork for long-term stability and prosperity.</p>
<p>We remain committed to supporting the Haitian government’s investigation into the assassination of Jovenel Moïse, expanding COVID-19 vaccination efforts, working with the Haitian National Police to promote security and the rule of law, and coordinating with the international community to establish the conditions necessary for Haitians to vote as soon as feasible.</p>
<p>We call on all Haitians to work together to maintain peace and will continue to support the Haitian people as they strive to build a stable, prosperous, and democratic country.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes efforts by Haiti’s political leadership to come together in choosing an interim Prime Minister and a unity cabinet to chart a path forward in the wake of the heinous assassination of Jovenel Moïse.  The formation of this interim government is a positive and necessary step to respond to the Haitian people’s needs and begin restoring Haiti’s democratic institutions.</p>
<p>The United States, together with the international community, urges Haiti’s political and civil society leaders to continue to work together to advance a broad and inclusive dialogue that responds to the needs of the Haitian people and lays the groundwork for long-term stability and prosperity.</p>
<p>We remain committed to supporting the Haitian government’s investigation into the assassination of Jovenel Moïse, expanding COVID-19 vaccination efforts, working with the Haitian National Police to promote security and the rule of law, and coordinating with the international community to establish the conditions necessary for Haitians to vote as soon as feasible.</p>
<p>We call on all Haitians to work together to maintain peace and will continue to support the Haitian people as they strive to build a stable, prosperous, and democratic country.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Trilateral Meeting with Japanese Vice Foreign Minister Mori and Republic of Korea First Vice Foreign Minister Choi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-trilateral-meeting-with-japanese-vice-foreign-minister-mori-and-republic-of-korea-first-vice-foreign-minister-choi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 02:14:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260839</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman met with Japanese Vice Foreign Minister Mori Takeo and Republic of Korea First Vice Foreign Minister Choi Jong Kun today in Tokyo.  During the meeting, the Deputy Secretary and the two vice foreign ministers committed to deepening trilateral cooperation to address the global challenges of the 21st century, including the climate crisis, pandemic response, and economic resilience and recovery.</p>
<p>They also discussed the shared commitment of the United States, Japan, and the Republic of Korea to work toward the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and their intent to address the threat posed by the nuclear and ballistic missile programs of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea.</p>
<p>In addition, they discussed combined efforts to promote peace, security, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific and around the world, based upon our shared values of defending freedom, championing economic opportunity, upholding human rights, and respecting the rule of law.</p>
<p>The Deputy Secretary and the two vice foreign ministers reiterated opposition to all activities that undermine, destabilize, or threaten the rules-based international order; affirmed the need to maintain an inclusive, free, and open Indo-Pacific; opposed any unilateral attempts to change the status quo in the East China Sea; and pledged to maintain peace and stability, lawful unimpeded commerce, and respect for international law, including freedom of navigation and overflight in the South China Sea and beyond.  The Deputy Secretary stressed the importance of support for gender equity and equality and LGBTQI+ rights.  The discussion also emphasized the importance of preserving peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The Deputy Secretary and the two vice foreign ministers reaffirmed support for ASEAN centrality and the ASEAN-led regional architecture. They also discussed efforts to support the people of Burma in promoting a return to democracy.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman met with Japanese Vice Foreign Minister Mori Takeo and Republic of Korea First Vice Foreign Minister Choi Jong Kun today in Tokyo.  During the meeting, the Deputy Secretary and the two vice foreign ministers committed to deepening trilateral cooperation to address the global challenges of the 21st century, including the climate crisis, pandemic response, and economic resilience and recovery.</p>
<p>They also discussed the shared commitment of the United States, Japan, and the Republic of Korea to work toward the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and their intent to address the threat posed by the nuclear and ballistic missile programs of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea.</p>
<p>In addition, they discussed combined efforts to promote peace, security, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific and around the world, based upon our shared values of defending freedom, championing economic opportunity, upholding human rights, and respecting the rule of law.</p>
<p>The Deputy Secretary and the two vice foreign ministers reiterated opposition to all activities that undermine, destabilize, or threaten the rules-based international order; affirmed the need to maintain an inclusive, free, and open Indo-Pacific; opposed any unilateral attempts to change the status quo in the East China Sea; and pledged to maintain peace and stability, lawful unimpeded commerce, and respect for international law, including freedom of navigation and overflight in the South China Sea and beyond.  The Deputy Secretary stressed the importance of support for gender equity and equality and LGBTQI+ rights.  The discussion also emphasized the importance of preserving peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The Deputy Secretary and the two vice foreign ministers reaffirmed support for ASEAN centrality and the ASEAN-led regional architecture. They also discussed efforts to support the people of Burma in promoting a return to democracy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On the Occasion of Eid al-Adha</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/on-the-occasion-of-eid-al-adha/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 01:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260835</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I extend my warmest wishes to all those celebrating Eid al-Adha in the United States and around the world.</p>
<p>This special occasion is a time to reflect on the values of sacrifice, service, compassion, charity, and for helping those less fortunate. As we mark Eid al-Adha this year, the COVID-19 pandemic continues to restrict the ways in which members of religious communities observe holy days and traditions. We honor the Muslims worldwide who are spending the holiday separated from their families and friends and following health and safety guidelines, especially those who were not able to participate in the Hajj pilgrimage. We are hopeful that many pilgrims will have an opportunity to perform their pilgrimage once it is safe.</p>
<p>I wish you all a happy Eid al-Adha.  Eid Mubarak and Hajj Mabrour.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I extend my warmest wishes to all those celebrating Eid al-Adha in the United States and around the world.</p>
<p>This special occasion is a time to reflect on the values of sacrifice, service, compassion, charity, and for helping those less fortunate. As we mark Eid al-Adha this year, the COVID-19 pandemic continues to restrict the ways in which members of religious communities observe holy days and traditions. We honor the Muslims worldwide who are spending the holiday separated from their families and friends and following health and safety guidelines, especially those who were not able to participate in the Hajj pilgrimage. We are hopeful that many pilgrims will have an opportunity to perform their pilgrimage once it is safe.</p>
<p>I wish you all a happy Eid al-Adha.  Eid Mubarak and Hajj Mabrour.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Transfer of Parts of Varosha to Turkish Cypriot Control </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/transfer-of-parts-of-varosha-to-turkish-cypriot-control/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 01:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=260832</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States condemns the announcement by Turkish Cypriot leader Ersin Tatar and Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan today regarding the transfer of parts of Varosha to Turkish Cypriot control.  This move is clearly inconsistent with UN Security Council Resolutions 550 and 789, which explicitly call for Varosha to be administered by the United Nations.</p>
<p>Since October 2020 when Turkish Cypriots, with the support of Turkey, announced the opening of the Varosha beachfront and began taking actions to implement this decision, Turkish Cypriots and Turkey have ignored calls from the international community and the UN Security Council to reverse their unilateral steps on Varosha.  The United States views Turkish Cypriot actions in Varosha, with the support of Turkey, as provocative, unacceptable, and incompatible with their past commitments to engage constructively in settlement talks.  We urge Turkish Cypriots and Turkey to reverse their decision announced today and all steps taken since October 2020.</p>
<p>The United States is working with like-minded partners to refer this concerning situation to the UN Security Council and will urge a strong response.</p>
<p>We underscore the importance of avoiding provocative unilateral actions that increase tensions on the island and hinder efforts to resume Cyprus settlement talks in accordance with UN Security Council resolutions.  We remain supportive of a Cypriot-led comprehensive settlement to reunify the island as a bizonal, bicommunal federation to benefit all Cypriots and the wider region.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States condemns the announcement by Turkish Cypriot leader Ersin Tatar and Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan today regarding the transfer of parts of Varosha to Turkish Cypriot control.  This move is clearly inconsistent with UN Security Council Resolutions 550 and 789, which explicitly call for Varosha to be administered by the United Nations.</p>
<p>Since October 2020 when Turkish Cypriots, with the support of Turkey, announced the opening of the Varosha beachfront and began taking actions to implement this decision, Turkish Cypriots and Turkey have ignored calls from the international community and the UN Security Council to reverse their unilateral steps on Varosha.  The United States views Turkish Cypriot actions in Varosha, with the support of Turkey, as provocative, unacceptable, and incompatible with their past commitments to engage constructively in settlement talks.  We urge Turkish Cypriots and Turkey to reverse their decision announced today and all steps taken since October 2020.</p>
<p>The United States is working with like-minded partners to refer this concerning situation to the UN Security Council and will urge a strong response.</p>
<p>We underscore the importance of avoiding provocative unilateral actions that increase tensions on the island and hinder efforts to resume Cyprus settlement talks in accordance with UN Security Council resolutions.  We remain supportive of a Cypriot-led comprehensive settlement to reunify the island as a bizonal, bicommunal federation to benefit all Cypriots and the wider region.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
