<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 23:15:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The United States and Australia: A Vital Partnership for the Indo-Pacific Region and the World</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-and-australia-a-vital-partnership-for-the-indo-pacific-region-and-the-world/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 23:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312563</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>As democratic anchors in the Indo-Pacific, the United States and Australia share an unshakeable commitment to defending freedom and democracy, championing opportunity, upholding human rights, respecting the rule of law, and countering state-sponsored disinformation.</p>
<p>Australia and the United States have a proud history of working together in times of crisis for more than 100 years.  Australia and the United States have stood shoulder to shoulder in every major conflict since World War 1.  Last year marked the 70th anniversary of the signing of the Australia, New Zealand, United States (ANZUS) Treaty—a keystone of our relationship with Australia and an enduring force for stability in the wider region.  The only time the collective defense article of the ANZUS Treaty was formally invoked was after September 11, 2001.</p>
<p><strong>The United States and Australia: Securing a Safe and Prosperous Indo-Pacific</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The Quad – the United States, Australia, India, and Japan – is making tangible progress on the Indo-Pacific region’s most important challenges. The Quad Vaccine Partnership is committed to expanding local production of safe and effective doses of COVID-19 vaccines, having already collectively provided over 484 million safe and effective vaccine doses as of February 1, 2022.  Australia will focus on vaccine procurement and last-mile delivery support to the region.  Quad Partners are joining forces to expand safe, affordable, and effective vaccine production and equitable access to speed economic recovery and benefit global health.  At the same time, Quad partners are working with countries around the region to strengthen the region’s maritime security, counter-terrorism, counter-disinformation, and cybersecurity, and humanitarian and disaster relief response, including cooperatively supporting Tonga following the recent volcanic eruptions, ashfall, and tsunami.  The Quad will continue to meet regularly to deliver as a force for good for the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States is committed to deeper and more intensive engagement in the Indo-Pacific for generations to come. AUKUS, the enhanced trilateral security partnership between Australia, the United Kingdom, and the United States, demonstrates the U.S. commitment to revitalizing our partnerships and strengthening them to take on the challenges of the 21st century.  This partnership is especially important given the changing strategic environment in the region.  AUKUS will bring together our service members, our scientists, and our industries to maintain and expand our edge in military capabilities and critical technologies.  The partnership is about connecting existing U.S. allies and partners in new ways and amplifying our ability to collaborate.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>In the wake of the recent Hunga Tonga-Hunga Ha’apai volcanic eruptions, ashfall, and tsunami, the United States and Australia are coordinating closely, together with other international partners, to provide immediate help and support on assistance to Tonga. The USS Sampson (DDG 102) supported not only disaster relief efforts but also the Australian Defence Force-led response.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>The United States and Australia: A Vital Partnership for the World</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Australia and U.S. biotech company Moderna have agreed to build an mRNA vaccine manufacturing and finishing facility in Melbourne, Australia, that will produce as many as 100 million mRNA vaccines a year – increasing the health security of Australia and the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Australia is an essential partner in developing emerging technologies, including quantum information sciences, artificial intelligence, advanced manufacturing, and clean energy technologies. Our bilateral collaboration promotes innovative research, enhances economic productivity, and upholds the highest standards for these novel technologies.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>We welcome Australia’s work with us and likeminded partners to strengthen the resilience, security, and diversity of key supply chains, including critical minerals needed to fuel the clean energy transition, of which Australia has world-leading reserves. The United States and Australia are working to build robust, responsible supply chains for clean energy minerals and metals through the Energy Resource Governance Initiative (ERGI) and will continue to expand our cooperation bilaterally through the Quad Climate Working Group and other relevant multilateral initiatives.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States and Australia share a robust and growing economic relationship. The United States is proud to be the top foreign investor in Australia by far and to be the top destination for Australia’s foreign investment.  Deep people-to-people ties also reinforce our shared beliefs and common interests.  Tens of thousands of Australian and American students have participated in academic exchange programs.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>As democratic anchors in the Indo-Pacific, the United States and Australia share an unshakeable commitment to defending freedom and democracy, championing opportunity, upholding human rights, respecting the rule of law, and countering state-sponsored disinformation.</p>
<p>Australia and the United States have a proud history of working together in times of crisis for more than 100 years.  Australia and the United States have stood shoulder to shoulder in every major conflict since World War 1.  Last year marked the 70th anniversary of the signing of the Australia, New Zealand, United States (ANZUS) Treaty—a keystone of our relationship with Australia and an enduring force for stability in the wider region.  The only time the collective defense article of the ANZUS Treaty was formally invoked was after September 11, 2001.</p>
<p><strong>The United States and Australia: Securing a Safe and Prosperous Indo-Pacific</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The Quad – the United States, Australia, India, and Japan – is making tangible progress on the Indo-Pacific region’s most important challenges. The Quad Vaccine Partnership is committed to expanding local production of safe and effective doses of COVID-19 vaccines, having already collectively provided over 484 million safe and effective vaccine doses as of February 1, 2022.  Australia will focus on vaccine procurement and last-mile delivery support to the region.  Quad Partners are joining forces to expand safe, affordable, and effective vaccine production and equitable access to speed economic recovery and benefit global health.  At the same time, Quad partners are working with countries around the region to strengthen the region’s maritime security, counter-terrorism, counter-disinformation, and cybersecurity, and humanitarian and disaster relief response, including cooperatively supporting Tonga following the recent volcanic eruptions, ashfall, and tsunami.  The Quad will continue to meet regularly to deliver as a force for good for the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States is committed to deeper and more intensive engagement in the Indo-Pacific for generations to come. AUKUS, the enhanced trilateral security partnership between Australia, the United Kingdom, and the United States, demonstrates the U.S. commitment to revitalizing our partnerships and strengthening them to take on the challenges of the 21st century.  This partnership is especially important given the changing strategic environment in the region.  AUKUS will bring together our service members, our scientists, and our industries to maintain and expand our edge in military capabilities and critical technologies.  The partnership is about connecting existing U.S. allies and partners in new ways and amplifying our ability to collaborate.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>In the wake of the recent Hunga Tonga-Hunga Ha’apai volcanic eruptions, ashfall, and tsunami, the United States and Australia are coordinating closely, together with other international partners, to provide immediate help and support on assistance to Tonga. The USS Sampson (DDG 102) supported not only disaster relief efforts but also the Australian Defence Force-led response.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>The United States and Australia: A Vital Partnership for the World</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Australia and U.S. biotech company Moderna have agreed to build an mRNA vaccine manufacturing and finishing facility in Melbourne, Australia, that will produce as many as 100 million mRNA vaccines a year – increasing the health security of Australia and the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Australia is an essential partner in developing emerging technologies, including quantum information sciences, artificial intelligence, advanced manufacturing, and clean energy technologies. Our bilateral collaboration promotes innovative research, enhances economic productivity, and upholds the highest standards for these novel technologies.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>We welcome Australia’s work with us and likeminded partners to strengthen the resilience, security, and diversity of key supply chains, including critical minerals needed to fuel the clean energy transition, of which Australia has world-leading reserves. The United States and Australia are working to build robust, responsible supply chains for clean energy minerals and metals through the Energy Resource Governance Initiative (ERGI) and will continue to expand our cooperation bilaterally through the Quad Climate Working Group and other relevant multilateral initiatives.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States and Australia share a robust and growing economic relationship. The United States is proud to be the top foreign investor in Australia by far and to be the top destination for Australia’s foreign investment.  Deep people-to-people ties also reinforce our shared beliefs and common interests.  Tens of thousands of Australian and American students have participated in academic exchange programs.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing – February 8, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-february-8-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 22:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=312524</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Good afternoon, and thank you all for joining today’s press briefing. I don’t have any elements at the top, but I’ll give it a few extra minutes to have some more reporters filter in the queue before I start taking your questions.</p>
<p>So, let’s start off with the line of Cindy Spang, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, hello. Good afternoon. I have a question about Jamshid Sharmahd, a German Iranian dissident and longtime California resident who was abducted by Iran and went on trial Sunday and could face the death penalty. Would you have any comment or reaction to that, please? And thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-GermanyIran"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Cindy. We’re certainly aware of the reports regarding Jamshid Sharmahd’s detention, but we’re going to have to refer you to the Government of Germany for any further inquiries.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to Janne Pak.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hello.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hello.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you, Janne. Great to hear from you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, because very hard to – this signal here. So, I have two questions for you. And it is an important time for the U.S. and ROK-Japan trilateral alliance to respond to North Korea’s successive provocations. Will there be any discussion about the South Korea’s ascension to the Quad at the three-party foreign ministers meeting in Hawaii?</p>
<p>Second question: It is reported that the North Korea is operating on ICBM bases on the border between North Korea and China. My question is: Do you have any specific information about this? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Quad"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Janne. I’ll start with your first question first. And just broadly speaking, I’d like to say that the Quad is an essential multilateral grouping that convenes four like-minded democracies. Of course, that’s the U.S., Australia, Japan, and India. And the purpose, of course, is to make tangible progress on pressing challenges within the Indo Pacific. It’s also based on our shared values and capability. Each Quad member shares collective commitments to democracy, peace, security, and prosperity in the region.</p>
<p>To answer your questions about South Korea’s ascension into the Quad, I certainly don’t have any details to share other than what we issued in our readout – that was our travel announcement, excuse me, that was issued last Friday.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-NorthKorea"></a> But what I would say is that we continue to consult closely with the Republic of Korea, Japan, as well as other allies and partners on how to best engage the DPRK. The United States condemned the DPRK’s missile launches, and of course the DPRK wants to normalize illicit weapons testing, but we’re taking a calibrated approach, as we’ve said previously, to these provocations based on the degree of threat to the United States as well as to our allies.</p>
<p>Of course, as it can’t be understated, a number times, that our goal remains the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and that we have no hostile intent towards the DPRK and remain open to meeting the DPRK without preconditions. Of course, however, we also have an obligation to address the DPRK’s recent provocations and enforce UNSCRs that are already in place.</p>
<p>To your second question, on the ICBM base on the border with China, I would say that our goal remains the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. The DPRK constitutes a threat to international peace and security and the global nonproliferation regime. It’s – the United States has a vital interest in deterring the DPRK. That includes defending against its provocations or uses of force, limiting the reach of its most dangerous weapons programs, and above all keeping the American people, our deployed forces, and our allies safe.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to the line of Daphne Psaledakis, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for doing this. How has the resumption of Iran talks in Vienna gone today? Has any progress been made? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Iran"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks for your question, Daphne. Special Envoy Malley has actually just recently returned to Vienna. He returned yesterday for the eighth round of talks that resumed today. I don’t have anything to read out from there. Of course, he continues to meet on the sidelines with our partners in Vienna. He also continues to brief Congress virtually, but outside of that I don’t have anything else to say, and I certainly wouldn’t want to get ahead of the talks. Of course, if we do have updates, we’ll be certain to share them with you as soon as we have them.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Michel Ghandour, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for the call. I have a question on Iran talks, but since you have no update, I will ask you about Lebanon and Senior Advisor Hochstein who’s in Beirut today. Is he bringing any U.S. plan or offer to solve the maritime dispute between Lebanon and Israel? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-LebanonIsrael"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Michel. So, what I would say at the top is that the maritime boundary is a decision for both Israel and Lebanon to make. And of course, the U.S. stands ready to facilitate negotiations on the maritime boundary between both Lebanon and Israel, and we support efforts to reach a mutually beneficial agreement.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Conor Finnegan, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hi. Yes, Conor, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey. Hey, Jalina. Two questions for you. On Ukraine first, any response to the talks between Presidents Macron and Putin, now that we’ve heard a bit more about them from both sides? Macron specifically said today that Putin told him Russia wouldn’t initiate an escalation. I’m wondering if you believe that’s true.</p>
<p>And then a second question on Honduras. The information that was declassified and publicized last night that former President Hernández was included on the list of corrupt and undemocratic actors – why was this information declassified now, and does it send the wrong message that heads of government would only face repercussions like this once they leave power? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-UkraineFranceRussia"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So, Conor, I will start with your first question. On Macron, I would just say that we are engaged in intensive diplomacy with our allies and partners, but I’m – I just can’t get into detail about private meetings. But one of the messages that we’ve tried to send very clearly to Russia is that the West is united, and the fact is that there’s still more than 100,000 Russian troops surrounding Ukraine. Russia continues to surge troops and equipment to the borders of Ukraine, and we believe that they are in a position where they can invade at any time.</p>
<p>Of course, we just can’t control what Russia will do next, but what we can do is make clear with our allies and partners that there will be massive consequences to Russia should Putin choose to further invade Ukraine. And if Russia does invade, it will end up in a weaker position over time, and the NATO Alliance will be stronger and more united.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Honduras"></a> To your second question on Honduras, we’re declassifying and publicizing the inclusion of former Honduran President Juan Orlando Hernández in the Corrupt Undemocratic Actors List under Section 353 of the United States-Northern Triangle Enhancement Engagement Act. The department included Hernández on this list effective July 1st on – in 2021.</p>
<p>According to multiple credible media outlets, Juan Orlando Hernández has engaged in significant corruption by committing or facilitating acts of corruption and narcotrafficking and using proceeds of illicit activity to facilitate political campaigns.</p>
<p>I would say in addition Hernández was identified by name in a sworn witness testimony in a U.S. Federal criminal proceeding as having received narcotrafficking proceeds as a part of his campaign funding. And pursuant to Section 353 of the United States-Northern Triangle Enhancement Engagement Act, individuals identified through this list are generally ineligible for visas to travel to the United States.</p>
<p>I would also add that the United States encourages the fight against corruption as a core national security priority. And of course, we’re engaged in a careful, thorough effort to combat corruption in Honduras as well as across the region and as well as around the world.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to the line of Matt Lee.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hey Matt, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, I have two brief ones on Iran. I realize you don’t have a readout from Vienna, but I’m just wondering: Can you say if Rob Malley and the team has at least begun to have meetings – the indirect meetings – with the Europeans, or are they just kind of waiting for – to have – to begin those contacts tomorrow or later today?</p>
<p>And then secondly, you guys have made the case that the sanctions waivers that were signed on Friday by the Secretary do not invoke or do not require the provisions of INARA to be followed because it’s not a quid pro quo or part of a – part of an agreement. But you probably will have seen a letter that has been sent by, I think, 33 Republican senators that says that it does actually, and, also, more – perhaps more importantly that they will block or move to block any kind of an agreement that you do – that you may reach with Iran if it is not submitted to Congress first.</p>
<p>And so, part – and so without getting into congressional correspondence, I’m just wondering if you can assure members of Congress now that you will be submitting any agreement that you get in Vienna to Congress for its approval. And then also very briefly, just to remind you of the first one, have the actual meetings with the U.S. team begun? Thanks.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Iran2"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hey Matt, I think I want to go back to your first question. I thought you asked initially had meetings with Special Envoy Malley started with the Europeans yet. And if that’s correct, I don’t have anything to share or read out at the moment.</p>
<p>But to your second question on Congress, I’d reiterate at the top what I shared on the – with one of the questions of your colleagues, which is that Special Envoy Malley continues to brief members of Congress even remotely. But what I’ll say more specifically is that the administration will carefully consider the facts as well as the circumstances of any U.S. return to the JCPOA to determine the legal implications, which would include under INARA. We’re committed to ensuring the requirements of INARA are satisfied.</p>
<p>And the President believes that a bipartisan approach to Iran is the strongest way to safeguard U.S. interests for the long term. And the administration officials have reached out at all levels to members of Congress as well as their staff to discuss our approach to Iran. Special Envoy Malley remains deeply committed to continued close engagement with Congress in a bipartisan manner as Iran policy continues to develop.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to the line of Luis Rojas.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. I have only one question today. Do you have any update on the possible retabulation of remittance to Cuba or on the sending of diplomatic personnel to the United States Embassy in Havana, please?</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Cuba"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Luis. To your second question, I don’t have any announcements or any updates to make about personnel issues, but I’d just reiterate what we have shared in the past to your first question, which was: following the July 2021 protest the administration created a remittance working group to explore options to facilitate remittances to Cuba that would go to maximally benefit the Cuban people, and that would also include by allowing Cuban families to support each other and also minimize or eliminate benefits to the Cuban regime and its military.</p>
<p>Also, in August of 2021, the remittance working group shared its analysis that includes potential options with other members of the administration, and the administration continues to consider these options and explore innovative solutions such as digital payment. Outside of that, we don’t have any specific timetables for a decision or any other updates to share, at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to the line of Will Mauldin.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks so much, Jalina. I just wanted to follow up on Conor’s question about the French diplomacy in Russia and Ukraine, and was wondering if Secretary Blinken – I know he’s traveling, but he has a pretty good telephone set on board – or any of the other senior members of the department, Under Secretary Nuland or Deputy Secretary Sherman, had been in touch with the French or were expected to, or other people in the administration. And if they – and what was the general view on that? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-UkraineFranceRussia2"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Will. I don’t have anything much else to add from what I shared with Conor in that we are – we continue to be in close consultation and coordination with our allies and partners, and we continue to be in alliance with them as well.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Jiha Ham, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, good afternoon. I have two questions for you today. Yesterday, VOA reported that a North Korean defector, who is a military officer, who is also known as a cryptocurrency expert, was arrested by Russia and now imprisoned in a North Korean consulate in Vladivostok. Some expect that he will be sent back to North Korea. Do you have any concerns that this may be another forced repatriation case that we have seen in China many times? Some human rights experts suggest that the State Department should ask Russia to free this person. So, what’s your position on this?</p>
<p>And my second question is about China’s remark yesterday at the Security Council. The Chinese ambassador said that there have been serious humanitarian consequences in North Korea and the import of humanitarian livelihood goods have been severely restricted because of the sanctions on North Korea. But in fact, there are many aid groups who have received sanctions exemptions, and quite many of them are ready to send those important items, but the problem is North Korea’s border closure. So, do you have any response or comment on this? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-HumanitarianSanctionsNorthKorea"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Jiha. I’ll start with your second question. The United States has led efforts to streamline the process for humanitarian sanctions exemptions at the UN and it has also committed to reviewing such applications as quickly as possible. We’ve also maintained broad exemptions and authorizations across many of the sanctions programs, including the DPRK program, aimed at ensuring that U.S. sanctions don’t hamper the transfer and delivery of humanitarian aid.</p>
<p>And to your first question, I would have to refer you to colleagues at the Department of Homeland Security.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Albert Hong, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>One more North Korean issue. North Korea’s Foreign Ministry said it had never committed a cyber crime. North Korea also accused the United States for cyber crime. What is the State Department&#8217;s position of that?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks for your question. While I haven&#8217;t seen those reports before your question, I would just say that U.S. diplomats work with countries around the world to promote the stability in cyberspace and also reduce the risk of conflict. They coordinate with partners and allies to call out and impose consequences on states that use cyber capabilities irresponsibly. They also implement programs to enhance the capacity of partner countries to implement effective cyber policies, respond to cyber threats, which would include cyber crime, and also participate in international conversations on cyber issues.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s take a final question from Anas Elsabbar.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yes, thank you, Jalina. My question regarding the designation of Houthis as a terrorist group. I don&#8217;t know if you have any update on this. And also, there were news about designating some Houthis’ top leaders and sanctioning them in the near future. I don&#8217;t know if you have any update on that as well.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you, Anas. I, actually, don&#8217;t have any updates on either to share at this time, but certainly happy to share them as soon as we do.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Afghanistan"></a> Now, before I close today’s briefing I just – I thought this might have come up, but since it didn&#8217;t, I just wanted to take a moment to address something very specific that has been in our news cycle. Following the Secretary’s hearing in Congress last week on Afghanistan, there has been renewed reflection on events from last year as well as interest in our Afghan relocation efforts.</p>
<p>There was a media report today recounting internal discussions and deliberations from a Department of Defense internal report related to the end of the U.S. war in Afghanistan from last summer. Cherry-picked comments do not reflect the months of work that were already underway or the whole picture of what the U.S. diplomats undertook to facilitate the evacuation and relocation of U.S. citizens, lawful permanent residents, and allies – Afghan allies from Afghanistan. Some of the claims allegedly included in the report regarding State Department personnel and plans are outright false and shamefully so.</p>
<p>I also want to take a moment to acknowledge the career Foreign Service officers who were in Afghanistan, who demonstrated immense bravery, professionalism, and dedication to doing the mission during extraordinarily difficult circumstances. They put their lives at risk, standing shoulder to shoulder with our armed forces at gates to the airport, and in the end helping 124,000 Americans, foreigners, Afghan allies and their families leave Kabul.</p>
<p>Of course, this mission continues today. Many of these courageous colleagues have volunteered to be part of the team at State Department leading our ongoing Afghan relocation efforts. And this Department is proud of their service and their sacrifice, and I am personally honored to serve with them.</p>
<p>That ends today’s press briefing. I hope you have a wonderful day, and we’ll see you back here tomorrow.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:29 p.m.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Good afternoon, and thank you all for joining today’s press briefing. I don’t have any elements at the top, but I’ll give it a few extra minutes to have some more reporters filter in the queue before I start taking your questions.</p>
<p>So, let’s start off with the line of Cindy Spang, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, hello. Good afternoon. I have a question about Jamshid Sharmahd, a German Iranian dissident and longtime California resident who was abducted by Iran and went on trial Sunday and could face the death penalty. Would you have any comment or reaction to that, please? And thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-GermanyIran"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Cindy. We’re certainly aware of the reports regarding Jamshid Sharmahd’s detention, but we’re going to have to refer you to the Government of Germany for any further inquiries.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to Janne Pak.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hello.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hello.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you, Janne. Great to hear from you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, because very hard to – this signal here. So, I have two questions for you. And it is an important time for the U.S. and ROK-Japan trilateral alliance to respond to North Korea’s successive provocations. Will there be any discussion about the South Korea’s ascension to the Quad at the three-party foreign ministers meeting in Hawaii?</p>
<p>Second question: It is reported that the North Korea is operating on ICBM bases on the border between North Korea and China. My question is: Do you have any specific information about this? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Quad"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Janne. I’ll start with your first question first. And just broadly speaking, I’d like to say that the Quad is an essential multilateral grouping that convenes four like-minded democracies. Of course, that’s the U.S., Australia, Japan, and India. And the purpose, of course, is to make tangible progress on pressing challenges within the Indo Pacific. It’s also based on our shared values and capability. Each Quad member shares collective commitments to democracy, peace, security, and prosperity in the region.</p>
<p>To answer your questions about South Korea’s ascension into the Quad, I certainly don’t have any details to share other than what we issued in our readout – that was our travel announcement, excuse me, that was issued last Friday.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-NorthKorea"></a> But what I would say is that we continue to consult closely with the Republic of Korea, Japan, as well as other allies and partners on how to best engage the DPRK. The United States condemned the DPRK’s missile launches, and of course the DPRK wants to normalize illicit weapons testing, but we’re taking a calibrated approach, as we’ve said previously, to these provocations based on the degree of threat to the United States as well as to our allies.</p>
<p>Of course, as it can’t be understated, a number times, that our goal remains the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and that we have no hostile intent towards the DPRK and remain open to meeting the DPRK without preconditions. Of course, however, we also have an obligation to address the DPRK’s recent provocations and enforce UNSCRs that are already in place.</p>
<p>To your second question, on the ICBM base on the border with China, I would say that our goal remains the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. The DPRK constitutes a threat to international peace and security and the global nonproliferation regime. It’s – the United States has a vital interest in deterring the DPRK. That includes defending against its provocations or uses of force, limiting the reach of its most dangerous weapons programs, and above all keeping the American people, our deployed forces, and our allies safe.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to the line of Daphne Psaledakis, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for doing this. How has the resumption of Iran talks in Vienna gone today? Has any progress been made? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Iran"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks for your question, Daphne. Special Envoy Malley has actually just recently returned to Vienna. He returned yesterday for the eighth round of talks that resumed today. I don’t have anything to read out from there. Of course, he continues to meet on the sidelines with our partners in Vienna. He also continues to brief Congress virtually, but outside of that I don’t have anything else to say, and I certainly wouldn’t want to get ahead of the talks. Of course, if we do have updates, we’ll be certain to share them with you as soon as we have them.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Michel Ghandour, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for the call. I have a question on Iran talks, but since you have no update, I will ask you about Lebanon and Senior Advisor Hochstein who’s in Beirut today. Is he bringing any U.S. plan or offer to solve the maritime dispute between Lebanon and Israel? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-LebanonIsrael"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Michel. So, what I would say at the top is that the maritime boundary is a decision for both Israel and Lebanon to make. And of course, the U.S. stands ready to facilitate negotiations on the maritime boundary between both Lebanon and Israel, and we support efforts to reach a mutually beneficial agreement.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Conor Finnegan, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hi. Yes, Conor, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey. Hey, Jalina. Two questions for you. On Ukraine first, any response to the talks between Presidents Macron and Putin, now that we’ve heard a bit more about them from both sides? Macron specifically said today that Putin told him Russia wouldn’t initiate an escalation. I’m wondering if you believe that’s true.</p>
<p>And then a second question on Honduras. The information that was declassified and publicized last night that former President Hernández was included on the list of corrupt and undemocratic actors – why was this information declassified now, and does it send the wrong message that heads of government would only face repercussions like this once they leave power? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-UkraineFranceRussia"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So, Conor, I will start with your first question. On Macron, I would just say that we are engaged in intensive diplomacy with our allies and partners, but I’m – I just can’t get into detail about private meetings. But one of the messages that we’ve tried to send very clearly to Russia is that the West is united, and the fact is that there’s still more than 100,000 Russian troops surrounding Ukraine. Russia continues to surge troops and equipment to the borders of Ukraine, and we believe that they are in a position where they can invade at any time.</p>
<p>Of course, we just can’t control what Russia will do next, but what we can do is make clear with our allies and partners that there will be massive consequences to Russia should Putin choose to further invade Ukraine. And if Russia does invade, it will end up in a weaker position over time, and the NATO Alliance will be stronger and more united.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Honduras"></a> To your second question on Honduras, we’re declassifying and publicizing the inclusion of former Honduran President Juan Orlando Hernández in the Corrupt Undemocratic Actors List under Section 353 of the United States-Northern Triangle Enhancement Engagement Act. The department included Hernández on this list effective July 1st on – in 2021.</p>
<p>According to multiple credible media outlets, Juan Orlando Hernández has engaged in significant corruption by committing or facilitating acts of corruption and narcotrafficking and using proceeds of illicit activity to facilitate political campaigns.</p>
<p>I would say in addition Hernández was identified by name in a sworn witness testimony in a U.S. Federal criminal proceeding as having received narcotrafficking proceeds as a part of his campaign funding. And pursuant to Section 353 of the United States-Northern Triangle Enhancement Engagement Act, individuals identified through this list are generally ineligible for visas to travel to the United States.</p>
<p>I would also add that the United States encourages the fight against corruption as a core national security priority. And of course, we’re engaged in a careful, thorough effort to combat corruption in Honduras as well as across the region and as well as around the world.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to the line of Matt Lee.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hey Matt, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, I have two brief ones on Iran. I realize you don’t have a readout from Vienna, but I’m just wondering: Can you say if Rob Malley and the team has at least begun to have meetings – the indirect meetings – with the Europeans, or are they just kind of waiting for – to have – to begin those contacts tomorrow or later today?</p>
<p>And then secondly, you guys have made the case that the sanctions waivers that were signed on Friday by the Secretary do not invoke or do not require the provisions of INARA to be followed because it’s not a quid pro quo or part of a – part of an agreement. But you probably will have seen a letter that has been sent by, I think, 33 Republican senators that says that it does actually, and, also, more – perhaps more importantly that they will block or move to block any kind of an agreement that you do – that you may reach with Iran if it is not submitted to Congress first.</p>
<p>And so, part – and so without getting into congressional correspondence, I’m just wondering if you can assure members of Congress now that you will be submitting any agreement that you get in Vienna to Congress for its approval. And then also very briefly, just to remind you of the first one, have the actual meetings with the U.S. team begun? Thanks.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Iran2"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hey Matt, I think I want to go back to your first question. I thought you asked initially had meetings with Special Envoy Malley started with the Europeans yet. And if that’s correct, I don’t have anything to share or read out at the moment.</p>
<p>But to your second question on Congress, I’d reiterate at the top what I shared on the – with one of the questions of your colleagues, which is that Special Envoy Malley continues to brief members of Congress even remotely. But what I’ll say more specifically is that the administration will carefully consider the facts as well as the circumstances of any U.S. return to the JCPOA to determine the legal implications, which would include under INARA. We’re committed to ensuring the requirements of INARA are satisfied.</p>
<p>And the President believes that a bipartisan approach to Iran is the strongest way to safeguard U.S. interests for the long term. And the administration officials have reached out at all levels to members of Congress as well as their staff to discuss our approach to Iran. Special Envoy Malley remains deeply committed to continued close engagement with Congress in a bipartisan manner as Iran policy continues to develop.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to the line of Luis Rojas.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. I have only one question today. Do you have any update on the possible retabulation of remittance to Cuba or on the sending of diplomatic personnel to the United States Embassy in Havana, please?</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Cuba"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Luis. To your second question, I don’t have any announcements or any updates to make about personnel issues, but I’d just reiterate what we have shared in the past to your first question, which was: following the July 2021 protest the administration created a remittance working group to explore options to facilitate remittances to Cuba that would go to maximally benefit the Cuban people, and that would also include by allowing Cuban families to support each other and also minimize or eliminate benefits to the Cuban regime and its military.</p>
<p>Also, in August of 2021, the remittance working group shared its analysis that includes potential options with other members of the administration, and the administration continues to consider these options and explore innovative solutions such as digital payment. Outside of that, we don’t have any specific timetables for a decision or any other updates to share, at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s please go to the line of Will Mauldin.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks so much, Jalina. I just wanted to follow up on Conor’s question about the French diplomacy in Russia and Ukraine, and was wondering if Secretary Blinken – I know he’s traveling, but he has a pretty good telephone set on board – or any of the other senior members of the department, Under Secretary Nuland or Deputy Secretary Sherman, had been in touch with the French or were expected to, or other people in the administration. And if they – and what was the general view on that? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-UkraineFranceRussia2"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Will. I don’t have anything much else to add from what I shared with Conor in that we are – we continue to be in close consultation and coordination with our allies and partners, and we continue to be in alliance with them as well.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Jiha Ham, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, good afternoon. I have two questions for you today. Yesterday, VOA reported that a North Korean defector, who is a military officer, who is also known as a cryptocurrency expert, was arrested by Russia and now imprisoned in a North Korean consulate in Vladivostok. Some expect that he will be sent back to North Korea. Do you have any concerns that this may be another forced repatriation case that we have seen in China many times? Some human rights experts suggest that the State Department should ask Russia to free this person. So, what’s your position on this?</p>
<p>And my second question is about China’s remark yesterday at the Security Council. The Chinese ambassador said that there have been serious humanitarian consequences in North Korea and the import of humanitarian livelihood goods have been severely restricted because of the sanctions on North Korea. But in fact, there are many aid groups who have received sanctions exemptions, and quite many of them are ready to send those important items, but the problem is North Korea’s border closure. So, do you have any response or comment on this? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-HumanitarianSanctionsNorthKorea"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Jiha. I’ll start with your second question. The United States has led efforts to streamline the process for humanitarian sanctions exemptions at the UN and it has also committed to reviewing such applications as quickly as possible. We’ve also maintained broad exemptions and authorizations across many of the sanctions programs, including the DPRK program, aimed at ensuring that U.S. sanctions don’t hamper the transfer and delivery of humanitarian aid.</p>
<p>And to your first question, I would have to refer you to colleagues at the Department of Homeland Security.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Albert Hong, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>One more North Korean issue. North Korea’s Foreign Ministry said it had never committed a cyber crime. North Korea also accused the United States for cyber crime. What is the State Department&#8217;s position of that?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks for your question. While I haven&#8217;t seen those reports before your question, I would just say that U.S. diplomats work with countries around the world to promote the stability in cyberspace and also reduce the risk of conflict. They coordinate with partners and allies to call out and impose consequences on states that use cyber capabilities irresponsibly. They also implement programs to enhance the capacity of partner countries to implement effective cyber policies, respond to cyber threats, which would include cyber crime, and also participate in international conversations on cyber issues.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s take a final question from Anas Elsabbar.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yes, thank you, Jalina. My question regarding the designation of Houthis as a terrorist group. I don&#8217;t know if you have any update on this. And also, there were news about designating some Houthis’ top leaders and sanctioning them in the near future. I don&#8217;t know if you have any update on that as well.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you, Anas. I, actually, don&#8217;t have any updates on either to share at this time, but certainly happy to share them as soon as we do.</p>
<p><a id="post-312524-Afghanistan"></a> Now, before I close today’s briefing I just – I thought this might have come up, but since it didn&#8217;t, I just wanted to take a moment to address something very specific that has been in our news cycle. Following the Secretary’s hearing in Congress last week on Afghanistan, there has been renewed reflection on events from last year as well as interest in our Afghan relocation efforts.</p>
<p>There was a media report today recounting internal discussions and deliberations from a Department of Defense internal report related to the end of the U.S. war in Afghanistan from last summer. Cherry-picked comments do not reflect the months of work that were already underway or the whole picture of what the U.S. diplomats undertook to facilitate the evacuation and relocation of U.S. citizens, lawful permanent residents, and allies – Afghan allies from Afghanistan. Some of the claims allegedly included in the report regarding State Department personnel and plans are outright false and shamefully so.</p>
<p>I also want to take a moment to acknowledge the career Foreign Service officers who were in Afghanistan, who demonstrated immense bravery, professionalism, and dedication to doing the mission during extraordinarily difficult circumstances. They put their lives at risk, standing shoulder to shoulder with our armed forces at gates to the airport, and in the end helping 124,000 Americans, foreigners, Afghan allies and their families leave Kabul.</p>
<p>Of course, this mission continues today. Many of these courageous colleagues have volunteered to be part of the team at State Department leading our ongoing Afghan relocation efforts. And this Department is proud of their service and their sacrifice, and I am personally honored to serve with them.</p>
<p>That ends today’s press briefing. I hope you have a wonderful day, and we’ll see you back here tomorrow.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:29 p.m.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Promoting Sustainable Peace and Responsive Governance in Somalia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/promoting-sustainable-peace-and-responsive-governance-in-somalia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 21:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The best path toward sustainable peace in Somalia is through the rapid conclusion of credible elections. The United States has repeatedly expressed concern over the delays and procedural irregularities in Somalia’s electoral process and the broader implications of those irregularities for the country’s democracy and stability.</p>
<p>Today, on the one-year anniversary of the expiration of the Somali president’s term in office, I am announcing the implementation of a policy under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act that restricts the issuance of visas to current or former Somali officials or other individuals who are believed to be responsible for, or complicit in, undermining the democratic process in Somalia, including through violence against protestors, unjust arrests or intimidation of journalists and opposition members, and manipulation of the electoral process. Immediate family members of such persons may also be subject to these restrictions.</p>
<p>This policy will apply to individuals who have played a role in procedural irregularities that have undermined the electoral process, who have failed to follow through with their obligations to implement timely and transparent elections, and who have targeted journalists and opposition party members with harassment, intimidation, arrest, and violence.</p>
<p>Somalia’s national and federal member state leaders must follow through on their commitments to complete the parliamentary process in a credible and transparent manner by February 25, which will further lay the groundwork for responsive governance in Somalia. The United States strongly supports the Somali people, and we are committed to working together to advance democracy and mutual prosperity for both of our countries.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The best path toward sustainable peace in Somalia is through the rapid conclusion of credible elections. The United States has repeatedly expressed concern over the delays and procedural irregularities in Somalia’s electoral process and the broader implications of those irregularities for the country’s democracy and stability.</p>
<p>Today, on the one-year anniversary of the expiration of the Somali president’s term in office, I am announcing the implementation of a policy under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act that restricts the issuance of visas to current or former Somali officials or other individuals who are believed to be responsible for, or complicit in, undermining the democratic process in Somalia, including through violence against protestors, unjust arrests or intimidation of journalists and opposition members, and manipulation of the electoral process. Immediate family members of such persons may also be subject to these restrictions.</p>
<p>This policy will apply to individuals who have played a role in procedural irregularities that have undermined the electoral process, who have failed to follow through with their obligations to implement timely and transparent elections, and who have targeted journalists and opposition party members with harassment, intimidation, arrest, and violence.</p>
<p>Somalia’s national and federal member state leaders must follow through on their commitments to complete the parliamentary process in a credible and transparent manner by February 25, which will further lay the groundwork for responsive governance in Somalia. The United States strongly supports the Somali people, and we are committed to working together to advance democracy and mutual prosperity for both of our countries.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States Releases Updated List of Critical and Emerging Technologies</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-releases-updated-list-of-critical-and-emerging-technologies/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 20:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312490</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The White House has released an updated list of Critical and Emerging Technologies (“CET List”), which will serve to inform a forthcoming strategy on U.S. technological competitiveness and national security.</p>
<p>Critical and emerging technologies (CETs) are a subset of advanced technologies that are potentially significant to U.S. national security. The 2021 Interim National Security Strategic Guidance defines three national security objectives: protect the security of the American people, expand economic prosperity and opportunity, and realize and defend democratic values. This list identifies CETs with the potential to further these objectives and builds on the October 2020 National Strategy for Critical and Emerging Technologies, which contains an initial list of priority CETs.</p>
<p>The U.S. Government, the private sector, and allies and partners must understand and remain focused on developing and deploying the technologies that are most critical to our national security, economic prosperity, and to realizing and defending our democratic values. In addition, our joint leadership in CETs faces growing challenges from strategic competitors and adversaries who recognize the benefits of CET and are organizing human and capital resources on a national scale to challenge our lead in areas with long-term consequences.</p>
<p>In response to these challenges, the United States remains unwaveringly committed to advancing technology leadership with our allies and partners to protect our shared security interests, economic prosperity, and democratic values.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The White House has released an updated list of Critical and Emerging Technologies (“CET List”), which will serve to inform a forthcoming strategy on U.S. technological competitiveness and national security.</p>
<p>Critical and emerging technologies (CETs) are a subset of advanced technologies that are potentially significant to U.S. national security. The 2021 Interim National Security Strategic Guidance defines three national security objectives: protect the security of the American people, expand economic prosperity and opportunity, and realize and defend democratic values. This list identifies CETs with the potential to further these objectives and builds on the October 2020 National Strategy for Critical and Emerging Technologies, which contains an initial list of priority CETs.</p>
<p>The U.S. Government, the private sector, and allies and partners must understand and remain focused on developing and deploying the technologies that are most critical to our national security, economic prosperity, and to realizing and defending our democratic values. In addition, our joint leadership in CETs faces growing challenges from strategic competitors and adversaries who recognize the benefits of CET and are organizing human and capital resources on a national scale to challenge our lead in areas with long-term consequences.</p>
<p>In response to these challenges, the United States remains unwaveringly committed to advancing technology leadership with our allies and partners to protect our shared security interests, economic prosperity, and democratic values.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Turkish Foreign Minister Cavusoglu</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-turkish-foreign-minister-cavusoglu-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 18:21:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312409</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Turkish Foreign Minister Mevlut Cavusoglu. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Cavusoglu discussed ways to further coordination and NATO unity regarding the threat of further Russian escalation and aggression against Ukraine. The Secretary emphasized our shared commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and noted President Erdogan’s engagement in support of a diplomatic resolution. The leaders discussed Turkey-Armenia normalization and additional steps the United States could take to support these efforts. They also reviewed opportunities to maintain a robust U.S.-Turkey bilateral relationship.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Turkish Foreign Minister Mevlut Cavusoglu. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Cavusoglu discussed ways to further coordination and NATO unity regarding the threat of further Russian escalation and aggression against Ukraine. The Secretary emphasized our shared commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and noted President Erdogan’s engagement in support of a diplomatic resolution. The leaders discussed Turkey-Armenia normalization and additional steps the United States could take to support these efforts. They also reviewed opportunities to maintain a robust U.S.-Turkey bilateral relationship.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with African Union Commission Chairperson Faki</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-african-union-commission-chairperson-faki-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 17:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312387</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with African Union Commission Chairperson Moussa Faki Mahamat. They discussed possible ways forward on political and security matters in Africa, including Sudan, Mali, and Burkina Faso and the need to bolster democracy on the continent. Secretary Blinken reaffirmed U.S. prioritization of our important partnership with the AU, particularly in initiatives to strengthen democratic institutions in furtherance of peace and security resulting from the recent 2022 AU Heads of State Summit on February 5-6.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with African Union Commission Chairperson Moussa Faki Mahamat. They discussed possible ways forward on political and security matters in Africa, including Sudan, Mali, and Burkina Faso and the need to bolster democracy on the continent. Secretary Blinken reaffirmed U.S. prioritization of our important partnership with the AU, particularly in initiatives to strengthen democratic institutions in furtherance of peace and security resulting from the recent 2022 AU Heads of State Summit on February 5-6.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Media Freedom Coalition Statement on Closure of Media Outlets in Hong Kong</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/media-freedom-coalition-statement-on-closure-of-media-outlets-in-hong-kong/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 17:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312384</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The undersigned members of the Media Freedom Coalition express their deep concern at the Hong Kong and mainland Chinese authorities’ attacks on freedom of the press and their suppression of independent local media in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Recent developments include the raid of Stand News offices, the arrests of its staff, and the subsequent self-closure of Citizen News, stemming from concern over the safety of its staff. Since the enactment of the National Security Law in June 2020, authorities have targeted and suppressed independent media in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. This has eroded the protected rights and freedoms set out in the Basic Law and undermines China’s obligations under the Sino-British Joint Declaration. This has also caused the near-complete disappearance of local independent media outlets in Hong Kong. These ongoing actions further undermine confidence in Hong Kong’s international reputation through the suppression of human rights, freedom of speech and free flow and exchange of opinions and information.</p>
<p>A stable and prosperous Hong Kong in which human rights and fundamental freedoms are protected should be in everybody’s interest. We urge Hong Kong and mainland Chinese authorities to respect freedom of the press and freedom of speech in Hong Kong, in line with the Basic Law and China’s obligations under the Sino-British Joint Declaration.</p>
<p><em>Signed by the Governments of Australia, Austria, Canada, Czech Republic, Estonia, Finland, Germany, Iceland, Ireland, Italy, Japan, Latvia, Lithuania, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, New Zealand, Slovakia, Slovenia, Switzerland, the United Kingdom, the United States.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The undersigned members of the Media Freedom Coalition express their deep concern at the Hong Kong and mainland Chinese authorities’ attacks on freedom of the press and their suppression of independent local media in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Recent developments include the raid of Stand News offices, the arrests of its staff, and the subsequent self-closure of Citizen News, stemming from concern over the safety of its staff. Since the enactment of the National Security Law in June 2020, authorities have targeted and suppressed independent media in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. This has eroded the protected rights and freedoms set out in the Basic Law and undermines China’s obligations under the Sino-British Joint Declaration. This has also caused the near-complete disappearance of local independent media outlets in Hong Kong. These ongoing actions further undermine confidence in Hong Kong’s international reputation through the suppression of human rights, freedom of speech and free flow and exchange of opinions and information.</p>
<p>A stable and prosperous Hong Kong in which human rights and fundamental freedoms are protected should be in everybody’s interest. We urge Hong Kong and mainland Chinese authorities to respect freedom of the press and freedom of speech in Hong Kong, in line with the Basic Law and China’s obligations under the Sino-British Joint Declaration.</p>
<p><em>Signed by the Governments of Australia, Austria, Canada, Czech Republic, Estonia, Finland, Germany, Iceland, Ireland, Italy, Japan, Latvia, Lithuania, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, New Zealand, Slovakia, Slovenia, Switzerland, the United Kingdom, the United States.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary Zeya and Acting Assistant Secretary Peterson Travel to the Global Conference for Media Freedom Hosted by Estonia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-zeya-and-acting-assistant-secretary-peterson-travel-to-the-global-conference-for-media-freedom-hosted-by-estonia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 15:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312329</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights Uzra Zeya and Acting Assistant Secretary for Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor Lisa Peterson will visit Tallinn, Estonia, February 9-11 for the third Global Conference for Media Freedom. Co-hosted by the Estonian Ministry of Foreign Affairs and Estonian Institute of Human Rights, this event is a multilateral, multi-stakeholder forum for strengthening global efforts that defend media freedom and the safety of journalists worldwide.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Zeya’s participation in the main conference panel on the Protection of Journalists reinforces to our international partners that we remain resolute in our position that journalists must be able to do their work free from threats, harassment, violence, and all forms of intimidation.</p>
<p>In the spirit of the Year of Action following President Biden’s first Summit for Democracy, the Estonian Ministry of Foreign Affairs is organizing a pledging session focused on defending media freedom, a key Summit theme. During this session, participants will make statements on their commitments to defend media freedom. Acting Assistant Secretary Peterson will provide opening remarks framing this session. As part of the Year of Action, the U.S. and other governments will turn words into action and discuss progress at the second Summit for Democracy.</p>
<p>Concurrently, the United Kingdom, Canada, and the Netherlands are hosting the second Media Freedom Coalition Ministerial where video remarks from Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will set the stage for two days of in-person and virtual roundtables, panels, and sessions, with government representatives, journalists, academics, civil society representatives, and other stakeholders. Under Secretary Zeya will lead the U.S. delegation to the Ministerial.</p>
<p>While in Tallinn, Under Secretary Zeya and Acting Assistant Secretary Peterson will engage senior government counterparts and civil society on human rights issues and will emphasize the United States’ firm commitment to press freedom &#8211; both online and offline &#8211; and advocate for the safety of journalists and media workers worldwide.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights Uzra Zeya and Acting Assistant Secretary for Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor Lisa Peterson will visit Tallinn, Estonia, February 9-11 for the third Global Conference for Media Freedom. Co-hosted by the Estonian Ministry of Foreign Affairs and Estonian Institute of Human Rights, this event is a multilateral, multi-stakeholder forum for strengthening global efforts that defend media freedom and the safety of journalists worldwide.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Zeya’s participation in the main conference panel on the Protection of Journalists reinforces to our international partners that we remain resolute in our position that journalists must be able to do their work free from threats, harassment, violence, and all forms of intimidation.</p>
<p>In the spirit of the Year of Action following President Biden’s first Summit for Democracy, the Estonian Ministry of Foreign Affairs is organizing a pledging session focused on defending media freedom, a key Summit theme. During this session, participants will make statements on their commitments to defend media freedom. Acting Assistant Secretary Peterson will provide opening remarks framing this session. As part of the Year of Action, the U.S. and other governments will turn words into action and discuss progress at the second Summit for Democracy.</p>
<p>Concurrently, the United Kingdom, Canada, and the Netherlands are hosting the second Media Freedom Coalition Ministerial where video remarks from Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will set the stage for two days of in-person and virtual roundtables, panels, and sessions, with government representatives, journalists, academics, civil society representatives, and other stakeholders. Under Secretary Zeya will lead the U.S. delegation to the Ministerial.</p>
<p>While in Tallinn, Under Secretary Zeya and Acting Assistant Secretary Peterson will engage senior government counterparts and civil society on human rights issues and will emphasize the United States’ firm commitment to press freedom &#8211; both online and offline &#8211; and advocate for the safety of journalists and media workers worldwide.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary Monica Medina’s Travel to France</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-monica-medinas-travel-to-france/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312224</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica Medina will travel to France, February 8-11, to participate in the One Planet Summit for the Ocean (One Ocean Summit), sponsored by the Government of France. Assistant Secretary Medina will speak on panels that address ocean governance and the role of women in the protection of the ocean, among others. She will also engage with government counterparts to advance efforts related to marine protected areas; ocean plastic pollution; countering illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing; and conservation and sustainable use of marine biological diversity in areas beyond national jurisdiction.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica Medina will travel to France, February 8-11, to participate in the One Planet Summit for the Ocean (One Ocean Summit), sponsored by the Government of France. Assistant Secretary Medina will speak on panels that address ocean governance and the role of women in the protection of the ocean, among others. She will also engage with government counterparts to advance efforts related to marine protected areas; ocean plastic pollution; countering illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing; and conservation and sustainable use of marine biological diversity in areas beyond national jurisdiction.</p>
<p>For press inquiries, contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OES-PA-DG@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing – February 7, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-february-7-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=312152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:36 p.m. EST</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon. One element at the top, and then we’ll go ahead and get started with your questions.</p>
<p>The United States is deeply concerned by <a id="post-312152-TUNISIA"></a>Tunisian President Saied’s calls to dissolve the Supreme Judicial Council, and the reported barring of employees from entering the Supreme Judicial Council.</p>
<p>An independent judiciary is a core element of an effective and transparent democracy.</p>
<p>It is essential that the Government of Tunisia uphold its commitments to respect the independence of the judiciary as stipulated in the constitution.</p>
<p>The United States reiterates our calls for an accelerated political reform process in Tunisia that responds to the aspirations of the Tunisian people through the inclusion of diverse voices representing political parties, civil society and unions, particularly in the ongoing national consultations, and that ensures the continued respect for Tunisia’s human rights.</p>
<p>At this critical time, we also urge the Government of Tunisia to prioritize implementing the economic reforms required to stabilize the financial situation and address Tunisia’s growing economic challenges.</p>
<p>With that, happy to take your questions. Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. So I realize that <a id="post-312152-UKRAINERUSSIAREGION"></a>Ukraine is still the flavor of the day, but I don’t really have anything big on Ukraine, so I will – after I ask my first very brief initial question I’ll defer to others on Ukraine because I want to go to Iran.</p>
<p>Just on Ukraine, the joint statement – I realize that in the press conference the Secretary and Mr. Borrell spoke about Russia, but I’m just wondering why there was no mention of Russia at all in the joint statement from the EU-U.S. Energy Council meeting. I mean, it wasn’t – the word wasn’t even in there.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the word Ukraine certainly was. There was a &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, it was.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There was a robust discussion of Ukraine. There was a robust discussion of the contingency planning that we’re doing in the event that Russia does not choose the path of diplomacy, does not choose the path of dialogue. And as the joint statement noted, the council reiterated that it is unacceptable to use energy supplies as a weapon or geopolitical lever. This is what we have been saying all along, and much of the discussion today between the Secretary and between the high representative was part and parcel of the contingency planning that we’ve been doing for some time now.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. But what – I mean, was there a reason that Russia is not mentioned in there? I mean presumably, yes, it’s obvious that the threat to European energy security is coming from Russia. They are the main supplier and this is – but I’m just wondering why it wasn’t mentioned. Was there some objection to it being mentioned, or was it – did it ever come up in the discussions?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I am not aware there was any substantive reason for it. It’s a question of syntax.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All right. Then I will pass and &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But I do want to – I have a couple important ones on Iran.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m sure we’ll get there. Daphne.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Senior U.S. officials are in Europe this week coordinating sanctions and export control measures that can be used in the event that Russia invades Ukraine. Is the U.S. looking for commitments from counterparts during this trip on what action will be taken if Russia invades, and will Nord Stream 2 be part of discussions?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So, Daphne, what we spoke about earlier was the fact that we continue to take part in robust and to lead robust coordination and consultation with our European partners and allies on the consequences that would befall Moscow if it chooses the path of aggression. We have been consulting very closely with our allies and our partners over the course not of weeks but really of months now, and that includes the package that would respond to Russian aggression.</p>
<p>And so as you alluded to, today a U.S. delegation that included officials from Treasury and from the Department of State, including the Assistant Secretary of the Treasury for Terrorist Financing and Financial Crimes Elizabeth Rosenberg, Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Export Administration Assistant Secretary Rozman Kendler, Deputy Assistant Secretary here at the State Department Molly Montgomery, traveling to Europe to discuss technical coordination. And so over the past several weeks and even longer, we have discussed at a strategic level what we would – what the consequences that would befall Moscow were it choose – were it to choose this path.</p>
<p>There have been very detailed discussions in the context of that. Beyond the broad top lines there are a myriad of details and technical matters that will need to be worked out if we are in the unfortunate position of having to move forward with this strong and unified response. And so what you – what our team from the State Department, from the Department of Commerce, from the Department of Treasury are doing is meeting with their counterparts and European interlocutors to have those – to continue, I should say, those technical discussions to ensure that across the board we’re ready to go should, again, we be in the unfortunate position of needing to mobilize this response.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And will <a id="post-312152-NORDSTREAM"></a>Nord Stream 2 be a part of that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I don’t know if it’ll be part of these specific discussions. What I can say is that, of course, the President is meeting with Chancellor Scholz today at the White House. Leading up to this meeting we have had a number of discussions with our German allies on energy security broadly, on Nord Stream 2 specifically, both in the context of what we’re seeing from Russia and beyond.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. Good to see you again.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good to see you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. I have a few questions on South Korea, China, and North Korea. First of all, on South Korea: South Korea Government frequently fails to participate in the UN Security Council statement condemning North Korea’s missile provocations or ignored North Korea’s human rights issues. How does the U.S. evaluate South Korea’s attitude?</p>
<p>The second one, on China. After the UN Security Council meeting last week, the Chinese ambassador to the UN has blamed United States for the recent missile launch by North Korea. As you know, the South Korea – and I’m sorry, he has insisted that the U.S. should take more flexible approach, as in you know South – North Korea and China and Russia are strategically the same body. What is the United States position on China justifying North Korea’s missile provocations?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-312152-SOUTHKOREANORTHKOREA"></a>So let me take your first question first. As you know, since the start of this administration we have been investing heavily in our alliances and partnerships around the globe, and of course, that includes in the Indo-Pacific. There are a number of shared challenges and shared opportunities we have with our allies in the Indo-Pacific, of course, our treaty allies Japan and the ROK among them. And among those challenges are the DPRK, maybe one of the more – certainly is one of the more pressing challenges we have with those allies.</p>
<p>In recent days, the deputy secretary, the – our Special Representative for the DPRK Sung Kim, they have engaged their South Korean, their ROK, and Japanese counterparts. And as I think you know, this evening we’ll be departing for Australia, where we will see our Japanese counterparts in the context of the Quad – there will be a bilateral engagement there – before we then go by way of Fiji to Hawaii, where we’ll engage in a trilateral discussion with our South Korean and Japanese counterparts. And I think you – I can be confident that one of the priority issues of discussion in that setting will be the recent provocations we’ve seen from the DPRK, including its missile launches.</p>
<p>We know that when it comes to the fulfillment and the achievement of any progress towards our overriding goal, one of the indispensable ingredients is close coordination with our allies and partners. And the Japan – Japan and ROK are, of course, two of our allies with whom we work with most closely on this challenge. We know that that bilateral coordination is important, but we also know that trilateral coordination between the United States, Japan, and the ROK really is and will be indispensable if we are to achieve progress. It’s also a priority for our allies, Japan and the ROK, because of the threat that the DPRK poses not only to Americans in the region, potentially to deployed forces, but also to our treaty allies Japan and the ROK. So it’s something we take extraordinarily seriously and we know they do as well.</p>
<p>When it comes to – and this gets to your second question – our approach to the <a id="post-312152-NORTHKOREA"></a><a id="post-312152-PALESTINIANS"></a>DPRK, look, if you want to assign responsibility for the DPRK’s provocations, for the potential threats to international peace and security we’ve seen emanate from the DPRK, the only party that deserves blame, the only party that can be assigned culpability, is the DPRK. We have made very clear that we have no hostile intent towards the DPRK. We have made very clear that we wish to engage in dialogue and diplomacy. We have made very clear that we believe that only through dialogue and diplomacy can we most effectively achieve what, again, is our overriding policy objective, and that’s the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Follow-up, quick questions. North Korea has been engaged in peace process dialogue with the United States and South Korea in the past, while on the other hand it has been accelerating its – has been North Korea military buildup work. What is the ultimate tool for the United States besides diplomatic compromise to block North Korea global threat?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the ultimate tool is diplomacy, and we know that previous administrations have tried this. No administration has been successful, despite undertaking strategies that, in many cases, look very different from one another. And so the strategy we have is not akin to the strategy that the last administration had. It is not also exactly akin to the strategy that the Obama administration had. It is a strategy that the Biden-Harris administration has put forward after an intense policy review, and a policy review that determined that, through diplomacy and dialogue, it is our hope that there can be incremental progress – incremental progress towards the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>Now, of course, we have not yet found a willing partner in Pyongyang to engage in that dialogue, but we have continued even in the absence of substantive engagement from the DPRK to coordinate closely with Japan, with the ROK, other allies and partners in the Indo-Pacific, but also allies and partners around the world, which you have seen us do in the UN, which you’ve seen us do in Europe, and elsewhere as we take on this challenge.</p>
<p>Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you. Can I go to the Palestinian issue?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I have a couple questions on settler violence on Omar Assad. <a id="post-312152-ISRAELPAL"></a> But before that, the White House issued a statement saying that President Biden is going to go and visit Israel later this year. Is he likely to also go – I mean, I know this is a White House probably question, but do you think that he will also make a detour to, like, Bethlehem or Ramallah 20 minutes away?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, Said, as you alluded to, the readout of the conversation between President Biden and Prime Minister Bennett did make a reference to President Biden’s intent to travel to the region later this year. Obviously, this was just announced yesterday, so I wouldn’t want to get into the itinerary at this point. In any case, I’d need to refer you to the White House.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I understand. Ned, I mean, you – almost every week, you come – you state opposition or displeasure with settler violence activities and so on. And I mean, in the last four days, I could cite a number of issues. I don’t want to go through them all – I mean, the Israelis – from home demolishing to attacks on the Al-Aqsa Mosque to poisoning of wells. I mean, all kinds of things, a whole – across the gamut. When will you guys issue a very strong statement and say this should not stand? I mean, if you want to give the two-state solution, as you keep saying, a chance, they should stop right now this stuff.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Said, I would take issue with the premise of your question. We have spoken to this clearly and unequivocally &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I understand that you’ve spoken – sorry to interrupt, but you speak all the time. I said that to begin with. But you – what action are you taking to make sure that what you say is actually listened to and adhered to?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, first of all, it is important what we say. And you have – as you alluded to, you’ve heard me say this, including in recent days. But we have been very clear, we have been very consistent on this: We believe it is absolutely critical for all parties to refrain from steps that exacerbate tensions. This includes violence, incitement to violence; home demolitions; the eviction of families from homes in East Jerusalem, including families that have lived there for generations; that includes the destruction of property and for providing compensation for individuals imprisoned for acts of terrorism. All of these things move us further away from what continues to be our desired end state, and that is a two-state solution – a two-state solution that continues to be in the best interests of Israel, of the Palestinian people, and something that successive American administrations have supported.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Now, one last question on Omar Assad, the Palestinian-American who died in Israeli custody. I know that last Tuesday you guys issued a statement. Has anything transpired since then? Have the Israelis come forward to you? Are you completely satisfied, or are you still asking for more accountability? Because apparently, those who did it, they were sort of slapped on the wrist.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, we did issue a statement on this yesterday. That statement spoke of our concern, but it also spoke of our ongoing dialogue with our Israeli partners on this.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You did?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We did. We issued one on February 1st, I believe.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah, not yesterday. Yesterday &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sorry, did I say yesterday?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yes, you did.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We issued it last week. I’m sorry.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Last Tuesday. Last week we got it.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes, yes. Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just a quick update on Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Do you have any idea when you’re going to have the formal response from Moscow and when there is new engagement with Foreign Minister Lavrov &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We don’t <a id="post-312152-RUSSIAUKRAINE"></a>have any updates on that. As I conveyed last week, the Secretary had an opportunity to speak to Foreign Minister Lavrov. It was our understanding following that engagement that the Russians were working on a response to our so-called non-paper, a response that would be sent to and approved, presumably, by Vladimir Putin before it would transmitted back to us. That has not yet happened. It was also our understanding that once that did happen, that the Russians would be prepared to engage in follow-on diplomacy, but again, we’ll need to – the first step in that was receiving the Russian response, which has not yet happened.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And do you expect that follow-on engagement can happen while the Secretary is traveling, or more probably when he comes back from his travel?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We don’t have any additional details to share in terms of timing, in terms of format or the mode for that engagement, so I’d hesitate to get ahead of it.</p>
<p>Ben.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just make sure – I think I know the answer to this, but I just want to make about the – and without getting into the whole back and forth that happened last week, your &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t know what you’re talking about, Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, and nor do I. Your belief that there is some Russian false flag operation that’s being planned has not changed, right, since last Thursday? Is that correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> That is correct. That is correct.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And are you prepared today to offer any additional &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I am prepared to do today is to explain what I perhaps inartfully tried to do last week in explaining what it is we’re trying to do and why we’re not able to provide a full set of information or at least all of the information that you and your colleagues may ask for. The Secretary spoke to this briefly earlier today, but this gets to our bottom line proposition. We believe that the best antidote to disinformation is information, and that is why you have seen us employ concerted efforts across the board. We want to go the extra mile to ensure that, again, to the extent possible, the American people and people around the world have an understanding of what we know and what undergirds our concern for the threat that Moscow poses.</p>
<p>Now, an element of that has been our declassification of information, including intelligence information, that is in our possession. And as you heard me say last week, we’ve done that with two overriding objectives in mind. The first and, of course, our preference is to be in a position to deter the Russians from going forward. We want by exposing this information and making sure that Moscow knows what we know to have them think twice or many more times before moving forward with such a reckless action.</p>
<p>If we’re not able to do that, if we’re not able to deter further invasion or aggression against Ukraine, we at least want to be in the position of having let the world know that despite the disinformation, despite the propaganda and lies that presumably Moscow will say after the fact, that the world will know what we knew all along, and that is the fact that Moscow sought to fabricate a pretext for this aggression very similar to what they did in 2014. Matt, you know that in 2014 the Russians went into Ukraine, sent their proxy forces into Ukraine, claiming that Russians were under threat, claiming that a three-year-old boy had been crucified, claiming that they had no choice but to do so. Again, this is why we are so concerned about what we are seeing now and what we know now.</p>
<p>Now, in taking this approach, we recognize that the information that we’re able to put forward will necessarily be limited, and it will be limited for a reason that you also know well. Again, we – even as we seek to expose Moscow’s efforts, we don’t want to jeopardize or potentially jeopardize our ability to collect this kind of information going forward. But when we do the cost-benefit analysis and we consider if the choice is between putting forward necessarily incomplete, sometimes broad, sometimes general information in an attempt to deter aggression or, on the other hand, if the choice is to keep that to ourselves and potentially not play every card available to us, that’s not a difficult choice.</p>
<p>Again, we are doing this in an effort to, in the first instance, deter; if we’re not able to do that, to expose what Moscow has had in mind all along. We want to see this crisis resolved peacefully, we want to see this crisis resolved diplomatically, and we will do everything we responsibly think we can – responsible in terms of tactics, but also responsible in terms of our national security and our ability to continue to benefit from this information going forward to bring about what we hope is a diplomatic outcome.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. So – and I’m not going to get into sort of what like we – I did last week, but the bottom line is that no, you are not prepared to share any of the information that you have that would suggest that this is actually correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Is that right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Again, we have shared significant information &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, no &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>And &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, I said I didn’t want to get back into this. Do you have anything more that you can say &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Beyond &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; to back up the claim than you did – than you had to say last week? That’s all.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Beyond what we told you last week &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; in pretty detailed terms about the Russian plans &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We don’t have anything further to offer on that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. And then and the proof &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Then you’re saying – hold on, Said, just – last one. The proof that you’re correct is that nothing is actually going to happen? Is that what you’re saying?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, I – that is not – that’s not &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Because you will have – because you putting this out there will have stopped the Russians from doing it, correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, I – what I said is that our overriding objective in the first instance is to deter Russian aggression. That is why we are doing a number of things.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I’m speaking entirely only about this alleged false flag operation that you’re talking about. You’re saying that the proof that there is a false flag operation is going to come when nothing actually happens, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I did not say that, Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I said that our overriding objective is to deter Russian aggression against Ukraine, further Russian aggression against Ukraine. I acknowledge I will probably never be able – well, I will certainly never be able to give you the proof that you I’m sure want. But we are doing this – we are doing this not in an effort, I’m sorry to say, to satisfy you but in an effort to prevent and deter an invasion.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>It’s not really about satisfying me. But anyway, I don’t want to – I don’t want to take up &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, can you clarify something at this time?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So you think that the Russians are still scheming to do this today with the same intensity as they were last week? Or have they &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I’m not in a position to give you an update on this specific scheme, but I think our concerns about the Russians potentially resorting to these tactics, the same sort of false flag tactics that they have – that they did resort to in the past, those concerns are still very present.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, you know one gets the impression that an attack or an invasion is imminent, it’s just a question of time, maybe a few days, mid-month, whatever. So on the scale of one to ten – I know you guys like this – what is the likelihood of invasion? Is it about seven? Is it about eight? Are we today closer to nine, let’s say, than we were last week?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I am going to refer you to Vladimir Putin. Again, we have put forward these two paths. It is our strong, strong preference that we pursue the path of diplomacy and dialogue. What I will say and what you heard the National Security Advisor speak to yesterday is that we are now in the window, given what we have seen from the Russians over weeks and even longer now – amassing troops along Ukraine’s borders, dispatching forces into Belarus, taking other steps that have positioned them to move forward at any moment if they so choose.</p>
<p>We do not yet believe that Vladimir Putin has made a decision. It is our goal in all of this, including what I was discussing with Matt just a moment ago, to deter an invasion. If we’re not able to deter an invasion, we will then resort to the other path. It’s a path of hefty, stark consequences for Russia. It’s also a path of defense for our allies on the eastern flank of NATO.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Are you aware of reports where a high-level Russian officer – or the head of the officers school, whatever it is – warned Putin against the invasion of Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I’ve seen these reports. I understand that there was an open letter, so I’ve certainly seek that – seen that. Again, I don’t have a specific comment on it. Our goal is to solve conflicts through diplomacy. We’re seeking to do that for the good of the American people, the good of Ukrainian people, the good of the Russian people, and people all throughout Europe, knowing that any renewed invasion of Ukraine would carry tremendous costs, tremendous costs across many realms. It’s our goal to do everything we can to avoid that.</p>
<p>Yes, Ben.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You just said in your answer to Matt that if you have to put forward incomplete information to deter an attack, then so be it. What were you referring to there? I mean, is the intelligence behind this video perhaps incomplete?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, I was referring to the fact that there have been demands for everything we have in our possession behind this intelligence, and that’s not something we’re able to provide, again, because of our desire not to jeopardize sources and methods, our desire not to jeopardize &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, if you’re referring to me, that’s not true. I asked for literally, quote/unquote, any shred of evidence – not even proof, because not all evidence is proof. I asked for anything. I didn’t ask for everything. I didn’t ask for sources or methods. I just asked &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; for anything that would back it up. That’s all.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The challenge, Matt, is that by divulging details, further details, you would necessarily get into sources and methods. And so that is why we’re in the position of putting forward what we know in a way that we consider to be responsible vis-à-vis our objectives going forward, and one of those objectives going forward is to protect our ability to collect this kind of information going forward. We are trying to strike a very difficult balance. There are – when it comes to national security and the tension, the inherent tension between national security and transparency, there is never an easy formula. Not always do we get it right. No administration has always gotten it right, but we are leaning forward here.</p>
<p>The only reason we’re having this discussion is because we publicized some of what was in our possession. We could have kept that to ourselves. It would have made for a much less memorable briefing last Thursday, but that wasn’t the responsible thing in our estimation to do. Again, we want to make sure at the end of the day, whether we are able to deter an invasion or whether in the aftermath of an invasion, that we have done everything we responsibly can to do that. And one of the tactics we’ve used, one of the tactics I would say we’ve used probably more so than previous administrations, is declassifying information or making public information that previously was not public. That is not something that – it is not something that administrations have done certainly to this degree.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You also say that we’re in the window now where an attack might happen. You’ve said it repeatedly that an attack is imminent.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We’ve never said repeatedly that an attack is imminent. We have said that we are now in the window where if &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I think numerous times you’ve used the word “imminent.”</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We – we have said that if Vladimir Putin decides to move &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Inaudible) and 50,000 people are going to be dead. What are you talking about?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I can’t be accountable for what others write. What we have said &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>What others write?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>What &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And “imminent” is a word that has been used.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>What we have said is that if Vladimir Putin decides to go forward with an invasion, they have now positioned themselves to the degree that they’re able to do that whether it is within a day, within a couple weeks. They have now reached that point.</p>
<p>But imminent suggests that this is a foregone conclusion, that this is a certainty. So &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No one in the administration has used the word “imminent” to describe &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think what you might have heard is potentially imminent. That &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>What – if an invasion were imminent, we would not be prioritizing diplomacy and dialogue the way we have. Imminence suggests that this is a foregone conclusion, that there is no way to avoid it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think if you’ve been listening to what we’ve been saying for the past two months now, the emphasis we’ve placed on dialogue and diplomacy, the emphasis that we’ve placed on deterring an invasion, the emphasis that we have placed on finding a diplomatic way out of this, you would understand that we’re not talking about something that is a foregone conclusion. We are talking about something that is one of two paths. We’ve consistently talked about one of two paths. It’s certainly possible that Vladimir Putin will choose that path. It is our hope that he will choose the path of diplomacy and dialogue, that we can avoid the bloodshed, that we can avoid the violence, that we can avoid the destabilizing forces that would descend not only on Ukraine but well beyond in terms of the implications.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>My question was actually going to be: Considering that we are in that window now and there’s talk of a potentially imminent invasion, was there ever a discussion about postponing the Australia trip? Is now the right time to be crossing the world, going to Fiji, when this invasion could happen at any time?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Ben, we are a big country. We are a big department. We have a lot of challenges on our plate. The Secretary of State is the Secretary of State wherever in the world he is. He has access to secure communications wherever in the world he is. He, I’m sure, will be focused to a large degree on this challenge even while he is in the Indo-Pacific. It will certainly come up in conversations with counterparts in the Quad and elsewhere, but I can assure you, you will also see that he will remain active on the phones with our interagency counterparts. He and we are capable of – again, not to use an overused metaphor, but of walking and chewing gum at the same time.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Sorry, Ned, but the Secretary said &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And juggling.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>And juggling.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The Secretary said that Ukraine is prepared to give special status in the Donbas region.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>He was referring to the – he was referring to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Is that, like, sort of walking back from the – that sort of thing?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, it was – it is reiterating what’s in the Minsk Agreements. The Minsk Agreements spell out a means by which to de-escalate the conflict in Eastern Ukraine. Special status is a term that’s used in the Minsk Agreements.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Ben.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>After you made the accusation last week – the administration – about this false flag operation and then the reassessments leaked over the weekend, the Ukrainian foreign minister tweeted today, “Do not believe the apocalyptic predictions. Different capitals are calculating different scenarios.” Is he wrong that there isn’t this sort of apocalyptic situation that you all are discussing?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We see eye to eye with our Ukrainian partners in the sense that now is not the time for panic. What we are calling for, what we are doing is moving forward with preparation. We want to be prepared and we need to position ourselves to be prepared regardless of which path it is that Vladimir Putin takes. It’s our hope that we pursue that of dialogue and diplomacy. It is certainly possible that we are not able to deter an invasion and not able to deter renewed aggression and that we’ll have to be prepared for that path of defense and deterrence.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But, I mean, you say that you’re seeing eye to eye. He’s saying that what you’re saying is wrong.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t think you’ve heard us use the term “cataclysmic,” if that’s – if that was the quote.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> “Apocalyptic.”</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> “Apocalyptic.”</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But he was specifically referring to what U.S. officials have said in recent days, in the last week.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I – the Ukrainian ambassador to Washington has spoken to this; President Zelenskyy has spoken to our coordination with the Ukrainian Government. What we are doing is engaged in prudent preparation. We are doing that with our European allies but also with our Ukrainian partners.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> When the Secretary and Foreign Minister Kuleba spoke on Friday, did the foreign minister express any of these concerns to the Secretary?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, we issued a readout of that call, so I don’t have anything to add beyond that readout. We have a close relationship with Ukraine. Ukraine, of course, is a close partner of ours. We can speak candidly with close partners when it comes to our concerns. Our Ukrainian partners, our European allies, and others, they know of the basis for our concerns. Number one, they hear what we say publicly in the same way you do, but we are also in a position to share some of that underlying information with our European allies, with other allies, as well as with our Ukrainian partners.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just one last question on this. During – in the Ukrainian readout as well, it said that the Secretary reaffirmed the U.S. was working to provide additional economic assistance to the Ukrainian Government. Can you say anything more about that? What’s on the table, dollar amount, or if anything is forthcoming?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, so we have said for some time now that even as we work to provide Ukraine with security assistance, we know that this – certainly Russian aggression, even the threat of Russian aggression, could have a toll on Ukraine’s economy. So we have provided half a billion dollars in development and humanitarian assistance in the past year. We are exploring additional macroeconomic support to help Ukraine’s economy amidst pressure resulting from Russia’s military buildup.</p>
<p>Last week, on February 3rd, we and several of our allies and partners announced a new partnership fund for a resilient Ukraine. It’s a fund that bolsters the resilience and perseverance of communities in eastern Ukraine, those communities that are in some ways bearing the brunt, have borne the brunt of Russia’s aggression. USAID has a expert in the country who’s monitoring the situation closely, coordinating with other donors, assessing the evolving humanitarian needs of the Ukrainian people, and liaising with partners to ensure that they are able to rapidly scale up assistance should the need arise.</p>
<p>Over the past year, we and Ukraine have finalized a memorandum of understanding on commercial cooperation. It’s a memorandum, MOU, designed to facilitate commercial participation by U.S. companies across the Ukrainian economy and by Ukrainian companies here in the United States.</p>
<p>And then finally, the EXIM, the Export-Import Bank, has made available $3 billion in support for projects in Ukraine, and the DFC, the Development Finance Corporation, has a current investment portfolio in Ukraine of approximately $800 million across more than a dozen projects. Those range from renewable energy to higher education and access to financing for small and medium-sized enterprises.</p>
<p>Rosiland.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Stay on Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m going to take off my mask because I can’t hear when I wear this. You keep talking about we want to resolve this diplomatically. There are reports that the Ukrainians have asked the U.S. to station some THAAD anti-missile systems in the eastern part of the country, ostensibly to guard against any Russian missile attacks. The UK has decided to deploy 350 Royal Marines to Poland. Are these kinds of actions the thing that the West wants to be telegraphing if it wants Moscow to actually resolve all of these issues about Ukraine and about NATO’s posture? I mean, how does that – how does moving troops and possibly stationing anti-missile systems actually get you what you want?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. So I can’t speak to moves that haven’t been announced, that are hypothetical, that may not come to pass. But what I can speak to is what we’ve announced, and everything we have announced has been in the vein of defense and deterrence, across the board. Whether it is our security assistance for Ukraine – the $650 million that was provided last year – that is defensive security assistance; whether it is the authorization for our NATO Allies to pass U.S.-origin material to Ukraine, that is defensive material.</p>
<p>When it comes to the service members who have been put on heightened state of readiness should they be called upon by the North Atlantic Council, that would be in the vein of defense and deterrence. When it comes to the service members who are being sent to offer reassurance and sent to deter further Russian aggression against – or Russian aggression, I should say – against NATO’s eastern flank, that is done in the vein of defense and deterrence.</p>
<p>Everything we are doing is in an effort to see to it that we are not faced with a renewed Russian invasion, that Russian aggression does not move forward. Now, we are doing all of this also knowing that in the end, Vladimir Putin may choose the path of conflict, of an invasion, of renewed aggression. But we are doing, as I was saying to Matt and to others earlier, everything we can in an effort to in the first instance deter, but also to send a very clear signal that we stand by our commitments under Article 5 when it comes to protecting our NATO Allies, that the United States will live up to its obligations, the United States will continue to provide the sort of defensive security assistance that Ukraine needs to defend itself.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But deploying a THAAD system is a pretty serious deal. I mean, think about the controversy in Korea, where they have asked for the systems and it’s engendered a lot of uproar as well as criticism from Pyongyang.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, I can’t speak to measures that haven’t been announced or that remain hypothetical.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Let me also ask you about Macron’s meeting with Putin today. What sense does the U.S. have about what Macron was going to try to bring up once the cameras left the meeting room? Has Ambassador Sullivan and his team been able to get a readout from the French on how willing Putin is to back away in this crisis?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, when it comes to the engagement of our partners, let me make the broader point that over the past month-plus, we have heard from our European allies, we have heard from our Ukrainian partners, we’ve heard from others an appreciation for what the United States has been doing with Russia diplomatically, and that includes in our bilateral engagement. And in expressing that appreciation and understanding, we’ve heard from our allies and partners that they have taken that approach because we have done all of this in a manner that is thoroughly coordinated, that has been consultative in its approach with our allies and partners, and that is conducted in full transparency with them. “Nothing about without” is not just a mantra for us, it is the guiding principle in terms of how we have conducted ourselves, including in this – in our bilateral engagements with Russia.</p>
<p>So, similarly, we would welcome any diplomatic efforts that are conducted in a similar manner that have the potential – excuse me – to de-escalate the crisis that Moscow has needlessly precipitated. When it comes to the<a id="post-312152-FRANCERUSSIA"></a> French, as you know, President Biden yesterday had an opportunity to speak to President Macron. This would be his second conversation with the French president in several days. Secretary Blinken yesterday spoke to the foreign minister, Foreign Minister Le Drian. We are well coordinated across the board, and that includes with the French, with Paris.</p>
<p>The result of all of this is that the message President Putin is hearing from the United States, from NATO, from our allies and partner – partners, it is loud and it is singular, and that is the fact that a diplomatic solution is the only responsible path. But again, if Russia chooses otherwise, we will be prepared. We will be prepared with a response that is swift, severe, and united. I saw President Macron made comments just before he left. You will hear those same messages from the French president.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And is the U.S. confident that once Chancellor Scholz goes to Moscow next week that that same unified message is going to be delivered? Because Germany is in a slightly different position than other countries in Europe.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, as luck would have it, C<a id="post-312152-GERMANYRUSSIA"></a>hancellor Scholz is in Washington today. He’s at the White House today. But I should say this is not luck, the fact that Chancellor Scholz is here to have these consultations with President Biden, a follow-on to the consultations and the discussions that the two leaders have had over the phone and over video conference in recent weeks. This is a testament to the close and continued coordination and cooperation with our European allies across the board – board, excuse me – including, of course, with Germany. So I expect you’ll be hearing a lot more about that today from the President and chancellor.</p>
<p>Yes, in the back.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, I’d like to ask about proximity of Vladimir Putin and Latin America. So last week the Argentinian President Alberto Fernández was in Moscow, and in the coming days the Brazilian President Jair Bolsonaro will be there. And there are reports in Brazil about the fact that the U.S. is putting pressure on Bolsonaro to cancel his trip to Russia. I would like you to elaborate a bit about the concerns and the reasons why the U.S. wants Brazil to skip this trip to Russia, and if the U.S. has the same confidence that – you talked about France – that you are well coordinated when we are talking about the Brazilian visit to Moscow.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we engage with our<a id="post-312152-BRAZILRUSSIA"></a> Brazilian partners on – at multiple levels regularly. We are, of course, aware of the reports of President Bolsonaro’s travel plans. We and many other nations around the world, including in this hemisphere, are deeply concerned about the potentially destabilizing role that Russia is playing and its ongoing threat to sovereignty and to territorial integrity, including, of course, in Ukraine.</p>
<p>As democratic countries – the United States, Brazil, Argentina, others in the region and beyond – we have a responsibility to stand up for democratic principles and for the rules-based order. This is the same order that has undergirded unprecedented levels of stability, of security, of prosperity over the past 70 years, and that is true – it is equally true in Europe as it is in the Western Hemisphere, as it is in the Indo-Pacific. So we know that Brazil and other countries in the region – you mentioned Argentina as well – we share values. That is one of the hallmarks of our relationship, and we have – we know that those values will be conveyed and will undergird concerns that President Putin hears not only from the United States but our partners around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But what does the U.S. expect from this Brazilian visit to Moscow?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It’s not for us to speak to what – the goals that President Bolsonaro may have in mind. I am confident that there will be discussions both before and after the trip with our Brazilian partners.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, and if China pledges it support Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, as well as North Korea, what actions will the United States take against China for this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sorry. Could you clarify the question?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. China pledged to support Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, as well as North Korea. What actions will the United States take against China?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, so if you’re asking about the relationship between <a id="post-312152-CHINARUSSIA"></a>Russia and China, I know that this is something that our Assistant Secretary for Asia and Pacific Affairs Dan Kritenbrink spoke to last week. But what we have seen over the course not of days, not of weeks, but of years and probably longer, is an approach that both of these countries have taken for some time, and that is an increasing closeness between Russia and China.</p>
<p>It would be our hope, given the implications of a renewed Russian aggression and certainly Russian invasion of Ukraine, that the PRC would have taken advantage of dialogue, of this relationship, to encourage Russia to pursue the course of diplomacy and de-escalation. This is what the world expects of responsible powers.</p>
<p>The Secretary had a conversation with Foreign Minister Wang of the PRC the other week – the other day, I should say – and there was a discussion of the potential for renewed Russian aggression, renewed Russian invasion, of Ukraine, and the fact that it would not only have implications in Ukraine, not only in Europe, but in many ways it would be a threat to peace and security around the world because it would be a flagrant violation of the same rules-based international order that applies equally in the Indo-Pacific as it does in Europe.</p>
<p>If in the end China is seen as having supported Russia’s move to choose conflict or war over diplomacy, it will cost China in terms of how it’s seen in the eyes of the world. It will have an effect on the PRC’s global reputation. We – as Russia and China talk about a singular partnership, we are focused with our 29 NATO Allies, we are working with the EU, we are working with our allies in the Indo-Pacific and partners around the world to not only incentivize and to work towards a diplomatic resolution, but also to be in a position to respond decisively if Russia does choose the path of aggression.</p>
<p>We told you last month of – we listed out many of the engagements that we’ve had with partners and allies. That tally has now grown to some 200 phone calls, in-person meetings, video conferences. Of course, one of them you saw today when Secretary Blinken hosted High Representative Josep Borrell of the EU.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>On North Korea, UN sanctions monitors reported to the Security Council that cyber attacks on cryptocurrency exchanges and financial institutions by North Korea were an important revenue source for North Korea to fund its nuclear and ballistic missile programs. What is the United States doing to try and stop this, and does the U.S. believe North Korea’s receiving any outside help to help carry out these cyber attacks?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I don’t have any assessment to offer from here in terms of outside support or assistance that <a id="post-312152-NORTHKOREA2"></a>North Korea may be receiving. What I can say generally without speaking to any specific report at this time is that North Korea’s activity and behavior in cyberspace has long been a serious concern of the United States. We have in the past disclosed and attributed malicious attacks to the DPRK – the attack in 2014, I believe it was, that the DPRK perpetrated against a private American company, a destructive attack against Sony may be an instructive case in point for some of the capabilities and some of the behavior that the DPRK has exhibited in cyberspace.</p>
<p>So it is not just the DPRK’s ballistic missile and nuclear weapons programs. It is – it is not just its record on human rights. There are other profound concerns we have, including its behavior in cyberspace.</p>
<p>Yes, Ben. Welcome to – yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>With the restoration – with the restoration of the sanctions waiver on<a id="post-312152-IRAN"></a> Iran, which is akin to lifting sanctions in the sense that it enriches them to a certain degree &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, it does not, Ben.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But wasn’t that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>But it – that’s not true. It does not do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, was the restoration of the sanctions waiver in any way an incentive to get them back to the table and continue negotiations?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So to be very clear, what you said was not true. The issuance of the so-called IFCA waiver in no way enriches Iran. This is about two things. This is about nuclear non-proliferation and nuclear safety. I would suspect most reasonable observers would agree that both of these things are in our vital national interest regardless of what happens with the JCPOA, if we’re able to achieve a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA or if we’re not. We decided to renew and to restore this sanctions waiver to do one thing, and that is to enable third-party participation in nuclear non-proliferation and safety projects in Iran, owing to the growing proliferation concerns we have, in particular with respect to the increasing stockpiles of enriched uranium in Iran, the stockpiles that have grown following the last administration’s decision to abandon the JCPOA.</p>
<p>Absent this waiver, the sort of detailed technical discussions with third parties regarding the disposition of stockpiles and other activities of non-proliferation value, they couldn’t take place. The Trump administration, as you know, provided a similar waiver for years even after its foolish decision to leave the JCPOA, precisely because the last administration recognized the non-proliferation value of these waivers. I don’t know that I’ve quoted Secretary Pompeo before from here, but Secretary Pompeo said about this waiver, quote, “This decision will help…reduce proliferation risks.”</p>
<p>So additionally, the technical discussions facilitated by the waiver are necessary in the final weeks of JCPOA talks, as the waiver itself would be essential if we were be in a position – to be in a position to – if Iran were to resume compliance with its nuclear commitments. But again, even if talks do not culminate in a mutual return to compliance, these sorts of technical discussions could still contribute to our non-proliferation goals.</p>
<p>Non-proliferation, nuclear safety – these things may not mean a lot to a whole lot of people. So just to give you a few examples of activities that these waivers – this waiver would cover: for example, the modernization of the Arak reactor based on the design approved by the JCPOA, the conversion of the reactor to a much less proliferation-sensitive design. This waiver would approve the preparation and modification of the Fordow facility for stable isotope production. It would remove a potential impediment to efforts to end uranium enrichment at Fordow, as Iran committed to do under the JCPOA. It would facilitate the transfer outside Iran of enriched uranium to result in a reduction in Iran’s stockpile to no more than 300 kilograms of up to 3.67 percent enriched LEU.</p>
<p>I could go on, but the point is that this waiver is not about providing Iran with funds. This waiver is about what is manifestly in our nonproliferation interests, in our – in service of nonproliferation safety to the United States, to our partners and allies around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you talk about the timing of it, though, and why the decision was taken on Friday?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Did it have anything to do with &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the fact is if we are in a position to resume compliance with the JCPOA, this waiver will need to be in place in order to effect some of the steps to make Iran’s nuclear program less dangerous. If we are not in a position to achieve a mutual return to compliance, these are still – these steps are still in our interest.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> What makes you think that that next step that they are – that we’re one step closer to rejoining the JCPOA then?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I didn’t say that we were. I’m saying that this prepares us in the event we are able to achieve a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA. This could still very much go one of two ways: a mutual return to compliance if Iran is in a position and willing and able to make the sort of political commitments necessary; or the alternatives that we’ve talked about in some less deal – detail but that we still talked about.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, are you – that long list of things that you said that these waivers give, you’re saying that there’s no benefit to Iran in any of that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I am saying that the net benefit of this is a nonproliferation benefit for us.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Iran gets nothing out of it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> When you say sanctions waiver &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m not talking about – hold on a second.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, you don’t need to raise your voice. You don’t &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But you’re the one – you’re the one who – you guys are the ones who said you were restoring the waivers, right? Okay. So if Iran really gets no benefit at all out of this, then why even bother?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Why bother? I just explained to Ben. Because if &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, well, you – tell me why Iran doesn’t benefit from this.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, this is something that redounds &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You’re talking about – you’re assuming that everyone thinks that sanctions relief equals dollars &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, that was the question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; going to Iran.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The question was you just waived &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It was.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That wasn’t really the question.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It was.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That was the way you interpreted the question.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You can refer to the transcript.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So sanctions relief does not necessarily mean only dollar bills flying across the table into Iran – into the Iranian treasury’s coffers, does it? Or is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> In this case, it will allow Iran to undertake nuclear nonproliferation and safety activities that would otherwise be proscribed.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, which is a benefit to Iran that it was not getting before.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The fact is, Matt, that what is in our nonproliferation interest can also be, in some ways, in Iran’s interest. That doesn’t change the fact that it is manifestly in our interest.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do they – so do they get a benefit of &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, I was referring to the sort &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do they get any benefit out of this or not?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It is – some of these steps redound to their interest.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do they get any benefit or not?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> This is in our interest to do, which is precisely why the last &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is it in Iran’s interest as well?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; which is why the last administration did it. In 2018, Secretary Pompeo, as I quoted before, said precisely this decision will help reduce proliferation &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And two years later – and two years later when he rescinded the waivers, he said that – he accused of Iran of taking – of participating in nuclear blackmail and said that they weren’t – that they weren’t deserving of the benefits that accrue to them under this.</p>
<p>You’re stuck on this idea that – and interesting that you used the word “enrich” because I think you’re talking about it in terms of money, but enrichment obviously has a different kind of meaning when it comes to Iran. But I don’t understand how you can say that Iran gets no benefit and that this isn’t some kind of sanctions relief that you – that the administration has offered to Iran before it has made any of its own concessions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, the question I was responding to took this in a vein &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Well, then, forget about the question you were &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; you think you were responding to. Answer my question: Does Iran benefit at all from the waivers that were signed?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You will need to ask the Iranian Government whether they think this is a benefit to them. We know &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, who do you think this benefits? Just you?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We know this is of benefit to us. The ability of third-party entities to work on nuclear nonproliferation projects &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, I’m sorry, now is the U.S. &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; and nuclear safety projects in Iran in the face of our growing concerns, nonproliferation and nuclear safety concerns – that is in our benefit, yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The people that this benefits, in fact, are actually Russian, Chinese, European companies, right? Is that what you’re saying?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, I am saying that it is manifestly to our advantage &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And not Iran’s?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It benefits us to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Well, if you can argue that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; be able to address nuclear safety and nuclear nonproliferation concerns on Iran.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> If you’re able to argue that Iran gets no benefit out of this successfully, which you haven’t convinced me of, but anyway – but if you’re able to, then good on you. Now, do you think that these waivers trigger INARA?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt, we have a robust conversation with Congress on progress in Vienna. We have briefed Congress regularly on the discussions. I have every expectations that those briefings will continue in the days and weeks ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, do you believe that this triggers the requirements of the Iran Nuclear Review Act?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>What I can say is that we’ve had conversations with Congress about requirements should we be in a position to resume compliance with the JCPOA, but I don’t have anything for you on these particular – this IFCA waiver.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, not IFCA. INARA.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Right, but you’re saying “these” in response to IFCA.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah. Well, so you’re aware of the requirements of INARA, right? That any agreement reached with Iran has to be submitted. Are you saying that it did trigger INARA and your notification to Congress on Friday fulfills the requirements of INARA?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, I’m not saying that. I’m saying &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Oh, well, then why did you even notify Congress in the first place?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We regularly notify Congress when it comes to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Laughter.) Okay. Well – so did it trigger INARA or not?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt, when it – we will carefully consider the facts and circumstances when it comes to any potential U.S. return to the JCPOA to determine the implications under INARA.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So you don’t think that this falls under the scope of INARA.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I have no reason to believe that this was done pursuant to INARA. This is something we, as I said before, we regularly engage with Congress when it comes to developments in Vienna &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, it’s a technical issue. I get that, and probably boring the hell out of everybody, but it is an important one, because if it – even if the notification wasn’t done under INARA, do you think that the waivers trigger the – trigger the INARA requirements for any agreement with Iran related to its nuclear program? These do relate to its nuclear program, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>This is, as you said, a technical question, so we’ll get you a technical answer.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, why shouldn’t Iran benefit – why shouldn’t Iran benefit from the waiver? I mean, I thought the whole purpose of negotiations is so everybody goes back to the deal and sanctions will be lifted, Iran will pull back from any nuclear threat and so on, and everything will be hunky-dory. So why is that such a bad thing if Iran benefits?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>You’ll have to ask &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, I’m asking you because you – you’re the one who’s &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I am not speaking to what Iran may be saying about this; I am speaking to the benefits that we accrue.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Isn’t that the incentive for Iran to go on in good faith in these negotiations and so on?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, the basic formula of the JCPOA, leaving aside Matt’s questioning about these specific measures, is in fact permanent, verifiable limits on Iran’s nuclear program in return for sanctions relief.</p>
<p>Francesco</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Do you have any indication that the talks resume tomorrow, that the Iranian negotiators are coming back empowered by the political decision you were expecting for &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We will have a better idea of that once the talks resume.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Wendy Sherman will be in Vienna for an OSCE meeting tomorrow. Will she meet with the U.S.-Iran team, any of the P5+1, or even the Iranians while there?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>She’s taking part virtually.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Oh, okay. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>One more – sorry.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Okay, sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Is – are the <a id="post-312152-RUSSIAUKRAINE2"></a>Russians taking a little bit longer to respond to this – the U.S. proposal than anticipated?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>You’ll have to ask them. I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No sense of any indigestion as they’re processing this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>You will have to ask them about their gastrointestinal fortitude.</p>
<p>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Can you just tell us what the AUKUS call that is on the schedule for this afternoon, I think, is about?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So we’ll have an opportunity – I do expect we’ll have a readout of the call. But in advance of the Secretary’s travel to the Indo-Pacific, this is just another opportunity for him to have a conversation with our<a id="post-312152-AUKUS"></a> AUKUS partners. They will, I suspect, discuss the work currently underway and the progress made in the implementation of some of the initiatives that we have talked about in the context of AUKUS. I don’t want to get ahead of that readout, but I think you will see one late this afternoon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>It’s the first follow-up at this level since AUKUS was announced, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>It’s been several months.</p>
<p>Yes, Ben.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Do you have any comment on China using a Uyghur to light the Olympic flame and what the State Department thinks?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Not specifically beyond the point that we’ve repeatedly made, that the P<a id="post-312152-CHINA"></a>RC has sought to – the PRC has sought to disguise the true reality of what is going on, what has gone on in Xinjiang – that is the ongoing genocide, those are the crimes against humanity, that’s the human rights abuses that have taken place there. But when it comes to their motives for choosing this specific individual, I’d have to refer you to them.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Will Rob Malley be in Vienna tomorrow for the start of the talks?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>He is traveling to <a id="post-312152-IRAN2"></a>Vienna today. Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:41 p.m.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:36 p.m. EST</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon. One element at the top, and then we’ll go ahead and get started with your questions.</p>
<p>The United States is deeply concerned by <a id="post-312152-TUNISIA"></a>Tunisian President Saied’s calls to dissolve the Supreme Judicial Council, and the reported barring of employees from entering the Supreme Judicial Council.</p>
<p>An independent judiciary is a core element of an effective and transparent democracy.</p>
<p>It is essential that the Government of Tunisia uphold its commitments to respect the independence of the judiciary as stipulated in the constitution.</p>
<p>The United States reiterates our calls for an accelerated political reform process in Tunisia that responds to the aspirations of the Tunisian people through the inclusion of diverse voices representing political parties, civil society and unions, particularly in the ongoing national consultations, and that ensures the continued respect for Tunisia’s human rights.</p>
<p>At this critical time, we also urge the Government of Tunisia to prioritize implementing the economic reforms required to stabilize the financial situation and address Tunisia’s growing economic challenges.</p>
<p>With that, happy to take your questions. Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. So I realize that <a id="post-312152-UKRAINERUSSIAREGION"></a>Ukraine is still the flavor of the day, but I don’t really have anything big on Ukraine, so I will – after I ask my first very brief initial question I’ll defer to others on Ukraine because I want to go to Iran.</p>
<p>Just on Ukraine, the joint statement – I realize that in the press conference the Secretary and Mr. Borrell spoke about Russia, but I’m just wondering why there was no mention of Russia at all in the joint statement from the EU-U.S. Energy Council meeting. I mean, it wasn’t – the word wasn’t even in there.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the word Ukraine certainly was. There was a &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, it was.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There was a robust discussion of Ukraine. There was a robust discussion of the contingency planning that we’re doing in the event that Russia does not choose the path of diplomacy, does not choose the path of dialogue. And as the joint statement noted, the council reiterated that it is unacceptable to use energy supplies as a weapon or geopolitical lever. This is what we have been saying all along, and much of the discussion today between the Secretary and between the high representative was part and parcel of the contingency planning that we’ve been doing for some time now.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. But what – I mean, was there a reason that Russia is not mentioned in there? I mean presumably, yes, it’s obvious that the threat to European energy security is coming from Russia. They are the main supplier and this is – but I’m just wondering why it wasn’t mentioned. Was there some objection to it being mentioned, or was it – did it ever come up in the discussions?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I am not aware there was any substantive reason for it. It’s a question of syntax.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> All right. Then I will pass and &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Okay.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But I do want to – I have a couple important ones on Iran.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m sure we’ll get there. Daphne.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Senior U.S. officials are in Europe this week coordinating sanctions and export control measures that can be used in the event that Russia invades Ukraine. Is the U.S. looking for commitments from counterparts during this trip on what action will be taken if Russia invades, and will Nord Stream 2 be part of discussions?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So, Daphne, what we spoke about earlier was the fact that we continue to take part in robust and to lead robust coordination and consultation with our European partners and allies on the consequences that would befall Moscow if it chooses the path of aggression. We have been consulting very closely with our allies and our partners over the course not of weeks but really of months now, and that includes the package that would respond to Russian aggression.</p>
<p>And so as you alluded to, today a U.S. delegation that included officials from Treasury and from the Department of State, including the Assistant Secretary of the Treasury for Terrorist Financing and Financial Crimes Elizabeth Rosenberg, Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Export Administration Assistant Secretary Rozman Kendler, Deputy Assistant Secretary here at the State Department Molly Montgomery, traveling to Europe to discuss technical coordination. And so over the past several weeks and even longer, we have discussed at a strategic level what we would – what the consequences that would befall Moscow were it choose – were it to choose this path.</p>
<p>There have been very detailed discussions in the context of that. Beyond the broad top lines there are a myriad of details and technical matters that will need to be worked out if we are in the unfortunate position of having to move forward with this strong and unified response. And so what you – what our team from the State Department, from the Department of Commerce, from the Department of Treasury are doing is meeting with their counterparts and European interlocutors to have those – to continue, I should say, those technical discussions to ensure that across the board we’re ready to go should, again, we be in the unfortunate position of needing to mobilize this response.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And will <a id="post-312152-NORDSTREAM"></a>Nord Stream 2 be a part of that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I don’t know if it’ll be part of these specific discussions. What I can say is that, of course, the President is meeting with Chancellor Scholz today at the White House. Leading up to this meeting we have had a number of discussions with our German allies on energy security broadly, on Nord Stream 2 specifically, both in the context of what we’re seeing from Russia and beyond.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. Good to see you again.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good to see you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. I have a few questions on South Korea, China, and North Korea. First of all, on South Korea: South Korea Government frequently fails to participate in the UN Security Council statement condemning North Korea’s missile provocations or ignored North Korea’s human rights issues. How does the U.S. evaluate South Korea’s attitude?</p>
<p>The second one, on China. After the UN Security Council meeting last week, the Chinese ambassador to the UN has blamed United States for the recent missile launch by North Korea. As you know, the South Korea – and I’m sorry, he has insisted that the U.S. should take more flexible approach, as in you know South – North Korea and China and Russia are strategically the same body. What is the United States position on China justifying North Korea’s missile provocations?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-312152-SOUTHKOREANORTHKOREA"></a>So let me take your first question first. As you know, since the start of this administration we have been investing heavily in our alliances and partnerships around the globe, and of course, that includes in the Indo-Pacific. There are a number of shared challenges and shared opportunities we have with our allies in the Indo-Pacific, of course, our treaty allies Japan and the ROK among them. And among those challenges are the DPRK, maybe one of the more – certainly is one of the more pressing challenges we have with those allies.</p>
<p>In recent days, the deputy secretary, the – our Special Representative for the DPRK Sung Kim, they have engaged their South Korean, their ROK, and Japanese counterparts. And as I think you know, this evening we’ll be departing for Australia, where we will see our Japanese counterparts in the context of the Quad – there will be a bilateral engagement there – before we then go by way of Fiji to Hawaii, where we’ll engage in a trilateral discussion with our South Korean and Japanese counterparts. And I think you – I can be confident that one of the priority issues of discussion in that setting will be the recent provocations we’ve seen from the DPRK, including its missile launches.</p>
<p>We know that when it comes to the fulfillment and the achievement of any progress towards our overriding goal, one of the indispensable ingredients is close coordination with our allies and partners. And the Japan – Japan and ROK are, of course, two of our allies with whom we work with most closely on this challenge. We know that that bilateral coordination is important, but we also know that trilateral coordination between the United States, Japan, and the ROK really is and will be indispensable if we are to achieve progress. It’s also a priority for our allies, Japan and the ROK, because of the threat that the DPRK poses not only to Americans in the region, potentially to deployed forces, but also to our treaty allies Japan and the ROK. So it’s something we take extraordinarily seriously and we know they do as well.</p>
<p>When it comes to – and this gets to your second question – our approach to the <a id="post-312152-NORTHKOREA"></a><a id="post-312152-PALESTINIANS"></a>DPRK, look, if you want to assign responsibility for the DPRK’s provocations, for the potential threats to international peace and security we’ve seen emanate from the DPRK, the only party that deserves blame, the only party that can be assigned culpability, is the DPRK. We have made very clear that we have no hostile intent towards the DPRK. We have made very clear that we wish to engage in dialogue and diplomacy. We have made very clear that we believe that only through dialogue and diplomacy can we most effectively achieve what, again, is our overriding policy objective, and that’s the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Follow-up, quick questions. North Korea has been engaged in peace process dialogue with the United States and South Korea in the past, while on the other hand it has been accelerating its – has been North Korea military buildup work. What is the ultimate tool for the United States besides diplomatic compromise to block North Korea global threat?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the ultimate tool is diplomacy, and we know that previous administrations have tried this. No administration has been successful, despite undertaking strategies that, in many cases, look very different from one another. And so the strategy we have is not akin to the strategy that the last administration had. It is not also exactly akin to the strategy that the Obama administration had. It is a strategy that the Biden-Harris administration has put forward after an intense policy review, and a policy review that determined that, through diplomacy and dialogue, it is our hope that there can be incremental progress – incremental progress towards the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>Now, of course, we have not yet found a willing partner in Pyongyang to engage in that dialogue, but we have continued even in the absence of substantive engagement from the DPRK to coordinate closely with Japan, with the ROK, other allies and partners in the Indo-Pacific, but also allies and partners around the world, which you have seen us do in the UN, which you’ve seen us do in Europe, and elsewhere as we take on this challenge.</p>
<p>Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you. Can I go to the Palestinian issue?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I have a couple questions on settler violence on Omar Assad. <a id="post-312152-ISRAELPAL"></a> But before that, the White House issued a statement saying that President Biden is going to go and visit Israel later this year. Is he likely to also go – I mean, I know this is a White House probably question, but do you think that he will also make a detour to, like, Bethlehem or Ramallah 20 minutes away?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, Said, as you alluded to, the readout of the conversation between President Biden and Prime Minister Bennett did make a reference to President Biden’s intent to travel to the region later this year. Obviously, this was just announced yesterday, so I wouldn’t want to get into the itinerary at this point. In any case, I’d need to refer you to the White House.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I understand. Ned, I mean, you – almost every week, you come – you state opposition or displeasure with settler violence activities and so on. And I mean, in the last four days, I could cite a number of issues. I don’t want to go through them all – I mean, the Israelis – from home demolishing to attacks on the Al-Aqsa Mosque to poisoning of wells. I mean, all kinds of things, a whole – across the gamut. When will you guys issue a very strong statement and say this should not stand? I mean, if you want to give the two-state solution, as you keep saying, a chance, they should stop right now this stuff.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Said, I would take issue with the premise of your question. We have spoken to this clearly and unequivocally &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I understand that you’ve spoken – sorry to interrupt, but you speak all the time. I said that to begin with. But you – what action are you taking to make sure that what you say is actually listened to and adhered to?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, first of all, it is important what we say. And you have – as you alluded to, you’ve heard me say this, including in recent days. But we have been very clear, we have been very consistent on this: We believe it is absolutely critical for all parties to refrain from steps that exacerbate tensions. This includes violence, incitement to violence; home demolitions; the eviction of families from homes in East Jerusalem, including families that have lived there for generations; that includes the destruction of property and for providing compensation for individuals imprisoned for acts of terrorism. All of these things move us further away from what continues to be our desired end state, and that is a two-state solution – a two-state solution that continues to be in the best interests of Israel, of the Palestinian people, and something that successive American administrations have supported.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Now, one last question on Omar Assad, the Palestinian-American who died in Israeli custody. I know that last Tuesday you guys issued a statement. Has anything transpired since then? Have the Israelis come forward to you? Are you completely satisfied, or are you still asking for more accountability? Because apparently, those who did it, they were sort of slapped on the wrist.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, we did issue a statement on this yesterday. That statement spoke of our concern, but it also spoke of our ongoing dialogue with our Israeli partners on this.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You did?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We did. We issued one on February 1st, I believe.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah, not yesterday. Yesterday &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sorry, did I say yesterday?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yes, you did.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We issued it last week. I’m sorry.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Last Tuesday. Last week we got it.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes, yes. Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just a quick update on Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Do you have any idea when you’re going to have the formal response from Moscow and when there is new engagement with Foreign Minister Lavrov &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We don’t <a id="post-312152-RUSSIAUKRAINE"></a>have any updates on that. As I conveyed last week, the Secretary had an opportunity to speak to Foreign Minister Lavrov. It was our understanding following that engagement that the Russians were working on a response to our so-called non-paper, a response that would be sent to and approved, presumably, by Vladimir Putin before it would transmitted back to us. That has not yet happened. It was also our understanding that once that did happen, that the Russians would be prepared to engage in follow-on diplomacy, but again, we’ll need to – the first step in that was receiving the Russian response, which has not yet happened.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And do you expect that follow-on engagement can happen while the Secretary is traveling, or more probably when he comes back from his travel?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We don’t have any additional details to share in terms of timing, in terms of format or the mode for that engagement, so I’d hesitate to get ahead of it.</p>
<p>Ben.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just make sure – I think I know the answer to this, but I just want to make about the – and without getting into the whole back and forth that happened last week, your &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t know what you’re talking about, Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, and nor do I. Your belief that there is some Russian false flag operation that’s being planned has not changed, right, since last Thursday? Is that correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> That is correct. That is correct.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And are you prepared today to offer any additional &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I am prepared to do today is to explain what I perhaps inartfully tried to do last week in explaining what it is we’re trying to do and why we’re not able to provide a full set of information or at least all of the information that you and your colleagues may ask for. The Secretary spoke to this briefly earlier today, but this gets to our bottom line proposition. We believe that the best antidote to disinformation is information, and that is why you have seen us employ concerted efforts across the board. We want to go the extra mile to ensure that, again, to the extent possible, the American people and people around the world have an understanding of what we know and what undergirds our concern for the threat that Moscow poses.</p>
<p>Now, an element of that has been our declassification of information, including intelligence information, that is in our possession. And as you heard me say last week, we’ve done that with two overriding objectives in mind. The first and, of course, our preference is to be in a position to deter the Russians from going forward. We want by exposing this information and making sure that Moscow knows what we know to have them think twice or many more times before moving forward with such a reckless action.</p>
<p>If we’re not able to do that, if we’re not able to deter further invasion or aggression against Ukraine, we at least want to be in the position of having let the world know that despite the disinformation, despite the propaganda and lies that presumably Moscow will say after the fact, that the world will know what we knew all along, and that is the fact that Moscow sought to fabricate a pretext for this aggression very similar to what they did in 2014. Matt, you know that in 2014 the Russians went into Ukraine, sent their proxy forces into Ukraine, claiming that Russians were under threat, claiming that a three-year-old boy had been crucified, claiming that they had no choice but to do so. Again, this is why we are so concerned about what we are seeing now and what we know now.</p>
<p>Now, in taking this approach, we recognize that the information that we’re able to put forward will necessarily be limited, and it will be limited for a reason that you also know well. Again, we – even as we seek to expose Moscow’s efforts, we don’t want to jeopardize or potentially jeopardize our ability to collect this kind of information going forward. But when we do the cost-benefit analysis and we consider if the choice is between putting forward necessarily incomplete, sometimes broad, sometimes general information in an attempt to deter aggression or, on the other hand, if the choice is to keep that to ourselves and potentially not play every card available to us, that’s not a difficult choice.</p>
<p>Again, we are doing this in an effort to, in the first instance, deter; if we’re not able to do that, to expose what Moscow has had in mind all along. We want to see this crisis resolved peacefully, we want to see this crisis resolved diplomatically, and we will do everything we responsibly think we can – responsible in terms of tactics, but also responsible in terms of our national security and our ability to continue to benefit from this information going forward to bring about what we hope is a diplomatic outcome.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. So – and I’m not going to get into sort of what like we – I did last week, but the bottom line is that no, you are not prepared to share any of the information that you have that would suggest that this is actually correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Is that right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Again, we have shared significant information &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, no &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>And &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, I said I didn’t want to get back into this. Do you have anything more that you can say &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Beyond &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; to back up the claim than you did – than you had to say last week? That’s all.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Beyond what we told you last week &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; in pretty detailed terms about the Russian plans &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We don’t have anything further to offer on that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. And then and the proof &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Then you’re saying – hold on, Said, just – last one. The proof that you’re correct is that nothing is actually going to happen? Is that what you’re saying?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, I – that is not – that’s not &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Because you will have – because you putting this out there will have stopped the Russians from doing it, correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, I – what I said is that our overriding objective in the first instance is to deter Russian aggression. That is why we are doing a number of things.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I’m speaking entirely only about this alleged false flag operation that you’re talking about. You’re saying that the proof that there is a false flag operation is going to come when nothing actually happens, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I did not say that, Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I said that our overriding objective is to deter Russian aggression against Ukraine, further Russian aggression against Ukraine. I acknowledge I will probably never be able – well, I will certainly never be able to give you the proof that you I’m sure want. But we are doing this – we are doing this not in an effort, I’m sorry to say, to satisfy you but in an effort to prevent and deter an invasion.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>It’s not really about satisfying me. But anyway, I don’t want to – I don’t want to take up &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, can you clarify something at this time?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So you think that the Russians are still scheming to do this today with the same intensity as they were last week? Or have they &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I’m not in a position to give you an update on this specific scheme, but I think our concerns about the Russians potentially resorting to these tactics, the same sort of false flag tactics that they have – that they did resort to in the past, those concerns are still very present.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, you know one gets the impression that an attack or an invasion is imminent, it’s just a question of time, maybe a few days, mid-month, whatever. So on the scale of one to ten – I know you guys like this – what is the likelihood of invasion? Is it about seven? Is it about eight? Are we today closer to nine, let’s say, than we were last week?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I am going to refer you to Vladimir Putin. Again, we have put forward these two paths. It is our strong, strong preference that we pursue the path of diplomacy and dialogue. What I will say and what you heard the National Security Advisor speak to yesterday is that we are now in the window, given what we have seen from the Russians over weeks and even longer now – amassing troops along Ukraine’s borders, dispatching forces into Belarus, taking other steps that have positioned them to move forward at any moment if they so choose.</p>
<p>We do not yet believe that Vladimir Putin has made a decision. It is our goal in all of this, including what I was discussing with Matt just a moment ago, to deter an invasion. If we’re not able to deter an invasion, we will then resort to the other path. It’s a path of hefty, stark consequences for Russia. It’s also a path of defense for our allies on the eastern flank of NATO.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Are you aware of reports where a high-level Russian officer – or the head of the officers school, whatever it is – warned Putin against the invasion of Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I’ve seen these reports. I understand that there was an open letter, so I’ve certainly seek that – seen that. Again, I don’t have a specific comment on it. Our goal is to solve conflicts through diplomacy. We’re seeking to do that for the good of the American people, the good of Ukrainian people, the good of the Russian people, and people all throughout Europe, knowing that any renewed invasion of Ukraine would carry tremendous costs, tremendous costs across many realms. It’s our goal to do everything we can to avoid that.</p>
<p>Yes, Ben.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You just said in your answer to Matt that if you have to put forward incomplete information to deter an attack, then so be it. What were you referring to there? I mean, is the intelligence behind this video perhaps incomplete?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, I was referring to the fact that there have been demands for everything we have in our possession behind this intelligence, and that’s not something we’re able to provide, again, because of our desire not to jeopardize sources and methods, our desire not to jeopardize &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, if you’re referring to me, that’s not true. I asked for literally, quote/unquote, any shred of evidence – not even proof, because not all evidence is proof. I asked for anything. I didn’t ask for everything. I didn’t ask for sources or methods. I just asked &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; for anything that would back it up. That’s all.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The challenge, Matt, is that by divulging details, further details, you would necessarily get into sources and methods. And so that is why we’re in the position of putting forward what we know in a way that we consider to be responsible vis-à-vis our objectives going forward, and one of those objectives going forward is to protect our ability to collect this kind of information going forward. We are trying to strike a very difficult balance. There are – when it comes to national security and the tension, the inherent tension between national security and transparency, there is never an easy formula. Not always do we get it right. No administration has always gotten it right, but we are leaning forward here.</p>
<p>The only reason we’re having this discussion is because we publicized some of what was in our possession. We could have kept that to ourselves. It would have made for a much less memorable briefing last Thursday, but that wasn’t the responsible thing in our estimation to do. Again, we want to make sure at the end of the day, whether we are able to deter an invasion or whether in the aftermath of an invasion, that we have done everything we responsibly can to do that. And one of the tactics we’ve used, one of the tactics I would say we’ve used probably more so than previous administrations, is declassifying information or making public information that previously was not public. That is not something that – it is not something that administrations have done certainly to this degree.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You also say that we’re in the window now where an attack might happen. You’ve said it repeatedly that an attack is imminent.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We’ve never said repeatedly that an attack is imminent. We have said that we are now in the window where if &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I think numerous times you’ve used the word “imminent.”</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We – we have said that if Vladimir Putin decides to move &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Inaudible) and 50,000 people are going to be dead. What are you talking about?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I can’t be accountable for what others write. What we have said &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>What others write?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>What &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And “imminent” is a word that has been used.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>What we have said is that if Vladimir Putin decides to go forward with an invasion, they have now positioned themselves to the degree that they’re able to do that whether it is within a day, within a couple weeks. They have now reached that point.</p>
<p>But imminent suggests that this is a foregone conclusion, that this is a certainty. So &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No one in the administration has used the word “imminent” to describe &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think what you might have heard is potentially imminent. That &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>What – if an invasion were imminent, we would not be prioritizing diplomacy and dialogue the way we have. Imminence suggests that this is a foregone conclusion, that there is no way to avoid it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think if you’ve been listening to what we’ve been saying for the past two months now, the emphasis we’ve placed on dialogue and diplomacy, the emphasis that we’ve placed on deterring an invasion, the emphasis that we have placed on finding a diplomatic way out of this, you would understand that we’re not talking about something that is a foregone conclusion. We are talking about something that is one of two paths. We’ve consistently talked about one of two paths. It’s certainly possible that Vladimir Putin will choose that path. It is our hope that he will choose the path of diplomacy and dialogue, that we can avoid the bloodshed, that we can avoid the violence, that we can avoid the destabilizing forces that would descend not only on Ukraine but well beyond in terms of the implications.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>My question was actually going to be: Considering that we are in that window now and there’s talk of a potentially imminent invasion, was there ever a discussion about postponing the Australia trip? Is now the right time to be crossing the world, going to Fiji, when this invasion could happen at any time?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Ben, we are a big country. We are a big department. We have a lot of challenges on our plate. The Secretary of State is the Secretary of State wherever in the world he is. He has access to secure communications wherever in the world he is. He, I’m sure, will be focused to a large degree on this challenge even while he is in the Indo-Pacific. It will certainly come up in conversations with counterparts in the Quad and elsewhere, but I can assure you, you will also see that he will remain active on the phones with our interagency counterparts. He and we are capable of – again, not to use an overused metaphor, but of walking and chewing gum at the same time.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Sorry, Ned, but the Secretary said &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And juggling.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>And juggling.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The Secretary said that Ukraine is prepared to give special status in the Donbas region.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>He was referring to the – he was referring to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Is that, like, sort of walking back from the – that sort of thing?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, it was – it is reiterating what’s in the Minsk Agreements. The Minsk Agreements spell out a means by which to de-escalate the conflict in Eastern Ukraine. Special status is a term that’s used in the Minsk Agreements.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Ben.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>After you made the accusation last week – the administration – about this false flag operation and then the reassessments leaked over the weekend, the Ukrainian foreign minister tweeted today, “Do not believe the apocalyptic predictions. Different capitals are calculating different scenarios.” Is he wrong that there isn’t this sort of apocalyptic situation that you all are discussing?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We see eye to eye with our Ukrainian partners in the sense that now is not the time for panic. What we are calling for, what we are doing is moving forward with preparation. We want to be prepared and we need to position ourselves to be prepared regardless of which path it is that Vladimir Putin takes. It’s our hope that we pursue that of dialogue and diplomacy. It is certainly possible that we are not able to deter an invasion and not able to deter renewed aggression and that we’ll have to be prepared for that path of defense and deterrence.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But, I mean, you say that you’re seeing eye to eye. He’s saying that what you’re saying is wrong.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t think you’ve heard us use the term “cataclysmic,” if that’s – if that was the quote.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> “Apocalyptic.”</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> “Apocalyptic.”</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But he was specifically referring to what U.S. officials have said in recent days, in the last week.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I – the Ukrainian ambassador to Washington has spoken to this; President Zelenskyy has spoken to our coordination with the Ukrainian Government. What we are doing is engaged in prudent preparation. We are doing that with our European allies but also with our Ukrainian partners.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> When the Secretary and Foreign Minister Kuleba spoke on Friday, did the foreign minister express any of these concerns to the Secretary?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, we issued a readout of that call, so I don’t have anything to add beyond that readout. We have a close relationship with Ukraine. Ukraine, of course, is a close partner of ours. We can speak candidly with close partners when it comes to our concerns. Our Ukrainian partners, our European allies, and others, they know of the basis for our concerns. Number one, they hear what we say publicly in the same way you do, but we are also in a position to share some of that underlying information with our European allies, with other allies, as well as with our Ukrainian partners.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just one last question on this. During – in the Ukrainian readout as well, it said that the Secretary reaffirmed the U.S. was working to provide additional economic assistance to the Ukrainian Government. Can you say anything more about that? What’s on the table, dollar amount, or if anything is forthcoming?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, so we have said for some time now that even as we work to provide Ukraine with security assistance, we know that this – certainly Russian aggression, even the threat of Russian aggression, could have a toll on Ukraine’s economy. So we have provided half a billion dollars in development and humanitarian assistance in the past year. We are exploring additional macroeconomic support to help Ukraine’s economy amidst pressure resulting from Russia’s military buildup.</p>
<p>Last week, on February 3rd, we and several of our allies and partners announced a new partnership fund for a resilient Ukraine. It’s a fund that bolsters the resilience and perseverance of communities in eastern Ukraine, those communities that are in some ways bearing the brunt, have borne the brunt of Russia’s aggression. USAID has a expert in the country who’s monitoring the situation closely, coordinating with other donors, assessing the evolving humanitarian needs of the Ukrainian people, and liaising with partners to ensure that they are able to rapidly scale up assistance should the need arise.</p>
<p>Over the past year, we and Ukraine have finalized a memorandum of understanding on commercial cooperation. It’s a memorandum, MOU, designed to facilitate commercial participation by U.S. companies across the Ukrainian economy and by Ukrainian companies here in the United States.</p>
<p>And then finally, the EXIM, the Export-Import Bank, has made available $3 billion in support for projects in Ukraine, and the DFC, the Development Finance Corporation, has a current investment portfolio in Ukraine of approximately $800 million across more than a dozen projects. Those range from renewable energy to higher education and access to financing for small and medium-sized enterprises.</p>
<p>Rosiland.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Stay on Ukraine?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m going to take off my mask because I can’t hear when I wear this. You keep talking about we want to resolve this diplomatically. There are reports that the Ukrainians have asked the U.S. to station some THAAD anti-missile systems in the eastern part of the country, ostensibly to guard against any Russian missile attacks. The UK has decided to deploy 350 Royal Marines to Poland. Are these kinds of actions the thing that the West wants to be telegraphing if it wants Moscow to actually resolve all of these issues about Ukraine and about NATO’s posture? I mean, how does that – how does moving troops and possibly stationing anti-missile systems actually get you what you want?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. So I can’t speak to moves that haven’t been announced, that are hypothetical, that may not come to pass. But what I can speak to is what we’ve announced, and everything we have announced has been in the vein of defense and deterrence, across the board. Whether it is our security assistance for Ukraine – the $650 million that was provided last year – that is defensive security assistance; whether it is the authorization for our NATO Allies to pass U.S.-origin material to Ukraine, that is defensive material.</p>
<p>When it comes to the service members who have been put on heightened state of readiness should they be called upon by the North Atlantic Council, that would be in the vein of defense and deterrence. When it comes to the service members who are being sent to offer reassurance and sent to deter further Russian aggression against – or Russian aggression, I should say – against NATO’s eastern flank, that is done in the vein of defense and deterrence.</p>
<p>Everything we are doing is in an effort to see to it that we are not faced with a renewed Russian invasion, that Russian aggression does not move forward. Now, we are doing all of this also knowing that in the end, Vladimir Putin may choose the path of conflict, of an invasion, of renewed aggression. But we are doing, as I was saying to Matt and to others earlier, everything we can in an effort to in the first instance deter, but also to send a very clear signal that we stand by our commitments under Article 5 when it comes to protecting our NATO Allies, that the United States will live up to its obligations, the United States will continue to provide the sort of defensive security assistance that Ukraine needs to defend itself.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But deploying a THAAD system is a pretty serious deal. I mean, think about the controversy in Korea, where they have asked for the systems and it’s engendered a lot of uproar as well as criticism from Pyongyang.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, I can’t speak to measures that haven’t been announced or that remain hypothetical.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Let me also ask you about Macron’s meeting with Putin today. What sense does the U.S. have about what Macron was going to try to bring up once the cameras left the meeting room? Has Ambassador Sullivan and his team been able to get a readout from the French on how willing Putin is to back away in this crisis?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, when it comes to the engagement of our partners, let me make the broader point that over the past month-plus, we have heard from our European allies, we have heard from our Ukrainian partners, we’ve heard from others an appreciation for what the United States has been doing with Russia diplomatically, and that includes in our bilateral engagement. And in expressing that appreciation and understanding, we’ve heard from our allies and partners that they have taken that approach because we have done all of this in a manner that is thoroughly coordinated, that has been consultative in its approach with our allies and partners, and that is conducted in full transparency with them. “Nothing about without” is not just a mantra for us, it is the guiding principle in terms of how we have conducted ourselves, including in this – in our bilateral engagements with Russia.</p>
<p>So, similarly, we would welcome any diplomatic efforts that are conducted in a similar manner that have the potential – excuse me – to de-escalate the crisis that Moscow has needlessly precipitated. When it comes to the<a id="post-312152-FRANCERUSSIA"></a> French, as you know, President Biden yesterday had an opportunity to speak to President Macron. This would be his second conversation with the French president in several days. Secretary Blinken yesterday spoke to the foreign minister, Foreign Minister Le Drian. We are well coordinated across the board, and that includes with the French, with Paris.</p>
<p>The result of all of this is that the message President Putin is hearing from the United States, from NATO, from our allies and partner – partners, it is loud and it is singular, and that is the fact that a diplomatic solution is the only responsible path. But again, if Russia chooses otherwise, we will be prepared. We will be prepared with a response that is swift, severe, and united. I saw President Macron made comments just before he left. You will hear those same messages from the French president.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And is the U.S. confident that once Chancellor Scholz goes to Moscow next week that that same unified message is going to be delivered? Because Germany is in a slightly different position than other countries in Europe.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, as luck would have it, C<a id="post-312152-GERMANYRUSSIA"></a>hancellor Scholz is in Washington today. He’s at the White House today. But I should say this is not luck, the fact that Chancellor Scholz is here to have these consultations with President Biden, a follow-on to the consultations and the discussions that the two leaders have had over the phone and over video conference in recent weeks. This is a testament to the close and continued coordination and cooperation with our European allies across the board – board, excuse me – including, of course, with Germany. So I expect you’ll be hearing a lot more about that today from the President and chancellor.</p>
<p>Yes, in the back.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, I’d like to ask about proximity of Vladimir Putin and Latin America. So last week the Argentinian President Alberto Fernández was in Moscow, and in the coming days the Brazilian President Jair Bolsonaro will be there. And there are reports in Brazil about the fact that the U.S. is putting pressure on Bolsonaro to cancel his trip to Russia. I would like you to elaborate a bit about the concerns and the reasons why the U.S. wants Brazil to skip this trip to Russia, and if the U.S. has the same confidence that – you talked about France – that you are well coordinated when we are talking about the Brazilian visit to Moscow.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we engage with our<a id="post-312152-BRAZILRUSSIA"></a> Brazilian partners on – at multiple levels regularly. We are, of course, aware of the reports of President Bolsonaro’s travel plans. We and many other nations around the world, including in this hemisphere, are deeply concerned about the potentially destabilizing role that Russia is playing and its ongoing threat to sovereignty and to territorial integrity, including, of course, in Ukraine.</p>
<p>As democratic countries – the United States, Brazil, Argentina, others in the region and beyond – we have a responsibility to stand up for democratic principles and for the rules-based order. This is the same order that has undergirded unprecedented levels of stability, of security, of prosperity over the past 70 years, and that is true – it is equally true in Europe as it is in the Western Hemisphere, as it is in the Indo-Pacific. So we know that Brazil and other countries in the region – you mentioned Argentina as well – we share values. That is one of the hallmarks of our relationship, and we have – we know that those values will be conveyed and will undergird concerns that President Putin hears not only from the United States but our partners around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But what does the U.S. expect from this Brazilian visit to Moscow?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It’s not for us to speak to what – the goals that President Bolsonaro may have in mind. I am confident that there will be discussions both before and after the trip with our Brazilian partners.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, and if China pledges it support Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, as well as North Korea, what actions will the United States take against China for this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sorry. Could you clarify the question?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. China pledged to support Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, as well as North Korea. What actions will the United States take against China?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, so if you’re asking about the relationship between <a id="post-312152-CHINARUSSIA"></a>Russia and China, I know that this is something that our Assistant Secretary for Asia and Pacific Affairs Dan Kritenbrink spoke to last week. But what we have seen over the course not of days, not of weeks, but of years and probably longer, is an approach that both of these countries have taken for some time, and that is an increasing closeness between Russia and China.</p>
<p>It would be our hope, given the implications of a renewed Russian aggression and certainly Russian invasion of Ukraine, that the PRC would have taken advantage of dialogue, of this relationship, to encourage Russia to pursue the course of diplomacy and de-escalation. This is what the world expects of responsible powers.</p>
<p>The Secretary had a conversation with Foreign Minister Wang of the PRC the other week – the other day, I should say – and there was a discussion of the potential for renewed Russian aggression, renewed Russian invasion, of Ukraine, and the fact that it would not only have implications in Ukraine, not only in Europe, but in many ways it would be a threat to peace and security around the world because it would be a flagrant violation of the same rules-based international order that applies equally in the Indo-Pacific as it does in Europe.</p>
<p>If in the end China is seen as having supported Russia’s move to choose conflict or war over diplomacy, it will cost China in terms of how it’s seen in the eyes of the world. It will have an effect on the PRC’s global reputation. We – as Russia and China talk about a singular partnership, we are focused with our 29 NATO Allies, we are working with the EU, we are working with our allies in the Indo-Pacific and partners around the world to not only incentivize and to work towards a diplomatic resolution, but also to be in a position to respond decisively if Russia does choose the path of aggression.</p>
<p>We told you last month of – we listed out many of the engagements that we’ve had with partners and allies. That tally has now grown to some 200 phone calls, in-person meetings, video conferences. Of course, one of them you saw today when Secretary Blinken hosted High Representative Josep Borrell of the EU.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>On North Korea, UN sanctions monitors reported to the Security Council that cyber attacks on cryptocurrency exchanges and financial institutions by North Korea were an important revenue source for North Korea to fund its nuclear and ballistic missile programs. What is the United States doing to try and stop this, and does the U.S. believe North Korea’s receiving any outside help to help carry out these cyber attacks?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I don’t have any assessment to offer from here in terms of outside support or assistance that <a id="post-312152-NORTHKOREA2"></a>North Korea may be receiving. What I can say generally without speaking to any specific report at this time is that North Korea’s activity and behavior in cyberspace has long been a serious concern of the United States. We have in the past disclosed and attributed malicious attacks to the DPRK – the attack in 2014, I believe it was, that the DPRK perpetrated against a private American company, a destructive attack against Sony may be an instructive case in point for some of the capabilities and some of the behavior that the DPRK has exhibited in cyberspace.</p>
<p>So it is not just the DPRK’s ballistic missile and nuclear weapons programs. It is – it is not just its record on human rights. There are other profound concerns we have, including its behavior in cyberspace.</p>
<p>Yes, Ben. Welcome to – yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>With the restoration – with the restoration of the sanctions waiver on<a id="post-312152-IRAN"></a> Iran, which is akin to lifting sanctions in the sense that it enriches them to a certain degree &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, it does not, Ben.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But wasn’t that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>But it – that’s not true. It does not do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, was the restoration of the sanctions waiver in any way an incentive to get them back to the table and continue negotiations?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So to be very clear, what you said was not true. The issuance of the so-called IFCA waiver in no way enriches Iran. This is about two things. This is about nuclear non-proliferation and nuclear safety. I would suspect most reasonable observers would agree that both of these things are in our vital national interest regardless of what happens with the JCPOA, if we’re able to achieve a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA or if we’re not. We decided to renew and to restore this sanctions waiver to do one thing, and that is to enable third-party participation in nuclear non-proliferation and safety projects in Iran, owing to the growing proliferation concerns we have, in particular with respect to the increasing stockpiles of enriched uranium in Iran, the stockpiles that have grown following the last administration’s decision to abandon the JCPOA.</p>
<p>Absent this waiver, the sort of detailed technical discussions with third parties regarding the disposition of stockpiles and other activities of non-proliferation value, they couldn’t take place. The Trump administration, as you know, provided a similar waiver for years even after its foolish decision to leave the JCPOA, precisely because the last administration recognized the non-proliferation value of these waivers. I don’t know that I’ve quoted Secretary Pompeo before from here, but Secretary Pompeo said about this waiver, quote, “This decision will help…reduce proliferation risks.”</p>
<p>So additionally, the technical discussions facilitated by the waiver are necessary in the final weeks of JCPOA talks, as the waiver itself would be essential if we were be in a position – to be in a position to – if Iran were to resume compliance with its nuclear commitments. But again, even if talks do not culminate in a mutual return to compliance, these sorts of technical discussions could still contribute to our non-proliferation goals.</p>
<p>Non-proliferation, nuclear safety – these things may not mean a lot to a whole lot of people. So just to give you a few examples of activities that these waivers – this waiver would cover: for example, the modernization of the Arak reactor based on the design approved by the JCPOA, the conversion of the reactor to a much less proliferation-sensitive design. This waiver would approve the preparation and modification of the Fordow facility for stable isotope production. It would remove a potential impediment to efforts to end uranium enrichment at Fordow, as Iran committed to do under the JCPOA. It would facilitate the transfer outside Iran of enriched uranium to result in a reduction in Iran’s stockpile to no more than 300 kilograms of up to 3.67 percent enriched LEU.</p>
<p>I could go on, but the point is that this waiver is not about providing Iran with funds. This waiver is about what is manifestly in our nonproliferation interests, in our – in service of nonproliferation safety to the United States, to our partners and allies around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you talk about the timing of it, though, and why the decision was taken on Friday?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Did it have anything to do with &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the fact is if we are in a position to resume compliance with the JCPOA, this waiver will need to be in place in order to effect some of the steps to make Iran’s nuclear program less dangerous. If we are not in a position to achieve a mutual return to compliance, these are still – these steps are still in our interest.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> What makes you think that that next step that they are – that we’re one step closer to rejoining the JCPOA then?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I didn’t say that we were. I’m saying that this prepares us in the event we are able to achieve a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA. This could still very much go one of two ways: a mutual return to compliance if Iran is in a position and willing and able to make the sort of political commitments necessary; or the alternatives that we’ve talked about in some less deal – detail but that we still talked about.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, are you – that long list of things that you said that these waivers give, you’re saying that there’s no benefit to Iran in any of that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I am saying that the net benefit of this is a nonproliferation benefit for us.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Iran gets nothing out of it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> When you say sanctions waiver &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m not talking about – hold on a second.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, you don’t need to raise your voice. You don’t &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But you’re the one – you’re the one who – you guys are the ones who said you were restoring the waivers, right? Okay. So if Iran really gets no benefit at all out of this, then why even bother?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Why bother? I just explained to Ben. Because if &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, well, you – tell me why Iran doesn’t benefit from this.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, this is something that redounds &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You’re talking about – you’re assuming that everyone thinks that sanctions relief equals dollars &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, that was the question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; going to Iran.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The question was you just waived &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It was.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That wasn’t really the question.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It was.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That was the way you interpreted the question.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You can refer to the transcript.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So sanctions relief does not necessarily mean only dollar bills flying across the table into Iran – into the Iranian treasury’s coffers, does it? Or is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> In this case, it will allow Iran to undertake nuclear nonproliferation and safety activities that would otherwise be proscribed.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, which is a benefit to Iran that it was not getting before.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The fact is, Matt, that what is in our nonproliferation interest can also be, in some ways, in Iran’s interest. That doesn’t change the fact that it is manifestly in our interest.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do they – so do they get a benefit of &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, I was referring to the sort &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do they get any benefit out of this or not?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It is – some of these steps redound to their interest.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do they get any benefit or not?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> This is in our interest to do, which is precisely why the last &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is it in Iran’s interest as well?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; which is why the last administration did it. In 2018, Secretary Pompeo, as I quoted before, said precisely this decision will help reduce proliferation &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And two years later – and two years later when he rescinded the waivers, he said that – he accused of Iran of taking – of participating in nuclear blackmail and said that they weren’t – that they weren’t deserving of the benefits that accrue to them under this.</p>
<p>You’re stuck on this idea that – and interesting that you used the word “enrich” because I think you’re talking about it in terms of money, but enrichment obviously has a different kind of meaning when it comes to Iran. But I don’t understand how you can say that Iran gets no benefit and that this isn’t some kind of sanctions relief that you – that the administration has offered to Iran before it has made any of its own concessions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, the question I was responding to took this in a vein &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Well, then, forget about the question you were &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; you think you were responding to. Answer my question: Does Iran benefit at all from the waivers that were signed?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> You will need to ask the Iranian Government whether they think this is a benefit to them. We know &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, who do you think this benefits? Just you?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We know this is of benefit to us. The ability of third-party entities to work on nuclear nonproliferation projects &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, I’m sorry, now is the U.S. &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; and nuclear safety projects in Iran in the face of our growing concerns, nonproliferation and nuclear safety concerns – that is in our benefit, yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The people that this benefits, in fact, are actually Russian, Chinese, European companies, right? Is that what you’re saying?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, I am saying that it is manifestly to our advantage &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And not Iran’s?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It benefits us to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Well, if you can argue that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; be able to address nuclear safety and nuclear nonproliferation concerns on Iran.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> If you’re able to argue that Iran gets no benefit out of this successfully, which you haven’t convinced me of, but anyway – but if you’re able to, then good on you. Now, do you think that these waivers trigger INARA?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt, we have a robust conversation with Congress on progress in Vienna. We have briefed Congress regularly on the discussions. I have every expectations that those briefings will continue in the days and weeks ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, do you believe that this triggers the requirements of the Iran Nuclear Review Act?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>What I can say is that we’ve had conversations with Congress about requirements should we be in a position to resume compliance with the JCPOA, but I don’t have anything for you on these particular – this IFCA waiver.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, not IFCA. INARA.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Right, but you’re saying “these” in response to IFCA.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah. Well, so you’re aware of the requirements of INARA, right? That any agreement reached with Iran has to be submitted. Are you saying that it did trigger INARA and your notification to Congress on Friday fulfills the requirements of INARA?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, I’m not saying that. I’m saying &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Oh, well, then why did you even notify Congress in the first place?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We regularly notify Congress when it comes to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Laughter.) Okay. Well – so did it trigger INARA or not?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt, when it – we will carefully consider the facts and circumstances when it comes to any potential U.S. return to the JCPOA to determine the implications under INARA.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So you don’t think that this falls under the scope of INARA.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I have no reason to believe that this was done pursuant to INARA. This is something we, as I said before, we regularly engage with Congress when it comes to developments in Vienna &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, it’s a technical issue. I get that, and probably boring the hell out of everybody, but it is an important one, because if it – even if the notification wasn’t done under INARA, do you think that the waivers trigger the – trigger the INARA requirements for any agreement with Iran related to its nuclear program? These do relate to its nuclear program, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>This is, as you said, a technical question, so we’ll get you a technical answer.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, why shouldn’t Iran benefit – why shouldn’t Iran benefit from the waiver? I mean, I thought the whole purpose of negotiations is so everybody goes back to the deal and sanctions will be lifted, Iran will pull back from any nuclear threat and so on, and everything will be hunky-dory. So why is that such a bad thing if Iran benefits?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>You’ll have to ask &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, I’m asking you because you – you’re the one who’s &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I am not speaking to what Iran may be saying about this; I am speaking to the benefits that we accrue.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Isn’t that the incentive for Iran to go on in good faith in these negotiations and so on?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, the basic formula of the JCPOA, leaving aside Matt’s questioning about these specific measures, is in fact permanent, verifiable limits on Iran’s nuclear program in return for sanctions relief.</p>
<p>Francesco</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Do you have any indication that the talks resume tomorrow, that the Iranian negotiators are coming back empowered by the political decision you were expecting for &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We will have a better idea of that once the talks resume.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Wendy Sherman will be in Vienna for an OSCE meeting tomorrow. Will she meet with the U.S.-Iran team, any of the P5+1, or even the Iranians while there?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>She’s taking part virtually.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Oh, okay. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>One more – sorry.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Okay, sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Is – are the <a id="post-312152-RUSSIAUKRAINE2"></a>Russians taking a little bit longer to respond to this – the U.S. proposal than anticipated?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>You’ll have to ask them. I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No sense of any indigestion as they’re processing this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>You will have to ask them about their gastrointestinal fortitude.</p>
<p>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Can you just tell us what the AUKUS call that is on the schedule for this afternoon, I think, is about?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So we’ll have an opportunity – I do expect we’ll have a readout of the call. But in advance of the Secretary’s travel to the Indo-Pacific, this is just another opportunity for him to have a conversation with our<a id="post-312152-AUKUS"></a> AUKUS partners. They will, I suspect, discuss the work currently underway and the progress made in the implementation of some of the initiatives that we have talked about in the context of AUKUS. I don’t want to get ahead of that readout, but I think you will see one late this afternoon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>It’s the first follow-up at this level since AUKUS was announced, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>It’s been several months.</p>
<p>Yes, Ben.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Do you have any comment on China using a Uyghur to light the Olympic flame and what the State Department thinks?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Not specifically beyond the point that we’ve repeatedly made, that the P<a id="post-312152-CHINA"></a>RC has sought to – the PRC has sought to disguise the true reality of what is going on, what has gone on in Xinjiang – that is the ongoing genocide, those are the crimes against humanity, that’s the human rights abuses that have taken place there. But when it comes to their motives for choosing this specific individual, I’d have to refer you to them.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Will Rob Malley be in Vienna tomorrow for the start of the talks?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>He is traveling to <a id="post-312152-IRAN2"></a>Vienna today. Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:41 p.m.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
