<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 01:40:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Briefing with Senior Administration Officials on the U.S. Humanitarian Assistance Response to Russia’s Further Invasion of Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-with-senior-administration-officials-on-the-u-s-humanitarian-assistance-response-to-russias-further-invasion-of-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 01:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324682</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Thank you, Ryan, and thank you, everyone, for joining us this afternoon for this briefing on the U.S. humanitarian assistance response to Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>Here at the top, before we get started, I would like to remind everyone that this briefing is on background with attribution to senior administration officials, and that the contents of this call are embargoed until the end of the briefing.</p>
<p>For the purposes of your reporting, you can refer to our briefers as Senior Administration Official Number One, Senior Administration Official Number Two, and Senior Administration Official Number Three.</p>
<p>Now, for your information but not for your reporting, I’m going to go ahead and let you know who our briefers are this afternoon.  I’m very glad to have with us ;  be Senior Administration Official Number One.  ;  be Senior Administration Official Number Two.  And third, , or Senior Administration Official Number Three.</p>
<p>Okay, we’re going to start our briefing today just with some brief remarks from each of our speakers and then we’ll take a few of your questions.  Again, let me just say that this briefing this afternoon is on the U.S. humanitarian assistance in response to Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine.  I would like to go ahead and ask folks to please limit your questions to that topic.  We’ve already had excellent briefings today from Press Secretary Jen Psaki over at the White House and Spokesperson Ned Price here at State covering the full gamut of issues with regard to Russia and its invasion of Ukraine, so we’ll ask you again to limit your questions to humanitarian assistance and our response in that regard.</p>
<p>Okay.  And with that, I’m going to go ahead and turn it over to  to get us started.  ?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL NUMBER ONE:</b>  Thank you and good afternoon, everyone.  I appreciate the opportunity to speak with you today about USAID’s humanitarian response to the crisis in Ukraine following Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.</p>
<p>Since this senseless campaign of unprovoked violence has begun, 4.7 million people have been displaced in and out of Ukraine.  That’s over 10 percent of Ukraine’s population, but one that the UN thinks the real figures may be significantly higher.</p>
<p>Putin’s war has turned nearly 3 million Ukrainians into refugees, including 1 million children, some of whom are forced to flee without their parents.  Nearly 2 million people are displaced inside of Ukraine.  We are hearing distressing reports from our partners in cities like Mariupol, where people remain in dire conditions and lack safe drinking water, food, fuel, and electricity.  The extensive damage we are seeing also means that shelter may be inadequate at a time when people face cold weather.  All of this is compounded by the terror of living under bombardment.</p>
<p>As the war continues into its third week, as just one of the many examples of the horrors civilians face, we are seeing Russian forces target schools and hospitals with a campaign of terror that has interrupted the cancer treatment for 1,500 children who are now forced to flee as bombs rain down on them while crossing into foreign countries with compromised immune systems during a pandemic with only the supplies they can carry.</p>
<p>We call for an immediate end to this needless war of aggression.  Short of that, the United States strongly supports the United Nations’ call for the establishment of safe passage of civilians out of areas under Russian attack and safe passage for aid workers attempting to provide humanitarian and medical supplies.  Russia must negotiate in good faith on these issues immediately.</p>
<p>In the face of this catastrophic toll on the people of Ukraine, you are seeing the U.S. stand united with our allies to aid those who are suffering.  USAID’s Disaster Assistance Response Team, or DART, has been in the region since the early days of Russia’s unprovoked war, making up-to-the-minute assessments of humanitarian needs and quickly ramping up assistance in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Over the past week alone, USAID has rapidly deployed four planeloads of lifesaving supplies from our warehouse in Dubai and mobilized our partners to immediately stand up surge support.</p>
<p>This includes blankets, high energy biscuits, kitchen sets, water treatment supplies, which USAID partner International Organization for Migration, or IOM, will distribute to vulnerable Ukrainians.</p>
<p>We’ve also worked with our partner the World Health Organization to provide emergency health kits with vital medicines and medical supplies, as well as trauma and emergency surgery kits to support emergency surgeries.  These supplies, which serve upwards of 100,000 people, are directly supporting the Government of Ukraine’s health care system, which has been badly damaged since the war began.</p>
<p>USAID partner the UN World Food Program also transported 500 metric tons of wheat flour, enough to provide bread for 500,000 people for a week, to Kyiv.  A WFP-contracted bakery also delivered nearly 15 metric tons of bread – sent to meet the needs of 60,000 people – to hospitals in Kharkiv.</p>
<p>Through our partners, we also continue to provide critical psychosocial support to children, people with disabilities, and older people, operating mobile medical units and protection teams to reach remote, displaced, or homebound communities and conducting mine-risk education activities to minimize protection risk.</p>
<p>In total, the United States has provided nearly 293 million in additional humanitarian assistance in just the last two weeks, including nearly 81 million from USAID.  We will continue to stand with the Ukrainian people during this crisis and work to meet their needs.</p>
<p>However, despite this project – progress, the situation on the ground in Ukraine is rapidly getting worse.  Russian bombardment and shelling continues to damage the infrastructure needed to get aid to people, destroying roads, bridges, and railroads, and making it difficult for aid workers to reach people in need.  In the absence of a ceasefire, humanitarian safe passage must be assured in order to allow aid workers to reach those in need.  As humanitarian needs continue to rise, USAID is working closely with European allies and partners who are on the front lines of this response on how to support people displaced internally and other people affected by the conflict.  We will continue to coordinate closely with the UN, other donors and partners to urge that robust humanitarian assistance can continue to prevent gaps in basic service delivery.</p>
<p>Thank you for your time.  I’d now like to pass it to  for  remarks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b>  Hi.  Thank you, , and thank you everybody for being here this afternoon.</p>
<p>I’m from , and we really want to underscore that our partnership with and commitment to the people of Ukraine and their government is steadfast and enduring.  We will continue to support and stand with them.</p>
<p>Today I want to share with you more about the enormous humanitarian efforts underway to assist the 12 million people in need of assistance across Ukraine, and the nearly 3 million refugees throughout neighboring countries due to the Russian Federation’s unprovoked and unjustified attack against Ukraine.</p>
<p>We are working with the Government of Ukraine, neighboring governments in the region, the European Union, international organizations like the United Nations, and other partners around the clock to address the urgent humanitarian needs of this crisis.  We are closely coordinating with these partners to monitor developments, assess needs, and respond accordingly.</p>
<p>Historically, the United States is the largest single country donor of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  Since the start of the current crisis, we have announced nearly $293 million in additional assistance to those affected by Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, including more than 186 million announced today.  This includes nearly 81 million from USAID, and nearly 212 million from the Department of State, and we will continue to do even more.</p>
<p>With this new contribution, we will complement the tremendous efforts of neighboring countries generously welcoming refugees.  We will work through our international and nongovernmental partners who provide food, safe drinking water, shelter, emergency health care, and protection.  This assistance will also support vulnerable populations inside Ukraine, as our humanitarian organization partners work tirelessly to provide safe passage for evacuees trying to leave danger.</p>
<p>Since the conflict in Ukraine began eight years ago, the United States has provided over 644 million in humanitarian assistance to vulnerable communities across Ukraine.  We will continue to support our European allies and partners who are at the forefront of this response, as well as international organizations and nongovernmental organizations working to mitigate the humanitarian impacts of this crisis.</p>
<p>We are also committed to working with a range of partners and stakeholders, including the Ukrainian diaspora community, to ensure that humanitarian organizations are prepared to respond to existing and new needs that arise in Ukraine and the neighboring countries.  The courage of the people of Ukraine and the generosity of all who have stepped up in their time of need is inspiring, and we will continue to stand with Ukraine.</p>
<p>Thank you, and I will turn it over to .  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THREE:</b>  Thank you, .  Good afternoon, everyone.  I’m here representing  to share information about visa processing for Ukrainians.</p>
<p>But first, just for a second, I want to go off – slightly off-topic and reiterate the State Department Travel Advisory for Ukraine is at a Level Four – Do Not Travel due to increased threat of Russian military action.  Our recommendations to U.S. citizens currently in Ukraine is that they should leave now using available transportation options if it is safe to do so.  We continue to encourage U.S. citizens in Ukraine to fill out our online form to let us know where they are, what they’re doing.</p>
<p>Turning to visas, given the suspension of our operations in Ukraine, the State Department is not offering visa services in Ukraine at this time.  I’ll talk a little bit about immigrant visas first and then nonimmigrant visas.  We want to share this information to further clarify visa options and outline alternatives to visas that Ukrainians may consider.  It’s important to note that a visa is not a viable way to achieve refugee resettlement in the United States.</p>
<p>We understand that any U.S. citizens who leave Ukraine may have families with mixed immigration status, for example, a U.S. citizen whose spouse has not yet started or completed the immigrant visa process.  We are prioritizing consular support to U.S. citizens and their immediate family members in this regard.  The Immigration and Nationality Act defines immediate family members as spouse, unmarried children under 21, and parents, so that’s our focus for immigrant visas.</p>
<p>We have designated the U.S. Consulate General in Frankfurt as the processing post for all the immigrant visa applications that would have been processed in Kyiv, with the exception of adoption cases, which will be handled at the U.S. embassy in Warsaw.</p>
<p>Ukraine passport holders can enter Schengen countries without a visa.  U.S. citizens and their immediate family members should relocate to a safe place and then follow detailed guidance on visa processing on our website and the website of the nearest U.S. embassy or consulate.  U.S. citizens who are overseas with the immediate family members that I described and have not yet filed an immigrant visa petition with USCIS may request to file a petition at the nearest embassy or consulate that processes immigrant visas.  Again, this only applies to the spouses, unmarried children under 21, and the parents that I just described.  Individuals who already have a USCIS-approved current petition for an immigrant visa for their relatives of any kind who have not yet been scheduled for an immigrant visa interview may be able to request expedited processing through the National Visa Center.</p>
<p>Now turning to nonimmigrant visas, again, I want to reiterate that nonimmigrant visas are for temporary stays in the United States.  They’re not the appropriate tool to begin an immigrant, refugee, or resettlement process.  If a person applies for a B1/B2 visa, commonly called a tourist visa, but they are unable to demonstrate their intent to leave the United States after a defined period in order to return to a residence abroad, a consular officer will have to refuse the application.  Nonimmigrant visa applicants may apply at any embassy or consulate where they are physically present and where appointments are available.  A full list of embassies and consulates is available at <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMTYuNTQ5NzI0NjEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnVzZW1iYXNzeS5nb3YvIn0.8RPP8ZoGYD-2ses9AtgWMkKjHRi1q5jrrBKo11-fGjs/s/2171565732/br/128169588585-l" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMTYuNTQ5NzI0NjEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnVzZW1iYXNzeS5nb3YvIn0.8RPP8ZoGYD-2ses9AtgWMkKjHRi1q5jrrBKo11-fGjs/s/2171565732/br/128169588585-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1647479859904000&amp;usg=AOvVaw36USQPSUvWnH2OFSehB8Va">usembassy.gov</a>.</p>
<p>As a result of COVID – as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic, applicants may face extended visa interview wait times at some embassies and consulates, but once an interview appointment is made, applicants will have the ability to request an expedited appointment.  However, they must describe the unique circumstances that justify such a request, i.e. justify that they go get an appointment earlier than many of the other people in a similar situation.</p>
<p>Finally, a note on adoption.  The department is actively working with adoption service providers to provide guidance and answer questions during this critical time.  Our website address – addresses adoptions and intended adoptions at various stages of the process and provides guidance on whom to consult and clarifications on the department’s potential role and ability to assist.  Prospective adoptive parents should consult their adoption service provider about how the crisis in Ukraine may impact their adoption plans.  They can also email <a href="mailto:adoption@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">adoption@state.gov</a> with questions.</p>
<p>With that, I’ll turn it back to .  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Great.  Thank you to  and  and to  for that.  Operator, would you please give the instructions once again for getting into the question queue?</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Certainly.  Ladies and gentlemen, if you’d like to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 now – 1, 0.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Okay, let’s go to the line of Michelle Hackman.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Okay.  Please, go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi there, thanks for doing this call.  I’m wondering if I guess someone from the refugee division can speak to there’s been some reporting about creating an expedited program for Ukrainian refugees to come to the U.S., particularly those with family members already here.  Could you tell us what the latest thinking is about that?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b>  Sure, and I will echo or refer everybody back to Jen Psaki’s comments on this earlier today as well, but the department is continuing to work to explore all possible options to support those who may want to resettle to the United States and meet the qualifications of our resettlement program.  We are recognizing, though, that most people who are fleeing Ukraine are – prefer to stay in the region where they can travel visa-free and many have families and there are large diaspora communities, with the hope that they can return home soon.  And so we do want to commend our European allies for keeping their borders open and continuing to provide protection to those who are fleeing.</p>
<p>If refugees are identified as having protection needs that cannot be met in the country where they currently are – again, recognizing that their immediate safety is of paramount importance – we will work with our UN partners and other resettlement partners to identify those that would be safer resettling to other countries, including the United States, and then we’ll seek to help assist them through our U.S. Refugee Resettlement Program.  That program is not an emergency response program, so again, our goal would be to provide humanitarian assistance to keep people safe where they are for now while that process would continue.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  And let’s please go to the line now of Camilla Schick.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Okay.  Please, go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi.  Hi, thank you for this.  I was wondering if you could give a little bit more detail – and I understand the security concerns in providing detail on this, but any more detail about what the U.S. or USAID is doing to help particularly Ukrainian journalists, anti-corruption activists, ethnic minorities, members of vulnerable communities such as LGBTQ who want to leave the country because of the Russian advance and whether – given that they’re Ukrainian, whether there is some kind of special status or visa application process for them to be able to come to the United States or elsewhere.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b>  This is .  I can start off on that and then let others chime in, but I would say – so first, our humanitarian organization partners are doing everything they can to continue to operate on the ground inside Ukraine to provide safe passage for evacuees trying to flee from the dangerous situation, including – particularly those who are most vulnerable, such as the groups that you have mentioned.</p>
<p>I – once refugees get to the border crossings, again, our international organization partners for whom we have now contributed a significant amount of resources in the past two weeks particularly focus on the protection of those groups that are most vulnerable and will seek to provide them with information at the border and where to go on the other side, and then again, our partners are on the other side of the border as well and will be providing protection to all of those who are most vulnerable, whether it be, again, dissidents, journalists, those who are LGBTQI+ individuals, those with disabilities, as well as third-country nationals who may be having challenges returning back to their home countries.  So they are particularly attuned to those groups, and are focusing their protection efforts, including surging additional staff with explicit expertise at providing protection to vulnerable groups.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THREE:</b>  And this is .  On the very last part of that question regarding visas, the options for visa application are defined in statute.  You mentioned journalists, you mentioned a couple other groups.  As I had discussed in my remarks, the B1/B2 visa is just for general visits to the United States, business or tourism.  There is a particular visa category for journalists who are coming to the US to work as journalists, called the I visa.  Maybe you already – you guys may be very familiar.  But apart from that, there are no – there’s a wide variety of visa categories, but I don’t believe any that would apply to the groups that you just noted.  By far the vast majority of the nonimmigrant visa categories require a residence abroad and have a presumption of intending immigration that the applicant needs to rebut.  But as I said, we are processing many emergency visa applications.  We are not able to process the volume of the people who are thinking about that as an option.</p>
<p>I hope that answers your question.  Over.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Okay.  And let’s go to the line of Erin Durkin.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi.  Thank you so much for taking my question.  I just have a two-part question on the use of humanitarian corridors, particularly by the USAID team on the ground.  I first wanted to just ask a clarifying question – if and when these are established or agreed upon with Russia, if the focus of the USAID team is more about getting people out or if it’s also about getting supplies into the regions.  And then the second part of that is how you will balance that with the safety of your own team given Russia’s particularly bad history with humanitarian corridors.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:</b>  Hi.  Okay, thank you for that question.  I’d first start by saying we – both USAID and the State Department work through and with nongovernmental and UN partners on the ground.  Their safety and security is of the utmost importance to us, but this is not – these programs are not directly implemented by U.S. Government personnel.  It is through our partners.  Our focus is on both the evacuation of civilians who are seeking to leave these encircled cities, as well as getting critical food and medical supplies in along those same safe passages should they be negotiated by the parties to the conflict.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  And as a reminder, if you’d like to queue up for a question, it’s 1 then 0.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  And just on that last question, I would add that of course colleagues here, we want to do everything possible to save lives, which is why the U.S. Government, we of course support the establishment of humanitarian corridors.  I would point out that there’s been I believe at this point six successive agreements for humanitarian pauses in fighting in Mariupol which have broken down.  During one of those reported pauses on March 9th, a maternity hospital was targeted.  These corridors will only be as effective as Moscow’s willingness to maintain them, and the corridors, while they would be welcome in the short term, are certainly no substitute for ending the war.  And I know that the U.S. Government will continue to pull every lever to bring about that outcome.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Abigail Williams.  Abby.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi.  Thanks so much for doing this call.  A couple of questions.  One of them, I wondered if you could just address sort of where you’re starting at here in this process where you are trying to help Ukrainians now after the system has been affected by COVID, by cuts in previous administrations, by processing the 70,000 Afghans that are being brought in recently, and how that impacts your ability to process visas now.  And more specifically, I wondered what you would say to the Ukrainian American community here who obviously are very focused on their loved ones overseas trying to come over and may not be a direct family member, may not fit into that – the nuclear family category, maybe an adult sibling or something along those lines.  And what would you say to them?  How would you say they can help to bring their family over here, and how long would that process take?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THREE:</b>  Hi, yes.  Many thanks for this question.  So we – as you’ve been following, we have many – many, many things we need – we are doing with our limited resources.  We are throwing many, many resources at the assistance for U.S. citizens in this region as well as visa processing, but the demand, as you can imagine, is very high, which is why we’re trying to educate the appropriateness of the immigrant visa and nonimmigrant visa channels so that the people who are using those pathways do so knowing what the requirements are.</p>
<p>With that respect, we are engaging with the Ukrainian diaspora.  You’re exactly right, these are many of the questions.  There are processes to bring other non-immediate relatives through the immigrant visa process.  This might include your adult child of a U.S. citizen, it would include relatives of legal permanent residents, spouse and minor children chief among them.  It would include your – even your siblings.  This process is not immediate and it goes through U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Service, after which we would process that application overseas.  And some of the ones that we are processing in Frankfurt are those cases, it’s just we can’t process immediately sort of everything from the petition to the immigrant visa all as one package, only for those immediate relatives, spouse, minor children, and parents expeditiously.</p>
<p>Other than that, many people may very well qualify for a nonimmigrant visa, but it definitely depends on their situation.  Again, the statute requires a residence abroad to which they have no intention of abandoning.  It does not have to be their home in Ukraine.  They have to have a plan for what they’re doing after – how does this trip to the United States fit in with their plans forward.  Don’t – doesn’t have to be concrete; you have to rebut the presumption of intending immigration, that you have something else planned for after this trip of a defined period to the United States, which might make sense in some people’s cases, might not make sense depending on what their purpose of the travel is.</p>
<p>I want to emphasize each of those is a case-by-case analysis by the consular officer.  They look at the totality of circumstances, and so it’s not a – that you can’t use this, it’s just if your plan is to go to the United States and you have absolutely no idea what you’ll do after that – which I have to say on a human level is very understandable – as U.S. consular officers who are charged with executing U.S. immigration law, they would be well advised to have much more of a plan afterward – I’ll be – going to go visit my aunts and come back to Poland where I’m enrolling in school, or Germany, or wherever.  That’s all possible.</p>
<p>I hope that answers your question.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Okay, one more time, if you have a question and would like to ask that question, please dial 1 and then 0.</p>
<p>Looks like we have a follow-up from Abby.  Operator, would you please open up Abigail’s line again, please?</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Okay.  Please, go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Sorry, since no one else is jumping in, I thought I might toss out another question.  I recognize it’s difficult to give specific numbers, but I wondered if you might be able to say what the current backlog is in processing visas more broadly or speak to what that backlog looks like, or – and/or if you could give a little more specifics on what you’re seeing as far as applications for visas right now by Americans – by Ukrainians trying to come over to the U.S.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THREE:</b>  I don’t have numbers for you at all on the backlog.  We do – particularly, I assume you’re asking about nonimmigrant visas.  Each post is different.  I do want to emphasize, as I said at the top, we do have an expedite channel, so even if the wait time for a routine B1/B2 visa is lengthy, someone with exceptional circumstances – a medical or unique humanitarian need – can request an expedite.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Okay, great.  With that, I’d like to thank our briefers today – , , and also .  Again, thank you.</p>
<p>Once again, as a quick reminder, this call was on background today with attribution to senior administration officials.  With that, we are concluding today’s conference call and the embargo is now lifted.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Thank you, Ryan, and thank you, everyone, for joining us this afternoon for this briefing on the U.S. humanitarian assistance response to Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>Here at the top, before we get started, I would like to remind everyone that this briefing is on background with attribution to senior administration officials, and that the contents of this call are embargoed until the end of the briefing.</p>
<p>For the purposes of your reporting, you can refer to our briefers as Senior Administration Official Number One, Senior Administration Official Number Two, and Senior Administration Official Number Three.</p>
<p>Now, for your information but not for your reporting, I’m going to go ahead and let you know who our briefers are this afternoon.  I’m very glad to have with us ;  be Senior Administration Official Number One.  ;  be Senior Administration Official Number Two.  And third, , or Senior Administration Official Number Three.</p>
<p>Okay, we’re going to start our briefing today just with some brief remarks from each of our speakers and then we’ll take a few of your questions.  Again, let me just say that this briefing this afternoon is on the U.S. humanitarian assistance in response to Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine.  I would like to go ahead and ask folks to please limit your questions to that topic.  We’ve already had excellent briefings today from Press Secretary Jen Psaki over at the White House and Spokesperson Ned Price here at State covering the full gamut of issues with regard to Russia and its invasion of Ukraine, so we’ll ask you again to limit your questions to humanitarian assistance and our response in that regard.</p>
<p>Okay.  And with that, I’m going to go ahead and turn it over to  to get us started.  ?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL NUMBER ONE:</b>  Thank you and good afternoon, everyone.  I appreciate the opportunity to speak with you today about USAID’s humanitarian response to the crisis in Ukraine following Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.</p>
<p>Since this senseless campaign of unprovoked violence has begun, 4.7 million people have been displaced in and out of Ukraine.  That’s over 10 percent of Ukraine’s population, but one that the UN thinks the real figures may be significantly higher.</p>
<p>Putin’s war has turned nearly 3 million Ukrainians into refugees, including 1 million children, some of whom are forced to flee without their parents.  Nearly 2 million people are displaced inside of Ukraine.  We are hearing distressing reports from our partners in cities like Mariupol, where people remain in dire conditions and lack safe drinking water, food, fuel, and electricity.  The extensive damage we are seeing also means that shelter may be inadequate at a time when people face cold weather.  All of this is compounded by the terror of living under bombardment.</p>
<p>As the war continues into its third week, as just one of the many examples of the horrors civilians face, we are seeing Russian forces target schools and hospitals with a campaign of terror that has interrupted the cancer treatment for 1,500 children who are now forced to flee as bombs rain down on them while crossing into foreign countries with compromised immune systems during a pandemic with only the supplies they can carry.</p>
<p>We call for an immediate end to this needless war of aggression.  Short of that, the United States strongly supports the United Nations’ call for the establishment of safe passage of civilians out of areas under Russian attack and safe passage for aid workers attempting to provide humanitarian and medical supplies.  Russia must negotiate in good faith on these issues immediately.</p>
<p>In the face of this catastrophic toll on the people of Ukraine, you are seeing the U.S. stand united with our allies to aid those who are suffering.  USAID’s Disaster Assistance Response Team, or DART, has been in the region since the early days of Russia’s unprovoked war, making up-to-the-minute assessments of humanitarian needs and quickly ramping up assistance in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Over the past week alone, USAID has rapidly deployed four planeloads of lifesaving supplies from our warehouse in Dubai and mobilized our partners to immediately stand up surge support.</p>
<p>This includes blankets, high energy biscuits, kitchen sets, water treatment supplies, which USAID partner International Organization for Migration, or IOM, will distribute to vulnerable Ukrainians.</p>
<p>We’ve also worked with our partner the World Health Organization to provide emergency health kits with vital medicines and medical supplies, as well as trauma and emergency surgery kits to support emergency surgeries.  These supplies, which serve upwards of 100,000 people, are directly supporting the Government of Ukraine’s health care system, which has been badly damaged since the war began.</p>
<p>USAID partner the UN World Food Program also transported 500 metric tons of wheat flour, enough to provide bread for 500,000 people for a week, to Kyiv.  A WFP-contracted bakery also delivered nearly 15 metric tons of bread – sent to meet the needs of 60,000 people – to hospitals in Kharkiv.</p>
<p>Through our partners, we also continue to provide critical psychosocial support to children, people with disabilities, and older people, operating mobile medical units and protection teams to reach remote, displaced, or homebound communities and conducting mine-risk education activities to minimize protection risk.</p>
<p>In total, the United States has provided nearly 293 million in additional humanitarian assistance in just the last two weeks, including nearly 81 million from USAID.  We will continue to stand with the Ukrainian people during this crisis and work to meet their needs.</p>
<p>However, despite this project – progress, the situation on the ground in Ukraine is rapidly getting worse.  Russian bombardment and shelling continues to damage the infrastructure needed to get aid to people, destroying roads, bridges, and railroads, and making it difficult for aid workers to reach people in need.  In the absence of a ceasefire, humanitarian safe passage must be assured in order to allow aid workers to reach those in need.  As humanitarian needs continue to rise, USAID is working closely with European allies and partners who are on the front lines of this response on how to support people displaced internally and other people affected by the conflict.  We will continue to coordinate closely with the UN, other donors and partners to urge that robust humanitarian assistance can continue to prevent gaps in basic service delivery.</p>
<p>Thank you for your time.  I’d now like to pass it to  for  remarks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b>  Hi.  Thank you, , and thank you everybody for being here this afternoon.</p>
<p>I’m from , and we really want to underscore that our partnership with and commitment to the people of Ukraine and their government is steadfast and enduring.  We will continue to support and stand with them.</p>
<p>Today I want to share with you more about the enormous humanitarian efforts underway to assist the 12 million people in need of assistance across Ukraine, and the nearly 3 million refugees throughout neighboring countries due to the Russian Federation’s unprovoked and unjustified attack against Ukraine.</p>
<p>We are working with the Government of Ukraine, neighboring governments in the region, the European Union, international organizations like the United Nations, and other partners around the clock to address the urgent humanitarian needs of this crisis.  We are closely coordinating with these partners to monitor developments, assess needs, and respond accordingly.</p>
<p>Historically, the United States is the largest single country donor of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  Since the start of the current crisis, we have announced nearly $293 million in additional assistance to those affected by Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, including more than 186 million announced today.  This includes nearly 81 million from USAID, and nearly 212 million from the Department of State, and we will continue to do even more.</p>
<p>With this new contribution, we will complement the tremendous efforts of neighboring countries generously welcoming refugees.  We will work through our international and nongovernmental partners who provide food, safe drinking water, shelter, emergency health care, and protection.  This assistance will also support vulnerable populations inside Ukraine, as our humanitarian organization partners work tirelessly to provide safe passage for evacuees trying to leave danger.</p>
<p>Since the conflict in Ukraine began eight years ago, the United States has provided over 644 million in humanitarian assistance to vulnerable communities across Ukraine.  We will continue to support our European allies and partners who are at the forefront of this response, as well as international organizations and nongovernmental organizations working to mitigate the humanitarian impacts of this crisis.</p>
<p>We are also committed to working with a range of partners and stakeholders, including the Ukrainian diaspora community, to ensure that humanitarian organizations are prepared to respond to existing and new needs that arise in Ukraine and the neighboring countries.  The courage of the people of Ukraine and the generosity of all who have stepped up in their time of need is inspiring, and we will continue to stand with Ukraine.</p>
<p>Thank you, and I will turn it over to .  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THREE:</b>  Thank you, .  Good afternoon, everyone.  I’m here representing  to share information about visa processing for Ukrainians.</p>
<p>But first, just for a second, I want to go off – slightly off-topic and reiterate the State Department Travel Advisory for Ukraine is at a Level Four – Do Not Travel due to increased threat of Russian military action.  Our recommendations to U.S. citizens currently in Ukraine is that they should leave now using available transportation options if it is safe to do so.  We continue to encourage U.S. citizens in Ukraine to fill out our online form to let us know where they are, what they’re doing.</p>
<p>Turning to visas, given the suspension of our operations in Ukraine, the State Department is not offering visa services in Ukraine at this time.  I’ll talk a little bit about immigrant visas first and then nonimmigrant visas.  We want to share this information to further clarify visa options and outline alternatives to visas that Ukrainians may consider.  It’s important to note that a visa is not a viable way to achieve refugee resettlement in the United States.</p>
<p>We understand that any U.S. citizens who leave Ukraine may have families with mixed immigration status, for example, a U.S. citizen whose spouse has not yet started or completed the immigrant visa process.  We are prioritizing consular support to U.S. citizens and their immediate family members in this regard.  The Immigration and Nationality Act defines immediate family members as spouse, unmarried children under 21, and parents, so that’s our focus for immigrant visas.</p>
<p>We have designated the U.S. Consulate General in Frankfurt as the processing post for all the immigrant visa applications that would have been processed in Kyiv, with the exception of adoption cases, which will be handled at the U.S. embassy in Warsaw.</p>
<p>Ukraine passport holders can enter Schengen countries without a visa.  U.S. citizens and their immediate family members should relocate to a safe place and then follow detailed guidance on visa processing on our website and the website of the nearest U.S. embassy or consulate.  U.S. citizens who are overseas with the immediate family members that I described and have not yet filed an immigrant visa petition with USCIS may request to file a petition at the nearest embassy or consulate that processes immigrant visas.  Again, this only applies to the spouses, unmarried children under 21, and the parents that I just described.  Individuals who already have a USCIS-approved current petition for an immigrant visa for their relatives of any kind who have not yet been scheduled for an immigrant visa interview may be able to request expedited processing through the National Visa Center.</p>
<p>Now turning to nonimmigrant visas, again, I want to reiterate that nonimmigrant visas are for temporary stays in the United States.  They’re not the appropriate tool to begin an immigrant, refugee, or resettlement process.  If a person applies for a B1/B2 visa, commonly called a tourist visa, but they are unable to demonstrate their intent to leave the United States after a defined period in order to return to a residence abroad, a consular officer will have to refuse the application.  Nonimmigrant visa applicants may apply at any embassy or consulate where they are physically present and where appointments are available.  A full list of embassies and consulates is available at <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMTYuNTQ5NzI0NjEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnVzZW1iYXNzeS5nb3YvIn0.8RPP8ZoGYD-2ses9AtgWMkKjHRi1q5jrrBKo11-fGjs/s/2171565732/br/128169588585-l" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMTYuNTQ5NzI0NjEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnVzZW1iYXNzeS5nb3YvIn0.8RPP8ZoGYD-2ses9AtgWMkKjHRi1q5jrrBKo11-fGjs/s/2171565732/br/128169588585-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1647479859904000&amp;usg=AOvVaw36USQPSUvWnH2OFSehB8Va">usembassy.gov</a>.</p>
<p>As a result of COVID – as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic, applicants may face extended visa interview wait times at some embassies and consulates, but once an interview appointment is made, applicants will have the ability to request an expedited appointment.  However, they must describe the unique circumstances that justify such a request, i.e. justify that they go get an appointment earlier than many of the other people in a similar situation.</p>
<p>Finally, a note on adoption.  The department is actively working with adoption service providers to provide guidance and answer questions during this critical time.  Our website address – addresses adoptions and intended adoptions at various stages of the process and provides guidance on whom to consult and clarifications on the department’s potential role and ability to assist.  Prospective adoptive parents should consult their adoption service provider about how the crisis in Ukraine may impact their adoption plans.  They can also email <a href="mailto:adoption@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">adoption@state.gov</a> with questions.</p>
<p>With that, I’ll turn it back to .  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Great.  Thank you to  and  and to  for that.  Operator, would you please give the instructions once again for getting into the question queue?</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Certainly.  Ladies and gentlemen, if you’d like to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 now – 1, 0.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Okay, let’s go to the line of Michelle Hackman.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Okay.  Please, go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi there, thanks for doing this call.  I’m wondering if I guess someone from the refugee division can speak to there’s been some reporting about creating an expedited program for Ukrainian refugees to come to the U.S., particularly those with family members already here.  Could you tell us what the latest thinking is about that?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b>  Sure, and I will echo or refer everybody back to Jen Psaki’s comments on this earlier today as well, but the department is continuing to work to explore all possible options to support those who may want to resettle to the United States and meet the qualifications of our resettlement program.  We are recognizing, though, that most people who are fleeing Ukraine are – prefer to stay in the region where they can travel visa-free and many have families and there are large diaspora communities, with the hope that they can return home soon.  And so we do want to commend our European allies for keeping their borders open and continuing to provide protection to those who are fleeing.</p>
<p>If refugees are identified as having protection needs that cannot be met in the country where they currently are – again, recognizing that their immediate safety is of paramount importance – we will work with our UN partners and other resettlement partners to identify those that would be safer resettling to other countries, including the United States, and then we’ll seek to help assist them through our U.S. Refugee Resettlement Program.  That program is not an emergency response program, so again, our goal would be to provide humanitarian assistance to keep people safe where they are for now while that process would continue.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  And let’s please go to the line now of Camilla Schick.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Okay.  Please, go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi.  Hi, thank you for this.  I was wondering if you could give a little bit more detail – and I understand the security concerns in providing detail on this, but any more detail about what the U.S. or USAID is doing to help particularly Ukrainian journalists, anti-corruption activists, ethnic minorities, members of vulnerable communities such as LGBTQ who want to leave the country because of the Russian advance and whether – given that they’re Ukrainian, whether there is some kind of special status or visa application process for them to be able to come to the United States or elsewhere.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b>  This is .  I can start off on that and then let others chime in, but I would say – so first, our humanitarian organization partners are doing everything they can to continue to operate on the ground inside Ukraine to provide safe passage for evacuees trying to flee from the dangerous situation, including – particularly those who are most vulnerable, such as the groups that you have mentioned.</p>
<p>I – once refugees get to the border crossings, again, our international organization partners for whom we have now contributed a significant amount of resources in the past two weeks particularly focus on the protection of those groups that are most vulnerable and will seek to provide them with information at the border and where to go on the other side, and then again, our partners are on the other side of the border as well and will be providing protection to all of those who are most vulnerable, whether it be, again, dissidents, journalists, those who are LGBTQI+ individuals, those with disabilities, as well as third-country nationals who may be having challenges returning back to their home countries.  So they are particularly attuned to those groups, and are focusing their protection efforts, including surging additional staff with explicit expertise at providing protection to vulnerable groups.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THREE:</b>  And this is .  On the very last part of that question regarding visas, the options for visa application are defined in statute.  You mentioned journalists, you mentioned a couple other groups.  As I had discussed in my remarks, the B1/B2 visa is just for general visits to the United States, business or tourism.  There is a particular visa category for journalists who are coming to the US to work as journalists, called the I visa.  Maybe you already – you guys may be very familiar.  But apart from that, there are no – there’s a wide variety of visa categories, but I don’t believe any that would apply to the groups that you just noted.  By far the vast majority of the nonimmigrant visa categories require a residence abroad and have a presumption of intending immigration that the applicant needs to rebut.  But as I said, we are processing many emergency visa applications.  We are not able to process the volume of the people who are thinking about that as an option.</p>
<p>I hope that answers your question.  Over.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Okay.  And let’s go to the line of Erin Durkin.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi.  Thank you so much for taking my question.  I just have a two-part question on the use of humanitarian corridors, particularly by the USAID team on the ground.  I first wanted to just ask a clarifying question – if and when these are established or agreed upon with Russia, if the focus of the USAID team is more about getting people out or if it’s also about getting supplies into the regions.  And then the second part of that is how you will balance that with the safety of your own team given Russia’s particularly bad history with humanitarian corridors.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:</b>  Hi.  Okay, thank you for that question.  I’d first start by saying we – both USAID and the State Department work through and with nongovernmental and UN partners on the ground.  Their safety and security is of the utmost importance to us, but this is not – these programs are not directly implemented by U.S. Government personnel.  It is through our partners.  Our focus is on both the evacuation of civilians who are seeking to leave these encircled cities, as well as getting critical food and medical supplies in along those same safe passages should they be negotiated by the parties to the conflict.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  And as a reminder, if you’d like to queue up for a question, it’s 1 then 0.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  And just on that last question, I would add that of course colleagues here, we want to do everything possible to save lives, which is why the U.S. Government, we of course support the establishment of humanitarian corridors.  I would point out that there’s been I believe at this point six successive agreements for humanitarian pauses in fighting in Mariupol which have broken down.  During one of those reported pauses on March 9th, a maternity hospital was targeted.  These corridors will only be as effective as Moscow’s willingness to maintain them, and the corridors, while they would be welcome in the short term, are certainly no substitute for ending the war.  And I know that the U.S. Government will continue to pull every lever to bring about that outcome.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Abigail Williams.  Abby.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi.  Thanks so much for doing this call.  A couple of questions.  One of them, I wondered if you could just address sort of where you’re starting at here in this process where you are trying to help Ukrainians now after the system has been affected by COVID, by cuts in previous administrations, by processing the 70,000 Afghans that are being brought in recently, and how that impacts your ability to process visas now.  And more specifically, I wondered what you would say to the Ukrainian American community here who obviously are very focused on their loved ones overseas trying to come over and may not be a direct family member, may not fit into that – the nuclear family category, maybe an adult sibling or something along those lines.  And what would you say to them?  How would you say they can help to bring their family over here, and how long would that process take?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THREE:</b>  Hi, yes.  Many thanks for this question.  So we – as you’ve been following, we have many – many, many things we need – we are doing with our limited resources.  We are throwing many, many resources at the assistance for U.S. citizens in this region as well as visa processing, but the demand, as you can imagine, is very high, which is why we’re trying to educate the appropriateness of the immigrant visa and nonimmigrant visa channels so that the people who are using those pathways do so knowing what the requirements are.</p>
<p>With that respect, we are engaging with the Ukrainian diaspora.  You’re exactly right, these are many of the questions.  There are processes to bring other non-immediate relatives through the immigrant visa process.  This might include your adult child of a U.S. citizen, it would include relatives of legal permanent residents, spouse and minor children chief among them.  It would include your – even your siblings.  This process is not immediate and it goes through U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Service, after which we would process that application overseas.  And some of the ones that we are processing in Frankfurt are those cases, it’s just we can’t process immediately sort of everything from the petition to the immigrant visa all as one package, only for those immediate relatives, spouse, minor children, and parents expeditiously.</p>
<p>Other than that, many people may very well qualify for a nonimmigrant visa, but it definitely depends on their situation.  Again, the statute requires a residence abroad to which they have no intention of abandoning.  It does not have to be their home in Ukraine.  They have to have a plan for what they’re doing after – how does this trip to the United States fit in with their plans forward.  Don’t – doesn’t have to be concrete; you have to rebut the presumption of intending immigration, that you have something else planned for after this trip of a defined period to the United States, which might make sense in some people’s cases, might not make sense depending on what their purpose of the travel is.</p>
<p>I want to emphasize each of those is a case-by-case analysis by the consular officer.  They look at the totality of circumstances, and so it’s not a – that you can’t use this, it’s just if your plan is to go to the United States and you have absolutely no idea what you’ll do after that – which I have to say on a human level is very understandable – as U.S. consular officers who are charged with executing U.S. immigration law, they would be well advised to have much more of a plan afterward – I’ll be – going to go visit my aunts and come back to Poland where I’m enrolling in school, or Germany, or wherever.  That’s all possible.</p>
<p>I hope that answers your question.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Okay, one more time, if you have a question and would like to ask that question, please dial 1 and then 0.</p>
<p>Looks like we have a follow-up from Abby.  Operator, would you please open up Abigail’s line again, please?</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Okay.  Please, go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Sorry, since no one else is jumping in, I thought I might toss out another question.  I recognize it’s difficult to give specific numbers, but I wondered if you might be able to say what the current backlog is in processing visas more broadly or speak to what that backlog looks like, or – and/or if you could give a little more specifics on what you’re seeing as far as applications for visas right now by Americans – by Ukrainians trying to come over to the U.S.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THREE:</b>  I don’t have numbers for you at all on the backlog.  We do – particularly, I assume you’re asking about nonimmigrant visas.  Each post is different.  I do want to emphasize, as I said at the top, we do have an expedite channel, so even if the wait time for a routine B1/B2 visa is lengthy, someone with exceptional circumstances – a medical or unique humanitarian need – can request an expedite.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Okay, great.  With that, I’d like to thank our briefers today – , , and also .  Again, thank you.</p>
<p>Once again, as a quick reminder, this call was on background today with attribution to senior administration officials.  With that, we are concluding today’s conference call and the embargo is now lifted.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2022 Turkmenistan Presidential Election</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/2022-turkmenistan-presidential-election/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 01:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States reaffirms our commitment to the people of Turkmenistan and their right to choose their leaders through free and fair elections and in a transparent manner.</p>
<p>We concur with the concerns described in the recent needs assessment conducted by the Office for Democratic Institutions and Human Rights (ODIHR) of the Organization for Security and Co-Operation in Europe.  The ODIHR assessment noted that Turkmenistan has not proved its election processes to be free, fair, or competitive.  We call on the Government of Turkmenistan to implement ODIHR recommendations in order to align its electoral system with the standards described in the needs assessment.</p>
<p>The growing partnership between the United States and Turkmenistan is based on respect for Turkmenistan’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, and shared objectives for security and prosperity in the Central Asia region.  We will continue to encourage political participation for the people of Turkmenistan, bolstering the role of civil society, and strengthening our shared interests.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States reaffirms our commitment to the people of Turkmenistan and their right to choose their leaders through free and fair elections and in a transparent manner.</p>
<p>We concur with the concerns described in the recent needs assessment conducted by the Office for Democratic Institutions and Human Rights (ODIHR) of the Organization for Security and Co-Operation in Europe.  The ODIHR assessment noted that Turkmenistan has not proved its election processes to be free, fair, or competitive.  We call on the Government of Turkmenistan to implement ODIHR recommendations in order to align its electoral system with the standards described in the needs assessment.</p>
<p>The growing partnership between the United States and Turkmenistan is based on respect for Turkmenistan’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, and shared objectives for security and prosperity in the Central Asia region.  We will continue to encourage political participation for the people of Turkmenistan, bolstering the role of civil society, and strengthening our shared interests.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Additional Humanitarian Assistance for the People of Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/additional-humanitarian-assistance-for-the-people-of-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 20:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is providing over $186 million in additional humanitarian assistance to support internally displaced persons and the more than three million refugees affected by Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war in Ukraine.  This will provide further support for humanitarian organizations responding to the crisis and complement the generosity of the neighboring countries that are welcoming and supporting refugees.</p>
<p>We call for an immediate end to Russia’s continuing war against Ukraine and for Russia to facilitate unhindered humanitarian access in Ukraine and safe passage for those who seek to leave the cities where they are trapped.  Humanitarian aid deliveries must be allowed to continue without interference, and humanitarian workers must have safe passage to deliver aid and assistance to those in need.</p>
<p>The United States is the largest single-country donor of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine, including providing nearly $293 million in humanitarian assistance both inside Ukraine and in the region since late February.  Our funding to-date amounts to nearly $644 million to vulnerable communities in the region since Russia first invaded Ukraine eight years ago.  Our humanitarian assistance flows through independent humanitarian organizations that deliver needs-based assistance with impartiality, humanity, neutrality, and independence.</p>
<p>The additional humanitarian assistance for refugees in Ukraine’s neighboring countries supports the provision of food, safe drinking water, protection, accessible shelter, and emergency health care through the support of our international and non-governmental partners. This funding will also help victims of this conflict maintain contact with family members who have been separated and promote family reunification when possible.</p>
<p>The United States commends the hospitality of the neighboring countries that are hosting those fleeing Ukraine.  As with any refugee situation, we call on the international community to respond to the needs of those seeking protection in a way that is consistent with the principle of non-refoulement and states’ respective obligations under international law.</p>
<p>We welcome the contributions of other donors toward this crisis response and urge still others to generously support the immediate humanitarian needs in Ukraine and the region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is providing over $186 million in additional humanitarian assistance to support internally displaced persons and the more than three million refugees affected by Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war in Ukraine.  This will provide further support for humanitarian organizations responding to the crisis and complement the generosity of the neighboring countries that are welcoming and supporting refugees.</p>
<p>We call for an immediate end to Russia’s continuing war against Ukraine and for Russia to facilitate unhindered humanitarian access in Ukraine and safe passage for those who seek to leave the cities where they are trapped.  Humanitarian aid deliveries must be allowed to continue without interference, and humanitarian workers must have safe passage to deliver aid and assistance to those in need.</p>
<p>The United States is the largest single-country donor of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine, including providing nearly $293 million in humanitarian assistance both inside Ukraine and in the region since late February.  Our funding to-date amounts to nearly $644 million to vulnerable communities in the region since Russia first invaded Ukraine eight years ago.  Our humanitarian assistance flows through independent humanitarian organizations that deliver needs-based assistance with impartiality, humanity, neutrality, and independence.</p>
<p>The additional humanitarian assistance for refugees in Ukraine’s neighboring countries supports the provision of food, safe drinking water, protection, accessible shelter, and emergency health care through the support of our international and non-governmental partners. This funding will also help victims of this conflict maintain contact with family members who have been separated and promote family reunification when possible.</p>
<p>The United States commends the hospitality of the neighboring countries that are hosting those fleeing Ukraine.  As with any refugee situation, we call on the international community to respond to the needs of those seeking protection in a way that is consistent with the principle of non-refoulement and states’ respective obligations under international law.</p>
<p>We welcome the contributions of other donors toward this crisis response and urge still others to generously support the immediate humanitarian needs in Ukraine and the region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Kuleba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-ukrainian-foreign-minister-kuleba-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 20:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324543</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke by phone today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to reiterate the United States’ ironclad commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and our resolve to provide security, economic, and humanitarian support to the people of Ukraine.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Kuleba discussed ongoing diplomatic efforts to stop President Putin’s war of choice. They shared deep concern regarding increasingly significant damage to infrastructure and buildings and resulting civilian deaths and injuries. The Secretary provided an update on the most recent U.S. and global efforts to hold Putin accountable for his unprovoked and brutal war.  He commended the bravery and determination of the Ukrainian people in the fight for their country in the face of the Russian forces’ callous disregard for civilian life.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke by phone today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to reiterate the United States’ ironclad commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and our resolve to provide security, economic, and humanitarian support to the people of Ukraine.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Kuleba discussed ongoing diplomatic efforts to stop President Putin’s war of choice. They shared deep concern regarding increasingly significant damage to infrastructure and buildings and resulting civilian deaths and injuries. The Secretary provided an update on the most recent U.S. and global efforts to hold Putin accountable for his unprovoked and brutal war.  He commended the bravery and determination of the Ukrainian people in the fight for their country in the face of the Russian forces’ callous disregard for civilian life.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General Delattre</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-french-foreign-ministry-secretary-general-delattre-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 16:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324477</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General François Delattre.  The Deputy Secretary and Secretary General Delattre reiterated their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Putin’s war of choice.  They agreed on the need for continued support for Ukraine and committed to continue to impose costs on Russia for its aggression.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General François Delattre.  The Deputy Secretary and Secretary General Delattre reiterated their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Putin’s war of choice.  They agreed on the need for continued support for Ukraine and committed to continue to impose costs on Russia for its aggression.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Azerbaijani President Aliyev</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-azerbaijani-president-aliyev-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 16:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324470</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Azerbaijani President Ilham Aliyev.  Secretary Blinken emphasized the continuing importance of the U.S.-Azerbaijani bilateral partnership and the U.S. commitment to promoting a peaceful, democratic, and prosperous future for the South Caucasus region.  Noting recent reports of escalation between Armenian and Azerbaijani forces, the Secretary called for the sides to show restraint and intensify diplomatic engagement to find comprehensive solutions to all outstanding issues.  He also stressed the importance of respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms in Azerbaijan.  The Secretary highlighted the U.S. commitment, alongside other partners, to continue to hold Moscow and its supporters, including the Lukashenka regime in Belarus, accountable for the Kremlin’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Azerbaijani President Ilham Aliyev.  Secretary Blinken emphasized the continuing importance of the U.S.-Azerbaijani bilateral partnership and the U.S. commitment to promoting a peaceful, democratic, and prosperous future for the South Caucasus region.  Noting recent reports of escalation between Armenian and Azerbaijani forces, the Secretary called for the sides to show restraint and intensify diplomatic engagement to find comprehensive solutions to all outstanding issues.  He also stressed the importance of respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms in Azerbaijan.  The Secretary highlighted the U.S. commitment, alongside other partners, to continue to hold Moscow and its supporters, including the Lukashenka regime in Belarus, accountable for the Kremlin’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the Occasion of the 11-year Anniversary of the Syrian Uprising</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-the-occasion-of-the-11-year-anniversary-of-the-syrian-uprising/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 16:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following statement was released by France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America on the occasion of the 11-year anniversary of the Syrian uprising:</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>Today marks 11 years since the Syrian people courageously and peacefully took to the streets to demand freedom, political reform, and a government that respects and upholds human rights.  The Assad regime met those demands with a brutal assault that continues today against the Syrian people.  After 11 years of death and suffering, it is past time for the regime and its enablers, including Russia and Iran, to halt their ruthless attack on the Syrian people.  The coincidence of this year’s anniversary with the appalling Russian aggression against Ukraine, which constitutes a breach of exceptional gravity to international law and the UN Charter, highlights Russia’s brutal and destructive behavior in both conflicts.  After more than a decade of conflict, the Syrian economic and humanitarian situation is bleak and millions of Syrian refugees hosted generously by Syria’s neighbors, as well as those internally displaced, cannot yet return home in line with UN standards, and without fear of violence, arbitrary arrest, and torture.  Continued conflict has also led to space for terrorists, particularly Daesh (ISIS), to exploit.  Preventing Daesh’s resurgence remains a priority.</p>
<p>We continue to support the UN-facilitated, Syrian-led process outlined within UN Security Council Resolution 2254.  We will continue to call for a nationwide ceasefire, respect for international humanitarian law, and unhindered aid access through all modalities, including through the continued authorization of the cross-border mechanism by the UN Security Council.  We additionally urge the immediate release of those arbitrarily detained and clarification of the fate and whereabouts of those who remain missing.  We do not support efforts to normalize relations with the Assad regime and will not normalize relations ourselves, nor lift sanctions or fund reconstruction until there is irreversible progress towards a political solution.  We encourage all parties, especially the Syrian regime, to participate in the March 21 meeting of the Constitutional Committee in good faith and call for the Committee to deliver on its mandate.</p>
<p>Impunity remains unacceptable.  We will therefore continue to actively promote accountability, including through support to the Commission of Inquiry, the International, Impartial and Independent Mechanism, and the Organization for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons (OPCW).  This also includes supporting organizations, many of which are Syrian-led, in collecting evidence and documenting the atrocities and serious violations of international law committed in Syria, including the use of chemical weapons.  The OPCW’s Investigation and Identification Team’s (IIT) efforts continue to attribute responsibility for the abhorrent use of chemical weapons in Syria.  Despite Syria’s lack of cooperation, the IIT has already confirmed the responsibility of the Assad regime in multiple chemical weapons attacks on the Syrian people. Those responsible for this disregard for the global norm against the use of chemical weapons must be held to account.</p>
<p>We welcome ongoing efforts by national courts to investigate and prosecute crimes within their jurisdiction committed in Syria and encourage increased support for these prosecutions.  As their harrowing testimonies show, justice for victims and their families is long overdue.  Pursuing accountability and justice is essential to building confidence in the political process called for in UNSCR 2254 and securing the stable, just, and enduring peace that Syrians need and deserve.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following statement was released by France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America on the occasion of the 11-year anniversary of the Syrian uprising:</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>Today marks 11 years since the Syrian people courageously and peacefully took to the streets to demand freedom, political reform, and a government that respects and upholds human rights.  The Assad regime met those demands with a brutal assault that continues today against the Syrian people.  After 11 years of death and suffering, it is past time for the regime and its enablers, including Russia and Iran, to halt their ruthless attack on the Syrian people.  The coincidence of this year’s anniversary with the appalling Russian aggression against Ukraine, which constitutes a breach of exceptional gravity to international law and the UN Charter, highlights Russia’s brutal and destructive behavior in both conflicts.  After more than a decade of conflict, the Syrian economic and humanitarian situation is bleak and millions of Syrian refugees hosted generously by Syria’s neighbors, as well as those internally displaced, cannot yet return home in line with UN standards, and without fear of violence, arbitrary arrest, and torture.  Continued conflict has also led to space for terrorists, particularly Daesh (ISIS), to exploit.  Preventing Daesh’s resurgence remains a priority.</p>
<p>We continue to support the UN-facilitated, Syrian-led process outlined within UN Security Council Resolution 2254.  We will continue to call for a nationwide ceasefire, respect for international humanitarian law, and unhindered aid access through all modalities, including through the continued authorization of the cross-border mechanism by the UN Security Council.  We additionally urge the immediate release of those arbitrarily detained and clarification of the fate and whereabouts of those who remain missing.  We do not support efforts to normalize relations with the Assad regime and will not normalize relations ourselves, nor lift sanctions or fund reconstruction until there is irreversible progress towards a political solution.  We encourage all parties, especially the Syrian regime, to participate in the March 21 meeting of the Constitutional Committee in good faith and call for the Committee to deliver on its mandate.</p>
<p>Impunity remains unacceptable.  We will therefore continue to actively promote accountability, including through support to the Commission of Inquiry, the International, Impartial and Independent Mechanism, and the Organization for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons (OPCW).  This also includes supporting organizations, many of which are Syrian-led, in collecting evidence and documenting the atrocities and serious violations of international law committed in Syria, including the use of chemical weapons.  The OPCW’s Investigation and Identification Team’s (IIT) efforts continue to attribute responsibility for the abhorrent use of chemical weapons in Syria.  Despite Syria’s lack of cooperation, the IIT has already confirmed the responsibility of the Assad regime in multiple chemical weapons attacks on the Syrian people. Those responsible for this disregard for the global norm against the use of chemical weapons must be held to account.</p>
<p>We welcome ongoing efforts by national courts to investigate and prosecute crimes within their jurisdiction committed in Syria and encourage increased support for these prosecutions.  As their harrowing testimonies show, justice for victims and their families is long overdue.  Pursuing accountability and justice is essential to building confidence in the political process called for in UNSCR 2254 and securing the stable, just, and enduring peace that Syrians need and deserve.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Promoting Accountability for Human Rights Abuses Perpetrated by the Governments of Russia and Belarus</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/promoting-accountability-for-human-rights-abuses-perpetrated-by-the-governments-of-russia-and-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 15:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States, with support from Allies and partners, is taking action to promote accountability for the Russian and Belarusian governments’ human rights abuses and violations within and outside their borders.  In doing so, we reiterate our condemnation of President Putin’s premeditated, unjustified, and unprovoked war against Ukraine, as well as the Lukashenka regime’s support and facilitation of the Russian Federation’s invasion.  President Putin’s military campaign against Ukraine has caused extensive and needless suffering, many hundreds and likely thousands of civilian casualties, including children, and growing reports of human rights abuses and violations.</p>
<p>At the same time, the Russian government has intensified a crackdown against its own citizens’ freedom of expression, including for members of the press, as well as freedom of association and peaceful assembly.  Today in Russia, those who provide factual reporting on the invasion or criticize Putin face criminal charges. Similarly, the Lukashenka regime in Belarus continues its violent repression against civil society, anti-war protestors, the democratic opposition, independent media, and ordinary Belarusians.</p>
<p>In response, the Department of State is announcing a series of actions to promote accountability for the Russian Federation’s and Government of Belarus’s human rights abuses and violations. These include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Designation of Alyaksandr Lukashenka pursuant to Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2021. Lukashenka was publicly designated for his involvement in gross violations of human rights and significant corruption. Under this authority, Lukashenka and Lukashenka’s immediate family members are ineligible for entry into the United States, to include his wife, Galina Lukashenka, his adult sons, Viktar Lukashenka and Dzmitry Lukashenka, and his minor son.</li>
<li>Designation of 11 senior Russian defense officials by the Department of State pursuant to E.O. 14024.  This includes Viktor Zolotov, the Head of the National Guard of Russia.  Under Zolotov’s leadership, the National Guard has cracked down on Russian citizens who have taken to the streets to protest their government’s brutal campaign in Ukraine. In addition, Zolotov’s troops are responsible for suppressing dissent in occupied areas of Ukraine.  More broadly, the designation of these 11 senior Russian defense leaders continues our imposition of severe costs on Russia’s Ministry of Defense as it pursues its brutal military invasion of Ukraine, which has led to unnecessary casualties and suffering, including the deaths of children. List here: <a href="https://www.state.gov/u-s-announces-sanctions-on-key-members-of-russias-defense-enterprise/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMTUuNTQ5MzU4MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvdS1zLWFubm91bmNlcy1zYW5jdGlvbnMtb24ta2V5LW1lbWJlcnMtb2YtcnVzc2lhcy1kZWZlbnNlLWVudGVycHJpc2UvIn0.2zOCYVpZR_-r0RqZfk2ksnvOg0uNxbNHd6Uo7B9bIJg/s/1039202793/br/128123916353-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1647441876727000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1dH2LbJXV6W4sZToI9AaF5">https://www.state.<wbr />gov/u-s-announces-sanctions-<wbr />on-key-members-of-russias-<wbr />defense-enterprise/</a></li>
<li>A new visa restriction policy under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act that applies to current and former Russian government officials believed to be involved in suppressing dissent in Russia and abroad. Family members of those who fall under the policy will also be ineligible for visas. We have taken our first action pursuant to this new visa authority against 38 individuals, and will continue to implement this policy to demonstrate solidarity with the victims of Russia’s repression.</li>
<li>Designation of two of Russia’s Federal Security Service (FSB) officers in Crimea, Artur Shambazov and <wbr />Andrey Tishenin, pursuant to Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2021.  Shambazov and Tishenin were publicly designated for their involvement in a gross violation of human rights, namely torture.</li>
<li>Action to impose visa restrictions on six individuals who, acting on behalf of the Russian Federation, were involved in attacks on Chechen dissidents living in Europe.  This action is being taken pursuant to the “Khashoggi Ban,” a visa restriction policy the Administration announced last year to counter transnational repression.</li>
<li>Action to impose visa restrictions on 25 individuals responsible for undermining democracy in Belarus pursuant to Presidential Proclamation 8015, including Belarusian nationals involved in the fatal shooting and beating of two peaceful protesters; security forces involved in the violent dispersal of peaceful protests; regime officials responsible for launching politically-motivated cases against members of the opposition and civil society; and individuals engaging in corrupt practices supporting the Lukashenka regime.</li>
</ul>
<p>Additionally, the Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) is imposing sanctions on Kurchaloi District of the Chechen Republic Branch of the Ministry of Internal Affairs of the Russian Federation, two of its officers, a Kurchaloi District prosecutor, and a district court judge in Moscow, pursuant to the Sergei Magnitsky Rule of Law Accountability Act of 2012.  OFAC is also re-designating Alyaksandr <wbr />Lukashenka for his corrupt practices, and, pursuant to E.O. 13405, designating Galina Lukashenka as a member of Lukashenka’s family.</p>
<p>Under President Putin, Russian authorities have repeatedly targeted human rights advocates, peaceful dissenters, and whistleblowers, and they continue to do so amidst their ruthless war on Ukraine.  The Russian government has failed to take adequate steps to identify, investigate, prosecute, or punish most officials who committed abuses or violations, resulting in a climate of impunity.  Likewise, the Lukashenka regime continues its brutal crackdown on peaceful activists while it intensifies its support to the invasion of Ukraine. We are taking action against this autocratic attack on democracy.  The United States will continue to promote accountability for those who support, enable, and perpetrate human rights abuses in Russia, Ukraine, Belarus, and elsewhere.</p>
<p>For a complete list of today’s Department of the Treasury actions, please see this press release: <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0654" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0654</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States, with support from Allies and partners, is taking action to promote accountability for the Russian and Belarusian governments’ human rights abuses and violations within and outside their borders.  In doing so, we reiterate our condemnation of President Putin’s premeditated, unjustified, and unprovoked war against Ukraine, as well as the Lukashenka regime’s support and facilitation of the Russian Federation’s invasion.  President Putin’s military campaign against Ukraine has caused extensive and needless suffering, many hundreds and likely thousands of civilian casualties, including children, and growing reports of human rights abuses and violations.</p>
<p>At the same time, the Russian government has intensified a crackdown against its own citizens’ freedom of expression, including for members of the press, as well as freedom of association and peaceful assembly.  Today in Russia, those who provide factual reporting on the invasion or criticize Putin face criminal charges. Similarly, the Lukashenka regime in Belarus continues its violent repression against civil society, anti-war protestors, the democratic opposition, independent media, and ordinary Belarusians.</p>
<p>In response, the Department of State is announcing a series of actions to promote accountability for the Russian Federation’s and Government of Belarus’s human rights abuses and violations. These include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Designation of Alyaksandr Lukashenka pursuant to Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2021. Lukashenka was publicly designated for his involvement in gross violations of human rights and significant corruption. Under this authority, Lukashenka and Lukashenka’s immediate family members are ineligible for entry into the United States, to include his wife, Galina Lukashenka, his adult sons, Viktar Lukashenka and Dzmitry Lukashenka, and his minor son.</li>
<li>Designation of 11 senior Russian defense officials by the Department of State pursuant to E.O. 14024.  This includes Viktor Zolotov, the Head of the National Guard of Russia.  Under Zolotov’s leadership, the National Guard has cracked down on Russian citizens who have taken to the streets to protest their government’s brutal campaign in Ukraine. In addition, Zolotov’s troops are responsible for suppressing dissent in occupied areas of Ukraine.  More broadly, the designation of these 11 senior Russian defense leaders continues our imposition of severe costs on Russia’s Ministry of Defense as it pursues its brutal military invasion of Ukraine, which has led to unnecessary casualties and suffering, including the deaths of children. List here: <a href="https://www.state.gov/u-s-announces-sanctions-on-key-members-of-russias-defense-enterprise/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMTUuNTQ5MzU4MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvdS1zLWFubm91bmNlcy1zYW5jdGlvbnMtb24ta2V5LW1lbWJlcnMtb2YtcnVzc2lhcy1kZWZlbnNlLWVudGVycHJpc2UvIn0.2zOCYVpZR_-r0RqZfk2ksnvOg0uNxbNHd6Uo7B9bIJg/s/1039202793/br/128123916353-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1647441876727000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1dH2LbJXV6W4sZToI9AaF5">https://www.state.<wbr />gov/u-s-announces-sanctions-<wbr />on-key-members-of-russias-<wbr />defense-enterprise/</a></li>
<li>A new visa restriction policy under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act that applies to current and former Russian government officials believed to be involved in suppressing dissent in Russia and abroad. Family members of those who fall under the policy will also be ineligible for visas. We have taken our first action pursuant to this new visa authority against 38 individuals, and will continue to implement this policy to demonstrate solidarity with the victims of Russia’s repression.</li>
<li>Designation of two of Russia’s Federal Security Service (FSB) officers in Crimea, Artur Shambazov and <wbr />Andrey Tishenin, pursuant to Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2021.  Shambazov and Tishenin were publicly designated for their involvement in a gross violation of human rights, namely torture.</li>
<li>Action to impose visa restrictions on six individuals who, acting on behalf of the Russian Federation, were involved in attacks on Chechen dissidents living in Europe.  This action is being taken pursuant to the “Khashoggi Ban,” a visa restriction policy the Administration announced last year to counter transnational repression.</li>
<li>Action to impose visa restrictions on 25 individuals responsible for undermining democracy in Belarus pursuant to Presidential Proclamation 8015, including Belarusian nationals involved in the fatal shooting and beating of two peaceful protesters; security forces involved in the violent dispersal of peaceful protests; regime officials responsible for launching politically-motivated cases against members of the opposition and civil society; and individuals engaging in corrupt practices supporting the Lukashenka regime.</li>
</ul>
<p>Additionally, the Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) is imposing sanctions on Kurchaloi District of the Chechen Republic Branch of the Ministry of Internal Affairs of the Russian Federation, two of its officers, a Kurchaloi District prosecutor, and a district court judge in Moscow, pursuant to the Sergei Magnitsky Rule of Law Accountability Act of 2012.  OFAC is also re-designating Alyaksandr <wbr />Lukashenka for his corrupt practices, and, pursuant to E.O. 13405, designating Galina Lukashenka as a member of Lukashenka’s family.</p>
<p>Under President Putin, Russian authorities have repeatedly targeted human rights advocates, peaceful dissenters, and whistleblowers, and they continue to do so amidst their ruthless war on Ukraine.  The Russian government has failed to take adequate steps to identify, investigate, prosecute, or punish most officials who committed abuses or violations, resulting in a climate of impunity.  Likewise, the Lukashenka regime continues its brutal crackdown on peaceful activists while it intensifies its support to the invasion of Ukraine. We are taking action against this autocratic attack on democracy.  The United States will continue to promote accountability for those who support, enable, and perpetrate human rights abuses in Russia, Ukraine, Belarus, and elsewhere.</p>
<p>For a complete list of today’s Department of the Treasury actions, please see this press release: <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0654" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0654</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Commending New Zealand’s New Sanctions Regime</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/commending-new-zealands-new-sanctions-regime/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 01:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the passage of New Zealand’s new sanctions regime, which allows the imposition of sanctions on those responsible for, or associated with, Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. It also gives the New Zealand government the power to sanction individuals and entities that are of economic or strategic relevance to Russia and will ensure Russia cannot use New Zealand to circumvent sanctions imposed by the international community.  Additionally, the law authorizes the imposition of sanctions on those supporting Russia’s invasion, including members of the regime in Belarus. For the first time, New Zealand has extended its sanctions authorities beyond its UN Security Council obligations.</p>
<p>New Zealand’s announcement underscores its commitment to the freedom, territorial integrity, and sovereignty of Ukraine and illustrates New Zealand’s lasting commitment to preserving the rules-based international order.  Together with the international community, we will hold Russia to account for its aggression.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the passage of New Zealand’s new sanctions regime, which allows the imposition of sanctions on those responsible for, or associated with, Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. It also gives the New Zealand government the power to sanction individuals and entities that are of economic or strategic relevance to Russia and will ensure Russia cannot use New Zealand to circumvent sanctions imposed by the international community.  Additionally, the law authorizes the imposition of sanctions on those supporting Russia’s invasion, including members of the regime in Belarus. For the first time, New Zealand has extended its sanctions authorities beyond its UN Security Council obligations.</p>
<p>New Zealand’s announcement underscores its commitment to the freedom, territorial integrity, and sovereignty of Ukraine and illustrates New Zealand’s lasting commitment to preserving the rules-based international order.  Together with the international community, we will hold Russia to account for its aggression.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Croatian Prime Minister Plenkovic</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-croatian-prime-minister-plenkovic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Croatian Prime Minister Andrej Plenkovic.  Secretary Blinken reaffirmed U.S. support for Ukraine in the face of President Putin’s continued war against Ukraine.  The Secretary expressed his deep appreciation for the strong support of Prime Minister Plenkovic and his government for Ukraine, including providing security assistance and accepting refugees, and for Croatia’s active role in NATO.  Secretary Blinken and Prime Minister Plenkovic also discussed the March 10 drone crash in Zagreb.  The Secretary noted Croatia’s critical role in securing the European future of the entire Western Balkans, including Bosnia and Herzegovina.  The Secretary also welcomed the March 17 U.S.-Croatia Strategic Dialogue, which will bring together senior-level interagency teams to review joint efforts to advance shared priorities.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Croatian Prime Minister Andrej Plenkovic.  Secretary Blinken reaffirmed U.S. support for Ukraine in the face of President Putin’s continued war against Ukraine.  The Secretary expressed his deep appreciation for the strong support of Prime Minister Plenkovic and his government for Ukraine, including providing security assistance and accepting refugees, and for Croatia’s active role in NATO.  Secretary Blinken and Prime Minister Plenkovic also discussed the March 10 drone crash in Zagreb.  The Secretary noted Croatia’s critical role in securing the European future of the entire Western Balkans, including Bosnia and Herzegovina.  The Secretary also welcomed the March 17 U.S.-Croatia Strategic Dialogue, which will bring together senior-level interagency teams to review joint efforts to advance shared priorities.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
