<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 13:14:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Senior Official for Public Diplomacy and Public Affairs Hall Godfrey&#8217;s Travel to the United Arab Emirates and Czech Republic</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/senior-official-for-public-diplomacy-and-public-affairs-hall-godfreys-travel-to-the-united-arab-emirates-and-czech-republic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 13:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=315651</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Senior Official for Public Diplomacy and Public Affairs Jennifer Hall Godfrey will travel to the United Arab Emirates and Czech Republic from February 20-26.</p>
<p>In the United Arab Emirates, Senior Official Hall Godfrey will visit the USA Pavilion at Expo 2020 Dubai. She will meet with government officials, and USA Pavilion staff, speakers, and Youth Ambassadors before joining a panel discussion with Emirati diplomats at the Anwar Gargash Diplomatic Academy in Abu Dhabi.</p>
<p>In the Czech Republic, Senior Official Hall Godfrey will meet with employees of Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, think tanks, and nongovernmental organizations, as well as Embassy staff.</p>
<p>For more information, follow @UnderSecPD on Twitter.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Senior Official for Public Diplomacy and Public Affairs Jennifer Hall Godfrey will travel to the United Arab Emirates and Czech Republic from February 20-26.</p>
<p>In the United Arab Emirates, Senior Official Hall Godfrey will visit the USA Pavilion at Expo 2020 Dubai. She will meet with government officials, and USA Pavilion staff, speakers, and Youth Ambassadors before joining a panel discussion with Emirati diplomats at the Anwar Gargash Diplomatic Academy in Abu Dhabi.</p>
<p>In the Czech Republic, Senior Official Hall Godfrey will meet with employees of Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, think tanks, and nongovernmental organizations, as well as Embassy staff.</p>
<p>For more information, follow @UnderSecPD on Twitter.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the 2nd United States-Thailand Energy Policy Dialogue</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-the-2nd-united-states-thailand-energy-policy-dialogue/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 13:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=315647</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and Thailand on the occasion of the 2nd United States-Thailand Energy Policy Dialogue.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>Delegations from Thailand and the United States met in Bangkok for the second United States-Thailand Energy Policy Dialogue on February 17. Thailand’s Permanent Secretary of Energy Kulit Sombatsiri and Bureau of Energy Resources Senior Bureau Official Harry Kamian led the delegations together with government officials and private sector representatives.</p>
<p>The dialogue strengthened the energy partnership between the United States and Thailand in key areas such as energy security, power development, energy transition, clean energy technologies, and energy efficiency. The allies noted their support for constructive engagement between U.S. and Thai private companies in the energy sector.</p>
<p>Thailand and the United States discussed the future of electric vehicles, solar technology and its supply chains, grid modernization, and next-generation energy innovation technologies. These topics align with the national energy policy of both countries, and will support mutual efforts to address climate change.</p>
<p>During the dialogue, Thailand signed the Clean Energy Demand Initiative (CEDI) non-binding Letter of Intent with major companies. CEDI will stimulate clean energy investment projects in Thailand and help achieve shared clean energy goals and ambitious climate targets set at COP26. The United States and Thailand agreed to enhance energy cooperation to spur economic growth and sustainable energy development.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and Thailand on the occasion of the 2nd United States-Thailand Energy Policy Dialogue.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>Delegations from Thailand and the United States met in Bangkok for the second United States-Thailand Energy Policy Dialogue on February 17. Thailand’s Permanent Secretary of Energy Kulit Sombatsiri and Bureau of Energy Resources Senior Bureau Official Harry Kamian led the delegations together with government officials and private sector representatives.</p>
<p>The dialogue strengthened the energy partnership between the United States and Thailand in key areas such as energy security, power development, energy transition, clean energy technologies, and energy efficiency. The allies noted their support for constructive engagement between U.S. and Thai private companies in the energy sector.</p>
<p>Thailand and the United States discussed the future of electric vehicles, solar technology and its supply chains, grid modernization, and next-generation energy innovation technologies. These topics align with the national energy policy of both countries, and will support mutual efforts to address climate change.</p>
<p>During the dialogue, Thailand signed the Clean Energy Demand Initiative (CEDI) non-binding Letter of Intent with major companies. CEDI will stimulate clean energy investment projects in Thailand and help achieve shared clean energy goals and ambitious climate targets set at COP26. The United States and Thailand agreed to enhance energy cooperation to spur economic growth and sustainable energy development.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Gambia’s National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-gambias-national-day-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 05:01:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=315464</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On the behalf of the Government and the people of the United States of America, it is my honor and pleasure to congratulate the people of The Gambia on their 57<sup>th</sup> anniversary of independence.</p>
<p>The people of the United States and The Gambia have many traits in common: belief in democracy, respect for human rights at home and abroad, and a commitment to justice.  I commend The Gambia on its successful election in December and encourage the government to continue the work of the Truth, Reconciliation, and Reparations Commission to heal the wounds of the past and move toward a more just society.</p>
<p>As Gambians around the world celebrate Independence Day this year, please know that your friends and partners in the United States celebrate alongside you and look forward to many celebrations together.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On the behalf of the Government and the people of the United States of America, it is my honor and pleasure to congratulate the people of The Gambia on their 57<sup>th</sup> anniversary of independence.</p>
<p>The people of the United States and The Gambia have many traits in common: belief in democracy, respect for human rights at home and abroad, and a commitment to justice.  I commend The Gambia on its successful election in December and encourage the government to continue the work of the Truth, Reconciliation, and Reparations Commission to heal the wounds of the past and move toward a more just society.</p>
<p>As Gambians around the world celebrate Independence Day this year, please know that your friends and partners in the United States celebrate alongside you and look forward to many celebrations together.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Polish Foreign Minister Rau</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-polish-foreign-minister-rau-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 22:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=315512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Polish Foreign Minister Zbigniew Rau. Secretary Blinken welcomed the Foreign Minister’s engagement in Kyiv and Moscow and expressed his support for Foreign Minister Rau’s initiative to launch a Renewed European Security Dialogue at the OSCE. The Secretary reiterated his commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and determination to deter and defend against further Russian aggression. The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Poland’s assistance with U.S. citizens who are leaving Ukraine.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Polish Foreign Minister Zbigniew Rau. Secretary Blinken welcomed the Foreign Minister’s engagement in Kyiv and Moscow and expressed his support for Foreign Minister Rau’s initiative to launch a Renewed European Security Dialogue at the OSCE. The Secretary reiterated his commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and determination to deter and defend against further Russian aggression. The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Poland’s assistance with U.S. citizens who are leaving Ukraine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with UN Special Envoy for Yemen Grundberg</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-un-special-envoy-for-yemen-grundberg/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 21:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=315484</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with UN Special Envoy for Yemen Hans Grundberg. The Secretary expressed deep concern with the uptick in civilian casualties in Yemen as well as the region and condemned attacks by all parties that lead to escalation in Yemen and extend the conflict. Secretary Blinken stressed the urgent need for de-escalation and for all parties to abide by their obligations under international humanitarian law, including those obligations related to the protection of civilians. The Secretary communicated his support for the UN Special Envoy’s ongoing efforts to develop an inclusive political framework and reiterated that justice and accountability will be key to securing an enduring peace in Yemen. Secretary Blinken welcomed collaboration to advance a durable resolution that ends the conflict in Yemen, improves Yemeni lives, and creates the space for Yemenis to collectively determine their own future. He reiterated that resolving the conflict in Yemen remains a top U.S. foreign policy priority.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with UN Special Envoy for Yemen Hans Grundberg. The Secretary expressed deep concern with the uptick in civilian casualties in Yemen as well as the region and condemned attacks by all parties that lead to escalation in Yemen and extend the conflict. Secretary Blinken stressed the urgent need for de-escalation and for all parties to abide by their obligations under international humanitarian law, including those obligations related to the protection of civilians. The Secretary communicated his support for the UN Special Envoy’s ongoing efforts to develop an inclusive political framework and reiterated that justice and accountability will be key to securing an enduring peace in Yemen. Secretary Blinken welcomed collaboration to advance a durable resolution that ends the conflict in Yemen, improves Yemeni lives, and creates the space for Yemenis to collectively determine their own future. He reiterated that resolving the conflict in Yemen remains a top U.S. foreign policy priority.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken on Russia’s Threat to Peace and Security at the UN Security Council</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-on-russias-threat-to-peace-and-security-at-the-un-security-council/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 17:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=315423</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>New York City, New York</p>
<p>UN Headquarters</p>
<p align="left"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Mr. President, this council was convened today to discuss the implementation of the Minsk Agreements, a goal that we all share, despite Russia’s persistent violations.  These agreements, which were negotiated in 2014 and 2015 and signed by Russia, remain the basis for the peace process to resolve the conflict in eastern Ukraine.</p>
<p>This council’s primary responsibility – the very reason for its creation – is the preservation of peace and security.  As we meet today, the most immediate threat to peace and security is Russia’s looming aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>The stakes go far beyond Ukraine.  This is a moment of peril for the lives and safety of millions of people, as well as for the foundation of the United Nations Charter and the rules-based international order that preserves stability worldwide.  This crisis directly affects every member of this council and every country in the world.</p>
<p>Because the basic principles that sustain peace and security – principles that were enshrined in the wake of two world wars and a Cold War – are under threat.  The principle that one country cannot change the borders of another by force.  The principle that one country cannot dictate another’s choices or policies, or with whom it will associate.  The principle of national sovereignty.</p>
<p>This is the exact kind of crisis that the United Nations – and specifically this Security Council – was created to prevent.</p>
<p>We must address what Russia is doing right now to Ukraine.</p>
<p>Over the past months, without provocation or justification, Russia has amassed more than 150,000 troops around Ukraine’s borders, in Russia, Belarus, occupied Crimea.  Russia says it’s drawing down those forces.  We do not see that happening on the ground.  Our information indicates clearly that these forces – including ground troops, aircraft, ships – are preparing to launch an attack against Ukraine in the coming days.</p>
<p>We don’t know precisely how things will play out, but here’s what the world can expect to see unfold.  In fact, it’s unfolding right now, today, as Russia takes steps down the path to war and reissued the threat of military action.</p>
<p>First, Russia plans to manufacture a pretext for its attack.  This could be a violent event that Russia will blame on Ukraine, or an outrageous accusation that Russia will level against the Ukrainian Government.  We don’t know exactly the form it will take.  It could be a fabricated so-called “terrorist” bombing inside Russia, the invented discovery of a mass grave, a staged drone strike against civilians, or a fake – even a real – attack using chemical weapons.  Russia may describe this event as ethnic cleansing or a genocide, making a mockery of a concept that we in this chamber do not take lightly, nor do I do take lightly based on my family history.</p>
<p>In the past few days, Russian media has already begun to spread some of these false alarms and claims, to maximize public outrage, to lay the groundwork for an invented justification for war. Today, that drumbeat has only intensified in Russia’s state-controlled media.  We’ve heard some of these baseless allegations from Russian-backed speakers here today.</p>
<p>Second, in response to this manufactured provocation, the highest levels of the Russian Government may theatrically convene emergency meetings to address the so-called crisis.  The government will issue proclamations declaring that Russia must respond to defend Russian citizens or ethnic Russians in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Next, the attack is planned to begin.  Russian missiles and bombs will drop across Ukraine.  Communications will be jammed.  Cyberattacks will shut down key Ukrainian institutions.</p>
<p>After that, Russian tanks and soldiers will advance on key targets that have already been identified and mapped out in detailed plans.  We believe these targets include Russia’s capital –Ukraine’s capital, Kyiv, a city of 2.8 million people.</p>
<p>And conventional attacks are not all that Russia plans to inflict upon the people of Ukraine.  We have information that indicates Russia will target specific groups of Ukrainians.</p>
<p>We’ve been warning the Ukrainian Government of all that is coming.  And here today, we are laying it out in great detail, with the hope that by sharing what we know with the world, we can influence Russia to abandon the path of war and choose a different path while there’s still time.</p>
<p>Now, I am mindful that some have called into question our information, recalling previous instances where intelligence ultimately did not bear out.  But let me be clear: I am here today, not to start a war, but to prevent one.  The information I’ve presented here is validated by what we’ve seen unfolding in plain sight before our eyes for months.  And remember that while Russia has repeatedly derided our warnings and alarms as melodrama and nonsense, they have been steadily amassing more than 150,000 troops on Ukraine’s borders, as well as the capabilities to conduct a massive military assault.</p>
<p>It isn’t just us seeing this: Allies and partners see the same thing.  And Russia hasn’t only been hearing from us.  The international chorus has grown louder and louder.</p>
<p>If Russia doesn’t invade Ukraine, then we will be relieved that Russia changed course and proved our predictions wrong.  That would be a far better outcome than the course we’re currently on.  And we will gladly accept any criticism that anyone directs at us.</p>
<p>As President Biden said, this would be a war of choice.  And if Russia makes that choice, we’ve been clear, along with Allies and partners, that our response will be sharp and decisive.  President Biden reiterated that forcefully earlier this week.</p>
<p>There is another choice Russia can still make, if there is any truth to its claim that it is committed to diplomacy.</p>
<p>Diplomacy is the only responsible way to resolve this crisis.  An essential part of this is through implementation of the Minsk agreements, the subject of our session today.</p>
<p>There are a series of commitments that Russia and Ukraine made under Minsk, with the OSCE and the Normandy Format partners involved as well.</p>
<p>If Russia is prepared to sit with the Ukrainian Government and work through the process of implementing these commitments, our friends in France and Germany stand ready to convene senior-level discussions in the Normandy Format to settle these issues.  Ukraine is ready for this.  And we stand fully ready to support the parties.</p>
<p>Progress toward resolving the Donbas crisis through the Minsk Agreements can reinforce the broader discussions on security issues that we’re prepared to engage in with Russia, in coordination with our Allies and partners.</p>
<p>More than three weeks ago, we provided Russia with a paper that detailed concrete, reciprocal steps that we can take in the near term to address our respective concerns and advance the collective security interests of Russia, the United States, and our European partners and allies. This morning, we received a response, which we are evaluating.</p>
<p>Earlier today, I sent a letter to Russia’s Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov proposing that we meet next week in Europe, following on our talks in recent weeks, to discuss the steps that we can take to resolve this crisis without conflict.  We are also proposing meetings of the NATO-Russia Council and the OSCE Permanent Council.</p>
<p>These meetings can pave the way for a summit of key leaders, in the context of de-escalation, to reach understandings on our mutual security concerns.  As lead diplomats for our nations, we have a responsibility to make every effort for diplomacy to succeed, to leave no diplomatic stone unturned.</p>
<p>If Russia is committed to diplomacy, we are presenting every opportunity for it to demonstrate that commitment.</p>
<p>I have no doubt that the response to my remarks here today will be more dismissals from the Russian Government about the United States stoking hysteria or that it has “no plans” to invade Ukraine.</p>
<p>So let me make this simple. The Russian Government can announce today – with no qualification, equivocation, or deflection – that Russia will not invade Ukraine.  State it clearly.  State it plainly to the world.  And then demonstrate it by sending your troops, your tanks, your planes back to their barracks and hangars and sending your diplomats to the negotiating table.</p>
<p>In the coming days, the world will remember that commitment – or the refusal to make it.  I yield the floor.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>New York City, New York</p>
<p>UN Headquarters</p>
<p align="left"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Mr. President, this council was convened today to discuss the implementation of the Minsk Agreements, a goal that we all share, despite Russia’s persistent violations.  These agreements, which were negotiated in 2014 and 2015 and signed by Russia, remain the basis for the peace process to resolve the conflict in eastern Ukraine.</p>
<p>This council’s primary responsibility – the very reason for its creation – is the preservation of peace and security.  As we meet today, the most immediate threat to peace and security is Russia’s looming aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>The stakes go far beyond Ukraine.  This is a moment of peril for the lives and safety of millions of people, as well as for the foundation of the United Nations Charter and the rules-based international order that preserves stability worldwide.  This crisis directly affects every member of this council and every country in the world.</p>
<p>Because the basic principles that sustain peace and security – principles that were enshrined in the wake of two world wars and a Cold War – are under threat.  The principle that one country cannot change the borders of another by force.  The principle that one country cannot dictate another’s choices or policies, or with whom it will associate.  The principle of national sovereignty.</p>
<p>This is the exact kind of crisis that the United Nations – and specifically this Security Council – was created to prevent.</p>
<p>We must address what Russia is doing right now to Ukraine.</p>
<p>Over the past months, without provocation or justification, Russia has amassed more than 150,000 troops around Ukraine’s borders, in Russia, Belarus, occupied Crimea.  Russia says it’s drawing down those forces.  We do not see that happening on the ground.  Our information indicates clearly that these forces – including ground troops, aircraft, ships – are preparing to launch an attack against Ukraine in the coming days.</p>
<p>We don’t know precisely how things will play out, but here’s what the world can expect to see unfold.  In fact, it’s unfolding right now, today, as Russia takes steps down the path to war and reissued the threat of military action.</p>
<p>First, Russia plans to manufacture a pretext for its attack.  This could be a violent event that Russia will blame on Ukraine, or an outrageous accusation that Russia will level against the Ukrainian Government.  We don’t know exactly the form it will take.  It could be a fabricated so-called “terrorist” bombing inside Russia, the invented discovery of a mass grave, a staged drone strike against civilians, or a fake – even a real – attack using chemical weapons.  Russia may describe this event as ethnic cleansing or a genocide, making a mockery of a concept that we in this chamber do not take lightly, nor do I do take lightly based on my family history.</p>
<p>In the past few days, Russian media has already begun to spread some of these false alarms and claims, to maximize public outrage, to lay the groundwork for an invented justification for war. Today, that drumbeat has only intensified in Russia’s state-controlled media.  We’ve heard some of these baseless allegations from Russian-backed speakers here today.</p>
<p>Second, in response to this manufactured provocation, the highest levels of the Russian Government may theatrically convene emergency meetings to address the so-called crisis.  The government will issue proclamations declaring that Russia must respond to defend Russian citizens or ethnic Russians in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Next, the attack is planned to begin.  Russian missiles and bombs will drop across Ukraine.  Communications will be jammed.  Cyberattacks will shut down key Ukrainian institutions.</p>
<p>After that, Russian tanks and soldiers will advance on key targets that have already been identified and mapped out in detailed plans.  We believe these targets include Russia’s capital –Ukraine’s capital, Kyiv, a city of 2.8 million people.</p>
<p>And conventional attacks are not all that Russia plans to inflict upon the people of Ukraine.  We have information that indicates Russia will target specific groups of Ukrainians.</p>
<p>We’ve been warning the Ukrainian Government of all that is coming.  And here today, we are laying it out in great detail, with the hope that by sharing what we know with the world, we can influence Russia to abandon the path of war and choose a different path while there’s still time.</p>
<p>Now, I am mindful that some have called into question our information, recalling previous instances where intelligence ultimately did not bear out.  But let me be clear: I am here today, not to start a war, but to prevent one.  The information I’ve presented here is validated by what we’ve seen unfolding in plain sight before our eyes for months.  And remember that while Russia has repeatedly derided our warnings and alarms as melodrama and nonsense, they have been steadily amassing more than 150,000 troops on Ukraine’s borders, as well as the capabilities to conduct a massive military assault.</p>
<p>It isn’t just us seeing this: Allies and partners see the same thing.  And Russia hasn’t only been hearing from us.  The international chorus has grown louder and louder.</p>
<p>If Russia doesn’t invade Ukraine, then we will be relieved that Russia changed course and proved our predictions wrong.  That would be a far better outcome than the course we’re currently on.  And we will gladly accept any criticism that anyone directs at us.</p>
<p>As President Biden said, this would be a war of choice.  And if Russia makes that choice, we’ve been clear, along with Allies and partners, that our response will be sharp and decisive.  President Biden reiterated that forcefully earlier this week.</p>
<p>There is another choice Russia can still make, if there is any truth to its claim that it is committed to diplomacy.</p>
<p>Diplomacy is the only responsible way to resolve this crisis.  An essential part of this is through implementation of the Minsk agreements, the subject of our session today.</p>
<p>There are a series of commitments that Russia and Ukraine made under Minsk, with the OSCE and the Normandy Format partners involved as well.</p>
<p>If Russia is prepared to sit with the Ukrainian Government and work through the process of implementing these commitments, our friends in France and Germany stand ready to convene senior-level discussions in the Normandy Format to settle these issues.  Ukraine is ready for this.  And we stand fully ready to support the parties.</p>
<p>Progress toward resolving the Donbas crisis through the Minsk Agreements can reinforce the broader discussions on security issues that we’re prepared to engage in with Russia, in coordination with our Allies and partners.</p>
<p>More than three weeks ago, we provided Russia with a paper that detailed concrete, reciprocal steps that we can take in the near term to address our respective concerns and advance the collective security interests of Russia, the United States, and our European partners and allies. This morning, we received a response, which we are evaluating.</p>
<p>Earlier today, I sent a letter to Russia’s Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov proposing that we meet next week in Europe, following on our talks in recent weeks, to discuss the steps that we can take to resolve this crisis without conflict.  We are also proposing meetings of the NATO-Russia Council and the OSCE Permanent Council.</p>
<p>These meetings can pave the way for a summit of key leaders, in the context of de-escalation, to reach understandings on our mutual security concerns.  As lead diplomats for our nations, we have a responsibility to make every effort for diplomacy to succeed, to leave no diplomatic stone unturned.</p>
<p>If Russia is committed to diplomacy, we are presenting every opportunity for it to demonstrate that commitment.</p>
<p>I have no doubt that the response to my remarks here today will be more dismissals from the Russian Government about the United States stoking hysteria or that it has “no plans” to invade Ukraine.</p>
<p>So let me make this simple. The Russian Government can announce today – with no qualification, equivocation, or deflection – that Russia will not invade Ukraine.  State it clearly.  State it plainly to the world.  And then demonstrate it by sending your troops, your tanks, your planes back to their barracks and hangars and sending your diplomats to the negotiating table.</p>
<p>In the coming days, the world will remember that commitment – or the refusal to make it.  I yield the floor.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken to Deliver Remarks at the UN Security Council</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinken-to-deliver-remarks-at-the-un-security-council/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 13:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=315356</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will deliver remarks on Russia&#8217;s threat to peace and security, at a UN Security Council Meeting at 10:00 a.m. EST today, February 17, from UN Headquarters in New York City.</p>
<p align="left">This event will be livestreamed on <a href="http://state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAyMTcuNTM1NTU3NzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi8ifQ.pP_aTeBzW19UU-eUu3L8qxHLS2HURQS8AHWyH-lbji8/s/1006560560/br/126761293013-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1645190312044000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0zBUCDExTaMA39ugFJMfUx">www.state.gov</a> and <a class="external-link" href="https://media.un.org/en/webtv/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://media.un.org/en/webtv/.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p align="left">For further information, please contact the Office of Press Relations at <a href="mailto:PAPressDuty@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PAPressDuty@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will deliver remarks on Russia&#8217;s threat to peace and security, at a UN Security Council Meeting at 10:00 a.m. EST today, February 17, from UN Headquarters in New York City.</p>
<p align="left">This event will be livestreamed on <a href="http://state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAyMTcuNTM1NTU3NzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi8ifQ.pP_aTeBzW19UU-eUu3L8qxHLS2HURQS8AHWyH-lbji8/s/1006560560/br/126761293013-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1645190312044000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0zBUCDExTaMA39ugFJMfUx">www.state.gov</a> and <a class="external-link" href="https://media.un.org/en/webtv/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://media.un.org/en/webtv/.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p align="left">For further information, please contact the Office of Press Relations at <a href="mailto:PAPressDuty@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PAPressDuty@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Estonian Foreign Minister Liimets</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-estonian-foreign-minister-liimets/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 13:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=315351</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met yesterday with Estonian Foreign Minister Eva-Maria Liimets.  Secretary Blinken underscored our strong support for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine in the face of a growing military threat from Russia.  Secretary Blinken reaffirmed U.S. commitment to the security of our NATO Allies and discussed the recently announced U.S. force posture changes to fortify the Alliance’s Eastern Flank.  Both leaders emphasized the importance of close consultation among Allies and partners as we urge Russia to de-escalate tensions and engage seriously in diplomacy.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister Liimets reviewed bilateral and multilateral efforts to strengthen democracies and promote human rights, and emphasized shared support for the Belarusian people’s democratic aspirations.  They also noted the upcoming 100-year anniversary, in July, of U.S.-Estonia diplomatic relations and expressed readiness to deepen our cooperation further in the next 100 years of our partnership.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met yesterday with Estonian Foreign Minister Eva-Maria Liimets.  Secretary Blinken underscored our strong support for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine in the face of a growing military threat from Russia.  Secretary Blinken reaffirmed U.S. commitment to the security of our NATO Allies and discussed the recently announced U.S. force posture changes to fortify the Alliance’s Eastern Flank.  Both leaders emphasized the importance of close consultation among Allies and partners as we urge Russia to de-escalate tensions and engage seriously in diplomacy.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister Liimets reviewed bilateral and multilateral efforts to strengthen democracies and promote human rights, and emphasized shared support for the Belarusian people’s democratic aspirations.  They also noted the upcoming 100-year anniversary, in July, of U.S.-Estonia diplomatic relations and expressed readiness to deepen our cooperation further in the next 100 years of our partnership.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kosovo National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/kosovo-national-day-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 05:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=314936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Kosovo as you celebrate your fourteenth anniversary as a sovereign, independent state.</p>
<p>The enduring partnership between the United States and Kosovo is rooted in our shared democratic values.  As one of the world’s youngest democracies, Kosovo and its citizens are rightly proud of the progress you have made during these 14 years.  For our part, we are proud to support you in this effort.</p>
<p>While Kosovo’s independence and sovereignty are irreversible and inviolable, building resilient democratic and inclusive institutions that deliver for all citizens requires persistence.  The United States stands by Kosovo as it works to build a better future for its citizens.</p>
<p>We look forward to Kosovo rightfully taking its place alongside its neighbors in European and Euro-Atlantic institutions and reiterate our support for the EU-facilitated Dialogue as the way to achieve an agreement on normalized relations centered on mutual recognition.</p>
<p>We remain grateful for Kosovo’s leadership beyond its borders – for your generosity in hosting vulnerable Afghans and your contributions to global security and stability.</p>
<p>I wish peace, prosperity, and good health to the people of Kosovo as you continue your democratic journey, and we further strengthen our steadfast friendship, together.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Kosovo as you celebrate your fourteenth anniversary as a sovereign, independent state.</p>
<p>The enduring partnership between the United States and Kosovo is rooted in our shared democratic values.  As one of the world’s youngest democracies, Kosovo and its citizens are rightly proud of the progress you have made during these 14 years.  For our part, we are proud to support you in this effort.</p>
<p>While Kosovo’s independence and sovereignty are irreversible and inviolable, building resilient democratic and inclusive institutions that deliver for all citizens requires persistence.  The United States stands by Kosovo as it works to build a better future for its citizens.</p>
<p>We look forward to Kosovo rightfully taking its place alongside its neighbors in European and Euro-Atlantic institutions and reiterate our support for the EU-facilitated Dialogue as the way to achieve an agreement on normalized relations centered on mutual recognition.</p>
<p>We remain grateful for Kosovo’s leadership beyond its borders – for your generosity in hosting vulnerable Afghans and your contributions to global security and stability.</p>
<p>I wish peace, prosperity, and good health to the people of Kosovo as you continue your democratic journey, and we further strengthen our steadfast friendship, together.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Canadian Foreign Minister Joly</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-canadian-foreign-minister-joly-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=315104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Canadian Foreign Minister Mélanie Joly. Secretary Blinken discussed the threat of a further Russian invasion of Ukraine and the importance of working with our allies and partners to impose swift, severe costs on Russia in response to any further military aggression by Russia against Ukraine. Secretary Blinken also reiterated U.S. appreciation to Canada for hosting the January ministerial meeting on Haiti. He underscored the importance of the international community contributing to Haiti&#8217;s efforts to improve security and encouraging a Haitian-led process to reach agreement on a political path forward.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Canadian Foreign Minister Mélanie Joly. Secretary Blinken discussed the threat of a further Russian invasion of Ukraine and the importance of working with our allies and partners to impose swift, severe costs on Russia in response to any further military aggression by Russia against Ukraine. Secretary Blinken also reiterated U.S. appreciation to Canada for hosting the January ministerial meeting on Haiti. He underscored the importance of the international community contributing to Haiti&#8217;s efforts to improve security and encouraging a Haitian-led process to reach agreement on a political path forward.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
