<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 22:18:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Timor-Leste Presidential Election</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/timor-leste-presidential-election/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 22:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336497</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We congratulate President-elect José Ramos-Horta on his election as Timor-Leste’s next president and look forward to working with President-elect Ramos-Horta to strengthen the enduring partnership between the United States and Timor-Leste.  Rooted in shared values and interests, our partnership has delivered opportunities to improve the livelihoods of the Timorese people through economic development, public health, security cooperation, and educational exchanges and training.</p>
<p>We commend Timorese authorities, including the Technical Secretariat for Electoral Administration and the National Elections Commission, for administering a free, fair, and transparent election and the hundreds of thousands of Timorese voters who cast their ballots peacefully.  Timor-Leste’s election serves as an inspiration for democracy in Southeast Asia, the Indo-Pacific region, and the world.  This achievement represents another milestone in Timor-Leste’s tremendous work to build and strengthen its robust, vibrant democracy over its nearly 20-year history as an independent nation.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>We congratulate President-elect José Ramos-Horta on his election as Timor-Leste’s next president and look forward to working with President-elect Ramos-Horta to strengthen the enduring partnership between the United States and Timor-Leste.  Rooted in shared values and interests, our partnership has delivered opportunities to improve the livelihoods of the Timorese people through economic development, public health, security cooperation, and educational exchanges and training.</p>
<p>We commend Timorese authorities, including the Technical Secretariat for Electoral Administration and the National Elections Commission, for administering a free, fair, and transparent election and the hundreds of thousands of Timorese voters who cast their ballots peacefully.  Timor-Leste’s election serves as an inspiration for democracy in Southeast Asia, the Indo-Pacific region, and the world.  This achievement represents another milestone in Timor-Leste’s tremendous work to build and strengthen its robust, vibrant democracy over its nearly 20-year history as an independent nation.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Migration Talks with the Government of Cuba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/migration-talks-with-the-government-of-cuba/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 20:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336440</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On April 21, U.S. and Cuban officials met in Washington, D.C. to discuss the implementation of the U.S.-Cuba Migration Accords. These bilateral discussions on migration are generally held semiannually, reflecting a commitment by both countries to regularly review the implementation of the Accords. Deputy Assistant Secretary for Western Hemisphere Affairs Emily Mendrala led the U.S. interagency delegation, and Cuba’s Vice Foreign Minister Carlos Fernandez de Cossio led the Cuban delegation. These migration talks provide an opportunity for discussions on mutual implementation of the Migration Accords (comprised of a series of bilateral agreements between the United States and Cuba done in 1984, 1994, 1995, and 2017). The U.S. delegation highlighted areas of successful cooperation on migration, while also identifying issues that have been obstacles to fulfilling the goals of the Accords. Engaging in these talks underscores our commitment to pursuing constructive discussions with the Government of Cuba where appropriate to advance U.S. interests. These discussions represent the first Migration Accord talks between the United States and Cuba since 2018.</p>
<p>The United States also addressed consular services at U.S. Embassy Havana, to include resumption of immigrant visa services on a limited basis starting in May, current American citizen services, and current issuance of emergency non-immigrant visas. Enabling safe, legal, and orderly migration between Cuba and the United States remains a mutual interest between the United States and Cuba and is consistent with U.S. interests in fostering family reunification and promoting greater respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms in Cuba.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On April 21, U.S. and Cuban officials met in Washington, D.C. to discuss the implementation of the U.S.-Cuba Migration Accords. These bilateral discussions on migration are generally held semiannually, reflecting a commitment by both countries to regularly review the implementation of the Accords. Deputy Assistant Secretary for Western Hemisphere Affairs Emily Mendrala led the U.S. interagency delegation, and Cuba’s Vice Foreign Minister Carlos Fernandez de Cossio led the Cuban delegation. These migration talks provide an opportunity for discussions on mutual implementation of the Migration Accords (comprised of a series of bilateral agreements between the United States and Cuba done in 1984, 1994, 1995, and 2017). The U.S. delegation highlighted areas of successful cooperation on migration, while also identifying issues that have been obstacles to fulfilling the goals of the Accords. Engaging in these talks underscores our commitment to pursuing constructive discussions with the Government of Cuba where appropriate to advance U.S. interests. These discussions represent the first Migration Accord talks between the United States and Cuba since 2018.</p>
<p>The United States also addressed consular services at U.S. Embassy Havana, to include resumption of immigrant visa services on a limited basis starting in May, current American citizen services, and current issuance of emergency non-immigrant visas. Enabling safe, legal, and orderly migration between Cuba and the United States remains a mutual interest between the United States and Cuba and is consistent with U.S. interests in fostering family reunification and promoting greater respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms in Cuba.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Suspension of Russia’s Permanent Observer Status at the Organization of American States</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/suspension-of-russias-permanent-observer-status-at-the-organization-of-american-states/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 20:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336433</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Today, the United States welcomes the adoption of a resolution at the Organization of American States (OAS) suspending Russia as a Permanent Observer to that institution.  With the passage of this resolution, OAS member states demonstrated that we do not stand on the sidelines in the face of the Russian government’s violations of international humanitarian law and human rights abuses.  Our Hemisphere stands with Ukraine.</p>
<p>The Kremlin’s inhumanity in its premeditated, unprovoked, unjust war against Ukraine is horrifically clear.   Deaths and destruction mount daily.  More than 10 million Ukrainian citizens and others have been uprooted by the Kremlin’s coldblooded aggression.  On a global scale, Putin’s senseless war of choice has hurt economies and threatened the food security of the world’s most vulnerable.  As President Biden stated, “An overwhelming majority of nations recognize that Putin is not only attacking Ukraine, he is attacking the very foundations of global peace and security.”</p>
<p>The Russian government’s brutal attack against Ukraine’s territorial integrity and sovereignty demonstrates the Kremlin’s utter contempt for the values of democracy and respect for human rights, values that form the bedrock of the Inter American system.  We commend the governments of Antigua and Barbuda and Guatemala for leading the adoption of the resolution, and all the governments that supported it.</p>
<p>The OAS action today sends a clear message to the Kremlin.   The overwhelming number of countries in the Americas called upon the Kremlin to end its unconscionable war of choice, withdraw its forces, and comply with international law.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Today, the United States welcomes the adoption of a resolution at the Organization of American States (OAS) suspending Russia as a Permanent Observer to that institution.  With the passage of this resolution, OAS member states demonstrated that we do not stand on the sidelines in the face of the Russian government’s violations of international humanitarian law and human rights abuses.  Our Hemisphere stands with Ukraine.</p>
<p>The Kremlin’s inhumanity in its premeditated, unprovoked, unjust war against Ukraine is horrifically clear.   Deaths and destruction mount daily.  More than 10 million Ukrainian citizens and others have been uprooted by the Kremlin’s coldblooded aggression.  On a global scale, Putin’s senseless war of choice has hurt economies and threatened the food security of the world’s most vulnerable.  As President Biden stated, “An overwhelming majority of nations recognize that Putin is not only attacking Ukraine, he is attacking the very foundations of global peace and security.”</p>
<p>The Russian government’s brutal attack against Ukraine’s territorial integrity and sovereignty demonstrates the Kremlin’s utter contempt for the values of democracy and respect for human rights, values that form the bedrock of the Inter American system.  We commend the governments of Antigua and Barbuda and Guatemala for leading the adoption of the resolution, and all the governments that supported it.</p>
<p>The OAS action today sends a clear message to the Kremlin.   The overwhelming number of countries in the Americas called upon the Kremlin to end its unconscionable war of choice, withdraw its forces, and comply with international law.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary Fernandez’s Travel to Chile </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-fernandezs-travel-to-chile/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State for Economic Growth, Energy, and Environment Jose W. Fernandez will travel to Santiago, Chile, April 21-23 to engage with government officials, business leaders, and civil society, in support of regional trade and investment objectives, climate and environment programs, and pandemic response and preparedness.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Fernandez will meet with officials from the Chilean Ministries of Foreign Affairs, Health, and Mining, and with private sector representatives to discuss our joint COVID-19 pandemic response, regional economic recovery, and ways to deepen our bilateral economic ties to promote increased economic inclusion and prosperity for U.S. and Chilean citizens. The Under Secretary will also meet with the Chilean Minister of Environment and Chilean environmental organizations to discuss additional opportunities for U.S.-Chilean collaboration on combatting the climate crisis and supporting sustainable trade and development. On Earth Day, he will also meet with Economic Commission for Latin America and the Caribbean Acting Executive Secretary Mario Cimoli.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State for Economic Growth, Energy, and Environment Jose W. Fernandez will travel to Santiago, Chile, April 21-23 to engage with government officials, business leaders, and civil society, in support of regional trade and investment objectives, climate and environment programs, and pandemic response and preparedness.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Fernandez will meet with officials from the Chilean Ministries of Foreign Affairs, Health, and Mining, and with private sector representatives to discuss our joint COVID-19 pandemic response, regional economic recovery, and ways to deepen our bilateral economic ties to promote increased economic inclusion and prosperity for U.S. and Chilean citizens. The Under Secretary will also meet with the Chilean Minister of Environment and Chilean environmental organizations to discuss additional opportunities for U.S.-Chilean collaboration on combatting the climate crisis and supporting sustainable trade and development. On Earth Day, he will also meet with Economic Commission for Latin America and the Caribbean Acting Executive Secretary Mario Cimoli.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary Donfried’s Travel to the Western Balkans</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-donfrieds-travel-to-the-western-balkans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336402</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs Dr. Karen Donfried will travel to the Western Balkans from April 25 to 29, with stops in Albania, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Kosovo, Montenegro, North Macedonia, and Serbia.</p>
<p>On April 25, she will thank Kosovo for providing refuge to Afghans and Ukrainians, encourage work on reforms for democratic consolidation and integration into European and Euro-Atlantic institutions, and review prospects for progress in the U.S.-supported, EU-facilitated Dialogue with Serbia toward an agreement on normalized relations centered on mutual recognition.</p>
<p>She will travel to Serbia on April 26 to urge Serbia to advance reforms for its European integration, enhance regional stability and prosperity, discuss opportunities for further energy diversification, and broaden our bilateral security and economic ties.  She will reiterate the need for Serbia and Kosovo to reengage in the EU-facilitated Dialogue.</p>
<p>On April 27, in Bosnia and Herzegovina (BiH), Dr. Donfried will encourage officials to resume institutional participation at all levels of government to advance functionality and common-sense reforms for greater prosperity and for BiH to obtain EU candidate status.  She will urge BiH to hold fall elections on time and make progress in fighting endemic corruption.</p>
<p>In North Macedonia on April 28, she will meet with government leaders to signal our strong support for North Macedonia’s EU accession negotiations and thank them for their ongoing assistance to Ukraine. She will urge NATO’s newest member to continue close cooperation on a range of regional, security, and defense issues to promote democracy and regional stability.</p>
<p>On April 28 she will commemorate 100 years of U.S.-Albanian diplomatic relations and thank Albania for our partnership on the United Nations Security Council and for its commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Russian aggression.  She will also underscore our strong support for Albania&#8217;s EU accession and regional economic integration, as well as emphasize the need to fully implement justice reform and combat corruption.</p>
<p>Dr. Donfried will travel to Montenegro on April 29, where she will highlight U.S. support for and the need to accelerate work on Montenegro’s Euro-Atlantic path and EU accession, strengthening NATO membership, and on supporting shared values, including tackling corruption.  She will also thank Montenegro for joining EU sanctions on Russia in support of Ukraine, and for providing humanitarian and security assistance, as well as for closing its airspace to Russian aircraft.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs Dr. Karen Donfried will travel to the Western Balkans from April 25 to 29, with stops in Albania, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Kosovo, Montenegro, North Macedonia, and Serbia.</p>
<p>On April 25, she will thank Kosovo for providing refuge to Afghans and Ukrainians, encourage work on reforms for democratic consolidation and integration into European and Euro-Atlantic institutions, and review prospects for progress in the U.S.-supported, EU-facilitated Dialogue with Serbia toward an agreement on normalized relations centered on mutual recognition.</p>
<p>She will travel to Serbia on April 26 to urge Serbia to advance reforms for its European integration, enhance regional stability and prosperity, discuss opportunities for further energy diversification, and broaden our bilateral security and economic ties.  She will reiterate the need for Serbia and Kosovo to reengage in the EU-facilitated Dialogue.</p>
<p>On April 27, in Bosnia and Herzegovina (BiH), Dr. Donfried will encourage officials to resume institutional participation at all levels of government to advance functionality and common-sense reforms for greater prosperity and for BiH to obtain EU candidate status.  She will urge BiH to hold fall elections on time and make progress in fighting endemic corruption.</p>
<p>In North Macedonia on April 28, she will meet with government leaders to signal our strong support for North Macedonia’s EU accession negotiations and thank them for their ongoing assistance to Ukraine. She will urge NATO’s newest member to continue close cooperation on a range of regional, security, and defense issues to promote democracy and regional stability.</p>
<p>On April 28 she will commemorate 100 years of U.S.-Albanian diplomatic relations and thank Albania for our partnership on the United Nations Security Council and for its commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Russian aggression.  She will also underscore our strong support for Albania&#8217;s EU accession and regional economic integration, as well as emphasize the need to fully implement justice reform and combat corruption.</p>
<p>Dr. Donfried will travel to Montenegro on April 29, where she will highlight U.S. support for and the need to accelerate work on Montenegro’s Euro-Atlantic path and EU accession, strengthening NATO membership, and on supporting shared values, including tackling corruption.  She will also thank Montenegro for joining EU sanctions on Russia in support of Ukraine, and for providing humanitarian and security assistance, as well as for closing its airspace to Russian aircraft.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Third Senior-Level International Partners Meeting on Haiti</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/third-senior-level-international-partners-meeting-on-haiti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336396</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs, Brian A. Nichols, attended a senior-level international partners meeting on Haiti on April 21.  Hosted by France, this meeting convened international partner countries and international organizations for the third time in the past four months in support of progress on the challenges facing Haiti.  Participants encouraged political accord among Haitian actors so elections can take place as soon as conditions permit.</p>
<p>On April 1, the United States announced it would partner with Haiti through the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability, which complements our existing programming in Haiti.  As the international community encourages Haitian political actors, civil society, and other stakeholders to find consensus and reach a political accord, this is an opportune time for coordinating future support for security, good governance, democratic institutions, and elections.</p>
<p>This meeting also reaffirms our efforts in providing advisory support, training, and other resources to the Haitian National Police (HNP).  In addition to deploying additional trainers and refurbishing HNP training facilities, the United States has delivered 60 new vehicles to the HNP.  The United States is working with HNP leadership to develop an elite unit capable of high-impact arrests and anti-gang operations, as well as expand its community policing efforts to regain the trust of citizens in gang-affected neighborhoods.</p>
<p>We commend our partners who have also contributed to building the operational capacity of the HNP.  We continue to work with international partners and organizations to support Haiti’s response to complex security challenges.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs, Brian A. Nichols, attended a senior-level international partners meeting on Haiti on April 21.  Hosted by France, this meeting convened international partner countries and international organizations for the third time in the past four months in support of progress on the challenges facing Haiti.  Participants encouraged political accord among Haitian actors so elections can take place as soon as conditions permit.</p>
<p>On April 1, the United States announced it would partner with Haiti through the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability, which complements our existing programming in Haiti.  As the international community encourages Haitian political actors, civil society, and other stakeholders to find consensus and reach a political accord, this is an opportune time for coordinating future support for security, good governance, democratic institutions, and elections.</p>
<p>This meeting also reaffirms our efforts in providing advisory support, training, and other resources to the Haitian National Police (HNP).  In addition to deploying additional trainers and refurbishing HNP training facilities, the United States has delivered 60 new vehicles to the HNP.  The United States is working with HNP leadership to develop an elite unit capable of high-impact arrests and anti-gang operations, as well as expand its community policing efforts to regain the trust of citizens in gang-affected neighborhoods.</p>
<p>We commend our partners who have also contributed to building the operational capacity of the HNP.  We continue to work with international partners and organizations to support Haiti’s response to complex security challenges.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with French, German, Italian, and UK Counterparts</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-french-german-italian-and-uk-counterparts-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with French MFA Secretary General Francois Delattre, German MFA State Secretary Andreas Michaelis, Italian MFA Secretary General Ettore Sequi, and UK Minister of State for Europe and North America James Cleverly. Deputy Secretary Sherman condemned Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war of choice against Ukraine and its brutal tactics, including egregious atrocities. The participants discussed the importance of providing further military and humanitarian aid to Ukraine and to assist the millions who have been forced to leave their homes. They also discussed the imposition of additional sanctions and other economic measures to hold the Russian Federation accountable. All expressed concern over food security due to Russia’s war and pledged to work together to find solutions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with French MFA Secretary General Francois Delattre, German MFA State Secretary Andreas Michaelis, Italian MFA Secretary General Ettore Sequi, and UK Minister of State for Europe and North America James Cleverly. Deputy Secretary Sherman condemned Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war of choice against Ukraine and its brutal tactics, including egregious atrocities. The participants discussed the importance of providing further military and humanitarian aid to Ukraine and to assist the millions who have been forced to leave their homes. They also discussed the imposition of additional sanctions and other economic measures to hold the Russian Federation accountable. All expressed concern over food security due to Russia’s war and pledged to work together to find solutions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opening of U.S.-Czech Republic Defense Cooperation Agreement Negotiations</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/opening-of-u-s-czech-republic-defense-cooperation-agreement-negotiations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 16:17:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes <wbr />Czech Defense Minister Jana Černochová’s announcement today to begin negotiating a bilateral Defense Cooperation Agreement. When concluded, this agreement will deepen our close security partnership, further strengthen cooperation in NATO operations, and together, contribute to continued growth in Transatlantic security.</p>
<p>The agreement builds on the provisions of the NATO Status of Forces Agreement (SOFA) and is similar to other bilateral agreements the United States has concluded with other NATO Allies, including many of the Czech Republic’s neighbors along NATO’s Eastern Flank.  This agreement, when concluded, will help create an overarching framework to codify already existing cooperation between our two militaries, formalizing procedures, and providing a more transparent, predictable, and robust framework for both bilateral and enhanced NATO cooperation.</p>
<p>Our alliances are a tremendous source of American strength.  Since 1993, the United States and the Czech Republic have worked closely together on a wide range of issues important to both countries, the NATO Alliance, and the world.  Opening these consultations with the Czech Republic reflects our commitment to reaffirming and reinvigorating America’s alliances to meet common security challenges while protecting shared interests and values.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes <wbr />Czech Defense Minister Jana Černochová’s announcement today to begin negotiating a bilateral Defense Cooperation Agreement. When concluded, this agreement will deepen our close security partnership, further strengthen cooperation in NATO operations, and together, contribute to continued growth in Transatlantic security.</p>
<p>The agreement builds on the provisions of the NATO Status of Forces Agreement (SOFA) and is similar to other bilateral agreements the United States has concluded with other NATO Allies, including many of the Czech Republic’s neighbors along NATO’s Eastern Flank.  This agreement, when concluded, will help create an overarching framework to codify already existing cooperation between our two militaries, formalizing procedures, and providing a more transparent, predictable, and robust framework for both bilateral and enhanced NATO cooperation.</p>
<p>Our alliances are a tremendous source of American strength.  Since 1993, the United States and the Czech Republic have worked closely together on a wide range of issues important to both countries, the NATO Alliance, and the world.  Opening these consultations with the Czech Republic reflects our commitment to reaffirming and reinvigorating America’s alliances to meet common security challenges while protecting shared interests and values.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Yemeni Presidential Leadership Council President Al-Alimi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-yemeni-presidential-leadership-council-president-al-alimi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 16:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336316</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Yemeni Presidential Leadership Council President Dr. Rashad al-Alimi.  Secretary Blinken congratulated President al-Alimi on his new position and welcomed the gathering in Aden this week of the Council, Cabinet, House of Representatives, and Shura Council.  The Secretary underscored the importance of an effective and transparent government that advances efforts to end the Yemeni conflict and protects human rights.</p>
<p>The Secretary reaffirmed U.S. support for the ongoing truce and the opportunity to provide relief to Yemenis by easing the movement of people and goods, including fuel.  He further stressed the importance of opening roads to Taiz and other areas.  The Secretary underscored the need to seize the momentum from these positive developments to secure a lasting ceasefire and a comprehensive peace process.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Yemeni Presidential Leadership Council President Dr. Rashad al-Alimi.  Secretary Blinken congratulated President al-Alimi on his new position and welcomed the gathering in Aden this week of the Council, Cabinet, House of Representatives, and Shura Council.  The Secretary underscored the importance of an effective and transparent government that advances efforts to end the Yemeni conflict and protects human rights.</p>
<p>The Secretary reaffirmed U.S. support for the ongoing truce and the opportunity to provide relief to Yemenis by easing the movement of people and goods, including fuel.  He further stressed the importance of opening roads to Taiz and other areas.  The Secretary underscored the need to seize the momentum from these positive developments to secure a lasting ceasefire and a comprehensive peace process.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Slovenian Prime Minister Janša</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-slovenian-prime-minister-jansa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 16:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=336307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Slovenian Prime Minister Janez Janša.  Secretary Blinken thanked Slovenia for its outspoken support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and emphasized the need for robust security assistance in response to Russia’s brutal war.  Secretary Blinken condemned the horrific atrocities committed by Russia’s forces in its unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine and stressed the need to hold Moscow accountable.  Secretary Blinken and Prime Minister Janša discussed Slovenia’s candidacy to the UN Security Council for 2024-2025, and the Secretary repeated the United States’ belief that Slovenia is a very well qualified candidate that, if elected, would be a credible voice in contributing to the maintenance of international peace and security.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Slovenian Prime Minister Janez Janša.  Secretary Blinken thanked Slovenia for its outspoken support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and emphasized the need for robust security assistance in response to Russia’s brutal war.  Secretary Blinken condemned the horrific atrocities committed by Russia’s forces in its unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine and stressed the need to hold Moscow accountable.  Secretary Blinken and Prime Minister Janša discussed Slovenia’s candidacy to the UN Security Council for 2024-2025, and the Secretary repeated the United States’ belief that Slovenia is a very well qualified candidate that, if elected, would be a credible voice in contributing to the maintenance of international peace and security.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
