<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 20:29:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Israeli Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Lapid</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-israeli-foreign-minister-and-alternate-prime-minister-lapid-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 20:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=353846</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Israeli Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Yair Lapid regarding the dissolution of the Knesset. Secretary Blinken underscored our respect for democratic processes and reiterated our unwavering commitment to the strong U.S.-Israel strategic relationship. The Secretary emphasized our continuing close coordination on regional and global issues and noted President Biden looks forward to his visit to Israel next month.</p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Israeli Foreign Minister and Alternate Prime Minister Yair Lapid regarding the dissolution of the Knesset. Secretary Blinken underscored our respect for democratic processes and reiterated our unwavering commitment to the strong U.S.-Israel strategic relationship. The Secretary emphasized our continuing close coordination on regional and global issues and noted President Biden looks forward to his visit to Israel next month.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Briefing on the United States&#8217; Updated Anti-Personnel Landmine Policy</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-on-the-united-states-updated-anti-personnel-landmine-policy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ambassador Bonnie Denise Jenkins, Under Secretary for Arms Control and International Security, Stanley L. Brown, Principal Deputy Assistant SecretaryBureau of Political-Military Affairs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 18:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=353757</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Ambassador Bonnie Denise Jenkins, Under Secretary for Arms Control and International Security</p>
<p>Stanley L. Brown, Principal Deputy Assistant SecretaryBureau of Political-Military Affairs</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thanks very much and good morning, everyone, and thanks for joining this call.  We’re pleased to have an opportunity to speak to the changes that we’ve announced today to U.S. anti-personnel landmine policy.  As a reminder, this call is on the record, but it is embargoed until the conclusion of the call.</p>
<p>We have two speakers with us this morning.  You’ll first hear from Bonnie Jenkins, Dr. Bonnie Jenkins.  She is our Under Secretary for Arms Control and International Security.  We also have on the line with us Stan Brown.  He is the Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary in our Bureau of Political and Military Affairs.</p>
<p>So without further ado, I will turn it over to Under Secretary Jenkins to kick us off.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>UNDER SECRETARY JENKINS:</strong>  Great.  Thank you, Ned.</p>
<p>Curtailing the use of landmines worldwide was a commitment that President Biden made as a candidate, and I’m extremely pleased to highlight the White House’s announcement today regarding the new anti-personnel landmine policy that achieves just what President Biden had promised.</p>
<p>The United States new policy on anti-personnel landmines is centered on people, the communities and the individuals around the world who seek peace and security.  It is a tenet of our humanitarian demining activities.  Our annual report, <em>To Walk the Earth in Safety</em>, which I rolled out in April, is a great reminder of the United States’ global leadership, and I strongly encourage you to read it if you have not yet done so.</p>
<p>I know that you have a lot of questions about today’s White House announcement, so I will ask my colleague Stan Brown, Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary at the Bureau of Political-Military Affairs, to speak more about it.</p>
<p>Over to you, Stan.</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:</strong>  Thank you, Under Secretary Jenkins.  I just want to take a moment to echo Under Secretary Jenkins’s comments and reiterate the importance of today’s announcement, which follows through on President Biden’s commitment to curtail the use of landmines worldwide.</p>
<p>After conducting a comprehensive policy review, the administration has announced a new U.S. policy to limit the use of anti-personnel landmines and align the United States’ policy and practice with key provisions of the Ottawa Convention for all activities outside the context of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>As a result of the decision, the United States will not develop, produce, or acquire anti-personnel landmines, not export or transfer anti-personnel landmines except when necessary for activities related to mine destruction or removal and for the purpose of destruction.  They will not use anti-personnel landmines outside the Korean Peninsula, they will not assist, encourage, or induce anyone outside the context of the Korean Peninsula to engage in activity that would be prohibited by the Ottawa Convention, and undertake to destroy anti-personnel landmines and their stockpiles not required for the defense of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>We will continue to pursue materiel and operational solutions that would be compliant with and ultimately allow the United States to accede to the Ottawa Convention, while we at the same ensure our ability to meet our alliance commitments.</p>
<p>The administration’s actions today are in a sharp contrast to Russia’s actions in Ukraine, where there’s compelling evidence that Russian forces are using explosive munitions, including landmines, in an irresponsible manner which is causing extensive harm to civilians and damage to vital civilian infrastructure there.</p>
<p>Lastly, just in a – here at – the United States is proud to lead the world in conventional weapons destruction.  We’ve invested more than 4.2 billion in more than 100 countries since 1993 to promote international peace and security through our conventional weapons destruction programs.  We’ll continue this important work and remain committed to continuing partnerships to address the humanitarian impacts of anti-personnel landmines.</p>
<p>With that just kind of as an opening statement, I’d be happy to take any questions from the group.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thanks very much.  Operator, if you wouldn’t mind repeating the instructions to ask a question.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And once again, for any questions or comments, you may queue up by pressing 1 and then 0.  That’s 1 and then 0 for any questions or comments.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Great.  We’ll start with the line of Shaun Tandon, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.  And your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Thanks for doing this.  Nice to hear from you, Bonnie and Stan, and Ned of course.</p>
<p>Could I ask you about – of course, you mentioned Russia.  China as well, as far as I know, is not part of the Ottawa Treaty.  How much do you expect to press other countries to also give up their landmines?  Is this going to become more of a diplomatic priority?  And could I also ask you a bit more about the Korean Peninsula and the reason for this continued exception, as it was under the Obama administration?  Is it because of the real threat of North Korea, the threats there?  Is it also because of that the ROK really has control over the landmines there?  Could you explain the reasoning behind continuing that exception?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:</strong>  All right.  So first of all, to address the Korea exception, that’s owing to our specific defense responsibilities there and our defense partnership.  The – first of all, the United States does not maintain any minefields in Korea or on the DMZ.  They’re all owned by the Republic of Korea.  We have a responsibility for defense of South Korea.  With the requirements of the Ottawa Convention, where we can’t assist, encourage, or induce anyone to use landmines, we cannot meet the treaty obligations there due to those defense requirements.  So in that regard, we are basically falling back to the Obama administration policies to make sure that we can meet our requirements with Korea in that regard.</p>
<p>In the – in regards to the requirements of the convention, we are basically aligning ourselves with – basically it’s with Article 1 of the Ottawa Convention and the principles that have been laid out in the fact sheets and kind of the discussion points that we’ve laid out here.  We will be meeting those requirements as – everywhere in the world except for on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Jennifer Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>One moment.  And your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Thanks for doing this.  I just want to be clear whether today’s action fully returns us to the Obama-era policy of landmine usage, and does this direct the Defense Department to destruct landmines in its possession?  And also, you mentioned Russia.  How much of an impetus was the war in Ukraine on finally making this change to the Trump-era policy?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:</strong>  So part of the – so as the policy is being put in place, basically we’re not going to develop or produce or acquire anti-personnel landmines; we’re not going to export or transfer anti-personnel landmines; we’re not going to use them outside the Korean Peninsula.  We would – part of the policy is also to undertake to destroy all anti-personnel stockpiles not required for the defense of Korea, Republic of Korea.  And again, we would not assist, encourage, or induce anyone outside the context of the Korean Peninsula to engage in any activity that would be prohibited by the convention.</p>
<p>In that regard – I’m sorry, could you repeat the second part of that question?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  I believe it was whether there – it would require the destruction of any anti-personnel landmines.</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:</strong>  Right, and we said the policy does undertake to destroy all anti-personnel landmines in stockpiles not required for the defense of the Republic of Korea.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll go to the line of Missy Ryan, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Do you all hear me?</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Okay.  Thanks.  Thanks very much for doing this.  And I just wanted to get an idea from the officials who are briefing – can you give us an idea of how far along the United States is in developing alternate weapons that could be employed in the Korean Peninsula along the DMZ to allow the United States to accede to the Ottawa Convention?  I haven’t been able to get a sense of whether those technologies are even in development, whether they’re close to being able to be fielded, or anything like that.   Any sort of context on that would be helpful.  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:</strong>  I can tell you that it’s being worked on, but I would have to defer you to the Department of Defense for the specific acquisition and operational capabilities of future devices.</p>
<p>The – going back to the last question as far as the Ukraine war being the impetus for the decision.  The decision has been under review for – since the Biden administration in January of 2021.  We have just reached the conclusion, and the President’s been able to make the announcement today.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Chris Megerian, Associated Press.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, everybody.  So a clarification question on the potential destruction of landmines that are currently in the U.S. stockpile.  Number one, how many landmines does the U.S. have in its stockpile?  Number two, are all of them deemed necessary to defend the Korean Peninsula?  Do we not plan to destroy any of those?</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:</strong>  The estimate of landmines in the stockpile is approximately three million.  In that regard, we – I would defer to DOD for what their operational requirements would be for what would be needed for defense of Korea.  And again, the policy states to basically look to undertake to destroy all anti-personnel landmines not needed for the defense of the Republic of Korea.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Daphne Psaledakis.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Also just a point of clarification.  Could you say when the U.S. last used anti-personnel landmines?</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:</strong>  The United States last used anti-personnel landmines in 1991 during the Gulf War.  There was one single incident of one munition being used in the 2002 timeframe in Afghanistan.  But otherwise, the United States has not used landmines in – anti-personnel landmines in any significant way since 1991.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We have time for a couple of final questions.  Anton La Guardia.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you very much.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yes, please go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Can you just clarify whether Ukraine uses landmines and how the policy not to assist, induce other countries to use landmines can be aligned with the policy of helping Ukraine to win the war?</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:  </strong>Ukraine is a – actually a party to the Ottawa Convention, and cannot use landmines that are not – do not comply with the convention themselves.  So in itself, Ukraine is not using landmines, and we have not provided landmines to Ukraine that aren’t compliant with the Ottawa Convention.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll go to the line of Hye Jun Seo from Radio Free Asia.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hello, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Yes.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, thanks for taking my question.  Just – follow-up on the Korean Peninsula. Was there any update on the numbers of the mines within the country?  And how concerned is the DOS on the possible incidents and casualties on the Korean Peninsula due to the extensive minefield?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:  </strong>The United States does not main<sup><a id="ftn1ref"></a><a href="#ftn1"></a></sup> any of the minefields in the Republic of Korea, so I would have to defer you to the Republic of Korea Government to get any numbers on the number of mines and the incidents in the minefields there.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>And we’ll take a final question from Oskar Gorzynski, Polish Press Agency.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi.  I was – I wanted to clarify something because the U.S. has – sorry, as I can remember – transferred some landmines to Ukraine, the Claymore mines.  How are – how is that compliant with the Ottawa Convention?  Can you explain that?</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:  </strong>Yeah.<strong>  </strong>The – basically, the anti-personnel landmine in the Ottawa Convention policies are related to landmines that are exploded with the contact or presence of an individual.  The Claymore mines that were transferred by the U.S. Government to Ukraine are command-detonated with a person in the loop who can actually detonate them, which reduces the impact that landmines – that type of landline, which is Ottawa-compliant, has to civilian populations.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Terrific.  Well, that concludes this call.  Just a reminder this call was on the record.  You heard from Dr. Bonnie Jenkins, our under secretary for arms control and international security, as well as Stan Brown, our principal deputy assistant secretary in the Bureau of Political and Military Affairs.  With that, the call is concluded and the embargo is lifted.  Thanks, everyone, for dialing in, and thanks very much to Dr. Jenkins and PDAS Brown.</p>
<hr />
<p><a id="ftn1"></a><a href="#ftn1ref"></a> maintain</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ambassador Bonnie Denise Jenkins, Under Secretary for Arms Control and International Security</p>
<p>Stanley L. Brown, Principal Deputy Assistant SecretaryBureau of Political-Military Affairs</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thanks very much and good morning, everyone, and thanks for joining this call.  We’re pleased to have an opportunity to speak to the changes that we’ve announced today to U.S. anti-personnel landmine policy.  As a reminder, this call is on the record, but it is embargoed until the conclusion of the call.</p>
<p>We have two speakers with us this morning.  You’ll first hear from Bonnie Jenkins, Dr. Bonnie Jenkins.  She is our Under Secretary for Arms Control and International Security.  We also have on the line with us Stan Brown.  He is the Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary in our Bureau of Political and Military Affairs.</p>
<p>So without further ado, I will turn it over to Under Secretary Jenkins to kick us off.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>UNDER SECRETARY JENKINS:</strong>  Great.  Thank you, Ned.</p>
<p>Curtailing the use of landmines worldwide was a commitment that President Biden made as a candidate, and I’m extremely pleased to highlight the White House’s announcement today regarding the new anti-personnel landmine policy that achieves just what President Biden had promised.</p>
<p>The United States new policy on anti-personnel landmines is centered on people, the communities and the individuals around the world who seek peace and security.  It is a tenet of our humanitarian demining activities.  Our annual report, <em>To Walk the Earth in Safety</em>, which I rolled out in April, is a great reminder of the United States’ global leadership, and I strongly encourage you to read it if you have not yet done so.</p>
<p>I know that you have a lot of questions about today’s White House announcement, so I will ask my colleague Stan Brown, Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary at the Bureau of Political-Military Affairs, to speak more about it.</p>
<p>Over to you, Stan.</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:</strong>  Thank you, Under Secretary Jenkins.  I just want to take a moment to echo Under Secretary Jenkins’s comments and reiterate the importance of today’s announcement, which follows through on President Biden’s commitment to curtail the use of landmines worldwide.</p>
<p>After conducting a comprehensive policy review, the administration has announced a new U.S. policy to limit the use of anti-personnel landmines and align the United States’ policy and practice with key provisions of the Ottawa Convention for all activities outside the context of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>As a result of the decision, the United States will not develop, produce, or acquire anti-personnel landmines, not export or transfer anti-personnel landmines except when necessary for activities related to mine destruction or removal and for the purpose of destruction.  They will not use anti-personnel landmines outside the Korean Peninsula, they will not assist, encourage, or induce anyone outside the context of the Korean Peninsula to engage in activity that would be prohibited by the Ottawa Convention, and undertake to destroy anti-personnel landmines and their stockpiles not required for the defense of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>We will continue to pursue materiel and operational solutions that would be compliant with and ultimately allow the United States to accede to the Ottawa Convention, while we at the same ensure our ability to meet our alliance commitments.</p>
<p>The administration’s actions today are in a sharp contrast to Russia’s actions in Ukraine, where there’s compelling evidence that Russian forces are using explosive munitions, including landmines, in an irresponsible manner which is causing extensive harm to civilians and damage to vital civilian infrastructure there.</p>
<p>Lastly, just in a – here at – the United States is proud to lead the world in conventional weapons destruction.  We’ve invested more than 4.2 billion in more than 100 countries since 1993 to promote international peace and security through our conventional weapons destruction programs.  We’ll continue this important work and remain committed to continuing partnerships to address the humanitarian impacts of anti-personnel landmines.</p>
<p>With that just kind of as an opening statement, I’d be happy to take any questions from the group.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thanks very much.  Operator, if you wouldn’t mind repeating the instructions to ask a question.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And once again, for any questions or comments, you may queue up by pressing 1 and then 0.  That’s 1 and then 0 for any questions or comments.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Great.  We’ll start with the line of Shaun Tandon, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.  And your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Thanks for doing this.  Nice to hear from you, Bonnie and Stan, and Ned of course.</p>
<p>Could I ask you about – of course, you mentioned Russia.  China as well, as far as I know, is not part of the Ottawa Treaty.  How much do you expect to press other countries to also give up their landmines?  Is this going to become more of a diplomatic priority?  And could I also ask you a bit more about the Korean Peninsula and the reason for this continued exception, as it was under the Obama administration?  Is it because of the real threat of North Korea, the threats there?  Is it also because of that the ROK really has control over the landmines there?  Could you explain the reasoning behind continuing that exception?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:</strong>  All right.  So first of all, to address the Korea exception, that’s owing to our specific defense responsibilities there and our defense partnership.  The – first of all, the United States does not maintain any minefields in Korea or on the DMZ.  They’re all owned by the Republic of Korea.  We have a responsibility for defense of South Korea.  With the requirements of the Ottawa Convention, where we can’t assist, encourage, or induce anyone to use landmines, we cannot meet the treaty obligations there due to those defense requirements.  So in that regard, we are basically falling back to the Obama administration policies to make sure that we can meet our requirements with Korea in that regard.</p>
<p>In the – in regards to the requirements of the convention, we are basically aligning ourselves with – basically it’s with Article 1 of the Ottawa Convention and the principles that have been laid out in the fact sheets and kind of the discussion points that we’ve laid out here.  We will be meeting those requirements as – everywhere in the world except for on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Jennifer Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>One moment.  And your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Thanks for doing this.  I just want to be clear whether today’s action fully returns us to the Obama-era policy of landmine usage, and does this direct the Defense Department to destruct landmines in its possession?  And also, you mentioned Russia.  How much of an impetus was the war in Ukraine on finally making this change to the Trump-era policy?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:</strong>  So part of the – so as the policy is being put in place, basically we’re not going to develop or produce or acquire anti-personnel landmines; we’re not going to export or transfer anti-personnel landmines; we’re not going to use them outside the Korean Peninsula.  We would – part of the policy is also to undertake to destroy all anti-personnel stockpiles not required for the defense of Korea, Republic of Korea.  And again, we would not assist, encourage, or induce anyone outside the context of the Korean Peninsula to engage in any activity that would be prohibited by the convention.</p>
<p>In that regard – I’m sorry, could you repeat the second part of that question?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  I believe it was whether there – it would require the destruction of any anti-personnel landmines.</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:</strong>  Right, and we said the policy does undertake to destroy all anti-personnel landmines in stockpiles not required for the defense of the Republic of Korea.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll go to the line of Missy Ryan, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  One moment.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Do you all hear me?</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Okay.  Thanks.  Thanks very much for doing this.  And I just wanted to get an idea from the officials who are briefing – can you give us an idea of how far along the United States is in developing alternate weapons that could be employed in the Korean Peninsula along the DMZ to allow the United States to accede to the Ottawa Convention?  I haven’t been able to get a sense of whether those technologies are even in development, whether they’re close to being able to be fielded, or anything like that.   Any sort of context on that would be helpful.  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:</strong>  I can tell you that it’s being worked on, but I would have to defer you to the Department of Defense for the specific acquisition and operational capabilities of future devices.</p>
<p>The – going back to the last question as far as the Ukraine war being the impetus for the decision.  The decision has been under review for – since the Biden administration in January of 2021.  We have just reached the conclusion, and the President’s been able to make the announcement today.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Chris Megerian, Associated Press.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, everybody.  So a clarification question on the potential destruction of landmines that are currently in the U.S. stockpile.  Number one, how many landmines does the U.S. have in its stockpile?  Number two, are all of them deemed necessary to defend the Korean Peninsula?  Do we not plan to destroy any of those?</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:</strong>  The estimate of landmines in the stockpile is approximately three million.  In that regard, we – I would defer to DOD for what their operational requirements would be for what would be needed for defense of Korea.  And again, the policy states to basically look to undertake to destroy all anti-personnel landmines not needed for the defense of the Republic of Korea.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Daphne Psaledakis.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi.  Also just a point of clarification.  Could you say when the U.S. last used anti-personnel landmines?</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:</strong>  The United States last used anti-personnel landmines in 1991 during the Gulf War.  There was one single incident of one munition being used in the 2002 timeframe in Afghanistan.  But otherwise, the United States has not used landmines in – anti-personnel landmines in any significant way since 1991.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We have time for a couple of final questions.  Anton La Guardia.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you very much.  Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yes, please go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Can you just clarify whether Ukraine uses landmines and how the policy not to assist, induce other countries to use landmines can be aligned with the policy of helping Ukraine to win the war?</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:  </strong>Ukraine is a – actually a party to the Ottawa Convention, and cannot use landmines that are not – do not comply with the convention themselves.  So in itself, Ukraine is not using landmines, and we have not provided landmines to Ukraine that aren’t compliant with the Ottawa Convention.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll go to the line of Hye Jun Seo from Radio Free Asia.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hello, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Yes.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, thanks for taking my question.  Just – follow-up on the Korean Peninsula. Was there any update on the numbers of the mines within the country?  And how concerned is the DOS on the possible incidents and casualties on the Korean Peninsula due to the extensive minefield?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:  </strong>The United States does not main<sup><a id="ftn1ref"></a><a href="#ftn1"></a></sup> any of the minefields in the Republic of Korea, so I would have to defer you to the Republic of Korea Government to get any numbers on the number of mines and the incidents in the minefields there.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>And we’ll take a final question from Oskar Gorzynski, Polish Press Agency.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi.  I was – I wanted to clarify something because the U.S. has – sorry, as I can remember – transferred some landmines to Ukraine, the Claymore mines.  How are – how is that compliant with the Ottawa Convention?  Can you explain that?</p>
<p><strong>MR BROWN:  </strong>Yeah.<strong>  </strong>The – basically, the anti-personnel landmine in the Ottawa Convention policies are related to landmines that are exploded with the contact or presence of an individual.  The Claymore mines that were transferred by the U.S. Government to Ukraine are command-detonated with a person in the loop who can actually detonate them, which reduces the impact that landmines – that type of landline, which is Ottawa-compliant, has to civilian populations.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Terrific.  Well, that concludes this call.  Just a reminder this call was on the record.  You heard from Dr. Bonnie Jenkins, our under secretary for arms control and international security, as well as Stan Brown, our principal deputy assistant secretary in the Bureau of Political and Military Affairs.  With that, the call is concluded and the embargo is lifted.  Thanks, everyone, for dialing in, and thanks very much to Dr. Jenkins and PDAS Brown.</p>
<hr />
<p><a id="ftn1"></a><a href="#ftn1ref"></a> maintain</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Implementation of the Uyghur Forced Labor Prevention Act</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/implementation-of-the-uyghur-forced-labor-prevention-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 14:28:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=353709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Starting today, U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) will begin to implement the Uyghur Forced Labor Prevention Act’s provisions to prohibit imports made by forced labor into the United States of products made in Xinjiang.  President Biden signed the Act into law on December 23, 2021, after it passed with overwhelming bipartisan support in the United States Congress, underscoring our commitment to combating forced labor everywhere, including in Xinjiang, where genocide and crimes against humanity are ongoing.</p>
<p>The State Department is committed to working with Congress and our interagency partners to continue combating forced labor in Xinjiang and strengthen international coordination against this egregious violation of human rights.  Addressing forced labor and other human rights abuses in the People’s Republic of China (PRC) and around the world is a priority for President Biden and this Administration.  We have taken concrete measures to promote accountability in Xinjiang, including visa restrictions, financial sanctions under Global Magnitsky, export controls, Withhold Release Orders and import restrictions, as well as the release of a multi-agency business advisory on Xinjiang to help U.S. companies avoid commerce that facilitates or benefits from human rights abuses, including forced labor.  Together with our interagency partners, we will continue to engage companies to remind them of U.S. legal obligations which prohibit importing goods to the United States that are made with forced labor.</p>
<p>We are rallying our allies and partners to make global supply chains free from the use of forced labor, to speak out against atrocities in Xinjiang, and to join us in calling on the government of the PRC to immediately end atrocities and human rights abuses, including forced labor.</p>
<p>For more information on implementation of the Act, see: <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjEuNTk2NzU0MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2djYzAyLnNhZmVsaW5rcy5wcm90ZWN0aW9uLm91dGxvb2suY29tLz91cmw9aHR0cHMlM0ElMkYlMkZ3d3cuZGhzLmdvdiUyRnVmbHBhJmRhdGE9MDUlN0MwMSU3Q0J1cnJpc1JXJTQwc3RhdGUuZ292JTdDZWU2YWUxMzNmMjRmNGY4Njk3NzcwOGRhNTM4ODQ1NzAlN0M2NmNmNTA3NDVhZmU0OGQxYTY5MWExMmIyMTIxZjQ0YiU3QzAlN0MwJTdDNjM3OTE0MTQyMDAwNzQwODIyJTdDVW5rbm93biU3Q1RXRnBiR1pzYjNkOGV5SldJam9pTUM0d0xqQXdNREFpTENKUUlqb2lWMmx1TXpJaUxDSkJUaUk2SWsxaGFXd2lMQ0pYVkNJNk1uMCUzRCU3QzMwMDAlN0MlN0MlN0Mmc2RhdGE9dlZ2b3J6VjJzaU43SGhKUWY1RDNoQWRUY000c2VWckNYd1JkeWQ2Z05RayUzRCZyZXNlcnZlZD0wIn0.GKn06WRtcZdYnKC3pAAkLAs19rVWROqh9-UqzJ7xUGE/s/2576317770/br/133344737519-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://www.dhs.gov/uflpa" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="0">https://www.dhs.gov/uflpa</a>.</p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Starting today, U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) will begin to implement the Uyghur Forced Labor Prevention Act’s provisions to prohibit imports made by forced labor into the United States of products made in Xinjiang.  President Biden signed the Act into law on December 23, 2021, after it passed with overwhelming bipartisan support in the United States Congress, underscoring our commitment to combating forced labor everywhere, including in Xinjiang, where genocide and crimes against humanity are ongoing.</p>
<p>The State Department is committed to working with Congress and our interagency partners to continue combating forced labor in Xinjiang and strengthen international coordination against this egregious violation of human rights.  Addressing forced labor and other human rights abuses in the People’s Republic of China (PRC) and around the world is a priority for President Biden and this Administration.  We have taken concrete measures to promote accountability in Xinjiang, including visa restrictions, financial sanctions under Global Magnitsky, export controls, Withhold Release Orders and import restrictions, as well as the release of a multi-agency business advisory on Xinjiang to help U.S. companies avoid commerce that facilitates or benefits from human rights abuses, including forced labor.  Together with our interagency partners, we will continue to engage companies to remind them of U.S. legal obligations which prohibit importing goods to the United States that are made with forced labor.</p>
<p>We are rallying our allies and partners to make global supply chains free from the use of forced labor, to speak out against atrocities in Xinjiang, and to join us in calling on the government of the PRC to immediately end atrocities and human rights abuses, including forced labor.</p>
<p>For more information on implementation of the Act, see: <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjEuNTk2NzU0MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2djYzAyLnNhZmVsaW5rcy5wcm90ZWN0aW9uLm91dGxvb2suY29tLz91cmw9aHR0cHMlM0ElMkYlMkZ3d3cuZGhzLmdvdiUyRnVmbHBhJmRhdGE9MDUlN0MwMSU3Q0J1cnJpc1JXJTQwc3RhdGUuZ292JTdDZWU2YWUxMzNmMjRmNGY4Njk3NzcwOGRhNTM4ODQ1NzAlN0M2NmNmNTA3NDVhZmU0OGQxYTY5MWExMmIyMTIxZjQ0YiU3QzAlN0MwJTdDNjM3OTE0MTQyMDAwNzQwODIyJTdDVW5rbm93biU3Q1RXRnBiR1pzYjNkOGV5SldJam9pTUM0d0xqQXdNREFpTENKUUlqb2lWMmx1TXpJaUxDSkJUaUk2SWsxaGFXd2lMQ0pYVkNJNk1uMCUzRCU3QzMwMDAlN0MlN0MlN0Mmc2RhdGE9dlZ2b3J6VjJzaU43SGhKUWY1RDNoQWRUY000c2VWckNYd1JkeWQ2Z05RayUzRCZyZXNlcnZlZD0wIn0.GKn06WRtcZdYnKC3pAAkLAs19rVWROqh9-UqzJ7xUGE/s/2576317770/br/133344737519-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://www.dhs.gov/uflpa" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="0">https://www.dhs.gov/uflpa</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Civilians Killed in Ethiopia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/civilians-killed-in-ethiopia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 13:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=353676</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is gravely concerned by reported killings of civilians in the Amhara community of the Oromia Region of Ethiopia this weekend. We mourn for the victims and extend our sincerest condolences to survivors and all those who lost loved ones in this horrific act. We also call on all Ethiopians to reject violence, and instead, pursue peaceful dialogue to resolve differences. National reconciliation must involve comprehensive, inclusive justice for victims and accountability for those responsible for human rights abuses and violations. Continued reports such as these underscore the urgency of ending the ongoing armed conflict in Ethiopia.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is gravely concerned by reported killings of civilians in the Amhara community of the Oromia Region of Ethiopia this weekend. We mourn for the victims and extend our sincerest condolences to survivors and all those who lost loved ones in this horrific act. We also call on all Ethiopians to reject violence, and instead, pursue peaceful dialogue to resolve differences. National reconciliation must involve comprehensive, inclusive justice for victims and accountability for those responsible for human rights abuses and violations. Continued reports such as these underscore the urgency of ending the ongoing armed conflict in Ethiopia.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken&#8217;s Call with Colombian President-Elect Petro</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-colombian-president-elect-petro/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=353560</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Colombian President-Elect Gustavo Petro to congratulate him on his election as President of the Republic of Colombia and to reiterate the United States’ steadfast commitment to the bilateral relationship. Secretary Blinken underscored our countries&#8217; shared democratic values and pledged to further strengthen the 200-year U.S.-Colombia friendship. They discussed mutual goals to address climate change, improve public health, and advance inclusive economic opportunity. The Secretary noted U.S. support for full implementation of Colombia’s commitments under the 2016 Peace Accord and discussed how the U.S.-Colombia integrated counternarcotics strategy aligns with President-Elect Petro’s goal to diminish rural violence.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Colombian President-Elect Gustavo Petro to congratulate him on his election as President of the Republic of Colombia and to reiterate the United States’ steadfast commitment to the bilateral relationship. Secretary Blinken underscored our countries&#8217; shared democratic values and pledged to further strengthen the 200-year U.S.-Colombia friendship. They discussed mutual goals to address climate change, improve public health, and advance inclusive economic opportunity. The Secretary noted U.S. support for full implementation of Colombia’s commitments under the 2016 Peace Accord and discussed how the U.S.-Colombia integrated counternarcotics strategy aligns with President-Elect Petro’s goal to diminish rural violence.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Commemorating World Refugee Day 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/commemorating-world-refugee-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 12:16:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=353522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>This World Refugee Day, we acknowledge the unprecedented humanitarian crises across the globe, resulting in the largest number of refugees in history.  Last month, we reached the tragic milestone of more than 100 million people forcibly displaced worldwide.  Through humanitarian assistance, diplomacy, and refugee resettlement, the United States leads the way in helping the courageous and resilient people who are forced to flee persecution to find safety and rebuild their lives.</p>
<p>The UN Refugee Agency’s theme for World Refugee Day this year is, “Whoever.  Wherever. Whenever.  Everyone has the right to safety.”  We value and honor refugees’ strength and perseverance.  Our commitment to the world’s vulnerable is unwavering.  The United States is the world’s largest single donor of humanitarian assistance, providing more than $13 billion in humanitarian aid to those in need during Fiscal Year 2021. The needs are significant, however, and we call on the donor community to increase contributions to support the needs of refugees and other vulnerable populations around the globe.  We will continue to represent the best of American values by saving lives and alleviating suffering, working with our partners at home and abroad to assist the forcibly displaced in their time of need – no matter who or where they are, on World Refugee Day and every day.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>This World Refugee Day, we acknowledge the unprecedented humanitarian crises across the globe, resulting in the largest number of refugees in history.  Last month, we reached the tragic milestone of more than 100 million people forcibly displaced worldwide.  Through humanitarian assistance, diplomacy, and refugee resettlement, the United States leads the way in helping the courageous and resilient people who are forced to flee persecution to find safety and rebuild their lives.</p>
<p>The UN Refugee Agency’s theme for World Refugee Day this year is, “Whoever.  Wherever. Whenever.  Everyone has the right to safety.”  We value and honor refugees’ strength and perseverance.  Our commitment to the world’s vulnerable is unwavering.  The United States is the world’s largest single donor of humanitarian assistance, providing more than $13 billion in humanitarian aid to those in need during Fiscal Year 2021. The needs are significant, however, and we call on the donor community to increase contributions to support the needs of refugees and other vulnerable populations around the globe.  We will continue to represent the best of American values by saving lives and alleviating suffering, working with our partners at home and abroad to assist the forcibly displaced in their time of need – no matter who or where they are, on World Refugee Day and every day.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Advancing Peace and Eliminating Sexual Violence in Conflict</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/advancing-peace-and-eliminating-sexual-violence-in-conflict/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 19:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=353493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>For more than a decade, the United States has joined the global community in recognizing June 19 as the International Day for the Elimination of Sexual Violence in Conflict (IDESVC). We remain deeply committed to preventing and responding to all forms of gender-based violence, including conflict-related sexual violence, which disproportionately impacts women and girls, and protecting and supporting survivors. The United States recognizes that respect for the rights and dignity of women and girls, in all their diversity is essential to promoting global peace, security, democracy, and economic prosperity.</p>
<p>The world faces a number of pressing issues that disproportionately impact women and girls, including the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic, the climate crisis, food insecurity, and conflict and humanitarian emergencies around the world. The international community has been inundated with devastating reports of conflict-related sexual violence from across the world, including in Ukraine, Ethiopia, and Syria. We have seen how conflict and crisis exacerbate gender inequality and increase women and girls’ vulnerability to gender-based violence, online and offline. Increased violence impedes women’s ability to participate meaningfully in the social, political, and economic sectors of life, causing cycles of poverty, marginalization, and insecurity.</p>
<p>The United States is taking concrete steps to ensure our efforts to prevent and respond to conflict-related sexual violence are survivor-centered and trauma-informed. As illustrated in the U.S. National Strategy on Gender Equity and Equality, the Administration is committed to developing and strengthening comprehensive gender-based violence policies, services, and prevention efforts. Later this year, the United States will release an update to the U.S. Strategy to Prevent and Respond to Gender-Based Violence Globally, which will address conflict-related sexual violence, among other policy priorities.</p>
<p>Additionally, through the U.S. Strategy on Women, Peace, and Security, the Department of State is working to promote the participation of women in decision-making and conflict resolution, protection of the human rights of women and girls, access to aid, and safety from violence, abuse – including conflict-related sexual violence – and exploitation around the world. We recognize that we cannot effect sustainable change on our own, so the United States works closely with multilateral partners and allies, including the United Nations Special Representative of the Secretary-General on Sexual Violence in Conflict.</p>
<p>Elimination of conflict-related sexual violence is both a moral and strategic imperative. Empty calls for action and expressions of concern are not enough. On this International Day for the Elimination of Sexual Violence in Conflict, the international community must take real action and coordinate efforts to prevent and respond to all forms of gender-based violence so that the support we provide is survivor-centered and truly advances justice and accountability for such crimes.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>For more than a decade, the United States has joined the global community in recognizing June 19 as the International Day for the Elimination of Sexual Violence in Conflict (IDESVC). We remain deeply committed to preventing and responding to all forms of gender-based violence, including conflict-related sexual violence, which disproportionately impacts women and girls, and protecting and supporting survivors. The United States recognizes that respect for the rights and dignity of women and girls, in all their diversity is essential to promoting global peace, security, democracy, and economic prosperity.</p>
<p>The world faces a number of pressing issues that disproportionately impact women and girls, including the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic, the climate crisis, food insecurity, and conflict and humanitarian emergencies around the world. The international community has been inundated with devastating reports of conflict-related sexual violence from across the world, including in Ukraine, Ethiopia, and Syria. We have seen how conflict and crisis exacerbate gender inequality and increase women and girls’ vulnerability to gender-based violence, online and offline. Increased violence impedes women’s ability to participate meaningfully in the social, political, and economic sectors of life, causing cycles of poverty, marginalization, and insecurity.</p>
<p>The United States is taking concrete steps to ensure our efforts to prevent and respond to conflict-related sexual violence are survivor-centered and trauma-informed. As illustrated in the U.S. National Strategy on Gender Equity and Equality, the Administration is committed to developing and strengthening comprehensive gender-based violence policies, services, and prevention efforts. Later this year, the United States will release an update to the U.S. Strategy to Prevent and Respond to Gender-Based Violence Globally, which will address conflict-related sexual violence, among other policy priorities.</p>
<p>Additionally, through the U.S. Strategy on Women, Peace, and Security, the Department of State is working to promote the participation of women in decision-making and conflict resolution, protection of the human rights of women and girls, access to aid, and safety from violence, abuse – including conflict-related sexual violence – and exploitation around the world. We recognize that we cannot effect sustainable change on our own, so the United States works closely with multilateral partners and allies, including the United Nations Special Representative of the Secretary-General on Sexual Violence in Conflict.</p>
<p>Elimination of conflict-related sexual violence is both a moral and strategic imperative. Empty calls for action and expressions of concern are not enough. On this International Day for the Elimination of Sexual Violence in Conflict, the international community must take real action and coordinate efforts to prevent and respond to all forms of gender-based violence so that the support we provide is survivor-centered and truly advances justice and accountability for such crimes.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at a Pride Reception</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-pride-reception/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:11:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=353381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, first let me say I’m just going to drop the microphone and leave it to these two, because who wants to follow that?  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>It is so wonderful to see everyone here.  And as Jessica said, there’s something wonderful about just being back in this room, in the Ben Franklin Room.  We haven’t had a chance to use it very much because of COVID in recent years, but to see it filled with all of you, to feel the energy in this room that you’re bringing to it, is a powerful thing.</p>
<p>And in some ways, it’s very appropriate that we’re here with Ben Franklin.  He was our nation’s first diplomat, as I think all of you know.  He charted the Gulf Stream, he pioneered electricity, he authored America’s first treaty, he helped forge a new ethos of self-government.  And virtually none of this did he do while sober.  (Laughter.)  So I know that’s not going to be an issue here tonight.</p>
<p>But first, Happy Pride, everyone.  (Cheers.)</p>
<p>As you’ve heard, this is our first in-person Pride reception in far too long – six years – and I’m thrilled that we’re finally able to do it, because Pride Month is all about love, authenticity, justice, equality, and those are very much worth celebrating.</p>
<p>Jessica, thank you for that introduction.  But mostly, thank you for your tireless efforts already as our special envoy to stand up for the rights of LGBTQI+ persons around the world, to tackle discrimination and violence wherever we find it.</p>
<p>We spent some time together this week.  I would not want to be in the way of Jessica Stern.  (Applause.)  I’m so glad that I’m on her team.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>And I also want to say a few words about a few other people.  Uzra Zeya – Uzra, are you here somewhere?  There.  (Applause.)  Uzra, as I think most of you know, is our under secretary of state for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights, and she is leading our efforts to defend rights around the world, including for LGBTQI+ persons.</p>
<p>And Michael, thank you, thank you, thank you for your extraordinary leadership of glifaa.  You’ve done a remarkable job.  We’re very, very pleased that you’re now off on a mission very soon to Luxembourg, but to you, to everyone from glifaa’s board and membership who is here, thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>
<p>We’re here tonight because, first and foremost, Pride Month is about supporting and celebrating LGBTQI+ persons everywhere, including in the workplace.  And simply put, we wouldn’t be able to do our work without you – and we wouldn’t want to.  You’re dedicated public servants, incredibly talented diplomats, cherished colleagues and teammates.  You make our country safer; you make our foreign policy stronger.  And we want to do everything we can to make sure that this department, the State Department, always recognizes your worth, supports you and your families, and is a place where you can bring your whole self to work every single day.</p>
<p>Now, to do that, we need to be honest about the work it’s taken to get where we are today, and you’ve heard reference to some of it.  For a long time, LGBTQI+ people couldn’t live openly and still get a State Department security clearance.  In contrast – in contrast – this week and this weekend, Diplomatic Security agents marched with glifaa in the DC Pride Parade.  (Applause.)  That in and of itself is a pretty remarkable journey.  And it’s thanks in large part to glifaa, and to all the people who stood up and fought for America’s foreign affairs agencies to be better.  That took courage.  It took resilience.  And it’s achieved real results.</p>
<p>But again, as you’ve heard, there’s still a lot of work to do.  The work is ongoing, and in a sense, it always will be.  We can’t ever become complacent in advancing equity in our workplace.  And especially now, it is so critical that we reaffirm our shared commitment to an America where all people are treated with equal respect and equal humanity, and where all kids know that they’re perfect just the way they are.  (Applause.)  At the same time, we’re also working very closely with glifaa to see to it that when an LGBTQI+ officer serves overseas, they can do so with their partner.  That is a priority for me and for all of us.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>So we here at State have another responsibility as well.  It is our job – and it’s quite literally Jessica’s job – to stand up for human rights all over the world.  And the fact is, again, as you’ve heard, the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons are vulnerable or actively violated in far too many places.  Homosexual status or conduct is still illegal in 70 countries around the world.  That’s about a third of the world’s countries.  In some, it’s punishable by death.  And in too much of the world, being lesbian, gay, bisexual, trans, intersex, or simply gender non-conforming means that you’re going to be dealing with violence, you’re going to be dealing with harassment, targeted by the police or security forces, denied education, denied employment, denied equal access to the justice sector or to healthcare, experiencing profoundly isolating social exclusion.</p>
<p>These are human rights abuses – and the United States fights for human rights.  Human rights are indivisible.  Whenever one group of people is targeted, all vulnerable groups are less safe.  And whenever one group’s rights are protected, societies as a whole become both more free, more prosperous, more secure.  This is the “inescapable network of mutuality” that Dr. Martin Luther King talked about when he said that “injustice anywhere is a threat to justice everywhere.”  That’s why it’s not just enough to stand up for LGBTQI rights at home. We have to continue and we will continue to stand up for equal rights everywhere, in partnership with local activists and local communities.</p>
<p>Human rights are also central to our support for democracy around the world, because any system in which some groups are treated as “less than” – as second-class citizens with fewer rights and protections – is fundamentally flawed.</p>
<p>Wednesday, as you heard, President Biden signed an executive order to advance LGBTQI+ equality at home and abroad that includes direction to this department, to the State Department, along with other relevant agencies, to develop a plan to promote an end to the profoundly harmful and medically discredited practice of so-called “conversion therapy” around the world and to ensure that our foreign – (applause) – and to ensure, to ensure, that our foreign assistance dollars do not fund it.</p>
<p>At the Human Rights Council, we are supporting renewing the mandate of the Independent Expert on Sexual Orientation and Gender Identity for another three years, so that this vital work to protect people facing violence and discrimination continues.</p>
<p>We’ll keep supporting marriage equality and legal recognition for same-sex relationships around the world.</p>
<p>And this year, we’re celebrating the 10th anniversary of the State Department’s Global Equality Fund.  With support from Congress, from other countries, private sector partners, we have provided more than $100 million to LGBTQI+ organizations in more than 100 countries.  (Cheers.)</p>
<p>We will continue to find ways to advance this work around the world.  And I have a pretty good feeling I can count on everyone in this room to help us do that – (laughter) – because many of you have been pushing us to do more and to do better for a long time.</p>
<p>So as Mike noted at the outset, this is the 30th anniversary of glifaa’s founding.  I think probably all of you know the backstory, but for the few of you who don’t:  David Buss was a Foreign Service officer.  He was posted to the Seychelles.  David Larson was there with the Peace Corps.  They became great friends.  Eventually, they fell in love.</p>
<p>As a result, David Larson was removed from the Peace Corps for his, quote, “inappropriate lifestyle.”  David Buss learned that the State Department was investigating him because of his sexuality.  He also learned that other people at State and USAID were going through the same ordeal.</p>
<p>So the two Davids invited some of those colleagues over for brunch one weekend back in 1992.  They included Bryan Dalton, Danny Hall, Jan Krc, Eric Nelson, John Schneider.  That’s how glifaa was born.</p>
<p>This story reminds us that powerful moments are often rooted in necessity, but also – also – in love, in friendship – and sometimes brunch.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>It’s a story about who we were but also who we’ve become.</p>
<p>And I just want to thank everyone who has courageously carried forward that legacy, the legacy that glifaa’s founders began all those years ago.  We will continue to march together.  Thank you very much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, first let me say I’m just going to drop the microphone and leave it to these two, because who wants to follow that?  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>It is so wonderful to see everyone here.  And as Jessica said, there’s something wonderful about just being back in this room, in the Ben Franklin Room.  We haven’t had a chance to use it very much because of COVID in recent years, but to see it filled with all of you, to feel the energy in this room that you’re bringing to it, is a powerful thing.</p>
<p>And in some ways, it’s very appropriate that we’re here with Ben Franklin.  He was our nation’s first diplomat, as I think all of you know.  He charted the Gulf Stream, he pioneered electricity, he authored America’s first treaty, he helped forge a new ethos of self-government.  And virtually none of this did he do while sober.  (Laughter.)  So I know that’s not going to be an issue here tonight.</p>
<p>But first, Happy Pride, everyone.  (Cheers.)</p>
<p>As you’ve heard, this is our first in-person Pride reception in far too long – six years – and I’m thrilled that we’re finally able to do it, because Pride Month is all about love, authenticity, justice, equality, and those are very much worth celebrating.</p>
<p>Jessica, thank you for that introduction.  But mostly, thank you for your tireless efforts already as our special envoy to stand up for the rights of LGBTQI+ persons around the world, to tackle discrimination and violence wherever we find it.</p>
<p>We spent some time together this week.  I would not want to be in the way of Jessica Stern.  (Applause.)  I’m so glad that I’m on her team.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>And I also want to say a few words about a few other people.  Uzra Zeya – Uzra, are you here somewhere?  There.  (Applause.)  Uzra, as I think most of you know, is our under secretary of state for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights, and she is leading our efforts to defend rights around the world, including for LGBTQI+ persons.</p>
<p>And Michael, thank you, thank you, thank you for your extraordinary leadership of glifaa.  You’ve done a remarkable job.  We’re very, very pleased that you’re now off on a mission very soon to Luxembourg, but to you, to everyone from glifaa’s board and membership who is here, thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>
<p>We’re here tonight because, first and foremost, Pride Month is about supporting and celebrating LGBTQI+ persons everywhere, including in the workplace.  And simply put, we wouldn’t be able to do our work without you – and we wouldn’t want to.  You’re dedicated public servants, incredibly talented diplomats, cherished colleagues and teammates.  You make our country safer; you make our foreign policy stronger.  And we want to do everything we can to make sure that this department, the State Department, always recognizes your worth, supports you and your families, and is a place where you can bring your whole self to work every single day.</p>
<p>Now, to do that, we need to be honest about the work it’s taken to get where we are today, and you’ve heard reference to some of it.  For a long time, LGBTQI+ people couldn’t live openly and still get a State Department security clearance.  In contrast – in contrast – this week and this weekend, Diplomatic Security agents marched with glifaa in the DC Pride Parade.  (Applause.)  That in and of itself is a pretty remarkable journey.  And it’s thanks in large part to glifaa, and to all the people who stood up and fought for America’s foreign affairs agencies to be better.  That took courage.  It took resilience.  And it’s achieved real results.</p>
<p>But again, as you’ve heard, there’s still a lot of work to do.  The work is ongoing, and in a sense, it always will be.  We can’t ever become complacent in advancing equity in our workplace.  And especially now, it is so critical that we reaffirm our shared commitment to an America where all people are treated with equal respect and equal humanity, and where all kids know that they’re perfect just the way they are.  (Applause.)  At the same time, we’re also working very closely with glifaa to see to it that when an LGBTQI+ officer serves overseas, they can do so with their partner.  That is a priority for me and for all of us.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>So we here at State have another responsibility as well.  It is our job – and it’s quite literally Jessica’s job – to stand up for human rights all over the world.  And the fact is, again, as you’ve heard, the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons are vulnerable or actively violated in far too many places.  Homosexual status or conduct is still illegal in 70 countries around the world.  That’s about a third of the world’s countries.  In some, it’s punishable by death.  And in too much of the world, being lesbian, gay, bisexual, trans, intersex, or simply gender non-conforming means that you’re going to be dealing with violence, you’re going to be dealing with harassment, targeted by the police or security forces, denied education, denied employment, denied equal access to the justice sector or to healthcare, experiencing profoundly isolating social exclusion.</p>
<p>These are human rights abuses – and the United States fights for human rights.  Human rights are indivisible.  Whenever one group of people is targeted, all vulnerable groups are less safe.  And whenever one group’s rights are protected, societies as a whole become both more free, more prosperous, more secure.  This is the “inescapable network of mutuality” that Dr. Martin Luther King talked about when he said that “injustice anywhere is a threat to justice everywhere.”  That’s why it’s not just enough to stand up for LGBTQI rights at home. We have to continue and we will continue to stand up for equal rights everywhere, in partnership with local activists and local communities.</p>
<p>Human rights are also central to our support for democracy around the world, because any system in which some groups are treated as “less than” – as second-class citizens with fewer rights and protections – is fundamentally flawed.</p>
<p>Wednesday, as you heard, President Biden signed an executive order to advance LGBTQI+ equality at home and abroad that includes direction to this department, to the State Department, along with other relevant agencies, to develop a plan to promote an end to the profoundly harmful and medically discredited practice of so-called “conversion therapy” around the world and to ensure that our foreign – (applause) – and to ensure, to ensure, that our foreign assistance dollars do not fund it.</p>
<p>At the Human Rights Council, we are supporting renewing the mandate of the Independent Expert on Sexual Orientation and Gender Identity for another three years, so that this vital work to protect people facing violence and discrimination continues.</p>
<p>We’ll keep supporting marriage equality and legal recognition for same-sex relationships around the world.</p>
<p>And this year, we’re celebrating the 10th anniversary of the State Department’s Global Equality Fund.  With support from Congress, from other countries, private sector partners, we have provided more than $100 million to LGBTQI+ organizations in more than 100 countries.  (Cheers.)</p>
<p>We will continue to find ways to advance this work around the world.  And I have a pretty good feeling I can count on everyone in this room to help us do that – (laughter) – because many of you have been pushing us to do more and to do better for a long time.</p>
<p>So as Mike noted at the outset, this is the 30th anniversary of glifaa’s founding.  I think probably all of you know the backstory, but for the few of you who don’t:  David Buss was a Foreign Service officer.  He was posted to the Seychelles.  David Larson was there with the Peace Corps.  They became great friends.  Eventually, they fell in love.</p>
<p>As a result, David Larson was removed from the Peace Corps for his, quote, “inappropriate lifestyle.”  David Buss learned that the State Department was investigating him because of his sexuality.  He also learned that other people at State and USAID were going through the same ordeal.</p>
<p>So the two Davids invited some of those colleagues over for brunch one weekend back in 1992.  They included Bryan Dalton, Danny Hall, Jan Krc, Eric Nelson, John Schneider.  That’s how glifaa was born.</p>
<p>This story reminds us that powerful moments are often rooted in necessity, but also – also – in love, in friendship – and sometimes brunch.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>It’s a story about who we were but also who we’ve become.</p>
<p>And I just want to thank everyone who has courageously carried forward that legacy, the legacy that glifaa’s founders began all those years ago.  We will continue to march together.  Thank you very much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-Chaired Annual Tripartite Consultations on Resettlement in Geneva to Highlight Innovation and Increasing Global Capacity for Refugee Resettlement</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-chaired-annual-tripartite-consultations-on-resettlement-in-geneva-to-highlight-innovation-and-increasing-global-capacity-for-refugee-resettlement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 22:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=353347</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On Monday, June 20, representatives from the United States and twenty-eight other governments, along with non-governmental organizations, the UN High Commissioner for Refugees, academia, refugees, and the private sector will convene the Annual Tripartite Consultations on Resettlement (ATCR) in Geneva, Switzerland. The three-day ATCR is a high-level, multilateral forum to discuss and advance refugee resettlement issues of common interest.</p>
<p>The 2022 ATCR is chaired by the Government of the United States, represented by the U.S. Department of State, Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM) and co-chaired by Refugee Council USA (RCUSA). Interagency representatives from the U.S. Departments of Homeland Security and Health and Human Services and the White House will be in attendance. This will be the first in-person ATCR event since 2019 and the first time the U.S. has chaired since 2011. The first day of the ATCR, June 20, also coincides with World Refugee Day. Secretary Blinken will address the delegates by video, highlighting renewed U.S. leadership on refugee resettlement.</p>
<p>The ATCR allows existing and emerging resettlement countries to share best practices, discuss priorities, and engage with resettlement stakeholders on global needs and opportunities for the upcoming year. The event will emphasize strengthening partnerships and increasing capacity for resettlement, complementary protection pathways, and integration of refugees into welcoming and inclusive societies. As a global leader in refugee resettlement, the United States will outline plans at the ATCR to not only restore the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program, but also expand and modernize it. The theme of this year’s ATCR is Reemerging and Building Globally.</p>
<p>Throughout the ATCR, the focus will be on reemerging from a year of unprecedented humanitarian emergencies such as Afghanistan and Ukraine, as well as the COVID-19 pandemic through renewed commitments to increased resettlement and complementary pathways, more innovative and nimble responses to emerging crises, and more equitable responsibility-sharing for supporting refugees globally. An additional goal of this year’s ATCR will be to advance the meaningful inclusion of refugees in resettlement policy and governance.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On Monday, June 20, representatives from the United States and twenty-eight other governments, along with non-governmental organizations, the UN High Commissioner for Refugees, academia, refugees, and the private sector will convene the Annual Tripartite Consultations on Resettlement (ATCR) in Geneva, Switzerland. The three-day ATCR is a high-level, multilateral forum to discuss and advance refugee resettlement issues of common interest.</p>
<p>The 2022 ATCR is chaired by the Government of the United States, represented by the U.S. Department of State, Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM) and co-chaired by Refugee Council USA (RCUSA). Interagency representatives from the U.S. Departments of Homeland Security and Health and Human Services and the White House will be in attendance. This will be the first in-person ATCR event since 2019 and the first time the U.S. has chaired since 2011. The first day of the ATCR, June 20, also coincides with World Refugee Day. Secretary Blinken will address the delegates by video, highlighting renewed U.S. leadership on refugee resettlement.</p>
<p>The ATCR allows existing and emerging resettlement countries to share best practices, discuss priorities, and engage with resettlement stakeholders on global needs and opportunities for the upcoming year. The event will emphasize strengthening partnerships and increasing capacity for resettlement, complementary protection pathways, and integration of refugees into welcoming and inclusive societies. As a global leader in refugee resettlement, the United States will outline plans at the ATCR to not only restore the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program, but also expand and modernize it. The theme of this year’s ATCR is Reemerging and Building Globally.</p>
<p>Throughout the ATCR, the focus will be on reemerging from a year of unprecedented humanitarian emergencies such as Afghanistan and Ukraine, as well as the COVID-19 pandemic through renewed commitments to increased resettlement and complementary pathways, more innovative and nimble responses to emerging crises, and more equitable responsibility-sharing for supporting refugees globally. An additional goal of this year’s ATCR will be to advance the meaningful inclusion of refugees in resettlement policy and governance.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111001000111" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken Selects Members of the Foreign Affairs Policy Board</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinken-selects-members-of-the-foreign-affairs-policy-board/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 21:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=353343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span>Today, Secretary Blinken announced his selections for the U.S. Department of State’s Foreign Affairs Policy Board.</span></p>
<p><span>Since its establishment in 2011, the Board has provided independent advice on the conduct of U.S. foreign policy and diplomacy, consistent with each Secretary of State and administration’s evolving priorities for it.</span></p>
<p><span>Secretary Blinken has sought to build a diverse board that could advance the Department’s efforts to better root American diplomacy in the needs and aspirations of the American people. With expertise at the intersection of foreign and domestic policy, the Board will focus on the issues of increasing importance to the lives and livelihoods of Americans in the decade ahead, including cybersecurity and emerging technologies, climate and energy, international economics, global health, and strategic competition with the People’s Republic of China.</span></p>
<p><span>Co-Chairs</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Thomas Donilon</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Thomas E. Donilon is Chairman of the BlackRock Investment Institute. He served as National Security Advisor to President Barack Obama. In that capacity Mr. Donilon oversaw the U.S. National Security Council staff, chaired the cabinet level National Security Principals Committee, provided the president’s daily national security briefing, and was responsible for the coordination and integration of the administration’s foreign policy, intelligence, and military efforts. Mr. Donilon also oversaw the White House’s cybersecurity and international energy efforts and served as the President’s personal emissary to a number of world leaders. Mr. Donilon has worked with and advised three U.S. presidents.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Cecilia Muñoz</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Cecilia Muñoz is a national leader in public policy and public interest technology with nearly three decades of experience in the non-profit sector and government. She was the first Latina to lead the White House Domestic Policy Council, serving 8 years on President Obama’s senior team. She led the domestic and economic policy team for the Biden/Harris presidential transition and serves as a senior advisor to New America in Washington, DC. An internationally recognized expert on immigration policy, in 2021, she co-founded Welcome.US, an organization that mobilizes civil society to support the resettlement of Afghan evacuees and other newcomers to the United States. Cecilia started her career at the National Council of La Raza (now UNIDOS US), the nation’s largest Hispanic policy and advocacy organization, where she spent 20 years focused on immigration, civil rights, education, and a broad range of policy concerns.</span></p>
<p><span>Members</span><span> </span></p>
<p><strong><span>David Autor</span></strong></p>
<p><span>David Autor is Ford Professor in the MIT Department of Economics, Vice President of the American Economic Association, codirector of the NBER Labor Studies Program and the JPAL Work of the Future experimental initiative. His scholarship explores the labor-market impacts of technological change and globalization on job polarization, skill demands, earnings levels and inequality, and electoral outcomes. Autor has received numerous awards for both his scholarship—the National Science Foundation CAREER Award, an Alfred P. Sloan Foundation Fellowship, the Sherwin Rosen Prize for outstanding contributions to the field of Labor Economics, the Andrew Carnegie Fellowship in 2019, the Society for Progress Medal in 2021—and for his teaching, including the MIT MacVicar Faculty Fellowship. In a 2019 article, the Economist magazine labeled him as “The academic voice of the American worker.”</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Dr. Sameer Bhalotra</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Dr. Sameer Bhalotra is the Co-founder &amp; CEO of ActZero, a security company based in Menlo Park, California. He previously worked in cybersecurity at Google and as a Board member of numerous security startups. In government, he served as Senior Director for Cybersecurity on the National Security Council staff at the White House, Cybersecurity &amp; Technology Lead for the Senate Select Committee on Intelligence, and in various roles in the Intelligence Community. He is affiliated with the US Secret Service Cyber Investigations Advisory Board, Center for Strategic and International Studies, Stanford University&#8217;s Center for International Security and Cooperation, and Harvard University’s Kennedy School of Government.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Dr. Hal Brands</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Hal Brands is the Henry A. Kissinger Distinguished Professor of Global Affairs at the Johns Hopkins School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS) and a senior fellow at the American Enterprise Institute. He is also a columnist for Bloomberg Opinion. Brands is the author or co-author of numerous books, most recently, The Lessons of Tragedy: Statecraft and World Order (2019), The Twilight Struggle: What the Cold War Teaches Us About Great-Power Rivalry Today (2022), and Danger Zone: The Coming Crisis with China (2022). Hal has also served as Special Assistant to the Secretary of Defense for Strategic Planning from 2015 to 2016, as lead writer for the Commission on the National Defense Strategy for the United States, and has consulted with a range of government offices and agencies.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Mariano-Florentino (Tino) Cuéllar</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Tino Cuéllar is the tenth president of the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace. A former justice of the Supreme Court of California, he served two U.S. presidents at the White House and in federal agencies and was a faculty member at Stanford University for two decades. During nearly seven years on California’s highest court, he wrote opinions addressing separation of powers, federalism, policing and criminal justice, democracy, technology and privacy, and climate and environmental policy among other issues, and led the court system’s efforts to better meet the needs of millions of limited English speakers.  </span><span>    </span></p>
<p><strong><span>Mitchell E. Daniels, Jr.</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Mitchell E. Daniels, Jr. is the 12th president of Purdue University and the former governor of Indiana. He was elected Indiana’s 49th governor in 2004 in his first bid for any elected office, and then re-elected in 2008 with more votes than any candidate in the state&#8217;s history. Prior to becoming governor, Daniels served as senior advisor to President Ronald Reagan and Director of the Office of Management and Budget under President George W. Bush. President Daniels also comes from a successful career in business, holding numerous top management positions. From 1987-1990, Daniels served as the CEO of the Hudson Institute.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Janine Davidson, Ph.D</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Janine Davidson, Ph.D. is president of Metropolitan State University of Denver, Colorado’s third largest and most diverse public university. Davidson is a national thought leader in higher education and on topics such as public service, U.S. foreign policy and national security. Dr. Davidson served in various senior civilian Pentagon positions, most recently as the 32nd undersecretary of the U.S. Navy. Previously she served as the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Plans and was also a senior civil servant in the stability operations office in the office of the Secretary of Defense. Davidson began her career as an Air Force officer and cargo pilot. She was a distinguished graduate of the Air Force Squadron Officer School and was the first woman to fly the Air Force’s tactical C-130.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Cathy Feingold</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Cathy Feingold is a leading advocate on foreign policy centered in the priorities of working people and their families. She brings more than 20 years of experience in trade and global economic policy, and worker, human and women&#8217;s rights issues. As director of the AFL-CIO’s International Department, she represents over 12.5 million workers and is a committed and passionate advocate, strategic campaigner and policy expert. In 2018, Feingold was elected Deputy President of the International Trade Union Confederation, the organization representing 200 million unionized workers worldwide and headquartered in Belgium, Brussels and she is a member of the Trade Union Advisory Committee at the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Margaret A. Hamburg, MD</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Dr. Margaret Hamburg is an internationally recognized leader in public health and medicine, who currently serves as chair of the Nuclear Threat Initiative’s Bio Advisory Group. She previously served as foreign secretary of the National Academy of Medicine and is a former Commissioner of the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA), having served for almost six years. Before joining FDA, Hamburg was founding vice president and senior scientist at the Nuclear Threat Initiative. Previous government positions include Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Health Commissioner for New York City, and Assistant Director of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, National Institutes of Health.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Jon M. Huntsman, Jr.</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Jon Huntsman currently serves as Vice Chair of Ford Motor Company. He has spent considerable time in public service at the state, national, and international levels. Huntsman began his career in public service as a staff assistant to President Ronald Reagan. He has served each of the five U.S. presidents since then in critical roles around the world, including as U.S. Ambassador to Singapore, Deputy Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Asia, Deputy U.S. Trade Representative, U.S. Ambassador to China, and most recently, U.S. Ambassador to Russia. Huntsman is the only American in history to have served as Chief of Mission in both China and Russia. In all four Senate confirmations, he received unanimous votes.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Dr. Ayana Elizabeth Johnson</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Dr. Ayana Elizabeth Johnson is a marine biologist, policy expert, writer, and Brooklyn native. She is co-founder of Urban Ocean Lab, a think tank for the future of coastal cities. She co-edited the bestselling climate anthology All We Can Save, co-founded The All We Can Save Project, and co-created the Spotify/Gimlet climate solutions podcast How to Save a Planet. Recently, she co-authored the Blue New Deal, a roadmap for including the ocean in climate policy. Previously, she was executive director of the Waitt Institute, developed policy at the Environmental Protection Agency and National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and taught as an adjunct professor at New York University.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Ambassador Kristie A. Kenney</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Ambassador Kristie Kenney holds the U.S. State Department’s highest rank of Career Ambassador. Over the course of her 35+-year career at the State Department, she represented the United States abroad as Ambassador three times and served in senior positions at the State Department and the National Security Council, including service as the 32nd Counselor of the State Department. As Ambassador to Thailand, Ambassador Kenney led U.S. assistance during Thailand’s devastating 2011 floods and managed the response to the 2014 military coup. She was the first female to head U.S. Embassy Bangkok, one of the United States’ largest diplomatic missions with over 3,000 staff. She is currently an adjunct professor at Georgetown University, teaching courses on leadership and public speaking.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Gilman G. Louie</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Gilman Louie is CEO and co-founder of America’s Frontier Fund, where he is responsible for the vision and leadership of the organization. Louie brings over 30 years of national security and investment experience. He served as an early CEO of In-Q-Tel—the pioneering technology investment firm funded by the Central Intelligence Agency—from 1999-2006, as an expert and Special Government Employee to the Defense Innovation Board from 2016-2020, and as a Commissioner on the National Security Commission on Artificial Intelligence from 2018-2021.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Katherine Maher</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Katherine Maher is the former chief executive officer and executive director of the Wikimedia Foundation who oversaw the operations of the organization and its professional staff. Katherine has spent her career at the intersection of technology, human rights, democracy and international development. Before joining the Foundation, she was Advocacy Director for the international digital rights organization Access in Washington, DC, where she worked on global policy issues related to freedom of expression, access to information and privacy.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Dr. James M. Manyika</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Dr. James Manyika is Senior Vice President at Google-Alphabet and a member of the senior leadership team where he focuses on Technology &amp; Society on areas ranging from AI, computing infrastructure, to the future of work, the digital economy and sustainability that have potential for broad impact on society. He is Senior Partner emeritus of McKinsey &amp; Company, and is Chair and director emeritus of the McKinsey Global Institute (MGI). At Mckinsey, he advised the chief executives of many of the world’s leading companies on technology and business strategies, and he led MGI’s research on technology, the economy, competitiveness, and other global economy trends.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Dr. Meghan L. O’Sullivan</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Meghan L. O’Sullivan is an educator, writer, former policymaker and diplomat, and advisor to companies. Throughout her career, she has been dedicated to resolving conflict and understanding the intersection of energy and geopolitics. Meghan has sought to help rebuild countries and craft constitutions and other frameworks for governing divided societies through her past positions, including two years in Iraq, as special assistant to President George W. Bush and Deputy National Security Advisor for Iraq and Afghanistan, and as a Vice Chair of the All Party peace negotiations in Northern Ireland in 2013.</span><span> </span></p>
<p><strong><span>Annise D. Parker</span></strong></p>
<p><span>The Honorable Annise Parker served the people of Houston with three terms as City Council member, three terms as City Controller, and three terms as Mayor. She is the only person in Houston history to have held all three offices. She was the first openly LGBT mayor of a major American city. Mayor Parker is currently President and CEO of The Victory Fund and Victory Institute. She served on President Obama’s State, Local and Tribal Leaders Task Force on Climate Preparedness and Resilience, on the Global Commission on the Economy and Climate, as a steering committee member of the C40 Cities Climate Leadership Group, and on the board of the Texas Environmental Research Consortium. </span><span> </span></p>
<p><strong><span>Vincent R. Stewart</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Retired Lieutenant General Vince Stewart, USMC is Chief Inclusion and Innovation Officer for Ankura and the Founder and CEO of Stewart Global Solutions, an international consulting company focused on issues pertaining to cybersecurity, geopolitical intelligence, strategic planning, and crisis management. Stewart previously served as Deputy Commander of the United States Cyber Command, where he provided strategic leadership to more than 10,000 personnel executing full spectrum cyberspace operations, including securing the Department of Defense’s Information Network. He also served as Director of the Defense Intelligence Agency, delivering intelligence on the military capabilities of potential adversaries and providing briefings to the President of the United States and National Security staff regarding global emerging threats and opportunities.</span></p>
<ul>
<li><a class="external-link__pdf" href="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/USSTATEBPA/2022/06/17/file_attachments/2188490/Foreign%20Affairs%20Policy%20Board%20Biographies.pdf" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Foreign Affairs Policy Board Biographies</span><span class="filesize icon-pdf"> </span></a></li>
</ul>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span>Today, Secretary Blinken announced his selections for the U.S. Department of State’s Foreign Affairs Policy Board.</span></p>
<p><span>Since its establishment in 2011, the Board has provided independent advice on the conduct of U.S. foreign policy and diplomacy, consistent with each Secretary of State and administration’s evolving priorities for it.</span></p>
<p><span>Secretary Blinken has sought to build a diverse board that could advance the Department’s efforts to better root American diplomacy in the needs and aspirations of the American people. With expertise at the intersection of foreign and domestic policy, the Board will focus on the issues of increasing importance to the lives and livelihoods of Americans in the decade ahead, including cybersecurity and emerging technologies, climate and energy, international economics, global health, and strategic competition with the People’s Republic of China.</span></p>
<p><span>Co-Chairs</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Thomas Donilon</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Thomas E. Donilon is Chairman of the BlackRock Investment Institute. He served as National Security Advisor to President Barack Obama. In that capacity Mr. Donilon oversaw the U.S. National Security Council staff, chaired the cabinet level National Security Principals Committee, provided the president’s daily national security briefing, and was responsible for the coordination and integration of the administration’s foreign policy, intelligence, and military efforts. Mr. Donilon also oversaw the White House’s cybersecurity and international energy efforts and served as the President’s personal emissary to a number of world leaders. Mr. Donilon has worked with and advised three U.S. presidents.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Cecilia Muñoz</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Cecilia Muñoz is a national leader in public policy and public interest technology with nearly three decades of experience in the non-profit sector and government. She was the first Latina to lead the White House Domestic Policy Council, serving 8 years on President Obama’s senior team. She led the domestic and economic policy team for the Biden/Harris presidential transition and serves as a senior advisor to New America in Washington, DC. An internationally recognized expert on immigration policy, in 2021, she co-founded Welcome.US, an organization that mobilizes civil society to support the resettlement of Afghan evacuees and other newcomers to the United States. Cecilia started her career at the National Council of La Raza (now UNIDOS US), the nation’s largest Hispanic policy and advocacy organization, where she spent 20 years focused on immigration, civil rights, education, and a broad range of policy concerns.</span></p>
<p><span>Members</span><span> </span></p>
<p><strong><span>David Autor</span></strong></p>
<p><span>David Autor is Ford Professor in the MIT Department of Economics, Vice President of the American Economic Association, codirector of the NBER Labor Studies Program and the JPAL Work of the Future experimental initiative. His scholarship explores the labor-market impacts of technological change and globalization on job polarization, skill demands, earnings levels and inequality, and electoral outcomes. Autor has received numerous awards for both his scholarship—the National Science Foundation CAREER Award, an Alfred P. Sloan Foundation Fellowship, the Sherwin Rosen Prize for outstanding contributions to the field of Labor Economics, the Andrew Carnegie Fellowship in 2019, the Society for Progress Medal in 2021—and for his teaching, including the MIT MacVicar Faculty Fellowship. In a 2019 article, the Economist magazine labeled him as “The academic voice of the American worker.”</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Dr. Sameer Bhalotra</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Dr. Sameer Bhalotra is the Co-founder &amp; CEO of ActZero, a security company based in Menlo Park, California. He previously worked in cybersecurity at Google and as a Board member of numerous security startups. In government, he served as Senior Director for Cybersecurity on the National Security Council staff at the White House, Cybersecurity &amp; Technology Lead for the Senate Select Committee on Intelligence, and in various roles in the Intelligence Community. He is affiliated with the US Secret Service Cyber Investigations Advisory Board, Center for Strategic and International Studies, Stanford University&#8217;s Center for International Security and Cooperation, and Harvard University’s Kennedy School of Government.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Dr. Hal Brands</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Hal Brands is the Henry A. Kissinger Distinguished Professor of Global Affairs at the Johns Hopkins School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS) and a senior fellow at the American Enterprise Institute. He is also a columnist for Bloomberg Opinion. Brands is the author or co-author of numerous books, most recently, The Lessons of Tragedy: Statecraft and World Order (2019), The Twilight Struggle: What the Cold War Teaches Us About Great-Power Rivalry Today (2022), and Danger Zone: The Coming Crisis with China (2022). Hal has also served as Special Assistant to the Secretary of Defense for Strategic Planning from 2015 to 2016, as lead writer for the Commission on the National Defense Strategy for the United States, and has consulted with a range of government offices and agencies.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Mariano-Florentino (Tino) Cuéllar</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Tino Cuéllar is the tenth president of the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace. A former justice of the Supreme Court of California, he served two U.S. presidents at the White House and in federal agencies and was a faculty member at Stanford University for two decades. During nearly seven years on California’s highest court, he wrote opinions addressing separation of powers, federalism, policing and criminal justice, democracy, technology and privacy, and climate and environmental policy among other issues, and led the court system’s efforts to better meet the needs of millions of limited English speakers.  </span><span>    </span></p>
<p><strong><span>Mitchell E. Daniels, Jr.</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Mitchell E. Daniels, Jr. is the 12th president of Purdue University and the former governor of Indiana. He was elected Indiana’s 49th governor in 2004 in his first bid for any elected office, and then re-elected in 2008 with more votes than any candidate in the state&#8217;s history. Prior to becoming governor, Daniels served as senior advisor to President Ronald Reagan and Director of the Office of Management and Budget under President George W. Bush. President Daniels also comes from a successful career in business, holding numerous top management positions. From 1987-1990, Daniels served as the CEO of the Hudson Institute.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Janine Davidson, Ph.D</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Janine Davidson, Ph.D. is president of Metropolitan State University of Denver, Colorado’s third largest and most diverse public university. Davidson is a national thought leader in higher education and on topics such as public service, U.S. foreign policy and national security. Dr. Davidson served in various senior civilian Pentagon positions, most recently as the 32nd undersecretary of the U.S. Navy. Previously she served as the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Plans and was also a senior civil servant in the stability operations office in the office of the Secretary of Defense. Davidson began her career as an Air Force officer and cargo pilot. She was a distinguished graduate of the Air Force Squadron Officer School and was the first woman to fly the Air Force’s tactical C-130.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Cathy Feingold</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Cathy Feingold is a leading advocate on foreign policy centered in the priorities of working people and their families. She brings more than 20 years of experience in trade and global economic policy, and worker, human and women&#8217;s rights issues. As director of the AFL-CIO’s International Department, she represents over 12.5 million workers and is a committed and passionate advocate, strategic campaigner and policy expert. In 2018, Feingold was elected Deputy President of the International Trade Union Confederation, the organization representing 200 million unionized workers worldwide and headquartered in Belgium, Brussels and she is a member of the Trade Union Advisory Committee at the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Margaret A. Hamburg, MD</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Dr. Margaret Hamburg is an internationally recognized leader in public health and medicine, who currently serves as chair of the Nuclear Threat Initiative’s Bio Advisory Group. She previously served as foreign secretary of the National Academy of Medicine and is a former Commissioner of the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA), having served for almost six years. Before joining FDA, Hamburg was founding vice president and senior scientist at the Nuclear Threat Initiative. Previous government positions include Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Health Commissioner for New York City, and Assistant Director of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, National Institutes of Health.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Jon M. Huntsman, Jr.</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Jon Huntsman currently serves as Vice Chair of Ford Motor Company. He has spent considerable time in public service at the state, national, and international levels. Huntsman began his career in public service as a staff assistant to President Ronald Reagan. He has served each of the five U.S. presidents since then in critical roles around the world, including as U.S. Ambassador to Singapore, Deputy Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Asia, Deputy U.S. Trade Representative, U.S. Ambassador to China, and most recently, U.S. Ambassador to Russia. Huntsman is the only American in history to have served as Chief of Mission in both China and Russia. In all four Senate confirmations, he received unanimous votes.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Dr. Ayana Elizabeth Johnson</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Dr. Ayana Elizabeth Johnson is a marine biologist, policy expert, writer, and Brooklyn native. She is co-founder of Urban Ocean Lab, a think tank for the future of coastal cities. She co-edited the bestselling climate anthology All We Can Save, co-founded The All We Can Save Project, and co-created the Spotify/Gimlet climate solutions podcast How to Save a Planet. Recently, she co-authored the Blue New Deal, a roadmap for including the ocean in climate policy. Previously, she was executive director of the Waitt Institute, developed policy at the Environmental Protection Agency and National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and taught as an adjunct professor at New York University.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Ambassador Kristie A. Kenney</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Ambassador Kristie Kenney holds the U.S. State Department’s highest rank of Career Ambassador. Over the course of her 35+-year career at the State Department, she represented the United States abroad as Ambassador three times and served in senior positions at the State Department and the National Security Council, including service as the 32nd Counselor of the State Department. As Ambassador to Thailand, Ambassador Kenney led U.S. assistance during Thailand’s devastating 2011 floods and managed the response to the 2014 military coup. She was the first female to head U.S. Embassy Bangkok, one of the United States’ largest diplomatic missions with over 3,000 staff. She is currently an adjunct professor at Georgetown University, teaching courses on leadership and public speaking.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Gilman G. Louie</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Gilman Louie is CEO and co-founder of America’s Frontier Fund, where he is responsible for the vision and leadership of the organization. Louie brings over 30 years of national security and investment experience. He served as an early CEO of In-Q-Tel—the pioneering technology investment firm funded by the Central Intelligence Agency—from 1999-2006, as an expert and Special Government Employee to the Defense Innovation Board from 2016-2020, and as a Commissioner on the National Security Commission on Artificial Intelligence from 2018-2021.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Katherine Maher</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Katherine Maher is the former chief executive officer and executive director of the Wikimedia Foundation who oversaw the operations of the organization and its professional staff. Katherine has spent her career at the intersection of technology, human rights, democracy and international development. Before joining the Foundation, she was Advocacy Director for the international digital rights organization Access in Washington, DC, where she worked on global policy issues related to freedom of expression, access to information and privacy.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Dr. James M. Manyika</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Dr. James Manyika is Senior Vice President at Google-Alphabet and a member of the senior leadership team where he focuses on Technology &amp; Society on areas ranging from AI, computing infrastructure, to the future of work, the digital economy and sustainability that have potential for broad impact on society. He is Senior Partner emeritus of McKinsey &amp; Company, and is Chair and director emeritus of the McKinsey Global Institute (MGI). At Mckinsey, he advised the chief executives of many of the world’s leading companies on technology and business strategies, and he led MGI’s research on technology, the economy, competitiveness, and other global economy trends.</span></p>
<p><strong><span>Dr. Meghan L. O’Sullivan</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Meghan L. O’Sullivan is an educator, writer, former policymaker and diplomat, and advisor to companies. Throughout her career, she has been dedicated to resolving conflict and understanding the intersection of energy and geopolitics. Meghan has sought to help rebuild countries and craft constitutions and other frameworks for governing divided societies through her past positions, including two years in Iraq, as special assistant to President George W. Bush and Deputy National Security Advisor for Iraq and Afghanistan, and as a Vice Chair of the All Party peace negotiations in Northern Ireland in 2013.</span><span> </span></p>
<p><strong><span>Annise D. Parker</span></strong></p>
<p><span>The Honorable Annise Parker served the people of Houston with three terms as City Council member, three terms as City Controller, and three terms as Mayor. She is the only person in Houston history to have held all three offices. She was the first openly LGBT mayor of a major American city. Mayor Parker is currently President and CEO of The Victory Fund and Victory Institute. She served on President Obama’s State, Local and Tribal Leaders Task Force on Climate Preparedness and Resilience, on the Global Commission on the Economy and Climate, as a steering committee member of the C40 Cities Climate Leadership Group, and on the board of the Texas Environmental Research Consortium. </span><span> </span></p>
<p><strong><span>Vincent R. Stewart</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Retired Lieutenant General Vince Stewart, USMC is Chief Inclusion and Innovation Officer for Ankura and the Founder and CEO of Stewart Global Solutions, an international consulting company focused on issues pertaining to cybersecurity, geopolitical intelligence, strategic planning, and crisis management. Stewart previously served as Deputy Commander of the United States Cyber Command, where he provided strategic leadership to more than 10,000 personnel executing full spectrum cyberspace operations, including securing the Department of Defense’s Information Network. He also served as Director of the Defense Intelligence Agency, delivering intelligence on the military capabilities of potential adversaries and providing briefings to the President of the United States and National Security staff regarding global emerging threats and opportunities.</span></p>
<ul>
<li><a class="external-link__pdf" href="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/USSTATEBPA/2022/06/17/file_attachments/2188490/Foreign%20Affairs%20Policy%20Board%20Biographies.pdf" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Foreign Affairs Policy Board Biographies</span><span class="filesize icon-pdf"> </span></a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
