<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 01:20:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Moscow Mechanism Invoked by 45 OSCE States to Review Reported Abuses by Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/moscow-mechanism-invoked-by-45-osce-states-to-review-reported-abuses-by-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 01:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>With Ukraine’s agreement, the United States and 44 other countries have invoked the OSCE Moscow Mechanism.  This action will establish an expert mission to address our grave concerns regarding the humanitarian and human rights impacts on the people of Ukraine caused by Russia’s further invasion with the support of Belarus.  We have seen the troubling media reports of human rights abuses and violations of humanitarian law by Russia’s forces, including the mounting number of civilian casualties and extensive damage to civilian infrastructure.  The OSCE expert mission will work impartially to establish the facts and circumstances surrounding possible contraventions of OSCE commitments and violations and abuses of international human rights law and international humanitarian law by Russia’s forces.  The expert mission will prepare a report that will be shared with all OSCE participating States and relevant accountability mechanisms, including national, regional, and international courts and tribunals.  The United States and our partners will hold Russia and its forces accountable for all human rights abuses, violations of international humanitarian law, war crimes, and crimes against humanity they commit in Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>With Ukraine’s agreement, the United States and 44 other countries have invoked the OSCE Moscow Mechanism.  This action will establish an expert mission to address our grave concerns regarding the humanitarian and human rights impacts on the people of Ukraine caused by Russia’s further invasion with the support of Belarus.  We have seen the troubling media reports of human rights abuses and violations of humanitarian law by Russia’s forces, including the mounting number of civilian casualties and extensive damage to civilian infrastructure.  The OSCE expert mission will work impartially to establish the facts and circumstances surrounding possible contraventions of OSCE commitments and violations and abuses of international human rights law and international humanitarian law by Russia’s forces.  The expert mission will prepare a report that will be shared with all OSCE participating States and relevant accountability mechanisms, including national, regional, and international courts and tribunals.  The United States and our partners will hold Russia and its forces accountable for all human rights abuses, violations of international humanitarian law, war crimes, and crimes against humanity they commit in Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement of the Syria Special Envoy Meeting </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-of-the-syria-special-envoy-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:40:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Representatives of the Arab League, Egypt, the European Union, France, Germany, Iraq, Jordan, Norway, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Turkey, the United Kingdom, and the United States met in Washington D.C. on March 3 to discuss the ongoing crisis in Syria.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>We remain committed to the pursuit of a political resolution to the Syrian crisis in accordance with UNSCR 2254 that will protect the rights and dignity of all Syrians.  As we near the 11th commemoration of the peaceful Syrian uprising on March 15, we acknowledge the continued suffering of the Syrian people, which is unacceptable and must end.  We continue to call for a nationwide ceasefire and respect for international humanitarian law, and to stress the importance of unhindered access to life-saving humanitarian assistance through all modalities, including through the re-authorization of cross-border humanitarian aid delivery, to which there is no alternative, as well as cross-line aid and early recovery projects consistent with UNSCR 2585.  We reaffirmed our support for the unity and territorial integrity of Syria and our commitment to the fight against terrorism in all its forms and manifestations.</p>
<p>We welcomed the briefing of UN Special Envoy Geir Pedersen, and took note of his efforts to build momentum, including through the step-for-step process, in accordance with our strong support to advance a comprehensive and inclusive political solution according to UNSCR 2254, as well as the implementation of all its aspects<strong>.</strong>  We call for concrete outcomes from the seventh round of the upcoming March session of Constitutional Committee. <strong> </strong>We will continue to press for accountability, especially for the most serious crimes perpetrated in Syria, including the use of chemical weapons, as well as to press for the release of the arbitrarily detained and a full accounting of the missing.  We welcomed ongoing efforts to prosecute crimes committed in Syria.  We urged continued support to Syrian refugees and host countries until Syrians can voluntarily return home with safety and dignity in line with UNHCR standards.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Representatives of the Arab League, Egypt, the European Union, France, Germany, Iraq, Jordan, Norway, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Turkey, the United Kingdom, and the United States met in Washington D.C. on March 3 to discuss the ongoing crisis in Syria.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>We remain committed to the pursuit of a political resolution to the Syrian crisis in accordance with UNSCR 2254 that will protect the rights and dignity of all Syrians.  As we near the 11th commemoration of the peaceful Syrian uprising on March 15, we acknowledge the continued suffering of the Syrian people, which is unacceptable and must end.  We continue to call for a nationwide ceasefire and respect for international humanitarian law, and to stress the importance of unhindered access to life-saving humanitarian assistance through all modalities, including through the re-authorization of cross-border humanitarian aid delivery, to which there is no alternative, as well as cross-line aid and early recovery projects consistent with UNSCR 2585.  We reaffirmed our support for the unity and territorial integrity of Syria and our commitment to the fight against terrorism in all its forms and manifestations.</p>
<p>We welcomed the briefing of UN Special Envoy Geir Pedersen, and took note of his efforts to build momentum, including through the step-for-step process, in accordance with our strong support to advance a comprehensive and inclusive political solution according to UNSCR 2254, as well as the implementation of all its aspects<strong>.</strong>  We call for concrete outcomes from the seventh round of the upcoming March session of Constitutional Committee. <strong> </strong>We will continue to press for accountability, especially for the most serious crimes perpetrated in Syria, including the use of chemical weapons, as well as to press for the release of the arbitrarily detained and a full accounting of the missing.  We welcomed ongoing efforts to prosecute crimes committed in Syria.  We urged continued support to Syrian refugees and host countries until Syrians can voluntarily return home with safety and dignity in line with UNHCR standards.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>World Wildlife Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/world-wildlife-day-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 23:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320434</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>We join in marking World Wildlife Day with many partners around the world. Together, we can conserve the diversity of life on this planet, which is critical for supporting healthy ecosystems.</p>
<p>Many wildlife species are under increasing threats from wildlife trafficking and nature crime. Wildlife trafficking is a security threat and an especially harmful form of transnational organized crime, often with far reaching impacts on nature.  Wildlife trafficking undermines the rule of law, facilitates corruption, deprives communities of legitimate livelihoods and natural resources, and contributes to the spread of disease.</p>
<p>As we seek to end the COVID-19 pandemic, the United States also endeavors to strengthen global health systems and health security including through promoting the One Health approach.  Strengthening the One Health approach will require tackling the upstream drivers of zoonotic disease risks such as illegal deforestation and wildlife trafficking.</p>
<p>We know what is possible when we work to conserve biodiversity.  As just one example, thanks to decades of hard work, our national symbol – the bald eagle – has been brought back from the brink of extinction and is no longer endangered.  The United States remains committed to leading global efforts to secure the continued existence of protected wildlife in their natural habits by conserving ecosystems, protecting biodiversity, and combating wildlife trafficking.  Together, we will continue to make sure that biodiversity – including species such as rhinos, tigers, and pangolins – continues to thrive.</p>
<p>We are currently facing the twin crises of biodiversity loss and climate change, adding pressure to ecosystems and their ability to function.  The Administration’s <a class="external-link__pdf" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Plan_to_Conserve_Global_Forests_final.pdf" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Plan to Conserve Global Forests: Critical Carbon Sinks</span><span class="filesize icon-pdf"> </span></a> released late last year details a whole-of-government approach to conserving, restoring, and sustainably managing forests and other ecosystems at home and abroad in order to combat these crises and ensure intact forests can continue to support wildlife.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>We join in marking World Wildlife Day with many partners around the world. Together, we can conserve the diversity of life on this planet, which is critical for supporting healthy ecosystems.</p>
<p>Many wildlife species are under increasing threats from wildlife trafficking and nature crime. Wildlife trafficking is a security threat and an especially harmful form of transnational organized crime, often with far reaching impacts on nature.  Wildlife trafficking undermines the rule of law, facilitates corruption, deprives communities of legitimate livelihoods and natural resources, and contributes to the spread of disease.</p>
<p>As we seek to end the COVID-19 pandemic, the United States also endeavors to strengthen global health systems and health security including through promoting the One Health approach.  Strengthening the One Health approach will require tackling the upstream drivers of zoonotic disease risks such as illegal deforestation and wildlife trafficking.</p>
<p>We know what is possible when we work to conserve biodiversity.  As just one example, thanks to decades of hard work, our national symbol – the bald eagle – has been brought back from the brink of extinction and is no longer endangered.  The United States remains committed to leading global efforts to secure the continued existence of protected wildlife in their natural habits by conserving ecosystems, protecting biodiversity, and combating wildlife trafficking.  Together, we will continue to make sure that biodiversity – including species such as rhinos, tigers, and pangolins – continues to thrive.</p>
<p>We are currently facing the twin crises of biodiversity loss and climate change, adding pressure to ecosystems and their ability to function.  The Administration’s <a class="external-link__pdf" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Plan_to_Conserve_Global_Forests_final.pdf" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Plan to Conserve Global Forests: Critical Carbon Sinks</span><span class="filesize icon-pdf"> </span></a> released late last year details a whole-of-government approach to conserving, restoring, and sustainably managing forests and other ecosystems at home and abroad in order to combat these crises and ensure intact forests can continue to support wildlife.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Targeting Russian Elites, Disinformation Outlets, and Defense Enterprises</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/targeting-russian-elites-disinformation-outlets-and-defense-enterprises/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 23:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320412</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States remains united with our allies and partners in our commitment to ensure the Government of Russia pays a severe economic and diplomatic price for its aggression against Ukraine.  Today we are targeting Russian elites and their financial networks and assets, major Russian disinformation outlets that contribute to the destabilization of Ukraine, and defense enterprises of the Russian Federation, as well as imposing additional export controls on Russian oil and gas refining.  These actions make it clear there is nowhere to hide for individuals and entities that support Russia’s flagrant war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Today’s actions by the Department of State and the Department of the Treasury target some of the wealthiest Russian elites close to Putin:  Alisher Usmanov, Boris Arkady, and Igor Rotenberg, and their family members and entities connected to them.  These actions also target influential Russian executives:  Nikolai Tokarev, President of Transneft; Sergei Chemezov, CEO of Rostec; and Igor Shuvalov, Chairman of VEB.RF.  These individuals, part of President Putin’s inner circle, have enriched themselves at the expense of the Russian people, and their support has facilitated Putin’s war of choice against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Second, the U.S. government is targeting those involved in Russia’s global disinformation and destabilizing influence campaign, including in Ukraine.  The Department of State is designating Dmitry Peskov, the chief propagandist of the Russian Federation and Vladimir Putin’s spokesperson, under E.O. 14024.  The Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assest Control (OFAC) is designating Russian elite Yevgeniy Prigozhin, who has been previously designated under various sanctions authorities.  Today, OFAC also is designating Prigozhin’s wife Polina, daughter Lyubov, and son Pavel, who play various roles in his business enterprise.  In addition, OFAC is designating 26 individuals and seven entities associated with Russia’s global disinformation campaign, particularly those backed by Russian intelligence services.  These targets utilize organizations that purport to serve as legitimate news sites but instead spread disinformation and ultra-nationalist propaganda for the Russian Federation.  These 33 individuals and entities have been designated under various authorities, including E.O. 13661, E.O. 13694, as amended, E.O. 13848, and 224(a)(l)(B) Countering America&#8217;s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act (“CAATSA”).</p>
<p>Third, the Department of State is imposing substantial costs on Russia’s defense enterprises by sanctioning 22 defense-related firms.  These far-reaching sanctions target entities that develop and produce fighter aircraft, infantry fighting vehicles, electronic warfare systems, missiles, and unmanned aerial vehicles for Russia’s military.  These sanctions strike at the core of Putin’s war machine.</p>
<p>Fourth, the Department of Commerce is imposing export controls on oil and gas extraction equipment that support Russia’s refining capacity.  Because a significant portion of the Russian government’s revenue comes from the sale of oil and gas, these actions will degrade Russia’s ability to raise revenue to support and sustain its military aggression.  These measures also align U.S. export controls in this area with those of the European Union.</p>
<p>Finally, today the Department of State is announcing a new visa restriction policy to restrict the issuance of visas to certain Russian oligarchs, their family members, and close associates pursuant to Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act.  These oligarchs are known to direct, authorize, fund, significantly support, or carry out malign activities in support of Russia’s destabilizing foreign policy.  Restrictions may be lifted for individuals who cease their support for and involvement in the Russian government’s destabilizing activity.  In an initial action under this policy today, we are targeting 19 oligarchs and 47 family members and close associates.  We will continue to add names to this visa restriction policy as long as individuals continue to support and carry out destabilizing activity on behalf of the Kremlin.  We welcome recent similar actions by Allies and partners.</p>
<p>The United States commends the continued support of our allies and partners across the world in the face of the Russian aggression against Ukraine.  We also applaud the bravery of the Ukrainian people who are fighting in defense of their country and those who must endure this unprovoked Russian invasion.  We stand in solidarity with them and will continue to support the government and people of Ukraine in the face of the Kremlin’s aggression, and we are resolute in our support for Ukraine’s sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of State’s <a href="https://www.state.gov/targeting-russian-elites-and-defense-enterprises-of-russian-federation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">factsheet</a> and Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0628" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States remains united with our allies and partners in our commitment to ensure the Government of Russia pays a severe economic and diplomatic price for its aggression against Ukraine.  Today we are targeting Russian elites and their financial networks and assets, major Russian disinformation outlets that contribute to the destabilization of Ukraine, and defense enterprises of the Russian Federation, as well as imposing additional export controls on Russian oil and gas refining.  These actions make it clear there is nowhere to hide for individuals and entities that support Russia’s flagrant war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Today’s actions by the Department of State and the Department of the Treasury target some of the wealthiest Russian elites close to Putin:  Alisher Usmanov, Boris Arkady, and Igor Rotenberg, and their family members and entities connected to them.  These actions also target influential Russian executives:  Nikolai Tokarev, President of Transneft; Sergei Chemezov, CEO of Rostec; and Igor Shuvalov, Chairman of VEB.RF.  These individuals, part of President Putin’s inner circle, have enriched themselves at the expense of the Russian people, and their support has facilitated Putin’s war of choice against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Second, the U.S. government is targeting those involved in Russia’s global disinformation and destabilizing influence campaign, including in Ukraine.  The Department of State is designating Dmitry Peskov, the chief propagandist of the Russian Federation and Vladimir Putin’s spokesperson, under E.O. 14024.  The Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assest Control (OFAC) is designating Russian elite Yevgeniy Prigozhin, who has been previously designated under various sanctions authorities.  Today, OFAC also is designating Prigozhin’s wife Polina, daughter Lyubov, and son Pavel, who play various roles in his business enterprise.  In addition, OFAC is designating 26 individuals and seven entities associated with Russia’s global disinformation campaign, particularly those backed by Russian intelligence services.  These targets utilize organizations that purport to serve as legitimate news sites but instead spread disinformation and ultra-nationalist propaganda for the Russian Federation.  These 33 individuals and entities have been designated under various authorities, including E.O. 13661, E.O. 13694, as amended, E.O. 13848, and 224(a)(l)(B) Countering America&#8217;s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act (“CAATSA”).</p>
<p>Third, the Department of State is imposing substantial costs on Russia’s defense enterprises by sanctioning 22 defense-related firms.  These far-reaching sanctions target entities that develop and produce fighter aircraft, infantry fighting vehicles, electronic warfare systems, missiles, and unmanned aerial vehicles for Russia’s military.  These sanctions strike at the core of Putin’s war machine.</p>
<p>Fourth, the Department of Commerce is imposing export controls on oil and gas extraction equipment that support Russia’s refining capacity.  Because a significant portion of the Russian government’s revenue comes from the sale of oil and gas, these actions will degrade Russia’s ability to raise revenue to support and sustain its military aggression.  These measures also align U.S. export controls in this area with those of the European Union.</p>
<p>Finally, today the Department of State is announcing a new visa restriction policy to restrict the issuance of visas to certain Russian oligarchs, their family members, and close associates pursuant to Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act.  These oligarchs are known to direct, authorize, fund, significantly support, or carry out malign activities in support of Russia’s destabilizing foreign policy.  Restrictions may be lifted for individuals who cease their support for and involvement in the Russian government’s destabilizing activity.  In an initial action under this policy today, we are targeting 19 oligarchs and 47 family members and close associates.  We will continue to add names to this visa restriction policy as long as individuals continue to support and carry out destabilizing activity on behalf of the Kremlin.  We welcome recent similar actions by Allies and partners.</p>
<p>The United States commends the continued support of our allies and partners across the world in the face of the Russian aggression against Ukraine.  We also applaud the bravery of the Ukrainian people who are fighting in defense of their country and those who must endure this unprovoked Russian invasion.  We stand in solidarity with them and will continue to support the government and people of Ukraine in the face of the Kremlin’s aggression, and we are resolute in our support for Ukraine’s sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of State’s <a href="https://www.state.gov/targeting-russian-elites-and-defense-enterprises-of-russian-federation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">factsheet</a> and Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0628" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Senegalese President and African Union Assembly Chairperson Sall</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-senegalese-president-and-african-union-assembly-chairperson-sall/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 22:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Senegalese President and African Union Assembly Chairperson Macky Sall.  Secretary Blinken and President Sall discussed his priorities as AU Chair, focusing on combating the COVID-19 pandemic, addressing the climate crisis, and bolstering democracy on the continent.  Secretary Blinken underscored the importance of supporting Ukraine against Russia’s premeditated and unprovoked invasion, and reaffirmed the strength of the U.S. partnership with both the AU and Senegal.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Senegalese President and African Union Assembly Chairperson Macky Sall.  Secretary Blinken and President Sall discussed his priorities as AU Chair, focusing on combating the COVID-19 pandemic, addressing the climate crisis, and bolstering democracy on the continent.  Secretary Blinken underscored the importance of supporting Ukraine against Russia’s premeditated and unprovoked invasion, and reaffirmed the strength of the U.S. partnership with both the AU and Senegal.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with Austrian Secretary General of Foreign Affairs Launsky-Tieffenthal</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-austrian-secretary-general-of-foreign-affairs-launsky-tieffenthal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 20:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320371</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Austrian Secretary General for Foreign Affairs Peter Launsky-Tieffenthal to discuss Russia’s unjustified, unprovoked, and premeditated war against Ukraine. The two strongly condemned Russia’s further invasion into Ukraine as a flagrant violation of international law and contravention of OSCE principles and commitments. They both expressed firm support for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine and pledged continued coordination to support the people of Ukraine and impose massive costs on Russia and hold Russia’s leadership accountable. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Secretary General Launsky-Tieffenthal also agreed on strong support for stability in the Western Balkans and the countries’ European integration.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Austrian Secretary General for Foreign Affairs Peter Launsky-Tieffenthal to discuss Russia’s unjustified, unprovoked, and premeditated war against Ukraine. The two strongly condemned Russia’s further invasion into Ukraine as a flagrant violation of international law and contravention of OSCE principles and commitments. They both expressed firm support for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine and pledged continued coordination to support the people of Ukraine and impose massive costs on Russia and hold Russia’s leadership accountable. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Secretary General Launsky-Tieffenthal also agreed on strong support for stability in the Western Balkans and the countries’ European integration.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Travel to Turkey, Spain, Morocco, Algeria, and Egypt</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-travel-to-turkey-spain-morocco-algeria-and-egypt/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[U.S. Department of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 19:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320341</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman will travel to Istanbul and Ankara, Turkey; Madrid, Spain; Rabat and Casablanca, Morocco; Algiers, Algeria; and Cairo, Egypt from March 4 to 11.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman will begin her trip in Istanbul and Ankara, Turkey from March 4 to 5 to meet with Deputy Foreign Minister Sedat Onal and other officials to discuss Putin’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. The Deputy’s meetings will include discussions on further joint U.S.-Turkey cooperation and our shared interest in supporting Ukraine.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman will then travel to Madrid, Spain from March 6 to 8 to co-open the U.S.-Spain Cybersecurity Dialogue on March 7 with Spanish Secretary of State for Foreign and Global Affairs Ángeles Moreno Bau. The Deputy Secretary and the State Secretary will also meet bilaterally to discuss a range of issues and challenges including Russia’s attack against Ukraine, our coordinated response, and the strong transatlantic partnership. The Deputy Secretary will also speak with students and faculty at a Madrid-based university and participate in a discussion with women entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>The Deputy Secretary will then travel to Rabat and Casablanca, Morocco from March 8 to 9, where she will lead the U.S. delegation to the U.S.-Morocco Strategic Dialogue on Regional Political Issues. She will have a working lunch with Foreign Minister Nasser Bourita and meet with other senior government officials. She will also deliver keynote remarks at an International Women’s Day event featuring entrepreneurs and businesswomen and will meet with Moroccan youth.</p>
<p>Next, Deputy Secretary Sherman will travel to Algiers, Algeria from March 9 to 10. She will meet with President Abdelmadjid Tebboune to discuss bilateral and regional issues. On March 10, the Deputy Secretary will meet with Foreign Minister Ramtane Lamamra and lead the U.S. delegation for the fifth U.S.-Algerian Strategic Dialogue. The Deputy Secretary will also meet with high school and college women participating in a U.S.-sponsored STEM program and local representatives of U.S. businesses.</p>
<p>Finally, from March 10 to 11, Deputy Secretary Sherman will travel to Cairo, Egypt, where she will meet with Foreign Minister Sameh Shoukry and other senior Egyptian officials. The Deputy will also meet with the head of the National Council of Human Rights Moushira Khattab, host a discussion with Egyptian human rights advocates, and meet with Egyptian youth.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman will travel to Istanbul and Ankara, Turkey; Madrid, Spain; Rabat and Casablanca, Morocco; Algiers, Algeria; and Cairo, Egypt from March 4 to 11.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman will begin her trip in Istanbul and Ankara, Turkey from March 4 to 5 to meet with Deputy Foreign Minister Sedat Onal and other officials to discuss Putin’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. The Deputy’s meetings will include discussions on further joint U.S.-Turkey cooperation and our shared interest in supporting Ukraine.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman will then travel to Madrid, Spain from March 6 to 8 to co-open the U.S.-Spain Cybersecurity Dialogue on March 7 with Spanish Secretary of State for Foreign and Global Affairs Ángeles Moreno Bau. The Deputy Secretary and the State Secretary will also meet bilaterally to discuss a range of issues and challenges including Russia’s attack against Ukraine, our coordinated response, and the strong transatlantic partnership. The Deputy Secretary will also speak with students and faculty at a Madrid-based university and participate in a discussion with women entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>The Deputy Secretary will then travel to Rabat and Casablanca, Morocco from March 8 to 9, where she will lead the U.S. delegation to the U.S.-Morocco Strategic Dialogue on Regional Political Issues. She will have a working lunch with Foreign Minister Nasser Bourita and meet with other senior government officials. She will also deliver keynote remarks at an International Women’s Day event featuring entrepreneurs and businesswomen and will meet with Moroccan youth.</p>
<p>Next, Deputy Secretary Sherman will travel to Algiers, Algeria from March 9 to 10. She will meet with President Abdelmadjid Tebboune to discuss bilateral and regional issues. On March 10, the Deputy Secretary will meet with Foreign Minister Ramtane Lamamra and lead the U.S. delegation for the fifth U.S.-Algerian Strategic Dialogue. The Deputy Secretary will also meet with high school and college women participating in a U.S.-sponsored STEM program and local representatives of U.S. businesses.</p>
<p>Finally, from March 10 to 11, Deputy Secretary Sherman will travel to Cairo, Egypt, where she will meet with Foreign Minister Sameh Shoukry and other senior Egyptian officials. The Deputy will also meet with the head of the National Council of Human Rights Moushira Khattab, host a discussion with Egyptian human rights advocates, and meet with Egyptian youth.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Georgian President Zourabichvili</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-georgian-president-zourabichvili/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 18:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Georgian President Salome Zourabichvili about the global response to the Russian government’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine and about Russia’s continuing occupation of Georgia.</p>
<p>The Secretary expressed appreciation for the people of Georgia and President Zourabichvili’s personal, steadfast support for Ukraine.  He underscored the firm U.S. commitment to Georgia’s sovereignty and territorial integrity within its internationally recognized borders and noted the United States will continue to support the Georgian people in pursuing a democratic, peaceful, and prosperous Euro-Atlantic future.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Georgian President Salome Zourabichvili about the global response to the Russian government’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine and about Russia’s continuing occupation of Georgia.</p>
<p>The Secretary expressed appreciation for the people of Georgia and President Zourabichvili’s personal, steadfast support for Ukraine.  He underscored the firm U.S. commitment to Georgia’s sovereignty and territorial integrity within its internationally recognized borders and noted the United States will continue to support the Georgian people in pursuing a democratic, peaceful, and prosperous Euro-Atlantic future.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Slovak Foreign Minister Korcok</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-slovak-foreign-minister-korcok/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 17:15:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Slovak Foreign Minister Ivan Korcok. The Secretary condemned Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. The Secretary emphasized that the United States stands with all of our NATO Allies, as we stand together with Ukraine. Secretary Blinken thanked Foreign Minister Korcok for Slovakia’s unwavering commitment to provide protection for the hundreds of thousands fleeing Putin’s war and seeking refuge. The Secretary also expressed the United States’ continued appreciation for Slovakia’s humanitarian and political response to Russia’s hostilities.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Slovak Foreign Minister Ivan Korcok. The Secretary condemned Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. The Secretary emphasized that the United States stands with all of our NATO Allies, as we stand together with Ukraine. Secretary Blinken thanked Foreign Minister Korcok for Slovakia’s unwavering commitment to provide protection for the hundreds of thousands fleeing Putin’s war and seeking refuge. The Secretary also expressed the United States’ continued appreciation for Slovakia’s humanitarian and political response to Russia’s hostilities.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Foreign Minister Solano of Costa Rica, Foreign Minister Álvarez of the Dominican Republic, and Foreign Minister Mouynes of Panama</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-foreign-minister-solano-of-costa-rica-foreign-minister-alvarez-of-the-dominican-republic-and-foreign-minister-mouynes-of-panama/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 15:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320212</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Costa Rican Foreign Minister Rodolfo Solano Quirós, Dominican Foreign Minister Roberto Álvarez, and Panamanian Foreign Minister Erika Mouynes on March 2 in Washington, DC. Secretary Blinken expressed strong appreciation for the leadership role the three governments took in forming the Alliance for Development in Democracy, a model for how leaders in the Western Hemisphere can collaborate to make progress on issues of common concern. Secretary Blinken thanked the Foreign Ministers for their nations’ efforts to strengthen democratic institutions and norms, including supporting the Nicaraguan people as they strive to re-establish democracy and protect their human rights from Ortega-Murillo regime abuses. They also advanced ongoing joint efforts to improve safe, orderly, and humane migration throughout the region. On regional issues, the group further noted Honduras’ progress in carrying out a democratic transition, and the Xiomara Castro administration’s efforts to combat corruption. They discussed the importance of restoring democracy in Haiti through a Haitian-led dialogue. The group discussed plans to increase coordination on nearshoring, financing, and trade to bolster economic recovery from the effects of the pandemic. Finally, Secretary Blinken noted the valuable support all three countries in the global effort to stand up for democracy and sovereignty for Ukraine and respond to Russia’s aggression with decisive action.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Costa Rican Foreign Minister Rodolfo Solano Quirós, Dominican Foreign Minister Roberto Álvarez, and Panamanian Foreign Minister Erika Mouynes on March 2 in Washington, DC. Secretary Blinken expressed strong appreciation for the leadership role the three governments took in forming the Alliance for Development in Democracy, a model for how leaders in the Western Hemisphere can collaborate to make progress on issues of common concern. Secretary Blinken thanked the Foreign Ministers for their nations’ efforts to strengthen democratic institutions and norms, including supporting the Nicaraguan people as they strive to re-establish democracy and protect their human rights from Ortega-Murillo regime abuses. They also advanced ongoing joint efforts to improve safe, orderly, and humane migration throughout the region. On regional issues, the group further noted Honduras’ progress in carrying out a democratic transition, and the Xiomara Castro administration’s efforts to combat corruption. They discussed the importance of restoring democracy in Haiti through a Haitian-led dialogue. The group discussed plans to increase coordination on nearshoring, financing, and trade to bolster economic recovery from the effects of the pandemic. Finally, Secretary Blinken noted the valuable support all three countries in the global effort to stand up for democracy and sovereignty for Ukraine and respond to Russia’s aggression with decisive action.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
