<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 23:17:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; June 22, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-june-22-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 23:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=354219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:32 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks very much, and thanks very much, everyone, for joining today as we do today’s briefing by phone. I have a couple things at the top and then we’ll turn to your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-DEPARTMENT"></a> First, today the First Lady of the United States Dr. Jill Biden and sports icon and equality champion Billie Jean King headline an event hosted by the U.S. Department of State’s Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs, or ECA, in celebration of the 50th anniversary of Title IX, the landmark legislation that afforded women equal opportunity in education and sports across the United States. ECA, in partnership with espnW, highlighted the dramatic impact of Title IX in increasing the participation of women and girls in sports.</p>
<p>Through sports diplomacy exchange programs, such as the Department of State espnW’s Global Sports Mentoring Program, or GSMP, the department is expanding the footprint of Title IX and its message of equality and opportunity for women in every corner of the globe. Now in its 10th year, the GSMP promotes key tenets of Title IX, such as inclusion, access, and opportunity, and applies them globally. The women of the GSMP have positively and directly impacted more than 350,000 people through their action plans as part of the exchange, from advocating for social welfare policy in Brazil to using boxing to teaching self-defense and leadership skills to Kenyan women and girls, they are making a difference every day to advance equality around the world.</p>
<p>And next and finally, the department is pleased to announce that Mr. Collin Walsh, a foreign affairs officer in the Bureau of Diplomatic Security, Office of Rewards for Justice, has been named by <em>CAREERS and the disABLED</em> magazine a 2022 employee of the year for his resilience, professional accomplishments, and commitment to advocacy for persons with disabilities. In 2016, on his third day of Foreign Service orientation as a Diplomatic Security service special agent candidate, Mr. Walsh became physically paralyzed and was told he would never walk again. After two years dedicated entirely to physical recovery, Mr. Walsh returned to DS, walking with elbow-supported mobility aids.</p>
<p>In his new role, Mr. Walsh serves as a Civil Service foreign affairs officer in the DS Rewards for Justice Office, which offers rewards for information regarding those who threaten U.S. national security. Among his many accomplishments are overseeing the RFJ’s – RFJ’s global tips program, serving on a cross-functional rotation in the Office of the Legal Adviser, and leading an accessibility overhaul of the DS headquarters building. So congratulations again to Collin Walsh on behalf of all of us here at the Department of State.</p>
<p>With that, we will turn now to questions. We can start with the line of Matt Lee, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, okay. I got a couple. I’ll try to make them real quick. You can answer them in order. One is: The Secretary, as we know, is supposed to speak with the detainee families today. I realize that may not have happened yet, but can you tell us anything about what he’s planning to say?</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-AFGHANISTAN"></a> And then secondly: The SIGAR, the Special Inspector General for Afghan Reconstruction, has just sent a series of really blistering letters – one to Congress, one to Secretary Blinken, and one to Administrator Power, and one to the legal counsels of both State and USAID – accusing State and USAID of illegally withholding information related to the withdrawal from Afghanistan and current assistance, any kind of assistance, to the country. And obviously, this takes on more relevance, given the earthquake that just happened this morning. But what’s your response to this? Are you guys cooperating with SIGAR as you have, or have you decided that you don’t need to do that anymore? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks, Matt. So on your first question, you are correct that Secretary Blinken will have an engagement this afternoon with the families of Americans who are held hostage or wrongfully detained around the world. That engagement has not yet taken place. It will take place shortly this afternoon. I expect we’ll have an opportunity to provide you with a written readout in the aftermath of this engagement.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken quite frequently engages on a one-on-one basis with family members of Americans who are held hostage or wrongfully detained. This will be an opportunity for him – another opportunity for him – to meet as a collective with the families of those Americans who are wrongfully detained or held hostage. There will be, we expect, several dozen participants in this call. Of course, a setting like this is not entirely conducive to discussing the specifics of particular cases, but the Secretary will use it as an opportunity to underscore for all of these families the paramount priority we attach to doing everything we can to see the safe return of their loved ones from wherever they are held hostage.</p>
<p>And of course, he will continue to follow up on this engagement with one-on-one engagement with individual families, where he has and will continue to have an opportunity to update families on, in more precise terms, what we are doing to see their loved ones released from captivity. So we’ll have more on the call – or on the engagement after it takes place today.</p>
<p>In terms of your question on SIGAR, Matt, what I can tell you is that, as you know, SIGAR published a report last month regarding the collapse of the ANDSF and the factors that led to its demise. Our view is that the report does not reflect the consensus view of the State Department or of the U.S. Government, for that matter. Many parts of the U.S. Government, including the State Department, have unique insights into developments in Afghanistan last year that were not captured in the report. And we don’t concur with many aspects of the report. We refer you to the many statements that the State Department has made over the past year on Afghanistan regarding our assessments.</p>
<p>But the fact is, Matt, that SIGAR did not request input from the State Department for – in the process of drafting this report, nor did they afford us an opportunity to review the draft before it was finalized, as had been a regular process for other reports. If we have any additional reaction to letters that were – and responses that were given today, we’ll be sure to pass those along.</p>
<p>We’ll go to the line of Jennifer Hansler, please. Do we have – yes, we hear you now.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sorry. Sorry if this has already been asked. Are you aware of any U.S. citizens who are victims of this earthquake in Afghanistan? I know there is some concern about particularly the American hostage Mark Frerichs and – given his – where his whereabouts might be. Do you have any update on his status?</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-VENEZUELA"></a> And then separately, do you have any updates on Matthew Heath, the detained American in Venezuela? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks very much. So first, on the earthquake in Afghanistan, you probably just saw the statement that emanated from Secretary Blinken. Secretary Blinken, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, other senior officials, have put out statements today expressing our deep sorrow and our deep sympathy for those who perished in today’s devastating earthquake in Afghanistan as well as to the loved ones of the victims. The people of Afghanistan have undergone extraordinary hardship, and this tragedy only compounds that on top of an already dire humanitarian situation. Our humanitarian partners are responding already, including by sending medical teams to help people affected by the earthquake. As you heard from the Secretary and from the National Security Advisor, we’re assessing other potential response options as well.</p>
<p>We stand with the people of Afghanistan. We’re working with the international community to serve Afghans and to help alleviate the humanitarian crisis and suffering in Afghanistan, which has long predated the earthquake today, but of course which was compounded by the earthquake today.</p>
<p>In terms of potential American victims, there’s not anything I’m in a position to offer at the moment. Of course, the scale of the – of this tragedy is just enormous, so we will work very closely with posts around the world to determine if any Americans were implicated in today’s earthquake. But I’m not aware of any such reports just yet.</p>
<p>In terms of your second question, Matthew Heath, as we’ve said, was arrested in September 2020 on specious charges. His trial is still ongoing. We continue to press for the immediate and unconditional release of Matthew and all wrongfully detained U.S. nationals in Venezuela and everywhere around the world, as I’ve already said in the course of this briefing at every opportunity. Using wrongful detention as a bargaining chip represents a threat to the safety of everyone traveling, working, and living abroad. We do oppose this practice everywhere. I’m not in a position to provide an update on the health of this individual or any other American for privacy considerations, but we are monitoring Matthew’s health and welfare as closely as possible, and we’re in regular contact with his family on that.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Francesco Fontemaggi. Do we have Francesco?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hello. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yes, yes. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-AFGHANISTAN2"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong> Okay. Hi. Thank you. I wanted to follow up on Afghanistan. Has the U.S. Government been in touch with the Taliban to coordinate this humanitarian aid or assistance? Are you planning to coordinate with them or even to go through the Taliban power to bring this assistance to the Afghan people? I know this has been redlined for now, going through the Taliban. But is this something that you can do for this occurrence? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you. And Francesco, before I go there, let me just say, most importantly, thank you. I know this is likely your last briefing as the AFP’s State Department correspondent. I want to thank you for the tremendous time we’ve had working together collegially in your role with AFP and your role with the Correspondents’ Association. We’ll very much miss your presence in the briefing room, your presence in the bullpen, your presence on the S plane, your presence on our travel around the world. But I wish you all the best as you head to your next adventure in what probably are considered greener pastures in Paris. So <em>bon voyage</em>, and looking forward to staying in touch.</p>
<p>In terms of Afghanistan, I am not aware of any request for assistance that the United States Government has received from the Taliban. But we have been in touch with our humanitarian partners. As I mentioned before, our humanitarian partners are already in the process of responding. They’re sending medical teams to help those who are affected by the disaster. As you know, the United States has been a humanitarian leader for the people of Afghanistan. We’ve provided $720 million in humanitarian assistance in Afghanistan and support to Afghan refugees in the region through multilateral organizations and NGOs since mid-August of last year.</p>
<p>Just earlier this week, Special Representative for Afghanistan Tom West – he was in Geneva actually yesterday, where he met with humanitarian partners who are providing critical aid to the people of Afghanistan. We’ll continue to support their role in serving Afghans to alleviate the humanitarian crisis and suffering, and our commitment to the Afghan people is unwavering.</p>
<p>I imagine the humanitarian response to the earthquake will be a topic of conversation between U.S. officials and Taliban officials in the coming days, certainly going forward. But I am not aware that any such conversations have taken place just yet as we are focusing our efforts and our discussions on our humanitarian partners in the first instance.</p>
<p>We’ll go to the line of Iain Marlow.</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-UKRAINE"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Inaudible) question. I’m just wondering if you have any comment on statements from two companies, Viterra and Bunge, that say infrastructure at the Ukrainian port of Mykolaiv were damaged by Russian rockets. And this is obviously – these are food companies, and so this is sort of in line with other sort of attacks on grain and agricultural infrastructure, so I’m just wondering if there was any additional comment on these sort of – these reports coming out.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have any specific reaction to those reports, but we have had a consistent reaction to what has been a consistent practice on the part of the Russian Federation to damage and to potentially even target what is infrastructure that provides food and foodstuffs, not only for the people of Ukraine but for countries around the world.</p>
<p>Since the start of President Putin’s war in Ukraine, Russia’s forces have knocked offline, have destroyed silos; they have destroyed what used to be arable fields; they have left farmers incapable and unable to tend to their fields; and they have not only attacked ships at sea, but perhaps worse, worse yet, they have mounted what amounts to a blockade against the port where tens – where more than 20 tons of grain sits on ships that should be departing for destinations around the world to provide much-needed food and much-needed assistance to people in the region and well beyond.</p>
<p>We’ve undertaken quite a bit of travel since the start of President Putin’s further invasion of Ukraine on February 24th, and in recent weeks, in recent months, the food insecurity crisis that this unprovoked war of aggression has caused has been top of mind for countries and for leaders around the world, including in Los Angeles earlier this month where the Western Hemisphere came together, including in our travels in Latin America and Europe as well.</p>
<p>And of course, we announced this morning that tomorrow Secretary Blinken will be departing for Berlin, where he will take part in a food security conference hosted by the German Government and German Foreign Minister Baerbock. So this will be a topic that will be high on the agenda later this week. It will be high on the agenda when President Biden travels to the G7 later this week as well. And you’ll be hearing more from us later today, from some of our senior officials, on this broad challenge, and you’ll be hearing more from the White House as well in short order.</p>
<p>We’ll got to the line of Janne Pak.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes, we can.</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-SOUTHKOREA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes. Hi, Ned. Thanks for (inaudible) me. I have a question about NATO meeting. Regarding South Korea’s participation in NATO summit next week, South Korea is not a NATO member country. What expectation does the U.S. have for South Korea’s role in attending the NATO summit next week? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks very much, Janne. You are right that South Korea, of course, is not a NATO Ally, but South Korea is an important partner of the NATO Alliance and of individual Allies. And this will be the second time in recent months that partners from the Indo-Pacific have been included in NATO consultations. The fact is that even though NATO is an Alliance, a defensive Alliance that protects and promotes the interests of its Allies in a different part of the world, there are a number of shared challenges that we face, whether it is the challenge from the PRC, whether it is the challenge of cyber and emerging technology that all of our countries face.</p>
<p>But at the end of the day, what we seek to uphold in the Indo-Pacific with our ROK allies and what NATO seeks to uphold in Europe is precisely the same thing, and that is the rules-based order that has promoted and led to what has been unprecedented levels of stability and prosperity around the world. Russia’s affront and assault – affront to and assault on that rules-based international order is a threat not only to Ukraine and to the people of Ukraine, but to that order everywhere around the world. And anytime that order comes under assault and it is not vigorously protected and defended, that order is undermined everywhere.</p>
<p>That’s precisely why we, together with our partners in the Indo-Pacific, have stood up to aggression in that arena as well. When countries in that region seek to challenge the rules-based international order, we have come together to make clear that it is an order that we will protect and promote in the face of challenge, whether that’s in Europe, the Indo-Pacific, or anywhere else.</p>
<p>So I know the Secretary is looking forward to consultations with our partners in the Indo-Pacific in the coming days, as is President Biden, who recently returned from both Japan and the ROK last month, not all that long ago.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Alex Raufoglu.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you so much, Ned. Two questions here. Russia’s Lavrov apparently will travel to Indonesia to take part in the G20 ministerial on July the 7th. He even is thinking to have bilats with Chinese, Brazilian, South African, Mexican colleagues, according to his spox, Zakharova. Is it your position that there is no place for Russia’s participation in the G20 summit? And if so, any steps you’re planning to take to prevent this from happening?</p>
<p>And secondly, Lavrov is also planning to go to Azerbaijan tomorrow to discuss the Karabakh issue. President Aliyev says that the Minsk Group is, quote/unquote, “dead.” Is that your position as well? Is Minsk Group alive, in your opinion, because the U.S. is the – one of the co-chairs? Thanks so much.</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-G20"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks very much, Alex. So when it comes to the G20, it’s an important forum for world and global economic issues. Secretary Blinken will attend to ensure that our interests are represented. We’ll have more details on that travel in the coming days.</p>
<p>But we also have to be clear that Russia’s war on Ukraine has caused global economic instability, and the United States has no intention, as a result, of reducing pressure on the Kremlin until and unless Russia’s aggression against Ukraine comes to a halt. We have reiterated to the Indonesian presidency that the G20 must be relevant to helping Ukraine deal with and recover from the invasion, and I’m confident that Russia’s aggression against Ukraine will be high on the agenda when G20 partners come together in Bali next month. During that set of days we’ll also have an opportunity to engage with allies as well as partners, and I know that Russia’s aggression will be a primary conversation for us as well.</p>
<p>When it comes to the meetings that Foreign Minister Lavrov will have in Bali at the G20 ministerial, I would leave that to the Russians to describe. For us, we are much less concerned about whom he meets with and much more concerned with the messages that are imparted during those meetings. And what we have emphasized over the course of the weeks since February 24th is that every responsible country around the world has an obligation to make very clear to the Russian Federation that its aggression against Ukraine, its peaceful neighbor, cannot be tolerated and will be met – and has been met – with steep costs and consequences for Russia. That’s the message that we’ll continue to convey; that’s the message we expect every responsible country around the world to convey as well.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Luis Rojas.</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-VENEZUELA2"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yes. Thank you, Ned. Thank you for having me. My question is Juan Guaidó’s wife Fabiana Rosales is visiting Washington, have met with senior officials. Do you have any update on the political prisoner of Venezuela, or the possible dialogue between the opposition and the Maduro government, or any question about Venezuela? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, thanks very much. Our contention continues to be that Venezuelan-led negotiations between the Maduro regime and the Unitary Platform represent the best path to restore to Venezuelans the democracy they deserve, and to alleviate their suffering.</p>
<p>We, for our part, remain steadfast in our commitment to the Venezuelan people, which includes supporting their democratic aspirations and providing assistance to address their humanitarian crisis. And we count ourselves among a broad coalition of nations that support these goals.</p>
<p>Look, we believe that, under the right circumstances and with the support of the international community, the parties are better positioned to negotiate steps toward the solution to the Venezuelan crisis. And we’ve urged the parties – the opposition and the Maduro regime – to return to dialogue, to return to Mexico City, and we’ve made clear that we would review our sanctions policies in response to constructive steps by the Maduro regime and if the Venezuelan parties make meaningful progress in those Venezuelan-led negotiations in Mexico.</p>
<p>We have had an opportunity in recent days, including at the most senior levels, including when President Biden spoke to Juan Guaidó on his way to Los Angeles to attend the Summit of the Americas – our support for Juan Guaidó, our support for the democratic aspirations of the Venezuelan people, and that will continue to be the case.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Christiane Jacke.</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-RUSSIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, hello, thanks for taking my question. I’m very sorry I was only able to join the call a little late, so my apologies if you already touched on that topic. It’s about Russia complaining that the U.S. is not allowing flights to bring Russian diplomats home to Russia that are supposed to leave the country. Is that correct? Can you say anything about that complaint from Moscow? Is there threats with consequences if you are not allowing a Russian plane to enter the U.S.? Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Thanks very much. There’s not much I can say because this is the subject of ongoing diplomatic conversation, but what I can say is that the Russian statements do not accurately reflect the current state of play. Of course, we have an interest in an embassy, a U.S. embassy in Moscow, that is functioning. We have an interest, too, in preserving the ability of the Russian Federation to have a functioning embassy here in Washington. I say that – and we’ve made this point before – because we believe that lines of communication and we believe that dialogue is especially important during times of tension, but vitally important during times of conflict and even crisis like the one we’re in now.</p>
<p>So we have engaged with the Russian Federation consistently in recent months to try to get to a better place in terms of our embassy staffing in Moscow to seek to preserve that diplomatic channel that our embassies afford, but there’s just not anything I’m in a position to say now on this specific issue.</p>
<p>We will conclude with the line of Pearl Matibe.</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-AFRICA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Good afternoon, Ned, with these very high temperatures from the second day of summer. Thanks for taking my question. So Ned, mine has to do with U.S. relations with African countries right now on the back of the meeting that Secretary Blinken had with Foreign Minister Tall Sall. Could you maybe give me a sense of the mood of the meeting? How did that go in general? And then on Monday, President Zelenskyy had a closed-door address that he was addressing the African Union, but only four African presidents listened in. I wanted to find out if you could probably share any reaction to that on the back of the meetings that you have been having. Thanks very much, Ned. Anything that you can give us a sense of would be great. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Thanks very much, Pearl. So let me start with the second element of your question first, and I alluded to the fact that everywhere we have traveled, and virtually with every foreign counterpart with whom we’ve interacted in recent weeks and recent months, the challenge of food insecurity has been very high on that agenda. And in many ways, nowhere is it higher than on the continent of Africa, and especially in Sub-Saharan Africa. The Secretary has had an opportunity to speak to a number of his African counterparts. You mentioned Tall Sall. He’s had an opportunity to meet with AU Commission Chairperson Faki. He’s had an opportunity to speak with his South African counterpart. He’s had a number of engagements that have either centered on this challenge of food insecurity or featured it prominently.</p>
<p>And our message has been consistent that we recognize the challenge that President Putin’s war – unprovoked war against Ukraine is causing when it comes to food insecurity. We realize that President Putin’s aggression is compounding what had already been a challenge owing to COVID and the implications of the pandemic, but also to the longer-term implications of climate change. But now that we have a third C, this time in the form of conflict, the issue of food insecurity is even more significant and severe because of the implications that this war is having on those who are hungry or otherwise food insecure around the world.</p>
<p>We are doing a number of things to address that. We have put forward billions of dollars in financial assistance. We are working with international financial institutions, international lending institutions to try to address this challenge. We’re working with other countries to mitigate the global fertilizer challenge. We announced a $500 million investment to increase domestic fertilizer production as part of that. We have an initiative that we’ve spoken to our African counterparts about called Feed the Future. It’s an important initiative that looks at longer-term agricultural capacity and resilience and seeks to ensure that we are in a stronger position going forward.</p>
<p>And we are keeping the issue high on the agenda. And Pearl, you’ve probably heard me mention that the Secretary will be traveling to Berlin tomorrow, where on Friday he’ll take part in a food security ministerial hosted by his German counterpart. And then of course, the President will address this when he’s in Europe for the G7 and other functions in the coming days as well.</p>
<p>So that’s not to say that is the totality of our engagement with our African partners, but it is certainly an important one. It’s an important one because of the devastating implications that President Putin’s war are having on populations around the world, including in Africa and certainly in Sub-Saharan Africa.</p>
<p>With that, I want to thank everyone for tuning in. We will be on travel for the next several days, but we’ll have an opportunity, I am sure, to be in touch from the road, and then we’ll see you back from the department next week. Thanks very much, everyone.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:04 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:32 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks very much, and thanks very much, everyone, for joining today as we do today’s briefing by phone. I have a couple things at the top and then we’ll turn to your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-DEPARTMENT"></a> First, today the First Lady of the United States Dr. Jill Biden and sports icon and equality champion Billie Jean King headline an event hosted by the U.S. Department of State’s Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs, or ECA, in celebration of the 50th anniversary of Title IX, the landmark legislation that afforded women equal opportunity in education and sports across the United States. ECA, in partnership with espnW, highlighted the dramatic impact of Title IX in increasing the participation of women and girls in sports.</p>
<p>Through sports diplomacy exchange programs, such as the Department of State espnW’s Global Sports Mentoring Program, or GSMP, the department is expanding the footprint of Title IX and its message of equality and opportunity for women in every corner of the globe. Now in its 10th year, the GSMP promotes key tenets of Title IX, such as inclusion, access, and opportunity, and applies them globally. The women of the GSMP have positively and directly impacted more than 350,000 people through their action plans as part of the exchange, from advocating for social welfare policy in Brazil to using boxing to teaching self-defense and leadership skills to Kenyan women and girls, they are making a difference every day to advance equality around the world.</p>
<p>And next and finally, the department is pleased to announce that Mr. Collin Walsh, a foreign affairs officer in the Bureau of Diplomatic Security, Office of Rewards for Justice, has been named by <em>CAREERS and the disABLED</em> magazine a 2022 employee of the year for his resilience, professional accomplishments, and commitment to advocacy for persons with disabilities. In 2016, on his third day of Foreign Service orientation as a Diplomatic Security service special agent candidate, Mr. Walsh became physically paralyzed and was told he would never walk again. After two years dedicated entirely to physical recovery, Mr. Walsh returned to DS, walking with elbow-supported mobility aids.</p>
<p>In his new role, Mr. Walsh serves as a Civil Service foreign affairs officer in the DS Rewards for Justice Office, which offers rewards for information regarding those who threaten U.S. national security. Among his many accomplishments are overseeing the RFJ’s – RFJ’s global tips program, serving on a cross-functional rotation in the Office of the Legal Adviser, and leading an accessibility overhaul of the DS headquarters building. So congratulations again to Collin Walsh on behalf of all of us here at the Department of State.</p>
<p>With that, we will turn now to questions. We can start with the line of Matt Lee, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, okay. I got a couple. I’ll try to make them real quick. You can answer them in order. One is: The Secretary, as we know, is supposed to speak with the detainee families today. I realize that may not have happened yet, but can you tell us anything about what he’s planning to say?</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-AFGHANISTAN"></a> And then secondly: The SIGAR, the Special Inspector General for Afghan Reconstruction, has just sent a series of really blistering letters – one to Congress, one to Secretary Blinken, and one to Administrator Power, and one to the legal counsels of both State and USAID – accusing State and USAID of illegally withholding information related to the withdrawal from Afghanistan and current assistance, any kind of assistance, to the country. And obviously, this takes on more relevance, given the earthquake that just happened this morning. But what’s your response to this? Are you guys cooperating with SIGAR as you have, or have you decided that you don’t need to do that anymore? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks, Matt. So on your first question, you are correct that Secretary Blinken will have an engagement this afternoon with the families of Americans who are held hostage or wrongfully detained around the world. That engagement has not yet taken place. It will take place shortly this afternoon. I expect we’ll have an opportunity to provide you with a written readout in the aftermath of this engagement.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken quite frequently engages on a one-on-one basis with family members of Americans who are held hostage or wrongfully detained. This will be an opportunity for him – another opportunity for him – to meet as a collective with the families of those Americans who are wrongfully detained or held hostage. There will be, we expect, several dozen participants in this call. Of course, a setting like this is not entirely conducive to discussing the specifics of particular cases, but the Secretary will use it as an opportunity to underscore for all of these families the paramount priority we attach to doing everything we can to see the safe return of their loved ones from wherever they are held hostage.</p>
<p>And of course, he will continue to follow up on this engagement with one-on-one engagement with individual families, where he has and will continue to have an opportunity to update families on, in more precise terms, what we are doing to see their loved ones released from captivity. So we’ll have more on the call – or on the engagement after it takes place today.</p>
<p>In terms of your question on SIGAR, Matt, what I can tell you is that, as you know, SIGAR published a report last month regarding the collapse of the ANDSF and the factors that led to its demise. Our view is that the report does not reflect the consensus view of the State Department or of the U.S. Government, for that matter. Many parts of the U.S. Government, including the State Department, have unique insights into developments in Afghanistan last year that were not captured in the report. And we don’t concur with many aspects of the report. We refer you to the many statements that the State Department has made over the past year on Afghanistan regarding our assessments.</p>
<p>But the fact is, Matt, that SIGAR did not request input from the State Department for – in the process of drafting this report, nor did they afford us an opportunity to review the draft before it was finalized, as had been a regular process for other reports. If we have any additional reaction to letters that were – and responses that were given today, we’ll be sure to pass those along.</p>
<p>We’ll go to the line of Jennifer Hansler, please. Do we have – yes, we hear you now.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sorry. Sorry if this has already been asked. Are you aware of any U.S. citizens who are victims of this earthquake in Afghanistan? I know there is some concern about particularly the American hostage Mark Frerichs and – given his – where his whereabouts might be. Do you have any update on his status?</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-VENEZUELA"></a> And then separately, do you have any updates on Matthew Heath, the detained American in Venezuela? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks very much. So first, on the earthquake in Afghanistan, you probably just saw the statement that emanated from Secretary Blinken. Secretary Blinken, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, other senior officials, have put out statements today expressing our deep sorrow and our deep sympathy for those who perished in today’s devastating earthquake in Afghanistan as well as to the loved ones of the victims. The people of Afghanistan have undergone extraordinary hardship, and this tragedy only compounds that on top of an already dire humanitarian situation. Our humanitarian partners are responding already, including by sending medical teams to help people affected by the earthquake. As you heard from the Secretary and from the National Security Advisor, we’re assessing other potential response options as well.</p>
<p>We stand with the people of Afghanistan. We’re working with the international community to serve Afghans and to help alleviate the humanitarian crisis and suffering in Afghanistan, which has long predated the earthquake today, but of course which was compounded by the earthquake today.</p>
<p>In terms of potential American victims, there’s not anything I’m in a position to offer at the moment. Of course, the scale of the – of this tragedy is just enormous, so we will work very closely with posts around the world to determine if any Americans were implicated in today’s earthquake. But I’m not aware of any such reports just yet.</p>
<p>In terms of your second question, Matthew Heath, as we’ve said, was arrested in September 2020 on specious charges. His trial is still ongoing. We continue to press for the immediate and unconditional release of Matthew and all wrongfully detained U.S. nationals in Venezuela and everywhere around the world, as I’ve already said in the course of this briefing at every opportunity. Using wrongful detention as a bargaining chip represents a threat to the safety of everyone traveling, working, and living abroad. We do oppose this practice everywhere. I’m not in a position to provide an update on the health of this individual or any other American for privacy considerations, but we are monitoring Matthew’s health and welfare as closely as possible, and we’re in regular contact with his family on that.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Francesco Fontemaggi. Do we have Francesco?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hello. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yes, yes. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-AFGHANISTAN2"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong> Okay. Hi. Thank you. I wanted to follow up on Afghanistan. Has the U.S. Government been in touch with the Taliban to coordinate this humanitarian aid or assistance? Are you planning to coordinate with them or even to go through the Taliban power to bring this assistance to the Afghan people? I know this has been redlined for now, going through the Taliban. But is this something that you can do for this occurrence? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you. And Francesco, before I go there, let me just say, most importantly, thank you. I know this is likely your last briefing as the AFP’s State Department correspondent. I want to thank you for the tremendous time we’ve had working together collegially in your role with AFP and your role with the Correspondents’ Association. We’ll very much miss your presence in the briefing room, your presence in the bullpen, your presence on the S plane, your presence on our travel around the world. But I wish you all the best as you head to your next adventure in what probably are considered greener pastures in Paris. So <em>bon voyage</em>, and looking forward to staying in touch.</p>
<p>In terms of Afghanistan, I am not aware of any request for assistance that the United States Government has received from the Taliban. But we have been in touch with our humanitarian partners. As I mentioned before, our humanitarian partners are already in the process of responding. They’re sending medical teams to help those who are affected by the disaster. As you know, the United States has been a humanitarian leader for the people of Afghanistan. We’ve provided $720 million in humanitarian assistance in Afghanistan and support to Afghan refugees in the region through multilateral organizations and NGOs since mid-August of last year.</p>
<p>Just earlier this week, Special Representative for Afghanistan Tom West – he was in Geneva actually yesterday, where he met with humanitarian partners who are providing critical aid to the people of Afghanistan. We’ll continue to support their role in serving Afghans to alleviate the humanitarian crisis and suffering, and our commitment to the Afghan people is unwavering.</p>
<p>I imagine the humanitarian response to the earthquake will be a topic of conversation between U.S. officials and Taliban officials in the coming days, certainly going forward. But I am not aware that any such conversations have taken place just yet as we are focusing our efforts and our discussions on our humanitarian partners in the first instance.</p>
<p>We’ll go to the line of Iain Marlow.</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-UKRAINE"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Inaudible) question. I’m just wondering if you have any comment on statements from two companies, Viterra and Bunge, that say infrastructure at the Ukrainian port of Mykolaiv were damaged by Russian rockets. And this is obviously – these are food companies, and so this is sort of in line with other sort of attacks on grain and agricultural infrastructure, so I’m just wondering if there was any additional comment on these sort of – these reports coming out.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have any specific reaction to those reports, but we have had a consistent reaction to what has been a consistent practice on the part of the Russian Federation to damage and to potentially even target what is infrastructure that provides food and foodstuffs, not only for the people of Ukraine but for countries around the world.</p>
<p>Since the start of President Putin’s war in Ukraine, Russia’s forces have knocked offline, have destroyed silos; they have destroyed what used to be arable fields; they have left farmers incapable and unable to tend to their fields; and they have not only attacked ships at sea, but perhaps worse, worse yet, they have mounted what amounts to a blockade against the port where tens – where more than 20 tons of grain sits on ships that should be departing for destinations around the world to provide much-needed food and much-needed assistance to people in the region and well beyond.</p>
<p>We’ve undertaken quite a bit of travel since the start of President Putin’s further invasion of Ukraine on February 24th, and in recent weeks, in recent months, the food insecurity crisis that this unprovoked war of aggression has caused has been top of mind for countries and for leaders around the world, including in Los Angeles earlier this month where the Western Hemisphere came together, including in our travels in Latin America and Europe as well.</p>
<p>And of course, we announced this morning that tomorrow Secretary Blinken will be departing for Berlin, where he will take part in a food security conference hosted by the German Government and German Foreign Minister Baerbock. So this will be a topic that will be high on the agenda later this week. It will be high on the agenda when President Biden travels to the G7 later this week as well. And you’ll be hearing more from us later today, from some of our senior officials, on this broad challenge, and you’ll be hearing more from the White House as well in short order.</p>
<p>We’ll got to the line of Janne Pak.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes, we can.</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-SOUTHKOREA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes. Hi, Ned. Thanks for (inaudible) me. I have a question about NATO meeting. Regarding South Korea’s participation in NATO summit next week, South Korea is not a NATO member country. What expectation does the U.S. have for South Korea’s role in attending the NATO summit next week? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks very much, Janne. You are right that South Korea, of course, is not a NATO Ally, but South Korea is an important partner of the NATO Alliance and of individual Allies. And this will be the second time in recent months that partners from the Indo-Pacific have been included in NATO consultations. The fact is that even though NATO is an Alliance, a defensive Alliance that protects and promotes the interests of its Allies in a different part of the world, there are a number of shared challenges that we face, whether it is the challenge from the PRC, whether it is the challenge of cyber and emerging technology that all of our countries face.</p>
<p>But at the end of the day, what we seek to uphold in the Indo-Pacific with our ROK allies and what NATO seeks to uphold in Europe is precisely the same thing, and that is the rules-based order that has promoted and led to what has been unprecedented levels of stability and prosperity around the world. Russia’s affront and assault – affront to and assault on that rules-based international order is a threat not only to Ukraine and to the people of Ukraine, but to that order everywhere around the world. And anytime that order comes under assault and it is not vigorously protected and defended, that order is undermined everywhere.</p>
<p>That’s precisely why we, together with our partners in the Indo-Pacific, have stood up to aggression in that arena as well. When countries in that region seek to challenge the rules-based international order, we have come together to make clear that it is an order that we will protect and promote in the face of challenge, whether that’s in Europe, the Indo-Pacific, or anywhere else.</p>
<p>So I know the Secretary is looking forward to consultations with our partners in the Indo-Pacific in the coming days, as is President Biden, who recently returned from both Japan and the ROK last month, not all that long ago.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Alex Raufoglu.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you so much, Ned. Two questions here. Russia’s Lavrov apparently will travel to Indonesia to take part in the G20 ministerial on July the 7th. He even is thinking to have bilats with Chinese, Brazilian, South African, Mexican colleagues, according to his spox, Zakharova. Is it your position that there is no place for Russia’s participation in the G20 summit? And if so, any steps you’re planning to take to prevent this from happening?</p>
<p>And secondly, Lavrov is also planning to go to Azerbaijan tomorrow to discuss the Karabakh issue. President Aliyev says that the Minsk Group is, quote/unquote, “dead.” Is that your position as well? Is Minsk Group alive, in your opinion, because the U.S. is the – one of the co-chairs? Thanks so much.</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-G20"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks very much, Alex. So when it comes to the G20, it’s an important forum for world and global economic issues. Secretary Blinken will attend to ensure that our interests are represented. We’ll have more details on that travel in the coming days.</p>
<p>But we also have to be clear that Russia’s war on Ukraine has caused global economic instability, and the United States has no intention, as a result, of reducing pressure on the Kremlin until and unless Russia’s aggression against Ukraine comes to a halt. We have reiterated to the Indonesian presidency that the G20 must be relevant to helping Ukraine deal with and recover from the invasion, and I’m confident that Russia’s aggression against Ukraine will be high on the agenda when G20 partners come together in Bali next month. During that set of days we’ll also have an opportunity to engage with allies as well as partners, and I know that Russia’s aggression will be a primary conversation for us as well.</p>
<p>When it comes to the meetings that Foreign Minister Lavrov will have in Bali at the G20 ministerial, I would leave that to the Russians to describe. For us, we are much less concerned about whom he meets with and much more concerned with the messages that are imparted during those meetings. And what we have emphasized over the course of the weeks since February 24th is that every responsible country around the world has an obligation to make very clear to the Russian Federation that its aggression against Ukraine, its peaceful neighbor, cannot be tolerated and will be met – and has been met – with steep costs and consequences for Russia. That’s the message that we’ll continue to convey; that’s the message we expect every responsible country around the world to convey as well.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Luis Rojas.</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-VENEZUELA2"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yes. Thank you, Ned. Thank you for having me. My question is Juan Guaidó’s wife Fabiana Rosales is visiting Washington, have met with senior officials. Do you have any update on the political prisoner of Venezuela, or the possible dialogue between the opposition and the Maduro government, or any question about Venezuela? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, thanks very much. Our contention continues to be that Venezuelan-led negotiations between the Maduro regime and the Unitary Platform represent the best path to restore to Venezuelans the democracy they deserve, and to alleviate their suffering.</p>
<p>We, for our part, remain steadfast in our commitment to the Venezuelan people, which includes supporting their democratic aspirations and providing assistance to address their humanitarian crisis. And we count ourselves among a broad coalition of nations that support these goals.</p>
<p>Look, we believe that, under the right circumstances and with the support of the international community, the parties are better positioned to negotiate steps toward the solution to the Venezuelan crisis. And we’ve urged the parties – the opposition and the Maduro regime – to return to dialogue, to return to Mexico City, and we’ve made clear that we would review our sanctions policies in response to constructive steps by the Maduro regime and if the Venezuelan parties make meaningful progress in those Venezuelan-led negotiations in Mexico.</p>
<p>We have had an opportunity in recent days, including at the most senior levels, including when President Biden spoke to Juan Guaidó on his way to Los Angeles to attend the Summit of the Americas – our support for Juan Guaidó, our support for the democratic aspirations of the Venezuelan people, and that will continue to be the case.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Christiane Jacke.</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-RUSSIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, hello, thanks for taking my question. I’m very sorry I was only able to join the call a little late, so my apologies if you already touched on that topic. It’s about Russia complaining that the U.S. is not allowing flights to bring Russian diplomats home to Russia that are supposed to leave the country. Is that correct? Can you say anything about that complaint from Moscow? Is there threats with consequences if you are not allowing a Russian plane to enter the U.S.? Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Thanks very much. There’s not much I can say because this is the subject of ongoing diplomatic conversation, but what I can say is that the Russian statements do not accurately reflect the current state of play. Of course, we have an interest in an embassy, a U.S. embassy in Moscow, that is functioning. We have an interest, too, in preserving the ability of the Russian Federation to have a functioning embassy here in Washington. I say that – and we’ve made this point before – because we believe that lines of communication and we believe that dialogue is especially important during times of tension, but vitally important during times of conflict and even crisis like the one we’re in now.</p>
<p>So we have engaged with the Russian Federation consistently in recent months to try to get to a better place in terms of our embassy staffing in Moscow to seek to preserve that diplomatic channel that our embassies afford, but there’s just not anything I’m in a position to say now on this specific issue.</p>
<p>We will conclude with the line of Pearl Matibe.</p>
<p><a id="post-354219-AFRICA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Good afternoon, Ned, with these very high temperatures from the second day of summer. Thanks for taking my question. So Ned, mine has to do with U.S. relations with African countries right now on the back of the meeting that Secretary Blinken had with Foreign Minister Tall Sall. Could you maybe give me a sense of the mood of the meeting? How did that go in general? And then on Monday, President Zelenskyy had a closed-door address that he was addressing the African Union, but only four African presidents listened in. I wanted to find out if you could probably share any reaction to that on the back of the meetings that you have been having. Thanks very much, Ned. Anything that you can give us a sense of would be great. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Thanks very much, Pearl. So let me start with the second element of your question first, and I alluded to the fact that everywhere we have traveled, and virtually with every foreign counterpart with whom we’ve interacted in recent weeks and recent months, the challenge of food insecurity has been very high on that agenda. And in many ways, nowhere is it higher than on the continent of Africa, and especially in Sub-Saharan Africa. The Secretary has had an opportunity to speak to a number of his African counterparts. You mentioned Tall Sall. He’s had an opportunity to meet with AU Commission Chairperson Faki. He’s had an opportunity to speak with his South African counterpart. He’s had a number of engagements that have either centered on this challenge of food insecurity or featured it prominently.</p>
<p>And our message has been consistent that we recognize the challenge that President Putin’s war – unprovoked war against Ukraine is causing when it comes to food insecurity. We realize that President Putin’s aggression is compounding what had already been a challenge owing to COVID and the implications of the pandemic, but also to the longer-term implications of climate change. But now that we have a third C, this time in the form of conflict, the issue of food insecurity is even more significant and severe because of the implications that this war is having on those who are hungry or otherwise food insecure around the world.</p>
<p>We are doing a number of things to address that. We have put forward billions of dollars in financial assistance. We are working with international financial institutions, international lending institutions to try to address this challenge. We’re working with other countries to mitigate the global fertilizer challenge. We announced a $500 million investment to increase domestic fertilizer production as part of that. We have an initiative that we’ve spoken to our African counterparts about called Feed the Future. It’s an important initiative that looks at longer-term agricultural capacity and resilience and seeks to ensure that we are in a stronger position going forward.</p>
<p>And we are keeping the issue high on the agenda. And Pearl, you’ve probably heard me mention that the Secretary will be traveling to Berlin tomorrow, where on Friday he’ll take part in a food security ministerial hosted by his German counterpart. And then of course, the President will address this when he’s in Europe for the G7 and other functions in the coming days as well.</p>
<p>So that’s not to say that is the totality of our engagement with our African partners, but it is certainly an important one. It’s an important one because of the devastating implications that President Putin’s war are having on populations around the world, including in Africa and certainly in Sub-Saharan Africa.</p>
<p>With that, I want to thank everyone for tuning in. We will be on travel for the next several days, but we’ll have an opportunity, I am sure, to be in touch from the road, and then we’ll see you back from the department next week. Thanks very much, everyone.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:04 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Families of U.S. Nationals Held Hostage or Wrongfully Detained Abroad</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-families-of-u-s-nationals-held-hostage-or-wrongfully-detained-abroad/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 22:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=354215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with families of U.S. nationals held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad. Secretary Blinken affirmed that working to bring their loved ones home is something he is personally focused on, and he has no higher priority as Secretary of State.  He reiterated that it is vital for the Department to continue to partner with families through regular and transparent communication. The Secretary relayed to the families that President Biden is aware of each of their loved ones’ cases and is committed to bringing all U.S. nationals held hostage or wrongfully detained home.</p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with families of U.S. nationals held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad. Secretary Blinken affirmed that working to bring their loved ones home is something he is personally focused on, and he has no higher priority as Secretary of State.  He reiterated that it is vital for the Department to continue to partner with families through regular and transparent communication. The Secretary relayed to the families that President Biden is aware of each of their loved ones’ cases and is committed to bringing all U.S. nationals held hostage or wrongfully detained home.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Envoy for Global Food Security Cary Fowler;  Assistant Secretary for Economic and Business Affairs Ramin Toloui; and  Deputy Director for Western Europe,  Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs Amy Radetsky  On the Secretary’s Upcoming Travel to Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-envoy-for-global-food-security-cary-fowler-assistant-secretary-for-economic-and-business-affairs-ramin-toloui-and-deputy-director-for-western-europe-bureau-of-european-and-eurasian-affai/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 22:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=354212</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thanks very much, and good afternoon, everyone.  Thank you very much for joining today.  We’re pleased to have an opportunity to preview the Secretary’s travel to Berlin, where he will take part, together with partners and allies, in a food security ministerial on Friday.</p>
<p>Just a reminder, this call is on the record, but it is embargoed until the conclusion of the call.  We have on the line with us three senior State Department officials you will hear from today.  We have Cary Fowler, who is our Special Envoy for Global Food Security; we have Ramin Toloui, who is our Assistant Secretary of State in the Bureau of Economic and Business Affairs; and we have Amy Radetsky, and she is the Deputy Director for Western Europe in our Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs.</p>
<p>I will turn it over to Cary Fowler, who will have some opening remarks, then we’ll move to Assistant Secretary Toloui, and then all three will be in a position to take your questions.</p>
<p>So with that, Special Envoy Fowler, over to you.</p>
<p><strong>MR FOWLER:</strong>  Okay.  Thank you, Ned.  What sets this global food crisis apart from previous similar situations is that there are multiple major causes behind it.</p>
<p>Obviously, everyone understands the impact that the Russian war of aggression has had on the Ukraine and how it has upended global grain markets.  But beyond that, we have also been dealing with climate change, its effect on agricultural production.  As you know, we have had droughts, major droughts in our own country in the United States, and in the Horn of Africa, and elsewhere.  We’ve had COVID, which has dealt supply chain problems to us.  And of course, conflict, not just in Ukraine but in probably 20 or so other countries that have been having ongoing conflict situations.</p>
<p>And I think what that means is that we have to realize that this crisis that we’re experiencing now is not one that is going to go away in the next few weeks, months.  This is probably a three-year crisis to work through all of these very serious problems, all of which the United States is addressing.  But we have to look at both the very immediate, short-term humanitarian issues, as well as longer-term issues, and begin to think about this as an acute crisis that will last for a couple of years, unfortunately, because of these very serious causal factors that we’ve been dealing with.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</strong>  Thank you all for joining the call.  This is Ramin Toloui here.  And as Special Envoy Fowler said, there is a backdrop to the current food security challenge that we’re facing, due to these three Cs:  climate, COVID, and conflict.  So even preceding Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, the UN estimates between 2018 and 2021 the number of people living in acute food insecurity increased from 110 million to 190 million.  And again, that’s preceding this war.</p>
<p>The Kremlin’s invasion, further invasion of Ukraine, has directly destabilized global food supply chains for both food and fertilizer.  Ukraine is one of the breadbaskets of the world and a leading producer and exporter of wheat, corn, and sunflower oil.  And Russian military forces have captured some of Ukraine’s most productive farm land.  They have destroyed vital agricultural infrastructure.  Russia’s naval blockade in the Black Sea and threat of further naval attacks are preventing Ukraine’s crops from being exported to their normal destinations.  And as a result of this, millions of tons of wheat are trapped in silos and on ships.</p>
<p>As long as Putin continues this war in Ukraine, millions of people beyond Ukraine’s borders will suffer from increased food insecurity, with countries in the Near East and Africa experiencing an outsized share of the pain.</p>
<p>We must urgently and collectively respond to this emergency, and the U.S. Government has organized its efforts focusing on six lines of effort.</p>
<p>First of all, we are working with others to mobilize resources to meet urgent humanitarian needs and resolve immediate disruptions in the agricultural supply system.  The U.S. has announced $2.8 billion in emergency food assistance since the war in – against Ukraine began.  And the supplemental appropriation signed by the President in May provides an additional $4.3 billion in humanitarian aid.</p>
<p>Second, we’re working with other countries to mitigate the global fertilizer shortage.  In the United States, President Biden has announced a $500 million investment to increase domestic fertilizer production; we’re working with other major fertilizer producers and encouraging them to take similar actions; and we’re working with multilateral agencies to help developing countries both increase fertilizer production and use fertilizer more effectively.</p>
<p>Third, we are making investments with our partners in agricultural capacity and resilience through our own development assistance with partners and with multilateral institutions.  The U.S. Feed the Future program is the – our flagship initiative in this area, which has historically provided a billion dollars per year in funding for this effort, and the supplemental appropriation I mentioned that was passed in May provides $760 million in additional exceptional funding.</p>
<p>Fourth, we’re working with the international financial institutions to cushion the macroeconomic shock of this crisis and the impact on the poor and most – poor people and most vulnerable populations.  At the insistence of the United States, or I should say at the urging of the United States and the G7, the international financial institutions have prepared an action plan to address global food security.</p>
<p>Fifth, we’re intent on keeping this issue high on the diplomatic agenda.  On May 18th, the United States hosted a Global Food Security Call to Action, a ministerial-level event that included foreign ministers, agriculture ministers, and development ministers which we hosted in New York, to rally countries and regional organizations to take steps to bolster global food supplies and increase resilience.  That ministerial produced a roadmap of actions that almost 90 countries have signed onto to address the current global food security crisis.  We’re supporting the German-led Global Alliance for Food Security, which was announced in May, to share information on country needs and donor responses and coordinate action to increase global food security.</p>
<p>And then the sixth component or sixth line of effort is efforts we’re taking to stabilize and boost domestic agricultural production for American consumers, and this includes a set of actions announced by the President to this end.</p>
<p>As was previewed by Ned at the top of this call, we’ll be leaving for Berlin for – I’ll be joining Secretary Blinken in Germany, where we’ll be joining other foreign ministers, agriculture ministers, development ministerials – ministers, for a Berlin ministerial conference entitled “Uniting for Global Food Security,” and that’ll take place on June 24th, Friday.  And at this meeting, we’ll be looking to build upon the work that we kicked off in New York in terms of mobilizing donor countries, recipient countries, multilateral organizations in order to address and provide solutions to mitigate the food insecurity stemming from Russia’s brutal, unprovoked war against Ukraine as well as the effects of other conflicts, climate change, COVID, and supply chain challenges that are relevant to addressing this problem.</p>
<p>Thank you very much, and look forward to your questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Great.  We’ll now have an opportunity for questions.  Operator, if you wouldn’t mind repeating the instructions to ask a question.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Certainly.  Ladies and gentlemen, once again, if you would like to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 on your telephone keypad.  One moment, please, for the first question.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thanks very much.  Just a reminder:  This call is about the upcoming Berlin ministerial.  We’d be happy to take those questions.  We’ll start with the line of Nick Schifrin of PBS.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Mr. Schifrin, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong> Hey, guys.  Thank you for doing this.  Question:  Has the U.S. made moves toward lifting some of the issues that companies would have in paying for Russian fertilizer?  Obviously there’s no export ban on Russian fertilizer, but the UN does acknowledge that some of the sanctions are causing problems and reducing the ability to – for Russian fertilizer to get around the world.</p>
<p>And I wanted to ask you about Turkey, whether you believe they’ve been helpful in discussing with Russia their military role in possibly de-mining the Odessa port, and in general whether they’ve helped on this issue overall.  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</strong>  Nick, thanks very much for this question.  This is Ramin Toloui.  First, I want to be really clear that the United States is – United States is not sanctioning exports of Russian grain, agricultural commodities, fertilizer, medicine, et cetera.  The – and that’s not only true of trade restrictions but also financial sanctions.  The U.S. has provided what are called general licenses, which allow agricultural commodity transactions that would otherwise be prohibited under our sanctions.</p>
<p>So that’s the first point that’s extremely clear – that needs to be clear.  Nothing is stopping Russia from exporting its grain or fertilizer except its own policies and actions, and to that – on that point, Russia itself imposed – had self-imposed restrictions on exports of its agricultural products.  Since February, Russia has implemented export restrictions, including bans, quotas, and other restrictions on products such as barley, corn, rye, soybeans, sunflower seeds and oil, and wheat.</p>
<p>Now, as your question suggests, there are concerns about so-called overcompliance with sanctions.  And to that end, it’s important that – for me to say that the United States does not want there to be impediments to the ability of countries, companies, to purchase Russian food, Russian fertilizer, and for those goods to access international markets.  If there are difficulties for completing these transactions, which are permitted, we encourage countries to contact the Treasury Department, including the Office of Foreign Asset Control, or OFAC, local U.S. embassies, so that we can work with them on these issues.</p>
<p>So the sanctions regime, again, in its original construction was specifically designed to exclude food and fertilizer.  We do not want any perceived restrictions – even though there are no actual restrictions, but perceived restrictions – from permitting the trade in those goods and getting them to the populations in the world that need them.</p>
<p>And then on your last – the last part of your question, on Turkey, we know that the UN is working hard to find an accommodation that will allow Ukrainian ports to reopen, including Odessa.  We are fully supportive of this and want to see that play out.  We’ll continue close coordination with the UN delegation and the Government of Ukraine on ways to mitigate the impacts to global food security of Putin’s war in Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Missy Ryan.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And Ms. Ryan, your line is now open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Okay.  Thanks so much.  I really appreciate you all doing this call.  I just have a clarification and then a question.  My question is related to China, and sorry, my – the call dropped for me for a minute or two, so hopefully I didn’t miss this.  Can you just talk a little bit about what the conversation with China has been like vis-à-vis the food crisis and its ability to help mitigate the effects of it and also given its relationship with Russia right now?</p>
<p>And then just following up on the question about – the answer you gave to Nick about sanctions, can you just talk – is there anything additional you could say about – in terms of a response to rebut Russia’s accusations that U.S. and allied sanctions are actually causing the food crisis?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</strong>  Well, thanks very much for that question.  I mean, first – first of all, we would – we would look forward to working with any and all partners to address these global food security challenges.  We believe very strongly that this is something that affects all of us, and that all countries have a role to play to addressing those.  We were disappointed that China did not – chose not to attend the ministerial that Secretary Blinken convened in New York in May.  That notwithstanding, we are – we stand ready to work with all countries on trying to alleviate the burden of food insecurity around the globe.</p>
<p>With respect to combating Russian misinformation, this is a much larger issue that goes beyond that of food security, and I’m sure Ned can speak to the broader effort.  I can say from the food security point of view the best we can do is get the facts out there about the fact that our sanctions do not apply to food; to state very clearly what I did state, that to the extent that there are impediments to the trade in goods – trade in food and fertilizer, that we stand ready to help countries and companies work through those; and to acknowledge and highlight the ways in which Russia’s military actions have directly interrupted the flow of vital agricultural commodities out of the Black Sea region that especially countries in the Middle East and North Africa rely upon so heavily.  And so we’ll continue to emphasize that.</p>
<p>The day after the food security ministerial in New York, Secretary Blinken hosted a UN Security Council meeting on May 19th that was focused on this very issue, and his remarks there documented the many ways in which Russian military actions have disrupted the ability of Ukrainian goods – food and agricultural products – to get to market.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Michelle Nichols, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Ms. Nichols, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Thanks so much for the briefing.  Just a bit of a follow-up, actually, on the previous questions on this UN attempt to broker a deal, obviously with the help of Turkey.  When it comes to issuing comfort letters for Russian food and fertilizer exports, which the USUN ambassador talked about a little while ago, have you actually issued any?</p>
<p>And then when it comes to the Ukrainian exports of grain from the Black Sea, if this deal comes together, what is being discussed among the U.S. and allies in terms of trying to encourage and convince shipping and insurance companies to then go ahead and ship these exports out through a route that they’re being told has no mines?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</strong>  Thanks very much for that question.  In terms of the mechanical issue of comfort letters, let me refer you to Treasury – the Treasury Department on that one.  The – I can say that in the communication I’ve just made and in other communications, we’ve underscored this message that – both to companies, to countries, et cetera that our sanctions do not apply to food and fertilizer – and we don’t want them to apply to food and fertilizer informally – and I’ll refer you to Treasury and OFAC on the specifics.</p>
<p>In terms of what – I think you were asking about what additional actions we’ve discussed with our allies in the context of the discussions that are taking place in Turkey.  I don’t really have anything to add on that given where those discussions are.</p>
<p>I should say that the focus that we’re going to have in Berlin on Friday is much broader.  It’s, of course, very important to this line of effort – to get Ukrainian grain to global markets is an incredibly important line of effort, but it’s only one of those, one of the things that we’ll be discussing in Berlin.  We’ll also be discussing other steps to get grain that’s elsewhere in the world to vulnerable populations through our joint humanitarian assistance, how to increase supplies of fertilizer and increase the efficiency with which they are deployed, to make investments in agricultural resilience and capacity to address the issues that Special Envoy Fowler mentioned at the very top about how climate is affecting global food security.</p>
<p>And so the purpose of the Berlin meetings is really this broad-based agenda and bringing together not only countries that are providing money, donating money, growing food, but also those countries that are in need, to give them the opportunity to articulate those needs and to be part of designing the solutions to this incredibly important problem.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Time for a final question or two.  Jennifer Hansler, CNN.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And Ms. Hansler, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, thanks for doing the call.  A couple questions.  Are the countries in the Gulf or in parts of Africa that are going to most acutely feel this crisis going to be involved in these conversations in Berlin?  And since the Secretary convened this meeting at the UN, has there been any progress at all on finding a viable route to get this grain out or any options that have been completely ruled out?</p>
<p>And then, if I could, President Biden mentioned building silos in Poland, for example, to house some of this grain.  What is the status of those?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</strong>  Thanks for that question.  In terms of the final list of invitees, I’ll refer you to Germany on the list of countries that were – that are involved.  The – I should note that in the ministerial that Secretary Blinken hosted in New York, there were multiple countries from the Middle East, North Africa, in addition to Sub-Saharan Africa in attendance, because those are some of the most affected countries.  And so that was very much a part of the group that we – and the discussions that we held in New York in May.</p>
<p>With respect to additional ways of getting Ukrainian grain to global markets, that’s been something that the United States has been working on very closely with the European Union in terms of expanding access to overland routes to getting Ukrainian grain out.  And as has already been discussed, there’s this initiative of the United Nations to get grain out through Odessa.</p>
<p>And more broadly, I should say, we’re looking at multiple ways to assist Ukraine, Ukrainian – the other logistical impediments to getting Ukraine – Ukrainian grain out.  For example, USDA is working very closely with the Ukrainians to make sure that equipment that is relevant to certifying, weighing, and other kinds of regulatory requirements on – for Ukrainian products, that they have the equipment that they need.</p>
<p>And I don’t have any more details to share for the moment on any specific projects, including food storage facilities, but we’re – we continue to work with European partners to find ways to get Ukrainian grain out to those who need it.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll take a final question from Teresa Welsh.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>And Ms. Welsh, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, there.  Thanks so much for taking the question.  You mentioned that the goal of the meeting on Friday is to mobilize additional action from governments and international organizations.  Could you talk a little bit more about what you mean by that?  Are you looking for financial commitments?  Are you looking for scheduling additional meetings, or perhaps a pledging conference?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:  </strong>I think it’s a combination of things.  We’ll be looking and encouraging additional financial contributions, whether they materialize at that meeting or in the weeks following, to meet the needs of humanitarian organizations like the World Food Program, and to also mobilize the resources of bilateral donors and international financial institutions and their development assistance programs.</p>
<p>And then we’ll also be looking to discuss mechanisms to ensure a follow-through on those commitments, and more generally to be providing political oversight of the ongoing efforts to make sure that the problem is well defined and that the various steps in addressing the problem are being implemented.</p>
<p>And I’ll see if my – if anyone else at the table has anything to add to that, but that’s the purpose of these Berlin meetings is to go from the call to action in New York to try to shape up now more specifically the contours of this response, and establish some mechanisms for ensuring its implementation going forward.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well, thank you very much to our speakers.  Thank you very much to everyone for dialing in, and we’ll have an opportunity to speak to you all in the coming days.  Thanks very much.</p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thanks very much, and good afternoon, everyone.  Thank you very much for joining today.  We’re pleased to have an opportunity to preview the Secretary’s travel to Berlin, where he will take part, together with partners and allies, in a food security ministerial on Friday.</p>
<p>Just a reminder, this call is on the record, but it is embargoed until the conclusion of the call.  We have on the line with us three senior State Department officials you will hear from today.  We have Cary Fowler, who is our Special Envoy for Global Food Security; we have Ramin Toloui, who is our Assistant Secretary of State in the Bureau of Economic and Business Affairs; and we have Amy Radetsky, and she is the Deputy Director for Western Europe in our Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs.</p>
<p>I will turn it over to Cary Fowler, who will have some opening remarks, then we’ll move to Assistant Secretary Toloui, and then all three will be in a position to take your questions.</p>
<p>So with that, Special Envoy Fowler, over to you.</p>
<p><strong>MR FOWLER:</strong>  Okay.  Thank you, Ned.  What sets this global food crisis apart from previous similar situations is that there are multiple major causes behind it.</p>
<p>Obviously, everyone understands the impact that the Russian war of aggression has had on the Ukraine and how it has upended global grain markets.  But beyond that, we have also been dealing with climate change, its effect on agricultural production.  As you know, we have had droughts, major droughts in our own country in the United States, and in the Horn of Africa, and elsewhere.  We’ve had COVID, which has dealt supply chain problems to us.  And of course, conflict, not just in Ukraine but in probably 20 or so other countries that have been having ongoing conflict situations.</p>
<p>And I think what that means is that we have to realize that this crisis that we’re experiencing now is not one that is going to go away in the next few weeks, months.  This is probably a three-year crisis to work through all of these very serious problems, all of which the United States is addressing.  But we have to look at both the very immediate, short-term humanitarian issues, as well as longer-term issues, and begin to think about this as an acute crisis that will last for a couple of years, unfortunately, because of these very serious causal factors that we’ve been dealing with.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</strong>  Thank you all for joining the call.  This is Ramin Toloui here.  And as Special Envoy Fowler said, there is a backdrop to the current food security challenge that we’re facing, due to these three Cs:  climate, COVID, and conflict.  So even preceding Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, the UN estimates between 2018 and 2021 the number of people living in acute food insecurity increased from 110 million to 190 million.  And again, that’s preceding this war.</p>
<p>The Kremlin’s invasion, further invasion of Ukraine, has directly destabilized global food supply chains for both food and fertilizer.  Ukraine is one of the breadbaskets of the world and a leading producer and exporter of wheat, corn, and sunflower oil.  And Russian military forces have captured some of Ukraine’s most productive farm land.  They have destroyed vital agricultural infrastructure.  Russia’s naval blockade in the Black Sea and threat of further naval attacks are preventing Ukraine’s crops from being exported to their normal destinations.  And as a result of this, millions of tons of wheat are trapped in silos and on ships.</p>
<p>As long as Putin continues this war in Ukraine, millions of people beyond Ukraine’s borders will suffer from increased food insecurity, with countries in the Near East and Africa experiencing an outsized share of the pain.</p>
<p>We must urgently and collectively respond to this emergency, and the U.S. Government has organized its efforts focusing on six lines of effort.</p>
<p>First of all, we are working with others to mobilize resources to meet urgent humanitarian needs and resolve immediate disruptions in the agricultural supply system.  The U.S. has announced $2.8 billion in emergency food assistance since the war in – against Ukraine began.  And the supplemental appropriation signed by the President in May provides an additional $4.3 billion in humanitarian aid.</p>
<p>Second, we’re working with other countries to mitigate the global fertilizer shortage.  In the United States, President Biden has announced a $500 million investment to increase domestic fertilizer production; we’re working with other major fertilizer producers and encouraging them to take similar actions; and we’re working with multilateral agencies to help developing countries both increase fertilizer production and use fertilizer more effectively.</p>
<p>Third, we are making investments with our partners in agricultural capacity and resilience through our own development assistance with partners and with multilateral institutions.  The U.S. Feed the Future program is the – our flagship initiative in this area, which has historically provided a billion dollars per year in funding for this effort, and the supplemental appropriation I mentioned that was passed in May provides $760 million in additional exceptional funding.</p>
<p>Fourth, we’re working with the international financial institutions to cushion the macroeconomic shock of this crisis and the impact on the poor and most – poor people and most vulnerable populations.  At the insistence of the United States, or I should say at the urging of the United States and the G7, the international financial institutions have prepared an action plan to address global food security.</p>
<p>Fifth, we’re intent on keeping this issue high on the diplomatic agenda.  On May 18th, the United States hosted a Global Food Security Call to Action, a ministerial-level event that included foreign ministers, agriculture ministers, and development ministers which we hosted in New York, to rally countries and regional organizations to take steps to bolster global food supplies and increase resilience.  That ministerial produced a roadmap of actions that almost 90 countries have signed onto to address the current global food security crisis.  We’re supporting the German-led Global Alliance for Food Security, which was announced in May, to share information on country needs and donor responses and coordinate action to increase global food security.</p>
<p>And then the sixth component or sixth line of effort is efforts we’re taking to stabilize and boost domestic agricultural production for American consumers, and this includes a set of actions announced by the President to this end.</p>
<p>As was previewed by Ned at the top of this call, we’ll be leaving for Berlin for – I’ll be joining Secretary Blinken in Germany, where we’ll be joining other foreign ministers, agriculture ministers, development ministerials – ministers, for a Berlin ministerial conference entitled “Uniting for Global Food Security,” and that’ll take place on June 24th, Friday.  And at this meeting, we’ll be looking to build upon the work that we kicked off in New York in terms of mobilizing donor countries, recipient countries, multilateral organizations in order to address and provide solutions to mitigate the food insecurity stemming from Russia’s brutal, unprovoked war against Ukraine as well as the effects of other conflicts, climate change, COVID, and supply chain challenges that are relevant to addressing this problem.</p>
<p>Thank you very much, and look forward to your questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Great.  We’ll now have an opportunity for questions.  Operator, if you wouldn’t mind repeating the instructions to ask a question.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Certainly.  Ladies and gentlemen, once again, if you would like to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 on your telephone keypad.  One moment, please, for the first question.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thanks very much.  Just a reminder:  This call is about the upcoming Berlin ministerial.  We’d be happy to take those questions.  We’ll start with the line of Nick Schifrin of PBS.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Mr. Schifrin, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong> Hey, guys.  Thank you for doing this.  Question:  Has the U.S. made moves toward lifting some of the issues that companies would have in paying for Russian fertilizer?  Obviously there’s no export ban on Russian fertilizer, but the UN does acknowledge that some of the sanctions are causing problems and reducing the ability to – for Russian fertilizer to get around the world.</p>
<p>And I wanted to ask you about Turkey, whether you believe they’ve been helpful in discussing with Russia their military role in possibly de-mining the Odessa port, and in general whether they’ve helped on this issue overall.  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</strong>  Nick, thanks very much for this question.  This is Ramin Toloui.  First, I want to be really clear that the United States is – United States is not sanctioning exports of Russian grain, agricultural commodities, fertilizer, medicine, et cetera.  The – and that’s not only true of trade restrictions but also financial sanctions.  The U.S. has provided what are called general licenses, which allow agricultural commodity transactions that would otherwise be prohibited under our sanctions.</p>
<p>So that’s the first point that’s extremely clear – that needs to be clear.  Nothing is stopping Russia from exporting its grain or fertilizer except its own policies and actions, and to that – on that point, Russia itself imposed – had self-imposed restrictions on exports of its agricultural products.  Since February, Russia has implemented export restrictions, including bans, quotas, and other restrictions on products such as barley, corn, rye, soybeans, sunflower seeds and oil, and wheat.</p>
<p>Now, as your question suggests, there are concerns about so-called overcompliance with sanctions.  And to that end, it’s important that – for me to say that the United States does not want there to be impediments to the ability of countries, companies, to purchase Russian food, Russian fertilizer, and for those goods to access international markets.  If there are difficulties for completing these transactions, which are permitted, we encourage countries to contact the Treasury Department, including the Office of Foreign Asset Control, or OFAC, local U.S. embassies, so that we can work with them on these issues.</p>
<p>So the sanctions regime, again, in its original construction was specifically designed to exclude food and fertilizer.  We do not want any perceived restrictions – even though there are no actual restrictions, but perceived restrictions – from permitting the trade in those goods and getting them to the populations in the world that need them.</p>
<p>And then on your last – the last part of your question, on Turkey, we know that the UN is working hard to find an accommodation that will allow Ukrainian ports to reopen, including Odessa.  We are fully supportive of this and want to see that play out.  We’ll continue close coordination with the UN delegation and the Government of Ukraine on ways to mitigate the impacts to global food security of Putin’s war in Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Missy Ryan.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And Ms. Ryan, your line is now open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Okay.  Thanks so much.  I really appreciate you all doing this call.  I just have a clarification and then a question.  My question is related to China, and sorry, my – the call dropped for me for a minute or two, so hopefully I didn’t miss this.  Can you just talk a little bit about what the conversation with China has been like vis-à-vis the food crisis and its ability to help mitigate the effects of it and also given its relationship with Russia right now?</p>
<p>And then just following up on the question about – the answer you gave to Nick about sanctions, can you just talk – is there anything additional you could say about – in terms of a response to rebut Russia’s accusations that U.S. and allied sanctions are actually causing the food crisis?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</strong>  Well, thanks very much for that question.  I mean, first – first of all, we would – we would look forward to working with any and all partners to address these global food security challenges.  We believe very strongly that this is something that affects all of us, and that all countries have a role to play to addressing those.  We were disappointed that China did not – chose not to attend the ministerial that Secretary Blinken convened in New York in May.  That notwithstanding, we are – we stand ready to work with all countries on trying to alleviate the burden of food insecurity around the globe.</p>
<p>With respect to combating Russian misinformation, this is a much larger issue that goes beyond that of food security, and I’m sure Ned can speak to the broader effort.  I can say from the food security point of view the best we can do is get the facts out there about the fact that our sanctions do not apply to food; to state very clearly what I did state, that to the extent that there are impediments to the trade in goods – trade in food and fertilizer, that we stand ready to help countries and companies work through those; and to acknowledge and highlight the ways in which Russia’s military actions have directly interrupted the flow of vital agricultural commodities out of the Black Sea region that especially countries in the Middle East and North Africa rely upon so heavily.  And so we’ll continue to emphasize that.</p>
<p>The day after the food security ministerial in New York, Secretary Blinken hosted a UN Security Council meeting on May 19th that was focused on this very issue, and his remarks there documented the many ways in which Russian military actions have disrupted the ability of Ukrainian goods – food and agricultural products – to get to market.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to the line of Michelle Nichols, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  Ms. Nichols, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  Thanks so much for the briefing.  Just a bit of a follow-up, actually, on the previous questions on this UN attempt to broker a deal, obviously with the help of Turkey.  When it comes to issuing comfort letters for Russian food and fertilizer exports, which the USUN ambassador talked about a little while ago, have you actually issued any?</p>
<p>And then when it comes to the Ukrainian exports of grain from the Black Sea, if this deal comes together, what is being discussed among the U.S. and allies in terms of trying to encourage and convince shipping and insurance companies to then go ahead and ship these exports out through a route that they’re being told has no mines?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</strong>  Thanks very much for that question.  In terms of the mechanical issue of comfort letters, let me refer you to Treasury – the Treasury Department on that one.  The – I can say that in the communication I’ve just made and in other communications, we’ve underscored this message that – both to companies, to countries, et cetera that our sanctions do not apply to food and fertilizer – and we don’t want them to apply to food and fertilizer informally – and I’ll refer you to Treasury and OFAC on the specifics.</p>
<p>In terms of what – I think you were asking about what additional actions we’ve discussed with our allies in the context of the discussions that are taking place in Turkey.  I don’t really have anything to add on that given where those discussions are.</p>
<p>I should say that the focus that we’re going to have in Berlin on Friday is much broader.  It’s, of course, very important to this line of effort – to get Ukrainian grain to global markets is an incredibly important line of effort, but it’s only one of those, one of the things that we’ll be discussing in Berlin.  We’ll also be discussing other steps to get grain that’s elsewhere in the world to vulnerable populations through our joint humanitarian assistance, how to increase supplies of fertilizer and increase the efficiency with which they are deployed, to make investments in agricultural resilience and capacity to address the issues that Special Envoy Fowler mentioned at the very top about how climate is affecting global food security.</p>
<p>And so the purpose of the Berlin meetings is really this broad-based agenda and bringing together not only countries that are providing money, donating money, growing food, but also those countries that are in need, to give them the opportunity to articulate those needs and to be part of designing the solutions to this incredibly important problem.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Time for a final question or two.  Jennifer Hansler, CNN.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong>  And Ms. Hansler, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, thanks for doing the call.  A couple questions.  Are the countries in the Gulf or in parts of Africa that are going to most acutely feel this crisis going to be involved in these conversations in Berlin?  And since the Secretary convened this meeting at the UN, has there been any progress at all on finding a viable route to get this grain out or any options that have been completely ruled out?</p>
<p>And then, if I could, President Biden mentioned building silos in Poland, for example, to house some of this grain.  What is the status of those?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:</strong>  Thanks for that question.  In terms of the final list of invitees, I’ll refer you to Germany on the list of countries that were – that are involved.  The – I should note that in the ministerial that Secretary Blinken hosted in New York, there were multiple countries from the Middle East, North Africa, in addition to Sub-Saharan Africa in attendance, because those are some of the most affected countries.  And so that was very much a part of the group that we – and the discussions that we held in New York in May.</p>
<p>With respect to additional ways of getting Ukrainian grain to global markets, that’s been something that the United States has been working on very closely with the European Union in terms of expanding access to overland routes to getting Ukrainian grain out.  And as has already been discussed, there’s this initiative of the United Nations to get grain out through Odessa.</p>
<p>And more broadly, I should say, we’re looking at multiple ways to assist Ukraine, Ukrainian – the other logistical impediments to getting Ukraine – Ukrainian grain out.  For example, USDA is working very closely with the Ukrainians to make sure that equipment that is relevant to certifying, weighing, and other kinds of regulatory requirements on – for Ukrainian products, that they have the equipment that they need.</p>
<p>And I don’t have any more details to share for the moment on any specific projects, including food storage facilities, but we’re – we continue to work with European partners to find ways to get Ukrainian grain out to those who need it.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll take a final question from Teresa Welsh.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:  </strong>And Ms. Welsh, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, there.  Thanks so much for taking the question.  You mentioned that the goal of the meeting on Friday is to mobilize additional action from governments and international organizations.  Could you talk a little bit more about what you mean by that?  Are you looking for financial commitments?  Are you looking for scheduling additional meetings, or perhaps a pledging conference?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY TOLOUI:  </strong>I think it’s a combination of things.  We’ll be looking and encouraging additional financial contributions, whether they materialize at that meeting or in the weeks following, to meet the needs of humanitarian organizations like the World Food Program, and to also mobilize the resources of bilateral donors and international financial institutions and their development assistance programs.</p>
<p>And then we’ll also be looking to discuss mechanisms to ensure a follow-through on those commitments, and more generally to be providing political oversight of the ongoing efforts to make sure that the problem is well defined and that the various steps in addressing the problem are being implemented.</p>
<p>And I’ll see if my – if anyone else at the table has anything to add to that, but that’s the purpose of these Berlin meetings is to go from the call to action in New York to try to shape up now more specifically the contours of this response, and establish some mechanisms for ensuring its implementation going forward.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Well, thank you very much to our speakers.  Thank you very much to everyone for dialing in, and we’ll have an opportunity to speak to you all in the coming days.  Thanks very much.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>G7 Media Ministers Meeting Communiqué</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/g7-media-ministers-meeting-communique/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 20:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=354138</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following statement was released by the G7 Media Ministers following their meeting in Bonn, Germany on June 19<sup>th</sup>, 2022:</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<ol>
<li>We, the Media Ministers of the G7, met in Bonn on 19 June 2022 to work more closely together on issues regarding our media policies and their role in strengthening democracy &#8211; a task that requires a global response.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="2">
<li>We as the G7 stand up for open, free and democratic societies. We will promote them and protect them. We firmly believe that democracies are best placed to serve their people and to address global challenges such as climate change and threats to sustainable development, as well as to provide people with the greatest security and freedom.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="3">
<li>We condemn Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine, which is being waged against a free and democratic society in violation of international law. This has always been a war built on lies, with the Kremlin creating false pretexts for invasion, obscuring the truth, and hiding and denying war crimes. It has shown us once again just how horrifying the effects of systematic and coordinated manipulation of the information environment can be. As Russia sought to disseminate disinformation abroad, it sought to silence and censor independent media at home. Journalists and the free media as a whole have been among the first targets of this war.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="4">
<li>This is not the first time in history that information manipulation, disinformation and the restriction of media freedom have been explicitly designed to support and enable injustice and oppression. However, we also recognize the courage and professionalism of Ukrainian and international media covering this war.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="5">
<li>As the G7, we reaffirm our commitment to a free and open media environment; robust and independent journalism; an open, free, global, interoperable, reliable and secure internet; and resilient telecommunication services. As G7 leaders decided last year, we need to cooperate in opposing government-imposed internet shutdowns and restrictions, which, among other harms, prevent people from accessing independent media reporting. We have to ensure and encourage access to and dissemination of independent media and in particular shine a light on regions affected by war and crisis.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="6">
<li>A society in which individuals can freely exercise the right to freedom of opinion and expression, including seeking, receiving and imparting information and ideas of all kinds, is of foundational importance for democracy and liberty. Free and plural media are an indispensable component for this: by providing accurate information and diverse viewpoints, they enable the public to participate in societal debates, make informed choices, and hold their governments to account.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="7">
<li>Information manipulation, including disinformation, and hate speech can undermine and hinder open, democratic dialogue and debate, and can promote division and polarization. As a result of targeted harassment and abuse, some parts of society, especially groups subject to multiple and intersecting forms of discrimination such as women and girls, LGBTQI+ individuals, and members of marginalized racial and ethnic communities, censor themselves, avoid specific topics, and even refrain from participating in public debates online Online harassment and abuse not only impedes individual ability to exercise their right to freedom of expression, but the suppression of diverse voices results in an opportunity cost in terms of the free exchange of ideas and ultimately lost innovation. This can result in the dominance of one-sided, false or manipulative content in public discourse online.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="8">
<li>To counter these threats, we will work together to protect and advance freedom of opinion and expression as laid down in Article 19 of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights (UDHR) and further enshrined in the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights. The G7 will take measures to preserve and promote free, independent and pluralistic media landscapes and improve economic, social, legal and actual conditions for those who shape those media landscapes to serve our democracies.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>The Protection of Journalists and Media Professionals and their Significance for Democracy</strong></p>
<ol start="9">
<li>When democracies are under attack, all too often journalists and members of the media are the first to have their human rights curtailed and to face threats and repression. Women in journalism are disproportionately impacted by threats and attacks, which are more often gendered and sexualised than threats against their male counterparts and increasingly take place online. Around the world, journalists and media professionals are persecuted, threatened and even killed for their work. In many cases, these crimes go unpunished. In democracies too, there have been attacks on journalists by those seeking to suppress fact-based and accurate reporting.According to the Reporters Without Borders 2022 World Press Freedom Index, press <span style="letter-spacing: -0.25px;">freedom is threatened in 70 countries worldwide; in 28 of those countries, the situation is classified as “very bad”.</span></li>
</ol>
<ol start="10">
<li>Not only individual journalists, but also newspaper publishers and broadcasters are censored or blocked entirely from operating. Digital platforms that provide access to content also increasingly face attempts at censorship by autocratic states, impeding the free flow of information from traditional media outlets, as well as calls from society more broadly to restrict content.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="11">
<li>In Russia, independent journalists and media outlets have long faced oppression, and now those who have reported about the war in Ukraine have been censored, repressed, threatened and forced to close. We have seen multiple media reports of abductions of journalists, as well as local elected officials, civil-society leaders, and others. And we have seen reports of deliberate targeting of Ukraine’s independent media by Russian forces.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="12">
<li>But it is not only Russia that suppresses critical and contrary opinions and threatens journalists. Around the world, journalists face harassment and violence for their work, and press freedom is being restricted, both online and offline. According to Reporters Without Borders, last year more than 400 journalists, media professionals and bloggers were imprisoned, and more than 40 were killed for their work. At least 12 journalists have been killed in Ukraine since Russia’s full scale invasion began.<a href="#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1"></a></li>
</ol>
<ol start="13">
<li>These shocking examples show that protecting a free, independent and pluralistic media landscape means first and foremost protecting journalists, particularly women journalists and those from marginalised communities.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="14">
<li>This requires a comprehensive approach that is both self-critical and prepared to cooperate and assist abroad in partnership with countries around the globe. Prevention of crimes against journalists also relies on the broader conditions in which media outlets, social media, and technology platforms operate.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Independence of the Media and Economic Conditions</strong></p>
<ol start="15">
<li>Media companies are enterprises that research, report and disseminate editorial content that inform the public and, in so doing, help people form their opinions. They are vital to democracy and its ability to function. These companies also should work to ensure that trustworthy information and diverse perspectives are available to the public. Therefore, we encourage independent and transparent standards developed by individual companies or within the sector itself (self-regulation) to ensure that media companies remain accountable to their audiences.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="16">
<li>Governments also play a role in maintaining conditions that allow independent media outlets to thrive. We seek to promote optimal environments for an economically sustainable and resilient media sector in order to preserve a pluralistic media landscape in the long term. However, any public funding, subsidies or state advertising should be distributed based on transparent criteria that do not lead to direct or indirect governmental interference and any other political influence on editorially independent media.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="17">
<li>Regarding the growing power of state-controlled media structures in multiple countries around the world, it is essential that we continue to fight against state-sponsored information manipulation and interference, including disinformation, while robustly defending media freedom and freedom of expression. Governmental non-interference in editorial work of independent media, including public service media, is a key principle in this regard and need to be ensured by legal and regulatory safeguards, including transparency requirements for foreign investments and ownership structures.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Technological Conditions and Media Convergence</strong></p>
<ol start="18">
<li>Media convergence, new forms of communication and new ways of shaping opinion have fundamentally altered the conditions under which media operate. At the same time, people around the world continue to need trustworthy journalism, free and independent reporting, and unimpeded access to reliable and pluralistic sources of objective information.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="19">
<li>Globalization, unimpeded access to fact-based information both online and offline, and the digital transformation have created a media environment in which cross-border access to media content and services is possible. The availability of information and spaces of communication is no longer contingent on national borders. Today, we can communicate directly with people around the world and access an unprecedented abundance and range of unfiltered first-hand impressions and different perspectives. This enables people to hear a broader range of viewpoints and develop global understanding, as well as facilitating connections across the world.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="20">
<li>Competition for users’ attention and for shaping the dominant narrative about current events no longer takes place only locally and regionally, but rather globally. This speaks to the importance of tackling the digital ecosystem challenges in an integrated way, with collaboration across governments and with all interested stakeholders to work together towards a common vision.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="21">
<li>Digital platforms play an ever more important role in this digital ecosystem and in the opinion-forming process online. These private companies have a strong influence on access to and the visibility of media content, and they dominate the advertising market.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="22">
<li>The internet and digital technologies enable innovation, the free and open exchange of opinions and ideas, and unprecedented opportunities for participation in public and social discourse.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="23">
<li>However, to fully seize the opportunities digital transformation brings, we should also manage its potential risks. In particular, we reaffirm the need to respond to those actors who threaten freedom and democracy by limiting access to independent sources of information, who inhibit plurality, and who engage in information manipulation and disinformation to sow doubt, distrust and hatred. At the same time, social-media platforms and other digital technologies have given rise to new forms and manifestations of violence through their misuse, including amplification of pre-existing forms of gender-based violence through their scale, speed, and reach.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="24">
<li>We strongly encourage platforms to act responsibly, in line with the UN Guiding Principles on Business and Human Rights, to prevent and address situations where their algorithms may elevate or amplify content that either incites imminent violence or otherwise violates the platforms&#8217; own terms of service and policies.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="25">
<li>We will promote access to a variety of sources of information and a range of opinions to facilitate pluralistic, vibrant democratic discourse and participation in society, while also supporting a secure public space of communication and ensuring that individuals have ready access to independent, fact-based, trustworthy sources of information – offline as well as online.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="26">
<li>That is why we have extensively discussed media policy online and offline issues, especially access to and availability of trustworthy information, freedom from discrimination, equality of opportunity, transparency and user autonomy. We have also talked about how human rights such as freedom of expression must be respected online and offline and how the influence of opinion, which is based on market power, can be better tackled.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="27">
<li>In addition to traditional media, civil-society initiatives also play a key role in a vibrant democracy and make a vital contribution to enabling individuals to form opinions. They create new opportunities for participation, especially for marginalised groups, and empower public opinion-forming, as well as providing new media formats. They inform people, raise awareness, and can help improve media literacy and impart trust in democracy and the media.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Conclusions for International Media Policy</strong></p>
<ol start="28">
<li>We have therefore committed to work together more closely in the coming years, especially in the following areas:</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>A. Supporting Media Freedom</strong></p>
<p><strong>We commit to:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>further mutual exchanges about market-based policy approaches that could level the playing field between dominant digital platforms and news businesses, and that allow bargaining over the total value of the news content created by journalists,</li>
<li>establish the right conditions to safeguard the freedom, independence and pluralism of the media, making sure that media markets function well and allow for the sustainable economic development of the media,</li>
<li>help support the sustainability of the media sector and its innovation and digital transformation, and therefore welcome implementation of commitments made at the Summit for Democracy to strengthen the sustainability and resilience of independent media and encourage all actors – governments, philanthropies, the private sector – to do more,</li>
<li>reach common ground on how to effectively address information manipulation and interference, including tackling propaganda and countering disinformation, while also respecting human rights and taking steps to protect the ability of critical and dissenting voices can continue to be heard around the world and human rights are respected,</li>
<li>act against state-driven censorship, network connectivity disruptions, and media bans of the free press, while bolstering the important role of independent media,</li>
<li>discuss ways to improve access to, and availability of, diverse and reliable information sources, with freedom from discrimination, equality of opportunity, transparency and user autonomy as key principles (such as through the international multi-stakeholder forum on the diversity of content online launched by Canada),</li>
<li>work to support online platforms’ transparency and provision of services that are safe, and promote respect for freedom of expression and information, and encourage such platforms to ensure the digital environment is fair and respectful of human rights and fundamental freedoms, including in particular freedom of expression, and encourage such platforms to support media freedom and pluralism,</li>
<li>advance existing initiatives to promote media freedom and plurality of media (such as the Media Freedom Coalition, the Diversity of Content Online initiative launched by Canada, UNESCO, the Media Pluralism Monitor, the Freedom Online Coalition, the Declaration for the Future of the Internet),</li>
<li>advance existing initiatives that support civil society, fact-checkers and researchers engaged in detecting and exposing threats from and incidents of information manipulation including disinformation threats and incidents and analysing trends (such as the European Digital Media Observatory),</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>strengthen efforts to coordinate approaches to prevent and response to online harassment and abuse and technology-facilitated gender-based violence, recognizing that targeted harassment and abuse online, which disproportionately impacts especially women, girls, and LGBTQI+ persons, can be an impediment to individuals’ ability to exercise their right to freedom of expression, build consensus and foster joint efforts with international partners on the best data. Stakeholders need to understand the effect of platform policies and interventions to address mis- and disinformation, for example the UK’s Measuring Effective Interventions Framework initiative,</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>strengthen mutual exchange to identify and counter malign information manipulation influenced by foreign governments that threatens media independence and to promote transparency of media ownership structures.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>B. Protecting Journalists and Media Professionals</strong></p>
<p>The current political situation in many places shows the fragility of human rights, including freedom of expression, as well as of the rule of law and press freedoms. In multiple countries, independent media professionals who can no longer practice their profession have been forced to leave and continue their work in exile. We need to act in a strong alliance to defend press freedom worldwide and to work effectively to protect journalists and media professionals.</p>
<p><strong>We commit to:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>keep developing and advancing programmes as well as work on accommodation options to support journalists and media professionals who are threatened in their home country or have fled from it, so that their voices are not silenced at home, and therefore welcome Germany’s initiative to actively support journalists as well as other individuals defending the freedom of expression,</li>
<li>protect and support – in accordance with each country’s own approach &#8211; journalists and media professionals under threat, while respecting the empowering of organisations that systematically monitor press and media freedom,</li>
<li>deepen our collaboration through existing initiatives, such as the Media Freedom Coalition and the Global Media Defence Fund (GMDF), which help to protect media freedom and journalists and to take action against abusive litigation against journalists and human rights defenders (known as SLAPP suits) which is used to silence them.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>C. Cooperation and Inclusion of Civil Society</strong></p>
<p>Freedom, plurality and sustainability are the values that should guide our path forward into the future. We will connect with civil-society actors, advance concrete initiatives, and in doing so strengthen the multilateral order to create and preserve peace. Space for open, democratic debate online and offline has to be maintained, in which ideas, projects, and visions of democratic society can be shared and discussed.</p>
<p><strong>We support all those who stand up for democracy by:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>noting the work of international initiatives and mechanisms such as the OECD’s work on Rebuilding Trust and Reinforcing Democracy and the Partnership on Information and Democracy,</li>
<li>reaffirming our commitment to existing institutions such as the European Audiovisual Observatory, which are important sources of information for media policy,</li>
<li>cooperating in opposing politically motivated internet shutdowns and restrictions,</li>
<li>welcoming initiatives that promote a safe and secure information environment, media and information literacy and trustworthy journalism, and therefore welcoming the Democracy Newsroom initiative,</li>
<li>encouraging initiatives that contribute to a viable, diverse and independent media industry, supporting innovation and digital transformation, including through additional collaborations to support and sustain independent public interest media,</li>
<li>welcoming media initiatives that enable independent journalism to remain a watchdog of democracy at local, national and international levels and contributes to the public debate,</li>
<li>encouraging the initiative “Transparency and freedom of opinion – Crisis resilience of media”,</li>
<li>welcoming the Canada-led international Guiding Principles on Diversity of Content Online, which were developed in collaboration with a multi-stakeholder working group that includes counterparts in other countries, and with civil-society and industry partners,</li>
<li>encouraging the establishment of media literacy courses for all generations to enable individuals to clearly differentiate between fact-based information and disinformation, to understand how manipulative tactics can be used online and offline and to understand journalism as an indispensable part of the checks and balances in democratic societies.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>D. Initiating Work Processes – The Way Forward</strong></p>
<p>We therefore intend to anchor media policy even more firmly at the global level as a field of work that is relevant to democracy. In coordination with existing initiatives and formats, in particular with the G7 Rapid Response Mechanism (RRM), we want, for the first time, to create a forum for increased dialogue at the G7 concerning the global media online and offline, a dialogue which requires a global response, and developing solutions and cooperative approaches.</p>
<p><strong>In order to achieve these goals, we commit to:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>continue to closely coordinate on questions concerning the spread of content and information from a security, human rights, technical and media policy perspective, and pursue a joint approach to support media freedom and pluralism,</li>
<li>create a follow-up process to achieve the aforementioned goals,</li>
<li>welcome the input of international experts on media freedom in state decision-making processes, in addition to forums such as the EU, the CoE, OSCE and the UN,</li>
<li>actively use opportunities for cooperation with international associations, civil-society organisations and initiatives on current media-related issues.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1"></a> As of 6 June 2022, according to the Council of Europe’s Platform to promote the protection of journalism and safety of journalists.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="100001000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following statement was released by the G7 Media Ministers following their meeting in Bonn, Germany on June 19<sup>th</sup>, 2022:</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<ol>
<li>We, the Media Ministers of the G7, met in Bonn on 19 June 2022 to work more closely together on issues regarding our media policies and their role in strengthening democracy &#8211; a task that requires a global response.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="2">
<li>We as the G7 stand up for open, free and democratic societies. We will promote them and protect them. We firmly believe that democracies are best placed to serve their people and to address global challenges such as climate change and threats to sustainable development, as well as to provide people with the greatest security and freedom.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="3">
<li>We condemn Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine, which is being waged against a free and democratic society in violation of international law. This has always been a war built on lies, with the Kremlin creating false pretexts for invasion, obscuring the truth, and hiding and denying war crimes. It has shown us once again just how horrifying the effects of systematic and coordinated manipulation of the information environment can be. As Russia sought to disseminate disinformation abroad, it sought to silence and censor independent media at home. Journalists and the free media as a whole have been among the first targets of this war.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="4">
<li>This is not the first time in history that information manipulation, disinformation and the restriction of media freedom have been explicitly designed to support and enable injustice and oppression. However, we also recognize the courage and professionalism of Ukrainian and international media covering this war.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="5">
<li>As the G7, we reaffirm our commitment to a free and open media environment; robust and independent journalism; an open, free, global, interoperable, reliable and secure internet; and resilient telecommunication services. As G7 leaders decided last year, we need to cooperate in opposing government-imposed internet shutdowns and restrictions, which, among other harms, prevent people from accessing independent media reporting. We have to ensure and encourage access to and dissemination of independent media and in particular shine a light on regions affected by war and crisis.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="6">
<li>A society in which individuals can freely exercise the right to freedom of opinion and expression, including seeking, receiving and imparting information and ideas of all kinds, is of foundational importance for democracy and liberty. Free and plural media are an indispensable component for this: by providing accurate information and diverse viewpoints, they enable the public to participate in societal debates, make informed choices, and hold their governments to account.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="7">
<li>Information manipulation, including disinformation, and hate speech can undermine and hinder open, democratic dialogue and debate, and can promote division and polarization. As a result of targeted harassment and abuse, some parts of society, especially groups subject to multiple and intersecting forms of discrimination such as women and girls, LGBTQI+ individuals, and members of marginalized racial and ethnic communities, censor themselves, avoid specific topics, and even refrain from participating in public debates online Online harassment and abuse not only impedes individual ability to exercise their right to freedom of expression, but the suppression of diverse voices results in an opportunity cost in terms of the free exchange of ideas and ultimately lost innovation. This can result in the dominance of one-sided, false or manipulative content in public discourse online.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="8">
<li>To counter these threats, we will work together to protect and advance freedom of opinion and expression as laid down in Article 19 of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights (UDHR) and further enshrined in the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights. The G7 will take measures to preserve and promote free, independent and pluralistic media landscapes and improve economic, social, legal and actual conditions for those who shape those media landscapes to serve our democracies.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>The Protection of Journalists and Media Professionals and their Significance for Democracy</strong></p>
<ol start="9">
<li>When democracies are under attack, all too often journalists and members of the media are the first to have their human rights curtailed and to face threats and repression. Women in journalism are disproportionately impacted by threats and attacks, which are more often gendered and sexualised than threats against their male counterparts and increasingly take place online. Around the world, journalists and media professionals are persecuted, threatened and even killed for their work. In many cases, these crimes go unpunished. In democracies too, there have been attacks on journalists by those seeking to suppress fact-based and accurate reporting.According to the Reporters Without Borders 2022 World Press Freedom Index, press <span style="letter-spacing: -0.25px;">freedom is threatened in 70 countries worldwide; in 28 of those countries, the situation is classified as “very bad”.</span></li>
</ol>
<ol start="10">
<li>Not only individual journalists, but also newspaper publishers and broadcasters are censored or blocked entirely from operating. Digital platforms that provide access to content also increasingly face attempts at censorship by autocratic states, impeding the free flow of information from traditional media outlets, as well as calls from society more broadly to restrict content.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="11">
<li>In Russia, independent journalists and media outlets have long faced oppression, and now those who have reported about the war in Ukraine have been censored, repressed, threatened and forced to close. We have seen multiple media reports of abductions of journalists, as well as local elected officials, civil-society leaders, and others. And we have seen reports of deliberate targeting of Ukraine’s independent media by Russian forces.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="12">
<li>But it is not only Russia that suppresses critical and contrary opinions and threatens journalists. Around the world, journalists face harassment and violence for their work, and press freedom is being restricted, both online and offline. According to Reporters Without Borders, last year more than 400 journalists, media professionals and bloggers were imprisoned, and more than 40 were killed for their work. At least 12 journalists have been killed in Ukraine since Russia’s full scale invasion began.<a href="#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1"></a></li>
</ol>
<ol start="13">
<li>These shocking examples show that protecting a free, independent and pluralistic media landscape means first and foremost protecting journalists, particularly women journalists and those from marginalised communities.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="14">
<li>This requires a comprehensive approach that is both self-critical and prepared to cooperate and assist abroad in partnership with countries around the globe. Prevention of crimes against journalists also relies on the broader conditions in which media outlets, social media, and technology platforms operate.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Independence of the Media and Economic Conditions</strong></p>
<ol start="15">
<li>Media companies are enterprises that research, report and disseminate editorial content that inform the public and, in so doing, help people form their opinions. They are vital to democracy and its ability to function. These companies also should work to ensure that trustworthy information and diverse perspectives are available to the public. Therefore, we encourage independent and transparent standards developed by individual companies or within the sector itself (self-regulation) to ensure that media companies remain accountable to their audiences.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="16">
<li>Governments also play a role in maintaining conditions that allow independent media outlets to thrive. We seek to promote optimal environments for an economically sustainable and resilient media sector in order to preserve a pluralistic media landscape in the long term. However, any public funding, subsidies or state advertising should be distributed based on transparent criteria that do not lead to direct or indirect governmental interference and any other political influence on editorially independent media.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="17">
<li>Regarding the growing power of state-controlled media structures in multiple countries around the world, it is essential that we continue to fight against state-sponsored information manipulation and interference, including disinformation, while robustly defending media freedom and freedom of expression. Governmental non-interference in editorial work of independent media, including public service media, is a key principle in this regard and need to be ensured by legal and regulatory safeguards, including transparency requirements for foreign investments and ownership structures.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Technological Conditions and Media Convergence</strong></p>
<ol start="18">
<li>Media convergence, new forms of communication and new ways of shaping opinion have fundamentally altered the conditions under which media operate. At the same time, people around the world continue to need trustworthy journalism, free and independent reporting, and unimpeded access to reliable and pluralistic sources of objective information.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="19">
<li>Globalization, unimpeded access to fact-based information both online and offline, and the digital transformation have created a media environment in which cross-border access to media content and services is possible. The availability of information and spaces of communication is no longer contingent on national borders. Today, we can communicate directly with people around the world and access an unprecedented abundance and range of unfiltered first-hand impressions and different perspectives. This enables people to hear a broader range of viewpoints and develop global understanding, as well as facilitating connections across the world.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="20">
<li>Competition for users’ attention and for shaping the dominant narrative about current events no longer takes place only locally and regionally, but rather globally. This speaks to the importance of tackling the digital ecosystem challenges in an integrated way, with collaboration across governments and with all interested stakeholders to work together towards a common vision.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="21">
<li>Digital platforms play an ever more important role in this digital ecosystem and in the opinion-forming process online. These private companies have a strong influence on access to and the visibility of media content, and they dominate the advertising market.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="22">
<li>The internet and digital technologies enable innovation, the free and open exchange of opinions and ideas, and unprecedented opportunities for participation in public and social discourse.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="23">
<li>However, to fully seize the opportunities digital transformation brings, we should also manage its potential risks. In particular, we reaffirm the need to respond to those actors who threaten freedom and democracy by limiting access to independent sources of information, who inhibit plurality, and who engage in information manipulation and disinformation to sow doubt, distrust and hatred. At the same time, social-media platforms and other digital technologies have given rise to new forms and manifestations of violence through their misuse, including amplification of pre-existing forms of gender-based violence through their scale, speed, and reach.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="24">
<li>We strongly encourage platforms to act responsibly, in line with the UN Guiding Principles on Business and Human Rights, to prevent and address situations where their algorithms may elevate or amplify content that either incites imminent violence or otherwise violates the platforms&#8217; own terms of service and policies.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="25">
<li>We will promote access to a variety of sources of information and a range of opinions to facilitate pluralistic, vibrant democratic discourse and participation in society, while also supporting a secure public space of communication and ensuring that individuals have ready access to independent, fact-based, trustworthy sources of information – offline as well as online.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="26">
<li>That is why we have extensively discussed media policy online and offline issues, especially access to and availability of trustworthy information, freedom from discrimination, equality of opportunity, transparency and user autonomy. We have also talked about how human rights such as freedom of expression must be respected online and offline and how the influence of opinion, which is based on market power, can be better tackled.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="27">
<li>In addition to traditional media, civil-society initiatives also play a key role in a vibrant democracy and make a vital contribution to enabling individuals to form opinions. They create new opportunities for participation, especially for marginalised groups, and empower public opinion-forming, as well as providing new media formats. They inform people, raise awareness, and can help improve media literacy and impart trust in democracy and the media.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Conclusions for International Media Policy</strong></p>
<ol start="28">
<li>We have therefore committed to work together more closely in the coming years, especially in the following areas:</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>A. Supporting Media Freedom</strong></p>
<p><strong>We commit to:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>further mutual exchanges about market-based policy approaches that could level the playing field between dominant digital platforms and news businesses, and that allow bargaining over the total value of the news content created by journalists,</li>
<li>establish the right conditions to safeguard the freedom, independence and pluralism of the media, making sure that media markets function well and allow for the sustainable economic development of the media,</li>
<li>help support the sustainability of the media sector and its innovation and digital transformation, and therefore welcome implementation of commitments made at the Summit for Democracy to strengthen the sustainability and resilience of independent media and encourage all actors – governments, philanthropies, the private sector – to do more,</li>
<li>reach common ground on how to effectively address information manipulation and interference, including tackling propaganda and countering disinformation, while also respecting human rights and taking steps to protect the ability of critical and dissenting voices can continue to be heard around the world and human rights are respected,</li>
<li>act against state-driven censorship, network connectivity disruptions, and media bans of the free press, while bolstering the important role of independent media,</li>
<li>discuss ways to improve access to, and availability of, diverse and reliable information sources, with freedom from discrimination, equality of opportunity, transparency and user autonomy as key principles (such as through the international multi-stakeholder forum on the diversity of content online launched by Canada),</li>
<li>work to support online platforms’ transparency and provision of services that are safe, and promote respect for freedom of expression and information, and encourage such platforms to ensure the digital environment is fair and respectful of human rights and fundamental freedoms, including in particular freedom of expression, and encourage such platforms to support media freedom and pluralism,</li>
<li>advance existing initiatives to promote media freedom and plurality of media (such as the Media Freedom Coalition, the Diversity of Content Online initiative launched by Canada, UNESCO, the Media Pluralism Monitor, the Freedom Online Coalition, the Declaration for the Future of the Internet),</li>
<li>advance existing initiatives that support civil society, fact-checkers and researchers engaged in detecting and exposing threats from and incidents of information manipulation including disinformation threats and incidents and analysing trends (such as the European Digital Media Observatory),</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>strengthen efforts to coordinate approaches to prevent and response to online harassment and abuse and technology-facilitated gender-based violence, recognizing that targeted harassment and abuse online, which disproportionately impacts especially women, girls, and LGBTQI+ persons, can be an impediment to individuals’ ability to exercise their right to freedom of expression, build consensus and foster joint efforts with international partners on the best data. Stakeholders need to understand the effect of platform policies and interventions to address mis- and disinformation, for example the UK’s Measuring Effective Interventions Framework initiative,</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>strengthen mutual exchange to identify and counter malign information manipulation influenced by foreign governments that threatens media independence and to promote transparency of media ownership structures.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>B. Protecting Journalists and Media Professionals</strong></p>
<p>The current political situation in many places shows the fragility of human rights, including freedom of expression, as well as of the rule of law and press freedoms. In multiple countries, independent media professionals who can no longer practice their profession have been forced to leave and continue their work in exile. We need to act in a strong alliance to defend press freedom worldwide and to work effectively to protect journalists and media professionals.</p>
<p><strong>We commit to:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>keep developing and advancing programmes as well as work on accommodation options to support journalists and media professionals who are threatened in their home country or have fled from it, so that their voices are not silenced at home, and therefore welcome Germany’s initiative to actively support journalists as well as other individuals defending the freedom of expression,</li>
<li>protect and support – in accordance with each country’s own approach &#8211; journalists and media professionals under threat, while respecting the empowering of organisations that systematically monitor press and media freedom,</li>
<li>deepen our collaboration through existing initiatives, such as the Media Freedom Coalition and the Global Media Defence Fund (GMDF), which help to protect media freedom and journalists and to take action against abusive litigation against journalists and human rights defenders (known as SLAPP suits) which is used to silence them.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>C. Cooperation and Inclusion of Civil Society</strong></p>
<p>Freedom, plurality and sustainability are the values that should guide our path forward into the future. We will connect with civil-society actors, advance concrete initiatives, and in doing so strengthen the multilateral order to create and preserve peace. Space for open, democratic debate online and offline has to be maintained, in which ideas, projects, and visions of democratic society can be shared and discussed.</p>
<p><strong>We support all those who stand up for democracy by:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>noting the work of international initiatives and mechanisms such as the OECD’s work on Rebuilding Trust and Reinforcing Democracy and the Partnership on Information and Democracy,</li>
<li>reaffirming our commitment to existing institutions such as the European Audiovisual Observatory, which are important sources of information for media policy,</li>
<li>cooperating in opposing politically motivated internet shutdowns and restrictions,</li>
<li>welcoming initiatives that promote a safe and secure information environment, media and information literacy and trustworthy journalism, and therefore welcoming the Democracy Newsroom initiative,</li>
<li>encouraging initiatives that contribute to a viable, diverse and independent media industry, supporting innovation and digital transformation, including through additional collaborations to support and sustain independent public interest media,</li>
<li>welcoming media initiatives that enable independent journalism to remain a watchdog of democracy at local, national and international levels and contributes to the public debate,</li>
<li>encouraging the initiative “Transparency and freedom of opinion – Crisis resilience of media”,</li>
<li>welcoming the Canada-led international Guiding Principles on Diversity of Content Online, which were developed in collaboration with a multi-stakeholder working group that includes counterparts in other countries, and with civil-society and industry partners,</li>
<li>encouraging the establishment of media literacy courses for all generations to enable individuals to clearly differentiate between fact-based information and disinformation, to understand how manipulative tactics can be used online and offline and to understand journalism as an indispensable part of the checks and balances in democratic societies.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>D. Initiating Work Processes – The Way Forward</strong></p>
<p>We therefore intend to anchor media policy even more firmly at the global level as a field of work that is relevant to democracy. In coordination with existing initiatives and formats, in particular with the G7 Rapid Response Mechanism (RRM), we want, for the first time, to create a forum for increased dialogue at the G7 concerning the global media online and offline, a dialogue which requires a global response, and developing solutions and cooperative approaches.</p>
<p><strong>In order to achieve these goals, we commit to:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>continue to closely coordinate on questions concerning the spread of content and information from a security, human rights, technical and media policy perspective, and pursue a joint approach to support media freedom and pluralism,</li>
<li>create a follow-up process to achieve the aforementioned goals,</li>
<li>welcome the input of international experts on media freedom in state decision-making processes, in addition to forums such as the EU, the CoE, OSCE and the UN,</li>
<li>actively use opportunities for cooperation with international associations, civil-society organisations and initiatives on current media-related issues.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1"></a> As of 6 June 2022, according to the Council of Europe’s Platform to promote the protection of journalism and safety of journalists.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="100001000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General Delattre</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-french-foreign-ministry-secretary-general-delattre-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 19:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=354093</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General François Delattre today to discuss continued coordination to support Ukraine and its sovereignty and territorial integrity, including how best to respond to Ukraine’s urgent security needs. They also discussed global food insecurity, which has been exacerbated by Putin’s unprovoked and unjustified war. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Secretary Delattre also spoke about preparations for the upcoming NATO Summit in Madrid and ensuring the Alliance remains ready to meet current and future challenges.</p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General François Delattre today to discuss continued coordination to support Ukraine and its sovereignty and territorial integrity, including how best to respond to Ukraine’s urgent security needs. They also discussed global food insecurity, which has been exacerbated by Putin’s unprovoked and unjustified war. Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Secretary Delattre also spoke about preparations for the upcoming NATO Summit in Madrid and ensuring the Alliance remains ready to meet current and future challenges.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with European External Action Service Secretary General Sannino</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-european-external-action-service-secretary-general-sannino-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 19:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=354104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary Wendy R. Sherman spoke today with European External Action Service Secretary General Stefano Sannino, continuing their close coordination on a wide range of shared challenges, including supporting Ukraine and holding Russia accountable for its brutal and unprovoked war in Ukraine.  They discussed their joint efforts to bolster Ukraine’s economic and financial resilience and ensure that it can export agricultural commodities to provide the world with critical food supplies.  The Deputy Secretary underscored U.S. support for the Euro-Atlantic aspirations of Ukraine, Moldova, Georgia, and the countries of the Western Balkans.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary Wendy R. Sherman spoke today with European External Action Service Secretary General Stefano Sannino, continuing their close coordination on a wide range of shared challenges, including supporting Ukraine and holding Russia accountable for its brutal and unprovoked war in Ukraine.  They discussed their joint efforts to bolster Ukraine’s economic and financial resilience and ensure that it can export agricultural commodities to provide the world with critical food supplies.  The Deputy Secretary underscored U.S. support for the Euro-Atlantic aspirations of Ukraine, Moldova, Georgia, and the countries of the Western Balkans.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devastating Earthquake in Afghanistan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/devastating-earthquake-in-afghanistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 19:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=354095</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p align="left">The United States expresses deep sorrow for the victims of today’s devastating earthquake in Afghanistan, and we offer our sympathy and prayers to those who lost loved ones in the tragedy. The people of Afghanistan have undergone extraordinary hardship, and this natural disaster compounds an already dire humanitarian situation. U.S. humanitarian partners are already responding, including by sending medical teams to help people affected, and we are assessing other response options.</p>
<p align="left">We stand with the people of Afghanistan and will continue to lead the international community in responding to their humanitarian needs.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p align="left">The United States expresses deep sorrow for the victims of today’s devastating earthquake in Afghanistan, and we offer our sympathy and prayers to those who lost loved ones in the tragedy. The people of Afghanistan have undergone extraordinary hardship, and this natural disaster compounds an already dire humanitarian situation. U.S. humanitarian partners are already responding, including by sending medical teams to help people affected, and we are assessing other response options.</p>
<p align="left">We stand with the people of Afghanistan and will continue to lead the international community in responding to their humanitarian needs.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ecuador: Travel Advisory Raised to Level 3 – Reconsider Travel</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/ecuador-travel-advisory-raised-to-level-3-reconsider-travel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 15:11:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=354001</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The Department of State raised the Travel Advisory Level for Ecuador to Level 3 – Reconsider Travel on June 22, 2022.  This replaces the previous Travel Advisory issued on April 19, 2022.</p>
<p align="left">The full text of the updated Travel Advisory is as follows:</p>
<p align="left"><b>Ecuador – Level 3:  Reconsider Travel C U</b></p>
<p align="left">Reconsider travel to Ecuador due to <b>civil unrest </b>and <b>crime</b>.  Some areas have increased risk.  Read the entire Travel Advisory.</p>
<p align="left">Do not travel to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Carchi, Sucumbíos, and the northern part of Esmeraldas provinces, including Esmeraldas city, due to <b>crime</b>.</li>
<li>Guayaquil, south of Portete de Tarquí Avenue, due to <b>crime</b>.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Country Summary:</b> Crime is a widespread problem in Ecuador.  Violent crime, such as murder, assault, express kidnapping, and armed robbery, is common.  Transnational criminal organizations and gangs operate in Carchi, Sucumbíos, and the northern part of Esmeraldas provinces, as well as in Guayaquil, south of Portete de Tarquí Avenue.</p>
<p>Demonstrations occur regularly throughout the country.  Public demonstrations can take place for a variety of political and economic issues.  Demonstrations can cause the shutdown of local roads and major highways, often without prior notice or estimated reopening timelines.  Road closures may significantly reduce access to public transportation and airports and may disrupt travel both within and between cities.</p>
<p>Read the <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vaW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC10cmF2ZWwvSW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC1UcmF2ZWwtQ291bnRyeS1JbmZvcm1hdGlvbi1QYWdlcy9FY3VhZG9yLmh0bWwifQ.huutpFymawKXK4r48oAUfCKFLlFPbbl7bbYzsslEk94/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vaW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC10cmF2ZWwvSW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC1UcmF2ZWwtQ291bnRyeS1JbmZvcm1hdGlvbi1QYWdlcy9FY3VhZG9yLmh0bWwifQ.huutpFymawKXK4r48oAUfCKFLlFPbbl7bbYzsslEk94%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=gZIkRvNFk74DIOZ8XJ36LvbdCo8jV1ylFeMSZfLvU9w%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="0">country information page</a> for additional information on traveling to Ecuador.</p>
<p>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) has determined Ecuador has a high level of COVID-19.  Visit the CDC page for the latest <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzL2VjdWFkb3ItdHJhdmVsLWFkdmlzb3J5Lmh0bWwjRXh0ZXJuYWxQb3B1cCJ9.Y_l4urIv44xgX2jZpDP2Uc3gDh0_sMAt3WECt30N2c0/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzL2VjdWFkb3ItdHJhdmVsLWFkdmlzb3J5Lmh0bWwjRXh0ZXJuYWxQb3B1cCJ9.Y_l4urIv44xgX2jZpDP2Uc3gDh0_sMAt3WECt30N2c0%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=s4wF9tyrFI00QDf52CnMYgWbaGUAApvrEFyjH3aPBW4%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="1">Travel Health Information</a> related to your travel.</p>
<p>If you decide to travel to Ecuador:</p>
<ul>
<li>Read the <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDIsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy9jb3ZpZC0xOS10cmF2ZWwtaW5mb3JtYXRpb24uaHRtbCJ9.Ummxb5CtOY6R_Di6ewv9ZIPT2egKqymQXAonn6IRU88/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDIsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy9jb3ZpZC0xOS10cmF2ZWwtaW5mb3JtYXRpb24uaHRtbCJ9.Ummxb5CtOY6R_Di6ewv9ZIPT2egKqymQXAonn6IRU88%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=BWmYH%2BEersXRAaXoWY%2FlMzPNe83mBE3uIMQjT3T1VoU%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="2">Department of State’s COVID-19 page </a>before planning any international travel, and read the <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDMsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2VjLnVzZW1iYXNzeS5nb3YvY292aWQtMTktaW5mb3JtYXRpb24tZWN1LTIvIn0.o0-jDinZ4jCiVp7aB-Lc_Oc4EfAtqGjp8NVWf19YmFE/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDMsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2VjLnVzZW1iYXNzeS5nb3YvY292aWQtMTktaW5mb3JtYXRpb24tZWN1LTIvIn0.o0-jDinZ4jCiVp7aB-Lc_Oc4EfAtqGjp8NVWf19YmFE%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=MsEX%2BKarppVs4MayjLEGfxD9TLr%2BrnvmMyCiskfyO0k%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="3">Embassy COVID-19 page</a> for country-specific COVID-19 information.</li>
<li>Enroll in the <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDQsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3N0ZXAuc3RhdGUuZ292L3N0ZXAvIn0.Hme-qIpdQHiLiUdbwChV9aEz_KXTv8FIhNo83e7h2gc/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDQsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3N0ZXAuc3RhdGUuZ292L3N0ZXAvIn0.Hme-qIpdQHiLiUdbwChV9aEz_KXTv8FIhNo83e7h2gc%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=rdLyUTDIc5Rk5mr%2BM8jbqcN6%2F8xz9VOsmrcDBtqXgYk%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="4">Smart Traveler Enrollment Program </a>(<a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDUsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3N0ZXAuc3RhdGUuZ292L3N0ZXAvIn0.jRE2QzKdkE9yVv_KcwWeWpOY-djq-vUNkP9zpaax7so/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDUsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3N0ZXAuc3RhdGUuZ292L3N0ZXAvIn0.jRE2QzKdkE9yVv_KcwWeWpOY-djq-vUNkP9zpaax7so%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=c11dac62RK0ula8El86FWCvSxRo7wZRDUNbCNy8fP9Y%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="5">STEP</a>) to receive Alerts and make it easier to locate you in an emergency.</li>
<li>Follow the Department of State on <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDYsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzL2VjdWFkb3ItdHJhdmVsLWFkdmlzb3J5Lmh0bWwjRXh0ZXJuYWxQb3B1cCJ9.95_-ke0K51MFqPaC6V4-j-xXfRg3-_1LlwYhzMG5hac/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDYsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzL2VjdWFkb3ItdHJhdmVsLWFkdmlzb3J5Lmh0bWwjRXh0ZXJuYWxQb3B1cCJ9.95_-ke0K51MFqPaC6V4-j-xXfRg3-_1LlwYhzMG5hac%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=NWHx2JKdaFz9GklKZshHBSFGH5PANnrS2T1MMVSvNW0%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="6">Facebook</a>, <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDcsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzL2VjdWFkb3ItdHJhdmVsLWFkdmlzb3J5Lmh0bWwjRXh0ZXJuYWxQb3B1cCJ9.F4DycbErkhqUGnvH7YkbaJ3UV7lpZ0GIZhOS5YRTOi8/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDcsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzL2VjdWFkb3ItdHJhdmVsLWFkdmlzb3J5Lmh0bWwjRXh0ZXJuYWxQb3B1cCJ9.F4DycbErkhqUGnvH7YkbaJ3UV7lpZ0GIZhOS5YRTOi8%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=wKbIrD8lZl%2BxphiUtkWeXBkTejQ8K3cMS7Vgdx7jqQE%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="7">Twitter</a>, and <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDgsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzL2VjdWFkb3ItdHJhdmVsLWFkdmlzb3J5Lmh0bWwjRXh0ZXJuYWxQb3B1cCJ9.7CjJ_8AZ29n2_YdMzx8Gd3uGNKkv1VImp3izJBk7DxM/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDgsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzL2VjdWFkb3ItdHJhdmVsLWFkdmlzb3J5Lmh0bWwjRXh0ZXJuYWxQb3B1cCJ9.7CjJ_8AZ29n2_YdMzx8Gd3uGNKkv1VImp3izJBk7DxM%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=Epqo2hweo5pBKRo1bwrD3tZYRpVhDmdKrEiWT0Y5GKA%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="8">Instagram</a></li>
<li>Review the <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDksInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5vc2FjLmdvdi9Db250ZW50L0Jyb3dzZS9SZXBvcnQ_c3ViQ29udGVudFR5cGVzPUNvdW50cnklMjBTZWN1cml0eSUyMFJlcG9ydCJ9.LWo08UM2V1PgKo76aDigAjtOxm2nYOadBX7acsz8_L0/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDksInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5vc2FjLmdvdi9Db250ZW50L0Jyb3dzZS9SZXBvcnQ_c3ViQ29udGVudFR5cGVzPUNvdW50cnklMjBTZWN1cml0eSUyMFJlcG9ydCJ9.LWo08UM2V1PgKo76aDigAjtOxm2nYOadBX7acsz8_L0%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=6LpvgMjG6P4B0laOCtFmP7i5w2buz6VdL7j%2FxM0a7m8%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="9">Country Security Report </a>for Ecuador.</li>
<li>Prepare a contingency plan for emergency situations. Review the <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMTAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vaW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC10cmF2ZWwvYmVmb3JlLXlvdS1nby90cmF2ZWxlcnMtY2hlY2tsaXN0Lmh0bWwifQ.UX4pLzbuNoFpE21lsx3HxltyLHVu23BcbHEic6gZJNQ/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMTAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vaW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC10cmF2ZWwvYmVmb3JlLXlvdS1nby90cmF2ZWxlcnMtY2hlY2tsaXN0Lmh0bWwifQ.UX4pLzbuNoFpE21lsx3HxltyLHVu23BcbHEic6gZJNQ%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=ZNiG96N7eba2uXHbn5P%2BNs9YcK4DAvyhbboteGNi6Os%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="10">Traveler’s Checklist</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Carchi, Sucumbíos, and northern Esmeraldas Provinces – Level 4: Do Not Travel</b></p>
<p><b></b>Transnational crime groups operating in Esmeraldas province have engaged in violent crime and killed local citizens in addition to carrying out bombings targeting Ecuadorian military and law enforcement.</p>
<p>The U.S. government is limited in its ability to provide emergency services to U.S. citizens in the Colombian border area, as U.S. government personnel cannot travel to the provinces of Esmeraldas, Carchi, and Sucumbíos without permission from the Embassy’s security office. However, U.S. government personnel are permitted to travel to the northern bank of the Napo River in Sucumbíos, an area approximately four miles wide, and the portion of Esmeraldas province that is south of Esmeraldas city.</p>
<p><b>Guayaquil, south of Portete de Tarquí Avenue – Level 4: Do Not Travel</b></p>
<p><b></b>Transnational crime groups and local gangs operating in Guayaquil have carried out a series of violent crimes in the region south of Portete de Tarquí Avenue, to include several murders and targeted assassinations, armed robberies, and assaults. The U.S. government is limited in its ability to provide emergency services to U.S. citizens in Guayaquil south of Portete de Tarquí Avenue, as U.S. government personnel cannot travel to this area without permission from the Embassy’s security office.</p>
<p>Visit our website for <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMTEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vaW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC10cmF2ZWwvYmVmb3JlLXlvdS1nby90cmF2ZWxlcnMtd2l0aC1zcGVjaWFsLWNvbnNpZGVyYXRpb25zL2hpZ2gtcmlzay10cmF2ZWxlcnMuaHRtbCJ9.J0jJlJyI7-3QCWrOzx0NRXISG3XJ4lLsF2jmT8UbwIU/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMTEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vaW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC10cmF2ZWwvYmVmb3JlLXlvdS1nby90cmF2ZWxlcnMtd2l0aC1zcGVjaWFsLWNvbnNpZGVyYXRpb25zL2hpZ2gtcmlzay10cmF2ZWxlcnMuaHRtbCJ9.J0jJlJyI7-3QCWrOzx0NRXISG3XJ4lLsF2jmT8UbwIU%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=k8cslE6qVRHAN%2B8%2BjBix4Vwk8ldAWAcnrJviI3mGTNA%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="11">Travel to High-Risk Areas</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The Department of State raised the Travel Advisory Level for Ecuador to Level 3 – Reconsider Travel on June 22, 2022.  This replaces the previous Travel Advisory issued on April 19, 2022.</p>
<p align="left">The full text of the updated Travel Advisory is as follows:</p>
<p align="left"><b>Ecuador – Level 3:  Reconsider Travel C U</b></p>
<p align="left">Reconsider travel to Ecuador due to <b>civil unrest </b>and <b>crime</b>.  Some areas have increased risk.  Read the entire Travel Advisory.</p>
<p align="left">Do not travel to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Carchi, Sucumbíos, and the northern part of Esmeraldas provinces, including Esmeraldas city, due to <b>crime</b>.</li>
<li>Guayaquil, south of Portete de Tarquí Avenue, due to <b>crime</b>.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Country Summary:</b> Crime is a widespread problem in Ecuador.  Violent crime, such as murder, assault, express kidnapping, and armed robbery, is common.  Transnational criminal organizations and gangs operate in Carchi, Sucumbíos, and the northern part of Esmeraldas provinces, as well as in Guayaquil, south of Portete de Tarquí Avenue.</p>
<p>Demonstrations occur regularly throughout the country.  Public demonstrations can take place for a variety of political and economic issues.  Demonstrations can cause the shutdown of local roads and major highways, often without prior notice or estimated reopening timelines.  Road closures may significantly reduce access to public transportation and airports and may disrupt travel both within and between cities.</p>
<p>Read the <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vaW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC10cmF2ZWwvSW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC1UcmF2ZWwtQ291bnRyeS1JbmZvcm1hdGlvbi1QYWdlcy9FY3VhZG9yLmh0bWwifQ.huutpFymawKXK4r48oAUfCKFLlFPbbl7bbYzsslEk94/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vaW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC10cmF2ZWwvSW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC1UcmF2ZWwtQ291bnRyeS1JbmZvcm1hdGlvbi1QYWdlcy9FY3VhZG9yLmh0bWwifQ.huutpFymawKXK4r48oAUfCKFLlFPbbl7bbYzsslEk94%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=gZIkRvNFk74DIOZ8XJ36LvbdCo8jV1ylFeMSZfLvU9w%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="0">country information page</a> for additional information on traveling to Ecuador.</p>
<p>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) has determined Ecuador has a high level of COVID-19.  Visit the CDC page for the latest <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzL2VjdWFkb3ItdHJhdmVsLWFkdmlzb3J5Lmh0bWwjRXh0ZXJuYWxQb3B1cCJ9.Y_l4urIv44xgX2jZpDP2Uc3gDh0_sMAt3WECt30N2c0/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzL2VjdWFkb3ItdHJhdmVsLWFkdmlzb3J5Lmh0bWwjRXh0ZXJuYWxQb3B1cCJ9.Y_l4urIv44xgX2jZpDP2Uc3gDh0_sMAt3WECt30N2c0%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=s4wF9tyrFI00QDf52CnMYgWbaGUAApvrEFyjH3aPBW4%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="1">Travel Health Information</a> related to your travel.</p>
<p>If you decide to travel to Ecuador:</p>
<ul>
<li>Read the <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDIsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy9jb3ZpZC0xOS10cmF2ZWwtaW5mb3JtYXRpb24uaHRtbCJ9.Ummxb5CtOY6R_Di6ewv9ZIPT2egKqymQXAonn6IRU88/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDIsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy9jb3ZpZC0xOS10cmF2ZWwtaW5mb3JtYXRpb24uaHRtbCJ9.Ummxb5CtOY6R_Di6ewv9ZIPT2egKqymQXAonn6IRU88%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=BWmYH%2BEersXRAaXoWY%2FlMzPNe83mBE3uIMQjT3T1VoU%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="2">Department of State’s COVID-19 page </a>before planning any international travel, and read the <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDMsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2VjLnVzZW1iYXNzeS5nb3YvY292aWQtMTktaW5mb3JtYXRpb24tZWN1LTIvIn0.o0-jDinZ4jCiVp7aB-Lc_Oc4EfAtqGjp8NVWf19YmFE/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDMsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2VjLnVzZW1iYXNzeS5nb3YvY292aWQtMTktaW5mb3JtYXRpb24tZWN1LTIvIn0.o0-jDinZ4jCiVp7aB-Lc_Oc4EfAtqGjp8NVWf19YmFE%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=MsEX%2BKarppVs4MayjLEGfxD9TLr%2BrnvmMyCiskfyO0k%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="3">Embassy COVID-19 page</a> for country-specific COVID-19 information.</li>
<li>Enroll in the <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDQsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3N0ZXAuc3RhdGUuZ292L3N0ZXAvIn0.Hme-qIpdQHiLiUdbwChV9aEz_KXTv8FIhNo83e7h2gc/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDQsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3N0ZXAuc3RhdGUuZ292L3N0ZXAvIn0.Hme-qIpdQHiLiUdbwChV9aEz_KXTv8FIhNo83e7h2gc%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=rdLyUTDIc5Rk5mr%2BM8jbqcN6%2F8xz9VOsmrcDBtqXgYk%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="4">Smart Traveler Enrollment Program </a>(<a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDUsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3N0ZXAuc3RhdGUuZ292L3N0ZXAvIn0.jRE2QzKdkE9yVv_KcwWeWpOY-djq-vUNkP9zpaax7so/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDUsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3N0ZXAuc3RhdGUuZ292L3N0ZXAvIn0.jRE2QzKdkE9yVv_KcwWeWpOY-djq-vUNkP9zpaax7so%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=c11dac62RK0ula8El86FWCvSxRo7wZRDUNbCNy8fP9Y%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="5">STEP</a>) to receive Alerts and make it easier to locate you in an emergency.</li>
<li>Follow the Department of State on <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDYsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzL2VjdWFkb3ItdHJhdmVsLWFkdmlzb3J5Lmh0bWwjRXh0ZXJuYWxQb3B1cCJ9.95_-ke0K51MFqPaC6V4-j-xXfRg3-_1LlwYhzMG5hac/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDYsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzL2VjdWFkb3ItdHJhdmVsLWFkdmlzb3J5Lmh0bWwjRXh0ZXJuYWxQb3B1cCJ9.95_-ke0K51MFqPaC6V4-j-xXfRg3-_1LlwYhzMG5hac%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=NWHx2JKdaFz9GklKZshHBSFGH5PANnrS2T1MMVSvNW0%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="6">Facebook</a>, <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDcsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzL2VjdWFkb3ItdHJhdmVsLWFkdmlzb3J5Lmh0bWwjRXh0ZXJuYWxQb3B1cCJ9.F4DycbErkhqUGnvH7YkbaJ3UV7lpZ0GIZhOS5YRTOi8/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDcsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzL2VjdWFkb3ItdHJhdmVsLWFkdmlzb3J5Lmh0bWwjRXh0ZXJuYWxQb3B1cCJ9.F4DycbErkhqUGnvH7YkbaJ3UV7lpZ0GIZhOS5YRTOi8%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=wKbIrD8lZl%2BxphiUtkWeXBkTejQ8K3cMS7Vgdx7jqQE%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="7">Twitter</a>, and <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDgsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzL2VjdWFkb3ItdHJhdmVsLWFkdmlzb3J5Lmh0bWwjRXh0ZXJuYWxQb3B1cCJ9.7CjJ_8AZ29n2_YdMzx8Gd3uGNKkv1VImp3izJBk7DxM/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDgsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vdHJhdmVsYWR2aXNvcmllcy90cmF2ZWxhZHZpc29yaWVzL2VjdWFkb3ItdHJhdmVsLWFkdmlzb3J5Lmh0bWwjRXh0ZXJuYWxQb3B1cCJ9.7CjJ_8AZ29n2_YdMzx8Gd3uGNKkv1VImp3izJBk7DxM%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=Epqo2hweo5pBKRo1bwrD3tZYRpVhDmdKrEiWT0Y5GKA%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="8">Instagram</a></li>
<li>Review the <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDksInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5vc2FjLmdvdi9Db250ZW50L0Jyb3dzZS9SZXBvcnQ_c3ViQ29udGVudFR5cGVzPUNvdW50cnklMjBTZWN1cml0eSUyMFJlcG9ydCJ9.LWo08UM2V1PgKo76aDigAjtOxm2nYOadBX7acsz8_L0/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDksInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5vc2FjLmdvdi9Db250ZW50L0Jyb3dzZS9SZXBvcnQ_c3ViQ29udGVudFR5cGVzPUNvdW50cnklMjBTZWN1cml0eSUyMFJlcG9ydCJ9.LWo08UM2V1PgKo76aDigAjtOxm2nYOadBX7acsz8_L0%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=6LpvgMjG6P4B0laOCtFmP7i5w2buz6VdL7j%2FxM0a7m8%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="9">Country Security Report </a>for Ecuador.</li>
<li>Prepare a contingency plan for emergency situations. Review the <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMTAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vaW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC10cmF2ZWwvYmVmb3JlLXlvdS1nby90cmF2ZWxlcnMtY2hlY2tsaXN0Lmh0bWwifQ.UX4pLzbuNoFpE21lsx3HxltyLHVu23BcbHEic6gZJNQ/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMTAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vaW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC10cmF2ZWwvYmVmb3JlLXlvdS1nby90cmF2ZWxlcnMtY2hlY2tsaXN0Lmh0bWwifQ.UX4pLzbuNoFpE21lsx3HxltyLHVu23BcbHEic6gZJNQ%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=ZNiG96N7eba2uXHbn5P%2BNs9YcK4DAvyhbboteGNi6Os%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="10">Traveler’s Checklist</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Carchi, Sucumbíos, and northern Esmeraldas Provinces – Level 4: Do Not Travel</b></p>
<p><b></b>Transnational crime groups operating in Esmeraldas province have engaged in violent crime and killed local citizens in addition to carrying out bombings targeting Ecuadorian military and law enforcement.</p>
<p>The U.S. government is limited in its ability to provide emergency services to U.S. citizens in the Colombian border area, as U.S. government personnel cannot travel to the provinces of Esmeraldas, Carchi, and Sucumbíos without permission from the Embassy’s security office. However, U.S. government personnel are permitted to travel to the northern bank of the Napo River in Sucumbíos, an area approximately four miles wide, and the portion of Esmeraldas province that is south of Esmeraldas city.</p>
<p><b>Guayaquil, south of Portete de Tarquí Avenue – Level 4: Do Not Travel</b></p>
<p><b></b>Transnational crime groups and local gangs operating in Guayaquil have carried out a series of violent crimes in the region south of Portete de Tarquí Avenue, to include several murders and targeted assassinations, armed robberies, and assaults. The U.S. government is limited in its ability to provide emergency services to U.S. citizens in Guayaquil south of Portete de Tarquí Avenue, as U.S. government personnel cannot travel to this area without permission from the Embassy’s security office.</p>
<p>Visit our website for <a title="Original URL: https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMTEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vaW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC10cmF2ZWwvYmVmb3JlLXlvdS1nby90cmF2ZWxlcnMtd2l0aC1zcGVjaWFsLWNvbnNpZGVyYXRpb25zL2hpZ2gtcmlzay10cmF2ZWxlcnMuaHRtbCJ9.J0jJlJyI7-3QCWrOzx0NRXISG3XJ4lLsF2jmT8UbwIU/s/1436012980/br/133399786464-l. Click or tap if you trust this link." href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMTEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA2MjIuNTk3MzQ5NDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3RyYXZlbC5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvY29udGVudC90cmF2ZWwvZW4vaW50ZXJuYXRpb25hbC10cmF2ZWwvYmVmb3JlLXlvdS1nby90cmF2ZWxlcnMtd2l0aC1zcGVjaWFsLWNvbnNpZGVyYXRpb25zL2hpZ2gtcmlzay10cmF2ZWxlcnMuaHRtbCJ9.J0jJlJyI7-3QCWrOzx0NRXISG3XJ4lLsF2jmT8UbwIU%2Fs%2F1436012980%2Fbr%2F133399786464-l&amp;data=05%7C01%7CSimmonsJX%40state.gov%7C85e996a14e394befc4ea08da545af492%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637915046889980015%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=k8cslE6qVRHAN%2B8%2BjBix4Vwk8ldAWAcnrJviI3mGTNA%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="11">Travel to High-Risk Areas</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Civilian Deaths in Mali</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/civilian-deaths-in-mali/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 13:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=353960</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States was deeply saddened to learn of the violence in the Bandiagara and Gao regions of Mali this past weekend, resulting in the deaths of more than 100 civilians. This development comes at a time when ongoing violence in Ménaka has also killed numerous civilians and displaced thousands more. The United States stands with the Malian people in the face of these grotesque acts of violence against civilian populations, and our thoughts are with the families of those killed. We wish a swift recovery to those injured, and we will continue to work with Mali’s accountable international partners to build a brighter and more peaceful future for all Malians.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States was deeply saddened to learn of the violence in the Bandiagara and Gao regions of Mali this past weekend, resulting in the deaths of more than 100 civilians. This development comes at a time when ongoing violence in Ménaka has also killed numerous civilians and displaced thousands more. The United States stands with the Malian people in the face of these grotesque acts of violence against civilian populations, and our thoughts are with the families of those killed. We wish a swift recovery to those injured, and we will continue to work with Mali’s accountable international partners to build a brighter and more peaceful future for all Malians.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Travel for the Germany-hosted Food Security Ministerial and the G7 and NATO Summits</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-for-the-germany-hosted-food-security-ministerial-and-the-g7-and-nato-summits/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 13:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=353957</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[		<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
		<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Germany on June 23 to join foreign ministers for the Berlin Ministerial Conference “Uniting for Global Food Security” on June 24.  He will meet with the participants to advance global initiatives to address food insecurity, stemming from both Russia’s brutal, unprovoked war against Ukraine and the continued challenges posed by climate change, the COVID-19 pandemic, other conflicts, and supply chain challenges.</p>
<p>On June 25, Secretary Blinken will travel to Schloss Elmau to join President Biden for the G7 Leaders’ Summit.  G7 leaders will discuss a range of pressing global issues, including our unwavering support for a democratic, sovereign, and prosperous Ukraine, economic and democratic resilience, tackling the climate crisis, development infrastructure, global health security, and the food and energy crisis caused by Russia’s war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Madrid, Spain, for the June 29-30 NATO Summit.  At the NATO Summit, Allied leaders will endorse a new Strategic Concept to guide NATO’s transformation over the next decade, from strengthening deterrence and defense to building resilience against transnational and hybrid threats, including cyber and climate, to deepening partnerships with like-minded partners in Europe and Asia in order to strengthen the rules-based international order.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
					<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
				<script type="text/javascript">
document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function(event) {
			jQuery(document).ready(function(){
			if (jQuery('p .watermark').length > 0 ) {

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().addClass('watermarked');

				jQuery('p .watermark').parent().each( function() {
					jQuery(this).children('img').attr('style', 'margin: 0 !important');
					jQuery(this).children().wrapAll('<div class="watermarked_image"></div>');
				});

				jQuery('.entry-content p.watermarked > div.watermarked_image > img').each( function() {
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignnone') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignnone' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignleft') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignleft' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('alignright') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'alignright' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('size-medium') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'has-size-medium' );
					}
					if ( jQuery(this).hasClass('aligncenter') ) {
						jQuery(this).parent().addClass( 'aligncenter' );
						jQuery(this).parent().children().wrapAll('<div class="wm_centered"></div>');
					}
				});
			}
		});
		});
		</script>
									<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Germany on June 23 to join foreign ministers for the Berlin Ministerial Conference “Uniting for Global Food Security” on June 24.  He will meet with the participants to advance global initiatives to address food insecurity, stemming from both Russia’s brutal, unprovoked war against Ukraine and the continued challenges posed by climate change, the COVID-19 pandemic, other conflicts, and supply chain challenges.</p>
<p>On June 25, Secretary Blinken will travel to Schloss Elmau to join President Biden for the G7 Leaders’ Summit.  G7 leaders will discuss a range of pressing global issues, including our unwavering support for a democratic, sovereign, and prosperous Ukraine, economic and democratic resilience, tackling the climate crisis, development infrastructure, global health security, and the food and energy crisis caused by Russia’s war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Madrid, Spain, for the June 29-30 NATO Summit.  At the NATO Summit, Allied leaders will endorse a new Strategic Concept to guide NATO’s transformation over the next decade, from strengthening deterrence and defense to building resilience against transnational and hybrid threats, including cyber and climate, to deepening partnerships with like-minded partners in Europe and Asia in order to strengthen the rules-based international order.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
