<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 12:37:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the Launch of the U.S.-Japan Global Digital Connectivity Partnership</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-the-launch-of-the-u-s-japan-global-digital-connectivity-partnership/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 12:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of Japan and the United States of America.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Begin text:</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On May 27, 2021, interagency representatives from the United States and Japan met virtually to launch the U.S.-Japan Global Digital Connectivity Partnership (GDCP).  Announced during the summit meeting between President Biden and Prime Minister Suga on April 16, 2021, the GDCP deepens bilateral cooperation on the digital economy and next-generation digital technology issues.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The GDCP builds upon previous cooperation, including through the Japan-U.S. Strategic Digital Economy Partnership (JUSDEP), by elevating and expanding the scope of discussions to promote secure connectivity and vibrant digital economies.  The GDCP will promote: (1) cooperation in third countries across the Indo-Pacific, Africa, Latin America, and other regions; (2) enhanced collaboration in multilateral fora; and (3) forward-looking mechanisms in both countries that catalyze investment in fifth-generation (5G) wireless technologies, next-generation telecommunications, and the corresponding research and development environment, as well as training and cybersecurity capacity building.  The initial meeting addressed an array of priority issues spanning these three categories.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The delegations from both governments, led by the U.S. Department of State and the Japanese Ministry of Internal Affairs and Communications, decided to convene an expert-level working group multiple times per year within the structure of the U.S.-Japan Policy Cooperation Dialogue on the Internet Economy (IED).  The two sides reaffirmed their commitment to strengthen their competitiveness in the digital field and looked forward to the IED annual meeting to be held later this year. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">End text.</span></i></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of Japan and the United States of America.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Begin text:</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On May 27, 2021, interagency representatives from the United States and Japan met virtually to launch the U.S.-Japan Global Digital Connectivity Partnership (GDCP).  Announced during the summit meeting between President Biden and Prime Minister Suga on April 16, 2021, the GDCP deepens bilateral cooperation on the digital economy and next-generation digital technology issues.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The GDCP builds upon previous cooperation, including through the Japan-U.S. Strategic Digital Economy Partnership (JUSDEP), by elevating and expanding the scope of discussions to promote secure connectivity and vibrant digital economies.  The GDCP will promote: (1) cooperation in third countries across the Indo-Pacific, Africa, Latin America, and other regions; (2) enhanced collaboration in multilateral fora; and (3) forward-looking mechanisms in both countries that catalyze investment in fifth-generation (5G) wireless technologies, next-generation telecommunications, and the corresponding research and development environment, as well as training and cybersecurity capacity building.  The initial meeting addressed an array of priority issues spanning these three categories.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The delegations from both governments, led by the U.S. Department of State and the Japanese Ministry of Internal Affairs and Communications, decided to convene an expert-level working group multiple times per year within the structure of the U.S.-Japan Policy Cooperation Dialogue on the Internet Economy (IED).  The two sides reaffirmed their commitment to strengthen their competitiveness in the digital field and looked forward to the IED annual meeting to be held later this year. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">End text.</span></i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Meet and Greet with Embassy San Jose Staff</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-meet-and-greet-with-embassy-san-jose-staff/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 01:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248367</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>San Jose, Costa Rica</p>
<p>Chief of Mission Residence</p>
<p><strong>MS BERBENA:</strong> Well, welcome, everybody, and so delighted to see you. It is my distinct honor and privilege to welcome to the Chief of Mission Residence in San Jose the Secretary of State Antony Blinken. Sir, normally, we would have the entire embassy here to welcome you, but out of respect for COVID mitigation, we have a representative group of our team here that includes first and second-tour officers, LE staff, family members, employees and staff from the State Department and the other agencies that work with the mission.</p>
<p>You’ve had a very full 24 hours. You have engaged our leaders, our partners on issues that this mission works on every single day with tremendous commitment. But we saved the best for last, and that’s meeting our team, and I think you will find that there is no greater, more dedicated, more committed team than the people right here in front of you and those that are watching from a distance virtually. So, sir, welcome to the podium and the floor is yours. (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Thank you. Well, thank you all very, very much. Gloria, thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you for your wonderful stewardship these past 24 hours, but more to the point, thanks for the (inaudible).</p>
<p>(Break.)</p>
<p>So deeply appreciate everything you’re doing at this mission, leading us every day. We have another important (inaudible).</p>
<p>(Break.)</p>
<p>This is Diplomatic Security – (laughter) – at its finest, able to do anything on short notice, whatever contingency emerges. All right. There we go.</p>
<p>And when my wife Evan Ryan was assistant secretary for ECA, you worked closely together. It’s wonderful to be reconnected here. And I’m really, really pleased to be here in person. We’ve finally gotten to the point where we’re traveling again, we’re getting out, and at least even if we’re not in some places meeting face to face, we’re meeting mask to mask, and that’s at least an improvement over Zoom to Zoom.</p>
<p>And it’s no accident that the first port of call in Latin America, Central America, for me, for us, is right here in Costa Rica. I think it’s evidence of the fact that we have an incredibly strong and valued partner in Costa Rica across so many different things that matter, starting with a number of things that we did today, including dealing with the challenge posed by climate change, but also such a strong voice for the democratic principles that we share, and a voice that I think is more important than ever at a time when our democracies are being challenged.</p>
<p>So it was particularly important to come here, to be here, to spend time with our counterparts and also to see a little bit of some of the wonderful things that are happening, including the community center that is really quite – as I’m sure many of you know – remarkable in providing a sense of opportunity, a sense of hope for young people and, of course, evidence of the wonderful environmental leadership that Costa Rica is engaged in.</p>
<p>So it’s been, as the charge said, a compressed time, but we’ve had a terrific (inaudible). I really appreciate the great work that this mission has done to make this all come together – come together so well, come together so fast. I’ve got some idea from the years I’ve been doing it what goes into having – receiving guests from Washington. I can only wish you a very, very good wheels-up party – (laughter) – in a few short hours. But I think for me at least, the trip drove home the values that really connect the United States and Costa Rica. It’s a topic that actually came up in many of the conversations \we had with our counterparts and the work we’re doing to make progress together.</p>
<p>So I want to just really start again by thanking everyone for the success of the visit, but one of the things that I know as well is that these visits come and go. The real work in the relationship, the real work in building it, sustaining it, making it stronger is what happens every single day, and it’s in the work that each of you is doing.</p>
<p>And you’re finding ways, even in the midst of the pandemic, to grow and deepen the partnership. Just a few examples that were cited to me: You’re rolling out a $15 million project to help Costa Rican Government improve the capacity to reduce and prevent child sex trafficking, something that is truly meaningful and important.</p>
<p>You’ve implemented multiple projects to support refugees and vulnerable migrants in Costa Rica, including the Fundacion Mujer, a local NGO that provides English courses and career counseling, and Aqui Estoy, which gives food, health care, and job help to Venezuelan refugees. Parenthetically, I think one of the things that’s also so powerful about our friends here is the generosity and hospitality that they’ve extended, including to Venezuelans, including, of course, to Nicaraguans, given the deep ties that go back so many years between these countries.</p>
<p>You’ve also provided security assistance that’s helped Costa Rica become a major counternarcotics force in the region. You supported the wonderful project that we saw this morning, the Sembremos Seguridad, the citizen security program. And as I said, I saw their great work firsthand today. It was really quite wonderful, everything from seeing kids learn new skills, including skateboarding – I’m not sure that was – that might have been an indigenous skill – but two wonderful young children playing the violin, others doing judo, more doing pottery, others in a classroom learning. In fact, the classroom course was apparently focused today on negotiation skills, so I asked if I could sit in because I might learn something very important to take back with me. But I was really impressed by that, and it’s quite something to see community leaders, national leaders, police, mayors, everyone coming together and offering genuine hope and opportunity for young people, which really is the answer to so many of our challenges.</p>
<p>You’re leading the regional effort to stop illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing through the Team Fish interagency group. That too is one of those stories that’s a little bit underreported. But we see the havoc that that illegal fishing is wreaking in so many places around the world. It’s been devastating to local communities in many places whose livelihoods depend on fishing. It’s having an impact on biodiversity. And it’s something I think we’re going to increasingly be focused on.</p>
<p>A few months ago, you signed an MOU with the government to protect Costa Rica’s cultural property. I understand that MOU was languishing for more than 20 years until the public affairs section picked it up, ran with it, and got it done. So congratulations on that.</p>
<p>And, of course, there’s all the work that you’ve done to help mitigate the effects of COVID-19. Between April and September of last year, you helped repatriate more than 11,000 American citizens and more than 6,000 Costa Rican citizens. And thanks to you, Costa Rica was the first country in the region to receive three mobile field hospital tents, as well as PPE, lab supplies, hand washing stations, sanitizing gel, gel dispensers, all on behalf of the United States embassy.</p>
<p>I want you to know as well that in a few short days – in fact, possibly as early as tomorrow – the President is going to announce in more detail the plan that he’s put together to push out 80 million vaccines around the world that we have at our disposal or soon will have at our disposal. And we’re going to do that in coordination significantly with COVAX. We’re going to do that based on science and need. And we’re going to do that without any political strings attached.</p>
<p>Even as we’re doing that, we’re going to be working very hard on increasing manufacturing capacity in the United States and around the world so that we can get – finally get ahead of this virus and be the leader in vaccinating the world. If we stayed on the current trajectory, the one that we were on just a few weeks ago in terms of the pace of vaccination, we would not get to 70 or 80 percent vaccination around the world until 2024. We can speed this up; we’re going to speed this up. I think we have an opportunity to get this done by the end of next year. So stay tuned for that. It’s very, very important and the President’s been working very hard on getting this plan together.</p>
<p>I know what a challenging time this has been for everyone in this mission, dealing with COVID, having to do your jobs in the midst of a pandemic. I’m relieved that we have not lost any members of this embassy community. And I especially want to recognize the incredible work of the health unit here in San Jose, led by Amy (inaudible) Is Amy here? (Applause.) As well as Oscar (inaudible) – is Oscar here? (Applause.) From the Regional Security Office, who traveled to Bogota to bring additional vaccines to post so all of our contractors, all of our local guards could be vaccinated.</p>
<p>So we’ve been fortunate, and not just fortunate, we’ve been the beneficiaries of great work by our colleagues. But I know that some of you have lost loved ones, some of you have lost friends, and it’s hard to put words to that loss, except to say that I’m deeply sorry for the loss and deeply grateful to all of you who carried on in spite of those losses, and seeing the mission through.</p>
<p>Whether you’re an employee of the State Department or one of the many government agencies here at this mission; whether you’re a direct hire, a contractor, a family member; whether you’re locally employed staff, the lifeblood of this and every embassy, I just wanted to have an opportunity to say, very simply, thank you. Thank you for the wonderful work that you’re doing every single day on behalf of our country, on behalf of the relationship with Costa Rica, on behalf of making the world just a little bit safer, a little bit more prosperous, a little bit more hopeful. It’s wonderful work, it’s inspiring work, and I’m grateful to you for doing it. Thank you, thank you, thank you. (Applause.)</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>San Jose, Costa Rica</p>
<p>Chief of Mission Residence</p>
<p><strong>MS BERBENA:</strong> Well, welcome, everybody, and so delighted to see you. It is my distinct honor and privilege to welcome to the Chief of Mission Residence in San Jose the Secretary of State Antony Blinken. Sir, normally, we would have the entire embassy here to welcome you, but out of respect for COVID mitigation, we have a representative group of our team here that includes first and second-tour officers, LE staff, family members, employees and staff from the State Department and the other agencies that work with the mission.</p>
<p>You’ve had a very full 24 hours. You have engaged our leaders, our partners on issues that this mission works on every single day with tremendous commitment. But we saved the best for last, and that’s meeting our team, and I think you will find that there is no greater, more dedicated, more committed team than the people right here in front of you and those that are watching from a distance virtually. So, sir, welcome to the podium and the floor is yours. (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Thank you. Well, thank you all very, very much. Gloria, thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you for your wonderful stewardship these past 24 hours, but more to the point, thanks for the (inaudible).</p>
<p>(Break.)</p>
<p>So deeply appreciate everything you’re doing at this mission, leading us every day. We have another important (inaudible).</p>
<p>(Break.)</p>
<p>This is Diplomatic Security – (laughter) – at its finest, able to do anything on short notice, whatever contingency emerges. All right. There we go.</p>
<p>And when my wife Evan Ryan was assistant secretary for ECA, you worked closely together. It’s wonderful to be reconnected here. And I’m really, really pleased to be here in person. We’ve finally gotten to the point where we’re traveling again, we’re getting out, and at least even if we’re not in some places meeting face to face, we’re meeting mask to mask, and that’s at least an improvement over Zoom to Zoom.</p>
<p>And it’s no accident that the first port of call in Latin America, Central America, for me, for us, is right here in Costa Rica. I think it’s evidence of the fact that we have an incredibly strong and valued partner in Costa Rica across so many different things that matter, starting with a number of things that we did today, including dealing with the challenge posed by climate change, but also such a strong voice for the democratic principles that we share, and a voice that I think is more important than ever at a time when our democracies are being challenged.</p>
<p>So it was particularly important to come here, to be here, to spend time with our counterparts and also to see a little bit of some of the wonderful things that are happening, including the community center that is really quite – as I’m sure many of you know – remarkable in providing a sense of opportunity, a sense of hope for young people and, of course, evidence of the wonderful environmental leadership that Costa Rica is engaged in.</p>
<p>So it’s been, as the charge said, a compressed time, but we’ve had a terrific (inaudible). I really appreciate the great work that this mission has done to make this all come together – come together so well, come together so fast. I’ve got some idea from the years I’ve been doing it what goes into having – receiving guests from Washington. I can only wish you a very, very good wheels-up party – (laughter) – in a few short hours. But I think for me at least, the trip drove home the values that really connect the United States and Costa Rica. It’s a topic that actually came up in many of the conversations \we had with our counterparts and the work we’re doing to make progress together.</p>
<p>So I want to just really start again by thanking everyone for the success of the visit, but one of the things that I know as well is that these visits come and go. The real work in the relationship, the real work in building it, sustaining it, making it stronger is what happens every single day, and it’s in the work that each of you is doing.</p>
<p>And you’re finding ways, even in the midst of the pandemic, to grow and deepen the partnership. Just a few examples that were cited to me: You’re rolling out a $15 million project to help Costa Rican Government improve the capacity to reduce and prevent child sex trafficking, something that is truly meaningful and important.</p>
<p>You’ve implemented multiple projects to support refugees and vulnerable migrants in Costa Rica, including the Fundacion Mujer, a local NGO that provides English courses and career counseling, and Aqui Estoy, which gives food, health care, and job help to Venezuelan refugees. Parenthetically, I think one of the things that’s also so powerful about our friends here is the generosity and hospitality that they’ve extended, including to Venezuelans, including, of course, to Nicaraguans, given the deep ties that go back so many years between these countries.</p>
<p>You’ve also provided security assistance that’s helped Costa Rica become a major counternarcotics force in the region. You supported the wonderful project that we saw this morning, the Sembremos Seguridad, the citizen security program. And as I said, I saw their great work firsthand today. It was really quite wonderful, everything from seeing kids learn new skills, including skateboarding – I’m not sure that was – that might have been an indigenous skill – but two wonderful young children playing the violin, others doing judo, more doing pottery, others in a classroom learning. In fact, the classroom course was apparently focused today on negotiation skills, so I asked if I could sit in because I might learn something very important to take back with me. But I was really impressed by that, and it’s quite something to see community leaders, national leaders, police, mayors, everyone coming together and offering genuine hope and opportunity for young people, which really is the answer to so many of our challenges.</p>
<p>You’re leading the regional effort to stop illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing through the Team Fish interagency group. That too is one of those stories that’s a little bit underreported. But we see the havoc that that illegal fishing is wreaking in so many places around the world. It’s been devastating to local communities in many places whose livelihoods depend on fishing. It’s having an impact on biodiversity. And it’s something I think we’re going to increasingly be focused on.</p>
<p>A few months ago, you signed an MOU with the government to protect Costa Rica’s cultural property. I understand that MOU was languishing for more than 20 years until the public affairs section picked it up, ran with it, and got it done. So congratulations on that.</p>
<p>And, of course, there’s all the work that you’ve done to help mitigate the effects of COVID-19. Between April and September of last year, you helped repatriate more than 11,000 American citizens and more than 6,000 Costa Rican citizens. And thanks to you, Costa Rica was the first country in the region to receive three mobile field hospital tents, as well as PPE, lab supplies, hand washing stations, sanitizing gel, gel dispensers, all on behalf of the United States embassy.</p>
<p>I want you to know as well that in a few short days – in fact, possibly as early as tomorrow – the President is going to announce in more detail the plan that he’s put together to push out 80 million vaccines around the world that we have at our disposal or soon will have at our disposal. And we’re going to do that in coordination significantly with COVAX. We’re going to do that based on science and need. And we’re going to do that without any political strings attached.</p>
<p>Even as we’re doing that, we’re going to be working very hard on increasing manufacturing capacity in the United States and around the world so that we can get – finally get ahead of this virus and be the leader in vaccinating the world. If we stayed on the current trajectory, the one that we were on just a few weeks ago in terms of the pace of vaccination, we would not get to 70 or 80 percent vaccination around the world until 2024. We can speed this up; we’re going to speed this up. I think we have an opportunity to get this done by the end of next year. So stay tuned for that. It’s very, very important and the President’s been working very hard on getting this plan together.</p>
<p>I know what a challenging time this has been for everyone in this mission, dealing with COVID, having to do your jobs in the midst of a pandemic. I’m relieved that we have not lost any members of this embassy community. And I especially want to recognize the incredible work of the health unit here in San Jose, led by Amy (inaudible) Is Amy here? (Applause.) As well as Oscar (inaudible) – is Oscar here? (Applause.) From the Regional Security Office, who traveled to Bogota to bring additional vaccines to post so all of our contractors, all of our local guards could be vaccinated.</p>
<p>So we’ve been fortunate, and not just fortunate, we’ve been the beneficiaries of great work by our colleagues. But I know that some of you have lost loved ones, some of you have lost friends, and it’s hard to put words to that loss, except to say that I’m deeply sorry for the loss and deeply grateful to all of you who carried on in spite of those losses, and seeing the mission through.</p>
<p>Whether you’re an employee of the State Department or one of the many government agencies here at this mission; whether you’re a direct hire, a contractor, a family member; whether you’re locally employed staff, the lifeblood of this and every embassy, I just wanted to have an opportunity to say, very simply, thank you. Thank you for the wonderful work that you’re doing every single day on behalf of our country, on behalf of the relationship with Costa Rica, on behalf of making the world just a little bit safer, a little bit more prosperous, a little bit more hopeful. It’s wonderful work, it’s inspiring work, and I’m grateful to you for doing it. Thank you, thank you, thank you. (Applause.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken on National Land Use, Land Cover, and Ecosystems Monitoring System (SIMOCUTE) Initiative</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-on-national-land-use-land-cover-and-ecosystems-monitoring-system-simocute-initiative/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 22:24:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248348</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>San Jose, Costa Rica</p>
<p>Rutas Naturbanas</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> Good afternoon. For Costa Rica it’s an honor to host the official visit of His Excellency Antony Blinken, Secretary of the United States of America. Also we are pleased to receive his distinguished delegation. For the Ministry of Environment and Energy, it’s a pleasure to host this event regarding nature-based solution for climate action in cities and its links with information systems. We give special thanks to the Central Bank of Costa Rica for being our meeting venue today. As mentioned before, we also greet Mrs. Claudia Dobles, first lady of the republic; Mrs. Andrea Meza, minister of environment and energy; Mr. Rodolfo Solano, minister of foreign affairs and worship; Mr. Andres Valenciano, minister of foreign trade; Mr. Rodrigo Cubero, president of the Central Bank of Costa Rica; and, of course, all the high authorities, members of diplomatic missions, private sector, non-state actors, ladies and gentlemen. With this, please now let’s hear our welcoming remarks from Mrs. Andrea Meza, minister of environment and energy. (Speaks in Spanish.)</p>
<p><b>ENVIRONMENT MINISTER MEZA:</b> Good morning. Good morning to everyone here, and I will start by saying that all protocol is observed, so let’s feel free, in a comfortable place. We are between friends. Good morning, Secretary Blinken – (speaks in Spanish) – which is more than our first lady. She’s our team leader in sustainable mobility and green cities. (Speaks in Spanish) Rodolfo Solano, minister of foreign affairs; Andres Valenciano, minister of foreign trade; Rodrigo Cubero, thank you for hosting us, for hosting this event; deputy ministers, diplomatic representatives, U.S. delegation, friends, thank you for being here.</p>
<p>Secretary and friends, we’re so pleased to be sharing this wonderful setting where we can see the seeds of how we can be transforming our cities, making them greener, embracing nature with more public spaces, with sustainable buildings – cities planned for our citizens and not for our cars. And this is the vision for the future. This is the city that we want and the city that we are fighting for right now.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Secretary Blinken, we mentioned that Costa Rica wants to be a strategic partner to catalyze a more inclusive green resilient development model for the Central American region. And let me elaborate a little bit more of what we understand is this green resilient model. We understand that it needs a transformational change that will take us to a net zero emission and a nature-positive economy. We need to move from just trying to create growth to a more systemic approach to generate welfare for our citizens, to boost our economies, to generate jobs but within the planetary boundaries, and addressing inequalities, generating solutions that offer justice to the countries and communities that have done little to create the climate problem.</p>
<p>And we know we can achieve that vision, and it is critical to do it fast. This is what the science is telling us. But the good news is that we have the technology, we have the resources, and right now we have the political will. And this is what makes everything happen for this transformational change. We recognized yesterday that we need to put people in the center of our development model, and I would just add that it is people and nature.</p>
<p>This pandemic is showing us how interconnected we are. If we want to see and if we want to have healthy economics, we need – and healthy societies, we need healthy ecosystems. And if we want to address the climate crisis, we need nature-based solutions.</p>
<p>But this is also a matter of opportunities, and to build the economy of the future, which within is circular, green, and blue. We must acknowledge that nature is an asset, and that we’re doing a terrible job right now in managing this portfolio.</p>
<p>Let me just share one report, one data from the Dasgupta report. It says that between 1992 and 2014, produced capital per person doubled, and human capital per person increased by about 30 percent globally. But the stock of natural capital per person declined by nearly 40 percent.</p>
<p>Nature-related risk matters to the business community. And do you know why? There we have representatives from the business community here. Because over half of the world’s total GDP is moderately or highly dependent on nature. And a nature-positive economy could create more than 400 million jobs by 2030, and we want those jobs for this region. And this is why we’re creating all this. We’re launching our decarbonization plan. We’re having specific packages of policies for short, medium, and long-term actions for strategic sectors – transport, energy, industry, construction, circular economy, agriculture, and nature-based solutions.</p>
<p>But the implementation of these measures needs a whole-of-government approach, and a whole-of-society approach. This is why we’re working with the different sectorial ministries – transport, agriculture. We’re working with the central bank. We’re working with foreign trade. Because we need alignment in these policies. And we are committed with the goals of the Paris Agreement. And we are also clear that we need to generate these good enabling conditions to facilitate engagement of the private sector and civil society in this agenda.</p>
<p>And this is why we selected this place, because Rutas Naturbanas, the project behind this, it’s an example of how we can integrate these kind of visions. Rutas Naturbanas is a grassroots, citizen-led initiative that was started in 2016 by a group of people and organizations committed to climate action and urban renewal, with the mandate – and this is so nice; I love the mandate – to connect people to the city through nature. And here we have Federico Cartin, who is one of the leaders. And we also have Daniel Mikoski as our representative from some of the private sector that it is supporting the initiative.</p>
<p>What I will say is that this project is showing us that it is possible to have public-private partnerships to be transforming the city and to be implementing decarbonization visions.</p>
<p>We also have other good examples through the different, nice stories that we have with CRUSA and the support with a lot of different entrepreneurs, SMEs, so they can adopt green practices, and with other of our strategic partners, such as AED. They are here.</p>
<p>And the other element that has been very interesting with Rutas Naturbanas is that many of the partners are (inaudible) members. And crowdfunding by the foundation has been majorly made possible through American contributions. So we want to thank these.</p>
<p>And the other element for this transformation is to have a robust, good, technical information. We strongly believe in science and data-based policy-making processes. And this is why we’re celebrating the launch of the formalization of the Costa Rica Comprehensive National Land Use, Land Cover, and Ecosystem Monitoring System, SIMOCUTE, with the official announcement of the executive decree that was signed by the president, the minister of agriculture, justice, and by myself – again, another instrument that is showing that it is possible to have this integrated approach.</p>
<p>But this is – this was possible because of the long-term presence and sustained funding from the U.S. Government, and alongside other international agencies like FAO, so thank you very much for the support.</p>
<p>This is the other element that it is critical: whole of government, whole of society, good information. So Secretary Blinken, thank you for all the support the U.S. has given us at the national level. Thank you for continuing your leadership in mobilizing climate finance for nature-based solutions.</p>
<p>As we mentioned yesterday, we welcome the LEAF Coalition presented by the United Kingdom, the U.S., and Norway. We’re working to submit a proposal soon. Count on us to accelerate climate action. Count on us in the multilateral arena to continue raising ambition on our way to Glasgow. We want to have a success COP and we are committed to that. Count on us to work in the Central American region. We’re partners that share values. Thank you. (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> <i>Muchas gracias</i>, Minister. Thank you, Minister Meza.</p>
<p>We invite His Excellency Antony Blinken, Secretary of State of the United States of America to give his remarks. Excellency.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, good afternoon, everyone, and first, Madam Minister, thank you. Thank you for not just your good words, but your important words, and also thank you for the partnership that we have, the United States and Costa Rica, on maybe the most critical issue of our times, and that is preserving and protecting our environment, combating climate change, and saving our planet. We value this partnership and we look to it, I think, more and more in the years ahead.</p>
<p>And let me say, first of all, greetings to everyone. Madam Minister, First Lady, thank you for honoring us with your presence today, and I very much enjoy the opportunity to speak as we were walking down this extraordinary corridor that I think is an example, really, to the world of how you bring people together with their cities through nature. It’s a very powerful idea, but it’s not – it’s more than an idea. We see it realized right here.</p>
<p>And as we were discussing, there is a powerful impact on all of our lives when we have an opportunity, especially those of us who live in cities, to spend some time surrounded by green, to be near the water and the extraordinary rivers that you have, to hear that sound. It has a profound, positive effect, I think, on all of us, and it’s wonderful to see this realized in a practical way right here.</p>
<p>But to both of you, to my colleague Rodolfo, and to all of the ministers here today, I think your presence speaks to Costa Rica’s recognition that all parts of government and all parts of our society, including the private sector, have a role to play in tackling the climate crisis – and more than tackling it, bringing nature and people together in meaningful ways.</p>
<p>I’m also delighted to celebrate the launch of Costa Rica’s National Land Use, Land Cover, and Ecosystems Monitoring System, as the minister mentioned, SIMOCUTE.</p>
<p>This system will make it possible for Costa Rica to collect and integrate high-quality data on natural, agricultural, and biodiversity resources across the entire country. And the aim is not just to measure the impact of greenhouse gas emissions but also to inform better decision making when it comes to managing forests and lands.</p>
<p>Its origins can be traced back to a partnership between Costa Rican experts, a U.S. Government climate fellow, Dr. Randy Hamilton, and several Costa Rican and U.S. Government agencies including, I’m pleased and proud to say, the United States Department of State. And the effort incorporated a range of partners including from the UN Food and Agricultural Organizations and 25 Costa Rican institutions – some of whom I know are represented here today.</p>
<p>This is precisely the kind of collaboration and knowledge sharing across borders, public and private institutions that’s essential to effectively tackling the climate challenge and the climate crisis.</p>
<p>The data it generates will be available online for all to access allowing experts and citizens alike to study them, to track whether government and private actors are actually meeting their commitments. That degree of transparency – and engagement of the citizens – I think is a model that others can and should aspire to.</p>
<p>Of course, SIMOCUTE program is just a small part of Costa Rica’s longstanding global leadership on climate. That’s evident in the targets that Costa Rica has set to achieve net zero emissions by 2050. Its proactive role in international climate change negotiations is pioneering use of debt-for-nature swaps.</p>
<p>And of course, what we know too is the powerful use and reliance on renewable energy here also sets a very, very strong example. Protecting nature by creating additional value for forests is at the heart of a new initiative the United States recently announced together with the United Kingdom, Norway, and nine leading companies at the climate summit that President Biden convened in April. And the minister referred to it – the Lowering Emissions by Accelerating Forest Finance Coalition. It’s a mouthful but the acronym, LEAF, is quite wonderful. It aims to mobilize at least a billion dollars this year to support tropical and subtropical countries in their efforts to reduce emissions from deforestation and forest degradation.</p>
<p>The concept is straightforward: generating verified emissions reductions can be rewarded with payments. These are the kinds of emissions SIMOCUTE is well placed to track. And given Costa Rica’s longstanding efforts to reduce deforestation and restore forests, we hope this is another area where indeed we can work together.</p>
<p>With nearly one-quarter of global greenhouse gas emissions today coming from forests, from agriculture, and other lands, this is an area where we must make significant and swift progress if we are going to avert a climate catastrophe.</p>
<p>I’d also like to thank Ambassador Lyster-Binns from the UK who I think is here today – somewhere – Ambassador. Good to see you. Thank you for your government’s partnership on this initiative.</p>
<p>I think we both know that this is not a battle that countries like Costa Rica can wage alone. Big emitters have their part to do.</p>
<p>The United States is prepared to lead by example, as President Biden demonstrated in the recent targets that he set for our country to cut emissions by at least half in 2030; to double the public international climate finance we provide, to $5.7 billion annually, by 2024.</p>
<p>And that brings me to my last point, which is why we are making such massive investments. Efforts to reduce emissions and build climate resilience are sometimes, maybe even often, presented as an impediment to growth, a strain on economies. But we believe that the climate crisis should be seen differently – as a once-in-generations opportunity to generate good-paying, sustainable jobs, something the minister also alluded to.</p>
<p>Every country in the world needs to reduce emissions, invest in climate resilience, capture more carbon dioxide. That’s an open space for innovation and broad-based growth – if only we seize it.</p>
<p>And I think that’s been Costa Rica’s experience, as Minister Meza pointed out at the climate summit, when she highlighted the millions of dollars in revenue that Costa Rica’s protected areas generate for communities, and the sustainable livelihoods that they support.</p>
<p>It is, as I said at the start, both a pleasure but also I think important that we are partnered in this effort. This is not just a once-in-a-generations opportunity, it’s in a sense a once-in-a-lifetime obligation that we have before us to try to get this right. We’re only going to succeed if we do it together, if we work in partnership, if we all meet our responsibilities and, in doing that, finding incredible opportunity in those responsibilities. So thank you so much for the warm welcome, but more important, thank you for what we’re doing, the United States and Costa Rica, every day to make progress for our people and for our planet. Thank you. (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR: </b>Thank you, your excellency. With this, now invite to the stage Mrs. Claudia Dobles, our first lady of the republic, to give her closing speech. Claudia.</p>
<p><b>MRS DOBLES:</b> Good day to everybody. Your excellency, Mr. Antony Blinken, Secretary of State of the United States, thank you so much for your visit for you and your team. Good day to all the ministers, vice ministers, and everybody from the government, from civil society, from all the institutions that work with us as a team. Thank you for being here today.</p>
<p>I would like to start saying that Costa Rica, it’s very well known for pioneering innovative policies, like abolishing the army more than 70 years ago, for investing and focusing on our health care which is universal and is free. That has been a enormous pillar in fighting this sanitary crisis. Also, that we invested in our people. That is the best resources that we have in Costa Rica is the talent of our people. So we don’t have oil, we don’t have other natural resources possibly; we don’t even want to explore that because we are pretty much focusing on our people and our human talent.</p>
<p>President Alvarado when we started this administration said very accurately that climate crisis is a challenge of this generation and that we really need to act and we need to act now. And we are in a pivotal point to make decisions for the future. That’s why we focusing on how to make a more equitable society, how to put our communities in the center, how to put our people in the center, how to put the services that we needed to provide in the center while lowering our carbon emissions, transitioning in a very just and fair transition towards a decarbonized economy; how to provide a new system, a new paradigm. So that’s why facing that we launch a little bit more than two years ago our national decarbonization plan. And it is important to say that while this is going to tackle climate crisis, it’s more of a social economical development based on sustainability and based on our people that we are talking about. So that is very important and this is something that we keep saying to our communities, that these type of interventions, that providing this type of quality of life, this is decarbonization, this is our national decarbonization plan. It’s part of it.</p>
<p>It’s important to say that Costa Rica, it’s pretty well-known – I was saying to Secretary Blinken that Costa Rica, it’s pretty much well-known for our biodiversity, our beaches, our mountains, our rivers. And we have done a very good job on nature-based solutions, on carbon capture, on reforestation, conservation. But if we really wanted to achieve the goals that we have in our national decarbonization plan, we really needed to focus on our urban agenda and we really need to start talking about urban planning, territorial planning. We need to start talking about how can we interconnect the public services that we provide to our people in order to provide better quality of life in order to enhance public transportation to incorporate the concepts of sustainable mobility. How can we work with the national government and the local governments and the rest of our society to provide answers bottom-up?</p>
<p>If we really want to tackle our goals, we need to focus on this urban agenda. That’s why under the leadership of the wonderful minister of environment, which I really want to thank you for your leadership, I have to say that this has been a team work, a whole government that is completely committed, that shared a vision, that really is working to achieve that vision and to create enabling conditions to continue this transition while – before we move to the next administration so the next administration can continue this transformation.</p>
<p>So thank you to all the government and the staff members that have been – made this possible. I really – I really have to say that this is teamwork. It’s even more important when we think about the recovery plans that we need to provide in a post-COVID era, and that we really need to focus on a green recovery, and when we – when we were talking about our national decarbonization plan, we provided specific actions that provided investment plans for a resilient infrastructure that will create new jobs, that will create new markets, that will create new industries based on new, clean technologies, based on the culture of knowledge, and based on sustainability. So I think our national decarbonization plan is also our green recovery plan post-COVID.</p>
<p>And Secretary Blinken said something that I think is very important. Costa Rica cannot do it alone. We have a strong voice and I am very proud to say that Costa Rica has a strong voice on sustainability. But we are not fighting this fight alone. We know that this is a global fight and we know that we have strategic partners in this, and we are very, very happy and I think the world is very happy to see that under President Biden’s administration, the U.S. has a strong commitment, a huge commitment in climate – in climate change and climate crisis.</p>
<p>So thank you very much, Secretary Blinken, for you and your team, and I am sure that we will keep working together. As the Minister Meza said, count on us because we’re committed, and we share the vision, and we share the values. Thank you so much for your visit, and we’ll keep working. Thank you so much. (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> <i>Muchas gracias, Dona Claudia.</i> Ladies and gentlemen, with this we have concluded the event. Thank you for being here and have a great afternoon.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>San Jose, Costa Rica</p>
<p>Rutas Naturbanas</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> Good afternoon. For Costa Rica it’s an honor to host the official visit of His Excellency Antony Blinken, Secretary of the United States of America. Also we are pleased to receive his distinguished delegation. For the Ministry of Environment and Energy, it’s a pleasure to host this event regarding nature-based solution for climate action in cities and its links with information systems. We give special thanks to the Central Bank of Costa Rica for being our meeting venue today. As mentioned before, we also greet Mrs. Claudia Dobles, first lady of the republic; Mrs. Andrea Meza, minister of environment and energy; Mr. Rodolfo Solano, minister of foreign affairs and worship; Mr. Andres Valenciano, minister of foreign trade; Mr. Rodrigo Cubero, president of the Central Bank of Costa Rica; and, of course, all the high authorities, members of diplomatic missions, private sector, non-state actors, ladies and gentlemen. With this, please now let’s hear our welcoming remarks from Mrs. Andrea Meza, minister of environment and energy. (Speaks in Spanish.)</p>
<p><b>ENVIRONMENT MINISTER MEZA:</b> Good morning. Good morning to everyone here, and I will start by saying that all protocol is observed, so let’s feel free, in a comfortable place. We are between friends. Good morning, Secretary Blinken – (speaks in Spanish) – which is more than our first lady. She’s our team leader in sustainable mobility and green cities. (Speaks in Spanish) Rodolfo Solano, minister of foreign affairs; Andres Valenciano, minister of foreign trade; Rodrigo Cubero, thank you for hosting us, for hosting this event; deputy ministers, diplomatic representatives, U.S. delegation, friends, thank you for being here.</p>
<p>Secretary and friends, we’re so pleased to be sharing this wonderful setting where we can see the seeds of how we can be transforming our cities, making them greener, embracing nature with more public spaces, with sustainable buildings – cities planned for our citizens and not for our cars. And this is the vision for the future. This is the city that we want and the city that we are fighting for right now.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Secretary Blinken, we mentioned that Costa Rica wants to be a strategic partner to catalyze a more inclusive green resilient development model for the Central American region. And let me elaborate a little bit more of what we understand is this green resilient model. We understand that it needs a transformational change that will take us to a net zero emission and a nature-positive economy. We need to move from just trying to create growth to a more systemic approach to generate welfare for our citizens, to boost our economies, to generate jobs but within the planetary boundaries, and addressing inequalities, generating solutions that offer justice to the countries and communities that have done little to create the climate problem.</p>
<p>And we know we can achieve that vision, and it is critical to do it fast. This is what the science is telling us. But the good news is that we have the technology, we have the resources, and right now we have the political will. And this is what makes everything happen for this transformational change. We recognized yesterday that we need to put people in the center of our development model, and I would just add that it is people and nature.</p>
<p>This pandemic is showing us how interconnected we are. If we want to see and if we want to have healthy economics, we need – and healthy societies, we need healthy ecosystems. And if we want to address the climate crisis, we need nature-based solutions.</p>
<p>But this is also a matter of opportunities, and to build the economy of the future, which within is circular, green, and blue. We must acknowledge that nature is an asset, and that we’re doing a terrible job right now in managing this portfolio.</p>
<p>Let me just share one report, one data from the Dasgupta report. It says that between 1992 and 2014, produced capital per person doubled, and human capital per person increased by about 30 percent globally. But the stock of natural capital per person declined by nearly 40 percent.</p>
<p>Nature-related risk matters to the business community. And do you know why? There we have representatives from the business community here. Because over half of the world’s total GDP is moderately or highly dependent on nature. And a nature-positive economy could create more than 400 million jobs by 2030, and we want those jobs for this region. And this is why we’re creating all this. We’re launching our decarbonization plan. We’re having specific packages of policies for short, medium, and long-term actions for strategic sectors – transport, energy, industry, construction, circular economy, agriculture, and nature-based solutions.</p>
<p>But the implementation of these measures needs a whole-of-government approach, and a whole-of-society approach. This is why we’re working with the different sectorial ministries – transport, agriculture. We’re working with the central bank. We’re working with foreign trade. Because we need alignment in these policies. And we are committed with the goals of the Paris Agreement. And we are also clear that we need to generate these good enabling conditions to facilitate engagement of the private sector and civil society in this agenda.</p>
<p>And this is why we selected this place, because Rutas Naturbanas, the project behind this, it’s an example of how we can integrate these kind of visions. Rutas Naturbanas is a grassroots, citizen-led initiative that was started in 2016 by a group of people and organizations committed to climate action and urban renewal, with the mandate – and this is so nice; I love the mandate – to connect people to the city through nature. And here we have Federico Cartin, who is one of the leaders. And we also have Daniel Mikoski as our representative from some of the private sector that it is supporting the initiative.</p>
<p>What I will say is that this project is showing us that it is possible to have public-private partnerships to be transforming the city and to be implementing decarbonization visions.</p>
<p>We also have other good examples through the different, nice stories that we have with CRUSA and the support with a lot of different entrepreneurs, SMEs, so they can adopt green practices, and with other of our strategic partners, such as AED. They are here.</p>
<p>And the other element that has been very interesting with Rutas Naturbanas is that many of the partners are (inaudible) members. And crowdfunding by the foundation has been majorly made possible through American contributions. So we want to thank these.</p>
<p>And the other element for this transformation is to have a robust, good, technical information. We strongly believe in science and data-based policy-making processes. And this is why we’re celebrating the launch of the formalization of the Costa Rica Comprehensive National Land Use, Land Cover, and Ecosystem Monitoring System, SIMOCUTE, with the official announcement of the executive decree that was signed by the president, the minister of agriculture, justice, and by myself – again, another instrument that is showing that it is possible to have this integrated approach.</p>
<p>But this is – this was possible because of the long-term presence and sustained funding from the U.S. Government, and alongside other international agencies like FAO, so thank you very much for the support.</p>
<p>This is the other element that it is critical: whole of government, whole of society, good information. So Secretary Blinken, thank you for all the support the U.S. has given us at the national level. Thank you for continuing your leadership in mobilizing climate finance for nature-based solutions.</p>
<p>As we mentioned yesterday, we welcome the LEAF Coalition presented by the United Kingdom, the U.S., and Norway. We’re working to submit a proposal soon. Count on us to accelerate climate action. Count on us in the multilateral arena to continue raising ambition on our way to Glasgow. We want to have a success COP and we are committed to that. Count on us to work in the Central American region. We’re partners that share values. Thank you. (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> <i>Muchas gracias</i>, Minister. Thank you, Minister Meza.</p>
<p>We invite His Excellency Antony Blinken, Secretary of State of the United States of America to give his remarks. Excellency.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b> Well, good afternoon, everyone, and first, Madam Minister, thank you. Thank you for not just your good words, but your important words, and also thank you for the partnership that we have, the United States and Costa Rica, on maybe the most critical issue of our times, and that is preserving and protecting our environment, combating climate change, and saving our planet. We value this partnership and we look to it, I think, more and more in the years ahead.</p>
<p>And let me say, first of all, greetings to everyone. Madam Minister, First Lady, thank you for honoring us with your presence today, and I very much enjoy the opportunity to speak as we were walking down this extraordinary corridor that I think is an example, really, to the world of how you bring people together with their cities through nature. It’s a very powerful idea, but it’s not – it’s more than an idea. We see it realized right here.</p>
<p>And as we were discussing, there is a powerful impact on all of our lives when we have an opportunity, especially those of us who live in cities, to spend some time surrounded by green, to be near the water and the extraordinary rivers that you have, to hear that sound. It has a profound, positive effect, I think, on all of us, and it’s wonderful to see this realized in a practical way right here.</p>
<p>But to both of you, to my colleague Rodolfo, and to all of the ministers here today, I think your presence speaks to Costa Rica’s recognition that all parts of government and all parts of our society, including the private sector, have a role to play in tackling the climate crisis – and more than tackling it, bringing nature and people together in meaningful ways.</p>
<p>I’m also delighted to celebrate the launch of Costa Rica’s National Land Use, Land Cover, and Ecosystems Monitoring System, as the minister mentioned, SIMOCUTE.</p>
<p>This system will make it possible for Costa Rica to collect and integrate high-quality data on natural, agricultural, and biodiversity resources across the entire country. And the aim is not just to measure the impact of greenhouse gas emissions but also to inform better decision making when it comes to managing forests and lands.</p>
<p>Its origins can be traced back to a partnership between Costa Rican experts, a U.S. Government climate fellow, Dr. Randy Hamilton, and several Costa Rican and U.S. Government agencies including, I’m pleased and proud to say, the United States Department of State. And the effort incorporated a range of partners including from the UN Food and Agricultural Organizations and 25 Costa Rican institutions – some of whom I know are represented here today.</p>
<p>This is precisely the kind of collaboration and knowledge sharing across borders, public and private institutions that’s essential to effectively tackling the climate challenge and the climate crisis.</p>
<p>The data it generates will be available online for all to access allowing experts and citizens alike to study them, to track whether government and private actors are actually meeting their commitments. That degree of transparency – and engagement of the citizens – I think is a model that others can and should aspire to.</p>
<p>Of course, SIMOCUTE program is just a small part of Costa Rica’s longstanding global leadership on climate. That’s evident in the targets that Costa Rica has set to achieve net zero emissions by 2050. Its proactive role in international climate change negotiations is pioneering use of debt-for-nature swaps.</p>
<p>And of course, what we know too is the powerful use and reliance on renewable energy here also sets a very, very strong example. Protecting nature by creating additional value for forests is at the heart of a new initiative the United States recently announced together with the United Kingdom, Norway, and nine leading companies at the climate summit that President Biden convened in April. And the minister referred to it – the Lowering Emissions by Accelerating Forest Finance Coalition. It’s a mouthful but the acronym, LEAF, is quite wonderful. It aims to mobilize at least a billion dollars this year to support tropical and subtropical countries in their efforts to reduce emissions from deforestation and forest degradation.</p>
<p>The concept is straightforward: generating verified emissions reductions can be rewarded with payments. These are the kinds of emissions SIMOCUTE is well placed to track. And given Costa Rica’s longstanding efforts to reduce deforestation and restore forests, we hope this is another area where indeed we can work together.</p>
<p>With nearly one-quarter of global greenhouse gas emissions today coming from forests, from agriculture, and other lands, this is an area where we must make significant and swift progress if we are going to avert a climate catastrophe.</p>
<p>I’d also like to thank Ambassador Lyster-Binns from the UK who I think is here today – somewhere – Ambassador. Good to see you. Thank you for your government’s partnership on this initiative.</p>
<p>I think we both know that this is not a battle that countries like Costa Rica can wage alone. Big emitters have their part to do.</p>
<p>The United States is prepared to lead by example, as President Biden demonstrated in the recent targets that he set for our country to cut emissions by at least half in 2030; to double the public international climate finance we provide, to $5.7 billion annually, by 2024.</p>
<p>And that brings me to my last point, which is why we are making such massive investments. Efforts to reduce emissions and build climate resilience are sometimes, maybe even often, presented as an impediment to growth, a strain on economies. But we believe that the climate crisis should be seen differently – as a once-in-generations opportunity to generate good-paying, sustainable jobs, something the minister also alluded to.</p>
<p>Every country in the world needs to reduce emissions, invest in climate resilience, capture more carbon dioxide. That’s an open space for innovation and broad-based growth – if only we seize it.</p>
<p>And I think that’s been Costa Rica’s experience, as Minister Meza pointed out at the climate summit, when she highlighted the millions of dollars in revenue that Costa Rica’s protected areas generate for communities, and the sustainable livelihoods that they support.</p>
<p>It is, as I said at the start, both a pleasure but also I think important that we are partnered in this effort. This is not just a once-in-a-generations opportunity, it’s in a sense a once-in-a-lifetime obligation that we have before us to try to get this right. We’re only going to succeed if we do it together, if we work in partnership, if we all meet our responsibilities and, in doing that, finding incredible opportunity in those responsibilities. So thank you so much for the warm welcome, but more important, thank you for what we’re doing, the United States and Costa Rica, every day to make progress for our people and for our planet. Thank you. (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR: </b>Thank you, your excellency. With this, now invite to the stage Mrs. Claudia Dobles, our first lady of the republic, to give her closing speech. Claudia.</p>
<p><b>MRS DOBLES:</b> Good day to everybody. Your excellency, Mr. Antony Blinken, Secretary of State of the United States, thank you so much for your visit for you and your team. Good day to all the ministers, vice ministers, and everybody from the government, from civil society, from all the institutions that work with us as a team. Thank you for being here today.</p>
<p>I would like to start saying that Costa Rica, it’s very well known for pioneering innovative policies, like abolishing the army more than 70 years ago, for investing and focusing on our health care which is universal and is free. That has been a enormous pillar in fighting this sanitary crisis. Also, that we invested in our people. That is the best resources that we have in Costa Rica is the talent of our people. So we don’t have oil, we don’t have other natural resources possibly; we don’t even want to explore that because we are pretty much focusing on our people and our human talent.</p>
<p>President Alvarado when we started this administration said very accurately that climate crisis is a challenge of this generation and that we really need to act and we need to act now. And we are in a pivotal point to make decisions for the future. That’s why we focusing on how to make a more equitable society, how to put our communities in the center, how to put our people in the center, how to put the services that we needed to provide in the center while lowering our carbon emissions, transitioning in a very just and fair transition towards a decarbonized economy; how to provide a new system, a new paradigm. So that’s why facing that we launch a little bit more than two years ago our national decarbonization plan. And it is important to say that while this is going to tackle climate crisis, it’s more of a social economical development based on sustainability and based on our people that we are talking about. So that is very important and this is something that we keep saying to our communities, that these type of interventions, that providing this type of quality of life, this is decarbonization, this is our national decarbonization plan. It’s part of it.</p>
<p>It’s important to say that Costa Rica, it’s pretty well-known – I was saying to Secretary Blinken that Costa Rica, it’s pretty much well-known for our biodiversity, our beaches, our mountains, our rivers. And we have done a very good job on nature-based solutions, on carbon capture, on reforestation, conservation. But if we really wanted to achieve the goals that we have in our national decarbonization plan, we really needed to focus on our urban agenda and we really need to start talking about urban planning, territorial planning. We need to start talking about how can we interconnect the public services that we provide to our people in order to provide better quality of life in order to enhance public transportation to incorporate the concepts of sustainable mobility. How can we work with the national government and the local governments and the rest of our society to provide answers bottom-up?</p>
<p>If we really want to tackle our goals, we need to focus on this urban agenda. That’s why under the leadership of the wonderful minister of environment, which I really want to thank you for your leadership, I have to say that this has been a team work, a whole government that is completely committed, that shared a vision, that really is working to achieve that vision and to create enabling conditions to continue this transition while – before we move to the next administration so the next administration can continue this transformation.</p>
<p>So thank you to all the government and the staff members that have been – made this possible. I really – I really have to say that this is teamwork. It’s even more important when we think about the recovery plans that we need to provide in a post-COVID era, and that we really need to focus on a green recovery, and when we – when we were talking about our national decarbonization plan, we provided specific actions that provided investment plans for a resilient infrastructure that will create new jobs, that will create new markets, that will create new industries based on new, clean technologies, based on the culture of knowledge, and based on sustainability. So I think our national decarbonization plan is also our green recovery plan post-COVID.</p>
<p>And Secretary Blinken said something that I think is very important. Costa Rica cannot do it alone. We have a strong voice and I am very proud to say that Costa Rica has a strong voice on sustainability. But we are not fighting this fight alone. We know that this is a global fight and we know that we have strategic partners in this, and we are very, very happy and I think the world is very happy to see that under President Biden’s administration, the U.S. has a strong commitment, a huge commitment in climate – in climate change and climate crisis.</p>
<p>So thank you very much, Secretary Blinken, for you and your team, and I am sure that we will keep working together. As the Minister Meza said, count on us because we’re committed, and we share the vision, and we share the values. Thank you so much for your visit, and we’ll keep working. Thank you so much. (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> <i>Muchas gracias, Dona Claudia.</i> Ladies and gentlemen, with this we have concluded the event. Thank you for being here and have a great afternoon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing – June 2, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-june-2-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 22:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=248345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:02 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-DEPARTMENT"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you for joining today’s briefing. I have three updates at the top and then we’ll resume taking your questions. I’d like to start off today by noting the tragic passing of our friend and colleague Tejinder Singh, who was the founder and editor of India America Today. Tejinder covered the State Department for 11 years, participating in many State Department briefings both in person and also calling in every telephonic briefing. We already miss seeing his name in the question queue here today. Tejinder was well-known for being a kind and generous colleague, and also for keeping us on our toes with his questions. Our thoughts are with his family, friends, and colleagues as we grieve his loss. And I speak for my colleagues here when I say that he was such a pleasure to work with for all of us, and his presence will be sorely missed.</p>
<p>Yesterday the United States began celebrating the first day of Pride Month. Not only do we recognize how far we have come in the fight for the protection of the human rights of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex persons, but we also acknowledge the distance that remains on the path to full equality and equity.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-_Hlk73544734"></a> The United States is committed to increasing U.S. engagement on LGBTQI+ issues intersectionally<sup><a id="post-248345-footnote-ref-1" href="#post-248345-footnote-1"></a></sup>, working to ensure the same-sex spouses for our diplomats assigned abroad are afforded the same privileges and immunities as opposite-sex spouses, and empowering local movements and persons advancing the rights of LGBTQI+ persons. We are proud of our work with local and international partners to build a more inclusive global society for all LGBTQI+ communities.</p>
<p>We seek to increase the visibility of and address the acute challenges faced by particularly marginalized members of these communities, including women and girls, transgender, non-binary, and intersex persons. Although the United States still has work to do, we strive to lead by example in the promotion and protection of human rights for all persons.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-SECRETARY"></a> And finally, as you know, Secretary Blinken was in Costa Rica yesterday and today, where he met with senior government officials from across the Central American region to discuss how our countries can work together to create a more democratic, prosperous, and secure region. They also worked to deepening the region’s collaborative approach to shared challenges of irregular migration.</p>
<p>Yesterday, the Secretary attended a meeting with foreign ministers and vice ministers from all seven Central American countries, as well as Mexico and the Dominican Republic. They discussed issues essential to the wellbeing of people in this region, including strategies for addressing root causes of migration and managing migration flows in and throughout the region; combating corruption and strengthening democratic institutions; generating inclusive economic growth; recovering from the COVID-19 pandemic; and healthy environmental stewardship.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken also met yesterday with President Alvarado and Foreign Minister Solano of Costa Rica to discuss the strong partnership between our countries on migration, climate change, and security. In addition, he met with the foreign secretary of Mexico and the foreign ministers of Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador to discuss vital work to address migration and other challenges within those countries.</p>
<p>This morning, Secretary Blinken visited a pair of joint U.S.-Costa Rican initiatives that show how the United States can successfully partner with the region to help build a better future. <a id="post-248345-_Hlk73544790"></a>He first visited a neighborhood that benefits from “<em>Sembremos Seguridad</em>,” an initiative<sup><a id="post-248345-footnote-ref-2" href="#post-248345-footnote-2"></a></sup> citizen security program for at-risk youth. He then visited an environmental stewardship initiative that sets a model for efforts to reduce deforestation and fight climate change in the region. He also sat down with a Costa Rican media outlet to communicate with local audiences and demonstrate support for media independence in Central America.</p>
<p>This trip is a part of the administration’s focus on Central America. Vice President Harris will be headed to the region next week to further advance our efforts to improve conditions for people of Central America, which also advances the interests of people in the United States.</p>
<p>And with that, we’ll give it a few minutes before taking your questions.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Ladies and gentlemen, if you wish to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 on your telephone keypad. You may withdraw your question at any time by repeating the 1, 0 command. If you are using a speaker phone, please pick up the handset before pressing the numbers. Once again, if you have a question, you may press 1 then 0 at this time.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Let’s go to Pearl Matibe, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-ETHIOPIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Good afternoon. Hope you’re having a great day today. My question is regarding President Joe Biden’s upcoming trip with President Vladimir Putin of Russia. And I’m just wondering after the sanctions and recent diplomatic tools you’re using regarding Ethiopia, Russia is now preparing to have an Africa summit in 2022. Is Africa going to be part of the agenda between President Biden and President Putin given the fact that Africa over the next decades beyond Biden’s administration will have such a huge population and role to play in the world? Is Africa going to be a significant topic on that agenda, and does the United States anticipate an Africa summit as well? Do you have anything to share? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you for your question, Pearl. Well, what I will say broadly is that Africa is a priority for – the relationship with Africa is a priority for the Biden administration, but I certainly won’t get ahead of any meetings and don’t have anything to share for you at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Casey O’Neill.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-BURMA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, hi, Jalina. Thanks so much for doing this. I – my question is actually on Myanmar. So I know today – earlier today, excuse me – Deputy Secretary Sherman in Bangkok delivered some remarks and spoke about the two American journalists that are detained in Myanmar, Danny Fenster and Nathan Maung. Their – excuse me – Mr. Fenster’s family has also been making the rounds on television and spoke earlier this morning and said that the United States Government has requested consular access, but so far that request has not been addressed by the military junta in Myanmar. So I’m just wondering if you could provide us any update on steps that the U.S. Government is taking to ensure that these two detained journalists are safe and if you have any update on whether or not the embassy personnel have been able to gain consular access to them. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks for your question, Casey. Well, I’ll start off by saying that the safety and safe return of U.S. citizens is a priority for the United States. At this time we have nothing to announce or any updates about these two specific cases.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Rosiland Jordan.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-CHINA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for taking my call. I have two questions. One: The anniversary of the Tiananmen Square massacre is coming up. Is the U.S. sending a message to Beijing about how its security forces should handle themselves on this anniversary, both in mainland China and in Hong Kong?</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-IRAN"></a> And the other question has to do with, one, the sinking of an Iranian oil tanker, the <em>Kharg</em>, in the Gulf of Oman, was – does the U.S. have any more information about whether this was an accident or perhaps an act of sabotage? And connected to that, does the U.S. have any more updates on the travel of two Iranian warships that rumor – that the rumors suggest may be heading to Venezuela? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Rosiland. I’ll start with your first question on Tiananmen, and I’ll start by broadly saying that the United States condemns actions by Hong Kong authorities that prompted organizers to close the June 4th Museum that commemorates the 1989 Tiananmen Square massacre. As far as your question of sending any particular messages, no, we’re not sending any direct messages at this time, other than saying that Hong Kong and Beijing authorities continue to silence dissenting voices by also attempting to erase the horrific massacre from history.</p>
<p>And to your question on Iran, speaking of the naval ships on the Gulf of Oman, well, we’ve definitely seen the media reports on the Iranian naval vessels that have caught fire and have sank. Other than that, we don’t have anything to announce at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Rich Edson.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-WORLDHEALTHASSEMBLY"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Jalina, just looking into the conclusion of the World Health Assembly, there is really no sense of a phase two investigation or commitment to one, Taiwan was excluded from the proceedings, Syria and Belarus are now on the executive committee. I was just wondering if you could provide what the State Department’s assessment of the proceedings were and how the U.S. plans on attempting to follow through with reforms of the World Health Organization.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Rich. What I’ll say is to your point about countries that you’ve mentioned. We have grave concerns that Syria and Belarus have been elected for a three-year term by the World Health Assembly Executive Board. Members of the executive board each have a duty to advance public health and likewise are expected to uphold universal values as well as human rights. And, of course, this would include providing access for delivery of lifesaving humanitarian supplies, and that would include medical equipment as well. <a id="post-248345-_Hlk73544881"></a>We don’t believe the actions of either Syria or Belarus demonstrate this, and although the U.S. is not currently part of the executive board, we’ll continue to monitor closely the board’s activities and make clear that – U.S. exemptions<sup><a id="post-248345-footnote-ref-3" href="#post-248345-footnote-3"></a></sup> that the board members uphold the highest standards of human rights.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Laura Rozen.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-IRAN1"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you have anything on the latest round of Iran talks in Vienna, which I think are wrapping up right now.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Laura. So the delegation led by Special Envoy for Iran Robert Malley is currently in Vienna, and he’s in Vienna for a fifth round of talks. And any update to share that he actually may come back to Washington for consultations at the end of the week. Outside of that, I’d just underscore that these last few rounds of discussion have actually helped crystallize the choices that need to be made by Iran, and also by us, the United States, in order to achieve a mutual return to compliance of the JCPOA.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Soyoung Kim, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> About North Korea, Deputy Secretary Sherman said today that the U.S. has made its policy known to the DPRK. Can you clarify whether this means the U.S. recently reached out to North Korea again or the separate contact made a few months ago the Department of State had confirmed before? And any response from North Korea?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hi, thanks for the question. I won’t get ahead of Deputy Secretary Sherman’s comments, and any other update we’ll be able to preview at a later time but nothing’s going out today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Said Arikat.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Said’s line has left the queue.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> All right. With that, let’s go to Michel Ghandour, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I have two questions on Iran. Sources in Vienna said that the parties reached a draft agreement. Can you confirm that? And any comment on the fire in Tehran’s refinery today?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks for your question. Nothing to announce. I’m not able to confirm the reports of a fire in Tehran today, but just to underscore what was mentioned previously, our Special Envoy for Iran Robert Malley, he’s currently in Vienna for his fifth round of talks and should be coming back to Washington sometime later this week. Anything beyond that and the decisions and the discussions that have been made, I have nothing to announce.</p>
<p>Looks like we have Said Arikat back in the queue. We’ll go to Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. Thank you, Jalina. And I also want to thank you for mentioning my good friend, Tejinder. May God bless his soul. We will miss him dearly. Jalina, I wanted to ask you about two issues: one, if you have any comment on a report by <em>The Washington Post</em> that Israel is preventing cancer patients from leaving Gaza through the Erez Crossing, if you have any comment on that. I also want to ask about the whereabouts of Mr. Hady Amr right now, and what is next on his agenda? What is he doing? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you for your question, Said. And again, to underscore, we definitely will all miss Tejinder and his spirit, and his vigor and his contributions to not only foreign affairs but journalism as well.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-_Hlk73546868"></a> To your first question on cancer, I certainly look forward to these reports and would have to get back to you specifically on that question. And I’d have to do the same for your question on Hady and what he’s doing. We don’t have anything to announce at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Lara Jakes.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> I do not see Lara Jakes’s line in queue.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Okay. Let’s go to the line of Jennifer Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> It looks like Jennifer’s line is not in queue either.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> All right. Let’s go to the line of Hiba Nasr.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thank you. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. I have one question about Israel. First, we saw during Secretary Blinken’s visit to Israel two weeks ago, he extended an invitation to the Israeli president to visit Washington, and tomorrow that Israeli defense minister is visiting Washington. Did this administration extend an invitation to Prime Minister Netanyahu to visit Washington? And my second question is on Nord Stream 2; yesterday Republicans in the House sent a letter to Secretary Blinken expressing concern over the decision to – over the decision to apply a waiver to some sanctions. Do you have any comments on that?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Hiba, for your first question on extending an invitation – on invites. We have nothing at all to announce on that. And your second question on NS2, I’ll have to take that one back for you.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Claudia Uceda.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-COSTARICA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi. Thanks for taking my questions. I have two questions. First is: How can Costa Rica help stop illegal immigration flow into the U.S.? What is the Secretary looking into specifically? And my second question is about Nicaragua. I would like a reaction to the fact that <a id="post-248345-NICARAGUA"></a>Nicaraguan prosecutors question and are investigating 16 independent journalists, and they are threatening them with a criminal investigation related to money laundering investigation into Violeta Chamorro, who is a prospective candidate. What’s your reaction to that? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you, Claudia. So to your first question, I won’t get into specifics on what Costa Rica should be doing when it comes to the fight for regular migration, but I will say that Costa Rica honestly is a top partner of the United States and it has a strong democracy. And we do have shared values as well as shared commitments. And part of that is championing human rights across the board, and that will be integral into fighting that common challenge together. To your second question, I’ll just say broadly speaking that the United States supports the freedom of the press and will continue to champion that not only in Nicaragua but all over the world.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-IRAN2"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Inaudible) press you a tiny bit more on Iran. In the past, you guys have said that there had been progress in the talks, though a lot of differences remained, and the U.S. and Iran were sort of closer to the start of the talks than they were toward the end of the talks. So do you believe that progress continues to be made? Have those talks stalled? And do you feel that the two sides are gradually inching closer to a resolution? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Well, certainly some progress has been made, and like I said, Rob Malley is in Vienna. He’ll be returning to Washington pretty soon. And again, talks are ongoing. And they will continue at a pace that’s honestly appropriate to address the significance of the issues that are currently on the table being negotiated right now. And I’ll continue to underscore that discussions like this are always thorough. They’re thoughtful. They’re businesslike even though they are indirect. And of course that’s to be expected. This isn’t going to be a quick or easy process.</p>
<p>It looks like we have Jennifer Hansler back on the line, so I’ll take that last question from her.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hello.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Hi, Jennifer.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi, Jalina. Thanks so much for taking my question. Just a little more on Iran, can you confirm that the indirect talks will resume next week? And then separately, has there been any communication with Russia in the wake of the latest cyber-attack on JBS? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks for your questions, Jennifer. To your first one, I don’t have anything to announce of any – for any future talks. And the second question, we’ll have to take that one back for you.</p>
<p>And thank you all very much for joining today’s briefing. I hope you have a wonderful rest of your day.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:29 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
<ol>
<li id="post-248345-footnote-1">internationally <a href="#post-248345-footnote-ref-1">↑</a></li>
<li id="post-248345-footnote-2">innovative <a href="#post-248345-footnote-ref-2">↑</a></li>
<li id="post-248345-footnote-3">expectations <a href="#post-248345-footnote-ref-3">↑</a></li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:02 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-DEPARTMENT"></a><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you for joining today’s briefing. I have three updates at the top and then we’ll resume taking your questions. I’d like to start off today by noting the tragic passing of our friend and colleague Tejinder Singh, who was the founder and editor of India America Today. Tejinder covered the State Department for 11 years, participating in many State Department briefings both in person and also calling in every telephonic briefing. We already miss seeing his name in the question queue here today. Tejinder was well-known for being a kind and generous colleague, and also for keeping us on our toes with his questions. Our thoughts are with his family, friends, and colleagues as we grieve his loss. And I speak for my colleagues here when I say that he was such a pleasure to work with for all of us, and his presence will be sorely missed.</p>
<p>Yesterday the United States began celebrating the first day of Pride Month. Not only do we recognize how far we have come in the fight for the protection of the human rights of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex persons, but we also acknowledge the distance that remains on the path to full equality and equity.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-_Hlk73544734"></a> The United States is committed to increasing U.S. engagement on LGBTQI+ issues intersectionally<sup><a id="post-248345-footnote-ref-1" href="#post-248345-footnote-1"></a></sup>, working to ensure the same-sex spouses for our diplomats assigned abroad are afforded the same privileges and immunities as opposite-sex spouses, and empowering local movements and persons advancing the rights of LGBTQI+ persons. We are proud of our work with local and international partners to build a more inclusive global society for all LGBTQI+ communities.</p>
<p>We seek to increase the visibility of and address the acute challenges faced by particularly marginalized members of these communities, including women and girls, transgender, non-binary, and intersex persons. Although the United States still has work to do, we strive to lead by example in the promotion and protection of human rights for all persons.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-SECRETARY"></a> And finally, as you know, Secretary Blinken was in Costa Rica yesterday and today, where he met with senior government officials from across the Central American region to discuss how our countries can work together to create a more democratic, prosperous, and secure region. They also worked to deepening the region’s collaborative approach to shared challenges of irregular migration.</p>
<p>Yesterday, the Secretary attended a meeting with foreign ministers and vice ministers from all seven Central American countries, as well as Mexico and the Dominican Republic. They discussed issues essential to the wellbeing of people in this region, including strategies for addressing root causes of migration and managing migration flows in and throughout the region; combating corruption and strengthening democratic institutions; generating inclusive economic growth; recovering from the COVID-19 pandemic; and healthy environmental stewardship.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken also met yesterday with President Alvarado and Foreign Minister Solano of Costa Rica to discuss the strong partnership between our countries on migration, climate change, and security. In addition, he met with the foreign secretary of Mexico and the foreign ministers of Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador to discuss vital work to address migration and other challenges within those countries.</p>
<p>This morning, Secretary Blinken visited a pair of joint U.S.-Costa Rican initiatives that show how the United States can successfully partner with the region to help build a better future. <a id="post-248345-_Hlk73544790"></a>He first visited a neighborhood that benefits from “<em>Sembremos Seguridad</em>,” an initiative<sup><a id="post-248345-footnote-ref-2" href="#post-248345-footnote-2"></a></sup> citizen security program for at-risk youth. He then visited an environmental stewardship initiative that sets a model for efforts to reduce deforestation and fight climate change in the region. He also sat down with a Costa Rican media outlet to communicate with local audiences and demonstrate support for media independence in Central America.</p>
<p>This trip is a part of the administration’s focus on Central America. Vice President Harris will be headed to the region next week to further advance our efforts to improve conditions for people of Central America, which also advances the interests of people in the United States.</p>
<p>And with that, we’ll give it a few minutes before taking your questions.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Ladies and gentlemen, if you wish to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 on your telephone keypad. You may withdraw your question at any time by repeating the 1, 0 command. If you are using a speaker phone, please pick up the handset before pressing the numbers. Once again, if you have a question, you may press 1 then 0 at this time.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Let’s go to Pearl Matibe, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-ETHIOPIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Good afternoon. Hope you’re having a great day today. My question is regarding President Joe Biden’s upcoming trip with President Vladimir Putin of Russia. And I’m just wondering after the sanctions and recent diplomatic tools you’re using regarding Ethiopia, Russia is now preparing to have an Africa summit in 2022. Is Africa going to be part of the agenda between President Biden and President Putin given the fact that Africa over the next decades beyond Biden’s administration will have such a huge population and role to play in the world? Is Africa going to be a significant topic on that agenda, and does the United States anticipate an Africa summit as well? Do you have anything to share? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you for your question, Pearl. Well, what I will say broadly is that Africa is a priority for – the relationship with Africa is a priority for the Biden administration, but I certainly won’t get ahead of any meetings and don’t have anything to share for you at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Casey O’Neill.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-BURMA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, hi, Jalina. Thanks so much for doing this. I – my question is actually on Myanmar. So I know today – earlier today, excuse me – Deputy Secretary Sherman in Bangkok delivered some remarks and spoke about the two American journalists that are detained in Myanmar, Danny Fenster and Nathan Maung. Their – excuse me – Mr. Fenster’s family has also been making the rounds on television and spoke earlier this morning and said that the United States Government has requested consular access, but so far that request has not been addressed by the military junta in Myanmar. So I’m just wondering if you could provide us any update on steps that the U.S. Government is taking to ensure that these two detained journalists are safe and if you have any update on whether or not the embassy personnel have been able to gain consular access to them. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks for your question, Casey. Well, I’ll start off by saying that the safety and safe return of U.S. citizens is a priority for the United States. At this time we have nothing to announce or any updates about these two specific cases.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Rosiland Jordan.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-CHINA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for taking my call. I have two questions. One: The anniversary of the Tiananmen Square massacre is coming up. Is the U.S. sending a message to Beijing about how its security forces should handle themselves on this anniversary, both in mainland China and in Hong Kong?</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-IRAN"></a> And the other question has to do with, one, the sinking of an Iranian oil tanker, the <em>Kharg</em>, in the Gulf of Oman, was – does the U.S. have any more information about whether this was an accident or perhaps an act of sabotage? And connected to that, does the U.S. have any more updates on the travel of two Iranian warships that rumor – that the rumors suggest may be heading to Venezuela? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Rosiland. I’ll start with your first question on Tiananmen, and I’ll start by broadly saying that the United States condemns actions by Hong Kong authorities that prompted organizers to close the June 4th Museum that commemorates the 1989 Tiananmen Square massacre. As far as your question of sending any particular messages, no, we’re not sending any direct messages at this time, other than saying that Hong Kong and Beijing authorities continue to silence dissenting voices by also attempting to erase the horrific massacre from history.</p>
<p>And to your question on Iran, speaking of the naval ships on the Gulf of Oman, well, we’ve definitely seen the media reports on the Iranian naval vessels that have caught fire and have sank. Other than that, we don’t have anything to announce at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Rich Edson.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-WORLDHEALTHASSEMBLY"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Jalina, just looking into the conclusion of the World Health Assembly, there is really no sense of a phase two investigation or commitment to one, Taiwan was excluded from the proceedings, Syria and Belarus are now on the executive committee. I was just wondering if you could provide what the State Department’s assessment of the proceedings were and how the U.S. plans on attempting to follow through with reforms of the World Health Organization.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Rich. What I’ll say is to your point about countries that you’ve mentioned. We have grave concerns that Syria and Belarus have been elected for a three-year term by the World Health Assembly Executive Board. Members of the executive board each have a duty to advance public health and likewise are expected to uphold universal values as well as human rights. And, of course, this would include providing access for delivery of lifesaving humanitarian supplies, and that would include medical equipment as well. <a id="post-248345-_Hlk73544881"></a>We don’t believe the actions of either Syria or Belarus demonstrate this, and although the U.S. is not currently part of the executive board, we’ll continue to monitor closely the board’s activities and make clear that – U.S. exemptions<sup><a id="post-248345-footnote-ref-3" href="#post-248345-footnote-3"></a></sup> that the board members uphold the highest standards of human rights.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Laura Rozen.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-IRAN1"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you have anything on the latest round of Iran talks in Vienna, which I think are wrapping up right now.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Laura. So the delegation led by Special Envoy for Iran Robert Malley is currently in Vienna, and he’s in Vienna for a fifth round of talks. And any update to share that he actually may come back to Washington for consultations at the end of the week. Outside of that, I’d just underscore that these last few rounds of discussion have actually helped crystallize the choices that need to be made by Iran, and also by us, the United States, in order to achieve a mutual return to compliance of the JCPOA.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Soyoung Kim, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> About North Korea, Deputy Secretary Sherman said today that the U.S. has made its policy known to the DPRK. Can you clarify whether this means the U.S. recently reached out to North Korea again or the separate contact made a few months ago the Department of State had confirmed before? And any response from North Korea?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hi, thanks for the question. I won’t get ahead of Deputy Secretary Sherman’s comments, and any other update we’ll be able to preview at a later time but nothing’s going out today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Said Arikat.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Said’s line has left the queue.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> All right. With that, let’s go to Michel Ghandour, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I have two questions on Iran. Sources in Vienna said that the parties reached a draft agreement. Can you confirm that? And any comment on the fire in Tehran’s refinery today?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks for your question. Nothing to announce. I’m not able to confirm the reports of a fire in Tehran today, but just to underscore what was mentioned previously, our Special Envoy for Iran Robert Malley, he’s currently in Vienna for his fifth round of talks and should be coming back to Washington sometime later this week. Anything beyond that and the decisions and the discussions that have been made, I have nothing to announce.</p>
<p>Looks like we have Said Arikat back in the queue. We’ll go to Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. Thank you, Jalina. And I also want to thank you for mentioning my good friend, Tejinder. May God bless his soul. We will miss him dearly. Jalina, I wanted to ask you about two issues: one, if you have any comment on a report by <em>The Washington Post</em> that Israel is preventing cancer patients from leaving Gaza through the Erez Crossing, if you have any comment on that. I also want to ask about the whereabouts of Mr. Hady Amr right now, and what is next on his agenda? What is he doing? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you for your question, Said. And again, to underscore, we definitely will all miss Tejinder and his spirit, and his vigor and his contributions to not only foreign affairs but journalism as well.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-_Hlk73546868"></a> To your first question on cancer, I certainly look forward to these reports and would have to get back to you specifically on that question. And I’d have to do the same for your question on Hady and what he’s doing. We don’t have anything to announce at this time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Lara Jakes.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> I do not see Lara Jakes’s line in queue.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Okay. Let’s go to the line of Jennifer Hansler.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> It looks like Jennifer’s line is not in queue either.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> All right. Let’s go to the line of Hiba Nasr.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thank you. Can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. I have one question about Israel. First, we saw during Secretary Blinken’s visit to Israel two weeks ago, he extended an invitation to the Israeli president to visit Washington, and tomorrow that Israeli defense minister is visiting Washington. Did this administration extend an invitation to Prime Minister Netanyahu to visit Washington? And my second question is on Nord Stream 2; yesterday Republicans in the House sent a letter to Secretary Blinken expressing concern over the decision to – over the decision to apply a waiver to some sanctions. Do you have any comments on that?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Hiba, for your first question on extending an invitation – on invites. We have nothing at all to announce on that. And your second question on NS2, I’ll have to take that one back for you.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Claudia Uceda.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-COSTARICA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi. Thanks for taking my questions. I have two questions. First is: How can Costa Rica help stop illegal immigration flow into the U.S.? What is the Secretary looking into specifically? And my second question is about Nicaragua. I would like a reaction to the fact that <a id="post-248345-NICARAGUA"></a>Nicaraguan prosecutors question and are investigating 16 independent journalists, and they are threatening them with a criminal investigation related to money laundering investigation into Violeta Chamorro, who is a prospective candidate. What’s your reaction to that? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thank you, Claudia. So to your first question, I won’t get into specifics on what Costa Rica should be doing when it comes to the fight for regular migration, but I will say that Costa Rica honestly is a top partner of the United States and it has a strong democracy. And we do have shared values as well as shared commitments. And part of that is championing human rights across the board, and that will be integral into fighting that common challenge together. To your second question, I’ll just say broadly speaking that the United States supports the freedom of the press and will continue to champion that not only in Nicaragua but all over the world.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><a id="post-248345-IRAN2"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>(Inaudible) press you a tiny bit more on Iran. In the past, you guys have said that there had been progress in the talks, though a lot of differences remained, and the U.S. and Iran were sort of closer to the start of the talks than they were toward the end of the talks. So do you believe that progress continues to be made? Have those talks stalled? And do you feel that the two sides are gradually inching closer to a resolution? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Well, certainly some progress has been made, and like I said, Rob Malley is in Vienna. He’ll be returning to Washington pretty soon. And again, talks are ongoing. And they will continue at a pace that’s honestly appropriate to address the significance of the issues that are currently on the table being negotiated right now. And I’ll continue to underscore that discussions like this are always thorough. They’re thoughtful. They’re businesslike even though they are indirect. And of course that’s to be expected. This isn’t going to be a quick or easy process.</p>
<p>It looks like we have Jennifer Hansler back on the line, so I’ll take that last question from her.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hello.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Hi, Jennifer.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi, Jalina. Thanks so much for taking my question. Just a little more on Iran, can you confirm that the indirect talks will resume next week? And then separately, has there been any communication with Russia in the wake of the latest cyber-attack on JBS? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks for your questions, Jennifer. To your first one, I don’t have anything to announce of any – for any future talks. And the second question, we’ll have to take that one back for you.</p>
<p>And thank you all very much for joining today’s briefing. I hope you have a wonderful rest of your day.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:29 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
<ol>
<li id="post-248345-footnote-1">internationally <a href="#post-248345-footnote-ref-1">↑</a></li>
<li id="post-248345-footnote-2">innovative <a href="#post-248345-footnote-ref-2">↑</a></li>
<li id="post-248345-footnote-3">expectations <a href="#post-248345-footnote-ref-3">↑</a></li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at Sembremos Seguridad Site Visit</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-sembremos-seguridad-site-visit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 20:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>San Jose, Costa Rica</p>
<p>Civic Center in Desamparados</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Well, good morning, everyone. <em>Buenos dias a todos.</em> Very, very good to be here, and I thank you so much for the incredibly warm welcome, and I especially thank so many of the young people whose activities I interrupted this morning. I’m grateful for them allowing me to do that. And I am very, very happy to be here in Desamparados to see for myself the truly outstanding work that you’re doing to support your community, especially the young people who are the heart of Costa Rica and its future.</p>
<p>I very much want to thank all of the colleagues from the government who are here today –Minister Soto, Vice Minister Solano, Vice Minister Vargas, Mayor Jimenez, Minister Solano, of course, Minister Salazar. All of you: Thank you, thank you so much for coming out and spending the time as well.</p>
<p>I know from my conversations that the leaders of Costa Rica take great pride in what you do here, and now I can see why. I had read about this project, but seeing it firsthand makes a huge difference.</p>
<p>Oh, okay. Thank you very much. Thank you.</p>
<p>So I just met with members of the youth police brigade. I heard a performance by the municipal band. I saw some extremely impressive skateboarding moves, and I’m glad I didn’t have to try that myself, so thank you. I visited workshops with students learning pottery, violin – and the wonderful young boy and young girl who played violin played one of my son’s favorite songs, so I’ll take that back as well – an amazing display of judo, and we just saw a classroom where young adults are studying for their high school equivalency degrees. In fact, the class that they were teaching – I asked – is on negotiation. So Mr. Minister, I asked if I could sit in and maybe you can sit in with me and maybe we’ll both learn some new skills.</p>
<p>This is an incredibly lively, creative, welcoming space. Everyone who works here – everyone who helps sustain this community – deserves a big round of applause. (Applause.)</p>
<p>Many of the programs here are part of Sembremos Seguridad, an initiative which in English means “We Grow Security,” and it’s now, as I understand it, in 64 municipalities across Costa Rica and will be in 82 by next year.</p>
<p>The United States is very proud to be your partner in “We Grow Security.” This program reflects the aspirations of the people of Costa Rica to live safe and secure lives; to create pathways to opportunity for all people from all neighborhoods; to give children fun and enriching activities in a safe environment, instead of having to choose between staying inside all day or risking being caught up in violence or targeted for recruitment by gangs.</p>
<p>In fact, maybe the hardest choice here: I asked the young man playing violin – there was also a foosball table right next to it – what he preferred and he honestly – he answered me honestly and said, “Foosball.” But that was a – he made the hard decision to also stick with the violin.</p>
<p>“We Grow Security” also creates a new kind of relationship between police and communities, based in partnership, not punishment. It focuses on preventing crime by addressing the root causes, because we know crime does not happen out of nowhere. To stop it, we need to make the right social, economic, educational, and security investments to support communities, to create the conditions for safety, for opportunity, for dignity for all. And we have our own experience in so many of our communities with programs that bring the police closer to the community, because, in fact, they’re part of the community, and the community should be part of them as well.</p>
<p>Best of all – and I heard it and now I’ve seen it – the program works. Crime rates have gone down in places where “We Grow Security” has been implemented – both violent crime and property crime. Communities are now stronger in other ways too. A number of the mayors who are here are able, I think, to have an even stronger relationship with the state. They also have greater connectivity with the police; they’re able to tell the police where to focus their efforts. Police trainers know how to teach officers to build closer ties with residents, with the community. Towns have reclaimed parks and plazas, where neighbors now feel safe gathering together. And of course, COVID has interrupted things a little bit but we’re going to get beyond that, and I think these gatherings will resume. And young people have discovered science, discovered music, discovered sports, jobs programs that make them feel excited and hopeful about their futures. And I think that’s the most important thing of all.</p>
<p>I recently heard two stories that capture the literally transformative power of this program, about two young people that I suspect many of you know – Ariana and Mariano.</p>
<p>Ariana started coming to the center when she was 15 years old – now she’s 18. She joined the cooking program here. She learned how to write a resume. She practiced interviewing for a job. And then thanks to the center, she got a paid internship at a local restaurant. Now Ariana is the first person in her family to have a high school degree. She’s on her way to fulfilling her dream of being a professional chef. And her two little siblings, as I understand it, have enrolled in programs here too. This center has transformed the futures of the entire family. I don’t know if she’s actually here with us today, but I send my greetings and my congratulations.</p>
<p>And Mariano is 22 years old. He’s also been coming to the center since the beginning. He enrolled in skating and guitar lessons. He graduated from high school. He’s now at the University of Costa Rica, studying to become a music teacher. And he has a job here at the center teaching music to hundreds of children, a lot like the one he used to be himself. As we say in the United States, we call that paying it forward – taking some benefit and experience that you’ve received and sharing it with others, making sure that the opportunities that you receive are shared with others.</p>
<p>What all of you have accomplished here – and what Costa Rica has accomplished across the country – I think is a model not just here in Costa Rica, not just in the region, but potentially for the world. And I’m very glad that the Government of Costa Rica will be sharing the lessons of “We Grow Security” with other governments across Central America at a citizen security conference next week.</p>
<p>Because the truth is too many young people in the region live in insecurity. Many are so desperate for a better life that they risk everything – everything: their families, their communities, their town, their language, their culture – they risk all of that to make a very dangerous journey north. People die along the way. They experience violence. And those who do make it to our border are turned around because the border is not open. The United States has made it clear – and I’ll say it again – that people should not make the dangerous journey to our border. But we know it is not enough to say, “Don’t come.” We have to work together to make it safer for people across Central America to stay in their homes and communities – without fear and with hope for a better future for themselves and for their children.</p>
<p>One of our colleagues last night in the meeting that we had with our Central American colleagues talked about the right to remain, and I think we have to give real meaning to that right because people should want to stay and build their own communities. We want to make that possible. I think it’s what people want everywhere. And together, I believe we can make it possible.</p>
<p>Seeing all the young people here today is proof that we can make it possible. And with all the challenges that we face around the world as well as the challenges we face in our work every day, a moment like this is more than anything else heartwarming. It creates a profound sense of hope. It demonstrates the power of community. So thank you for what really has been a very, very special visit. <em>Gracias a todos.</em> (Applause.)</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>San Jose, Costa Rica</p>
<p>Civic Center in Desamparados</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Well, good morning, everyone. <em>Buenos dias a todos.</em> Very, very good to be here, and I thank you so much for the incredibly warm welcome, and I especially thank so many of the young people whose activities I interrupted this morning. I’m grateful for them allowing me to do that. And I am very, very happy to be here in Desamparados to see for myself the truly outstanding work that you’re doing to support your community, especially the young people who are the heart of Costa Rica and its future.</p>
<p>I very much want to thank all of the colleagues from the government who are here today –Minister Soto, Vice Minister Solano, Vice Minister Vargas, Mayor Jimenez, Minister Solano, of course, Minister Salazar. All of you: Thank you, thank you so much for coming out and spending the time as well.</p>
<p>I know from my conversations that the leaders of Costa Rica take great pride in what you do here, and now I can see why. I had read about this project, but seeing it firsthand makes a huge difference.</p>
<p>Oh, okay. Thank you very much. Thank you.</p>
<p>So I just met with members of the youth police brigade. I heard a performance by the municipal band. I saw some extremely impressive skateboarding moves, and I’m glad I didn’t have to try that myself, so thank you. I visited workshops with students learning pottery, violin – and the wonderful young boy and young girl who played violin played one of my son’s favorite songs, so I’ll take that back as well – an amazing display of judo, and we just saw a classroom where young adults are studying for their high school equivalency degrees. In fact, the class that they were teaching – I asked – is on negotiation. So Mr. Minister, I asked if I could sit in and maybe you can sit in with me and maybe we’ll both learn some new skills.</p>
<p>This is an incredibly lively, creative, welcoming space. Everyone who works here – everyone who helps sustain this community – deserves a big round of applause. (Applause.)</p>
<p>Many of the programs here are part of Sembremos Seguridad, an initiative which in English means “We Grow Security,” and it’s now, as I understand it, in 64 municipalities across Costa Rica and will be in 82 by next year.</p>
<p>The United States is very proud to be your partner in “We Grow Security.” This program reflects the aspirations of the people of Costa Rica to live safe and secure lives; to create pathways to opportunity for all people from all neighborhoods; to give children fun and enriching activities in a safe environment, instead of having to choose between staying inside all day or risking being caught up in violence or targeted for recruitment by gangs.</p>
<p>In fact, maybe the hardest choice here: I asked the young man playing violin – there was also a foosball table right next to it – what he preferred and he honestly – he answered me honestly and said, “Foosball.” But that was a – he made the hard decision to also stick with the violin.</p>
<p>“We Grow Security” also creates a new kind of relationship between police and communities, based in partnership, not punishment. It focuses on preventing crime by addressing the root causes, because we know crime does not happen out of nowhere. To stop it, we need to make the right social, economic, educational, and security investments to support communities, to create the conditions for safety, for opportunity, for dignity for all. And we have our own experience in so many of our communities with programs that bring the police closer to the community, because, in fact, they’re part of the community, and the community should be part of them as well.</p>
<p>Best of all – and I heard it and now I’ve seen it – the program works. Crime rates have gone down in places where “We Grow Security” has been implemented – both violent crime and property crime. Communities are now stronger in other ways too. A number of the mayors who are here are able, I think, to have an even stronger relationship with the state. They also have greater connectivity with the police; they’re able to tell the police where to focus their efforts. Police trainers know how to teach officers to build closer ties with residents, with the community. Towns have reclaimed parks and plazas, where neighbors now feel safe gathering together. And of course, COVID has interrupted things a little bit but we’re going to get beyond that, and I think these gatherings will resume. And young people have discovered science, discovered music, discovered sports, jobs programs that make them feel excited and hopeful about their futures. And I think that’s the most important thing of all.</p>
<p>I recently heard two stories that capture the literally transformative power of this program, about two young people that I suspect many of you know – Ariana and Mariano.</p>
<p>Ariana started coming to the center when she was 15 years old – now she’s 18. She joined the cooking program here. She learned how to write a resume. She practiced interviewing for a job. And then thanks to the center, she got a paid internship at a local restaurant. Now Ariana is the first person in her family to have a high school degree. She’s on her way to fulfilling her dream of being a professional chef. And her two little siblings, as I understand it, have enrolled in programs here too. This center has transformed the futures of the entire family. I don’t know if she’s actually here with us today, but I send my greetings and my congratulations.</p>
<p>And Mariano is 22 years old. He’s also been coming to the center since the beginning. He enrolled in skating and guitar lessons. He graduated from high school. He’s now at the University of Costa Rica, studying to become a music teacher. And he has a job here at the center teaching music to hundreds of children, a lot like the one he used to be himself. As we say in the United States, we call that paying it forward – taking some benefit and experience that you’ve received and sharing it with others, making sure that the opportunities that you receive are shared with others.</p>
<p>What all of you have accomplished here – and what Costa Rica has accomplished across the country – I think is a model not just here in Costa Rica, not just in the region, but potentially for the world. And I’m very glad that the Government of Costa Rica will be sharing the lessons of “We Grow Security” with other governments across Central America at a citizen security conference next week.</p>
<p>Because the truth is too many young people in the region live in insecurity. Many are so desperate for a better life that they risk everything – everything: their families, their communities, their town, their language, their culture – they risk all of that to make a very dangerous journey north. People die along the way. They experience violence. And those who do make it to our border are turned around because the border is not open. The United States has made it clear – and I’ll say it again – that people should not make the dangerous journey to our border. But we know it is not enough to say, “Don’t come.” We have to work together to make it safer for people across Central America to stay in their homes and communities – without fear and with hope for a better future for themselves and for their children.</p>
<p>One of our colleagues last night in the meeting that we had with our Central American colleagues talked about the right to remain, and I think we have to give real meaning to that right because people should want to stay and build their own communities. We want to make that possible. I think it’s what people want everywhere. And together, I believe we can make it possible.</p>
<p>Seeing all the young people here today is proof that we can make it possible. And with all the challenges that we face around the world as well as the challenges we face in our work every day, a moment like this is more than anything else heartwarming. It creates a profound sense of hope. It demonstrates the power of community. So thank you for what really has been a very, very special visit. <em>Gracias a todos.</em> (Applause.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rewards for Justice – Reward Offer for Information on Abu Ubaydah Yusuf al-Anabi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/rewards-for-justice-reward-offer-for-information-on-abu-ubaydah-yusuf-al-anabi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 18:43:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248218</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State’s Rewards for Justice program, which is administered by the Diplomatic Security Service, is offering a reward of up to $7 million for information leading to the location or identification of Abu Ubaydah Yusuf al-Anabi, the leader of the terrorist organization al-Qa’ida in the Islamic Maghreb (AQIM).</p>
<p>In November 2020, AQIM announced al-Anabi, an Algerian citizen also known as Yazid Mubarak, as the group’s new leader after AQIM’s previous and first emir, Abdelmalek Droukdel, was killed in June 2020. Al-Anabi has pledged allegiance to al-Qa’ida leader Ayman al-Zawahiri on AQIM’s behalf and is expected to play a role in al-Qa’ida’s global management as Droukdel had done.</p>
<p>Al-Anabi was previously the leader of AQIM’s Council of Notables and served on AQIM’s Shura Council. Al-Anabi has also served as AQIM’s Media Chief.</p>
<p>On September 9, 2015, the U.S. Department of State designated al-Anabi as a Specially Designated Global Terrorist (SDGT) under Executive Order (E.O.) 13224. On February 29, 2016, he was placed on the United Nations (UNSCR 1267) sanctions list.</p>
<p>AQIM is responsible for the abduction and killing of Americans. AQIM, formerly known as the Salafist Group for Preaching and Combat (GSPC), was declared a Specially Designated Global Terrorist on September 23, 2001. The U.S. Department of State designated the group as a Foreign Terrorist Organization on March 27, 2002. In September 2006, GSPC officially joined al-Qa’ida’s terrorist network and re-branded itself as AQIM.</p>
<p>More information about this reward offer is located on the Rewards for Justice website at <a class="external-link" href="https://rewardsforjustice.net/english/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">www.rewardsforjustice.net</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>. We encourage anyone with information on Abu Ubaydah Yusuf al-Anabi to text Rewards for Justice via Signal, Telegram, or WhatsApp at +1-202-702-7843. All information will be kept strictly confidential.</p>
<p>The Rewards for Justice Program is an effective law enforcement tool. Since its inception in 1984, the program has paid in excess of $200 million to more than 200 people who provided actionable information that helped bring terrorists to justice or prevented acts of international terrorism worldwide. Follow us on Twitter at <a class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/rfj_usa" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://twitter.com/rfj_usa</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State’s Rewards for Justice program, which is administered by the Diplomatic Security Service, is offering a reward of up to $7 million for information leading to the location or identification of Abu Ubaydah Yusuf al-Anabi, the leader of the terrorist organization al-Qa’ida in the Islamic Maghreb (AQIM).</p>
<p>In November 2020, AQIM announced al-Anabi, an Algerian citizen also known as Yazid Mubarak, as the group’s new leader after AQIM’s previous and first emir, Abdelmalek Droukdel, was killed in June 2020. Al-Anabi has pledged allegiance to al-Qa’ida leader Ayman al-Zawahiri on AQIM’s behalf and is expected to play a role in al-Qa’ida’s global management as Droukdel had done.</p>
<p>Al-Anabi was previously the leader of AQIM’s Council of Notables and served on AQIM’s Shura Council. Al-Anabi has also served as AQIM’s Media Chief.</p>
<p>On September 9, 2015, the U.S. Department of State designated al-Anabi as a Specially Designated Global Terrorist (SDGT) under Executive Order (E.O.) 13224. On February 29, 2016, he was placed on the United Nations (UNSCR 1267) sanctions list.</p>
<p>AQIM is responsible for the abduction and killing of Americans. AQIM, formerly known as the Salafist Group for Preaching and Combat (GSPC), was declared a Specially Designated Global Terrorist on September 23, 2001. The U.S. Department of State designated the group as a Foreign Terrorist Organization on March 27, 2002. In September 2006, GSPC officially joined al-Qa’ida’s terrorist network and re-branded itself as AQIM.</p>
<p>More information about this reward offer is located on the Rewards for Justice website at <a class="external-link" href="https://rewardsforjustice.net/english/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">www.rewardsforjustice.net</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>. We encourage anyone with information on Abu Ubaydah Yusuf al-Anabi to text Rewards for Justice via Signal, Telegram, or WhatsApp at +1-202-702-7843. All information will be kept strictly confidential.</p>
<p>The Rewards for Justice Program is an effective law enforcement tool. Since its inception in 1984, the program has paid in excess of $200 million to more than 200 people who provided actionable information that helped bring terrorists to justice or prevented acts of international terrorism worldwide. Follow us on Twitter at <a class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/rfj_usa" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://twitter.com/rfj_usa</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Mexican Foreign Secretary Ebrard</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-mexican-foreign-secretary-ebrard-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 17:58:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Mexican Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard today in San Jose, Costa Rica. Secretary Blinken and Secretary Ebrard discussed continued cooperation between the United States and Mexico on a variety of issues to promote the prosperity and security of both nations.  Secretary Blinken thanked Secretary Ebrard for the Mexican government’s continued collaboration on addressing the root causes of irregular migration in the region.  The two leaders also discussed progress towards addressing COVID-19 and economic recovery, as well as issues related to regional democracy and governance, and security.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Mexican Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard today in San Jose, Costa Rica. Secretary Blinken and Secretary Ebrard discussed continued cooperation between the United States and Mexico on a variety of issues to promote the prosperity and security of both nations.  Secretary Blinken thanked Secretary Ebrard for the Mexican government’s continued collaboration on addressing the root causes of irregular migration in the region.  The two leaders also discussed progress towards addressing COVID-19 and economic recovery, as well as issues related to regional democracy and governance, and security.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Public Designation of Five Bulgarian Public Officials Due to Involvement in Significant Corruption</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/public-designation-of-five-bulgarian-public-officials-due-to-involvement-in-significant-corruption/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 15:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, we are announcing the public designation of former Bulgarian public officials Alexander Manolev, Petar Haralampiev, Krasimir Tomov, and Delyan Slavchev Peevski, as well as current Bulgarian public official Ilko Dimitrov Zhelyazkov, due to their involvement in significant corruption.  In their official capacities as Deputy Minister of the Economy, Director of the State Agency for Bulgarians Abroad, and Chief Secretary of the State Agency for Bulgarians Abroad, respectively, Manolev, Haralampiev, and Tomov were involved in corrupt acts that undermined the rule of law and the Bulgarian public’s faith in their government’s democratic institutions and public processes, including by using their political influence and official power for personal benefit.  In his capacity as a member of parliament, Peevski used Zhelyazkov, an official in the National Bureau for Control on Special Intelligence-Gathering Devices, as an intermediary and accomplice to peddle influence and pay bribes to protect himself from public scrutiny and to exert influence over key institutions and sectors in Bulgarian society.</p>
<p>The Department of the Treasury also has designated Peevski, Zhelyazkov and Bulgarian oligarch Vassil Bojkov, along with 64 entities owned and controlled by Bojkov and Peevski, for their roles in public corruption, pursuant to Executive Order 13818, which builds upon and implements the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act.</p>
<p>These designations are made under Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2021.  In addition to Manolev, Haralampiev, Tomov, Zhelyazkov, and Peevski, we are publicly designating Manolev’s wife, Nadya Manoleva, and his children, Alexa, Joanna, and Dimitar; Haralampiev’s wife and son, Veselka Haralampieva and Pavel Haralampiev; Peevski’s minor son and daughter; and Zhelyazkov’s daughters Vania Ilkova Zhelyazkova and Roza Ilkova Zhelyazkova.  This action renders Manolev, Haralampiev, Tomov, Zhelyazkov, and Peevski, and each of their immediate families, ineligible for entry into the United States.</p>
<p>Today’s actions reaffirm our commitment to supporting rule of law and strengthening democratic institutions in Bulgaria.  The United States stands with all Bulgarians whose work drives reforms forward, and the Department will continue to use its authorities to promote accountability for corrupt actors in the region and globally.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact <a href="mailto:INL-PAPD@state.gov">INL-PAPD@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, we are announcing the public designation of former Bulgarian public officials Alexander Manolev, Petar Haralampiev, Krasimir Tomov, and Delyan Slavchev Peevski, as well as current Bulgarian public official Ilko Dimitrov Zhelyazkov, due to their involvement in significant corruption.  In their official capacities as Deputy Minister of the Economy, Director of the State Agency for Bulgarians Abroad, and Chief Secretary of the State Agency for Bulgarians Abroad, respectively, Manolev, Haralampiev, and Tomov were involved in corrupt acts that undermined the rule of law and the Bulgarian public’s faith in their government’s democratic institutions and public processes, including by using their political influence and official power for personal benefit.  In his capacity as a member of parliament, Peevski used Zhelyazkov, an official in the National Bureau for Control on Special Intelligence-Gathering Devices, as an intermediary and accomplice to peddle influence and pay bribes to protect himself from public scrutiny and to exert influence over key institutions and sectors in Bulgarian society.</p>
<p>The Department of the Treasury also has designated Peevski, Zhelyazkov and Bulgarian oligarch Vassil Bojkov, along with 64 entities owned and controlled by Bojkov and Peevski, for their roles in public corruption, pursuant to Executive Order 13818, which builds upon and implements the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act.</p>
<p>These designations are made under Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2021.  In addition to Manolev, Haralampiev, Tomov, Zhelyazkov, and Peevski, we are publicly designating Manolev’s wife, Nadya Manoleva, and his children, Alexa, Joanna, and Dimitar; Haralampiev’s wife and son, Veselka Haralampieva and Pavel Haralampiev; Peevski’s minor son and daughter; and Zhelyazkov’s daughters Vania Ilkova Zhelyazkova and Roza Ilkova Zhelyazkova.  This action renders Manolev, Haralampiev, Tomov, Zhelyazkov, and Peevski, and each of their immediate families, ineligible for entry into the United States.</p>
<p>Today’s actions reaffirm our commitment to supporting rule of law and strengthening democratic institutions in Bulgaria.  The United States stands with all Bulgarians whose work drives reforms forward, and the Department will continue to use its authorities to promote accountability for corrupt actors in the region and globally.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact <a href="mailto:INL-PAPD@state.gov">INL-PAPD@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>G7 Ministers’ Statement on the UN General Assembly Special Session Against Corruption</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/g7-ministers-statement-on-the-un-general-assembly-special-session-against-corruption/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 12:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the G7 ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>We, the G7 Ministers<i>, </i>recognize that corruption is a pressing global challenge. As the UN Convention against Corruption notes, corruption threatens the stability and security of societies, undermining the institutions and values of democracy, ethical values and justice, and jeopardizing sustainable development and the rule of law. Corruption presents serious threats for individuals and societies and often enables other forms of crime, including organized crime and economic crime, including money laundering. These threats have been heightened by COVID-19. As the world continues to recover, it is critical that we do not let corruption threaten our efforts to build back better and address global challenges especially the achievement of the 2030 Sustainable Development Goals.</p>
<p>We are looking forward to the G7 ministerial meeting in September this year, where there will be a discussion on our joint efforts to address corruption.</p>
<p>Corruption is a challenge faced by all countries. Its effects are felt at local, national, and global levels and it is our common and shared responsibility to take action. We as the G7 stand up for an open society, with a strong civil society and free media. We are convinced that these actors are crucial in preventing and combatting corruption. Thus, it is our goal to acknowledge the role of civil society and free media and to promote their freedom and protection in the UNGASS declaration. We recognise that progress will catalyse prosperity, security and development.</p>
<p>G7 Foreign Ministers committed to work collectively to strengthen the foundations of open societies and protect against threats, including corruption, and illicit finance, and the closure of civic space. In this regard, we reaffirm the fundamental role of the UN Convention Against Corruption (UNCAC) and its supporting bodies play in the global fight against corruption.  It is the only legally binding universal instrument on corruption, negotiated on the basis of consensus. The Convention is the cornerstone of our international anti-corruption framework. It forms an integral part of the international anti-corruption architecture which, when fully and effectively implemented, will robustly combat corruption.</p>
<p>We fully support the aims of this Special Session of the General Assembly against corruption to address challenges and measures to more effectively prevent, detect, prosecute, and punish corruption and strengthen international cooperation.</p>
<p>We welcome the adoption of the action-oriented political declaration and commit to achieving its aims. Given our international responsibilities, we as the G7 recognise the need to enhance our efforts to prevent and combat corruption by leading by example. We must continue to make real progress on this issue. We will ensure strong and effective implementation of UNGASS commitments.  To this end, we commit to:</p>
<ol>
<li>Prevention: As the G7, we will work to ensure there are strong measures in place to prevent corruption and other forms of illicit finance to protect our financial centres and deny safe haven to the proceeds of crime. We will support other countries’ efforts to do the same, including anti-corruption safeguards and transparency mechanisms in the delivery of humanitarian aid to ensure that aid, required in times of natural disaster and other emergencies including the COVID-19 pandemic, reaches intended beneficiaries. We also reaffirm our commitment to putting in place measures that promote transparency in the beneficial ownership of legal entities. We further commit to promoting the effective implementation of the Financial Action Task Force (FATF) Standards, the global standard setter for combatting money laundering, terrorist financing and proliferation finance.</li>
<li>Transparency: Comprising many of the world’s most open societies, we note that enhancing transparency benefits citizens and societies and is the foundation on which effective anti-corruption efforts are built. As such, we reaffirm our commitment to implementing measures that afford a high degree of transparency in governance, including measures to enhance transparency in public procurement, and supply chain transparency in the private sector. Consistent with our legal obligations, we will protect and promote access to information for all citizens, including civil society organisations, media and journalists.</li>
<li>Law Enforcement Cooperation/Criminalization:</li>
<li>Foreign bribery: As major centres of private enterprise, we commit to actively enforcing our domestic and foreign bribery laws and ensuring effective implementation of the OECD Anti-Bribery Convention and we urge all G20 countries to do the same.  We recognize the positive impact that incentivizing robust private sector corporate compliance can have on the goal of effectively preventing corruption. We also recognise the corrosive effect of bribe solicitation and call for greater preventive action including awareness raising and training.</li>
<li>Denial of Safe Haven: As some of our financial centres and industries can attract corrupt actors and the proceeds of crime, we commit to strengthening international cooperation to deny safe haven to corrupt individuals and their ill-gotten gains, including through information sharing, and the appropriate use of sanctions and visa restrictions.</li>
<li>International Cooperation and Technical Assistance (TA):  As many of the world’s largest donors, we recognise the role of Official Development Assistance and commit to using our programmes efficiently to build capacities and provide timely, sustainable, adequate and effective technical assistance that meet needs. We call on our partner countries to take a lead in the coordination of TA at country level, including by, publishing needs identified by the implementation review mechanism, involving all relevant stakeholders and, mainstreaming gender in analysis and the delivery of programmes.</li>
<li>Civil Society (including protection of journalists and role of the media): We commit to championing the role of civil society and media freedom as a vital part of upholding democracy and human rights around the world. We condemn all attacks on those who work to expose corruption, including journalists, civil society and individual whistle-blowers, and commit to support and protect those who report and stand up against corruption.</li>
<li>Asset Recovery:  As home to many of the world’s leading financial centres and as recipients of some of the largest volumes of mutual legal assistance requests in the world, we renew our commitment to counter money laundering linked to foreign corruption and to effectively recover proceeds of crime, particularly money laundering proceeds. We further underline the importance of ensuring confiscated stolen assets, when returned, are returned in a transparent and accountable manner, within the framework of the UNCAC, that ultimately benefits those harmed by corruption. We will promote and support international co-operation among relevant law enforcement agencies including in asset recovery.</li>
<li>Rule of Law and Fundamental Freedoms: We recognise that the fight against corruption must be based on respect for the rule of law, support for democratic governance, fundamental freedoms and human rights including due process rights of those accused of and sought for corruption. Rule of law is an essential component to achieve sustainability, to counter abuses of power and to foster an environment needed to effectively achieve the goals of the 2030 Agenda.</li>
<li>Implementation of anti-corruption conventions and other initiatives: As global leaders in the fight against corruption, we recognise the importance of international and regional conventions and other initiatives to fight corruption and emphasise our individual and collective responsibility to step up our efforts towards their effective implementation.</li>
<li>Commit to consulting civil society in our country reviews and promoting their inclusion as observers in subsidiary bodies of the UNCAC and Conference of States Parties.</li>
<li>Call all countries under review by UNCAC to publish their full UNCAC country reports and invite inputs from a wide range of stakeholders.</li>
<li>Support UNODC to prepare a comprehensive report on member state implementation of UNCAC, after completion of the current review phase, and report its findings to the COSP.</li>
<li>Support the effective implementation of existing regional anticorruption frameworks and the FATF standards, including their review mechanisms for compliance.</li>
<li>Urge those who have not ratified the UNCAC to join the 187 other state parties who have done so.</li>
</ol>
<p>We firmly reiterate the importance of strong and unified leadership in addressing corruption. We look to forthcoming processes in relevant fora with close cooperation with other stakeholders such as, the US Summit for Democracy and the Open Government Partnership 10-year Anniversary Summit in South Korea and the UK presidency of the G7 to build on these commitments. We commit to working within these forums, as well as through the G20 Anti-Corruption Working Group, to continue to drive progress on this important agenda.</p>
<p><i>End text.</i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000000" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the G7 ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>We, the G7 Ministers<i>, </i>recognize that corruption is a pressing global challenge. As the UN Convention against Corruption notes, corruption threatens the stability and security of societies, undermining the institutions and values of democracy, ethical values and justice, and jeopardizing sustainable development and the rule of law. Corruption presents serious threats for individuals and societies and often enables other forms of crime, including organized crime and economic crime, including money laundering. These threats have been heightened by COVID-19. As the world continues to recover, it is critical that we do not let corruption threaten our efforts to build back better and address global challenges especially the achievement of the 2030 Sustainable Development Goals.</p>
<p>We are looking forward to the G7 ministerial meeting in September this year, where there will be a discussion on our joint efforts to address corruption.</p>
<p>Corruption is a challenge faced by all countries. Its effects are felt at local, national, and global levels and it is our common and shared responsibility to take action. We as the G7 stand up for an open society, with a strong civil society and free media. We are convinced that these actors are crucial in preventing and combatting corruption. Thus, it is our goal to acknowledge the role of civil society and free media and to promote their freedom and protection in the UNGASS declaration. We recognise that progress will catalyse prosperity, security and development.</p>
<p>G7 Foreign Ministers committed to work collectively to strengthen the foundations of open societies and protect against threats, including corruption, and illicit finance, and the closure of civic space. In this regard, we reaffirm the fundamental role of the UN Convention Against Corruption (UNCAC) and its supporting bodies play in the global fight against corruption.  It is the only legally binding universal instrument on corruption, negotiated on the basis of consensus. The Convention is the cornerstone of our international anti-corruption framework. It forms an integral part of the international anti-corruption architecture which, when fully and effectively implemented, will robustly combat corruption.</p>
<p>We fully support the aims of this Special Session of the General Assembly against corruption to address challenges and measures to more effectively prevent, detect, prosecute, and punish corruption and strengthen international cooperation.</p>
<p>We welcome the adoption of the action-oriented political declaration and commit to achieving its aims. Given our international responsibilities, we as the G7 recognise the need to enhance our efforts to prevent and combat corruption by leading by example. We must continue to make real progress on this issue. We will ensure strong and effective implementation of UNGASS commitments.  To this end, we commit to:</p>
<ol>
<li>Prevention: As the G7, we will work to ensure there are strong measures in place to prevent corruption and other forms of illicit finance to protect our financial centres and deny safe haven to the proceeds of crime. We will support other countries’ efforts to do the same, including anti-corruption safeguards and transparency mechanisms in the delivery of humanitarian aid to ensure that aid, required in times of natural disaster and other emergencies including the COVID-19 pandemic, reaches intended beneficiaries. We also reaffirm our commitment to putting in place measures that promote transparency in the beneficial ownership of legal entities. We further commit to promoting the effective implementation of the Financial Action Task Force (FATF) Standards, the global standard setter for combatting money laundering, terrorist financing and proliferation finance.</li>
<li>Transparency: Comprising many of the world’s most open societies, we note that enhancing transparency benefits citizens and societies and is the foundation on which effective anti-corruption efforts are built. As such, we reaffirm our commitment to implementing measures that afford a high degree of transparency in governance, including measures to enhance transparency in public procurement, and supply chain transparency in the private sector. Consistent with our legal obligations, we will protect and promote access to information for all citizens, including civil society organisations, media and journalists.</li>
<li>Law Enforcement Cooperation/Criminalization:</li>
<li>Foreign bribery: As major centres of private enterprise, we commit to actively enforcing our domestic and foreign bribery laws and ensuring effective implementation of the OECD Anti-Bribery Convention and we urge all G20 countries to do the same.  We recognize the positive impact that incentivizing robust private sector corporate compliance can have on the goal of effectively preventing corruption. We also recognise the corrosive effect of bribe solicitation and call for greater preventive action including awareness raising and training.</li>
<li>Denial of Safe Haven: As some of our financial centres and industries can attract corrupt actors and the proceeds of crime, we commit to strengthening international cooperation to deny safe haven to corrupt individuals and their ill-gotten gains, including through information sharing, and the appropriate use of sanctions and visa restrictions.</li>
<li>International Cooperation and Technical Assistance (TA):  As many of the world’s largest donors, we recognise the role of Official Development Assistance and commit to using our programmes efficiently to build capacities and provide timely, sustainable, adequate and effective technical assistance that meet needs. We call on our partner countries to take a lead in the coordination of TA at country level, including by, publishing needs identified by the implementation review mechanism, involving all relevant stakeholders and, mainstreaming gender in analysis and the delivery of programmes.</li>
<li>Civil Society (including protection of journalists and role of the media): We commit to championing the role of civil society and media freedom as a vital part of upholding democracy and human rights around the world. We condemn all attacks on those who work to expose corruption, including journalists, civil society and individual whistle-blowers, and commit to support and protect those who report and stand up against corruption.</li>
<li>Asset Recovery:  As home to many of the world’s leading financial centres and as recipients of some of the largest volumes of mutual legal assistance requests in the world, we renew our commitment to counter money laundering linked to foreign corruption and to effectively recover proceeds of crime, particularly money laundering proceeds. We further underline the importance of ensuring confiscated stolen assets, when returned, are returned in a transparent and accountable manner, within the framework of the UNCAC, that ultimately benefits those harmed by corruption. We will promote and support international co-operation among relevant law enforcement agencies including in asset recovery.</li>
<li>Rule of Law and Fundamental Freedoms: We recognise that the fight against corruption must be based on respect for the rule of law, support for democratic governance, fundamental freedoms and human rights including due process rights of those accused of and sought for corruption. Rule of law is an essential component to achieve sustainability, to counter abuses of power and to foster an environment needed to effectively achieve the goals of the 2030 Agenda.</li>
<li>Implementation of anti-corruption conventions and other initiatives: As global leaders in the fight against corruption, we recognise the importance of international and regional conventions and other initiatives to fight corruption and emphasise our individual and collective responsibility to step up our efforts towards their effective implementation.</li>
<li>Commit to consulting civil society in our country reviews and promoting their inclusion as observers in subsidiary bodies of the UNCAC and Conference of States Parties.</li>
<li>Call all countries under review by UNCAC to publish their full UNCAC country reports and invite inputs from a wide range of stakeholders.</li>
<li>Support UNODC to prepare a comprehensive report on member state implementation of UNCAC, after completion of the current review phase, and report its findings to the COSP.</li>
<li>Support the effective implementation of existing regional anticorruption frameworks and the FATF standards, including their review mechanisms for compliance.</li>
<li>Urge those who have not ratified the UNCAC to join the 187 other state parties who have done so.</li>
</ol>
<p>We firmly reiterate the importance of strong and unified leadership in addressing corruption. We look to forthcoming processes in relevant fora with close cooperation with other stakeholders such as, the US Summit for Democracy and the Open Government Partnership 10-year Anniversary Summit in South Korea and the UK presidency of the G7 to build on these commitments. We commit to working within these forums, as well as through the G20 Anti-Corruption Working Group, to continue to drive progress on this important agenda.</p>
<p><i>End text.</i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000000" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Foreign Ministers from Central America and Mexico</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-foreign-ministers-from-central-america-and-mexico/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 12:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=248105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met yesterday with Foreign Ministers from Costa Rica, Guatemala, Honduras, El Salvador, Nicaragua, Panama, and Mexico in San Jose at a meeting of the Central America Integration System (SICA), the economic and political organization of the region’s states. Secretary Blinken emphasized the importance of strong democratic institutions and a commitment to combatting corruption as well as the need for governments to serve their people.  The leaders discussed the U.S. strategy to address the root causes of irregular migration, including generating economic opportunities for Central Americans and advancing the essential work of reducing violence and addressing the COVID-19 pandemic and climate change. Secretary Blinken underscored, on the 20th anniversary of the InterAmerican Democratic Charter, the need for commitment from all leaders to free and fair elections, good governance, separation of powers, rule of law, respect for human rights, and a level economic playing field.  Secretary Blinken also noted that Central America can be a stronger region if the people and countries cooperate to jointly tackle challenges, including with partners like Mexico. </span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met yesterday with Foreign Ministers from Costa Rica, Guatemala, Honduras, El Salvador, Nicaragua, Panama, and Mexico in San Jose at a meeting of the Central America Integration System (SICA), the economic and political organization of the region’s states. Secretary Blinken emphasized the importance of strong democratic institutions and a commitment to combatting corruption as well as the need for governments to serve their people.  The leaders discussed the U.S. strategy to address the root causes of irregular migration, including generating economic opportunities for Central Americans and advancing the essential work of reducing violence and addressing the COVID-19 pandemic and climate change. Secretary Blinken underscored, on the 20th anniversary of the InterAmerican Democratic Charter, the need for commitment from all leaders to free and fair elections, good governance, separation of powers, rule of law, respect for human rights, and a level economic playing field.  Secretary Blinken also noted that Central America can be a stronger region if the people and countries cooperate to jointly tackle challenges, including with partners like Mexico. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
