<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 14:19:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Aruba National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/aruba-national-day-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 14:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States government, I congratulate the people of Aruba on your National Day celebrating the 36th anniversary of Aruba’s <em>Status Aparte</em>.</p>
<p>We deeply value the strong ties between our two countries and commend Aruba’s steadfast support for Ukraine and readiness to take action with allies to protect and defend democracy.  The signing of Aruba’s historic energy deal with an American company for your transition to clean energy further highlights our shared vision for a more prosperous and sustainable future.  We welcome the opportunity to promote educational opportunities for Aruba’s youth at our EducationUSA Advising Center and to facilitate secure travel through a strong U.S. Customs and Border Protection program.</p>
<p>In appreciation of the strong relationship that we share, I wish all Arubans a happy National Anthem and Flag Day.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States government, I congratulate the people of Aruba on your National Day celebrating the 36th anniversary of Aruba’s <em>Status Aparte</em>.</p>
<p>We deeply value the strong ties between our two countries and commend Aruba’s steadfast support for Ukraine and readiness to take action with allies to protect and defend democracy.  The signing of Aruba’s historic energy deal with an American company for your transition to clean energy further highlights our shared vision for a more prosperous and sustainable future.  We welcome the opportunity to promote educational opportunities for Aruba’s youth at our EducationUSA Advising Center and to facilitate secure travel through a strong U.S. Customs and Border Protection program.</p>
<p>In appreciation of the strong relationship that we share, I wish all Arubans a happy National Anthem and Flag Day.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary Nuland’s Travel to Bangladesh, India, and Sri Lanka</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-nulands-travel-to-bangladesh-india-and-sri-lanka/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 12:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325707</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland will travel March 19-23 to Bangladesh, India, and Sri Lanka with an interagency delegation to underscore U.S. commitment to, and cooperation with, Indo-Pacific partners.  Under Secretary Nuland will hold Partnership Dialogues in Bangladesh and Sri Lanka and Foreign Office Consultations in New Delhi.  On each stop, Under Secretary Nuland and the delegation will meet with civil society and business leaders to strengthen economic partnerships and deepen ties in the pursuit of peace, prosperity, and security in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p>Other senior members of the delegation include Assistant Secretary for South and Central Asian Affairs Donald Lu and Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Policy Amanda Dory.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:sca-press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sca-press@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland will travel March 19-23 to Bangladesh, India, and Sri Lanka with an interagency delegation to underscore U.S. commitment to, and cooperation with, Indo-Pacific partners.  Under Secretary Nuland will hold Partnership Dialogues in Bangladesh and Sri Lanka and Foreign Office Consultations in New Delhi.  On each stop, Under Secretary Nuland and the delegation will meet with civil society and business leaders to strengthen economic partnerships and deepen ties in the pursuit of peace, prosperity, and security in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p>Other senior members of the delegation include Assistant Secretary for South and Central Asian Affairs Donald Lu and Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Policy Amanda Dory.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:sca-press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sca-press@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate Kerry’s Travel to Monaco, France, and Qatar </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-presidential-envoy-for-climate-kerrys-travel-to-monaco-france-and-qatar/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 22:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325632</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Monte Carlo, Monaco, March 20-21, for the Monaco Blue Initiative and discuss the ocean-climate nexus with key stakeholders.  Further information may be found at <a class="external-link" href="https://www.monacoblueinitiative.org/en/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://www.monacoblueinitiative.org/en/</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>On March 22-24, Secretary Kerry will travel to Paris, France, to participate in the International Energy Agency 2022 Ministerial Meeting and discuss urgent energy security challenges, including accelerating the clean energy transition.  The event will be livestreamed at <a class="external-link" href="https://www.iea.org/events/iea-2022-ministerial-meeting" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://www.iea.org/events/iea-2022-ministerial-meeting</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>Secretary Kerry will travel to Doha, Qatar, March 25-27, to attend the Doha Forum and discuss opportunities to advance security and prosperity by tackling the climate crisis.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:ClimateComms@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">ClimateComms@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Monte Carlo, Monaco, March 20-21, for the Monaco Blue Initiative and discuss the ocean-climate nexus with key stakeholders.  Further information may be found at <a class="external-link" href="https://www.monacoblueinitiative.org/en/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://www.monacoblueinitiative.org/en/</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>On March 22-24, Secretary Kerry will travel to Paris, France, to participate in the International Energy Agency 2022 Ministerial Meeting and discuss urgent energy security challenges, including accelerating the clean energy transition.  The event will be livestreamed at <a class="external-link" href="https://www.iea.org/events/iea-2022-ministerial-meeting" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://www.iea.org/events/iea-2022-ministerial-meeting</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>Secretary Kerry will travel to Doha, Qatar, March 25-27, to attend the Doha Forum and discuss opportunities to advance security and prosperity by tackling the climate crisis.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:ClimateComms@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">ClimateComms@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-Croatia Joint Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-croatia-joint-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 22:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><i>The following is the text of a joint statement by the United States of America and the Republic of Croatia on the occasion of the U.S. Croatia Strategic Dialogue</i><i>.</i></p>
<p><i>Begin text:</i></p>
<p>The Governments of the United States and Croatia held a Strategic Dialogue in Washington, D.C. on March 17, 2022, which underscored the deepening cooperation between the United States and Croatia and sets the vision for our shared goals of promoting peace, security, and prosperity in both Europe and globally.</p>
<p>The Strategic Dialogue comes as the United States and Croatia mark the 30th anniversary of diplomatic relations.</p>
<p>Croatian Ministry of Foreign and European Affairs Director for Political Affairs Petar Mihatov and U.S. Assistant Secretary of State for European and Eurasian Affairs Dr. Karen Donfried led the Strategic Dialogue, which included discussions on six key pillars of the bilateral relationship:  Global Issues, Defense and Security, Energy and Climate Change, Regional Cooperation, Trade and Investment, and People-to-People Ties.</p>
<p><b>Global Issues </b></p>
<p>The United States and Croatia committed to work together to advance shared foreign policy goals, intensify bilateral cooperation and strengthen the Transatlantic bond.  They also committed to promote democracy, rule of law, and fundamental human rights both regionally and globally, building on pledges made during President Biden’s Summit for Democracy in December 2021.  The United States and Croatia underscored their strong support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and called on Russia to cease its unprovoked war.  They underscored a joint desire to defend the common values of the Euro-Atlantic community and stressed the importance of preserving the rules-based international order, supporting good governance, and protecting democratic societies.  The United States welcomed Croatia’s entry as the 40th member of the Visa Waiver program and affirmed Croatia has made great progress toward becoming a partner country in the Global Entry Program.  The United States welcomed Croatia’s commitment to fully empower a Holocaust envoy with a view to intensifying dialogue on all related issues, including property wrongfully seized during the Holocaust.</p>
<p><b>Defense and Security </b></p>
<p>As NATO Allies and strategic partners, the United States and Croatia underscored their commitment to promoting peace and stability in Southeast Europe and Europe as a whole.  Both sides emphasized the continued importance of developing high-end defense capabilities, conducting bilateral exercises and training activities to improve interoperability and readiness, and the importance of meeting NATO commitments in support of our collective security.  The United States and Croatia reaffirmed that the most recent cooperation resulting in Croatian procurement of M2A2 Bradley vehicles is a significant step toward meeting one of Croatia’s priority NATO Capability Target requirements.  The two countries intend to work closely on the future Strategic Concept of NATO, with a view to strengthening the Alliance in fulfilling its mission as the guarantor of peace and security in Europe.  Both parties underlined the importance of EU-NATO cooperation, ensuring complementarity and strengthening interoperability, and recognized NATO as the foundation of Euro-Atlantic security and the essential forum for collective defense of the transatlantic community.  The United States and Croatia underscored the importance of cybersecurity and intend to look to strengthen cooperation in this field.</p>
<p><b>Energy and Climate Change </b></p>
<p>The United States and Croatia recommitted to their shared goals of increasing energy diversification and security and tackling climate change through decarbonization and clean energy policies, as well as the adaptation of our societies to climate change.  The United States lauded Croatia for its leadership on energy diversification through the opening of the floating liquefied natural gas terminal off Krk island and noted the shared goal that Croatia support energy diversification for the broader region through projects like the Southern Connector to Bosnia and Herzegovina.  The two sides explored opportunities for strengthening cooperation in renewable energy production and distribution.  Croatia reiterated its commitment to phase out coal by 2033, and the United States praised Croatia’s goal to achieve net zero emissions by 2050 and join the Global Methane Pledge.  Both sides committed to deepen bilateral and regional cooperation on energy and climate through the Partnership for Transatlantic Energy and Climate Cooperation (P-TECC).</p>
<p><b>Regional Cooperation </b></p>
<p>The United States and Croatia emphasized their joint commitment to advance the Euro-Atlantic perspective of the Western Balkans countries, and to see Croatia’s neighbors firmly anchored in a Europe free, whole, and at peace.  The United States and Croatia recognized that the countries of the Western Balkans must meet the strict criteria to join the EU and NATO while underscoring that the door to these organizations must remain open and viable to incentivize necessary reforms to promote lasting stability and security.  The United States and Croatia concurred on the importance of preserving the stability and territorial integrity of Bosnia and Herzegovina, and the need to secure electoral and limited constitutional reforms aimed at eliminating all forms of discrimination and ensuring the equality of three constituent peoples and rights of all citizens.  They also concurred on the need to eliminate fraud, corruption, and pressure on voters, and to ensure election outcomes reflect the will of the people.  The United States and Croatia highlighted the importance of Western Balkans countries resolving near-term legacy and open issues as an essential step on their Euro-Atlantic path.  The United States thanked Croatia for its leadership on joint efforts to fight corruption and protect the rule of law through the INL-funded Department of Justice law enforcement educational partnership and prosecutor training in the Western Balkans.</p>
<p><b>Trade and Investment </b></p>
<p>The two sides reaffirmed their shared commitment to broaden and deepen bilateral economic and commercial cooperation, expressing satisfaction with reaching a final stage of negotiations and recognizing the desire for a swift conclusion of a treaty for the avoidance of double taxation.  They shared ideas on increasing trade and investment across various sectors.  The United States welcomed Croatia’s invitation to begin the accession process to the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development.  Croatia and the United States exchanged ideas and concrete plans for intensifying cooperation taking into account the growing urgency for development and humanitarian aid for countries in need.</p>
<p><b>People-to-People Ties   </b></p>
<p>The United States and Croatia share extensive and meaningful people-to-people connections that promote mutual understanding between the people of both nations.  Both countries remain committed to expanding educational, cultural, and professional exchange opportunities, including through the Fulbright Program.  The two sides look forward to collaboration on STEM programming and enhanced connections between U.S. and Croatian universities.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><i>The following is the text of a joint statement by the United States of America and the Republic of Croatia on the occasion of the U.S. Croatia Strategic Dialogue</i><i>.</i></p>
<p><i>Begin text:</i></p>
<p>The Governments of the United States and Croatia held a Strategic Dialogue in Washington, D.C. on March 17, 2022, which underscored the deepening cooperation between the United States and Croatia and sets the vision for our shared goals of promoting peace, security, and prosperity in both Europe and globally.</p>
<p>The Strategic Dialogue comes as the United States and Croatia mark the 30th anniversary of diplomatic relations.</p>
<p>Croatian Ministry of Foreign and European Affairs Director for Political Affairs Petar Mihatov and U.S. Assistant Secretary of State for European and Eurasian Affairs Dr. Karen Donfried led the Strategic Dialogue, which included discussions on six key pillars of the bilateral relationship:  Global Issues, Defense and Security, Energy and Climate Change, Regional Cooperation, Trade and Investment, and People-to-People Ties.</p>
<p><b>Global Issues </b></p>
<p>The United States and Croatia committed to work together to advance shared foreign policy goals, intensify bilateral cooperation and strengthen the Transatlantic bond.  They also committed to promote democracy, rule of law, and fundamental human rights both regionally and globally, building on pledges made during President Biden’s Summit for Democracy in December 2021.  The United States and Croatia underscored their strong support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and called on Russia to cease its unprovoked war.  They underscored a joint desire to defend the common values of the Euro-Atlantic community and stressed the importance of preserving the rules-based international order, supporting good governance, and protecting democratic societies.  The United States welcomed Croatia’s entry as the 40th member of the Visa Waiver program and affirmed Croatia has made great progress toward becoming a partner country in the Global Entry Program.  The United States welcomed Croatia’s commitment to fully empower a Holocaust envoy with a view to intensifying dialogue on all related issues, including property wrongfully seized during the Holocaust.</p>
<p><b>Defense and Security </b></p>
<p>As NATO Allies and strategic partners, the United States and Croatia underscored their commitment to promoting peace and stability in Southeast Europe and Europe as a whole.  Both sides emphasized the continued importance of developing high-end defense capabilities, conducting bilateral exercises and training activities to improve interoperability and readiness, and the importance of meeting NATO commitments in support of our collective security.  The United States and Croatia reaffirmed that the most recent cooperation resulting in Croatian procurement of M2A2 Bradley vehicles is a significant step toward meeting one of Croatia’s priority NATO Capability Target requirements.  The two countries intend to work closely on the future Strategic Concept of NATO, with a view to strengthening the Alliance in fulfilling its mission as the guarantor of peace and security in Europe.  Both parties underlined the importance of EU-NATO cooperation, ensuring complementarity and strengthening interoperability, and recognized NATO as the foundation of Euro-Atlantic security and the essential forum for collective defense of the transatlantic community.  The United States and Croatia underscored the importance of cybersecurity and intend to look to strengthen cooperation in this field.</p>
<p><b>Energy and Climate Change </b></p>
<p>The United States and Croatia recommitted to their shared goals of increasing energy diversification and security and tackling climate change through decarbonization and clean energy policies, as well as the adaptation of our societies to climate change.  The United States lauded Croatia for its leadership on energy diversification through the opening of the floating liquefied natural gas terminal off Krk island and noted the shared goal that Croatia support energy diversification for the broader region through projects like the Southern Connector to Bosnia and Herzegovina.  The two sides explored opportunities for strengthening cooperation in renewable energy production and distribution.  Croatia reiterated its commitment to phase out coal by 2033, and the United States praised Croatia’s goal to achieve net zero emissions by 2050 and join the Global Methane Pledge.  Both sides committed to deepen bilateral and regional cooperation on energy and climate through the Partnership for Transatlantic Energy and Climate Cooperation (P-TECC).</p>
<p><b>Regional Cooperation </b></p>
<p>The United States and Croatia emphasized their joint commitment to advance the Euro-Atlantic perspective of the Western Balkans countries, and to see Croatia’s neighbors firmly anchored in a Europe free, whole, and at peace.  The United States and Croatia recognized that the countries of the Western Balkans must meet the strict criteria to join the EU and NATO while underscoring that the door to these organizations must remain open and viable to incentivize necessary reforms to promote lasting stability and security.  The United States and Croatia concurred on the importance of preserving the stability and territorial integrity of Bosnia and Herzegovina, and the need to secure electoral and limited constitutional reforms aimed at eliminating all forms of discrimination and ensuring the equality of three constituent peoples and rights of all citizens.  They also concurred on the need to eliminate fraud, corruption, and pressure on voters, and to ensure election outcomes reflect the will of the people.  The United States and Croatia highlighted the importance of Western Balkans countries resolving near-term legacy and open issues as an essential step on their Euro-Atlantic path.  The United States thanked Croatia for its leadership on joint efforts to fight corruption and protect the rule of law through the INL-funded Department of Justice law enforcement educational partnership and prosecutor training in the Western Balkans.</p>
<p><b>Trade and Investment </b></p>
<p>The two sides reaffirmed their shared commitment to broaden and deepen bilateral economic and commercial cooperation, expressing satisfaction with reaching a final stage of negotiations and recognizing the desire for a swift conclusion of a treaty for the avoidance of double taxation.  They shared ideas on increasing trade and investment across various sectors.  The United States welcomed Croatia’s invitation to begin the accession process to the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development.  Croatia and the United States exchanged ideas and concrete plans for intensifying cooperation taking into account the growing urgency for development and humanitarian aid for countries in need.</p>
<p><b>People-to-People Ties   </b></p>
<p>The United States and Croatia share extensive and meaningful people-to-people connections that promote mutual understanding between the people of both nations.  Both countries remain committed to expanding educational, cultural, and professional exchange opportunities, including through the Fulbright Program.  The two sides look forward to collaboration on STEM programming and enhanced connections between U.S. and Croatian universities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at a Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-press-availability-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 21:33:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325622</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Press Briefing Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone.</p>
<p>Three weeks ago, Russia launched its unprovoked war on Ukraine.</p>
<p>With every day that passes, the numbers of civilians, including children, killed and wounded continues to climb.</p>
<p>Russia continues to attack civilian sites, including – this week alone – a hospital, three schools, a boarding school for visually impaired kids in the Luhansk region of Ukraine.</p>
<p>Yesterday Russian forces bombed a theater in Mariupol, where hundreds of people had been taking shelter.</p>
<p>The word “children” had been written in Russian in giant white letters on the pavement outside the building, so that you could know from the air that there were children inside.</p>
<p>Russian forces also opened fire on 10 civilians in who were waiting in line for bread.</p>
<p>These incidents join a long list of attacks on civilian – not military – locations across Ukraine, including apartment buildings, public squares, and, last week, a maternity hospital in Mariupol.</p>
<p>I doubt that any of us who saw those images will ever forget them.</p>
<p>We’ve seen Russia use similar tactics before in Grozny and Aleppo.  They stepped up their bombardment with the goal of breaking the will of the people.</p>
<p>Yesterday President Biden said that, in his opinion, war crimes have been committed in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Personally, I agree.</p>
<p>Intentionally targeting civilians is a war crime.</p>
<p>After all the destruction of the past three weeks, I find it difficult to conclude that the Russians are doing otherwise.</p>
<p>The consequences of Moscow’s war are being felt around the world – in rising food costs, concerns about fuel supplies, more broadly in worries about how this war will affect the global economy and the fight against COVID-19.</p>
<p>These are serious issues that the global community urgently needs to address.  This war is making that much more difficult.</p>
<p>In this way, Russia’s actions are having an impact on every person on the planet, wherever they live.</p>
<p>We also feel the impact right here in this room.</p>
<p>There should be a seat reserved here today for Benjamin Hall from Fox News, who was injured badly when his vehicle came under attack near Kyiv.</p>
<p>Many of us, myself included, have gotten to know Ben very well as part of the traveling press corps.</p>
<p>He’s an incredibly talented reporter, always asking tough questions.  He’s a lovely person, as well.</p>
<p>Our thoughts – my thoughts – are with him and his family, including his three little kids.</p>
<p>Two of Ben’s Fox News colleagues, Pierre Zokchefski and Sasha Koofshenova, were killed in the attack.  And Brent Renaud, a reporter on assignment with <i>Time Magazine</i>, was killed in a separate attack a day earlier.</p>
<p>I know that everyone in this room, in particular, feels these losses deeply.</p>
<p>Being a war correspondent is vital work; they make sure that the world knows what’s really happening when armies move in and bombs start falling.</p>
<p>It also takes incredible courage; they go into war zones when others, understandably, are heading out as fast as possible.</p>
<p>So these are huge losses, of course, for families, for friends, but also for their colleagues, their profession, their readers and viewers who understand world events because of them.</p>
<p>Our experts are in the process of documenting and evaluating potential war crimes being committed in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Beth Van Schaack, whom the Senate finally confirmed this week as our Ambassador at Large for Global Criminal Justice, will be leading that effort within the State Department.</p>
<p>We’ll make sure that our findings help international efforts to investigate war crimes and hold those responsible accountable.</p>
<p>I’d also mention that there are several other nominations before the Senate with a direct bearing on our ability to support Ukraine, including for Assistant Secretary of State for Population, Refugees, and Migration; Assistant Secretary of State for International Security and Non-Proliferation; and our Coordinator for Sanctions Policy.</p>
<p>So I urge the Senate to confirm these nominees quickly, so that they can get to work as soon as possible.</p>
<p>A few weeks ago, just days before Russia’s invasion began, I went to the United Nations Security Council to lay out what we believed was about to happen.</p>
<p>Again today, we have a strong sense of what Russia could do next.</p>
<p>We believe that Moscow may be setting the stage to use a chemical weapon, and then falsely blame Ukraine to justify escalating its attacks on the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p>Manufacturing events and creating false narratives of genocide to justify greater use of military force is a tactic that Russia has used before, including in Georgia.</p>
<p>We believe Russia will bring its mercenaries from private military groups and foreign countries to Ukraine.</p>
<p>President Putin acknowledged as much over the weekend when he authorized the recruitment of additional forces from the Middle East and elsewhere – another indication that his war effort is not going as he hoped it would.</p>
<p>They are also likely to systematically kidnap local officials and replace them with puppets.</p>
<p>Again, this has already begun.</p>
<p>The mayor of Melitopol was grabbed off the street several days ago, released yesterday in a prisoner exchange.</p>
<p>The mayor of another city in southern Ukraine was also kidnapped; he hasn’t yet been let go.</p>
<p>This is a terror tactic – grab local officials, depose local governments, put proxies in their place.</p>
<p>After devastating Ukrainian cities, Moscow may bring in officials from Russia to serve as local government officials, and surge what they describe as “economic support” in an attempt to make the people dependent on Moscow for survival.</p>
<p>Again, something that Russia did in Georgia.</p>
<p>President Putin’s invasion of Ukraine is not going to plan.</p>
<p>The Ukrainian people haven’t welcomed the Russian military.  They haven’t submitted.</p>
<p>On the contrary.  They’re fighting with extraordinary courage to protect their homes, their families, their country.</p>
<p>Russia has been hit by unprecedented sanctions and cut off from the global economy.</p>
<p>Its own economy is in free fall.</p>
<p>Hundreds of corporations have closed operations.</p>
<p>In a matter of weeks, President Putin has destroyed 30 years of opening to the world and economic opportunity for the Russian people.</p>
<p>Dozens of members of the Kremlin’s corrupt power base have been sanctioned; several have lost their mega yachts and villas.</p>
<p>President Putin has derided those sanctions, using recent public diatribes to mock Russians living abroad as too dependent, as he said, on “foie gras and oysters.”</p>
<p>Meanwhile, he sits in his mansions, having accumulated billions taking wealth from the Russian people, while they stand in long lines to access cash and watch as stores close and the ruble plummets in value.</p>
<p>It’s no wonder that brave Russians continue to protest the war and be beaten and arrested for it.</p>
<p>And Russian journalists are resigning from their jobs at state media outlets, because they can’t stomach parroting the Kremlin’s lies any longer.</p>
<p>Still, President Putin is not relenting and in fact may be growing more desperate.</p>
<p>And so yesterday, President Biden authorized – announced, excuse me, not authorized – another $800 million in military aid to Ukraine.</p>
<p>That brings our support for Ukraine’s frontline defenders to more than $2 billion during this administration – one billion in the last week alone.</p>
<p>We’re grateful to have a determined and generous partner in Congress, which this week provided more than $13 billion in urgent support to Ukraine.</p>
<p>And we’ll continue to work with lawmakers to support Ukraine and hold the Kremlin to account.</p>
<p>As President Biden described, this new security assistance package includes 800 anti-aircraft systems, to stop attacking planes and helicopters before they destroy more of Ukraine; 9,000 anti-armor systems to destroy tanks and armored vehicles; 7,000 small arms, including machine guns and grenade launchers; and 20 million rounds of ammunition.</p>
<p>We’re also helping Ukraine acquire longer-range anti-aircraft systems and munitions, at President Zelenskyy’s request.</p>
<p>And I have been in almost daily contact with Foreign Minister Kuleba, coordinating to respond swiftly to Ukraine’s most urgent needs.</p>
<p>Our allies and partners continue to step up with their own significant shipments of security assistance.</p>
<p>I’ve authorized more than a dozen countries to provide U.S.-origin equipment, and dozens more around the world have provided security assistance of their own.</p>
<p>I’d also note that, in addition to assistance from the Department of Defense, we’re sending support from other agencies, including $10 million worth of armored vehicles from our own Diplomatic Security Service.</p>
<p>And yesterday I announced another $186 million in humanitarian assistance to help the more than 3 million refugees who have fled Ukraine in the past three weeks – the fastest-growing refugee crisis in Europe since World War II – as well as internally displaced people still in Ukraine.</p>
<p>This brings our total humanitarian aid since last month to $293 million.</p>
<p>And of the more than $13 billion for Ukraine that Congress is putting forward, more than 4 billion of that will go to humanitarian assistance.</p>
<p>Ukraine’s neighbors in Europe are generously welcoming, supporting refugees.  The United States will do our part to help those governments and the humanitarian organizations on the ground meet this tremendous need.</p>
<p>All the steps that we and our allies and partners are taking are aimed at one goal: to end the war.</p>
<p>The support we’re providing Ukraine, as well as our financial and economic measures against Moscow, will strengthen Ukraine’s hand at the diplomatic table.</p>
<p>And we commend Ukraine for staying at that table and continuing to pursue diplomacy while the Kremlin’s brutal aggression continues.</p>
<p>We’ll support Ukraine’s diplomatic efforts however we can.</p>
<p>We continue to call on all nations, especially those with direct influence with Russia, to use whatever leverage they have to compel Moscow to end this war of choice.</p>
<p>We believe China in particular has a responsibility to use its influence with President Putin and to defend the international rules and principles that it professes to support.</p>
<p>Instead, it appears that China is moving in the opposite direction by refusing to condemn this aggression while seeking to portray itself as a neutral arbiter – and we’re concerned that they are considering directly assisting Russia with military equipment to use in Ukraine.</p>
<p>President Biden will be speaking to President Xi tomorrow and will make clear that China will bear responsibility for any actions it takes to support Russia’s aggression, and we will not hesitate to impose costs.</p>
<p>Let me close by saying that President Zelenskyy’s message to Congress and to the American people yesterday was incredibly powerful.</p>
<p>He’s asked for more help, which we are providing and will continue to provide.</p>
<p>And he said that the people of Ukraine want the same things for themselves that we want for ourselves – democracy, independence, freedom.</p>
<p>No one who’s watched the events of the past three weeks could ever doubt the depth of Ukraine’s commitment to these ideals.</p>
<p>We’ll continue to stand with Ukraine as it fights for its future.</p>
<p>We’ll continue to increase the costs on Russia until it ends this war of choice.</p>
<p>And we’ll continue to provide life-saving aid to the Ukrainian people as they endure the brutal consequences of Russia’s aggression.</p>
<p>With that, happy to take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Paul.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Sir, what do you think about the talks between Ukraine and Russia?  Are they making any progress?  President Zelenskyy seems to suggest there are things they are talking about.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So we’re in close contact, as I said, with Ukraine’s leaders, including in my case Foreign Minister Kuleba.  We’re in close contact with other countries that have, in one way or another, been engaging on diplomacy.</p>
<p>And to date I have to say, on the one hand, we commend Ukraine for being at the table, despite being under bombardment every minute of that day.  At the same time, I have not seen any meaningful efforts by Russia to bring this war that it’s perpetrating to a conclusion through diplomacy.</p>
<p>We support Ukraine’s efforts to try to de-escalate through diplomacy, to reach a ceasefire, and of course the withdrawal of Russian forces.  We appreciate the efforts of other countries, including France, Germany, Israel, Turkey, and others.  But again, from where I sit, diplomacy requires both sides engaging in good faith to de-escalate, and I don’t see signs right now that Putin is prepared to stop.</p>
<p>On the contrary, if you listen to, just for example, his most recent remarks yesterday, that suggests that he is moving in the opposite direction.  But never mind the words.   What we’re really focused on is actions, and the actions that we’re seeing Russia take every single day, virtually every minute of every day, are in total contrast to any serious diplomatic effort to end the war.</p>
<p>So we’re looking to see Russia take meaningful actions to de-escalate, to stop the violence that it’s perpetrating on Ukraine, and to engage in good-faith talks.  We will support any effort that Ukraine makes to do that.  We’re certainly doing everything we can to back them, but also to make sure that they have the strongest possible hand, if there are any real negotiations and if diplomacy does advance – hence the support that we’re giving to Ukraine as well as the pressure that we continue to put and even increase on Russia.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Kylie.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you, Secretary.  There is – this department is confirming that an American has died in Ukraine today, so I’m wondering if you can share any more with us about the circumstances, about who that person is, and if there’ll be specific consequences for Russia because an American died.</p>
<p>And then second, earlier this week you said on CNN that one way or another Ukraine will be there and at some point Putin won’t.  But we’re watching every day Ukrainians are getting killed; their cities are being demolished.  So how can you be so confident to say something like that?  And are you suggesting that Putin should be removed as the leader of Russia?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Kylie, first, with regard to the American citizen, I can confirm that an American citizen was killed.  I don&#8217;t have any more details for you than that, but I can confirm that.</p>
<p>Second, it is I think not only clear to me but clear to the world that an independent Ukraine will be there long after Vladimir Putin.  And it’s also clear that this could horrifically go on for some time.  But when all is said and done, an independent Ukraine will be there, and at some point Vladimir Putin will not.  The real question is how much death and destruction is going to occur in the meantime.  And we’re doing everything we can to bring this war, perpetrated by Russia, to the quickest possible end.  That’s where the support for Ukraine comes in; that’s where the pressure on Russia comes in; that’s where the work, the coordination that we’re doing with countries around the world comes in.</p>
<p>But I think the world has seen this.  The world has seen the absolute determination of the Ukrainian people to hold onto their country, to hold onto their future, to hold onto their freedom.  And there is nothing that Vladimir Putin can do to subjugate that to his will.  But as I said, this could go on for some time, and we’re going to continue to work to bring it to an end as quickly as we can.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And should Putin remain the leader of Russia?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Kylie, we’re going to try and move around.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, you described what you called Russia’s terror tactics.  Is the State Department considering designating Russia a state sponsor – excuse me – of terrorism?</p>
<p>And then second, everything that you described, the words that the President has used in recent days – war criminal, murderous dictator, pure thug – do you think that there can ever be normal relations between the United States and Russia so long as Vladimir Putin is in power?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So our focus first and foremost is on doing everything we can to help bring this war to a quick end, to stop the suffering of the Ukrainian people that’s the result of Russia’s aggression on Ukraine.  That’s our focus.  As we’re doing that, and as I said earlier, we’re also looking very carefully at what is happening, what is being done, and in particular looking at the question of whether war crimes are being committed.</p>
<p>And, among other things, the intentional targeting of civilians would constitute a war crime.  You heard President Biden speak to this yesterday.  You heard what I said a few minutes ago.  So we are documenting.  We welcome the efforts of various groups, institutions, organizations that focus on this to bring all of the evidence together, to continue to document things, and then for there to be accountability one way or the other.</p>
<p>In terms of other designations based on actions that Russia’s taking, we are and we will look at everything.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yulia Yarmolenko.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  On the second question?  I’m sorry.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I’m sorry, remind me.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  As long as Putin is in power, can there be normal relations between Russia and the United States?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Again, our focus is on ending this war.  I don’t want to speculate about the future, but there’s going to have to be, one way or another, accountability for this war of aggression.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yulia Yarmolenko, VOA Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  So on possible negotiations between Ukraine and Russia, if Russia agrees to stop attacks and withdraw its forces from Ukraine, are there any security formats that will guarantee that Russia would not renew its aggression against Ukraine?  If it’s not membership in NATO for Ukraine, then what?</p>
<p>And another question.  President Biden said that U.S. will accept Ukrainian refugees with open arms, and so far there is no official visa or other program for Ukrainians who are fleeing war or who want to come to the United States or reunite with their families.  Is Department of State working on some special expedited program for Ukrainian refugees?  And if yes, when it might be launched?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  First, on the diplomacy, look, I’m not going to speculate on the substance of any negotiations, where that might go.  As I said, we fully and strongly support whatever the Government of Ukraine – the democratically elected Government of Ukraine – does.  We very much welcome sentiments that we’ve heard expressed for trying to bring this to a diplomatic end as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>I think in the first instance what Ukraine needs is de-escalation.  It needs Russian forces out of Ukraine.  It needs to have its basic freedom and independence returned, but I leave it to Ukrainian partners to work on advancing the diplomacy if that’s – if they believe that can be productive.  We will look at whatever we can do to support that.</p>
<p>And if there are issues that wind up being negotiated that require in some fashion our participation, of course we will look at that and see where we can be helpful.  We want to be able in the first instance to do what we’re doing, which is to support the Government of Ukraine, the Ukrainian people, along with putting pressure on Russia.  If diplomacy finally carries the day and there are things that we can do to support that diplomacy and to support any outcomes that restore Ukraine’s independence, we will, of course, look at that and I’m sure do that.</p>
<p>With regard to refugees, a couple of things.  First, as I said, this is the largest refugee crisis in Europe since World War II.  The numbers are staggering.  And, of course, what gets lost sometimes behind these numbers are the real lives that are at stake and that are being changed, maybe not forever, but are being changed in profound ways.</p>
<p>I saw some of that firsthand when I was on the border between Poland and Ukraine with a number of you just a couple of weeks ago, talking to people who had made the journey across the border, looking for safety in the face of this Russian onslaught.  And in many cases – most cases, women and children – the men staying behind to fight.</p>
<p>And we see the impact, of course, in Ukraine.  We see the impact on neighboring countries – Poland, Moldova, Romania, others – that are taking in very large numbers of refugees.  The generosity I think is extraordinary.  But the numbers are growing.  The challenge is growing.  I was on a call, a video conference, this morning with our G7 partners, and this is one of the things that we talked about – having a coordinated approach to dealing with and helping refugees coming over.</p>
<p>The United States is already and will remain the largest provider of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  Part of the package that is in the supplemental includes about $4 billion in humanitarian assistance, and that will go both directly to Ukraine.  It will also go to neighboring countries and others – and Ukrainians outside of Ukraine – to support them.</p>
<p>Second, we are working closely with UNHCR to see how we can support this effort.</p>
<p>Finally, we’re looking at things that we can do ourselves and do directly – for example, looking at steps we may be able to take on family reunification and other things that we can do to be supportive and to really take part in this effort.</p>
<p>Last thing I’ll say is this:  What – and of course, there is the refugee referral process, but that takes time.  But if people apply for refugee status and seek to come to the United States, of course we will take referrals.  But we’re looking at steps that we can take in the near term.</p>
<p>Last thing is this:  I think what we’re seeing, at least initially, is that so many people coming out of Ukraine understandably want to stay close to home.  They hope – we hope – that they’ll be able to return home as soon as possible.  They also want to stay close to home because, as I said, in many cases it’s women and children who have left behind spouses, husbands, fathers, brothers, and they want to be reunited as quickly as possible, so they want to stay as close as possible.  But as this and if this goes on, as the numbers increase, as the burden increases for European partners, we will certainly do everything we can to help.  So I suspect we’ll have more to say on this in the coming – in the coming days.  It’s something we’re very focused on right now.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Time for one final, quick question from Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, you’ve outlined, recounted a litany of horrific attacks on civilians.  You’ve said you agree with the President’s comment that they’re war crimes, as the UN ambassador said last week.  I know there has to be an investigation, but where will the accountability be?  What should happen to Vladimir Putin if he is found guilty, since he is the state?  What should happen to this (inaudible)?  Tell the world.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So, Andrea, a few things.  First, we’re all seeing what – and you’re showing, powerfully, on television – these devastating images coming out of Ukraine, and we are seeing the destruction of so much of the country by Russian bombs, artillery.  We’re seeing civilian sites being devastated; we’re seeing people being killed – hundreds, thousands of people, civilians.  And yes, as I – again, as the President said yesterday, in his opinion, war crimes are being committed.  I agree with that.  After all the destruction that we’ve seen, it’s really hard to conclude otherwise.</p>
<p>But what we’re doing is this – and I’ll come to your question – we are in the first instance supporting the very important work that’s being done, the evidentiary process to bring the evidence together, to document what’s happened, to support and to work with human rights activists, with civil society, with independent media as well as with the appropriate organizations and institutions that look into this.  So we need to go through this process of compiling the evidence, collecting the evidence, understanding the evidence.  We’ll share that – and our allies and partners I’m sure will do the same with all of the investigations that are ongoing – to support accountability using every tool that we have available.</p>
<p>I’m not going to get ahead of, first of all, what the outcome will be or what the consequences will be, but I can say with conviction that there will be accountability for any war crimes that are determined to have occurred.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  How can you say that after Aleppo and Grozny?  He does it repeatedly.  He’s a repeat offender as a war criminal.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Andrea, when we said before Russia’s aggression that there would be massive consequences for that aggression, including unprecedented sanctions on Russia, I know some people had their doubts.  I think we’ve demonstrated that we’ve been good to our word.  When we said that there would be sustained, powerful support for Ukraine in its efforts to defend itself, we’ve demonstrated that we’re good to our word.  So when I tell you that there will be accountability and consequences for any war crimes that have been committed, I hope you’ll take me at my word, but actions always speak louder than words.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Thanks.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Press Briefing Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone.</p>
<p>Three weeks ago, Russia launched its unprovoked war on Ukraine.</p>
<p>With every day that passes, the numbers of civilians, including children, killed and wounded continues to climb.</p>
<p>Russia continues to attack civilian sites, including – this week alone – a hospital, three schools, a boarding school for visually impaired kids in the Luhansk region of Ukraine.</p>
<p>Yesterday Russian forces bombed a theater in Mariupol, where hundreds of people had been taking shelter.</p>
<p>The word “children” had been written in Russian in giant white letters on the pavement outside the building, so that you could know from the air that there were children inside.</p>
<p>Russian forces also opened fire on 10 civilians in who were waiting in line for bread.</p>
<p>These incidents join a long list of attacks on civilian – not military – locations across Ukraine, including apartment buildings, public squares, and, last week, a maternity hospital in Mariupol.</p>
<p>I doubt that any of us who saw those images will ever forget them.</p>
<p>We’ve seen Russia use similar tactics before in Grozny and Aleppo.  They stepped up their bombardment with the goal of breaking the will of the people.</p>
<p>Yesterday President Biden said that, in his opinion, war crimes have been committed in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Personally, I agree.</p>
<p>Intentionally targeting civilians is a war crime.</p>
<p>After all the destruction of the past three weeks, I find it difficult to conclude that the Russians are doing otherwise.</p>
<p>The consequences of Moscow’s war are being felt around the world – in rising food costs, concerns about fuel supplies, more broadly in worries about how this war will affect the global economy and the fight against COVID-19.</p>
<p>These are serious issues that the global community urgently needs to address.  This war is making that much more difficult.</p>
<p>In this way, Russia’s actions are having an impact on every person on the planet, wherever they live.</p>
<p>We also feel the impact right here in this room.</p>
<p>There should be a seat reserved here today for Benjamin Hall from Fox News, who was injured badly when his vehicle came under attack near Kyiv.</p>
<p>Many of us, myself included, have gotten to know Ben very well as part of the traveling press corps.</p>
<p>He’s an incredibly talented reporter, always asking tough questions.  He’s a lovely person, as well.</p>
<p>Our thoughts – my thoughts – are with him and his family, including his three little kids.</p>
<p>Two of Ben’s Fox News colleagues, Pierre Zokchefski and Sasha Koofshenova, were killed in the attack.  And Brent Renaud, a reporter on assignment with <i>Time Magazine</i>, was killed in a separate attack a day earlier.</p>
<p>I know that everyone in this room, in particular, feels these losses deeply.</p>
<p>Being a war correspondent is vital work; they make sure that the world knows what’s really happening when armies move in and bombs start falling.</p>
<p>It also takes incredible courage; they go into war zones when others, understandably, are heading out as fast as possible.</p>
<p>So these are huge losses, of course, for families, for friends, but also for their colleagues, their profession, their readers and viewers who understand world events because of them.</p>
<p>Our experts are in the process of documenting and evaluating potential war crimes being committed in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Beth Van Schaack, whom the Senate finally confirmed this week as our Ambassador at Large for Global Criminal Justice, will be leading that effort within the State Department.</p>
<p>We’ll make sure that our findings help international efforts to investigate war crimes and hold those responsible accountable.</p>
<p>I’d also mention that there are several other nominations before the Senate with a direct bearing on our ability to support Ukraine, including for Assistant Secretary of State for Population, Refugees, and Migration; Assistant Secretary of State for International Security and Non-Proliferation; and our Coordinator for Sanctions Policy.</p>
<p>So I urge the Senate to confirm these nominees quickly, so that they can get to work as soon as possible.</p>
<p>A few weeks ago, just days before Russia’s invasion began, I went to the United Nations Security Council to lay out what we believed was about to happen.</p>
<p>Again today, we have a strong sense of what Russia could do next.</p>
<p>We believe that Moscow may be setting the stage to use a chemical weapon, and then falsely blame Ukraine to justify escalating its attacks on the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p>Manufacturing events and creating false narratives of genocide to justify greater use of military force is a tactic that Russia has used before, including in Georgia.</p>
<p>We believe Russia will bring its mercenaries from private military groups and foreign countries to Ukraine.</p>
<p>President Putin acknowledged as much over the weekend when he authorized the recruitment of additional forces from the Middle East and elsewhere – another indication that his war effort is not going as he hoped it would.</p>
<p>They are also likely to systematically kidnap local officials and replace them with puppets.</p>
<p>Again, this has already begun.</p>
<p>The mayor of Melitopol was grabbed off the street several days ago, released yesterday in a prisoner exchange.</p>
<p>The mayor of another city in southern Ukraine was also kidnapped; he hasn’t yet been let go.</p>
<p>This is a terror tactic – grab local officials, depose local governments, put proxies in their place.</p>
<p>After devastating Ukrainian cities, Moscow may bring in officials from Russia to serve as local government officials, and surge what they describe as “economic support” in an attempt to make the people dependent on Moscow for survival.</p>
<p>Again, something that Russia did in Georgia.</p>
<p>President Putin’s invasion of Ukraine is not going to plan.</p>
<p>The Ukrainian people haven’t welcomed the Russian military.  They haven’t submitted.</p>
<p>On the contrary.  They’re fighting with extraordinary courage to protect their homes, their families, their country.</p>
<p>Russia has been hit by unprecedented sanctions and cut off from the global economy.</p>
<p>Its own economy is in free fall.</p>
<p>Hundreds of corporations have closed operations.</p>
<p>In a matter of weeks, President Putin has destroyed 30 years of opening to the world and economic opportunity for the Russian people.</p>
<p>Dozens of members of the Kremlin’s corrupt power base have been sanctioned; several have lost their mega yachts and villas.</p>
<p>President Putin has derided those sanctions, using recent public diatribes to mock Russians living abroad as too dependent, as he said, on “foie gras and oysters.”</p>
<p>Meanwhile, he sits in his mansions, having accumulated billions taking wealth from the Russian people, while they stand in long lines to access cash and watch as stores close and the ruble plummets in value.</p>
<p>It’s no wonder that brave Russians continue to protest the war and be beaten and arrested for it.</p>
<p>And Russian journalists are resigning from their jobs at state media outlets, because they can’t stomach parroting the Kremlin’s lies any longer.</p>
<p>Still, President Putin is not relenting and in fact may be growing more desperate.</p>
<p>And so yesterday, President Biden authorized – announced, excuse me, not authorized – another $800 million in military aid to Ukraine.</p>
<p>That brings our support for Ukraine’s frontline defenders to more than $2 billion during this administration – one billion in the last week alone.</p>
<p>We’re grateful to have a determined and generous partner in Congress, which this week provided more than $13 billion in urgent support to Ukraine.</p>
<p>And we’ll continue to work with lawmakers to support Ukraine and hold the Kremlin to account.</p>
<p>As President Biden described, this new security assistance package includes 800 anti-aircraft systems, to stop attacking planes and helicopters before they destroy more of Ukraine; 9,000 anti-armor systems to destroy tanks and armored vehicles; 7,000 small arms, including machine guns and grenade launchers; and 20 million rounds of ammunition.</p>
<p>We’re also helping Ukraine acquire longer-range anti-aircraft systems and munitions, at President Zelenskyy’s request.</p>
<p>And I have been in almost daily contact with Foreign Minister Kuleba, coordinating to respond swiftly to Ukraine’s most urgent needs.</p>
<p>Our allies and partners continue to step up with their own significant shipments of security assistance.</p>
<p>I’ve authorized more than a dozen countries to provide U.S.-origin equipment, and dozens more around the world have provided security assistance of their own.</p>
<p>I’d also note that, in addition to assistance from the Department of Defense, we’re sending support from other agencies, including $10 million worth of armored vehicles from our own Diplomatic Security Service.</p>
<p>And yesterday I announced another $186 million in humanitarian assistance to help the more than 3 million refugees who have fled Ukraine in the past three weeks – the fastest-growing refugee crisis in Europe since World War II – as well as internally displaced people still in Ukraine.</p>
<p>This brings our total humanitarian aid since last month to $293 million.</p>
<p>And of the more than $13 billion for Ukraine that Congress is putting forward, more than 4 billion of that will go to humanitarian assistance.</p>
<p>Ukraine’s neighbors in Europe are generously welcoming, supporting refugees.  The United States will do our part to help those governments and the humanitarian organizations on the ground meet this tremendous need.</p>
<p>All the steps that we and our allies and partners are taking are aimed at one goal: to end the war.</p>
<p>The support we’re providing Ukraine, as well as our financial and economic measures against Moscow, will strengthen Ukraine’s hand at the diplomatic table.</p>
<p>And we commend Ukraine for staying at that table and continuing to pursue diplomacy while the Kremlin’s brutal aggression continues.</p>
<p>We’ll support Ukraine’s diplomatic efforts however we can.</p>
<p>We continue to call on all nations, especially those with direct influence with Russia, to use whatever leverage they have to compel Moscow to end this war of choice.</p>
<p>We believe China in particular has a responsibility to use its influence with President Putin and to defend the international rules and principles that it professes to support.</p>
<p>Instead, it appears that China is moving in the opposite direction by refusing to condemn this aggression while seeking to portray itself as a neutral arbiter – and we’re concerned that they are considering directly assisting Russia with military equipment to use in Ukraine.</p>
<p>President Biden will be speaking to President Xi tomorrow and will make clear that China will bear responsibility for any actions it takes to support Russia’s aggression, and we will not hesitate to impose costs.</p>
<p>Let me close by saying that President Zelenskyy’s message to Congress and to the American people yesterday was incredibly powerful.</p>
<p>He’s asked for more help, which we are providing and will continue to provide.</p>
<p>And he said that the people of Ukraine want the same things for themselves that we want for ourselves – democracy, independence, freedom.</p>
<p>No one who’s watched the events of the past three weeks could ever doubt the depth of Ukraine’s commitment to these ideals.</p>
<p>We’ll continue to stand with Ukraine as it fights for its future.</p>
<p>We’ll continue to increase the costs on Russia until it ends this war of choice.</p>
<p>And we’ll continue to provide life-saving aid to the Ukrainian people as they endure the brutal consequences of Russia’s aggression.</p>
<p>With that, happy to take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Paul.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Sir, what do you think about the talks between Ukraine and Russia?  Are they making any progress?  President Zelenskyy seems to suggest there are things they are talking about.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So we’re in close contact, as I said, with Ukraine’s leaders, including in my case Foreign Minister Kuleba.  We’re in close contact with other countries that have, in one way or another, been engaging on diplomacy.</p>
<p>And to date I have to say, on the one hand, we commend Ukraine for being at the table, despite being under bombardment every minute of that day.  At the same time, I have not seen any meaningful efforts by Russia to bring this war that it’s perpetrating to a conclusion through diplomacy.</p>
<p>We support Ukraine’s efforts to try to de-escalate through diplomacy, to reach a ceasefire, and of course the withdrawal of Russian forces.  We appreciate the efforts of other countries, including France, Germany, Israel, Turkey, and others.  But again, from where I sit, diplomacy requires both sides engaging in good faith to de-escalate, and I don’t see signs right now that Putin is prepared to stop.</p>
<p>On the contrary, if you listen to, just for example, his most recent remarks yesterday, that suggests that he is moving in the opposite direction.  But never mind the words.   What we’re really focused on is actions, and the actions that we’re seeing Russia take every single day, virtually every minute of every day, are in total contrast to any serious diplomatic effort to end the war.</p>
<p>So we’re looking to see Russia take meaningful actions to de-escalate, to stop the violence that it’s perpetrating on Ukraine, and to engage in good-faith talks.  We will support any effort that Ukraine makes to do that.  We’re certainly doing everything we can to back them, but also to make sure that they have the strongest possible hand, if there are any real negotiations and if diplomacy does advance – hence the support that we’re giving to Ukraine as well as the pressure that we continue to put and even increase on Russia.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Kylie.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you, Secretary.  There is – this department is confirming that an American has died in Ukraine today, so I’m wondering if you can share any more with us about the circumstances, about who that person is, and if there’ll be specific consequences for Russia because an American died.</p>
<p>And then second, earlier this week you said on CNN that one way or another Ukraine will be there and at some point Putin won’t.  But we’re watching every day Ukrainians are getting killed; their cities are being demolished.  So how can you be so confident to say something like that?  And are you suggesting that Putin should be removed as the leader of Russia?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Kylie, first, with regard to the American citizen, I can confirm that an American citizen was killed.  I don&#8217;t have any more details for you than that, but I can confirm that.</p>
<p>Second, it is I think not only clear to me but clear to the world that an independent Ukraine will be there long after Vladimir Putin.  And it’s also clear that this could horrifically go on for some time.  But when all is said and done, an independent Ukraine will be there, and at some point Vladimir Putin will not.  The real question is how much death and destruction is going to occur in the meantime.  And we’re doing everything we can to bring this war, perpetrated by Russia, to the quickest possible end.  That’s where the support for Ukraine comes in; that’s where the pressure on Russia comes in; that’s where the work, the coordination that we’re doing with countries around the world comes in.</p>
<p>But I think the world has seen this.  The world has seen the absolute determination of the Ukrainian people to hold onto their country, to hold onto their future, to hold onto their freedom.  And there is nothing that Vladimir Putin can do to subjugate that to his will.  But as I said, this could go on for some time, and we’re going to continue to work to bring it to an end as quickly as we can.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And should Putin remain the leader of Russia?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Kylie, we’re going to try and move around.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, you described what you called Russia’s terror tactics.  Is the State Department considering designating Russia a state sponsor – excuse me – of terrorism?</p>
<p>And then second, everything that you described, the words that the President has used in recent days – war criminal, murderous dictator, pure thug – do you think that there can ever be normal relations between the United States and Russia so long as Vladimir Putin is in power?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So our focus first and foremost is on doing everything we can to help bring this war to a quick end, to stop the suffering of the Ukrainian people that’s the result of Russia’s aggression on Ukraine.  That’s our focus.  As we’re doing that, and as I said earlier, we’re also looking very carefully at what is happening, what is being done, and in particular looking at the question of whether war crimes are being committed.</p>
<p>And, among other things, the intentional targeting of civilians would constitute a war crime.  You heard President Biden speak to this yesterday.  You heard what I said a few minutes ago.  So we are documenting.  We welcome the efforts of various groups, institutions, organizations that focus on this to bring all of the evidence together, to continue to document things, and then for there to be accountability one way or the other.</p>
<p>In terms of other designations based on actions that Russia’s taking, we are and we will look at everything.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yulia Yarmolenko.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  On the second question?  I’m sorry.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I’m sorry, remind me.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  As long as Putin is in power, can there be normal relations between Russia and the United States?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Again, our focus is on ending this war.  I don’t want to speculate about the future, but there’s going to have to be, one way or another, accountability for this war of aggression.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yulia Yarmolenko, VOA Ukraine.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  So on possible negotiations between Ukraine and Russia, if Russia agrees to stop attacks and withdraw its forces from Ukraine, are there any security formats that will guarantee that Russia would not renew its aggression against Ukraine?  If it’s not membership in NATO for Ukraine, then what?</p>
<p>And another question.  President Biden said that U.S. will accept Ukrainian refugees with open arms, and so far there is no official visa or other program for Ukrainians who are fleeing war or who want to come to the United States or reunite with their families.  Is Department of State working on some special expedited program for Ukrainian refugees?  And if yes, when it might be launched?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  First, on the diplomacy, look, I’m not going to speculate on the substance of any negotiations, where that might go.  As I said, we fully and strongly support whatever the Government of Ukraine – the democratically elected Government of Ukraine – does.  We very much welcome sentiments that we’ve heard expressed for trying to bring this to a diplomatic end as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>I think in the first instance what Ukraine needs is de-escalation.  It needs Russian forces out of Ukraine.  It needs to have its basic freedom and independence returned, but I leave it to Ukrainian partners to work on advancing the diplomacy if that’s – if they believe that can be productive.  We will look at whatever we can do to support that.</p>
<p>And if there are issues that wind up being negotiated that require in some fashion our participation, of course we will look at that and see where we can be helpful.  We want to be able in the first instance to do what we’re doing, which is to support the Government of Ukraine, the Ukrainian people, along with putting pressure on Russia.  If diplomacy finally carries the day and there are things that we can do to support that diplomacy and to support any outcomes that restore Ukraine’s independence, we will, of course, look at that and I’m sure do that.</p>
<p>With regard to refugees, a couple of things.  First, as I said, this is the largest refugee crisis in Europe since World War II.  The numbers are staggering.  And, of course, what gets lost sometimes behind these numbers are the real lives that are at stake and that are being changed, maybe not forever, but are being changed in profound ways.</p>
<p>I saw some of that firsthand when I was on the border between Poland and Ukraine with a number of you just a couple of weeks ago, talking to people who had made the journey across the border, looking for safety in the face of this Russian onslaught.  And in many cases – most cases, women and children – the men staying behind to fight.</p>
<p>And we see the impact, of course, in Ukraine.  We see the impact on neighboring countries – Poland, Moldova, Romania, others – that are taking in very large numbers of refugees.  The generosity I think is extraordinary.  But the numbers are growing.  The challenge is growing.  I was on a call, a video conference, this morning with our G7 partners, and this is one of the things that we talked about – having a coordinated approach to dealing with and helping refugees coming over.</p>
<p>The United States is already and will remain the largest provider of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  Part of the package that is in the supplemental includes about $4 billion in humanitarian assistance, and that will go both directly to Ukraine.  It will also go to neighboring countries and others – and Ukrainians outside of Ukraine – to support them.</p>
<p>Second, we are working closely with UNHCR to see how we can support this effort.</p>
<p>Finally, we’re looking at things that we can do ourselves and do directly – for example, looking at steps we may be able to take on family reunification and other things that we can do to be supportive and to really take part in this effort.</p>
<p>Last thing I’ll say is this:  What – and of course, there is the refugee referral process, but that takes time.  But if people apply for refugee status and seek to come to the United States, of course we will take referrals.  But we’re looking at steps that we can take in the near term.</p>
<p>Last thing is this:  I think what we’re seeing, at least initially, is that so many people coming out of Ukraine understandably want to stay close to home.  They hope – we hope – that they’ll be able to return home as soon as possible.  They also want to stay close to home because, as I said, in many cases it’s women and children who have left behind spouses, husbands, fathers, brothers, and they want to be reunited as quickly as possible, so they want to stay as close as possible.  But as this and if this goes on, as the numbers increase, as the burden increases for European partners, we will certainly do everything we can to help.  So I suspect we’ll have more to say on this in the coming – in the coming days.  It’s something we’re very focused on right now.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Time for one final, quick question from Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, you’ve outlined, recounted a litany of horrific attacks on civilians.  You’ve said you agree with the President’s comment that they’re war crimes, as the UN ambassador said last week.  I know there has to be an investigation, but where will the accountability be?  What should happen to Vladimir Putin if he is found guilty, since he is the state?  What should happen to this (inaudible)?  Tell the world.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So, Andrea, a few things.  First, we’re all seeing what – and you’re showing, powerfully, on television – these devastating images coming out of Ukraine, and we are seeing the destruction of so much of the country by Russian bombs, artillery.  We’re seeing civilian sites being devastated; we’re seeing people being killed – hundreds, thousands of people, civilians.  And yes, as I – again, as the President said yesterday, in his opinion, war crimes are being committed.  I agree with that.  After all the destruction that we’ve seen, it’s really hard to conclude otherwise.</p>
<p>But what we’re doing is this – and I’ll come to your question – we are in the first instance supporting the very important work that’s being done, the evidentiary process to bring the evidence together, to document what’s happened, to support and to work with human rights activists, with civil society, with independent media as well as with the appropriate organizations and institutions that look into this.  So we need to go through this process of compiling the evidence, collecting the evidence, understanding the evidence.  We’ll share that – and our allies and partners I’m sure will do the same with all of the investigations that are ongoing – to support accountability using every tool that we have available.</p>
<p>I’m not going to get ahead of, first of all, what the outcome will be or what the consequences will be, but I can say with conviction that there will be accountability for any war crimes that are determined to have occurred.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  How can you say that after Aleppo and Grozny?  He does it repeatedly.  He’s a repeat offender as a war criminal.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Andrea, when we said before Russia’s aggression that there would be massive consequences for that aggression, including unprecedented sanctions on Russia, I know some people had their doubts.  I think we’ve demonstrated that we’ve been good to our word.  When we said that there would be sustained, powerful support for Ukraine in its efforts to defend itself, we’ve demonstrated that we’re good to our word.  So when I tell you that there will be accountability and consequences for any war crimes that have been committed, I hope you’ll take me at my word, but actions always speak louder than words.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Thanks.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Qatari Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Foreign Affairs Al-Thani</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-qatari-deputy-prime-minister-and-minister-of-foreign-affairs-al-thani-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 16:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325460</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke yesterday with Qatari Minister of Foreign Affairs Mohammed bin Abdulrahman Al-Thani.  Secretary Blinken affirmed that the United States and Qatar are united in their efforts to provide humanitarian assistance to the Ukrainian people. The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Qatar’s continued support for Ukraine’s sovereignty.  The two also discussed Afghanistan and other important regional issues.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke yesterday with Qatari Minister of Foreign Affairs Mohammed bin Abdulrahman Al-Thani.  Secretary Blinken affirmed that the United States and Qatar are united in their efforts to provide humanitarian assistance to the Ukrainian people. The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Qatar’s continued support for Ukraine’s sovereignty.  The two also discussed Afghanistan and other important regional issues.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States Shares 500 Million COVID-19 Vaccine Doses Worldwide</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-shares-500-million-covid-19-vaccine-doses-worldwide/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 11:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States has now shared over 500 million safe and effective COVID-19 vaccine doses, free of cost, to more than 110 countries and economies around the world – for the sole purpose of saving lives.</p>
<p>Since the start of the pandemic, we have provided nearly $20 billion in health, humanitarian, economic, and development assistance to over 120 countries, including rapid response support for urgent health needs and technical assistance to expand vaccine access.  We have also invested and supported the expansion of regional COVID-19 vaccine manufacturing in Africa and Asia. Today, we continue to work tirelessly with governments and international organizations, vaccine producers, NGOs, the private sector, and others to deliver vaccines, get shots in arms, increase testing and treatment, support and protect healthcare workers, and more.  Our recently announced <a href="https://www.state.gov/the-covid-19-global-action-meeting/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMTcuNTUwMzcyNzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvdGhlLWNvdmlkLTE5LWdsb2JhbC1hY3Rpb24tbWVldGluZy8ifQ.gIFO23O6JBG30mThVQJIkcGcNXxqG57hpbhHnVFpxrs/s/2171565732/br/128251539481-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1647601262513000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1P4JH42BRHaT8S00Aveyqv">COVID-19 Global Action Plan</a> provides a clear roadmap for this international coordination.</p>
<p>Our work is making a difference around the world.</p>
<p>In Paraguay, our donation of two million Pfizer vaccine doses were quickly administered.  The government set up a mass vaccination site based on a U.S. model and administered 500,000 doses within a week.  In Zambia, the President’s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR) used American Rescue Plan Act funds to support the administration of nearly two million COVID-19 vaccines through more than 500 health facilities across Zambia’s 10 provinces as part of its work to combat HIV/AIDS.</p>
<p>In addition, a State Department grant helped Alfred Kankuzi in Malawi build his own app to respond to the rapid spread of misinformation and disinformation across social media.  Called COVID-19 NEBA, or “Hey Neighbor,” the app is offered in three languages – Chichewa, Tumbuka, and English – and increases access to fact-based information from trusted sources including U.S. Centers for Disease Control, World Health Organization, and Malawi’s Ministry of Health.  Alfred has helped over 648,000 fellow citizens access accurate COVID-19 information.</p>
<p>In Thailand, State Department exchange alumni used a small grant to support Chiang Dao residents in the Chiang Mai Province.  Alumni joined community organizations to create visual and audio media in seven local languages on COVID-19 prevention best practices, collaborated with public health officials to conduct COVID-19 prevention workshops for village health volunteers, and provided effective communication tools and techniques to village leaders to help residents stay updated on COVID-19 – reaching more than 70,000 people.</p>
<p>This work is critical because this pandemic is not over.  Many lives are still at risk globally as countries contend with Omicron and we face the possibility of new variants.  The United States will continue to work with partners and communities at every level to save lives and better prepare for future pandemics.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States has now shared over 500 million safe and effective COVID-19 vaccine doses, free of cost, to more than 110 countries and economies around the world – for the sole purpose of saving lives.</p>
<p>Since the start of the pandemic, we have provided nearly $20 billion in health, humanitarian, economic, and development assistance to over 120 countries, including rapid response support for urgent health needs and technical assistance to expand vaccine access.  We have also invested and supported the expansion of regional COVID-19 vaccine manufacturing in Africa and Asia. Today, we continue to work tirelessly with governments and international organizations, vaccine producers, NGOs, the private sector, and others to deliver vaccines, get shots in arms, increase testing and treatment, support and protect healthcare workers, and more.  Our recently announced <a href="https://www.state.gov/the-covid-19-global-action-meeting/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMTcuNTUwMzcyNzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvdGhlLWNvdmlkLTE5LWdsb2JhbC1hY3Rpb24tbWVldGluZy8ifQ.gIFO23O6JBG30mThVQJIkcGcNXxqG57hpbhHnVFpxrs/s/2171565732/br/128251539481-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1647601262513000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1P4JH42BRHaT8S00Aveyqv">COVID-19 Global Action Plan</a> provides a clear roadmap for this international coordination.</p>
<p>Our work is making a difference around the world.</p>
<p>In Paraguay, our donation of two million Pfizer vaccine doses were quickly administered.  The government set up a mass vaccination site based on a U.S. model and administered 500,000 doses within a week.  In Zambia, the President’s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR) used American Rescue Plan Act funds to support the administration of nearly two million COVID-19 vaccines through more than 500 health facilities across Zambia’s 10 provinces as part of its work to combat HIV/AIDS.</p>
<p>In addition, a State Department grant helped Alfred Kankuzi in Malawi build his own app to respond to the rapid spread of misinformation and disinformation across social media.  Called COVID-19 NEBA, or “Hey Neighbor,” the app is offered in three languages – Chichewa, Tumbuka, and English – and increases access to fact-based information from trusted sources including U.S. Centers for Disease Control, World Health Organization, and Malawi’s Ministry of Health.  Alfred has helped over 648,000 fellow citizens access accurate COVID-19 information.</p>
<p>In Thailand, State Department exchange alumni used a small grant to support Chiang Dao residents in the Chiang Mai Province.  Alumni joined community organizations to create visual and audio media in seven local languages on COVID-19 prevention best practices, collaborated with public health officials to conduct COVID-19 prevention workshops for village health volunteers, and provided effective communication tools and techniques to village leaders to help residents stay updated on COVID-19 – reaching more than 70,000 people.</p>
<p>This work is critical because this pandemic is not over.  Many lives are still at risk globally as countries contend with Omicron and we face the possibility of new variants.  The United States will continue to work with partners and communities at every level to save lives and better prepare for future pandemics.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On the Occasion of St. Patrick’s Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/on-the-occasion-of-st-patricks-day-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 04:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325159</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I extend warm wishes to the people of Ireland for a joyful, healthy, and hopeful St. Patrick’s Day.</p>
<p>Each March 17, people from Ireland, the United States, and around the world celebrate the Emerald Isle’s rich heritage and culture.  Today and every day, the United States and Ireland cooperate closely on a number of critical issues.  We work together to strengthen global health security, increase our shared prosperity, combat climate change, advance democratic values, and respond to authoritarian threats.  We welcome Ireland’s continued leadership and look forward to many years ahead of deep collaboration and partnership.</p>
<p>As the United States and Ireland continue our important work together, may all enjoy a safe and happy St. Patrick’s Day.  Lá Fhéile Pádraig sona daoibh!</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I extend warm wishes to the people of Ireland for a joyful, healthy, and hopeful St. Patrick’s Day.</p>
<p>Each March 17, people from Ireland, the United States, and around the world celebrate the Emerald Isle’s rich heritage and culture.  Today and every day, the United States and Ireland cooperate closely on a number of critical issues.  We work together to strengthen global health security, increase our shared prosperity, combat climate change, advance democratic values, and respond to authoritarian threats.  We welcome Ireland’s continued leadership and look forward to many years ahead of deep collaboration and partnership.</p>
<p>As the United States and Ireland continue our important work together, may all enjoy a safe and happy St. Patrick’s Day.  Lá Fhéile Pádraig sona daoibh!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcoming the International Court of Justice’s Order Directing the Russian Federation to Immediately Suspend Military Operations in Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/welcoming-the-international-court-of-justices-order-directing-the-russian-federation-to-immediately-suspend-military-operations-in-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325216</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The International Court of Justice today issued a significant ruling in Ukraine’s case against the Russian Federation under the Convention on the Prevention and Punishment of the Crime of Genocide. The ruling clearly and unequivocally ordered Russia to immediately suspend the military operations Russia commenced last month and further directed Russia to ensure that anyone subject to its direction, including military or irregular armed units, take no steps in furtherance of such military operations.</p>
<p>The Court – which plays a vital role in the peaceful settlement of disputes under the UN Charter – stressed the need for States to act in conformity with their obligations under international law, including the laws of war.  And the Court expressed deep concern about the extreme vulnerability of the civilian population of Ukraine, the numerous civilian deaths and injuries that have resulted from the Kremlin’s actions, and the significant material damage, including the destruction of buildings and infrastructure.  The Court further noted its profound concern with the Russian government’s use of force and emphasized the Court’s acute awareness of “the extent of the human tragedy that is taking place in Ukraine” as well as the “continuing loss of life and human suffering.”  The Court also observed that it did not possess any evidence substantiating Russia’s claims that genocide had been committed by Ukraine in the Donbas region.</p>
<p>We welcome the Court’s order and call on the Russian Federation to comply with the order, immediately cease its military operations in Ukraine, and to establish unhindered humanitarian access in Ukraine.</p>
<p>The United States will continue to act with our allies and partners in support of Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The International Court of Justice today issued a significant ruling in Ukraine’s case against the Russian Federation under the Convention on the Prevention and Punishment of the Crime of Genocide. The ruling clearly and unequivocally ordered Russia to immediately suspend the military operations Russia commenced last month and further directed Russia to ensure that anyone subject to its direction, including military or irregular armed units, take no steps in furtherance of such military operations.</p>
<p>The Court – which plays a vital role in the peaceful settlement of disputes under the UN Charter – stressed the need for States to act in conformity with their obligations under international law, including the laws of war.  And the Court expressed deep concern about the extreme vulnerability of the civilian population of Ukraine, the numerous civilian deaths and injuries that have resulted from the Kremlin’s actions, and the significant material damage, including the destruction of buildings and infrastructure.  The Court further noted its profound concern with the Russian government’s use of force and emphasized the Court’s acute awareness of “the extent of the human tragedy that is taking place in Ukraine” as well as the “continuing loss of life and human suffering.”  The Court also observed that it did not possess any evidence substantiating Russia’s claims that genocide had been committed by Ukraine in the Donbas region.</p>
<p>We welcome the Court’s order and call on the Russian Federation to comply with the order, immediately cease its military operations in Ukraine, and to establish unhindered humanitarian access in Ukraine.</p>
<p>The United States will continue to act with our allies and partners in support of Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Additional Visa Restrictions for Undermining the Democratic Process in Somalia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/additional-visa-restrictions-for-undermining-the-democratic-process-in-somalia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 23:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=325208</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Following the government of Somalia’s failure to meet another self-established deadline of March 15 for the completion of its parliamentary electoral process, the United States is expanding the number of Somali individuals subject to visa restrictions.</p>
<p>I am taking this action pursuant to a policy I announced on February 8, under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, to restrict the issuance of visas for those believed to be responsible for, or complicit in, undermining the democratic process in Somalia.</p>
<p>While encouraging progress has been made over the past few weeks, there are still more than three dozen unfilled parliamentary seats.  There are continued credible reports of procedural irregularities.  Journalists and opposition party members working to support democratic institutions and transparent processes have been targeted with harassment, intimidation, arrest, and violence.</p>
<p>We will continue to evaluate additional designations under this policy and other tools at our disposal to promote accountability and support the rapid conclusion of Somalia’s electoral process in a credible and transparent manner.</p>
<p>The United States strongly supports the Somali people and remains committed to working to advance democracy and mutual prosperity.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Following the government of Somalia’s failure to meet another self-established deadline of March 15 for the completion of its parliamentary electoral process, the United States is expanding the number of Somali individuals subject to visa restrictions.</p>
<p>I am taking this action pursuant to a policy I announced on February 8, under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, to restrict the issuance of visas for those believed to be responsible for, or complicit in, undermining the democratic process in Somalia.</p>
<p>While encouraging progress has been made over the past few weeks, there are still more than three dozen unfilled parliamentary seats.  There are continued credible reports of procedural irregularities.  Journalists and opposition party members working to support democratic institutions and transparent processes have been targeted with harassment, intimidation, arrest, and violence.</p>
<p>We will continue to evaluate additional designations under this policy and other tools at our disposal to promote accountability and support the rapid conclusion of Somalia’s electoral process in a credible and transparent manner.</p>
<p>The United States strongly supports the Somali people and remains committed to working to advance democracy and mutual prosperity.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
