<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 18:36:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-european-commission-president-ursula-von-der-leyen-before-their-meeting-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 18:36:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320825</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>European Commission</p>
<p><b>PRESIDENT VON DER LEYEN:  </b>So Secretary of State Blinken, dear Tony, a very warm welcome.  I’m very glad to have you again here in Berlaymont.  Your visit to Europe illustrates how very close the cooperation is between the European Union and the United States in response to Putin’s reckless invasion of Ukraine.  And thanks to this coordination, we have together designed, developed, and deployed sanctions in record time, sanctions that demonstrate our determination to make Putin pay a price for his war.</p>
<p>We do not take these measures lightly, but it is clear we need to act.  And with these measures, the central bank cannot use a significant share of its reserves to defend the ruble, now in free fall.  The central bank has had to raise interest rates by 20 percent, stoking inflation.  Significant commercial banks are cut off from global markets and from SWIFT, curtailing their ability to finance the economy.  The stock exchange in Moscow remains closed since the beginning of this week.  One after another, Western companies announced their own measures stopping production, investment, and sales.</p>
<p>The European Union and the U.S. cooperation is at the core of this effective response, and it has pulled together an ever-growing number of countries that apply identical or similar sanctions – our G7 partners, UK, Canada, and Japan, but also countries like Norway, Switzerland, South Korea, Australia, by now over 40 countries partially or completely aligned with our sanctions.  And this is testimony to the determination of the global community to reject this invasion.  One only needs to see the result of this week’s United Nations General Assembly: 141 countries, an overwhelming majority, supported the resolution condemning Russia for its brutal invasion.  Only four countries out of 193 stood by Russia.  It was Belarus, North Korea, Syria, and Eritrea.</p>
<p>President Putin is increasingly isolated in the world community, but in the face of the world’s protests, Putin’s army carries on.  Bombings and missile attacks on civilian targets are intensifying.  Rest assured the European Union and the United States will continue to stand by Ukraine and its courageous people and its steadfast leadership.</p>
<p>The scale of the humanitarian catastrophe that – in Ukraine that is unfolding really worries us.  Europe is seeing destruction and displacement on a scale not seen since the darkest days of the last century.  The European Union, as Ukraine’s neighbor, is sparing no effort.  We’re providing 500 million euros of humanitarian aid immediately, and more will come.  We’re working fast to establish civil protection hubs in Poland, in Slovakia, and in Romania.  And we are also doing everything we can with international organizations and NGOs to set up humanitarian corridors that stretch inside Ukraine.  Desperately needed humanitarian aid must be able to reach all parts of Ukraine and civilians must be allowed to escape cities under siege.</p>
<p>Finally, the European Union has triggered for the first time ever the so-called Temporary Protection Directive.  What is it?  It effectively opens up residency rights for most refugees to live and work in the European Union, to have access to health services or, for example, schools for at least a year.</p>
<p>We know that this conflict is far from over, and to be very clear, we are ready to take further severe measures if Putin does not stop and reverse the war he has unleashed.  We’re determined, we’re united, and it’s a pleasure to have you here, dear Tony.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Madam President, Ursula, thank you.  A short while ago we were meeting with the EU’s Foreign Affairs Council, and before that at NATO, and I’ll have more to say about that later.  But with us was – by video was Dmytro Kuleba, the Ukrainian foreign minister.  And in the course of speaking to us, he showed us some photographs, one of which – which I think has also been in the media – shows a father grieving over his dead child.  Blood is still on the sheet that drapes him.  It’s a reminder that even as we talk about these weighty issues of war and peace, what this is really about is the lives of men, women, children – hundreds, thousands of individual human tragedies inflicted by Vladimir Putin and his war of choice on Ukraine and its people.  And we can’t lose sight of that fact.</p>
<p>It’s also about an assault on some very basic principles that we established together after two world wars to make sure that we wouldn’t see another one, principles that are at the heart of an international system that has a responsibility to preserve peace and security among nations, principles like the notion that one country can’t simply commit acts of aggression on another, changing its borders by force; that one country can’t dictate to another its choices, its decisions, its policies, with whom it will associate; principles like one country can’t exert a sphere of influence to subjugate its neighbors to its will – each principle now under assault by the aggression against Ukraine committed by President Putin and Russia.</p>
<p>If we allow those principles to be violated with impunity, then we’re opening a Pandora’s box in every corner of the world for this to happen again and again and again, and the peace and security – with all of the deficiencies that we’ve known over the last 80 years, but nonetheless peace and security that we’ve been able to establish – that will be gone.  So the stakes here are very real.  They’re about real lives, real people, real human beings, and they are about large principles that we have to defend.</p>
<p>And we are.  And we are in no small measure because of the extraordinary work that we’ve been able to do together, the United States and the European Union.  When President Biden took office, one of the first trips he asked me to make was here to see you, to see the leaders of the European Union, because President Biden was convinced that this partnership between us was really a partnership of first choice, that looking at all of the problems that our citizens face in their daily lives, we would be so much more effective in dealing with those problems, those challenges, and those opportunities together, not alone, not individually.</p>
<p>And over the course of this year in this effort that we’ve taken together to revitalize, to re-energize the partnership between the United States and the European Union, we have done some remarkable things in so many different areas, from climate to COVID to emerging technologies.  But now, now we’re being tested in a moment of crisis, and I think that precisely because we have invested together in this partnership, we’re responding and we’re meeting the test.  As the president said, across so many different areas – the support for Ukraine, the sanctions against Russia, the help being provided to people in distress – we’re standing up together.</p>
<p>But I have to say that as someone who’s watched this over the years, both from Europe and from the United States, I am – it’s hard to find the right word for it, but let me simply say it’s been almost overwhelming to see how quickly, how effectively the European Union has come together and acted in the face of this aggression.  Things that none of us thought were possible weeks ago now are reality because this union is strong, it’s united, and it’s acting, and we’re grateful to have this partnership because it is making a difference.</p>
<p>I think we know something else, and the president alluded to it.  Unfortunately, tragically, horrifically, this may not be over soon.  And so these efforts that we’re making together, we have to sustain them, we have to build upon them.  We have to get to the point together and with, as the president said, so many other countries around the world who are united in their abhorrence of what President Putin has unleashed.  We have to sustain this until it stops, until the war is over, Russian forces leave, the Ukrainian people regain their independence, their sovereignty, their territorial integrity.  We’re committed to doing that.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>PRESIDENT VON DER LEYEN:</b>  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>European Commission</p>
<p><b>PRESIDENT VON DER LEYEN:  </b>So Secretary of State Blinken, dear Tony, a very warm welcome.  I’m very glad to have you again here in Berlaymont.  Your visit to Europe illustrates how very close the cooperation is between the European Union and the United States in response to Putin’s reckless invasion of Ukraine.  And thanks to this coordination, we have together designed, developed, and deployed sanctions in record time, sanctions that demonstrate our determination to make Putin pay a price for his war.</p>
<p>We do not take these measures lightly, but it is clear we need to act.  And with these measures, the central bank cannot use a significant share of its reserves to defend the ruble, now in free fall.  The central bank has had to raise interest rates by 20 percent, stoking inflation.  Significant commercial banks are cut off from global markets and from SWIFT, curtailing their ability to finance the economy.  The stock exchange in Moscow remains closed since the beginning of this week.  One after another, Western companies announced their own measures stopping production, investment, and sales.</p>
<p>The European Union and the U.S. cooperation is at the core of this effective response, and it has pulled together an ever-growing number of countries that apply identical or similar sanctions – our G7 partners, UK, Canada, and Japan, but also countries like Norway, Switzerland, South Korea, Australia, by now over 40 countries partially or completely aligned with our sanctions.  And this is testimony to the determination of the global community to reject this invasion.  One only needs to see the result of this week’s United Nations General Assembly: 141 countries, an overwhelming majority, supported the resolution condemning Russia for its brutal invasion.  Only four countries out of 193 stood by Russia.  It was Belarus, North Korea, Syria, and Eritrea.</p>
<p>President Putin is increasingly isolated in the world community, but in the face of the world’s protests, Putin’s army carries on.  Bombings and missile attacks on civilian targets are intensifying.  Rest assured the European Union and the United States will continue to stand by Ukraine and its courageous people and its steadfast leadership.</p>
<p>The scale of the humanitarian catastrophe that – in Ukraine that is unfolding really worries us.  Europe is seeing destruction and displacement on a scale not seen since the darkest days of the last century.  The European Union, as Ukraine’s neighbor, is sparing no effort.  We’re providing 500 million euros of humanitarian aid immediately, and more will come.  We’re working fast to establish civil protection hubs in Poland, in Slovakia, and in Romania.  And we are also doing everything we can with international organizations and NGOs to set up humanitarian corridors that stretch inside Ukraine.  Desperately needed humanitarian aid must be able to reach all parts of Ukraine and civilians must be allowed to escape cities under siege.</p>
<p>Finally, the European Union has triggered for the first time ever the so-called Temporary Protection Directive.  What is it?  It effectively opens up residency rights for most refugees to live and work in the European Union, to have access to health services or, for example, schools for at least a year.</p>
<p>We know that this conflict is far from over, and to be very clear, we are ready to take further severe measures if Putin does not stop and reverse the war he has unleashed.  We’re determined, we’re united, and it’s a pleasure to have you here, dear Tony.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Madam President, Ursula, thank you.  A short while ago we were meeting with the EU’s Foreign Affairs Council, and before that at NATO, and I’ll have more to say about that later.  But with us was – by video was Dmytro Kuleba, the Ukrainian foreign minister.  And in the course of speaking to us, he showed us some photographs, one of which – which I think has also been in the media – shows a father grieving over his dead child.  Blood is still on the sheet that drapes him.  It’s a reminder that even as we talk about these weighty issues of war and peace, what this is really about is the lives of men, women, children – hundreds, thousands of individual human tragedies inflicted by Vladimir Putin and his war of choice on Ukraine and its people.  And we can’t lose sight of that fact.</p>
<p>It’s also about an assault on some very basic principles that we established together after two world wars to make sure that we wouldn’t see another one, principles that are at the heart of an international system that has a responsibility to preserve peace and security among nations, principles like the notion that one country can’t simply commit acts of aggression on another, changing its borders by force; that one country can’t dictate to another its choices, its decisions, its policies, with whom it will associate; principles like one country can’t exert a sphere of influence to subjugate its neighbors to its will – each principle now under assault by the aggression against Ukraine committed by President Putin and Russia.</p>
<p>If we allow those principles to be violated with impunity, then we’re opening a Pandora’s box in every corner of the world for this to happen again and again and again, and the peace and security – with all of the deficiencies that we’ve known over the last 80 years, but nonetheless peace and security that we’ve been able to establish – that will be gone.  So the stakes here are very real.  They’re about real lives, real people, real human beings, and they are about large principles that we have to defend.</p>
<p>And we are.  And we are in no small measure because of the extraordinary work that we’ve been able to do together, the United States and the European Union.  When President Biden took office, one of the first trips he asked me to make was here to see you, to see the leaders of the European Union, because President Biden was convinced that this partnership between us was really a partnership of first choice, that looking at all of the problems that our citizens face in their daily lives, we would be so much more effective in dealing with those problems, those challenges, and those opportunities together, not alone, not individually.</p>
<p>And over the course of this year in this effort that we’ve taken together to revitalize, to re-energize the partnership between the United States and the European Union, we have done some remarkable things in so many different areas, from climate to COVID to emerging technologies.  But now, now we’re being tested in a moment of crisis, and I think that precisely because we have invested together in this partnership, we’re responding and we’re meeting the test.  As the president said, across so many different areas – the support for Ukraine, the sanctions against Russia, the help being provided to people in distress – we’re standing up together.</p>
<p>But I have to say that as someone who’s watched this over the years, both from Europe and from the United States, I am – it’s hard to find the right word for it, but let me simply say it’s been almost overwhelming to see how quickly, how effectively the European Union has come together and acted in the face of this aggression.  Things that none of us thought were possible weeks ago now are reality because this union is strong, it’s united, and it’s acting, and we’re grateful to have this partnership because it is making a difference.</p>
<p>I think we know something else, and the president alluded to it.  Unfortunately, tragically, horrifically, this may not be over soon.  And so these efforts that we’re making together, we have to sustain them, we have to build upon them.  We have to get to the point together and with, as the president said, so many other countries around the world who are united in their abhorrence of what President Putin has unleashed.  We have to sustain this until it stops, until the war is over, Russian forces leave, the Ukrainian people regain their independence, their sovereignty, their territorial integrity.  We’re committed to doing that.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>PRESIDENT VON DER LEYEN:</b>  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>G7 Foreign Ministers’ Statement on Russia and Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/g7-foreign-ministers-statement-on-russia-and-ukraine-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 17:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320784</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union reiterate our profound condemnation of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustifiable war of choice against Ukraine, enabled by the Belarussian government.</p>
<p>Russia must immediately stop its ongoing assault against Ukraine, which has dramatically impacted the civilian population and destroyed civilian infrastructure, and immediately withdraw Russia’s military forces. With its further aggression, President Putin has isolated Russia in the world, as evidenced by the overwhelming vote at the United Nations General Assembly condemning Russia’s aggression and calling upon it to withdraw its forces immediately.</p>
<p>We express our heart-felt solidarity with the Ukrainian people and our sympathy with the victims of this war and their families. We underline our unwavering support for Ukraine, its freely-elected government and its brave people at this most difficult time, and express our readiness to assist them further.</p>
<p>We condemn the Russian attacks on Ukrainian civilians and civilian infrastructure, including schools and hospitals. We call on Russia to uphold its obligation to fully respect international humanitarian law and human rights law. Ukrainian and UN humanitarian agencies, medical personnel, and non-governmental assistance providers must be given safe, rapid and unimpeded access to people in need immediately throughout the entire territory of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders. We acknowledge the announcement of an arrangement on humanitarian access as an important first step. This will need to be implemented reliably and swiftly. We commit to increasing humanitarian support, as the needs of the Ukrainian people grow due to Russia’s aggression. We urge Russia to stop its attacks especially in the direct vicinity of Ukraine’s nuclear power plants. Any armed attack on and threat against nuclear facilities devoted to peaceful purposes constitutes a violation of the principles of international law. We support the initiative of IAEA Director General Grossi announced today for an agreement between Ukraine and Russia to ensure the safety and security of nuclear facilities in Ukraine.</p>
<p>We are deeply concerned with the catastrophic humanitarian toll taken by Russia’s continuing strikes against the civilian population of Ukraine’s cities. We reemphasize that indiscriminate attacks are prohibited by international humanitarian law. We will hold accountable those responsible for war crimes, including indiscriminate use of weapons against civilians, and we welcome the ongoing work to investigate and gather evidence, including by the Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court (ICC).</p>
<p>Russia’s blatant violation of the fundamental principles of international peace and security and the breach of international law have not gone unanswered. We have imposed several rounds of far-reaching economic and financial sanctions. We will continue to impose further severe sanctions in response to Russian aggression, enabled by the Lukashenka regime in Belarus.</p>
<p>We wish to make clear to the Russian and Belarusian people that the severe sanctions imposed on Russia and Belarus are a consequence of and clear reaction to President Putin’s unprovoked and unjustifiable war against Ukraine. President Putin, and his government and supporters, and the Lukashenka regime, bear full responsibility for the economic and social consequences of these sanctions.</p>
<p>We condemn the widespread use of disinformation by the Russian Government and its affiliated media and proxies to support its military aggression against Ukraine. Their steady stream of fabricated claims is putting additional lives at risk. We commit to countering Russia’s disinformation campaign.</p>
<p>We reaffirm our support and commitment to the sovereignty, independence, unity and territorial integrity of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders, extending to its territorial waters. We underline that any purported change of status achieved by Russia’s renewed aggression will not be recognized.</p>
<p><em>End Text</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union reiterate our profound condemnation of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustifiable war of choice against Ukraine, enabled by the Belarussian government.</p>
<p>Russia must immediately stop its ongoing assault against Ukraine, which has dramatically impacted the civilian population and destroyed civilian infrastructure, and immediately withdraw Russia’s military forces. With its further aggression, President Putin has isolated Russia in the world, as evidenced by the overwhelming vote at the United Nations General Assembly condemning Russia’s aggression and calling upon it to withdraw its forces immediately.</p>
<p>We express our heart-felt solidarity with the Ukrainian people and our sympathy with the victims of this war and their families. We underline our unwavering support for Ukraine, its freely-elected government and its brave people at this most difficult time, and express our readiness to assist them further.</p>
<p>We condemn the Russian attacks on Ukrainian civilians and civilian infrastructure, including schools and hospitals. We call on Russia to uphold its obligation to fully respect international humanitarian law and human rights law. Ukrainian and UN humanitarian agencies, medical personnel, and non-governmental assistance providers must be given safe, rapid and unimpeded access to people in need immediately throughout the entire territory of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders. We acknowledge the announcement of an arrangement on humanitarian access as an important first step. This will need to be implemented reliably and swiftly. We commit to increasing humanitarian support, as the needs of the Ukrainian people grow due to Russia’s aggression. We urge Russia to stop its attacks especially in the direct vicinity of Ukraine’s nuclear power plants. Any armed attack on and threat against nuclear facilities devoted to peaceful purposes constitutes a violation of the principles of international law. We support the initiative of IAEA Director General Grossi announced today for an agreement between Ukraine and Russia to ensure the safety and security of nuclear facilities in Ukraine.</p>
<p>We are deeply concerned with the catastrophic humanitarian toll taken by Russia’s continuing strikes against the civilian population of Ukraine’s cities. We reemphasize that indiscriminate attacks are prohibited by international humanitarian law. We will hold accountable those responsible for war crimes, including indiscriminate use of weapons against civilians, and we welcome the ongoing work to investigate and gather evidence, including by the Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court (ICC).</p>
<p>Russia’s blatant violation of the fundamental principles of international peace and security and the breach of international law have not gone unanswered. We have imposed several rounds of far-reaching economic and financial sanctions. We will continue to impose further severe sanctions in response to Russian aggression, enabled by the Lukashenka regime in Belarus.</p>
<p>We wish to make clear to the Russian and Belarusian people that the severe sanctions imposed on Russia and Belarus are a consequence of and clear reaction to President Putin’s unprovoked and unjustifiable war against Ukraine. President Putin, and his government and supporters, and the Lukashenka regime, bear full responsibility for the economic and social consequences of these sanctions.</p>
<p>We condemn the widespread use of disinformation by the Russian Government and its affiliated media and proxies to support its military aggression against Ukraine. Their steady stream of fabricated claims is putting additional lives at risk. We commit to countering Russia’s disinformation campaign.</p>
<p>We reaffirm our support and commitment to the sovereignty, independence, unity and territorial integrity of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders, extending to its territorial waters. We underline that any purported change of status achieved by Russia’s renewed aggression will not be recognized.</p>
<p><em>End Text</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With EU High Representative Josep Borrell</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-eu-high-representative-josep-borrell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Josep Borrell, EU High Representative]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 17:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320755</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Josep Borrell, EU High Representative</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p>Europa Building</p>
<p><b>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:  </b>Good morning.  I – this is going to be a very important council meeting.  We have with us the Secretary of State Tony Blinken.  We already have the ministers of United Kingdom and Canada and the Foreign Minister Kuleba, who will explain to us what is the situation in the ground.</p>
<p>Today, what we see is the ugly phase of war erupting again in our borders, and the Russians are bombing and shelling everything – hospitals, houses, schools, a lot of civilian casualties.  This is a barbarian way of doing war.  And the Human Rights Council will soon launch a mission in order to assess the violations of human rights which is happening in Ukrainian territory.</p>
<p>This is Putin’s war, and Putin has to stop this war.  We remain united.  We know that to ask for this war – stop – to stop and avoid killing of innocent people.  We are providing arms to Ukraine in order to let them defend their soil, their rights, their nation.  We are providing help to the refugees.  Already 1 million people have been crossing our borders, and happily, more will come.  We are putting sanctions that going to really affect the Russian economy, the value of its currency.  It’s going to be having massive effects, as we have already said before.</p>
<p>So sanctions, help the refugees, arms for the Ukrainian people to defend themselves, and stop the violations of human rights, and a strong unity among Europeans and with our partners, transatlantic partners on the NATO framework.  That’s – you are here.  Thank you very much for being with us.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you, my friend.<b>  </b>It’s hard for me to improve on anything that Josep said, but just to say a couple of things quickly.</p>
<p>First, when President Biden took office a little over a year ago, his first priority was to revitalize, re-energize our alliances and partnerships, starting with the European Union, because of our conviction that we have to be partners of first resort.  Virtually everything that we’re trying to do around the world that’s affecting the lives of our citizens, we’re more effective when we’re doing it together.  And we spent the last year actually making good on that commitment.  And it’s, I think, very, very instructive that now in a time of crisis, the investment that both of us have made in this relationship is proving how important it is, how vital it is.</p>
<p>What the European Union has done over the space of a couple of weeks is quite simply remarkable.  The speed with which it acted, the actions that it took, both with regard to sanctions and also support for Ukraine, are, I think it’s not an exaggeration to say, historic.  And it only further validates for us the importance of this partnership.  As Josep said, we are faced together with what is President Putin’s war of choice – unprovoked, unjustified – and a war that is having horrific, horrific consequences for real people, for mothers, for fathers, for children.  We see the images on TV and it has to stop.  We’re committed to doing everything we can to make it stop.</p>
<p>So the coordination between us is vital, but of course it’s beyond the United States and Europe. This is an aggression, a challenge, a threat that is relevant to the entire world, because what’s at risk first and foremost are literally the lives of Ukrainian men, women, and children.  But beyond that, the very fundamental principles that we’ve established together after two world wars that are so important to keeping peace and security for everyone, principles that President Putin is egregiously violating every single day: the notion that one country can’t simply go in and change the borders of another by force or take it over; the principle that one country can’t dictate to another the choices that its citizens would make about their future; the principle that we’re past the time of spheres of influence where one country subjugates its neighbors to its will – all of those things are at stake.  And if we allow those principles to be challenged, as Putin is doing now, with impunity, that will open a Pandora’s box of trouble for not just us, but quite frankly, for the entire world.  So the stakes are high, but because we’re doing this together, I am very confident that we’ll succeed.</p>
<p>I have to say, finally, the two of us have been working like this for many, many months.  And that collaboration, that partnership, that friendship, is also what makes a difference, and I’m really grateful for it.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Josep Borrell, EU High Representative</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p>Europa Building</p>
<p><b>HIGH REPRESENTATIVE BORRELL:  </b>Good morning.  I – this is going to be a very important council meeting.  We have with us the Secretary of State Tony Blinken.  We already have the ministers of United Kingdom and Canada and the Foreign Minister Kuleba, who will explain to us what is the situation in the ground.</p>
<p>Today, what we see is the ugly phase of war erupting again in our borders, and the Russians are bombing and shelling everything – hospitals, houses, schools, a lot of civilian casualties.  This is a barbarian way of doing war.  And the Human Rights Council will soon launch a mission in order to assess the violations of human rights which is happening in Ukrainian territory.</p>
<p>This is Putin’s war, and Putin has to stop this war.  We remain united.  We know that to ask for this war – stop – to stop and avoid killing of innocent people.  We are providing arms to Ukraine in order to let them defend their soil, their rights, their nation.  We are providing help to the refugees.  Already 1 million people have been crossing our borders, and happily, more will come.  We are putting sanctions that going to really affect the Russian economy, the value of its currency.  It’s going to be having massive effects, as we have already said before.</p>
<p>So sanctions, help the refugees, arms for the Ukrainian people to defend themselves, and stop the violations of human rights, and a strong unity among Europeans and with our partners, transatlantic partners on the NATO framework.  That’s – you are here.  Thank you very much for being with us.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you, my friend.<b>  </b>It’s hard for me to improve on anything that Josep said, but just to say a couple of things quickly.</p>
<p>First, when President Biden took office a little over a year ago, his first priority was to revitalize, re-energize our alliances and partnerships, starting with the European Union, because of our conviction that we have to be partners of first resort.  Virtually everything that we’re trying to do around the world that’s affecting the lives of our citizens, we’re more effective when we’re doing it together.  And we spent the last year actually making good on that commitment.  And it’s, I think, very, very instructive that now in a time of crisis, the investment that both of us have made in this relationship is proving how important it is, how vital it is.</p>
<p>What the European Union has done over the space of a couple of weeks is quite simply remarkable.  The speed with which it acted, the actions that it took, both with regard to sanctions and also support for Ukraine, are, I think it’s not an exaggeration to say, historic.  And it only further validates for us the importance of this partnership.  As Josep said, we are faced together with what is President Putin’s war of choice – unprovoked, unjustified – and a war that is having horrific, horrific consequences for real people, for mothers, for fathers, for children.  We see the images on TV and it has to stop.  We’re committed to doing everything we can to make it stop.</p>
<p>So the coordination between us is vital, but of course it’s beyond the United States and Europe. This is an aggression, a challenge, a threat that is relevant to the entire world, because what’s at risk first and foremost are literally the lives of Ukrainian men, women, and children.  But beyond that, the very fundamental principles that we’ve established together after two world wars that are so important to keeping peace and security for everyone, principles that President Putin is egregiously violating every single day: the notion that one country can’t simply go in and change the borders of another by force or take it over; the principle that one country can’t dictate to another the choices that its citizens would make about their future; the principle that we’re past the time of spheres of influence where one country subjugates its neighbors to its will – all of those things are at stake.  And if we allow those principles to be challenged, as Putin is doing now, with impunity, that will open a Pandora’s box of trouble for not just us, but quite frankly, for the entire world.  So the stakes are high, but because we’re doing this together, I am very confident that we’ll succeed.</p>
<p>I have to say, finally, the two of us have been working like this for many, many months.  And that collaboration, that partnership, that friendship, is also what makes a difference, and I’m really grateful for it.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with European Council President Michel</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-european-council-president-michel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 17:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320754</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with European Council President Charles Michel today in Brussels, Belgium.  Secretary Blinken and President Michel emphasized the need for continued, close U.S.-EU coordination to respond to President Putin&#8217;s premeditated, unjustified, and unprovoked war on Ukraine.  Secretary Blinken thanked President Michel for the EU’s commitment to supply much-needed humanitarian, economic, and military assistance to Ukraine.  The two also reiterated the United States’ and the EU’s shared resolve to continue to support Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and to hold Russia accountable for its unlawful war of choice and Belarus for its complicity in Russian aggression.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with European Council President Charles Michel today in Brussels, Belgium.  Secretary Blinken and President Michel emphasized the need for continued, close U.S.-EU coordination to respond to President Putin&#8217;s premeditated, unjustified, and unprovoked war on Ukraine.  Secretary Blinken thanked President Michel for the EU’s commitment to supply much-needed humanitarian, economic, and military assistance to Ukraine.  The two also reiterated the United States’ and the EU’s shared resolve to continue to support Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and to hold Russia accountable for its unlawful war of choice and Belarus for its complicity in Russian aggression.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-nato-secretary-general-stoltenberg-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 17:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320750</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg today in Brussels on the margins of the NATO Foreign Ministerial.  Secretary Blinken and Secretary General Stoltenberg reiterated their strong support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of President Putin’s premeditated invasion of a peaceful democratic neighbor.  They encouraged NATO Allies and partners to continue to respond to Ukraine’s requests for supplies and equipment to defend against Russia’s unprovoked aggression.  They welcomed Ukrainian President Zelenskyy’s diplomatic initiatives, while condemning President Putin’s continued belligerence, escalation, and refusal to negotiate in good faith.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg today in Brussels on the margins of the NATO Foreign Ministerial.  Secretary Blinken and Secretary General Stoltenberg reiterated their strong support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of President Putin’s premeditated invasion of a peaceful democratic neighbor.  They encouraged NATO Allies and partners to continue to respond to Ukraine’s requests for supplies and equipment to defend against Russia’s unprovoked aggression.  They welcomed Ukrainian President Zelenskyy’s diplomatic initiatives, while condemning President Putin’s continued belligerence, escalation, and refusal to negotiate in good faith.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sanctioning Hizballah Financiers in Guinea</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/sanctioning-hizballah-financiers-in-guinea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 16:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320735</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is designating two Hizballah financiers operating in Guinea:  Ali Saade and Ibrahim Taher.  This action will help disrupt Hizballah’s business network in West Africa, which relies on bribery to circumvent the rule of law.</p>
<p>Hizballah has developed a global network of financiers, supporters, donors, and facilitators, enabling the group to constantly threaten the security, stability, and prosperity of Lebanon and the broader region.  The illicit financial activity of those designated today not only supports the terrorist group’s malign activities but also undermines the commercial sector and rule of law in countries where legitimate financial activity takes place.  The United States will continue to expose individuals such as those designated today who support Hizballah’s destabilizing activities.</p>
<p>Today’s designations were taken under Executive Order 13224, as amended, which targets terrorists, leaders, and officials of terrorist groups and those providing support to terrorists or acts of terrorism.  For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0631" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is designating two Hizballah financiers operating in Guinea:  Ali Saade and Ibrahim Taher.  This action will help disrupt Hizballah’s business network in West Africa, which relies on bribery to circumvent the rule of law.</p>
<p>Hizballah has developed a global network of financiers, supporters, donors, and facilitators, enabling the group to constantly threaten the security, stability, and prosperity of Lebanon and the broader region.  The illicit financial activity of those designated today not only supports the terrorist group’s malign activities but also undermines the commercial sector and rule of law in countries where legitimate financial activity takes place.  The United States will continue to expose individuals such as those designated today who support Hizballah’s destabilizing activities.</p>
<p>Today’s designations were taken under Executive Order 13224, as amended, which targets terrorists, leaders, and officials of terrorist groups and those providing support to terrorists or acts of terrorism.  For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0631" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-nato-secretary-general-jens-stoltenberg-before-their-meeting-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320608</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p>NATO Headquarters</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:</strong>  So Secretary Blinken, dear Tony, welcome to NATO Headquarters.  It’s great have you back here, and thank you for your tremendous leadership and for your tireless efforts in this critical time for our security.  Later on today, NATO defense – NATO foreign ministers will meet and coordinate and consult on our response to the brutal Russian invasion of Ukraine and also the longer-term implications.</p>
<p>We condemn the attacks on civilians, and over the night we have also seen reports about the attack against a nuclear power plant.  This just demonstrates the recklessness of this war and the importance of ending it and the importance of Russia withdrawing all its troops and engage in good faith in diplomatic efforts.</p>
<p>NATO Allies have implemented unprecedented sanctions.  We provide support to Ukraine.  At the same time, NATO is not part to the conflict.  NATO is a defensive alliance.  We don’t seek war, conflict with Russia.  At the same time, we need to make sure that there is no misunderstanding about our commitment to defend and protect our Allies, and therefore we have increased the presence of NATO forces in the eastern part of the Alliance.  This is a defensive presence, and I welcome the strong commitment by – from the United States with more troops.  I met many of them, and it’s always great to meet U.S. troops in Europe and to see their commitment and their professionalism being part of the transatlantic bond.</p>
<p>I also welcome that European allies and Canada are stepping up with more presence in the eastern part of the Alliance on land, at sea, and in the air.  If anything, I think the crisis we are facing now demonstrates the importance of North America standing together in strategic solidarity in NATO.  So once again, Tony, welcome.  It’s great to see you here.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Jens, thank you so much, and I really couldn’t say it any better.  But simply put, in the wake of Russia’s unprovoked, premeditated aggression against Ukraine, this Alliance came together with speed, with unity, with determination, immediately launching the rapid response task force, putting in place the graduated plans to continue to bolster NATO’s security.  Every Ally in one way or another is coming to Ukraine’s assistance.  Every Ally in one way or another is helping to strengthen NATO itself.  And as the secretary general said, ours is a defensive alliance.  We seek no conflict.  But if conflict comes to us, we are ready for it, and we will defend every inch of NATO territory.</p>
<p>At the same time, as the secretary general said, we’re preparing for NATO’s future.  And the events of the last few weeks as they continue will further inform that future, particularly going into the NATO summit in a few months, and the writing of a new strategic concept.  All of these things are coming together at a critical time.  But the single common denominator that we found, and that is the strength of everything that we do, is the unity of this Alliance.  It’s been on full display in these weeks.  It will remain on full display going forward.  And I look forward to consulting with you, Jens, about the steps we’re going to take next.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p>NATO Headquarters</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:</strong>  So Secretary Blinken, dear Tony, welcome to NATO Headquarters.  It’s great have you back here, and thank you for your tremendous leadership and for your tireless efforts in this critical time for our security.  Later on today, NATO defense – NATO foreign ministers will meet and coordinate and consult on our response to the brutal Russian invasion of Ukraine and also the longer-term implications.</p>
<p>We condemn the attacks on civilians, and over the night we have also seen reports about the attack against a nuclear power plant.  This just demonstrates the recklessness of this war and the importance of ending it and the importance of Russia withdrawing all its troops and engage in good faith in diplomatic efforts.</p>
<p>NATO Allies have implemented unprecedented sanctions.  We provide support to Ukraine.  At the same time, NATO is not part to the conflict.  NATO is a defensive alliance.  We don’t seek war, conflict with Russia.  At the same time, we need to make sure that there is no misunderstanding about our commitment to defend and protect our Allies, and therefore we have increased the presence of NATO forces in the eastern part of the Alliance.  This is a defensive presence, and I welcome the strong commitment by – from the United States with more troops.  I met many of them, and it’s always great to meet U.S. troops in Europe and to see their commitment and their professionalism being part of the transatlantic bond.</p>
<p>I also welcome that European allies and Canada are stepping up with more presence in the eastern part of the Alliance on land, at sea, and in the air.  If anything, I think the crisis we are facing now demonstrates the importance of North America standing together in strategic solidarity in NATO.  So once again, Tony, welcome.  It’s great to see you here.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Jens, thank you so much, and I really couldn’t say it any better.  But simply put, in the wake of Russia’s unprovoked, premeditated aggression against Ukraine, this Alliance came together with speed, with unity, with determination, immediately launching the rapid response task force, putting in place the graduated plans to continue to bolster NATO’s security.  Every Ally in one way or another is coming to Ukraine’s assistance.  Every Ally in one way or another is helping to strengthen NATO itself.  And as the secretary general said, ours is a defensive alliance.  We seek no conflict.  But if conflict comes to us, we are ready for it, and we will defend every inch of NATO territory.</p>
<p>At the same time, as the secretary general said, we’re preparing for NATO’s future.  And the events of the last few weeks as they continue will further inform that future, particularly going into the NATO summit in a few months, and the writing of a new strategic concept.  All of these things are coming together at a critical time.  But the single common denominator that we found, and that is the strength of everything that we do, is the unity of this Alliance.  It’s been on full display in these weeks.  It will remain on full display going forward.  And I look forward to consulting with you, Jens, about the steps we’re going to take next.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Envoy Lenderking and Chargé Westley Conclude Visit to Yemen</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-envoy-lenderking-and-charge-westley-conclude-visit-to-yemen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 02:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320481</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking and Chargé d’Affaires of the U.S. Embassy to Yemen Cathy Westley concluded their visit to Yemen.  During the trip, they met with the Governors of Hadhramaut, Mahra, and Shabwa.</p>
<p>The visit highlighted how Yemenis across the country &#8211; even those far from the frontlines &#8211; are suffering from years of political and economic instability.  It provided an opportunity to discuss the needs in these governorates and efforts to strengthen basic services, economic opportunity, and security, which would allow peace to take root.  This visit to Yemen also emphasized the continued challenges posed by terrorism and smuggling, which feed instability.</p>
<p>The U.S. delegation stressed its support for an inclusive UN-led peace process that incorporates the views of diverse Yemeni groups, including those from Hadhramaut, Mahra, and Shabwa, as well as women, civil society leaders, and representatives of other traditionally marginalized groups.</p>
<p>The visit to Yemen underscored the importance of the international community continuing to support economic stability and humanitarian relief efforts.  Millions of Yemenis have been displaced by the conflict and rely on international assistance to meet basic needs, including food, health care, and water. The United States has provided over $4 billion in humanitarian assistance for Yemen since the conflict began, and strongly urges donors to generously support the people of Yemen at the upcoming High-Level Pledging Event for Yemen co-hosted by the UN, Switzerland, and Sweden on March 16.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110010001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking and Chargé d’Affaires of the U.S. Embassy to Yemen Cathy Westley concluded their visit to Yemen.  During the trip, they met with the Governors of Hadhramaut, Mahra, and Shabwa.</p>
<p>The visit highlighted how Yemenis across the country &#8211; even those far from the frontlines &#8211; are suffering from years of political and economic instability.  It provided an opportunity to discuss the needs in these governorates and efforts to strengthen basic services, economic opportunity, and security, which would allow peace to take root.  This visit to Yemen also emphasized the continued challenges posed by terrorism and smuggling, which feed instability.</p>
<p>The U.S. delegation stressed its support for an inclusive UN-led peace process that incorporates the views of diverse Yemeni groups, including those from Hadhramaut, Mahra, and Shabwa, as well as women, civil society leaders, and representatives of other traditionally marginalized groups.</p>
<p>The visit to Yemen underscored the importance of the international community continuing to support economic stability and humanitarian relief efforts.  Millions of Yemenis have been displaced by the conflict and rely on international assistance to meet basic needs, including food, health care, and water. The United States has provided over $4 billion in humanitarian assistance for Yemen since the conflict began, and strongly urges donors to generously support the people of Yemen at the upcoming High-Level Pledging Event for Yemen co-hosted by the UN, Switzerland, and Sweden on March 16.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110010001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Kuleba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-ukrainian-foreign-minister-kuleba-12/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 01:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320470</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba. They discussed the remarkable resolve and actions taken by nations around the world to support the Government of Ukraine and the Ukrainian people in the face of Putin’s war against Ukraine. They also discussed additional security, economic, and humanitarian support needs. The Secretary extended condolences on behalf of the United States to those killed as a result of Russia’s aggression, by land, sea, and air, and made clear that the Russian government and its enablers will be held to account. The Secretary relayed that while the United States grieves for Ukraine’s losses, we are ever proud to stand with the people of Ukraine and support Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba. They discussed the remarkable resolve and actions taken by nations around the world to support the Government of Ukraine and the Ukrainian people in the face of Putin’s war against Ukraine. They also discussed additional security, economic, and humanitarian support needs. The Secretary extended condolences on behalf of the United States to those killed as a result of Russia’s aggression, by land, sea, and air, and made clear that the Russian government and its enablers will be held to account. The Secretary relayed that while the United States grieves for Ukraine’s losses, we are ever proud to stand with the people of Ukraine and support Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moscow Mechanism Invoked by 45 OSCE States To Review Reported Abuses by Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/moscow-mechanism-invoked-by-45-osce-states-to-review-reported-abuses-by-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 01:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=320463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>With Ukraine’s agreement, the United States and 44 other countries have invoked the OSCE Moscow Mechanism.  This action will establish an expert mission to address our grave concerns regarding the humanitarian and human rights impacts on the people of Ukraine caused by Russia’s further invasion with the support of Belarus.  We have seen the troubling media reports of human rights abuses and violations of humanitarian law by Russia’s forces, including the mounting number of civilian casualties and extensive damage to civilian infrastructure.  The OSCE expert mission will work impartially to establish the facts and circumstances surrounding possible contraventions of OSCE commitments and violations and abuses of international human rights law and international humanitarian law by Russia’s forces.  The expert mission will prepare a report that will be shared with all OSCE participating States and relevant accountability mechanisms, including national, regional, and international courts and tribunals.  The United States and our partners will hold Russia and its forces accountable for all human rights abuses, violations of international humanitarian law, war crimes, and crimes against humanity they commit in Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>With Ukraine’s agreement, the United States and 44 other countries have invoked the OSCE Moscow Mechanism.  This action will establish an expert mission to address our grave concerns regarding the humanitarian and human rights impacts on the people of Ukraine caused by Russia’s further invasion with the support of Belarus.  We have seen the troubling media reports of human rights abuses and violations of humanitarian law by Russia’s forces, including the mounting number of civilian casualties and extensive damage to civilian infrastructure.  The OSCE expert mission will work impartially to establish the facts and circumstances surrounding possible contraventions of OSCE commitments and violations and abuses of international human rights law and international humanitarian law by Russia’s forces.  The expert mission will prepare a report that will be shared with all OSCE participating States and relevant accountability mechanisms, including national, regional, and international courts and tribunals.  The United States and our partners will hold Russia and its forces accountable for all human rights abuses, violations of international humanitarian law, war crimes, and crimes against humanity they commit in Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
