<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 23:55:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken At the Graduation Commencement Ceremonies for the Georgetown Class of 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-the-graduation-commencement-ceremonies-for-the-georgetown-class-of-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 23:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346471</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Walsh School of Foreign Service</p>
<p><b>MR DEGIOIA:</b>  By virtue of the authority vested in me by the Congress of the United States and by the Board of Directors of Georgetown University, I officially confer upon Secretary Antony Blinken the degree of Doctor of Humane Letters honoris causa.  And it’s now my pleasure to present Dr. Antony Blinken, who will offer the commencement address.  (Applause.)<b></b></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Hello Georgetown.  (Cheers.)  Thank you, Ambassador Bodine, for a truly incredible and overly generous introduction.  I don’t know if it will be possible to live up to anything near what you said, but I am grateful for your remarks, and grateful as well for your remarkable service to this country over so many years.</p>
<p>President DeGioia, Dean Hellman, Provost Groves, distinguished faculty and staff, proud parents and grandparents, supportive and rival siblings (laughter); devoted aunts, uncles, and friends; and most of all, members of the Georgetown School of Foreign Service Class of 2022 (cheers):  Thank you, thank you, thank you for the honor of being part of this outstanding institution’s commencement celebration.</p>
<p>Now, I’m not a Georgetown alum, but I am the son-in-law of two of them, Tony and Donna Ryan.  Standing up here today in front of Healy Hall probably earned me more points with them than the current job that I hold.  (Laughter.)  It’s probably also true of my former boss, President Clinton, class of ’68.  So thank you, Georgetown.  The only difference, Mr. President, is that, like you, they actually earned their honors.</p>
<p>So I want to start by kicking the elephant out of the room.  Yes, NYU got Taylor Swift as their commencement speaker.  (Laughter and applause.)</p>
<p>Now, my staff did not let me bring my guitar up here to dedicate a performance of “We Are Never Ever Getting Back Together” to President Putin.  (Laughter and applause.)  They said it would be “undiplomatic” and also “cringe.”  (Laughter.)  Also, since when is cringe an adjective?  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>In any case, guitar or not, I am thrilled to be here.</p>
<p>This is a special day for many reasons.  And maybe the most exhilarating is that this is indeed the first in-person commencement since 2019, so it’s just wonderful to be in the same place with all of you.  And I really want to commend these graduates for persevering through lockdowns, Zoom classes, quarantining, and – for some of you – through loss, including a beloved classmate.</p>
<p>I know this has not been an easy road.  But you have traveled it together, and you’ve done it while practicing the core principle of cura personalis – of taking care of yourselves and taking care of one another.  So today, I hope you’ll take a moment to savor the fact that you have done something extraordinary.  You’ve completed a world-class education at one of the finest schools for international affairs on the entire planet.  (Cheers.)</p>
<p>Now, this accomplishment is yours, but it also belongs to everyone who loved and supported you along the way.  None of us achieves everything on our own.  So before we go any further, can we please have a huge round of applause to all the family and friends who helped make today possible?  (Cheers.)</p>
<p>There’s someone else who’s already been mentioned that I want to mention as well – someone that we dearly wish was here with us today, and who would be cheering for this class with all her might – and that is the great Madeleine Albright.  (Applause.)  Madeleine was a strong Georgetown partisan.  This was her cherished home for decades.  And as has been noted – in a little twist of history – she was the speaker for that last in-person SFS commencement three years ago.</p>
<p>And I have to tell you it feels a little bit like she has passed a torch to me today, and not for the first time.  After all, I sit at her desk every day.</p>
<p>So on the occasion of the Class of 2022’s commencement, I thought what I’d do is talk a little bit about her and about two other secretaries of state we said goodbye to since last year, Colin Powell and George Shultz.</p>
<p>Now, they were three very different people – different backgrounds, different political philosophies, different styles of leadership.  And the times during which they were secretary were different, too.  But they devoted their lives to service.  They left their mark.  And their stories hold lessons for each and every one of us, especially for you, the graduates of this school.</p>
<p>Now, let’s face it:  If anyone is going to appreciate secretary of state stories, it’s someone with the words “foreign service” on their diploma.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>I know that every young person graduating today is immediately inundated with advice, and it can probably feel impossible to sort through it all.  So let me say this:  Don’t think of this as advice, just a few stories from a few people who led remarkable lives and who once were sitting right where you’re sitting, deeply interested in the world, wondering how they would fit in.</p>
<p>And I know they wouldn’t mind if just for today we drop the honorifics.  So if it’s all right, for today they’re not secretaries.  They’re Madeleine, they’re Colin, they’re George.</p>
<p>The first lesson is about remembering where you came from.  Colin drilled this into his three kids as they grew up.</p>
<p>He was the son of Jamaican immigrants in the South Bronx.  His block, Kelly Street, had all kinds of people on it – West Indians, African Americans, Puerto Ricans, and Jews like the Klein family, who lived downstairs from the Powells.  They had the only television in the building and they would invite the entire neighborhood – all the kids over – to watch it on Tuesday nights.</p>
<p>Colin later said his neighborhood stuck with him as a model for America at its best, a place where diversity made people’s lives richer, more vibrant, and where people looked out for one another even when they looked different.</p>
<p>Colin brought that spirit to every team that he built.  It’s why he worked so hard, as he used to say, to make the State Department look more like America.  And it’s why he’d be so proud of the outsized cohorts of Pickering, Rangel, and Payne Fellows here at the School of Foreign Service – including 33 current fellows, and 37 more starting next year.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>Madeleine came to the United States at age 11 as a refugee. Her family had been driven from their home in Czechoslovakia twice – first by the Nazis, then by the communists.  She already had experienced the horrors of war; she hid in shelters in London as bombs dropped from the sky.</p>
<p>She never forgot why it mattered for countries to stand up to tyrants and open their arms to the displaced.  That was true whether she was speaking at the United Nations Security Council, swearing in a new group of American citizens, or meeting with refugees uprooted by war.  She couldn’t help but put herself in the shoes of people fleeing repression, because she had once walked in those shoes.</p>
<p>George kept a giant globe in his office as secretary.  Before any new ambassador left for their post, he would administer one last test.  Show me your country on the globe, he’d say.  So they’d spin the globe and they’d look for Argentina or Nigeria or Indonesia, wherever they were going.  And George would gently take their finger and move it and put it on the United States.  This is your country, he would say.</p>
<p>It was his way of reminding America’s diplomats that no matter how far they traveled, the people that they served were still here.  Of course, if the members of this class stood before that globe, you’d point at dozens of different countries, some of which were not even on the map when George was secretary.</p>
<p>But here’s the point:  No matter where you go or what cause you serve, try to hold on to what’s shaped you.  Use those first coordinates, the places and people that make up your Map of the Modern World.</p>
<p>And try to remember this for other people.  It’s worth putting some work into learning where other people come from, especially people whose map is vastly different from yours.  That is the foundation of empathy, and it’s handy no matter where you go.</p>
<p>The second lesson is about always being a student.</p>
<p>Madeleine started teaching here 40 years ago.  So I tracked down the most recent syllabus for her course, America’s National Security Toolbox.  Here’s how it starts:  “I am looking forward to both teaching and learning from you.  Together,  do our best to make sense of  happening in the world.”</p>
<p>Madeleine saw every student who passed through SFS as someone that she could learn from.  She’d meet individually with every student that she came across during her time here.  She quoted students in her books.  In her interviews, she often said things like, “I have a student who” or “My students tell me.”</p>
<p>And as her daughters shared at her memorial service, Madeleine brought a stack of your papers with her to the hospital.  She was still learning from you right till the very end.</p>
<p>Likewise, George always looked to engage people at every level.  So some of you may know we have a system at the State Department that produces policy memos.  Some of you are familiar with it.  Indeed, a junior staffer would write a draft, it works its way up through the hierarchy, until eventually a senior official signs off on it.</p>
<p>When George had a question about a memo, he didn’t ask the senior person.  He called the person who drafted it.  He’d ask them to swing by his office.  Many had never been in a room with a secretary of state.  Now they were debating policy with one, because George knew that these desk officers had information that no one else did.</p>
<p>And as secretary, Colin would sneak away from his security detail to talk to people he probably wouldn’t otherwise meet.  One day, he went down to the State Department garage.  Now, those of you who know the garage know that it’s too small for all the cars to fit.  So every morning, the parking attendants line the cars up in very, very tight rows.  When they saw George – excuse me, Colin walking up, they thought he was lost.  But he had come to talk.</p>
<p>He asked them where they were from, how did they like the job.  And they told him things that only they could know – like how they decided which car got out first at the end of the day.  If the person actually knew their names and treated them like human beings, they got out first.  If they acted like the attendants were invisible, they were last.</p>
<p>Decency ruled.</p>
<p>Learning from others is a way of showing respect.  It tells people that you see them, that you value them.</p>
<p>As anyone who knew Colin, Madeleine, or George can tell you, they spent their whole lives in learning mode.  This openness, this curiosity, meant that they were always stumbling across new ideas and new ways of seeing things.  And it meant life never stopped being interesting.</p>
<p>The third lesson is about getting lost.  And not just in the ICC here on campus.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>It’s incredibly tempting to see the lives of the super-accomplished as somehow following a straight line that led all the way to the top.  But in real life, it rarely goes that way.</p>
<p>Colin’s parents didn’t go to college, so they pinned very high expectations on him.  His mom decided he should study engineering, so he signed up for it.  But he just couldn’t get through mechanical drawing; he switched to geology.  A family meeting was called.  His parents made clear their disappointment.  He wasn’t making friends at school either, and back home on Kelly Street, his neighbors were calling him “college kid,” and not always in a nice way.  He felt like he didn’t quite fit in anywhere.</p>
<p>Madeleine got married three days after graduating from Wellesley.  By age 24, she was mom to twins.  One after another, she pushed on doors, only to find them shut.</p>
<p>When she and her husband at the time – who was a journalist – had dinner with the editor of his newspaper, Madeleine said that she too wanted to be a reporter.  The editor immediately shot her down.  “You wouldn’t want to compete with your husband,” he said.  Madeleine was silent.  Maybe that’s why she later urged so many women to learn to interrupt.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>Years after, she said, “All of a sudden, these things that I thought I was going to be able to do, I couldn&#8217;t do.”</p>
<p>George was halfway through his senior year at Princeton, on a date at a football game, when word spread that Japan had attacked Pearl Harbor.</p>
<p>Soon after, he drove with a friend to New York City to sign up for the Royal Canadian Air Force.  That was the quickest path at the time to actually get into action.  Both of them failed the eye test.  Dejected, they went out for drinks and learned one of life’s most painful lessons: Beware of bars with tattoo parlors in the back.  (Laughter.)  George and his friend emerged with matching tattoos of the proud old Princeton tiger – on their tails.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>So if you’ve had a big setback in your time at SFS and did not tattoo Jack the Bulldog on your rear, consider yourself a step ahead of George.  (Laughter and applause.)</p>
<p>The point is this:  We assume that giants like them always had it figured out.  But they went through times when they felt profoundly lost.  Everybody does.  If you have no idea what’s next for you, even though that’s probably what everyone is asking you today, don’t be scared.  That’s okay.  That’s the way it is.</p>
<p>And don’t get knocked off your stride by all the Instagram and LinkedIn posts by peers celebrating their lives.  It doesn’t mean they’ve got it all figured out, either.  Don’t compare their outsides to your insides.</p>
<p>That also goes for the times when people are not at their best selves with you.  As Colin used to tell his team, “We always need to treat people with a little more respect than they deserve, because we don’t know what’s going on in their lives.”  A lot of times, it’s got nothing to do with you.  Just keep going.</p>
<p>Not long after switching to geology, Colin kept crossing paths with a bunch of guys from the ROTC.  He figured he’d give it a try.  Putting on the uniform, he found that it fit.</p>
<p>Madeleine went back to school to get her Ph.D., which is how she met a brilliant academic whose family, like hers, had fled the Nazis: Zbigniew Brzezinski.  When he became national security advisor, he hired Madeleine.</p>
<p>George and his tiger returned to Princeton, finished their senior year, and enlisted in the Marines – the start of what turned into a lifetime of service to the United States.</p>
<p>They found their way. You will, too.</p>
<p>The final lesson is about sticking with it for the long haul.</p>
<p>In Madeleine’s 2019 commencement speech, she drew parallels between 2019 and 1919, and warned of the rising tides of authoritarianism, nationalism, isolationism.</p>
<p>She made the case – as she did so often – for why service, your service, was crucial to meeting the challenges that we face.  She said, and I quote, “You must remember that there is not a page of this institution’s hundred-year history of which  proud that was  by a chronic complainer.  We are doers.  We have a responsibility not to be prisoners of history but to shape .”</p>
<p>There’s not really any doubt in my mind that all of you will find a way to serve, if that’s what you choose to do.  That’s why you’re here.  That’s who you are.</p>
<p>But to make a real dent, you’ve got stick with it.  Progress takes a long time.  It can feel like you’re getting nowhere.  Don’t give up.</p>
<p>That’s the story of George, Madeleine, and Colin.  Each served in many ways over their lifetimes – as teachers and soldiers, as diplomats and advocates.  Some of those hats fit better than others.  But they kept at it, despite losses, despite setbacks, even seeing the progress they worked so hard to achieve get rolled back.</p>
<p>They endured because they learned to take the long view, to accept that every cause worth fighting for would actually outlive them; to aim for the big wins, but also to savor the small ones.</p>
<p>Yakoob Haloughkah grew up in a tiny town in the Czech Republic.  In 2007, when he was a junior in high school, he came across Madeleine’s memoir in the local library.  He was so moved by the story he sent her a note in Czech telling her that she’d inspired him to pursue a career in international relations.  He didn’t expect to hear back.  Then he got a reply from Madeleine, saying he was making a wise choice, telling him to keep at it.</p>
<p>Six years later, Yakoob was sitting in her seminar at a grad – as a grad student at SFS.  Today, he is a public policy professor at USC, where he tries to emulate Madeleine every single day.</p>
<p>I work with people like Yakoob every day at the State Department, people whose trajectory Madeleine helped to shape.</p>
<p>Suzy George, my chief of staff, got her first job in government when Madeleine was the U.S. ambassador to the United Nations, and spent the next several decades by her side.</p>
<p>Ned Price, the spokesperson at the State Department, described seeing Madeleine walking down Prospect Street when he was a freshman here at SFS, feeling like he’d just spotted Madonna.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Sarah McCool, who manages my team’s schedule, also wrote a letter to Madeleine when she was in high school.  And Madeleine answered her, inviting Sarah to come meet with her before a speech that she was giving.</p>
<p>Each of these individuals – and they’re here today – is part of Madeleine’s legacy, and our country is so much better for it.</p>
<p>We often measure the impact of public servants, especially in international affairs, with a big ruler – the rise and fall of great powers, conflicts and alliances.  But one of the things that made Madeleine, Colin, and George great was that they always measured their progress in the steps of the people around them.</p>
<p>When Colin was secretary, George sent him a letter that said, and I quote, “I am always amazed at the way people presume leaders in government focus almost exclusively on policy problems and  their own ups and downs.  But leadership is about the people under your charge.  A real leader is conscious of what he  leaves behind.”</p>
<p>That’s the thing about this kind of work.  It will always outlast us.  So what we leave behind matters.  We need others to pick up where we left off.</p>
<p>When I look out at all of you today, I see hundreds of people ready to carry the baton for another leg, picking up where George, Madeleine, and Colin, and so many others left off.</p>
<p>And so, graduates, as you leave the school of service for a life of service, I hope that you’ll see that everything you need to serve – to serve with purpose – is right here.</p>
<p>Let the loved ones celebrating you today help remind you always of where you came from.</p>
<p>Let your professors and fellow graduates and all that you learned in this extraordinary place remind you of the joy of forever being a student.</p>
<p>Know that you will get lost, and that the losses and setbacks may well outnumber the wins.</p>
<p>And as you stick with it, you’ll find that even the smallest steps forward will do more than sustain you.  They will fulfill you.  They will lift you up.  They’ll lift up others.  They will help shape this world for the better.</p>
<p>So Class of 2022, we welcome you with open arms to the ranks of the doers, and we can’t wait to see all that you – all that you – will get done.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Walsh School of Foreign Service</p>
<p><b>MR DEGIOIA:</b>  By virtue of the authority vested in me by the Congress of the United States and by the Board of Directors of Georgetown University, I officially confer upon Secretary Antony Blinken the degree of Doctor of Humane Letters honoris causa.  And it’s now my pleasure to present Dr. Antony Blinken, who will offer the commencement address.  (Applause.)<b></b></p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Hello Georgetown.  (Cheers.)  Thank you, Ambassador Bodine, for a truly incredible and overly generous introduction.  I don’t know if it will be possible to live up to anything near what you said, but I am grateful for your remarks, and grateful as well for your remarkable service to this country over so many years.</p>
<p>President DeGioia, Dean Hellman, Provost Groves, distinguished faculty and staff, proud parents and grandparents, supportive and rival siblings (laughter); devoted aunts, uncles, and friends; and most of all, members of the Georgetown School of Foreign Service Class of 2022 (cheers):  Thank you, thank you, thank you for the honor of being part of this outstanding institution’s commencement celebration.</p>
<p>Now, I’m not a Georgetown alum, but I am the son-in-law of two of them, Tony and Donna Ryan.  Standing up here today in front of Healy Hall probably earned me more points with them than the current job that I hold.  (Laughter.)  It’s probably also true of my former boss, President Clinton, class of ’68.  So thank you, Georgetown.  The only difference, Mr. President, is that, like you, they actually earned their honors.</p>
<p>So I want to start by kicking the elephant out of the room.  Yes, NYU got Taylor Swift as their commencement speaker.  (Laughter and applause.)</p>
<p>Now, my staff did not let me bring my guitar up here to dedicate a performance of “We Are Never Ever Getting Back Together” to President Putin.  (Laughter and applause.)  They said it would be “undiplomatic” and also “cringe.”  (Laughter.)  Also, since when is cringe an adjective?  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>In any case, guitar or not, I am thrilled to be here.</p>
<p>This is a special day for many reasons.  And maybe the most exhilarating is that this is indeed the first in-person commencement since 2019, so it’s just wonderful to be in the same place with all of you.  And I really want to commend these graduates for persevering through lockdowns, Zoom classes, quarantining, and – for some of you – through loss, including a beloved classmate.</p>
<p>I know this has not been an easy road.  But you have traveled it together, and you’ve done it while practicing the core principle of cura personalis – of taking care of yourselves and taking care of one another.  So today, I hope you’ll take a moment to savor the fact that you have done something extraordinary.  You’ve completed a world-class education at one of the finest schools for international affairs on the entire planet.  (Cheers.)</p>
<p>Now, this accomplishment is yours, but it also belongs to everyone who loved and supported you along the way.  None of us achieves everything on our own.  So before we go any further, can we please have a huge round of applause to all the family and friends who helped make today possible?  (Cheers.)</p>
<p>There’s someone else who’s already been mentioned that I want to mention as well – someone that we dearly wish was here with us today, and who would be cheering for this class with all her might – and that is the great Madeleine Albright.  (Applause.)  Madeleine was a strong Georgetown partisan.  This was her cherished home for decades.  And as has been noted – in a little twist of history – she was the speaker for that last in-person SFS commencement three years ago.</p>
<p>And I have to tell you it feels a little bit like she has passed a torch to me today, and not for the first time.  After all, I sit at her desk every day.</p>
<p>So on the occasion of the Class of 2022’s commencement, I thought what I’d do is talk a little bit about her and about two other secretaries of state we said goodbye to since last year, Colin Powell and George Shultz.</p>
<p>Now, they were three very different people – different backgrounds, different political philosophies, different styles of leadership.  And the times during which they were secretary were different, too.  But they devoted their lives to service.  They left their mark.  And their stories hold lessons for each and every one of us, especially for you, the graduates of this school.</p>
<p>Now, let’s face it:  If anyone is going to appreciate secretary of state stories, it’s someone with the words “foreign service” on their diploma.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>I know that every young person graduating today is immediately inundated with advice, and it can probably feel impossible to sort through it all.  So let me say this:  Don’t think of this as advice, just a few stories from a few people who led remarkable lives and who once were sitting right where you’re sitting, deeply interested in the world, wondering how they would fit in.</p>
<p>And I know they wouldn’t mind if just for today we drop the honorifics.  So if it’s all right, for today they’re not secretaries.  They’re Madeleine, they’re Colin, they’re George.</p>
<p>The first lesson is about remembering where you came from.  Colin drilled this into his three kids as they grew up.</p>
<p>He was the son of Jamaican immigrants in the South Bronx.  His block, Kelly Street, had all kinds of people on it – West Indians, African Americans, Puerto Ricans, and Jews like the Klein family, who lived downstairs from the Powells.  They had the only television in the building and they would invite the entire neighborhood – all the kids over – to watch it on Tuesday nights.</p>
<p>Colin later said his neighborhood stuck with him as a model for America at its best, a place where diversity made people’s lives richer, more vibrant, and where people looked out for one another even when they looked different.</p>
<p>Colin brought that spirit to every team that he built.  It’s why he worked so hard, as he used to say, to make the State Department look more like America.  And it’s why he’d be so proud of the outsized cohorts of Pickering, Rangel, and Payne Fellows here at the School of Foreign Service – including 33 current fellows, and 37 more starting next year.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>Madeleine came to the United States at age 11 as a refugee. Her family had been driven from their home in Czechoslovakia twice – first by the Nazis, then by the communists.  She already had experienced the horrors of war; she hid in shelters in London as bombs dropped from the sky.</p>
<p>She never forgot why it mattered for countries to stand up to tyrants and open their arms to the displaced.  That was true whether she was speaking at the United Nations Security Council, swearing in a new group of American citizens, or meeting with refugees uprooted by war.  She couldn’t help but put herself in the shoes of people fleeing repression, because she had once walked in those shoes.</p>
<p>George kept a giant globe in his office as secretary.  Before any new ambassador left for their post, he would administer one last test.  Show me your country on the globe, he’d say.  So they’d spin the globe and they’d look for Argentina or Nigeria or Indonesia, wherever they were going.  And George would gently take their finger and move it and put it on the United States.  This is your country, he would say.</p>
<p>It was his way of reminding America’s diplomats that no matter how far they traveled, the people that they served were still here.  Of course, if the members of this class stood before that globe, you’d point at dozens of different countries, some of which were not even on the map when George was secretary.</p>
<p>But here’s the point:  No matter where you go or what cause you serve, try to hold on to what’s shaped you.  Use those first coordinates, the places and people that make up your Map of the Modern World.</p>
<p>And try to remember this for other people.  It’s worth putting some work into learning where other people come from, especially people whose map is vastly different from yours.  That is the foundation of empathy, and it’s handy no matter where you go.</p>
<p>The second lesson is about always being a student.</p>
<p>Madeleine started teaching here 40 years ago.  So I tracked down the most recent syllabus for her course, America’s National Security Toolbox.  Here’s how it starts:  “I am looking forward to both teaching and learning from you.  Together,  do our best to make sense of  happening in the world.”</p>
<p>Madeleine saw every student who passed through SFS as someone that she could learn from.  She’d meet individually with every student that she came across during her time here.  She quoted students in her books.  In her interviews, she often said things like, “I have a student who” or “My students tell me.”</p>
<p>And as her daughters shared at her memorial service, Madeleine brought a stack of your papers with her to the hospital.  She was still learning from you right till the very end.</p>
<p>Likewise, George always looked to engage people at every level.  So some of you may know we have a system at the State Department that produces policy memos.  Some of you are familiar with it.  Indeed, a junior staffer would write a draft, it works its way up through the hierarchy, until eventually a senior official signs off on it.</p>
<p>When George had a question about a memo, he didn’t ask the senior person.  He called the person who drafted it.  He’d ask them to swing by his office.  Many had never been in a room with a secretary of state.  Now they were debating policy with one, because George knew that these desk officers had information that no one else did.</p>
<p>And as secretary, Colin would sneak away from his security detail to talk to people he probably wouldn’t otherwise meet.  One day, he went down to the State Department garage.  Now, those of you who know the garage know that it’s too small for all the cars to fit.  So every morning, the parking attendants line the cars up in very, very tight rows.  When they saw George – excuse me, Colin walking up, they thought he was lost.  But he had come to talk.</p>
<p>He asked them where they were from, how did they like the job.  And they told him things that only they could know – like how they decided which car got out first at the end of the day.  If the person actually knew their names and treated them like human beings, they got out first.  If they acted like the attendants were invisible, they were last.</p>
<p>Decency ruled.</p>
<p>Learning from others is a way of showing respect.  It tells people that you see them, that you value them.</p>
<p>As anyone who knew Colin, Madeleine, or George can tell you, they spent their whole lives in learning mode.  This openness, this curiosity, meant that they were always stumbling across new ideas and new ways of seeing things.  And it meant life never stopped being interesting.</p>
<p>The third lesson is about getting lost.  And not just in the ICC here on campus.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>It’s incredibly tempting to see the lives of the super-accomplished as somehow following a straight line that led all the way to the top.  But in real life, it rarely goes that way.</p>
<p>Colin’s parents didn’t go to college, so they pinned very high expectations on him.  His mom decided he should study engineering, so he signed up for it.  But he just couldn’t get through mechanical drawing; he switched to geology.  A family meeting was called.  His parents made clear their disappointment.  He wasn’t making friends at school either, and back home on Kelly Street, his neighbors were calling him “college kid,” and not always in a nice way.  He felt like he didn’t quite fit in anywhere.</p>
<p>Madeleine got married three days after graduating from Wellesley.  By age 24, she was mom to twins.  One after another, she pushed on doors, only to find them shut.</p>
<p>When she and her husband at the time – who was a journalist – had dinner with the editor of his newspaper, Madeleine said that she too wanted to be a reporter.  The editor immediately shot her down.  “You wouldn’t want to compete with your husband,” he said.  Madeleine was silent.  Maybe that’s why she later urged so many women to learn to interrupt.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>Years after, she said, “All of a sudden, these things that I thought I was going to be able to do, I couldn&#8217;t do.”</p>
<p>George was halfway through his senior year at Princeton, on a date at a football game, when word spread that Japan had attacked Pearl Harbor.</p>
<p>Soon after, he drove with a friend to New York City to sign up for the Royal Canadian Air Force.  That was the quickest path at the time to actually get into action.  Both of them failed the eye test.  Dejected, they went out for drinks and learned one of life’s most painful lessons: Beware of bars with tattoo parlors in the back.  (Laughter.)  George and his friend emerged with matching tattoos of the proud old Princeton tiger – on their tails.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>So if you’ve had a big setback in your time at SFS and did not tattoo Jack the Bulldog on your rear, consider yourself a step ahead of George.  (Laughter and applause.)</p>
<p>The point is this:  We assume that giants like them always had it figured out.  But they went through times when they felt profoundly lost.  Everybody does.  If you have no idea what’s next for you, even though that’s probably what everyone is asking you today, don’t be scared.  That’s okay.  That’s the way it is.</p>
<p>And don’t get knocked off your stride by all the Instagram and LinkedIn posts by peers celebrating their lives.  It doesn’t mean they’ve got it all figured out, either.  Don’t compare their outsides to your insides.</p>
<p>That also goes for the times when people are not at their best selves with you.  As Colin used to tell his team, “We always need to treat people with a little more respect than they deserve, because we don’t know what’s going on in their lives.”  A lot of times, it’s got nothing to do with you.  Just keep going.</p>
<p>Not long after switching to geology, Colin kept crossing paths with a bunch of guys from the ROTC.  He figured he’d give it a try.  Putting on the uniform, he found that it fit.</p>
<p>Madeleine went back to school to get her Ph.D., which is how she met a brilliant academic whose family, like hers, had fled the Nazis: Zbigniew Brzezinski.  When he became national security advisor, he hired Madeleine.</p>
<p>George and his tiger returned to Princeton, finished their senior year, and enlisted in the Marines – the start of what turned into a lifetime of service to the United States.</p>
<p>They found their way. You will, too.</p>
<p>The final lesson is about sticking with it for the long haul.</p>
<p>In Madeleine’s 2019 commencement speech, she drew parallels between 2019 and 1919, and warned of the rising tides of authoritarianism, nationalism, isolationism.</p>
<p>She made the case – as she did so often – for why service, your service, was crucial to meeting the challenges that we face.  She said, and I quote, “You must remember that there is not a page of this institution’s hundred-year history of which  proud that was  by a chronic complainer.  We are doers.  We have a responsibility not to be prisoners of history but to shape .”</p>
<p>There’s not really any doubt in my mind that all of you will find a way to serve, if that’s what you choose to do.  That’s why you’re here.  That’s who you are.</p>
<p>But to make a real dent, you’ve got stick with it.  Progress takes a long time.  It can feel like you’re getting nowhere.  Don’t give up.</p>
<p>That’s the story of George, Madeleine, and Colin.  Each served in many ways over their lifetimes – as teachers and soldiers, as diplomats and advocates.  Some of those hats fit better than others.  But they kept at it, despite losses, despite setbacks, even seeing the progress they worked so hard to achieve get rolled back.</p>
<p>They endured because they learned to take the long view, to accept that every cause worth fighting for would actually outlive them; to aim for the big wins, but also to savor the small ones.</p>
<p>Yakoob Haloughkah grew up in a tiny town in the Czech Republic.  In 2007, when he was a junior in high school, he came across Madeleine’s memoir in the local library.  He was so moved by the story he sent her a note in Czech telling her that she’d inspired him to pursue a career in international relations.  He didn’t expect to hear back.  Then he got a reply from Madeleine, saying he was making a wise choice, telling him to keep at it.</p>
<p>Six years later, Yakoob was sitting in her seminar at a grad – as a grad student at SFS.  Today, he is a public policy professor at USC, where he tries to emulate Madeleine every single day.</p>
<p>I work with people like Yakoob every day at the State Department, people whose trajectory Madeleine helped to shape.</p>
<p>Suzy George, my chief of staff, got her first job in government when Madeleine was the U.S. ambassador to the United Nations, and spent the next several decades by her side.</p>
<p>Ned Price, the spokesperson at the State Department, described seeing Madeleine walking down Prospect Street when he was a freshman here at SFS, feeling like he’d just spotted Madonna.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Sarah McCool, who manages my team’s schedule, also wrote a letter to Madeleine when she was in high school.  And Madeleine answered her, inviting Sarah to come meet with her before a speech that she was giving.</p>
<p>Each of these individuals – and they’re here today – is part of Madeleine’s legacy, and our country is so much better for it.</p>
<p>We often measure the impact of public servants, especially in international affairs, with a big ruler – the rise and fall of great powers, conflicts and alliances.  But one of the things that made Madeleine, Colin, and George great was that they always measured their progress in the steps of the people around them.</p>
<p>When Colin was secretary, George sent him a letter that said, and I quote, “I am always amazed at the way people presume leaders in government focus almost exclusively on policy problems and  their own ups and downs.  But leadership is about the people under your charge.  A real leader is conscious of what he  leaves behind.”</p>
<p>That’s the thing about this kind of work.  It will always outlast us.  So what we leave behind matters.  We need others to pick up where we left off.</p>
<p>When I look out at all of you today, I see hundreds of people ready to carry the baton for another leg, picking up where George, Madeleine, and Colin, and so many others left off.</p>
<p>And so, graduates, as you leave the school of service for a life of service, I hope that you’ll see that everything you need to serve – to serve with purpose – is right here.</p>
<p>Let the loved ones celebrating you today help remind you always of where you came from.</p>
<p>Let your professors and fellow graduates and all that you learned in this extraordinary place remind you of the joy of forever being a student.</p>
<p>Know that you will get lost, and that the losses and setbacks may well outnumber the wins.</p>
<p>And as you stick with it, you’ll find that even the smallest steps forward will do more than sustain you.  They will fulfill you.  They will lift you up.  They’ll lift up others.  They will help shape this world for the better.</p>
<p>So Class of 2022, we welcome you with open arms to the ranks of the doers, and we can’t wait to see all that you – all that you – will get done.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Stern’s Travel to Malaysia, Thailand, and Vietnam </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-special-envoy-to-advance-the-human-rights-of-lgbtqi-persons-sterns-travel-to-malaysia-thailand-and-vietnam/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 19:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346458</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="text-align: left;" align="center">U.S. Special Envoy Jessica Stern will travel to Malaysia, Thailand, and Vietnam, May 21-27. During her visits, Special Envoy Stern will meet with government officials, like-minded multilateral institutions, members of the diplomatic corps, local LGBTQI+ activists, and civil society organizations to discuss advancing the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons in each country and regionally.</p>
<p>Among her engagements, the Special Envoy will speak at a collaborative and international workshop on Protection Against Violence and Discrimination Based on Sexual Orientation and Gender Identity in Hanoi<s>.</s></p>
<p>In Thailand, the Special Envoy will meet with the National Human Rights Commission and members of civil society.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:DRL-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">DRL-Press@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="text-align: left;" align="center">U.S. Special Envoy Jessica Stern will travel to Malaysia, Thailand, and Vietnam, May 21-27. During her visits, Special Envoy Stern will meet with government officials, like-minded multilateral institutions, members of the diplomatic corps, local LGBTQI+ activists, and civil society organizations to discuss advancing the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons in each country and regionally.</p>
<p>Among her engagements, the Special Envoy will speak at a collaborative and international workshop on Protection Against Violence and Discrimination Based on Sexual Orientation and Gender Identity in Hanoi<s>.</s></p>
<p>In Thailand, the Special Envoy will meet with the National Human Rights Commission and members of civil society.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:DRL-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">DRL-Press@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meeting with Saudi Deputy Minister of Defense Prince Khalid bin Salman Al Saud</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/meeting-with-saudi-deputy-minister-of-defense-prince-khalid-bin-salman-al-saud/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 11:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken joined Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman’s meeting today with His Royal Highness Prince Khalid bin Salman Al Saud, the Deputy Minister of Defense of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, in Washington, D.C. The Secretary and Deputy expressed strong support for the UN-negotiated truce and reviewed other recent progress in Yemen, including the resumption of commercial flights from Sana’a and regular fuel imports through Hudaydah, while stressing the need to urgently improve access to Taiz and other cities on the front lines of the conflict. They discussed with the Deputy Minister the enduring U.S. commitment to strengthen Saudi Arabia’s defenses, efforts to counter Iranian threats, and the importance of maintaining strong international support for Ukraine. They also discussed managing pressures in global energy markets stemming from Russia’s invasion of Ukraine and reviewed human rights issues as well as Saudi Arabia’s progress on its Vision 2030 program.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken joined Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman’s meeting today with His Royal Highness Prince Khalid bin Salman Al Saud, the Deputy Minister of Defense of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, in Washington, D.C. The Secretary and Deputy expressed strong support for the UN-negotiated truce and reviewed other recent progress in Yemen, including the resumption of commercial flights from Sana’a and regular fuel imports through Hudaydah, while stressing the need to urgently improve access to Taiz and other cities on the front lines of the conflict. They discussed with the Deputy Minister the enduring U.S. commitment to strengthen Saudi Arabia’s defenses, efforts to counter Iranian threats, and the importance of maintaining strong international support for Ukraine. They also discussed managing pressures in global energy markets stemming from Russia’s invasion of Ukraine and reviewed human rights issues as well as Saudi Arabia’s progress on its Vision 2030 program.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Kazakhstani Foreign Minister Tileuberdi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-kazakhstani-foreign-minister-tileuberdi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 23:46:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346414</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today in Washington, D.C. with Kazakhstani Foreign Minister Mukhtar Tileuberdi regarding the values of the United States-Kazakhstan partnership.  The Secretary reiterated the United States’ unwavering support for Kazakhstan&#8217;s independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity.  He described President Tokayev’s political and economic reforms as a positive step in promoting prosperity, strengthening security, and protecting human rights in Kazakhstan and Central Asia.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken confirmed our commitment to minimizing the impact on allies and partners, including Kazakhstan, from the sanctions imposed on Russia in response to Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war against Ukraine.  Secretary Blinken also thanked Foreign Minister Tileuberdi for Kazakhstan’s generous humanitarian assistance, both at the government level and by individuals, to the people of Ukraine.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Tileuberdi plan to stay in close contact.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today in Washington, D.C. with Kazakhstani Foreign Minister Mukhtar Tileuberdi regarding the values of the United States-Kazakhstan partnership.  The Secretary reiterated the United States’ unwavering support for Kazakhstan&#8217;s independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity.  He described President Tokayev’s political and economic reforms as a positive step in promoting prosperity, strengthening security, and protecting human rights in Kazakhstan and Central Asia.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken confirmed our commitment to minimizing the impact on allies and partners, including Kazakhstan, from the sanctions imposed on Russia in response to Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war against Ukraine.  Secretary Blinken also thanked Foreign Minister Tileuberdi for Kazakhstan’s generous humanitarian assistance, both at the government level and by individuals, to the people of Ukraine.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Tileuberdi plan to stay in close contact.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing – May 20, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-may-20-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 21:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=346333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>WASHINGTON, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon, everyone. Beyond preemptively apologizing for the limited time I’ll have with you today, I don’t have anything at the top beyond wishing everyone a Happy Friday, and we’ll turn to your questions.</p>
<p>Operator, do you mind repeating the instructions to ask a question?</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Yes, and once more, as a reminder, ladies and gentlemen, if you do have a question, please press 1 then 0 on your touchtone phone.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll go to the line of Tracy Wilkinson.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thank you. My question is about the Summit of the Americas. Ned, you a week or so ago said that once the invitations went out, you would have more to say. And now that the invitations have gone out as of Wednesday, could you talk a little bit about this – what appears to be a widening threat to boycott, what it says about the U.S. role and influence in this hemisphere that it can’t get everybody to a summit, and then the wider criticism that we’re hearing about the organization being chaotic and that it’s taken this long to get the list together – the invitation list together, this long – the agenda is still vague. Some people are saying the U.S. is sort of missing an opportunity here to really make a splash on its – on the U.S. – Biden administration’s policy towards Latin America. Thanks.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-SummitAmericas"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks, Tracy. Lots of assertions there, not many of which I would agree with, but let me start with this: The first tranche of invitations for the summit did go out yesterday. As is standard in the case of summits, we’re still considering additional invites and we’ll share the final list of invites once all invitations have gone out. We certainly understand the speculation you alluded to about who will receive an invite or who will attend – that’s understandable. It’s understandable in part because this would be the first since – summit of this sort since its inauguration in 1994 that we’ve been able to serve as host, and the first time since 2015 that a U.S. president will participate.</p>
<p>We’ll plan to work through a variety of questions by engaging directly with the countries of the region. The President has engaged with his counterparts; the Secretary has had a number of calls with his counterparts as well. He’s also engaged with special advisor for the summit, former Senator Chris Dodd. He has been traveling throughout the hemisphere, and also speaking with leaders from the region.</p>
<p>For the summit itself, our agenda is to focus on working together when it comes to the core challenges that face our hemisphere, that face our neighbors. We’re a region that’s still recovering from COVID-19. We’re a region that has endured economic shocks that are generating unprecedented levels of migration – not just to the United States, but also to Mexico and Central America. We’ll talk about shared challenges like climate change as well.</p>
<p>So, there’s a lot to talk about. We are confident that there will be robust participation. We’re confident that the summit will bring together thousands of people to focus on some of the most important and, again, shared challenges and opportunity – opportunities that face our hemisphere. In addition to heads of state and representatives of government, we also look forward to welcoming civil society stakeholders, young leaders, CEOs, business leaders from across the hemisphere, making this summit the most inclusive to date.</p>
<p>With that, why don’t we go to Shaun Tandon, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Inaudible) doing this. If you don’t mind, I’ll try to be brief on a couple of different unrelated things. North Korea – the administration has been saying for a number of days now that there’s a risk of a nuclear test. Do you have anything new on that? Is there anything new in the messaging you might have to North Korea about repercussions, if any, if they go ahead with this?</p>
<p>On China, the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Michelle Bachelet is – has confirmed a trip next week to China. Civil rights groups are critical of this, saying she could be seeing a Potemkin village. What – does the United States have an assessment of whether the trip is appropriate at this point, whether be useful, whether the Chinese will be giving access?</p>
<p>And just finally, briefly, Brittney Griner – I was wondering if there’s any update. I know the Secretary spoke to her wife recently. Do you have any more updates on the case there? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-RussiaGriner"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure, let me start with that last question first. I do have an update to offer. I can confirm that a consular officer visited Brittney Griner in detention yesterday, on Thursday, May 19th. The consular officer found her continuing to do as well as could be expected under these exceedingly challenging circumstances. But again, our message is a clear and simple one. We continue to insist that Russia allow consistent and timely consular access to all U.S. citizen detainees. One-off visits are not sufficient, and we will continue to call on Moscow to uphold its commitments under the Vienna Convention for consistent and timely access as well.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-China"></a> When it comes to China and the visit of High Commissioner for Human Rights Michelle Bachelet to the PRC, what I’ll say is that we are deeply concerned about the upcoming visit. Our understanding of the planned restrictions that she will be subjected to during the visit – based on that, we have no expectation that the PRC will grant the necessary access required to conduct a complete, unmanipulated assessment of the human rights environment in Xinjiang. The high commissioner, we believe, must act, and be allowed to act, independently; and the high commissioner must report objectively and factually on the human rights situation.</p>
<p>A credible visit to the region would feature unhindered, transparent, and unsupervised access to affected communities of the high commissioner’s choosing, as well as timely, candid, and complete reporting of the visit’s full findings. We have repeatedly made our concerns known to the PRC and to the high commissioner, and for months we and others in the international community have called upon the high commissioner to release a report drafted by her staff detailing the situation in Xinjiang. Despite frequent assurances by her office that the report would be released in short order, it remains unavailable to us, and we call on the high commissioner to release the report without delay and not to wait for the visit to do so.</p>
<p>The high commissioner’s continued silence in the face of indisputable evidence of atrocities in Xinjiang and other human rights violations and abuses throughout the PRC, it is deeply concerning, particularly as she is and should be the leading UN voice on human rights. The United States remains gravely concerned by the genocide and crimes against humanity that PRC authorities are perpetrating against Uyghurs, who are predominantly Muslim, and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups in Xinjiang. And we call on the PRC to immediately cease committing these atrocities, release those unjustly detained, and allow independent investigators full and unhindered access to the region. We’ll continue to work closely with our likeminded partners and the international community to urge an end to these atrocities and provide justice to the many victims.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-NorthKorea"></a> When it comes to the DPRK, we’ve spoken for several weeks now about our concerns for additional provocations. We’ve seen multiple tests of ICBM systems. We’ve seen additional tests of ballistic missile technology. We remain concerned that the DPRK may attempt to undertake another provocation during the course of the President’s visit to Northeast Asia or in the days following. That could include an – another ICBM test. That could include a test of a nuclear weapon. Of course, the President is in the region. He is in the region to send a message of solidarity with our partners, to send a message that the United States is there and will be there for our allies and partners to provide deterrence, to provide defense for our treaty allies in the region – of course, the ROK and Japan, both of which the President will have an opportunity to visit in the coming days – and to make very clear that we’ll respond decisively to any threats and any aggression. And, of course, our cooperation bilaterally – and in the case of the ROK and Japan, trilateral – is an essential ingredient to the way in which we will approach – what are shared security concerns in the region and beyond.</p>
<p>With that, let’s go to Missy Ryan, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi. Not sure if you guys can hear me or if you have to unmute to be unmuted, but just wondering, Ned, if you could give us an update on the discussions in NATO about the ongoing troop presence in Eastern Europe. There was a record today from CNN that’s saying that there would be a ongoing presence of 100,000 troops in Europe. And that is something that – that seems like it would be something as – sort of a forerunner to the decisions that are going to be locked in or out in Madrid. Any comment on that would be helpful. Thanks.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-NATO"></a><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Missy, I’m confident these discussions will continue, especially as we look forward to the NATO Summit in Madrid next month. These are conversations that we’ve been having within Alliance both since and before President Putin’s decision to further invade Ukraine on February 24th.</p>
<p>Before that invasion, we were clear that we would do a few things if President Putin’s aggression went ahead. We made clear that we would provide unprecedented levels of security assistance to support our Ukrainian partners so that they could effectively defend their freedom, defend their democracy, defend their country from what was then the potential of Russian aggression. We made clear that we would impose severe consequences on the Russian economy, on the Russian financial system. But to your question, we also said that we would reinforce and take steps to reassure the Alliance, the member states of the Alliance, and particularly those on the eastern flank of the NATO Alliance, and that’s what we’ve done.</p>
<p>We have – there are now some 100,000 U.S. service members on the European continent. That number has risen in recent weeks precisely because we are fulfilling the pledge that we made prior to Russian – prior to Russia’s invasion. But we will continue to speak to questions of force posture, both in terms of NATO forces and in terms of U.S. deployment as an alliance and bilaterally and multilaterally with our Allies and partners in Europe, in the weeks ahead – especially as we look towards the summit in June.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Alex Raufoglu of Turan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. Happy Friday. I have two questions, one on Russia. Russia’s supply of natural gas to Finland will be cut tomorrow morning, both Finnish and Russian energy companies confirmed today. Can I get your reaction to this latest attempt of Kremlin’s wielding natural gas flows as a weapon and its implications, if possible, for the region?</p>
<p>And secondly on Armenia and Azerbaijan, Prime Minister Pashinyan and President Aliyev will be in Brussels this weekend and they’re going to meet for the third time since last December. What is your expectation of the current ongoing negotiations process? Thanks so much.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-RussiaEnergy"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thank you very much. I think you put it well in your first question. You said Russia’s latest attempt to weaponize energy, and the fact is that this is not the first time Russia has attempted to weaponize energy. What we are doing is to work with our allies and partners to see to it that, going forward, Russia won’t be able to do this in a way that holds hostage countries in the region and around the world who have a reliance on Russian energy sources. So, in many ways, what we’re seeing from Russia is not surprising precisely because they have done this before. They have done this before, in the context of Ukraine in 2014; they have done this before in the context of Ukraine, more recently; and of course, we’ve seen them make these threats and follow through with actions in the aftermath of Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine on February 24th.</p>
<p>Since Russia’s invasion, actually well before Russia’s invasion, we began working very closely – as I mentioned before, with our allies and partners around the world, including those partners in Europe that are reliant on Russian energy. And we’ve done this with two timeframes in mind. In the short term, we have sought to ensure that there is adequate energy supply available to our allies and partners, in part by tapping various strategic petroleum reserves – our own, a million barrels a day over the course of six months is what President Biden has committed to; other allies and partners around the world are doing the same. We’re working with those same partners to see to it that energy is shipped and available to countries that may find themselves vulnerable to Russia’s manipulation in the near term.</p>
<p>Of course, this is not only a near-term challenge. There is a longer-term dimension to this as well, and our goal is to see to it that countries in Europe and countries well beyond, including countries that have been reliant on Russian energy for decades, are and will be in a position to lessen that reliance over time. In the case of Europe, in the aftermath of President Biden’s visit to Brussels last summer, we established with our European Union counterpart, the U.S.-EU Energy Council, to discuss these very issues, how we can work together to see to it that in the years to come Russia is not able to use energy as a weapon in the same way.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Humeyra Pamuk, please.</p>
<p>Oh, I’m sorry, I – you asked a second question about Armenia and Azerbaijan. Before we go to Humeyra, let me just spend a moment on that.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-ArmeniaAzerbaijan"></a> We very much welcome the dialogue between Armenia and Azerbaijan. We remain committed to promoting a peaceful, democratic, and prosperous future for the South Caucasus region as part of that. We do urge this dialogue to continue and for the parties to intensify their diplomatic engagements to make use of existing mechanisms for direct engagement, and in an effort to find comprehensive solutions to all outstanding issues related to and resulting from the Nagorno-Karabakh conflict, and – to normalize their relations through the conclusion – excuse me – conclusion of a comprehensive peace agreement. We are there to support this process. We remain ready to assist Armenia and Azerbaijan with these efforts, including in our capacity as a co-chair of the OSCE Minsk Group.</p>
<p>We’ll go to Humeyra Pamuk, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> A question on the NATO issue. While the dispute is officially between Turkey, Sweden, and Finland, American officials have said if there is anything they can do to be supportive, they’ll do it. And it’s no secret that Turkey has a number of asks from Washington. I’m wondering if the U.S. is willing to entertain any of these to solve this issue. Some of those would be expediting the F-16 sale or expediting the smaller F-16 package, or lifting any of the S-400-related sanctions. Basically, if there is anything you’re prepared to do beyond expressing your support and having consultations with Turkey.</p>
<p>Second question is: Israel said they’re holding an operational inquiry into the killing of Palestinian-American journalist Shireen Abu Akleh, but they’re not launching a criminal probe for now. Is the United States satisfied with that? Can you say if the Biden administration is committed to making sure that there will be accountability for her killing? Thanks.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-NATOTurkeySwedenFinland"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks, Humeyra. On your first question, you raised a series of bilateral topics of conversation and potential topics of conversation between the United States and Turkey. The question of Turkey’s approach to the NATO accession of Finland and Sweden, that is not a bilateral question between the United States and Turkey; that is a question before Turkey as a member of the NATO Alliance, and between and among Turkey and other members of the NATO Alliance.</p>
<p>For our part, you heard President Biden say this yesterday when he greeted his Swedish and Finnish counterparts at the White House. You heard Secretary Blinken make this same point in Berlin last week when he attended the NATO ministerial. But we strongly support NATO’s “Open Door” policy, the right of each country to decide its own future, its foreign policy, its security arrangements. And when it comes to Sweden and Finland, two countries that have now made that decision for themselves, we are proud to offer the strong support of the United States for their applications.</p>
<p>The President yesterday called them two great democracies, two close, highly capable partners to join the strongest, most powerful, defensive Alliance in the history of the world. These are countries that have been longstanding partners of the United States in terms of security, in terms of our economic integration, in terms of the important ties that bind us to the region as well.</p>
<p>As you know, we did have an opportunity to meet with – Secretary Blinken had an opportunity to meet with his Turkish counterpart yesterday in New York City. Turkey is a longstanding, valued NATO Ally. We understand Turkey’s longstanding concerns, and will continue to work together in our efforts to end the scourge of terrorism. For their part, Finland and Sweden are working directly with Turkey. But we’re also talking to Turkey about this issue. Yesterday the Secretary had a good, constructive conversation with Foreign Minister Çavuşoğlu. I’m not going to go into the full details of that engagement, beyond saying that we remain confident that Turkey’s concerns will be addressed and that we’ll be able to reach consensus as an Alliance on the accession process for Finland and Sweden. We’ve heard strong allied support for their applications, and we look forward to quickly bringing them into the strongest defensive Alliance in history.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-Israel"></a> Finally, on your question into – regarding the investigation on the killing of Shireen Abu Akleh, we reiterate the administration’s call for a thorough and transparent investigation to determine the circumstances of her killing. Investigating attacks on independent media and prosecuting those responsible are of paramount importance. We urge countries around the world to pursue accountability for attacks on journalists anywhere. And we’ll continue to promote media freedom and to protect journalists’ ability to do their jobs without fear of violence, threats to their lives or safety, or unjust detention. So again, we’ve been clear that there must be a transparent and credible investigation of Ms.<a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/shireen-abu-akleh-killed-west-bank-israel-al-jazeera-palestinian-american-journalist/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Abu Akleh</a>’s killing, and that any such investigation must include accountability.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Laura Kelly, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> How concerned is the U.S. over Turkish military flights over Greek islands, and how do those actions impact NATO’s stability?</p>
<p>And if I could ask a second question, the Anti-Corruption Foundation headed by Aleksey Navalny has compiled a list of 6,000 Russians that it wants the U.S. and allies to sanction in response to Russia’s war in Ukraine. Are you aware of this list they have compiled, and is it likely to be considered for another round of sanctions against Russia?</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-RussiaNavalnyList"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thank you very much. So, on your second question, Mr. Navalny’s organization has consistently put forward proposals. We take a look at – we take a look at what we receive and information available to us, but also information that is available in the public realm. We very much appreciate the efforts on the part of organizations, like Mr. Navalny’s, to shine a spotlight on corruption, to shine a spotlight on injustice, to shine a spotlight on repression in Russia and around the world. And so, of course, we will take a very close look at what they have put forward as we continue to hold to account the Russian Federation for its invasion of Ukraine, for its human rights abuses, for corruption, and other offenses when it comes to Russia’s conduct.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-TurkeyGreece"></a> On your first question on Turkish overflights, we encourage all countries to respect the sovereign airspace of other countries and to operate state aircraft with due regard for the safety of navigation of civil aircraft. Where disagreements exist over the limits of a country’s territorial airspace, we urge coordination and discussion, not provocative actions that could lead to deadly accidents. As a matter of principle, we encourage all states to resolve maritime delimitation issues peacefully and in accordance with international law.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Cindy Saine.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> I don’t show Cindy on any longer. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Okay. Let’s go to Joseph Haboush, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Inaudible) to ask, over the last week we’ve seen the Secretary of Defense speak to his Russian counterpart, and then I believe yesterday we saw General Milley also speak with his Russian counterpart. Are there any plans or is there any will to have a conversation between Secretary Blinken and his counterpart Lavrov? Is there – or are there any updates on the U.S. trying to open a line of communication there? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-RussiaDiplomacy"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks, Joseph. So, we discussed this earlier this week in the last briefing, so let me briefly recap. As you know, prior to the February 24th Russian invasion of Ukraine, Secretary Blinken was at the forefront of the effort to attempt to forestall what may well have been an inevitability the whole time. But Secretary Blinken traveled around the world, met with his Russian counterpart. Deputy Secretary Sherman met with her Russian counterpart. Both of them took part in phone calls in an effort to prevent what has since taken place.</p>
<p>We have demonstrated time and again that we believe in the power of dialogue and the effectiveness and the usefulness of open lines of communication. But we also believe that there needs to be the potential for any such engagement to have a constructive outcome and to advance the ultimate and overriding objective. And of course, in this case the ultimate and overriding objective is a diminution of violence in Ukraine leading an end to this brutal war of aggression – a brutal war of choice, against the people, the government, and the state of Ukraine.</p>
<p>It is, in our assessment, not the time at the moment for a high-level call between Secretary Blinken or other seniors at the department precisely because we have seen no indication just yet that the Russians are serious about engaging in a constructive dialogue that could help to advance the prospects for a diminution of the violence or ultimately putting this conflict to an end. If we feel that a conversation has the potential to do that, has the potential to save lives, of course we won’t hesitate to do that.</p>
<p>In the meantime, I don’t have to tell you because you’ve seen the readouts. You’ve seen our travel around the world, including to be with our allies and partners in Europe that the Secretary has been leading the diplomatic effort to provide support to our Ukrainian partners, to provide security assistance to them, to provide economic assistance to them, and to provide humanitarian assistance to the Ukrainian people. He’s been leading the effort to hold Russia to account for its actions in Ukraine and its actions against its own people, and he will continue to engage with our allies and partners, including as we look to the Madrid summit next month to convene the NATO Allies.</p>
<p>We’ll go to Kylie Atwood, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Ned. Thanks for doing this. Quick question on a report yesterday from <em>The Wall Street Journal</em> about the Biden administration weighing the possibility of waiving Belarus potash sanctions to get Lukashenko to allow a corridor from Ukraine to Lithuania to get that grain out of Ukraine. I know you guys don’t preview sanctions, or sanctions relief for that matter. But would the administration consider any form of sanctions relief if Russia, or Belarus for that matter, were to come to some sort of agreement to essentially entice them to get this grain out of the country?</p>
<p>And then my second question is just a bit of a throwback here, something we haven’t talked about in a while, but the State Department concluded their Afghanistan withdrawal review, as I understand it, back in March or April. And I’m just wondering when the State Department plans to present those findings, at least the unclassified portion of it, speaking to kind of transparency and the fact that you guys said you would reflect upon the lessons that could be learned. Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-GlobalFoodSecurity"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks, Kylie. So on your first question, of course, we had an opportunity over the past couple days in New York City to discuss the issue of food security and food insecurity owing to longer-term challenges like climate change, but also owing to in many cases what is the proximate cause of food scarcity and the rise in commodity prices, and that is Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>It is very simply that the Government of Russia, using food as a weapon in this case by blocking the exports – the export of foodstuffs from Ukraine’s ports, the Kremlin has sought to deflect responsibility for its actions by blaming sanctions for disruptions to the global food system. This is patently false. Our sanctions on Russia specifically exclude food and fertilizer.</p>
<p>On the other hand, it is very clear that it is President Putin’s unjustified, his unprovoked, his brutal war against Ukraine that has put millions around the globe at risk of food insecurity and whose effects are felt thousands of miles away by many of the world’s most vulnerable citizens. And so when we think about what would be the most effective means by which to alleviate the challenge of food insecurity, of course, that would be for the Kremlin to end this senseless war; to see them let farmers safely plant, harvest, tend to their fields; to let ships loaded with essential food commodities and related goods to sail freely; and essentially, to stop weaponizing the flow of food and foodstuffs from Ukraine and from Ukraine’s ports.</p>
<p>In terms of the broader issue, no country has done more than the United States to seek to address that, and Secretary Blinken was able to convene dozens of high-level officials, including many of his counterparts, on Wednesday and Thursday of this week in the UN General Assembly but also in the Security Council to discuss this very issue. This is something that the UN secretary-general has focused on as well. We support his efforts to persuade Russia to end its unprovoked, unjustified war, and his efforts to see to it that Ukraine is able to export its agricultural products unhindered to once again help feed the world.</p>
<p>When it comes to Belarus, we sanctioned Belarusian state-owned potash producer Belaruskali and its primary exporting arm in coordination with our transatlantic allies in 2020. This was to impose costs on the Lukashenka regime following the fraudulent 2020 elections and the regime’s ensuing crackdown on peaceful protests and human rights – peaceful protests and human rights and fundamental freedoms. It is the Lukashenka regime that uses these state-owned enterprises to enrich and to sustain its repressive regime. And until the regime ends its support for Russia’s unprovoked aggression against Ukraine, we’ll continue to take all appropriate actions to disrupt its military’s – its military and financial capabilities through targeted sanctions, including the actions taken against Russia.</p>
<p>So as you alluded to at the top, we don’t preview potential upcoming actions, but sanctions will remain a key tool in our efforts to address global security concerns as well as human rights abuses in Belarus and other areas of concern for the United States.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-Afghanistan"></a> On Afghanistan, you are right that we did launch a review, an after-action review, covering the couple years before the military withdrawal from Afghanistan late last year. We are reviewing the findings of that review, and we’ll let you know when we’re at a point to potentially say more on that front.</p>
<p>We have time for one final question. Let’s go to Ali Harb.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong>At this time, I don’t show Ali Harb in queue.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Okay, let’s go to the line of Shannon Crawford.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thanks so much. Just a quick question about the family of Paul Whelan. They’ve put out a statement saying that State Department representatives have told them they need to make more noise or be a squeakier wheel to get the attention of the administration, or perhaps to prove that Paul’s case deserves action. Can you comment on this?</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-StateDept"></a><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Thank you for the question. We know that each of these cases deserve action, and we are taking action in each and every one of these cases. It is accurate, it is true, that we don’t often speak publicly to what we’re doing behind the scenes, but Secretary Blinken is committed to seeing to it that this department, including the office of our special envoy – special presidential envoy for hostage affairs, is doing everything we potentially can to see the safe and effective release of Americans who are unjustly or wrongfully detained or held hostage around the world.</p>
<p>We remain in regular contact with the families of those held hostage or wrongfully detained. We are absolutely grateful for their partnership and feedback, and we continue to work to ensure that we’re communicating and sharing information in a way that is useful to families. One of the most vital sources of information to us is that communication with the families. There is no one that knows the context, that knows the background, that knows the history of any particular case better than the families and the loved ones of those who are held hostage or wrongfully detained around the world. It’s why it’s so vitally important to us that we continue that coordination and that communication, even as we are often taking steps that we don’t speak to publicly to ensure that we are doing everything we can to effect the safe release of Americans who are wrongfully detained or held hostage.</p>
<p>Thank you very much, everyone. We will see you back at the department next week. In the meantime, have a good weekend.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:28 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>WASHINGTON, D.C.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon, everyone. Beyond preemptively apologizing for the limited time I’ll have with you today, I don’t have anything at the top beyond wishing everyone a Happy Friday, and we’ll turn to your questions.</p>
<p>Operator, do you mind repeating the instructions to ask a question?</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Yes, and once more, as a reminder, ladies and gentlemen, if you do have a question, please press 1 then 0 on your touchtone phone.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll go to the line of Tracy Wilkinson.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thank you. My question is about the Summit of the Americas. Ned, you a week or so ago said that once the invitations went out, you would have more to say. And now that the invitations have gone out as of Wednesday, could you talk a little bit about this – what appears to be a widening threat to boycott, what it says about the U.S. role and influence in this hemisphere that it can’t get everybody to a summit, and then the wider criticism that we’re hearing about the organization being chaotic and that it’s taken this long to get the list together – the invitation list together, this long – the agenda is still vague. Some people are saying the U.S. is sort of missing an opportunity here to really make a splash on its – on the U.S. – Biden administration’s policy towards Latin America. Thanks.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-SummitAmericas"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks, Tracy. Lots of assertions there, not many of which I would agree with, but let me start with this: The first tranche of invitations for the summit did go out yesterday. As is standard in the case of summits, we’re still considering additional invites and we’ll share the final list of invites once all invitations have gone out. We certainly understand the speculation you alluded to about who will receive an invite or who will attend – that’s understandable. It’s understandable in part because this would be the first since – summit of this sort since its inauguration in 1994 that we’ve been able to serve as host, and the first time since 2015 that a U.S. president will participate.</p>
<p>We’ll plan to work through a variety of questions by engaging directly with the countries of the region. The President has engaged with his counterparts; the Secretary has had a number of calls with his counterparts as well. He’s also engaged with special advisor for the summit, former Senator Chris Dodd. He has been traveling throughout the hemisphere, and also speaking with leaders from the region.</p>
<p>For the summit itself, our agenda is to focus on working together when it comes to the core challenges that face our hemisphere, that face our neighbors. We’re a region that’s still recovering from COVID-19. We’re a region that has endured economic shocks that are generating unprecedented levels of migration – not just to the United States, but also to Mexico and Central America. We’ll talk about shared challenges like climate change as well.</p>
<p>So, there’s a lot to talk about. We are confident that there will be robust participation. We’re confident that the summit will bring together thousands of people to focus on some of the most important and, again, shared challenges and opportunity – opportunities that face our hemisphere. In addition to heads of state and representatives of government, we also look forward to welcoming civil society stakeholders, young leaders, CEOs, business leaders from across the hemisphere, making this summit the most inclusive to date.</p>
<p>With that, why don’t we go to Shaun Tandon, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Inaudible) doing this. If you don’t mind, I’ll try to be brief on a couple of different unrelated things. North Korea – the administration has been saying for a number of days now that there’s a risk of a nuclear test. Do you have anything new on that? Is there anything new in the messaging you might have to North Korea about repercussions, if any, if they go ahead with this?</p>
<p>On China, the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Michelle Bachelet is – has confirmed a trip next week to China. Civil rights groups are critical of this, saying she could be seeing a Potemkin village. What – does the United States have an assessment of whether the trip is appropriate at this point, whether be useful, whether the Chinese will be giving access?</p>
<p>And just finally, briefly, Brittney Griner – I was wondering if there’s any update. I know the Secretary spoke to her wife recently. Do you have any more updates on the case there? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-RussiaGriner"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure, let me start with that last question first. I do have an update to offer. I can confirm that a consular officer visited Brittney Griner in detention yesterday, on Thursday, May 19th. The consular officer found her continuing to do as well as could be expected under these exceedingly challenging circumstances. But again, our message is a clear and simple one. We continue to insist that Russia allow consistent and timely consular access to all U.S. citizen detainees. One-off visits are not sufficient, and we will continue to call on Moscow to uphold its commitments under the Vienna Convention for consistent and timely access as well.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-China"></a> When it comes to China and the visit of High Commissioner for Human Rights Michelle Bachelet to the PRC, what I’ll say is that we are deeply concerned about the upcoming visit. Our understanding of the planned restrictions that she will be subjected to during the visit – based on that, we have no expectation that the PRC will grant the necessary access required to conduct a complete, unmanipulated assessment of the human rights environment in Xinjiang. The high commissioner, we believe, must act, and be allowed to act, independently; and the high commissioner must report objectively and factually on the human rights situation.</p>
<p>A credible visit to the region would feature unhindered, transparent, and unsupervised access to affected communities of the high commissioner’s choosing, as well as timely, candid, and complete reporting of the visit’s full findings. We have repeatedly made our concerns known to the PRC and to the high commissioner, and for months we and others in the international community have called upon the high commissioner to release a report drafted by her staff detailing the situation in Xinjiang. Despite frequent assurances by her office that the report would be released in short order, it remains unavailable to us, and we call on the high commissioner to release the report without delay and not to wait for the visit to do so.</p>
<p>The high commissioner’s continued silence in the face of indisputable evidence of atrocities in Xinjiang and other human rights violations and abuses throughout the PRC, it is deeply concerning, particularly as she is and should be the leading UN voice on human rights. The United States remains gravely concerned by the genocide and crimes against humanity that PRC authorities are perpetrating against Uyghurs, who are predominantly Muslim, and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups in Xinjiang. And we call on the PRC to immediately cease committing these atrocities, release those unjustly detained, and allow independent investigators full and unhindered access to the region. We’ll continue to work closely with our likeminded partners and the international community to urge an end to these atrocities and provide justice to the many victims.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-NorthKorea"></a> When it comes to the DPRK, we’ve spoken for several weeks now about our concerns for additional provocations. We’ve seen multiple tests of ICBM systems. We’ve seen additional tests of ballistic missile technology. We remain concerned that the DPRK may attempt to undertake another provocation during the course of the President’s visit to Northeast Asia or in the days following. That could include an – another ICBM test. That could include a test of a nuclear weapon. Of course, the President is in the region. He is in the region to send a message of solidarity with our partners, to send a message that the United States is there and will be there for our allies and partners to provide deterrence, to provide defense for our treaty allies in the region – of course, the ROK and Japan, both of which the President will have an opportunity to visit in the coming days – and to make very clear that we’ll respond decisively to any threats and any aggression. And, of course, our cooperation bilaterally – and in the case of the ROK and Japan, trilateral – is an essential ingredient to the way in which we will approach – what are shared security concerns in the region and beyond.</p>
<p>With that, let’s go to Missy Ryan, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hi. Not sure if you guys can hear me or if you have to unmute to be unmuted, but just wondering, Ned, if you could give us an update on the discussions in NATO about the ongoing troop presence in Eastern Europe. There was a record today from CNN that’s saying that there would be a ongoing presence of 100,000 troops in Europe. And that is something that – that seems like it would be something as – sort of a forerunner to the decisions that are going to be locked in or out in Madrid. Any comment on that would be helpful. Thanks.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-NATO"></a><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Missy, I’m confident these discussions will continue, especially as we look forward to the NATO Summit in Madrid next month. These are conversations that we’ve been having within Alliance both since and before President Putin’s decision to further invade Ukraine on February 24th.</p>
<p>Before that invasion, we were clear that we would do a few things if President Putin’s aggression went ahead. We made clear that we would provide unprecedented levels of security assistance to support our Ukrainian partners so that they could effectively defend their freedom, defend their democracy, defend their country from what was then the potential of Russian aggression. We made clear that we would impose severe consequences on the Russian economy, on the Russian financial system. But to your question, we also said that we would reinforce and take steps to reassure the Alliance, the member states of the Alliance, and particularly those on the eastern flank of the NATO Alliance, and that’s what we’ve done.</p>
<p>We have – there are now some 100,000 U.S. service members on the European continent. That number has risen in recent weeks precisely because we are fulfilling the pledge that we made prior to Russian – prior to Russia’s invasion. But we will continue to speak to questions of force posture, both in terms of NATO forces and in terms of U.S. deployment as an alliance and bilaterally and multilaterally with our Allies and partners in Europe, in the weeks ahead – especially as we look towards the summit in June.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Alex Raufoglu of Turan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Ned. Happy Friday. I have two questions, one on Russia. Russia’s supply of natural gas to Finland will be cut tomorrow morning, both Finnish and Russian energy companies confirmed today. Can I get your reaction to this latest attempt of Kremlin’s wielding natural gas flows as a weapon and its implications, if possible, for the region?</p>
<p>And secondly on Armenia and Azerbaijan, Prime Minister Pashinyan and President Aliyev will be in Brussels this weekend and they’re going to meet for the third time since last December. What is your expectation of the current ongoing negotiations process? Thanks so much.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-RussiaEnergy"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thank you very much. I think you put it well in your first question. You said Russia’s latest attempt to weaponize energy, and the fact is that this is not the first time Russia has attempted to weaponize energy. What we are doing is to work with our allies and partners to see to it that, going forward, Russia won’t be able to do this in a way that holds hostage countries in the region and around the world who have a reliance on Russian energy sources. So, in many ways, what we’re seeing from Russia is not surprising precisely because they have done this before. They have done this before, in the context of Ukraine in 2014; they have done this before in the context of Ukraine, more recently; and of course, we’ve seen them make these threats and follow through with actions in the aftermath of Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine on February 24th.</p>
<p>Since Russia’s invasion, actually well before Russia’s invasion, we began working very closely – as I mentioned before, with our allies and partners around the world, including those partners in Europe that are reliant on Russian energy. And we’ve done this with two timeframes in mind. In the short term, we have sought to ensure that there is adequate energy supply available to our allies and partners, in part by tapping various strategic petroleum reserves – our own, a million barrels a day over the course of six months is what President Biden has committed to; other allies and partners around the world are doing the same. We’re working with those same partners to see to it that energy is shipped and available to countries that may find themselves vulnerable to Russia’s manipulation in the near term.</p>
<p>Of course, this is not only a near-term challenge. There is a longer-term dimension to this as well, and our goal is to see to it that countries in Europe and countries well beyond, including countries that have been reliant on Russian energy for decades, are and will be in a position to lessen that reliance over time. In the case of Europe, in the aftermath of President Biden’s visit to Brussels last summer, we established with our European Union counterpart, the U.S.-EU Energy Council, to discuss these very issues, how we can work together to see to it that in the years to come Russia is not able to use energy as a weapon in the same way.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Humeyra Pamuk, please.</p>
<p>Oh, I’m sorry, I – you asked a second question about Armenia and Azerbaijan. Before we go to Humeyra, let me just spend a moment on that.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-ArmeniaAzerbaijan"></a> We very much welcome the dialogue between Armenia and Azerbaijan. We remain committed to promoting a peaceful, democratic, and prosperous future for the South Caucasus region as part of that. We do urge this dialogue to continue and for the parties to intensify their diplomatic engagements to make use of existing mechanisms for direct engagement, and in an effort to find comprehensive solutions to all outstanding issues related to and resulting from the Nagorno-Karabakh conflict, and – to normalize their relations through the conclusion – excuse me – conclusion of a comprehensive peace agreement. We are there to support this process. We remain ready to assist Armenia and Azerbaijan with these efforts, including in our capacity as a co-chair of the OSCE Minsk Group.</p>
<p>We’ll go to Humeyra Pamuk, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> A question on the NATO issue. While the dispute is officially between Turkey, Sweden, and Finland, American officials have said if there is anything they can do to be supportive, they’ll do it. And it’s no secret that Turkey has a number of asks from Washington. I’m wondering if the U.S. is willing to entertain any of these to solve this issue. Some of those would be expediting the F-16 sale or expediting the smaller F-16 package, or lifting any of the S-400-related sanctions. Basically, if there is anything you’re prepared to do beyond expressing your support and having consultations with Turkey.</p>
<p>Second question is: Israel said they’re holding an operational inquiry into the killing of Palestinian-American journalist Shireen Abu Akleh, but they’re not launching a criminal probe for now. Is the United States satisfied with that? Can you say if the Biden administration is committed to making sure that there will be accountability for her killing? Thanks.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-NATOTurkeySwedenFinland"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks, Humeyra. On your first question, you raised a series of bilateral topics of conversation and potential topics of conversation between the United States and Turkey. The question of Turkey’s approach to the NATO accession of Finland and Sweden, that is not a bilateral question between the United States and Turkey; that is a question before Turkey as a member of the NATO Alliance, and between and among Turkey and other members of the NATO Alliance.</p>
<p>For our part, you heard President Biden say this yesterday when he greeted his Swedish and Finnish counterparts at the White House. You heard Secretary Blinken make this same point in Berlin last week when he attended the NATO ministerial. But we strongly support NATO’s “Open Door” policy, the right of each country to decide its own future, its foreign policy, its security arrangements. And when it comes to Sweden and Finland, two countries that have now made that decision for themselves, we are proud to offer the strong support of the United States for their applications.</p>
<p>The President yesterday called them two great democracies, two close, highly capable partners to join the strongest, most powerful, defensive Alliance in the history of the world. These are countries that have been longstanding partners of the United States in terms of security, in terms of our economic integration, in terms of the important ties that bind us to the region as well.</p>
<p>As you know, we did have an opportunity to meet with – Secretary Blinken had an opportunity to meet with his Turkish counterpart yesterday in New York City. Turkey is a longstanding, valued NATO Ally. We understand Turkey’s longstanding concerns, and will continue to work together in our efforts to end the scourge of terrorism. For their part, Finland and Sweden are working directly with Turkey. But we’re also talking to Turkey about this issue. Yesterday the Secretary had a good, constructive conversation with Foreign Minister Çavuşoğlu. I’m not going to go into the full details of that engagement, beyond saying that we remain confident that Turkey’s concerns will be addressed and that we’ll be able to reach consensus as an Alliance on the accession process for Finland and Sweden. We’ve heard strong allied support for their applications, and we look forward to quickly bringing them into the strongest defensive Alliance in history.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-Israel"></a> Finally, on your question into – regarding the investigation on the killing of Shireen Abu Akleh, we reiterate the administration’s call for a thorough and transparent investigation to determine the circumstances of her killing. Investigating attacks on independent media and prosecuting those responsible are of paramount importance. We urge countries around the world to pursue accountability for attacks on journalists anywhere. And we’ll continue to promote media freedom and to protect journalists’ ability to do their jobs without fear of violence, threats to their lives or safety, or unjust detention. So again, we’ve been clear that there must be a transparent and credible investigation of Ms.<a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/shireen-abu-akleh-killed-west-bank-israel-al-jazeera-palestinian-american-journalist/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Abu Akleh</a>’s killing, and that any such investigation must include accountability.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Laura Kelly, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> How concerned is the U.S. over Turkish military flights over Greek islands, and how do those actions impact NATO’s stability?</p>
<p>And if I could ask a second question, the Anti-Corruption Foundation headed by Aleksey Navalny has compiled a list of 6,000 Russians that it wants the U.S. and allies to sanction in response to Russia’s war in Ukraine. Are you aware of this list they have compiled, and is it likely to be considered for another round of sanctions against Russia?</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-RussiaNavalnyList"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thank you very much. So, on your second question, Mr. Navalny’s organization has consistently put forward proposals. We take a look at – we take a look at what we receive and information available to us, but also information that is available in the public realm. We very much appreciate the efforts on the part of organizations, like Mr. Navalny’s, to shine a spotlight on corruption, to shine a spotlight on injustice, to shine a spotlight on repression in Russia and around the world. And so, of course, we will take a very close look at what they have put forward as we continue to hold to account the Russian Federation for its invasion of Ukraine, for its human rights abuses, for corruption, and other offenses when it comes to Russia’s conduct.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-TurkeyGreece"></a> On your first question on Turkish overflights, we encourage all countries to respect the sovereign airspace of other countries and to operate state aircraft with due regard for the safety of navigation of civil aircraft. Where disagreements exist over the limits of a country’s territorial airspace, we urge coordination and discussion, not provocative actions that could lead to deadly accidents. As a matter of principle, we encourage all states to resolve maritime delimitation issues peacefully and in accordance with international law.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Cindy Saine.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> I don’t show Cindy on any longer. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Okay. Let’s go to Joseph Haboush, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Inaudible) to ask, over the last week we’ve seen the Secretary of Defense speak to his Russian counterpart, and then I believe yesterday we saw General Milley also speak with his Russian counterpart. Are there any plans or is there any will to have a conversation between Secretary Blinken and his counterpart Lavrov? Is there – or are there any updates on the U.S. trying to open a line of communication there? Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-RussiaDiplomacy"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks, Joseph. So, we discussed this earlier this week in the last briefing, so let me briefly recap. As you know, prior to the February 24th Russian invasion of Ukraine, Secretary Blinken was at the forefront of the effort to attempt to forestall what may well have been an inevitability the whole time. But Secretary Blinken traveled around the world, met with his Russian counterpart. Deputy Secretary Sherman met with her Russian counterpart. Both of them took part in phone calls in an effort to prevent what has since taken place.</p>
<p>We have demonstrated time and again that we believe in the power of dialogue and the effectiveness and the usefulness of open lines of communication. But we also believe that there needs to be the potential for any such engagement to have a constructive outcome and to advance the ultimate and overriding objective. And of course, in this case the ultimate and overriding objective is a diminution of violence in Ukraine leading an end to this brutal war of aggression – a brutal war of choice, against the people, the government, and the state of Ukraine.</p>
<p>It is, in our assessment, not the time at the moment for a high-level call between Secretary Blinken or other seniors at the department precisely because we have seen no indication just yet that the Russians are serious about engaging in a constructive dialogue that could help to advance the prospects for a diminution of the violence or ultimately putting this conflict to an end. If we feel that a conversation has the potential to do that, has the potential to save lives, of course we won’t hesitate to do that.</p>
<p>In the meantime, I don’t have to tell you because you’ve seen the readouts. You’ve seen our travel around the world, including to be with our allies and partners in Europe that the Secretary has been leading the diplomatic effort to provide support to our Ukrainian partners, to provide security assistance to them, to provide economic assistance to them, and to provide humanitarian assistance to the Ukrainian people. He’s been leading the effort to hold Russia to account for its actions in Ukraine and its actions against its own people, and he will continue to engage with our allies and partners, including as we look to the Madrid summit next month to convene the NATO Allies.</p>
<p>We’ll go to Kylie Atwood, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Ned. Thanks for doing this. Quick question on a report yesterday from <em>The Wall Street Journal</em> about the Biden administration weighing the possibility of waiving Belarus potash sanctions to get Lukashenko to allow a corridor from Ukraine to Lithuania to get that grain out of Ukraine. I know you guys don’t preview sanctions, or sanctions relief for that matter. But would the administration consider any form of sanctions relief if Russia, or Belarus for that matter, were to come to some sort of agreement to essentially entice them to get this grain out of the country?</p>
<p>And then my second question is just a bit of a throwback here, something we haven’t talked about in a while, but the State Department concluded their Afghanistan withdrawal review, as I understand it, back in March or April. And I’m just wondering when the State Department plans to present those findings, at least the unclassified portion of it, speaking to kind of transparency and the fact that you guys said you would reflect upon the lessons that could be learned. Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-GlobalFoodSecurity"></a><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thanks, Kylie. So on your first question, of course, we had an opportunity over the past couple days in New York City to discuss the issue of food security and food insecurity owing to longer-term challenges like climate change, but also owing to in many cases what is the proximate cause of food scarcity and the rise in commodity prices, and that is Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>It is very simply that the Government of Russia, using food as a weapon in this case by blocking the exports – the export of foodstuffs from Ukraine’s ports, the Kremlin has sought to deflect responsibility for its actions by blaming sanctions for disruptions to the global food system. This is patently false. Our sanctions on Russia specifically exclude food and fertilizer.</p>
<p>On the other hand, it is very clear that it is President Putin’s unjustified, his unprovoked, his brutal war against Ukraine that has put millions around the globe at risk of food insecurity and whose effects are felt thousands of miles away by many of the world’s most vulnerable citizens. And so when we think about what would be the most effective means by which to alleviate the challenge of food insecurity, of course, that would be for the Kremlin to end this senseless war; to see them let farmers safely plant, harvest, tend to their fields; to let ships loaded with essential food commodities and related goods to sail freely; and essentially, to stop weaponizing the flow of food and foodstuffs from Ukraine and from Ukraine’s ports.</p>
<p>In terms of the broader issue, no country has done more than the United States to seek to address that, and Secretary Blinken was able to convene dozens of high-level officials, including many of his counterparts, on Wednesday and Thursday of this week in the UN General Assembly but also in the Security Council to discuss this very issue. This is something that the UN secretary-general has focused on as well. We support his efforts to persuade Russia to end its unprovoked, unjustified war, and his efforts to see to it that Ukraine is able to export its agricultural products unhindered to once again help feed the world.</p>
<p>When it comes to Belarus, we sanctioned Belarusian state-owned potash producer Belaruskali and its primary exporting arm in coordination with our transatlantic allies in 2020. This was to impose costs on the Lukashenka regime following the fraudulent 2020 elections and the regime’s ensuing crackdown on peaceful protests and human rights – peaceful protests and human rights and fundamental freedoms. It is the Lukashenka regime that uses these state-owned enterprises to enrich and to sustain its repressive regime. And until the regime ends its support for Russia’s unprovoked aggression against Ukraine, we’ll continue to take all appropriate actions to disrupt its military’s – its military and financial capabilities through targeted sanctions, including the actions taken against Russia.</p>
<p>So as you alluded to at the top, we don’t preview potential upcoming actions, but sanctions will remain a key tool in our efforts to address global security concerns as well as human rights abuses in Belarus and other areas of concern for the United States.</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-Afghanistan"></a> On Afghanistan, you are right that we did launch a review, an after-action review, covering the couple years before the military withdrawal from Afghanistan late last year. We are reviewing the findings of that review, and we’ll let you know when we’re at a point to potentially say more on that front.</p>
<p>We have time for one final question. Let’s go to Ali Harb.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong>At this time, I don’t show Ali Harb in queue.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Okay, let’s go to the line of Shannon Crawford.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thanks so much. Just a quick question about the family of Paul Whelan. They’ve put out a statement saying that State Department representatives have told them they need to make more noise or be a squeakier wheel to get the attention of the administration, or perhaps to prove that Paul’s case deserves action. Can you comment on this?</p>
<p><a id="post-346333-StateDept"></a><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Thank you for the question. We know that each of these cases deserve action, and we are taking action in each and every one of these cases. It is accurate, it is true, that we don’t often speak publicly to what we’re doing behind the scenes, but Secretary Blinken is committed to seeing to it that this department, including the office of our special envoy – special presidential envoy for hostage affairs, is doing everything we potentially can to see the safe and effective release of Americans who are unjustly or wrongfully detained or held hostage around the world.</p>
<p>We remain in regular contact with the families of those held hostage or wrongfully detained. We are absolutely grateful for their partnership and feedback, and we continue to work to ensure that we’re communicating and sharing information in a way that is useful to families. One of the most vital sources of information to us is that communication with the families. There is no one that knows the context, that knows the background, that knows the history of any particular case better than the families and the loved ones of those who are held hostage or wrongfully detained around the world. It’s why it’s so vitally important to us that we continue that coordination and that communication, even as we are often taking steps that we don’t speak to publicly to ensure that we are doing everything we can to effect the safe release of Americans who are wrongfully detained or held hostage.</p>
<p>Thank you very much, everyone. We will see you back at the department next week. In the meantime, have a good weekend.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:28 p.m.)</p>
<p># # #</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary of State Blinken’s Travel to Japan on May 21-24</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-of-state-blinkens-travel-to-japan-on-may-21-24/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346319</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Tokyo, Japan, May 21-24 to accompany President Biden on his first official trip to Asia as President to meet with Japanese Prime Minister Kishida Fumio and attend the Quad Leaders’ Summit.  While in Tokyo, the Secretary will meet with Foreign Minister Hayashi Yoshimasa and other senior Japanese officials.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister will discuss our global response to President Putin’s continued brutal war on Ukraine, the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea’s increasingly destabilizing behavior, and U.S.-Japan cooperation under the new Economic Policy Consultative Committee (EPCC), including on regional economic development.  He will also join President Biden for the launch of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, which will tackle 21st century economic challenges and deliver for the American people and people in the region.</p>
<p align="left">The Secretary&#8217;s visit will reaffirm the U.S.-Japan Alliance’s central role as the cornerstone of peace, security, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region and around the world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Tokyo, Japan, May 21-24 to accompany President Biden on his first official trip to Asia as President to meet with Japanese Prime Minister Kishida Fumio and attend the Quad Leaders’ Summit.  While in Tokyo, the Secretary will meet with Foreign Minister Hayashi Yoshimasa and other senior Japanese officials.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister will discuss our global response to President Putin’s continued brutal war on Ukraine, the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea’s increasingly destabilizing behavior, and U.S.-Japan cooperation under the new Economic Policy Consultative Committee (EPCC), including on regional economic development.  He will also join President Biden for the launch of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, which will tackle 21st century economic challenges and deliver for the American people and people in the region.</p>
<p align="left">The Secretary&#8217;s visit will reaffirm the U.S.-Japan Alliance’s central role as the cornerstone of peace, security, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region and around the world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Delegation on Atrocity Prevention and Response to Travel to The Hague</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-delegation-on-atrocity-prevention-and-response-to-travel-to-the-hague/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 18:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">A U.S. delegation led by Assistant Secretary of State for Conflict and Stabilization Operations Anne A. Witkowsky, Ambassador-at-Large for Global Criminal Justice Beth Van Schaack, and Bureau of International Organization Affairs Deputy Assistant Secretary Allison Lombardo will travel to The Hague, the Netherlands, from May 22 to 25, 2022.</p>
<p align="left">In The Hague, the U.S. delegation will hold high-level talks with allies and partners regarding our responses to atrocities committed in Ukraine, Burma, Ethiopia, and other locations experiencing violence.  They will also examine how to mitigate the drivers of atrocity risk in regions where preventative efforts can effectively preempt atrocities.  The delegation will review support for accountability measures and mechanisms to bring the perpetrators of atrocities to justice, including those committed in the context of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, through the Biden-Harris Administration’s newly announced European Democratic Resilience Initiative (EDRI).</p>
<p align="left">Also in The Hague, Assistant Secretary Witkowsky will meet with Dutch government counterparts to underscore our deep and longstanding transatlantic commitment to European security and coordination.  She will emphasize the need for comprehensive partnerships to address shared security concerns, including to advance implementation of the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.</p>
<p align="left">Follow @StateCSO and @StateDept_GCJ on Twitter for updates.  For more information, please contact CSO Public Affairs at <a href="mailto:CSOPublicAffairs1@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSOPublicAffairs1@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">A U.S. delegation led by Assistant Secretary of State for Conflict and Stabilization Operations Anne A. Witkowsky, Ambassador-at-Large for Global Criminal Justice Beth Van Schaack, and Bureau of International Organization Affairs Deputy Assistant Secretary Allison Lombardo will travel to The Hague, the Netherlands, from May 22 to 25, 2022.</p>
<p align="left">In The Hague, the U.S. delegation will hold high-level talks with allies and partners regarding our responses to atrocities committed in Ukraine, Burma, Ethiopia, and other locations experiencing violence.  They will also examine how to mitigate the drivers of atrocity risk in regions where preventative efforts can effectively preempt atrocities.  The delegation will review support for accountability measures and mechanisms to bring the perpetrators of atrocities to justice, including those committed in the context of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, through the Biden-Harris Administration’s newly announced European Democratic Resilience Initiative (EDRI).</p>
<p align="left">Also in The Hague, Assistant Secretary Witkowsky will meet with Dutch government counterparts to underscore our deep and longstanding transatlantic commitment to European security and coordination.  She will emphasize the need for comprehensive partnerships to address shared security concerns, including to advance implementation of the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.</p>
<p align="left">Follow @StateCSO and @StateDept_GCJ on Twitter for updates.  For more information, please contact CSO Public Affairs at <a href="mailto:CSOPublicAffairs1@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSOPublicAffairs1@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ambassador Hussain’s Trip to Saudi Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/ambassador-hussains-trip-to-saudi-arabia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 18:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">U.S. Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom Rashad Hussain traveled to Riyadh and Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, from May 11-15, 2022.</p>
<p align="left">In Riyahd, Ambassador Hussain attended the Forum on Promoting Common Values among the Followers of Religion.  There, he met with ministers of religious affairs and civil society, in attendance, including the Ecumenical Patriarch Bartholomew and the Secretary General of the Muslim World League.  For the first time in Saudi Arabia, the event convened representatives from Christian, Jewish, Hindu and Buddhist faith traditions alongside Islamic leaders to explore shared values and a common global vision for interfaith cooperation.  Leaders from faith communities from around the world, many of whom had never visited Saudi Arabia, also attended.  Ambassador Hussain spoke with attendees on the urgent need for the international community to protect religious freedom worldwide, repeal and cease enforcement of blasphemy and apostasy laws, confront crimes against humanity and genocide against Uyghurs and Rohingya, and support the empowerment of marginalized communities, including women and girls.</p>
<p align="left">Ambassador Hussain also traveled to Jeddah, where he met with Organisation of Islamic Cooperation (OIC) officials and members, including the Secretary General of the OIC and the Islamic Development Bank, to discuss how their organizations can advance religious freedom for all, address the treatment of Muslim minorities including Uyghurs and Rohingya, and respond to the threats to religious freedom in Afghanistan.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">U.S. Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom Rashad Hussain traveled to Riyadh and Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, from May 11-15, 2022.</p>
<p align="left">In Riyahd, Ambassador Hussain attended the Forum on Promoting Common Values among the Followers of Religion.  There, he met with ministers of religious affairs and civil society, in attendance, including the Ecumenical Patriarch Bartholomew and the Secretary General of the Muslim World League.  For the first time in Saudi Arabia, the event convened representatives from Christian, Jewish, Hindu and Buddhist faith traditions alongside Islamic leaders to explore shared values and a common global vision for interfaith cooperation.  Leaders from faith communities from around the world, many of whom had never visited Saudi Arabia, also attended.  Ambassador Hussain spoke with attendees on the urgent need for the international community to protect religious freedom worldwide, repeal and cease enforcement of blasphemy and apostasy laws, confront crimes against humanity and genocide against Uyghurs and Rohingya, and support the empowerment of marginalized communities, including women and girls.</p>
<p align="left">Ambassador Hussain also traveled to Jeddah, where he met with Organisation of Islamic Cooperation (OIC) officials and members, including the Secretary General of the OIC and the Islamic Development Bank, to discuss how their organizations can advance religious freedom for all, address the treatment of Muslim minorities including Uyghurs and Rohingya, and respond to the threats to religious freedom in Afghanistan.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General Delattre</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-french-foreign-ministry-secretary-general-delattre-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 17:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346268</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General François Delattre today to discuss continued coordination to support Ukraine and its sovereignty in the face of Putin’s unprovoked and unjustified war.  In addition, they highlighted the need for swift international action to confront the growing crisis of food insecurity, exacerbated by Russia&#8217;s full-scale invasion.  The two also exchanged views on developments in NATO, including Finland and Sweden’s welcome request to join, and the lead up to the Madrid Summit.  Deputy Secretary Sherman also discussed with Secretary General Delattre France’s plans for the final weeks of France’s presidency of the Council of the European Union, including support for EU accession paths for aspirants willing to do the hard work to qualify for membership.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General François Delattre today to discuss continued coordination to support Ukraine and its sovereignty in the face of Putin’s unprovoked and unjustified war.  In addition, they highlighted the need for swift international action to confront the growing crisis of food insecurity, exacerbated by Russia&#8217;s full-scale invasion.  The two also exchanged views on developments in NATO, including Finland and Sweden’s welcome request to join, and the lead up to the Madrid Summit.  Deputy Secretary Sherman also discussed with Secretary General Delattre France’s plans for the final weeks of France’s presidency of the Council of the European Union, including support for EU accession paths for aspirants willing to do the hard work to qualify for membership.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Kazakhstani Foreign Minister Mukhtar Tileuberdi Before Their Meeting </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-kazakhstani-foreign-minister-mukhtar-tileuberdi-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Mukhtar Tileuberdi, Kazakhstani Foreign Minister]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 17:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Mukhtar Tileuberdi, Kazakhstani Foreign Minister</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good morning everyone, and welcome to our friends and colleagues.  It’s very good to have Foreign Minister Tileuberdi here today.  We have been strategic partners with Kazakhstan for 30 years, something that we value very much.  We very much support as well the important efforts at political and economic reform that are taking place now in Kazakhstan.  This long relationship is one girded by our strong commitment to Kazakhstan’s independence, sovereignty, territorial integrity.</p>
<p>We have a lot to talk about today in terms of the region, security.  What we’re seeing among other things from Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine are profound impacts beyond Ukraine, including in Central Asia – food, energy, trade – and we’re working to address all of these second and third order effects of the aggression.</p>
<p>So Mukhtar, it’s very good to have you here.  Thank you for being here, and I look forward to a good conversation.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER TILEUBERDI:</strong>  Dear Secretary of State, thank you for the invitation to visit Washington, D.C., and for the warm welcome.  And I am here today with a special mission to deliver our key messages, to reaffirm our steadfast commitment to further advance our Enhanced Strategic Partnership with the United States.</p>
<p>Just also using this opportunity, I would like to thank you for your initiative to the ministerial meeting on global food security.  I participated in New York this 18 of May, and I believe that it was important and timely event to address the actual issues and the challenges, which is very important especially for our region of Central Asia.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, everyone.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Mukhtar Tileuberdi, Kazakhstani Foreign Minister</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good morning everyone, and welcome to our friends and colleagues.  It’s very good to have Foreign Minister Tileuberdi here today.  We have been strategic partners with Kazakhstan for 30 years, something that we value very much.  We very much support as well the important efforts at political and economic reform that are taking place now in Kazakhstan.  This long relationship is one girded by our strong commitment to Kazakhstan’s independence, sovereignty, territorial integrity.</p>
<p>We have a lot to talk about today in terms of the region, security.  What we’re seeing among other things from Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine are profound impacts beyond Ukraine, including in Central Asia – food, energy, trade – and we’re working to address all of these second and third order effects of the aggression.</p>
<p>So Mukhtar, it’s very good to have you here.  Thank you for being here, and I look forward to a good conversation.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER TILEUBERDI:</strong>  Dear Secretary of State, thank you for the invitation to visit Washington, D.C., and for the warm welcome.  And I am here today with a special mission to deliver our key messages, to reaffirm our steadfast commitment to further advance our Enhanced Strategic Partnership with the United States.</p>
<p>Just also using this opportunity, I would like to thank you for your initiative to the ministerial meeting on global food security.  I participated in New York this 18 of May, and I believe that it was important and timely event to address the actual issues and the challenges, which is very important especially for our region of Central Asia.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, everyone.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
