<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 17:04:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Joint Statement of the United States and Finland on Cooperation in Quantum Information Science and Technology</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-of-the-united-states-and-finland-on-cooperation-in-quantum-information-science-and-technology/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 17:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332086</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><i>The text of the following joint statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and the Republic of Finland on the occasion of a U.S.-Finland meeting held April 5, 2022, on science and technology.</i></p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>Recognizing that science, technology, and innovation have enabled transformative capabilities across multiple sectors, from energy to health and communications to transportation, and that the foundation of this progress is the global research enterprise, and its constant creation of new knowledge, understanding, and insights;</p>
<p>Appreciating that Quantum Information Science and Technology (QIST) revolutionizes both our understanding of fundamental phenomena as well as the development of powerful computers, secure and rapid communication, and sensors with unprecedented precision, accuracy, and modalities;</p>
<p>Understanding that the emergence of such robust technologies depends on an intensive effort to expand theoretical and practical understandings of QIST and to develop new tools for characterization, validation, and verification purposes;</p>
<p>Acknowledging that international partnerships are key to combine the expertise, ingenuity, and creativity of our countries to expand our fundamental understanding of QIST and thereby accelerate the realization of new technologies for the benefit of humanity; and</p>
<p>Mindful of the terms of research and innovation programs in which both nations actively participate, and within which both advocate for international cooperation to be as open as possible;</p>
<p>We, signed below, intend to harness the spirit of science, technology, and innovation to pursue cooperation and the mutual respect it confers, and to promote QIST including but not limited to quantum computing, quantum networking, and quantum sensing, which underpins the development of society and industry.</p>
<p>We intend to advance this agenda by:</p>
<ul>
<li>Embarking on good-faith cooperation, that is underpinned by our shared principles, including openness, transparency, honesty, equity, fair competition, objectivity, and democratic values.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Committing to create inclusive scientific research communities and tackle cross-cutting issues of common interest such as equity, diversity, inclusion, and accessibility, so that every person is able to fully participate and have an equal opportunity to succeed.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Collaborating in venues such as workshops, seminars, and conferences to discuss and recognize the progress of research in QIST, which in turn will lead to the identification of overlapping interests and opportunities for future scientific cooperation.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Promoting avenues to encourage a broad and inclusive quantum ecosystem to facilitate multidisciplinary research, and to share research methodologies, infrastructure and data, when appropriate.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Fostering shared economic prosperity by building a trusted global market and supply chain for QIST R&amp;D, and supporting economic growth, by engaging stakeholders including industry consortia, research leaders, policy makers, and business security stakeholders to grow the future QIST marketplace based on shared engagement principles.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Supporting the development of the next generation of scientists and engineers necessary to expand the field, which could include personnel exchanges and other potential mechanisms</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Leveraging regular multilateral opportunities to discuss QIST matters of international importance and respective policy issues.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Exploring other potential activities to be decided upon by participating countries.</li>
</ul>
<p>We confirm our mutual understanding that cooperation informed and enabled by this Statement will leverage, as appropriate, the Agreement Relating to Scientific and Technological Cooperation between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Republic of Finland as an operational framework.</p>
<p>We intend to focus on cooperation in QIST as outlined in this vision for the mutual benefit of participating countries and continue to enhance scientific cooperation under our respective leaderships.</p>
<p><i>End text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><i>The text of the following joint statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and the Republic of Finland on the occasion of a U.S.-Finland meeting held April 5, 2022, on science and technology.</i></p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>Recognizing that science, technology, and innovation have enabled transformative capabilities across multiple sectors, from energy to health and communications to transportation, and that the foundation of this progress is the global research enterprise, and its constant creation of new knowledge, understanding, and insights;</p>
<p>Appreciating that Quantum Information Science and Technology (QIST) revolutionizes both our understanding of fundamental phenomena as well as the development of powerful computers, secure and rapid communication, and sensors with unprecedented precision, accuracy, and modalities;</p>
<p>Understanding that the emergence of such robust technologies depends on an intensive effort to expand theoretical and practical understandings of QIST and to develop new tools for characterization, validation, and verification purposes;</p>
<p>Acknowledging that international partnerships are key to combine the expertise, ingenuity, and creativity of our countries to expand our fundamental understanding of QIST and thereby accelerate the realization of new technologies for the benefit of humanity; and</p>
<p>Mindful of the terms of research and innovation programs in which both nations actively participate, and within which both advocate for international cooperation to be as open as possible;</p>
<p>We, signed below, intend to harness the spirit of science, technology, and innovation to pursue cooperation and the mutual respect it confers, and to promote QIST including but not limited to quantum computing, quantum networking, and quantum sensing, which underpins the development of society and industry.</p>
<p>We intend to advance this agenda by:</p>
<ul>
<li>Embarking on good-faith cooperation, that is underpinned by our shared principles, including openness, transparency, honesty, equity, fair competition, objectivity, and democratic values.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Committing to create inclusive scientific research communities and tackle cross-cutting issues of common interest such as equity, diversity, inclusion, and accessibility, so that every person is able to fully participate and have an equal opportunity to succeed.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Collaborating in venues such as workshops, seminars, and conferences to discuss and recognize the progress of research in QIST, which in turn will lead to the identification of overlapping interests and opportunities for future scientific cooperation.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Promoting avenues to encourage a broad and inclusive quantum ecosystem to facilitate multidisciplinary research, and to share research methodologies, infrastructure and data, when appropriate.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Fostering shared economic prosperity by building a trusted global market and supply chain for QIST R&amp;D, and supporting economic growth, by engaging stakeholders including industry consortia, research leaders, policy makers, and business security stakeholders to grow the future QIST marketplace based on shared engagement principles.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Supporting the development of the next generation of scientists and engineers necessary to expand the field, which could include personnel exchanges and other potential mechanisms</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Leveraging regular multilateral opportunities to discuss QIST matters of international importance and respective policy issues.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Exploring other potential activities to be decided upon by participating countries.</li>
</ul>
<p>We confirm our mutual understanding that cooperation informed and enabled by this Statement will leverage, as appropriate, the Agreement Relating to Scientific and Technological Cooperation between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Republic of Finland as an operational framework.</p>
<p>We intend to focus on cooperation in QIST as outlined in this vision for the mutual benefit of participating countries and continue to enhance scientific cooperation under our respective leaderships.</p>
<p><i>End text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Australian Foreign Minister Payne</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-australian-foreign-minister-payne-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 16:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332080</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Australian Foreign Minister Marise Payne in Brussels. The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed joint efforts to hold the Russian Federation accountable for its unprovoked and unjust war against Ukraine as well as mutual efforts to provide security assistance to Ukraine.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister reiterated their commitment to ensuring peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific region and noted the April 4 release of the AUKUS Leaders’ Statement, summarizing the progress AUKUS partners have made over the past six months.  They also shared concerns about recent regional developments and ways to support countries in making open and transparent decisions about their own security and economic interests.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Australian Foreign Minister Marise Payne in Brussels. The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed joint efforts to hold the Russian Federation accountable for its unprovoked and unjust war against Ukraine as well as mutual efforts to provide security assistance to Ukraine.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister reiterated their commitment to ensuring peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific region and noted the April 4 release of the AUKUS Leaders’ Statement, summarizing the progress AUKUS partners have made over the past six months.  They also shared concerns about recent regional developments and ways to support countries in making open and transparent decisions about their own security and economic interests.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>50th Anniversary of the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/50th-anniversary-of-the-biological-and-toxin-weapons-convention/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 15:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Fifty years ago, the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention (BTWC) was opened for signature and later became the first treaty to ban an entire category of weapons. Today, with over 180 States Parties, it is the cornerstone of international efforts to prevent biological weapons.</p>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic demonstrated the devastating impact that disease can have on the world. We must recognize that other biological risks are growing and take action to address them. We face not only an increased threat of naturally occurring diseases, but also the potential for laboratory accidents and the intentional misuse of life sciences and biotechnology. The weaponization of biological agents and toxins violates the BTWC and is unacceptable, and the use of biological weapons – in the words of the Convention – “would be repugnant to the conscience of mankind.”</p>
<p>We are determined to use the occasion of this important anniversary as a reminder of the need to strengthen and revitalize the BTWC. As we look to its Ninth Review Conference later this year, the United States urges States Parties to overcome differences and take urgent steps to guard against the development and use of biological weapons.</p>
<p>Specifically, we believe the Review Conference should take near-term, concrete action to strengthen the Convention and benefit States Parties in such areas as increasing resources for international assistance and cooperation and establishing a mechanism to review advances in science and technology. Additionally, we have proposed that the Conference establish a new expert group to study additional measures to strengthen implementation of the Convention, increase transparency, and enhance assurances of compliance. We also urge all states that have not yet become party to the BTWC to join it now, so they can play an active role in this year’s Review Conference.</p>
<p>The best way to commemorate this anniversary is for States Parties to work together to strengthen the BTWC and end the threat of biological weapons. Through our collective action to counter all biological threats – naturally occurring, accidental, and deliberate – we can make the world a safer place for all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Fifty years ago, the Biological and Toxin Weapons Convention (BTWC) was opened for signature and later became the first treaty to ban an entire category of weapons. Today, with over 180 States Parties, it is the cornerstone of international efforts to prevent biological weapons.</p>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic demonstrated the devastating impact that disease can have on the world. We must recognize that other biological risks are growing and take action to address them. We face not only an increased threat of naturally occurring diseases, but also the potential for laboratory accidents and the intentional misuse of life sciences and biotechnology. The weaponization of biological agents and toxins violates the BTWC and is unacceptable, and the use of biological weapons – in the words of the Convention – “would be repugnant to the conscience of mankind.”</p>
<p>We are determined to use the occasion of this important anniversary as a reminder of the need to strengthen and revitalize the BTWC. As we look to its Ninth Review Conference later this year, the United States urges States Parties to overcome differences and take urgent steps to guard against the development and use of biological weapons.</p>
<p>Specifically, we believe the Review Conference should take near-term, concrete action to strengthen the Convention and benefit States Parties in such areas as increasing resources for international assistance and cooperation and establishing a mechanism to review advances in science and technology. Additionally, we have proposed that the Conference establish a new expert group to study additional measures to strengthen implementation of the Convention, increase transparency, and enhance assurances of compliance. We also urge all states that have not yet become party to the BTWC to join it now, so they can play an active role in this year’s Review Conference.</p>
<p>The best way to commemorate this anniversary is for States Parties to work together to strengthen the BTWC and end the threat of biological weapons. Through our collective action to counter all biological threats – naturally occurring, accidental, and deliberate – we can make the world a safer place for all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with Andrea Mitchell of NBC</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-andrea-mitchell-of-nbc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 15:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=332032</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Mr. Secretary, thank you so much for being with us.  I wanted to ask you about what is going on right now.  The chairman of the Joint Chiefs had told Congress that this will likely last years, this war.  A protracted war is going to last years, according to the chairman of the Joint Chiefs.  Will today’s new commitment of Javelins, anti-tank weapons to Ukraine shorten that timeline?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Andrea, we want to see this come to an end as quickly as possible, and that’s exactly why we’re making sure that we’re doing everything we can to support Ukraine and to give them the assistance that they need to put pressure and to increase pressure on Russia, even as we’re strengthening our – the defenses of our NATO Alliance.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So what about the Javelins?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So the Javelins, we just did – the President authorized another $100 million in a drawdown that will provide more Javelins to our Ukrainian partners.  Put this in perspective:  Between the United States and other allies and partners, for every Russian tank in Ukraine, we have provided or will soon provide 10 anti-tank systems – 10 for every single Russian tank.  So in terms of what they need to act quickly and act effectively, to deal with the planes that are firing at them from the skies, the tanks that are trying to destroy their cities from the ground, they have the tools that they need, they’re going to keep getting them, and we’re going to keep sustaining that.</p>
<p>But to the chairman’s point, and the President said this as well, as much as we want to see this come to an end as soon as possible to stop the death and destruction that’s being wrought by Russia in Ukraine, there is also a very likely scenario by which this goes on for some time.  The Russians, even as they’re moving their forces, they’ve retreated from Kyiv, they’ve retreated from the north and the west, they’re consolidating forces in the east, in the Donbas.  They have a lot of force still left.  The Ukrainians have something else that’s ultimately stronger, and that is a fierce determination and will to defend their country with the support of many countries around the world.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Can they win?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So ultimately, yes, because what is success, what is victory?  It’s holding on to the sovereignty and independence of their country.  And there is no scenario by which over time that will not happen.  The problem is it may take time, and in the meantime, tremendous death and destruction.  But what is so powerful here is that the Ukrainians have made it very clear that they will not subjugate themselves to Vladimir Putin’s will.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But no matter how much we give them, how can Ukraine ever last against Russia for the long term unless the U.S. and other countries guarantee its borders, its safety, as President Zelenskyy wants?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, first things first.  The first thing is to see that this aggression by Russia comes to an end, that there is a ceasefire, that Russia withdraws its forces, that Ukraine asserts its sovereignty and its independence.  But then, yes, we have to do things to make sure that, to the best of our ability and Ukraine’s ability, this can’t happen again, that Russia is deterred, that Ukraine is defended.  We’re having constant conversations with &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will we guarantee that?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So we’re having &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will the U.S. get more involved?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We’re having constant conversations with our Ukrainian partners pretty much on a daily basis, including about what it is we and others could do in the event of a successful negotiation to defend them and help them defend themselves going forward.  All of this is the subject of conversations right now.  I’m not going to get ahead of that, but we’re going to do everything we can, others will do what they can to make sure that Ukraine can defend itself and deter aggression being repeated by Russia.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  President Putin has said he wants to recreate the Soviet Union, the glory of the Soviet Union.  With those ambitions, how can Ukraine ever be safe as long as Putin’s in power?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, two things:  First, in terms of what Russia set out to do, what Putin set out to do in Ukraine, this has already been a strategic setback, if not a failure.  Because keep in mind, Andrea, the goal that Putin set in his own words was to eliminate Ukraine’s sovereignty and independence.  He sees it as a state that doesn’t deserve to be independent, that needs to be subsumed back into some kind of greater Russia.  That is not happening, not just the retreat from Kyiv but the fact that no matter how you play this out the Ukrainians are not going to subject themselves to a Russian dictatorship.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  He’s more popular than ever at home.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So he may be for now more popular.  Of course, if you were getting fed a steady diet, morning, noon, and night of propaganda, which unfortunately the Russian people are, that speaks to what popularity he has.  At the same time, when people are responding to polls, they may be very much afraid of giving the truthful answer.  There’s now a 15-year criminal penalty for anyone who in any way opposes the so-called special military operation.  So you have to take that with a grain of salt.</p>
<p>Having said that, I think there is a real fundamental problem, which is the Russians don’t get the factual information that they need to make judgments for themselves, and that’s because of a system that Vladimir Putin has perfected in which that information is denied them.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  President Biden has called Putin a butcher, a war criminal.  You have said that the people responsible for the crimes in Bucha and those who ordered them will be held accountable.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  That’s right.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  How can that happen without Vladimir Putin standing trial?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  First, Andrea, the wheels of accountability can move slowly, but they move, and someday, someway, somewhere, those who committed these crimes and those who ordered the crimes will be held accountable.  But it takes time, and part of this is building the case, part of this is – which we’re doing and others are doing.  Part – there’s a Ukrainian special prosecutor who is working on this.  We’re supporting her efforts.  We set up at the United Nations at the Human Rights Council a Commission of Inquiry that’s looking into this as well.  We’re supporting those efforts, building the case, getting the evidence, documenting it.  The International Criminal Court is looking at this too.</p>
<p>But all of this will play out over time, and we have to build the case, we have to get the evidence, we have to document it – we’re doing all of that.  So is that next month, next year, in five years?  It could take time, but I think – I can guarantee you there will be a relentless effort to make sure that those responsible for what we’re seeing are held accountable.  And what we’re seeing, Andrea, is I think beyond what any of us even could fully anticipate.  We said before Russia committed this aggression that there would be atrocities, that it was a deliberate part of their campaign.  And even knowing that, when this Russian tide receded from Bucha and we saw the death and destruction left in its wake, and we saw what that looked like, including people who had been assassinated – and in fact, their hands tied – executed, their hands tied behind their backs – the abuse committed against women, against children, it’s horrific.  And there has to be accountability for it.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Did you see the video that President Zelenskyy provided to the United Nations, or other images from Bucha?  As you describe it, the atrocities, you have small children.  What do you tell your children?  What would you tell them?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, thankfully, they’re too small to actually see that, be able to digest it and to understand it.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But some day, they’ll – they will &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  But some day they will.  And I have to tell you, Andrea, I think – and I suspect most of us have the same reaction, especially those of who have children or even small children – you put yourself in the shoes of the father, the mother, the grandfather, the grandmother who’s in the middle of this, who is suffering this, whose kids’ lives are at stake or in jeopardy, or who have been lost.  And it hits you – I said the other day, seeing these images from Bucha was like a punch to the gut.  It takes the wind out of you.  You can know something intellectually, but then when you see these images and you translate that into your own life, when you ask yourself, “What if this was happening in my town, to my kids?  To my family?”  I think it only reinforces our determination to do everything we can to support the Ukrainians, to put pressure on Russia, to bring this to an end as quickly as possible.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Your UN ambassador, Linda Thomas-Greenfield, described these atrocities and compared it by extension to the Holocaust.  Talked about what the council in Mariupol had described, people forcibly – tens of thousands – taken from their homes, taken to Russia and put in camps.  Isn’t that the very definition of genocide?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, we have to get all of the information, all of the evidence.  We have to, as I said, document everything that’s happened, fully understand what’s happened.  It’s an interesting irony in a sense.  This is in some ways the most documented war in real time that we’ve experienced because of technology, because of smart phones, because of the incredible courage of reporters who remained in Ukraine.  But even so, the things that we’re not seeing in real time, including Bucha – and it’s only when that tide recedes that you see what’s actually happened.</p>
<p>So I think we’re going to learn a lot more in the days and weeks ahead.  I’m afraid that what we’re going to learn is even more horrifying.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Do we know anything about what’s happening in these Russian camps with Ukrainians, and do we have any hope of getting them back?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We don’t have good information on that, but certainly we’re doing everything we can.  Other countries are doing everything they can to make sure that anyone who is being detained is released.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  The U.S. has promised to take in 100,000 of these millions of refugees.  Europe has opened their doors, put them in their homes.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  They have.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  NBC has reported on at least two women, two Ukrainian women on the southern border, who were taken and for two weeks put behind barbed wire and at times shackled in an ICE camp.  How can we do that compared to the way Europe is welcoming them?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, I’m not aware of those reports.  It’s something I’ll certainly look into.  But here’s what’s going on.  First, Europeans have been extraordinary in their generosity, in opening their hearts, opening their arms, opening their homes to so many people.  Our friends in Poland, in the first instance, have had more than 2 million people come through Poland.  Many of the refugees – most of them, in fact – want to stay close to home because what you’re seeing, Andrea – and I know you’ve seen this firsthand – is virtually everyone is a woman and children.  Most of the men between 18 and 60 have stayed in Ukraine to fight.  They like to stay close at hand.  They want to go back, they want to be reunited with their husbands, with their brothers, with their sons.  And once they’re in Europe, they also have a lot of freedom of movement and the ability to reunite with other family members there.</p>
<p>Having said that, President Biden made clear that we will welcome 100,000 Ukrainians.  We’re ‑‑</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Is there a time frame?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So it’s over a period of time.  What we’re doing right now is looking at what are the legal pathways that we can do that because there’s the normal refugee program, but that, by definition, takes a long time.  It takes a couple years –</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Quick question before we lose time: sanctions.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Yeah.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  New sanctions, now Europe is putting on new sanctions.  China and India keep buying fuel from Russia and fueling this war, helping to fund Putin’s war.  Why aren’t we sanctioning China and India?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So in the first instance, Andrea, these sanctions are having a dramatic impact.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But there are big loopholes, and Europe still is buying natural gas and still will for another year.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  There are loopholes that, piece by piece, one by one, we’re trying to close.  Sometimes that takes time.  But let’s look at what’s already happened.  The sanctions cumulatively have put the Russian economy into a deep recession.  And what we’re seeing is a likely contraction of the Russian economy by about 15 percent.  That is dramatic.  We’ve seen something else.  We’ve seen an exodus from Russia of virtually every major company in the world.  And Putin, in the space of a matter of weeks, has basically shut down Russia to the world.  All of the opening, all of the opportunity that took place over the last 30 years is gone.  And the Russians will feel that, I’m afraid, in their daily lives.  They won’t be able to buy the things they’re used to buying, and they won’t be able to afford to buy what they’d like to buy.</p>
<p>And beyond that, the export controls that we put in place, denying Russia the technology that it needs to modernize critical industries like defense, like energy extraction – over time, those are going to have an even greater impact.</p>
<p>So we’re already seeing a dramatic impact to this.  And yes, there are places where different countries are doing different things.  We’re working every single day to close that down.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Quick question on Iran before I let you go.  You’re talking about Iran here in Brussels.  Is Iran’s Revolutionary Guard – which has attacked Americans and our allies – a terrorist organization?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So, they are.  And &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will they continue to be?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I’m not going to get into the details of where we are on the negotiations.  I would say simply that I’m not overly optimistic at the prospects of actually getting an agreement to conclusion, despite all the efforts we put into it and despite the fact that I believe we would be – our security would be better off.  We’re not there.  We’ll have to see if we can close &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Is time running out?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  And time is getting extremely short.  But this is something that we’ll be talking to our European partners about this afternoon and then over the course of the next day.  We’ve been working in very close coordination with the Europeans, with the European Union, with France, with Germany, with the UK.</p>
<p>So we’ll see where we get.  I continue to believe it would be in the best interests of our country if we can get back into compliance with the deal, if Iran will do the same.  We’re not there.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  Thanks for your patience.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks, Andrea.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Good to see you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  You as well.  Thanks.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Mr. Secretary, thank you so much for being with us.  I wanted to ask you about what is going on right now.  The chairman of the Joint Chiefs had told Congress that this will likely last years, this war.  A protracted war is going to last years, according to the chairman of the Joint Chiefs.  Will today’s new commitment of Javelins, anti-tank weapons to Ukraine shorten that timeline?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Andrea, we want to see this come to an end as quickly as possible, and that’s exactly why we’re making sure that we’re doing everything we can to support Ukraine and to give them the assistance that they need to put pressure and to increase pressure on Russia, even as we’re strengthening our – the defenses of our NATO Alliance.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  So what about the Javelins?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So the Javelins, we just did – the President authorized another $100 million in a drawdown that will provide more Javelins to our Ukrainian partners.  Put this in perspective:  Between the United States and other allies and partners, for every Russian tank in Ukraine, we have provided or will soon provide 10 anti-tank systems – 10 for every single Russian tank.  So in terms of what they need to act quickly and act effectively, to deal with the planes that are firing at them from the skies, the tanks that are trying to destroy their cities from the ground, they have the tools that they need, they’re going to keep getting them, and we’re going to keep sustaining that.</p>
<p>But to the chairman’s point, and the President said this as well, as much as we want to see this come to an end as soon as possible to stop the death and destruction that’s being wrought by Russia in Ukraine, there is also a very likely scenario by which this goes on for some time.  The Russians, even as they’re moving their forces, they’ve retreated from Kyiv, they’ve retreated from the north and the west, they’re consolidating forces in the east, in the Donbas.  They have a lot of force still left.  The Ukrainians have something else that’s ultimately stronger, and that is a fierce determination and will to defend their country with the support of many countries around the world.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Can they win?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So ultimately, yes, because what is success, what is victory?  It’s holding on to the sovereignty and independence of their country.  And there is no scenario by which over time that will not happen.  The problem is it may take time, and in the meantime, tremendous death and destruction.  But what is so powerful here is that the Ukrainians have made it very clear that they will not subjugate themselves to Vladimir Putin’s will.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But no matter how much we give them, how can Ukraine ever last against Russia for the long term unless the U.S. and other countries guarantee its borders, its safety, as President Zelenskyy wants?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, first things first.  The first thing is to see that this aggression by Russia comes to an end, that there is a ceasefire, that Russia withdraws its forces, that Ukraine asserts its sovereignty and its independence.  But then, yes, we have to do things to make sure that, to the best of our ability and Ukraine’s ability, this can’t happen again, that Russia is deterred, that Ukraine is defended.  We’re having constant conversations with &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will we guarantee that?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So we’re having &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will the U.S. get more involved?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We’re having constant conversations with our Ukrainian partners pretty much on a daily basis, including about what it is we and others could do in the event of a successful negotiation to defend them and help them defend themselves going forward.  All of this is the subject of conversations right now.  I’m not going to get ahead of that, but we’re going to do everything we can, others will do what they can to make sure that Ukraine can defend itself and deter aggression being repeated by Russia.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  President Putin has said he wants to recreate the Soviet Union, the glory of the Soviet Union.  With those ambitions, how can Ukraine ever be safe as long as Putin’s in power?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, two things:  First, in terms of what Russia set out to do, what Putin set out to do in Ukraine, this has already been a strategic setback, if not a failure.  Because keep in mind, Andrea, the goal that Putin set in his own words was to eliminate Ukraine’s sovereignty and independence.  He sees it as a state that doesn’t deserve to be independent, that needs to be subsumed back into some kind of greater Russia.  That is not happening, not just the retreat from Kyiv but the fact that no matter how you play this out the Ukrainians are not going to subject themselves to a Russian dictatorship.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  He’s more popular than ever at home.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So he may be for now more popular.  Of course, if you were getting fed a steady diet, morning, noon, and night of propaganda, which unfortunately the Russian people are, that speaks to what popularity he has.  At the same time, when people are responding to polls, they may be very much afraid of giving the truthful answer.  There’s now a 15-year criminal penalty for anyone who in any way opposes the so-called special military operation.  So you have to take that with a grain of salt.</p>
<p>Having said that, I think there is a real fundamental problem, which is the Russians don’t get the factual information that they need to make judgments for themselves, and that’s because of a system that Vladimir Putin has perfected in which that information is denied them.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  President Biden has called Putin a butcher, a war criminal.  You have said that the people responsible for the crimes in Bucha and those who ordered them will be held accountable.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  That’s right.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  How can that happen without Vladimir Putin standing trial?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  First, Andrea, the wheels of accountability can move slowly, but they move, and someday, someway, somewhere, those who committed these crimes and those who ordered the crimes will be held accountable.  But it takes time, and part of this is building the case, part of this is – which we’re doing and others are doing.  Part – there’s a Ukrainian special prosecutor who is working on this.  We’re supporting her efforts.  We set up at the United Nations at the Human Rights Council a Commission of Inquiry that’s looking into this as well.  We’re supporting those efforts, building the case, getting the evidence, documenting it.  The International Criminal Court is looking at this too.</p>
<p>But all of this will play out over time, and we have to build the case, we have to get the evidence, we have to document it – we’re doing all of that.  So is that next month, next year, in five years?  It could take time, but I think – I can guarantee you there will be a relentless effort to make sure that those responsible for what we’re seeing are held accountable.  And what we’re seeing, Andrea, is I think beyond what any of us even could fully anticipate.  We said before Russia committed this aggression that there would be atrocities, that it was a deliberate part of their campaign.  And even knowing that, when this Russian tide receded from Bucha and we saw the death and destruction left in its wake, and we saw what that looked like, including people who had been assassinated – and in fact, their hands tied – executed, their hands tied behind their backs – the abuse committed against women, against children, it’s horrific.  And there has to be accountability for it.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Did you see the video that President Zelenskyy provided to the United Nations, or other images from Bucha?  As you describe it, the atrocities, you have small children.  What do you tell your children?  What would you tell them?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, thankfully, they’re too small to actually see that, be able to digest it and to understand it.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But some day, they’ll – they will &#8212;</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  But some day they will.  And I have to tell you, Andrea, I think – and I suspect most of us have the same reaction, especially those of who have children or even small children – you put yourself in the shoes of the father, the mother, the grandfather, the grandmother who’s in the middle of this, who is suffering this, whose kids’ lives are at stake or in jeopardy, or who have been lost.  And it hits you – I said the other day, seeing these images from Bucha was like a punch to the gut.  It takes the wind out of you.  You can know something intellectually, but then when you see these images and you translate that into your own life, when you ask yourself, “What if this was happening in my town, to my kids?  To my family?”  I think it only reinforces our determination to do everything we can to support the Ukrainians, to put pressure on Russia, to bring this to an end as quickly as possible.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Your UN ambassador, Linda Thomas-Greenfield, described these atrocities and compared it by extension to the Holocaust.  Talked about what the council in Mariupol had described, people forcibly – tens of thousands – taken from their homes, taken to Russia and put in camps.  Isn’t that the very definition of genocide?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, we have to get all of the information, all of the evidence.  We have to, as I said, document everything that’s happened, fully understand what’s happened.  It’s an interesting irony in a sense.  This is in some ways the most documented war in real time that we’ve experienced because of technology, because of smart phones, because of the incredible courage of reporters who remained in Ukraine.  But even so, the things that we’re not seeing in real time, including Bucha – and it’s only when that tide recedes that you see what’s actually happened.</p>
<p>So I think we’re going to learn a lot more in the days and weeks ahead.  I’m afraid that what we’re going to learn is even more horrifying.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Do we know anything about what’s happening in these Russian camps with Ukrainians, and do we have any hope of getting them back?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  We don’t have good information on that, but certainly we’re doing everything we can.  Other countries are doing everything they can to make sure that anyone who is being detained is released.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  The U.S. has promised to take in 100,000 of these millions of refugees.  Europe has opened their doors, put them in their homes.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  They have.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  NBC has reported on at least two women, two Ukrainian women on the southern border, who were taken and for two weeks put behind barbed wire and at times shackled in an ICE camp.  How can we do that compared to the way Europe is welcoming them?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, I’m not aware of those reports.  It’s something I’ll certainly look into.  But here’s what’s going on.  First, Europeans have been extraordinary in their generosity, in opening their hearts, opening their arms, opening their homes to so many people.  Our friends in Poland, in the first instance, have had more than 2 million people come through Poland.  Many of the refugees – most of them, in fact – want to stay close to home because what you’re seeing, Andrea – and I know you’ve seen this firsthand – is virtually everyone is a woman and children.  Most of the men between 18 and 60 have stayed in Ukraine to fight.  They like to stay close at hand.  They want to go back, they want to be reunited with their husbands, with their brothers, with their sons.  And once they’re in Europe, they also have a lot of freedom of movement and the ability to reunite with other family members there.</p>
<p>Having said that, President Biden made clear that we will welcome 100,000 Ukrainians.  We’re ‑‑</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Is there a time frame?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So it’s over a period of time.  What we’re doing right now is looking at what are the legal pathways that we can do that because there’s the normal refugee program, but that, by definition, takes a long time.  It takes a couple years –</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Quick question before we lose time: sanctions.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Yeah.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  New sanctions, now Europe is putting on new sanctions.  China and India keep buying fuel from Russia and fueling this war, helping to fund Putin’s war.  Why aren’t we sanctioning China and India?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So in the first instance, Andrea, these sanctions are having a dramatic impact.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  But there are big loopholes, and Europe still is buying natural gas and still will for another year.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  There are loopholes that, piece by piece, one by one, we’re trying to close.  Sometimes that takes time.  But let’s look at what’s already happened.  The sanctions cumulatively have put the Russian economy into a deep recession.  And what we’re seeing is a likely contraction of the Russian economy by about 15 percent.  That is dramatic.  We’ve seen something else.  We’ve seen an exodus from Russia of virtually every major company in the world.  And Putin, in the space of a matter of weeks, has basically shut down Russia to the world.  All of the opening, all of the opportunity that took place over the last 30 years is gone.  And the Russians will feel that, I’m afraid, in their daily lives.  They won’t be able to buy the things they’re used to buying, and they won’t be able to afford to buy what they’d like to buy.</p>
<p>And beyond that, the export controls that we put in place, denying Russia the technology that it needs to modernize critical industries like defense, like energy extraction – over time, those are going to have an even greater impact.</p>
<p>So we’re already seeing a dramatic impact to this.  And yes, there are places where different countries are doing different things.  We’re working every single day to close that down.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Quick question on Iran before I let you go.  You’re talking about Iran here in Brussels.  Is Iran’s Revolutionary Guard – which has attacked Americans and our allies – a terrorist organization?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  So, they are.  And &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Will they continue to be?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  I’m not going to get into the details of where we are on the negotiations.  I would say simply that I’m not overly optimistic at the prospects of actually getting an agreement to conclusion, despite all the efforts we put into it and despite the fact that I believe we would be – our security would be better off.  We’re not there.  We’ll have to see if we can close &#8212;</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Is time running out?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  And time is getting extremely short.  But this is something that we’ll be talking to our European partners about this afternoon and then over the course of the next day.  We’ve been working in very close coordination with the Europeans, with the European Union, with France, with Germany, with the UK.</p>
<p>So we’ll see where we get.  I continue to believe it would be in the best interests of our country if we can get back into compliance with the deal, if Iran will do the same.  We’re not there.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  Thanks for your patience.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks, Andrea.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Good to see you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  You as well.  Thanks.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Australian Foreign Minister Marise Payne Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-australian-foreign-minister-marise-payne-before-their-meeting-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 15:02:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=331987</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p>The Hotel</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  I’ll just say very quickly what a pleasure it is to see my friend and colleague Marise Payne.  We’ve spent a fair bit of time together in various parts of the world &#8212;</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER PAYNE:</b>  We’re here.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  &#8212; but it’s very good to see you here in Brussels.  We’re excited at the prospect of bringing some of our partners from the Asia Pacific together with NATO – that’s certainly part of what we’re doing here together – but also a lot of work that we’re following up on that we’ve been doing together in the region through AUKUS, and many other initiatives that we’re engaged in, and of course, the situation resulting from Russia’s aggression in Ukraine.</p>
<p>So, lots to catch up on.  Great to see you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER PAYNE:  </b>Indeed.  Great to be here too, Tony, with our team.  We’ve just arrived, as you noted, but importantly, at this critical time, a critical time for partners like Australia and the United States to be closely joined in response to the actions of authoritarian states that are untenable, unacceptable, complete illegal violations, wholesale violations of international law and the UN Charter.  So coming here this week is extremely important for Australia to join with the United States and our partners in that response to make sure that we are working in as coordinated and comprehensive a way as possible.</p>
<p>So I’m looking forward to those discussions, and also to reinforcing the importance that no matter where in the world they behave like this, authoritarian states cannot be allowed to trample on the rights of democratic countries and on the people who have chosen to live and work in those democracies.  So it is a very important engagement.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Brussels, Belgium</p>
<p>The Hotel</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  I’ll just say very quickly what a pleasure it is to see my friend and colleague Marise Payne.  We’ve spent a fair bit of time together in various parts of the world &#8212;</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER PAYNE:</b>  We’re here.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  &#8212; but it’s very good to see you here in Brussels.  We’re excited at the prospect of bringing some of our partners from the Asia Pacific together with NATO – that’s certainly part of what we’re doing here together – but also a lot of work that we’re following up on that we’ve been doing together in the region through AUKUS, and many other initiatives that we’re engaged in, and of course, the situation resulting from Russia’s aggression in Ukraine.</p>
<p>So, lots to catch up on.  Great to see you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER PAYNE:  </b>Indeed.  Great to be here too, Tony, with our team.  We’ve just arrived, as you noted, but importantly, at this critical time, a critical time for partners like Australia and the United States to be closely joined in response to the actions of authoritarian states that are untenable, unacceptable, complete illegal violations, wholesale violations of international law and the UN Charter.  So coming here this week is extremely important for Australia to join with the United States and our partners in that response to make sure that we are working in as coordinated and comprehensive a way as possible.</p>
<p>So I’m looking forward to those discussions, and also to reinforcing the importance that no matter where in the world they behave like this, authoritarian states cannot be allowed to trample on the rights of democratic countries and on the people who have chosen to live and work in those democracies.  So it is a very important engagement.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Belgian Foreign Minister Wilmès</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-belgian-foreign-minister-wilmes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 13:29:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=331956</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Belgian Foreign Minister Sophie Wilmès in Brussels.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Wilmès condemned the atrocities committed by President Putin’s forces in Bucha and elsewhere in Ukraine and reaffirmed the U.S. and Belgian commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity. They noted that, together with other Allies and partners, we will continue to impose severe sanctions on the Kremlin for as long as it carries out its brutal and unprovoked war in Ukraine. The Secretary also expressed support for Belgium’s investment screening to protect national security interests.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Belgian Foreign Minister Sophie Wilmès in Brussels.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Wilmès condemned the atrocities committed by President Putin’s forces in Bucha and elsewhere in Ukraine and reaffirmed the U.S. and Belgian commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity. They noted that, together with other Allies and partners, we will continue to impose severe sanctions on the Kremlin for as long as it carries out its brutal and unprovoked war in Ukraine. The Secretary also expressed support for Belgium’s investment screening to protect national security interests.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Department of State Breaks Ground on New U.S. Consulate General in Milan, Italy</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-department-of-state-breaks-ground-on-new-u-s-consulate-general-in-milan-italy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 11:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=331902</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>In a display of the strengthening ties between the United States and Italy, the Bureau of Overseas Buildings Operations (OBO), the U.S. Mission in Italy, and other U.S. and local officials celebrated the groundbreaking of the new U.S. Consulate General in Milan on April 6.</p>
<p>The new U.S. Consulate General campus, which includes the restored iconic Liberty Building, Liberty Plaza, and Parade Ground, will offer a modern public gathering space and gateway welcoming visitors and staff.</p>
<p>SHoP Architects of New York is the design architect and Caddell Construction Company, LLC of Montgomery, Alabama, is the construction contractor.  An estimated $65 million will be directly invested in the local economy and approximately 450 workers will be employed at the peak of construction activities.  The new U.S. Consulate General is scheduled for completion in 2025 and will provide an ecologically resilient platform for diplomacy in northern Italy.</p>
<p>Learn more about the project <a href="https://www.state.gov/overseas-buildings-operations/milan" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDYuNTYwMDEyOTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3Yvb3ZlcnNlYXMtYnVpbGRpbmdzLW9wZXJhdGlvbnMvbWlsYW4ifQ.HmFr2VhhjzRPynsjEmPb4g_a4ls0KIdPUBr0KymMMtw/s/1006560560/br/129370542144-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649331962435000&amp;usg=AOvVaw37-DeObFp1lkUg5oegO_uW">here.</a></p>
<p>Since the start of the Department’s Capital Security Construction Program in 1999, OBO has completed 171 new diplomatic facilities.  OBO currently has more than 50 active projects either in the design phase or under construction worldwide.</p>
<p>OBO provides safe, secure, functional, and resilient facilities that represent the U.S. government to the host nation and that support U.S. diplomats in advancing U.S. foreign policy objectives abroad.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact Christine Foushee at <a href="mailto:FousheeCT@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FousheeCT@state.gov</a> or visit <a href="http://www.state.gov/obo" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDYuNTYwMDEyOTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi9vYm8ifQ.cblyvpEbvB7jnu5u9xRW3zdrx4DUQbv4yDME5L7vZII/s/1006560560/br/129370542144-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649331962435000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2YYHhOaNYRwgDWAKFcNk22">www.state.gov/obo</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>In a display of the strengthening ties between the United States and Italy, the Bureau of Overseas Buildings Operations (OBO), the U.S. Mission in Italy, and other U.S. and local officials celebrated the groundbreaking of the new U.S. Consulate General in Milan on April 6.</p>
<p>The new U.S. Consulate General campus, which includes the restored iconic Liberty Building, Liberty Plaza, and Parade Ground, will offer a modern public gathering space and gateway welcoming visitors and staff.</p>
<p>SHoP Architects of New York is the design architect and Caddell Construction Company, LLC of Montgomery, Alabama, is the construction contractor.  An estimated $65 million will be directly invested in the local economy and approximately 450 workers will be employed at the peak of construction activities.  The new U.S. Consulate General is scheduled for completion in 2025 and will provide an ecologically resilient platform for diplomacy in northern Italy.</p>
<p>Learn more about the project <a href="https://www.state.gov/overseas-buildings-operations/milan" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDYuNTYwMDEyOTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3Yvb3ZlcnNlYXMtYnVpbGRpbmdzLW9wZXJhdGlvbnMvbWlsYW4ifQ.HmFr2VhhjzRPynsjEmPb4g_a4ls0KIdPUBr0KymMMtw/s/1006560560/br/129370542144-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649331962435000&amp;usg=AOvVaw37-DeObFp1lkUg5oegO_uW">here.</a></p>
<p>Since the start of the Department’s Capital Security Construction Program in 1999, OBO has completed 171 new diplomatic facilities.  OBO currently has more than 50 active projects either in the design phase or under construction worldwide.</p>
<p>OBO provides safe, secure, functional, and resilient facilities that represent the U.S. government to the host nation and that support U.S. diplomats in advancing U.S. foreign policy objectives abroad.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact Christine Foushee at <a href="mailto:FousheeCT@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FousheeCT@state.gov</a> or visit <a href="http://www.state.gov/obo" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDYuNTYwMDEyOTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi9vYm8ifQ.cblyvpEbvB7jnu5u9xRW3zdrx4DUQbv4yDME5L7vZII/s/1006560560/br/129370542144-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649331962435000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2YYHhOaNYRwgDWAKFcNk22">www.state.gov/obo</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>$100 Million in Additional U.S. Security Assistance for Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/100-million-in-additional-u-s-security-assistance-for-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 01:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=331815</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The world has been shocked and appalled by the atrocities committed by Russia’s forces in Bucha and across Ukraine.  Ukraine’s forces bravely continue to defend their country and their freedom, and the United States, along with our Allies and partners, stand steadfast in support of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>I have authorized, pursuant to a delegation from the President earlier today, the immediate drawdown of security assistance valued at up to $100 million to meet Ukraine’s urgent need for additional anti-armor systems.  This authorization is the sixth drawdown of arms, equipment, and supplies from Department of Defense inventories for Ukraine since August 2021.  Combined with $300 million in assistance announced by the Department of Defense on April 1 under the Ukraine Security Assistance Initiative, this additional drawdown brings the total U.S. security assistance commitment to Ukraine to more than $2.4 billion since the beginning of this Administration, and more than $1.7 billion* *since the beginning of Russia’s brutal assault against Ukraine began on February 24.</p>
<p>In addition to what we have provided, more than 30 countries have joined us to deliver security assistance to Ukraine since Russia’s invasion began. Together, we are delivering security assistance every day, and we are expediting shipments of even more of the arms and defense equipment Ukraine is using to defend itself.  As we strengthen Ukraine’s position on the battlefield and at the negotiating table, we will also work with our Allies and partners to gather information to document reported abuses and make it available to the appropriate bodies to hold those responsible to account.</p>
<p>United with our Allies and partners, we will continue to provide security assistance in support of Ukraine’s defense, as well as economic support, and humanitarian aid for communities devastated by Russia’s ruthless brutality.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The world has been shocked and appalled by the atrocities committed by Russia’s forces in Bucha and across Ukraine.  Ukraine’s forces bravely continue to defend their country and their freedom, and the United States, along with our Allies and partners, stand steadfast in support of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>I have authorized, pursuant to a delegation from the President earlier today, the immediate drawdown of security assistance valued at up to $100 million to meet Ukraine’s urgent need for additional anti-armor systems.  This authorization is the sixth drawdown of arms, equipment, and supplies from Department of Defense inventories for Ukraine since August 2021.  Combined with $300 million in assistance announced by the Department of Defense on April 1 under the Ukraine Security Assistance Initiative, this additional drawdown brings the total U.S. security assistance commitment to Ukraine to more than $2.4 billion since the beginning of this Administration, and more than $1.7 billion* *since the beginning of Russia’s brutal assault against Ukraine began on February 24.</p>
<p>In addition to what we have provided, more than 30 countries have joined us to deliver security assistance to Ukraine since Russia’s invasion began. Together, we are delivering security assistance every day, and we are expediting shipments of even more of the arms and defense equipment Ukraine is using to defend itself.  As we strengthen Ukraine’s position on the battlefield and at the negotiating table, we will also work with our Allies and partners to gather information to document reported abuses and make it available to the appropriate bodies to hold those responsible to account.</p>
<p>United with our Allies and partners, we will continue to provide security assistance in support of Ukraine’s defense, as well as economic support, and humanitarian aid for communities devastated by Russia’s ruthless brutality.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Representative for the DPRK Kim’s Meeting with the People’s Republic of China (PRC) Special Representative Liu</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-representative-for-the-dprk-kims-meeting-with-the-peoples-republic-of-china-prc-special-representative-liu/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 23:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=331810</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>On April 5 Special Representative for the DPRK Sung Kim met with the People’s Republic of China (PRC) Special Representative for Korean Peninsula Affairs Liu Xiaoming in Washington, D.C., to discuss recent developments in the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK).</p>
<p>Special Representative Kim condemned the DPRK’s March 24 ICBM launch, the latest in a series of increasingly escalatory actions by the DPRK. He noted that each of the DPRK’s 13 ballistic missile launches this year constituted clear violations of multiple UN Security Council resolutions and posed a serious threat to regional stability, and reiterated the importance of responding firmly to these escalatory actions. Special Representative Kim reaffirmed that the United States is committed to engage in serious and sustained diplomacy with the DPRK. Special Representative Kim and Special Representative Liu discussed opportunities to advance our shared goal of denuclearizing the Korean Peninsula and how to encourage the DPRK to engage in meaningful negotiations.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>On April 5 Special Representative for the DPRK Sung Kim met with the People’s Republic of China (PRC) Special Representative for Korean Peninsula Affairs Liu Xiaoming in Washington, D.C., to discuss recent developments in the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK).</p>
<p>Special Representative Kim condemned the DPRK’s March 24 ICBM launch, the latest in a series of increasingly escalatory actions by the DPRK. He noted that each of the DPRK’s 13 ballistic missile launches this year constituted clear violations of multiple UN Security Council resolutions and posed a serious threat to regional stability, and reiterated the importance of responding firmly to these escalatory actions. Special Representative Kim reaffirmed that the United States is committed to engage in serious and sustained diplomacy with the DPRK. Special Representative Kim and Special Representative Liu discussed opportunities to advance our shared goal of denuclearizing the Korean Peninsula and how to encourage the DPRK to engage in meaningful negotiations.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Azerbaijan President Aliyev</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-azerbaijan-president-aliyev/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 21:41:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=331764</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Azerbaijan’s President Aliyev today. The Secretary offered his condolences for the tragic gas explosion in Baku over the weekend. The Secretary condemned the Kremlin’s heinous war crimes in Ukraine and highlighted the continued commitment of the U.S. and its partners to hold the Russian Federation and its enablers accountable for the unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine. The Secretary called for restraint, de-escalation, and renewed diplomacy. The Secretary expressed his encouragement for peace negotiations between Armenia and Azerbaijan, including President Aliyev and Armenian Prime Minister Pashinyan’s planned meeting on April 6 with European Council President Michel. He reiterated the United States stood ready to help by engaging bilaterally and with like-minded partners, including through our role as an OSCE Minsk Group Co-Chair, to help the countries find a long-term comprehensive peace.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Azerbaijan’s President Aliyev today. The Secretary offered his condolences for the tragic gas explosion in Baku over the weekend. The Secretary condemned the Kremlin’s heinous war crimes in Ukraine and highlighted the continued commitment of the U.S. and its partners to hold the Russian Federation and its enablers accountable for the unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine. The Secretary called for restraint, de-escalation, and renewed diplomacy. The Secretary expressed his encouragement for peace negotiations between Armenia and Azerbaijan, including President Aliyev and Armenian Prime Minister Pashinyan’s planned meeting on April 6 with European Council President Michel. He reiterated the United States stood ready to help by engaging bilaterally and with like-minded partners, including through our role as an OSCE Minsk Group Co-Chair, to help the countries find a long-term comprehensive peace.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
