<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 20:20:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken  at a Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-press-availability-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 20:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246281</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Jerusalem</p>
<p>David Citadel Hotel</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good evening, everyone.  Ah, must be a slow night.  (Laughter.)  Good to see you all.</p>
<p>We had, as those of you who’ve been along with us all day know, a fairly busy and certainly very productive day in Jerusalem and Ramallah since arriving this morning.  I traveled here at the request of President Biden, who asked me to come to pursue four basic objectives.  First, to demonstrate the commitment of the United States to Israel’s security.  Second, to start to work toward greater stability and reduce tensions in the West Bank and Jerusalem.  Third, to support urgent humanitarian and reconstruction assistance for Gaza to benefit the Palestinian people.  And fourth, to continue to rebuild our relationship with the Palestinian people and the Palestinian Authority.</p>
<p>Those objectives shaped all of the meetings that I held today with elected leaders on both sides, including Prime Minister Netanyahu, Foreign Minister Ashkenazi, Defense Minister Gantz here in Jerusalem, and President Abbas and Prime Minister Shtayyeh in the West Bank.  They’ll drive my discussions this evening with Knesset opposition leader Lapid and tomorrow morning with President Rivlin.</p>
<p>Across the meetings that I’ve had so far, I’ve heard a shared recognition from all sides that steps need to be taken, work needs to be done, to address the underlying conditions that helped fuel this latest conflict.  The ceasefire creates space to begin to take those steps.  Attending to the urgent humanitarian needs of Palestinians in Gaza and helping rebuild is a key starting point.  The United States is committed to rallying international support to that effort and doing our part.  That’s why we announced additional assistance for the Palestinian people today.</p>
<p>But we all know that is not enough.  As President Biden has said, we believe that Palestinians and Israelis equally deserve to live safely and securely; to enjoy equal measures of freedom, opportunity, and democracy; to be treated with dignity.  Earlier today, I had a chance to meet with two of the State Department’s locally employed staff: an Israeli whose family lives near the Gaza separation wall and a Palestinian who lives in Gaza.  Both of them recounted how the violence in recent weeks repeatedly forced them and their families to take cover.  Both feared they would be killed.  For too many innocent Israelis and Palestinians, lives lost in the conflict and loved ones suffering immeasurably as a result.</p>
<p>But the stories of those staff members remind us that the survivors on both sides also walk away scarred, none as much as children.  That’s another reason we have to break the cycle of violence.  Leaders on both sides will need to chart a better course, starting by making real improvements in the lives of people in Israel, Gaza, and the West Bank.  I’m convinced that if they do, they will find willing partners in both Israeli and Palestinian civil society.  That’s one of the messages I took away from a meeting earlier today with Palestinian civil society leaders.</p>
<p>Tomorrow, I’ve got a chance to travel to Egypt and also to Jordan.  As you know, Egypt played a critical role in helping to broker the ceasefire, and Jordan has long been a voice for peace and stability in the region.  We’re grateful for their continued engagement, and I look forward to the meetings there tomorrow.</p>
<p>But with that, I’m happy to take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll start with Lara Jakes, <em>New York Times.</em></p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Good evening, Secretary Blinken.  Hello.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Where are you, Lara?  Oh, there you are.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I think some of my colleagues will ask you some of the nitty-gritty questions of the day.  I wanted to kind of take a step back, if I could.  Reasserting America’s role in the world has been one of the themes of your foreign policy.  Can you describe how that took shape over the last three weeks in this part of the Middle East, where the United States had a very active role in promoting Israeli interests during the Trump administration but had shut down relations with Palestinian officials?  And so what struck you in what you heard today from both sides?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, a few things.  First, I think that the violence that we’ve seen in recent weeks is a reminder of the need to try to make genuine progress toward peacefully resolving the conflict that continues to divide Israelis and Palestinians.</p>
<p>In terms of U.S. reengagement, U.S. leadership, I think what you saw was President Biden leading, very determined, very intensive, but also behind-the-scenes diplomacy to do the first thing that needed to be done, which was to end the violence, to get the ceasefire.  And with a lot of hard work, with the efforts of others, including the Egyptians, we were able to do that.  But that was just the starting point for something that I just described.</p>
<p>It’s now I think incumbent on us to work with our partners here and work with others, as I said, to address the urgent needs in Gaza itself and the people in Gaza, to then try to build something more positive on that, and also to address some of the underlying causes that could, if not addressed, spark another cycle of violence.</p>
<p>So I think we found in working on this intensely, quietly but resolutely, that America’s words matter, America’s actions matter, and America’s engagement matters.  I’m glad that we were able to make – help make a difference in getting to the ceasefire.  And I hope and expect that we can continue to make a difference in moving beyond it in trying to build something more positive.  So that’s what I take away from at least the last couple of weeks.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to Gili Cohen from KAN.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, thank you for that.  Prime Minister Netanyahu has been pretty vocal in his objection to the JCPOA.  Did those remarks encourage or deter the U.S. from returning to the JCPOA?  And speaking of the Iran deal, is it a matter of weeks before the U.S. will return to the agreement?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Let’s start with this.  The fact is the United States and Israel are absolutely united in the proposition that Iran must never be allowed to acquire a nuclear weapon.  We share exactly the same goal.  It’s no secret that we sometimes have our differences with regard to the best way to achieve that goal, and that’s what allies and partners do.  We work together, try to find the best way to achieve a common objective.  What we have done very, very resolutely, as we’ve tried to see whether a return to mutual compliance with the JCPOA is possible, is that we have regularly before, during, and after all of our engagements – indirect engagements with the Iranians in Vienna – kept our partners here in Israel informed, as well as others who are concerned.  And that’s not going to stop.</p>
<p>Let me add this:  The JCPOA I think accomplished something very important, and that is it cut off all of Iran’s pathways to produce fissile material for a nuclear weapon on short order.  And it pushed the so-called breakout time, the amount of time it would take Iran to develop that material for a nuclear weapon, to beyond a year.  It was the most heavily monitored and verified agreement in the history of arms control.  Our experts said that Iran was abiding by its commitments under the agreement.  So did international experts.  And as a result, the challenge that both the United States and Israel were focused on, the prospect of Iran getting to the point where it could have a – fissile material for a nuclear weapon or produce it on very short order, we took that off of the – off the field.  And I think that was an important development.</p>
<p>What have we seen since we pulled out of the agreement?  Well, Iran has stopped abiding by some of the critical constraints in the agreement, and as a result, it is far closer today to the ability to produce fissile material for a nuclear weapon on short order than it was even before the deal was reached, and certainly during the pendency of the deal itself.  And so I think that only underscores the importance and, indeed, urgency in seeing if we can get Iran back into compliance with the agreement, to put Iran back in the nuclear box that the deal constructed.  The alternative is an Iran that is getting closer and closer – if it continues to do what it’s doing, in spinning more and more sophisticated centrifuges and building up stockpiles of enriched uranium – getting closer and closer to having a very, very short breakout time, which is in – not in our interest, not in Israel’s interest, not in anyone’s interest.</p>
<p>So that’s why we’re working to see if we can get back into mutual compliance.  We’ve said all along that that would be a first step, that we also would seek to try to make the agreement longer and stronger, and also to deal with other issues and other challenges posed by Iran, to include its support for terrorism, its support for destabilizing proxy groups in countries throughout the region, its proliferation.  All of these things we’re determined to engage, but the first thing we’re trying to achieve is to, as I said, put the nuclear problem back into the box that we constructed and that was strong, solid, and doing what we needed to do.</p>
<p>Now, we’re engaged or about to engage in I think the fifth round of discussions in Vienna, and we still don’t know the answer to the most important question, which is whether Iran is actually willing and able to make the decisions it needs to make to come back into full compliance.  The jury is still out, and we will see whether or not Iran makes that decision.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks.  Mr. Secretary, a few of those nitty-gritty questions for you:  Did President Abbas say anything to you about reopening a Palestinian Authority representative office in the U.S.?  Can you give us a timeframe on when you would reopen the consulate and bring Michael Ratney here?</p>
<p>And then if I could just press you a little bit on the Iran issue, understanding everything you’ve laid out to us, did you offer any assurances to Prime Minister Netanyahu?  His comments to us essentially showed that he disagreed with everything you just said.  He thinks that the deal essentially legitimizes Iran getting a nuclear weapon.  So was there anything you asked of him or offered him on the JCPOA to try to reassure him?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  So on the question of an office in Washington, that did not come up today.  With regard to our consulate, we’re just beginning the process.  I can’t give you a timeline on how long that will take.  But I can tell you that it’s, I think, important to have that platform to be able to more effectively engage not just the Palestinian Authority, but Palestinians from different walks of life, the NGO community, the business community, and others.  And so we look forward to doing that, but I can’t put a timeline on it.</p>
<p>And coming back to Iran, no, I think the most important thing when it comes to this is what we committed to do from day one of this administration.  We said all along that if there was an opportunity, we would seek to return to mutual compliance with the JCPOA, but we also said that from day one, we would be keeping our closest allies and closest partners fully and contemporaneously informed of what we were doing and where we were going.  And that’s what we’ve done and that’s what we’ll continue to do.  That is how you keep faith with your partners and allies on something that, of course, is of great consequence to Israel.  We understand that.</p>
<p>And again, we have the same objective, and let’s see where things go in the next few weeks.  But I can again tell you that we are fully, fully engaged with our partners here in at least making sure that they’re fully informed of what we’re doing.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll turn to Hikmet Yosef from PalSawa.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (In Arabic.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Good afternoon.</p>
<p>(In Arabic.)</p>
<p><strong>INTERPRETER:</strong>  Okay.  So his question was:  “The U.S. administration said that it’s going to do the reconstruction of Gaza through the United Nations.  Is this considered an implicit, direct, or indirect recognition of Hamas that is taking over – that is the taken-over authority in Gaza?  And – or is there a plan for Washington to deal with Hamas directly or indirectly?”</p>
<p>And he’s asking also:  “Is the negotiation – will be resumed between the PA and Israel after the ceasefire?”  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much for your question.  Look, if we do this right, reconstruction and then – and relief for the people of Gaza, far from empowering Hamas, I think has the potential to undermine it.  I say that because Hamas thrives, unfortunately, on despair, on misery, on desperation, on a lack of opportunity.  In fact, it’s a movement that has thrived on a vacuum of opportunity.  And what reconstruction and relief need to do is not just answer the immediate needs – and those needs are significant and they’re urgent, whether it’s water, whether it’s sanitation, whether it’s electricity – but they need to offer a genuine prospect for opportunity, for progress, for material improvement in people’s lives.  And our goal is to give the Palestinian people, including those in Gaza, a renewed sense of confidence, of optimism, of real opportunity.</p>
<p>And if we succeed – and by the way, it’s not just us, it’s not just the UN.  It’s the Palestinian Authority that needs to be fully engaged, Israel needs to fully engage, other partners need to fully engage.  But in my judgment, at least, if we’re able to do that all together, then Hamas’s foothold in Gaza will slip, and we know that and I think that Hamas knows that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll take one final question from Andrea Mitchell.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  Did you get any commitments from Prime Minister Netanyahu to not evict Palestinians from East Jerusalem neighborhoods and to work with the Palestinian Authority and other Palestinians in order to avoid any spark that could break the ceasefire?  And did you get any assurances from the Palestinian Authority today that they could have any influence over Gaza?  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, Andrea.  So first, as – let me take a step back for a minute, because we’re focused right now on responding to, as I said, the urgent needs that exist in Gaza on a humanitarian basis, the urgent needs for rebuilding and reconstruction, and then looking to see actions on the part of both Israelis and Palestinians that will take down tension, and try to remove or minimize some of the potential catalysts for a renewed cycle of violence, and, building on that, try to – in very practical and material ways, start to improve people’s lives and add a real sense of dignity and hope.</p>
<p>If that happens – and that will take some time – that may, I think, produce a better environment in which ultimately there’s a possibility of resuming the effort to achieve a two-state solution, which we continue to believe is the only way to truly assure Israel’s future as a Jewish and democratic state, and of course, to give the Palestinians the state that they’re entitled to.</p>
<p>I say all that because any steps that either side takes that either risk sparking violence or – over time – and ultimately undermine the prospect for returning to the pursuit of two states, we oppose.  And that includes settlement activity, it includes demolitions, it includes evictions, it includes incitement to violence, it includes payment to terrorists.  All of those things would, I think, on the one hand potentially be catalysts for renewed tension and potentially violence, and certainly undermine the prospects of achieving two states.  And that’s something that we’ve been very clear about in our conversations with Israelis and Palestinians alike.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But did you get any commitment today?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I’ll let the – I’ll let our partners speak for themselves.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you very much, everybody.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Jerusalem</p>
<p>David Citadel Hotel</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good evening, everyone.  Ah, must be a slow night.  (Laughter.)  Good to see you all.</p>
<p>We had, as those of you who’ve been along with us all day know, a fairly busy and certainly very productive day in Jerusalem and Ramallah since arriving this morning.  I traveled here at the request of President Biden, who asked me to come to pursue four basic objectives.  First, to demonstrate the commitment of the United States to Israel’s security.  Second, to start to work toward greater stability and reduce tensions in the West Bank and Jerusalem.  Third, to support urgent humanitarian and reconstruction assistance for Gaza to benefit the Palestinian people.  And fourth, to continue to rebuild our relationship with the Palestinian people and the Palestinian Authority.</p>
<p>Those objectives shaped all of the meetings that I held today with elected leaders on both sides, including Prime Minister Netanyahu, Foreign Minister Ashkenazi, Defense Minister Gantz here in Jerusalem, and President Abbas and Prime Minister Shtayyeh in the West Bank.  They’ll drive my discussions this evening with Knesset opposition leader Lapid and tomorrow morning with President Rivlin.</p>
<p>Across the meetings that I’ve had so far, I’ve heard a shared recognition from all sides that steps need to be taken, work needs to be done, to address the underlying conditions that helped fuel this latest conflict.  The ceasefire creates space to begin to take those steps.  Attending to the urgent humanitarian needs of Palestinians in Gaza and helping rebuild is a key starting point.  The United States is committed to rallying international support to that effort and doing our part.  That’s why we announced additional assistance for the Palestinian people today.</p>
<p>But we all know that is not enough.  As President Biden has said, we believe that Palestinians and Israelis equally deserve to live safely and securely; to enjoy equal measures of freedom, opportunity, and democracy; to be treated with dignity.  Earlier today, I had a chance to meet with two of the State Department’s locally employed staff: an Israeli whose family lives near the Gaza separation wall and a Palestinian who lives in Gaza.  Both of them recounted how the violence in recent weeks repeatedly forced them and their families to take cover.  Both feared they would be killed.  For too many innocent Israelis and Palestinians, lives lost in the conflict and loved ones suffering immeasurably as a result.</p>
<p>But the stories of those staff members remind us that the survivors on both sides also walk away scarred, none as much as children.  That’s another reason we have to break the cycle of violence.  Leaders on both sides will need to chart a better course, starting by making real improvements in the lives of people in Israel, Gaza, and the West Bank.  I’m convinced that if they do, they will find willing partners in both Israeli and Palestinian civil society.  That’s one of the messages I took away from a meeting earlier today with Palestinian civil society leaders.</p>
<p>Tomorrow, I’ve got a chance to travel to Egypt and also to Jordan.  As you know, Egypt played a critical role in helping to broker the ceasefire, and Jordan has long been a voice for peace and stability in the region.  We’re grateful for their continued engagement, and I look forward to the meetings there tomorrow.</p>
<p>But with that, I’m happy to take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll start with Lara Jakes, <em>New York Times.</em></p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Good evening, Secretary Blinken.  Hello.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Where are you, Lara?  Oh, there you are.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  I think some of my colleagues will ask you some of the nitty-gritty questions of the day.  I wanted to kind of take a step back, if I could.  Reasserting America’s role in the world has been one of the themes of your foreign policy.  Can you describe how that took shape over the last three weeks in this part of the Middle East, where the United States had a very active role in promoting Israeli interests during the Trump administration but had shut down relations with Palestinian officials?  And so what struck you in what you heard today from both sides?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, a few things.  First, I think that the violence that we’ve seen in recent weeks is a reminder of the need to try to make genuine progress toward peacefully resolving the conflict that continues to divide Israelis and Palestinians.</p>
<p>In terms of U.S. reengagement, U.S. leadership, I think what you saw was President Biden leading, very determined, very intensive, but also behind-the-scenes diplomacy to do the first thing that needed to be done, which was to end the violence, to get the ceasefire.  And with a lot of hard work, with the efforts of others, including the Egyptians, we were able to do that.  But that was just the starting point for something that I just described.</p>
<p>It’s now I think incumbent on us to work with our partners here and work with others, as I said, to address the urgent needs in Gaza itself and the people in Gaza, to then try to build something more positive on that, and also to address some of the underlying causes that could, if not addressed, spark another cycle of violence.</p>
<p>So I think we found in working on this intensely, quietly but resolutely, that America’s words matter, America’s actions matter, and America’s engagement matters.  I’m glad that we were able to make – help make a difference in getting to the ceasefire.  And I hope and expect that we can continue to make a difference in moving beyond it in trying to build something more positive.  So that’s what I take away from at least the last couple of weeks.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll go to Gili Cohen from KAN.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, thank you for that.  Prime Minister Netanyahu has been pretty vocal in his objection to the JCPOA.  Did those remarks encourage or deter the U.S. from returning to the JCPOA?  And speaking of the Iran deal, is it a matter of weeks before the U.S. will return to the agreement?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Let’s start with this.  The fact is the United States and Israel are absolutely united in the proposition that Iran must never be allowed to acquire a nuclear weapon.  We share exactly the same goal.  It’s no secret that we sometimes have our differences with regard to the best way to achieve that goal, and that’s what allies and partners do.  We work together, try to find the best way to achieve a common objective.  What we have done very, very resolutely, as we’ve tried to see whether a return to mutual compliance with the JCPOA is possible, is that we have regularly before, during, and after all of our engagements – indirect engagements with the Iranians in Vienna – kept our partners here in Israel informed, as well as others who are concerned.  And that’s not going to stop.</p>
<p>Let me add this:  The JCPOA I think accomplished something very important, and that is it cut off all of Iran’s pathways to produce fissile material for a nuclear weapon on short order.  And it pushed the so-called breakout time, the amount of time it would take Iran to develop that material for a nuclear weapon, to beyond a year.  It was the most heavily monitored and verified agreement in the history of arms control.  Our experts said that Iran was abiding by its commitments under the agreement.  So did international experts.  And as a result, the challenge that both the United States and Israel were focused on, the prospect of Iran getting to the point where it could have a – fissile material for a nuclear weapon or produce it on very short order, we took that off of the – off the field.  And I think that was an important development.</p>
<p>What have we seen since we pulled out of the agreement?  Well, Iran has stopped abiding by some of the critical constraints in the agreement, and as a result, it is far closer today to the ability to produce fissile material for a nuclear weapon on short order than it was even before the deal was reached, and certainly during the pendency of the deal itself.  And so I think that only underscores the importance and, indeed, urgency in seeing if we can get Iran back into compliance with the agreement, to put Iran back in the nuclear box that the deal constructed.  The alternative is an Iran that is getting closer and closer – if it continues to do what it’s doing, in spinning more and more sophisticated centrifuges and building up stockpiles of enriched uranium – getting closer and closer to having a very, very short breakout time, which is in – not in our interest, not in Israel’s interest, not in anyone’s interest.</p>
<p>So that’s why we’re working to see if we can get back into mutual compliance.  We’ve said all along that that would be a first step, that we also would seek to try to make the agreement longer and stronger, and also to deal with other issues and other challenges posed by Iran, to include its support for terrorism, its support for destabilizing proxy groups in countries throughout the region, its proliferation.  All of these things we’re determined to engage, but the first thing we’re trying to achieve is to, as I said, put the nuclear problem back into the box that we constructed and that was strong, solid, and doing what we needed to do.</p>
<p>Now, we’re engaged or about to engage in I think the fifth round of discussions in Vienna, and we still don’t know the answer to the most important question, which is whether Iran is actually willing and able to make the decisions it needs to make to come back into full compliance.  The jury is still out, and we will see whether or not Iran makes that decision.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Nick Wadhams.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thanks.  Mr. Secretary, a few of those nitty-gritty questions for you:  Did President Abbas say anything to you about reopening a Palestinian Authority representative office in the U.S.?  Can you give us a timeframe on when you would reopen the consulate and bring Michael Ratney here?</p>
<p>And then if I could just press you a little bit on the Iran issue, understanding everything you’ve laid out to us, did you offer any assurances to Prime Minister Netanyahu?  His comments to us essentially showed that he disagreed with everything you just said.  He thinks that the deal essentially legitimizes Iran getting a nuclear weapon.  So was there anything you asked of him or offered him on the JCPOA to try to reassure him?  Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  So on the question of an office in Washington, that did not come up today.  With regard to our consulate, we’re just beginning the process.  I can’t give you a timeline on how long that will take.  But I can tell you that it’s, I think, important to have that platform to be able to more effectively engage not just the Palestinian Authority, but Palestinians from different walks of life, the NGO community, the business community, and others.  And so we look forward to doing that, but I can’t put a timeline on it.</p>
<p>And coming back to Iran, no, I think the most important thing when it comes to this is what we committed to do from day one of this administration.  We said all along that if there was an opportunity, we would seek to return to mutual compliance with the JCPOA, but we also said that from day one, we would be keeping our closest allies and closest partners fully and contemporaneously informed of what we were doing and where we were going.  And that’s what we’ve done and that’s what we’ll continue to do.  That is how you keep faith with your partners and allies on something that, of course, is of great consequence to Israel.  We understand that.</p>
<p>And again, we have the same objective, and let’s see where things go in the next few weeks.  But I can again tell you that we are fully, fully engaged with our partners here in at least making sure that they’re fully informed of what we’re doing.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll turn to Hikmet Yosef from PalSawa.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (In Arabic.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  (Via interpreter) Good afternoon.</p>
<p>(In Arabic.)</p>
<p><strong>INTERPRETER:</strong>  Okay.  So his question was:  “The U.S. administration said that it’s going to do the reconstruction of Gaza through the United Nations.  Is this considered an implicit, direct, or indirect recognition of Hamas that is taking over – that is the taken-over authority in Gaza?  And – or is there a plan for Washington to deal with Hamas directly or indirectly?”</p>
<p>And he’s asking also:  “Is the negotiation – will be resumed between the PA and Israel after the ceasefire?”  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much for your question.  Look, if we do this right, reconstruction and then – and relief for the people of Gaza, far from empowering Hamas, I think has the potential to undermine it.  I say that because Hamas thrives, unfortunately, on despair, on misery, on desperation, on a lack of opportunity.  In fact, it’s a movement that has thrived on a vacuum of opportunity.  And what reconstruction and relief need to do is not just answer the immediate needs – and those needs are significant and they’re urgent, whether it’s water, whether it’s sanitation, whether it’s electricity – but they need to offer a genuine prospect for opportunity, for progress, for material improvement in people’s lives.  And our goal is to give the Palestinian people, including those in Gaza, a renewed sense of confidence, of optimism, of real opportunity.</p>
<p>And if we succeed – and by the way, it’s not just us, it’s not just the UN.  It’s the Palestinian Authority that needs to be fully engaged, Israel needs to fully engage, other partners need to fully engage.  But in my judgment, at least, if we’re able to do that all together, then Hamas’s foothold in Gaza will slip, and we know that and I think that Hamas knows that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll take one final question from Andrea Mitchell.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  Did you get any commitments from Prime Minister Netanyahu to not evict Palestinians from East Jerusalem neighborhoods and to work with the Palestinian Authority and other Palestinians in order to avoid any spark that could break the ceasefire?  And did you get any assurances from the Palestinian Authority today that they could have any influence over Gaza?  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, Andrea.  So first, as – let me take a step back for a minute, because we’re focused right now on responding to, as I said, the urgent needs that exist in Gaza on a humanitarian basis, the urgent needs for rebuilding and reconstruction, and then looking to see actions on the part of both Israelis and Palestinians that will take down tension, and try to remove or minimize some of the potential catalysts for a renewed cycle of violence, and, building on that, try to – in very practical and material ways, start to improve people’s lives and add a real sense of dignity and hope.</p>
<p>If that happens – and that will take some time – that may, I think, produce a better environment in which ultimately there’s a possibility of resuming the effort to achieve a two-state solution, which we continue to believe is the only way to truly assure Israel’s future as a Jewish and democratic state, and of course, to give the Palestinians the state that they’re entitled to.</p>
<p>I say all that because any steps that either side takes that either risk sparking violence or – over time – and ultimately undermine the prospect for returning to the pursuit of two states, we oppose.  And that includes settlement activity, it includes demolitions, it includes evictions, it includes incitement to violence, it includes payment to terrorists.  All of those things would, I think, on the one hand potentially be catalysts for renewed tension and potentially violence, and certainly undermine the prospects of achieving two states.  And that’s something that we’ve been very clear about in our conversations with Israelis and Palestinians alike.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  But did you get any commitment today?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I’ll let the – I’ll let our partners speak for themselves.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you very much, everybody.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement by the Secretary of State of the United States of America, the Foreign Secretary of the United Kingdom, and the Foreign Ministers of France, Germany, and Italy</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-by-the-secretary-of-state-of-the-united-states-of-america-the-foreign-secretary-of-the-united-kingdom-and-the-foreign-ministers-of-france-germany-and-italy-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 19:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following statement was released by United States Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken, French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian, German Foreign Minister Heiko Maas, Italian Foreign Minister Luigi Di Maio, and UK Foreign Secretary Dominic Raab on Syria’s presidential election.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>We, the Foreign Ministers of France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom and the United States of America wish to make clear that Syria’s May 26 presidential election will neither be free nor fair. We denounce the Assad regime’s decision to hold an election outside of the framework described in UN Security Council Resolution 2254 and we support the voices of all Syrians, including civil society organisations and the Syrian opposition, who have condemned the electoral process as illegitimate.</p>
<p>As outlined in the Resolution, free and fair elections should be convened under UN supervision to the highest international standards of transparency and accountability. For an election to be credible, all Syrians should be allowed to participate, including internally displaced Syrians, refugees, and members of the diaspora, in a safe and neutral environment.</p>
<p>Without these elements, this fraudulent election does not represent any progress towards a political settlement. We urge the international community to unequivocally reject this attempt by the Assad regime to regain legitimacy without ending its grave human rights violations and meaningfully participating in the UN-facilitated political process to end the conflict.</p>
<p>We reiterate our firm support for the UN Special Envoy for Syria’s efforts to promote a political settlement, based on all aspects of UNSCR 2254, which protects the future prosperity and the rights of all Syrians, including the right to vote in free and fair elections.</p>
<p><em>End text. </em></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following statement was released by United States Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken, French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian, German Foreign Minister Heiko Maas, Italian Foreign Minister Luigi Di Maio, and UK Foreign Secretary Dominic Raab on Syria’s presidential election.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>We, the Foreign Ministers of France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom and the United States of America wish to make clear that Syria’s May 26 presidential election will neither be free nor fair. We denounce the Assad regime’s decision to hold an election outside of the framework described in UN Security Council Resolution 2254 and we support the voices of all Syrians, including civil society organisations and the Syrian opposition, who have condemned the electoral process as illegitimate.</p>
<p>As outlined in the Resolution, free and fair elections should be convened under UN supervision to the highest international standards of transparency and accountability. For an election to be credible, all Syrians should be allowed to participate, including internally displaced Syrians, refugees, and members of the diaspora, in a safe and neutral environment.</p>
<p>Without these elements, this fraudulent election does not represent any progress towards a political settlement. We urge the international community to unequivocally reject this attempt by the Assad regime to regain legitimacy without ending its grave human rights violations and meaningfully participating in the UN-facilitated political process to end the conflict.</p>
<p>We reiterate our firm support for the UN Special Envoy for Syria’s efforts to promote a political settlement, based on all aspects of UNSCR 2254, which protects the future prosperity and the rights of all Syrians, including the right to vote in free and fair elections.</p>
<p><em>End text. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas Statements to the Press</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-palestinian-authority-president-mahmoud-abbas-statements-to-the-press/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 17:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246201</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Ramallah, West Bank</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ABBAS:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  In the name of God, the merciful and the compassionate, we would like to welcome Secretary Clinton, who visits us these – in these days &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>STAFF:</strong>  Blinken.</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ABBAS:</strong>  (Via interpreter) – sorry – Blinken, who visits us in these days &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  It’s an improvement.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ABBAS:</strong>  (Via interpreter) – under very difficult conditions.  And we also would like to thank President Biden and the U.S. administration for their efforts to achieve a ceasefire between the Gaza Strip and Israel, and the efforts that they continue to exert in order to reach a comprehensive ceasefire that will hold.</p>
<p>We would also like to thank the U.S. administration for its support to the state of Palestine and for the resumption of its assistance to us and to the UNRWA.  This is something that we highly value, and we hope that the future will be rife with diplomatic and political effort headed by the U.S. and the Quartet so that we can reach a lasting and comprehensive peace in the region according to international legitimacy resolutions, and so that these actions on the part of a few – of a hurtful few would come to an end.</p>
<p>We also thank the U.S. administration for its commitment to a two-state solution, and the maintenance of the status quo in Jerusalem, and to keep the residents of Jerusalem and Sheikh Jarrah in their homes.  And also we thank the U.S. administration for its position vis-a-vis the expansion of settlements, and the actions taken by settlers.</p>
<p>We have also affirmed that we are committed to peaceful popular resistance and that we renounce violence and terrorism, and we only want to achieve a political solution through peaceful means between us and Israel.</p>
<p>We have also affirmed that our government stands ready to work directly in order for the reconstruction of Gaza and also to establish a national unity government for that end that would be all-inclusive.  And in the event that such agreement materializes, our first condition would be that Hamas and all parties have to abide by international legitimacy resolutions that are known for everyone.</p>
<p>And we also informed the Secretary that we have postponed the elections, because Israel has refused to include Jerusalem in these elections, and the minute that it does we will hold them immediately and without any delay, because ultimately what we’re interested in is to establish democracy throughout Palestine.</p>
<p>Once again, I thank the U.S. administration and President Biden and Secretary Tony Blinken for the efforts that he’s in engaging in now in order to achieve that end.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, Mr. President, thank you very, very much.  It’s very good to be in Ramallah, or maybe I should say back in Ramallah, to see you, to see the prime minister and your team.</p>
<p>And let me start by conveying the deep condolences of the United States to the families who’ve lost loved ones in the recent violence – the children, the women, the men whose lives were lost.  I say this as a father.  No child, whether Israeli, Palestinian, or American, is a statistic.  We know the human consequences when violence takes the upper hand, and we are determined that that not be the case.  I think the loss of any child is a universe of loss, and in some ways incomprehensible except to those who’ve suffered the loss.  And that’s true irrespective of whether you’re Israeli, Palestinian, American; if you’re a human being, that’s what matters.</p>
<p>We know that the last round of violence is symptomatic of a larger set of issues that we have to address if we’re going to prevent its recurrence, and that’s what we talked about today.  We welcome the ceasefire that continues to hold, but that’s not enough.  We have to build on the ceasefire and try to move things in a genuinely positive direction.  As I told the president, I am here to underscore the commitment of the United States to rebuilding a relationship with the Palestinian Authority and with the Palestinian people, a relationship built on mutual respect and also a shared conviction that Palestinians and Israelis alike deserve equal measures of freedom, security, opportunity, and dignity.</p>
<p>As I told Prime Minister Netanyahu and President Abbas, the United States will be moving forward with the process to reopen our consulate in Jerusalem.  That’s an important way for our country to engage with and provide support to the Palestinian people.  We’re also working in partnership with the United Nations, the international community, the Palestinian Authority, the Palestinian people, the Government of Israel to assist in the relief and recovery efforts in Gaza.  The – this relief is urgent.  We have to respond to the profound need to help people in this moment.</p>
<p>To that end, I informed President Abbas and, earlier, Prime Minister Netanyahu that the United States will notify Congress of our intention to provide $75 million in additional development and economic assistance for the Palestinians in 2021.  We’ll also provide $5.5 million in immediate disaster assistance for Gaza and a little over $32 million for UNRWA’s emergency humanitarian appeal.  This new assistance comes on top of significant support the United States has recently committed and resumed to the Palestinian Authority, the Palestinians, to different agencies and groups.</p>
<p>In total, we are in the process of providing more than $360 million of urgent support for the Palestinian people, and across these efforts, we will work with partners to ensure that Hamas does not benefit from these reconstruction efforts.  Asking the international community, asking all of us to help rebuild Gaza only makes sense if there is confidence that what is rebuilt is not lost again because Hamas decides to launch more rocket attacks in the future.  So this is vitally important.</p>
<p>We also talked a little bit about a challenge that all of us have faced together in the past year, and that is COVID-19.  And we will work in the United States to rally the international community to provide 1.5 million doses of safe, effective COVID-19 vaccines to the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>Beyond the immediate reconstruction and (inaudible), we’re also committed to working with the Palestinian Authority and the international community to promote economic stability and progress in the West Bank and Gaza, more opportunity, to strengthen the private sector, expand trade and investment, all of which are essential to growing opportunity across the board.  We’ll also work with the Palestinian Authority to ensure freedom of expression for all Palestinians and the promotion and protection of civil society.  I very much look forward in a short while to meeting with leaders from Palestinian civil society a little later today.</p>
<p>We will, as the president noted, continue to firmly oppose any unilateral provocative actions that risk sparking more violence and that undermine prospects for a just, durable resolution of the conflict between Palestinians and Israelis, which ultimately requires two states.  And whether that is settlement activity, whether that is home demolitions, annexation of territory, incitement to violence, compensation for individuals imprisoned for acts of terrorism, any unilateral action that undermines the prospects for genuine progress and genuine peace is something we will continue to oppose.</p>
<p>We remain committed to the historic status quo on the Haram al-Sharif.  Palestinians and Muslims from around the world must be able to pray in peace on the Noble Sanctuary, now and eternally.  In Jerusalem and across Israel, Christian and Muslim Palestinian families deserve the same right to worship, build, and thrive as their Jewish cohabitants.</p>
<p>The aspirations of the Palestinian people are like those of people everywhere: to live in freedom; to have their basic rights respected, including the right to choose their own leaders; to live in security; to have equal access to opportunity for themselves, for their children; to be treated with dignity.  And my message today is that the United States is committed, Mr. President, to working with you, to working with the Palestinian people, to realize these aspirations.</p>
<p>Thank you for having us here today.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Ramallah, West Bank</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ABBAS:</strong>  (Via interpreter)  In the name of God, the merciful and the compassionate, we would like to welcome Secretary Clinton, who visits us these – in these days &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>STAFF:</strong>  Blinken.</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ABBAS:</strong>  (Via interpreter) – sorry – Blinken, who visits us in these days &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  It’s an improvement.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT ABBAS:</strong>  (Via interpreter) – under very difficult conditions.  And we also would like to thank President Biden and the U.S. administration for their efforts to achieve a ceasefire between the Gaza Strip and Israel, and the efforts that they continue to exert in order to reach a comprehensive ceasefire that will hold.</p>
<p>We would also like to thank the U.S. administration for its support to the state of Palestine and for the resumption of its assistance to us and to the UNRWA.  This is something that we highly value, and we hope that the future will be rife with diplomatic and political effort headed by the U.S. and the Quartet so that we can reach a lasting and comprehensive peace in the region according to international legitimacy resolutions, and so that these actions on the part of a few – of a hurtful few would come to an end.</p>
<p>We also thank the U.S. administration for its commitment to a two-state solution, and the maintenance of the status quo in Jerusalem, and to keep the residents of Jerusalem and Sheikh Jarrah in their homes.  And also we thank the U.S. administration for its position vis-a-vis the expansion of settlements, and the actions taken by settlers.</p>
<p>We have also affirmed that we are committed to peaceful popular resistance and that we renounce violence and terrorism, and we only want to achieve a political solution through peaceful means between us and Israel.</p>
<p>We have also affirmed that our government stands ready to work directly in order for the reconstruction of Gaza and also to establish a national unity government for that end that would be all-inclusive.  And in the event that such agreement materializes, our first condition would be that Hamas and all parties have to abide by international legitimacy resolutions that are known for everyone.</p>
<p>And we also informed the Secretary that we have postponed the elections, because Israel has refused to include Jerusalem in these elections, and the minute that it does we will hold them immediately and without any delay, because ultimately what we’re interested in is to establish democracy throughout Palestine.</p>
<p>Once again, I thank the U.S. administration and President Biden and Secretary Tony Blinken for the efforts that he’s in engaging in now in order to achieve that end.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, Mr. President, thank you very, very much.  It’s very good to be in Ramallah, or maybe I should say back in Ramallah, to see you, to see the prime minister and your team.</p>
<p>And let me start by conveying the deep condolences of the United States to the families who’ve lost loved ones in the recent violence – the children, the women, the men whose lives were lost.  I say this as a father.  No child, whether Israeli, Palestinian, or American, is a statistic.  We know the human consequences when violence takes the upper hand, and we are determined that that not be the case.  I think the loss of any child is a universe of loss, and in some ways incomprehensible except to those who’ve suffered the loss.  And that’s true irrespective of whether you’re Israeli, Palestinian, American; if you’re a human being, that’s what matters.</p>
<p>We know that the last round of violence is symptomatic of a larger set of issues that we have to address if we’re going to prevent its recurrence, and that’s what we talked about today.  We welcome the ceasefire that continues to hold, but that’s not enough.  We have to build on the ceasefire and try to move things in a genuinely positive direction.  As I told the president, I am here to underscore the commitment of the United States to rebuilding a relationship with the Palestinian Authority and with the Palestinian people, a relationship built on mutual respect and also a shared conviction that Palestinians and Israelis alike deserve equal measures of freedom, security, opportunity, and dignity.</p>
<p>As I told Prime Minister Netanyahu and President Abbas, the United States will be moving forward with the process to reopen our consulate in Jerusalem.  That’s an important way for our country to engage with and provide support to the Palestinian people.  We’re also working in partnership with the United Nations, the international community, the Palestinian Authority, the Palestinian people, the Government of Israel to assist in the relief and recovery efforts in Gaza.  The – this relief is urgent.  We have to respond to the profound need to help people in this moment.</p>
<p>To that end, I informed President Abbas and, earlier, Prime Minister Netanyahu that the United States will notify Congress of our intention to provide $75 million in additional development and economic assistance for the Palestinians in 2021.  We’ll also provide $5.5 million in immediate disaster assistance for Gaza and a little over $32 million for UNRWA’s emergency humanitarian appeal.  This new assistance comes on top of significant support the United States has recently committed and resumed to the Palestinian Authority, the Palestinians, to different agencies and groups.</p>
<p>In total, we are in the process of providing more than $360 million of urgent support for the Palestinian people, and across these efforts, we will work with partners to ensure that Hamas does not benefit from these reconstruction efforts.  Asking the international community, asking all of us to help rebuild Gaza only makes sense if there is confidence that what is rebuilt is not lost again because Hamas decides to launch more rocket attacks in the future.  So this is vitally important.</p>
<p>We also talked a little bit about a challenge that all of us have faced together in the past year, and that is COVID-19.  And we will work in the United States to rally the international community to provide 1.5 million doses of safe, effective COVID-19 vaccines to the Palestinian people.</p>
<p>Beyond the immediate reconstruction and (inaudible), we’re also committed to working with the Palestinian Authority and the international community to promote economic stability and progress in the West Bank and Gaza, more opportunity, to strengthen the private sector, expand trade and investment, all of which are essential to growing opportunity across the board.  We’ll also work with the Palestinian Authority to ensure freedom of expression for all Palestinians and the promotion and protection of civil society.  I very much look forward in a short while to meeting with leaders from Palestinian civil society a little later today.</p>
<p>We will, as the president noted, continue to firmly oppose any unilateral provocative actions that risk sparking more violence and that undermine prospects for a just, durable resolution of the conflict between Palestinians and Israelis, which ultimately requires two states.  And whether that is settlement activity, whether that is home demolitions, annexation of territory, incitement to violence, compensation for individuals imprisoned for acts of terrorism, any unilateral action that undermines the prospects for genuine progress and genuine peace is something we will continue to oppose.</p>
<p>We remain committed to the historic status quo on the Haram al-Sharif.  Palestinians and Muslims from around the world must be able to pray in peace on the Noble Sanctuary, now and eternally.  In Jerusalem and across Israel, Christian and Muslim Palestinian families deserve the same right to worship, build, and thrive as their Jewish cohabitants.</p>
<p>The aspirations of the Palestinian people are like those of people everywhere: to live in freedom; to have their basic rights respected, including the right to choose their own leaders; to live in security; to have equal access to opportunity for themselves, for their children; to be treated with dignity.  And my message today is that the United States is committed, Mr. President, to working with you, to working with the Palestinian people, to realize these aspirations.</p>
<p>Thank you for having us here today.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with Palestinian Civil Society Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-palestinian-civil-society-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 17:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246198</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Ramallah, West Bank</p>
<p>AMIDEAST Offices</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Great.  So thank you, everybody, for being here.  I’m going to introduce our moderator, our Deputy Assistant Secretary Hady Amr.  He’s going to take it from here.  Thank you, sir.</p>
<p><strong>MR AMR:  </strong>Thank you so much.  And great to have you all here.  Good evening.  I know some of you.  My name’s Hady Amr, from Washington, working with Secretary Blinken.  As I’ve said before, it&#8217;s been a painful few weeks here in this land.  It’s been painful for us but I know it&#8217;s been much more painful for all of you.  The conditions that we’ve all seen have been heartbreaking, and I know that you want change and we do too.  As the Secretary said, as the President said, you all equally deserve to live in freedom, security, and prosperity.  And so that&#8217;s what we’re here to talk about today, so it’s very, very special for me personally to introduce you to Secretary Blinken.  He’s not just the Secretary of State.  He’s a good man, he’s a father, and he’s got a heart.  And so time is short, but I’d like the Secretary to maybe give some opening remarks and then go into a conversation.  So Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Hady, thank you very, very much.  And thank you all for being here.  I’m really anxious to hear from you so I want to be brief so we can use the time to – for me to learn and to hear from you.  But just a couple of things at the top.</p>
<p>One of the main purposes of my travel here at President Biden’s request is to renew ties between the United States and the Palestinian people, and to build on those ties going forward.  One critical aspect of any democratic society is civil society, and that’s why I’m particularly anxious to have a chance to talk to you.  Your voices, your experience, your insight, your advocacy I think are all critical components for the future.</p>
<p>And as Hady said a moment ago, we feel strongly that whether you’re Israeli, whether you’re Palestinian, you’re entitled to equal measures of peace, security, opportunity, and dignity.  And I know that from your different perspectives, that’s exactly what you&#8217;re working on.  So thank you for taking the time this evening.  And I really do want to turn it over to the four of you to hear from you.  So thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>All right.  Thank you, press.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Ramallah, West Bank</p>
<p>AMIDEAST Offices</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>Great.  So thank you, everybody, for being here.  I’m going to introduce our moderator, our Deputy Assistant Secretary Hady Amr.  He’s going to take it from here.  Thank you, sir.</p>
<p><strong>MR AMR:  </strong>Thank you so much.  And great to have you all here.  Good evening.  I know some of you.  My name’s Hady Amr, from Washington, working with Secretary Blinken.  As I’ve said before, it&#8217;s been a painful few weeks here in this land.  It’s been painful for us but I know it&#8217;s been much more painful for all of you.  The conditions that we’ve all seen have been heartbreaking, and I know that you want change and we do too.  As the Secretary said, as the President said, you all equally deserve to live in freedom, security, and prosperity.  And so that&#8217;s what we’re here to talk about today, so it’s very, very special for me personally to introduce you to Secretary Blinken.  He’s not just the Secretary of State.  He’s a good man, he’s a father, and he’s got a heart.  And so time is short, but I’d like the Secretary to maybe give some opening remarks and then go into a conversation.  So Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Hady, thank you very, very much.  And thank you all for being here.  I’m really anxious to hear from you so I want to be brief so we can use the time to – for me to learn and to hear from you.  But just a couple of things at the top.</p>
<p>One of the main purposes of my travel here at President Biden’s request is to renew ties between the United States and the Palestinian people, and to build on those ties going forward.  One critical aspect of any democratic society is civil society, and that’s why I’m particularly anxious to have a chance to talk to you.  Your voices, your experience, your insight, your advocacy I think are all critical components for the future.</p>
<p>And as Hady said a moment ago, we feel strongly that whether you’re Israeli, whether you’re Palestinian, you’re entitled to equal measures of peace, security, opportunity, and dignity.  And I know that from your different perspectives, that’s exactly what you&#8217;re working on.  So thank you for taking the time this evening.  And I really do want to turn it over to the four of you to hear from you.  So thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:  </strong>All right.  Thank you, press.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcoming Costa Rica to the OECD</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/welcoming-costa-rica-to-the-oecd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 15:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246151</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>I am very pleased to welcome Costa Rica as the 38th member of the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD). The OECD is a unique forum of like-minded democracies dedicated to promoting our shared values and addressing our shared challenges.</p>
<p>Costa Rica’s membership follows an extensive multiyear effort to align its economic policies with OECD recommendations and is a strong signal of confidence in the Costa Rican economy. I commend Costa Rica for the rigor in tackling the various requirements for accession. Costa Rica has made great strides in curbing its fiscal deficit in this challenging COVID-19 context. I applaud its agreement with the International Monetary Fund and hope to see a national consensus to make the necessary reforms to fully implement the accord. I want to recognize Manuel Tovar, Costa Rica’s Permanent Representative to the OECD, for his dedication and commitment as Costa Rica completed its accession process.</p>
<p>Costa Rica&#8217;s accession comes at a timely moment in OECD history, as the organization celebrates its 60th anniversary and transitions to leadership under a new Secretary General. As Chair of this year’s 60th anniversary Ministerial Council Meeting, I look forward to our increased partnership as OECD members focus on supporting a global economic recovery that builds back better and champions our shared values.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>I am very pleased to welcome Costa Rica as the 38th member of the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD). The OECD is a unique forum of like-minded democracies dedicated to promoting our shared values and addressing our shared challenges.</p>
<p>Costa Rica’s membership follows an extensive multiyear effort to align its economic policies with OECD recommendations and is a strong signal of confidence in the Costa Rican economy. I commend Costa Rica for the rigor in tackling the various requirements for accession. Costa Rica has made great strides in curbing its fiscal deficit in this challenging COVID-19 context. I applaud its agreement with the International Monetary Fund and hope to see a national consensus to make the necessary reforms to fully implement the accord. I want to recognize Manuel Tovar, Costa Rica’s Permanent Representative to the OECD, for his dedication and commitment as Costa Rica completed its accession process.</p>
<p>Costa Rica&#8217;s accession comes at a timely moment in OECD history, as the organization celebrates its 60th anniversary and transitions to leadership under a new Secretary General. As Chair of this year’s 60th anniversary Ministerial Council Meeting, I look forward to our increased partnership as OECD members focus on supporting a global economic recovery that builds back better and champions our shared values.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Israeli Alternate Prime Minister Gantz</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-israeli-alternate-prime-minister-gantz/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 13:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246067</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today in Jerusalem with Israeli Alternate Prime Minister and Minister of Defense Benjamin Gantz.  They expressed their support for the ceasefire and noted their gratitude for partners, including Egypt, that helped to bring it about. They exchanged views on Iran, and the Secretary underscored the United States’ strong commitment to Israel’s security as well as to the broader U.S.-Israel partnership.  The Secretary emphasized the need for Israelis and Palestinians to be able to live in safety and security, as well as enjoy equal measures of freedom, security, prosperity, and democracy.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today in Jerusalem with Israeli Alternate Prime Minister and Minister of Defense Benjamin Gantz.  They expressed their support for the ceasefire and noted their gratitude for partners, including Egypt, that helped to bring it about. They exchanged views on Iran, and the Secretary underscored the United States’ strong commitment to Israel’s security as well as to the broader U.S.-Israel partnership.  The Secretary emphasized the need for Israelis and Palestinians to be able to live in safety and security, as well as enjoy equal measures of freedom, security, prosperity, and democracy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Meet and Greet with Embassy Jerusalem Staff</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-meet-and-greet-with-embassy-jerusalem-staff/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 13:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246046</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Jerusalem, Israel</p>
<p>Embassy Jerusalem</p>
<p><strong>MR SHRIER:</strong>  We have – we are honored with a very special guest, Secretary of State Antony Blinken, and I just want to say in introduction, sir, that you’re looking at a very small part of our embassy staff of nearly 1,500 persons.  And when I look at our staff, what I see is hope – hope because we have a wide diversity of people represented in our embassy staff.  Of course, you have the Americans, who themselves represent the diverse parts of American society.  But we also see hope here because we see Israelis, we see – from all sorts of communities, including Arab citizens of Israel, Jewish citizens of Israel of various backgrounds.  And we also see Palestinians from the West Bank, we see East Jerusalemites, and you met two of our Gaza-based staff.  So you see a diverse community working together for the benefit of U.S. relations with Israel and with the Palestinian Authority.  And so that is what gives me hope.  And with that, sir, I give you the crowd.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Jonathan, thank you.  Thank you so much, not just for the remarks today, but for what you’ve been doing every day, your leadership in a rather challenging time – maybe it’s always a challenging time, but this one in particular is – and we are grateful for that.  And it is wonderful to be with all of you today, and thank you for literally a warm welcome, very much appreciate that.</p>
<p>I really wanted an opportunity, even during this very short trip, to get a chance to visit with some of you in person, and to say very simply thank you.  Thank you on behalf of the United States for serving so capably under such challenging circumstances in what is one of our most important missions in the world.  You know what you feel it, the eyes of the world are often on you, and they certainly have been the last couple of weeks.  And with that, you are still doing your work with remarkable skill, remarkable dedication, remarkable courage through all kinds of disruptions.</p>
<p>Three years ago, the embassy moved from Tel Aviv to Jerusalem.  A year later, the consulate and embassy merged.  Last year, the pandemic.  And of course, the recent hostilities that you have lived through and worked through.  Through all of this, through all of these challenges, you’ve kept going.  This entire community has kept going, carrying out day-to-day responsibilities, solving problems literally on the fly, being a resource, being a mainstay for more than 600,000 American citizens who live in Israel, the West Bank, and Gaza.</p>
<p>I’m here as the head of the State Department, but I really want to applaud everyone who is part of this community from so many other U.S. agencies, whether you work for the Department of Defense, Commerce, Justice, Homeland Security, USAID, the Social Security Administration, the U.S. Security Coordinator, or any other agency that’s part of this community.  Again, on behalf of the President, the Vice President, thank you for everything you do to make this mission work so well.</p>
<p>And as Jonathan mentioned, I also want to say a special thanks to our colleagues who are part of the locally employed staff.  I know from the many embassies I’ve had an opportunity to visit with over many years that the lifeblood of any of our missions is the locally employed staff, more than a thousand of our team here.  And it is extraordinary to think of what so many of our locally employed colleagues have endured.  I heard firsthand some of the stories from some of your colleagues.  I just met with several who had experienced the recent violence in Gaza, outside of Gaza in Israel, successfully evacuated but also with powerful stories about what they had experienced, what their families had experienced.</p>
<p>And as I said to them, this is such an important reminder to all of us who have any responsibility for policy, because one of the things it’s easy to forget is the impact of what you’re doing on real lives, and that what this comes down to – everything we’re doing every single day, everything you’re doing every single day, is going to have an impact on a father, a mother, a son, a daughter, a sister, a brother, an aunt, an uncle, and hopefully – hopefully, a positive one.</p>
<p>Sometimes this all gets reduced to numbers and statistics.  We’ve heard a lot of numbers and statistics the last few weeks, but we can’t lose sight of the profoundly human element of everything that we’re doing and that you’re doing, and I’m really grateful for that reminder today.  And I know that that animates you every single day.</p>
<p>I also hope that you’ll let your family members know how grateful we are to them, because we know that the sacrifices you’re making to serve has an effect on them as well.  And again, I know that for literally – probably literally everyone here – the last few weeks have been particularly stressful.  And I just want to say as well that nothing is more important to us than your safety and the safety of your loved ones.  That is always going to be priority number one.</p>
<p>We’re trying to do a number of things while we’re here just in this short period of time.  We have a strong and abiding commitment to Israel and to its security.  We have a determination to help as effectively as we can deal with the humanitarian crisis in Gaza and also start to build back.  We’re determined as well to re-engage with the Palestinian Authority and with the Palestinian people.  And mostly, we want to try to make a turn after the last couple of weeks to something that is more positive, that actually starts to improve the lives of people, whether they’re Palestinians or Israelis.  And none of this is going to be like flipping a switch.  There is a lot of hard, sustained work ahead but we’re committed to doing that, and it doesn’t work without all of you.</p>
<p>We want to see a future in which Israelis and Palestinians alike know equal measures of peace, security, justice, and maybe most fundamentally of all, dignity, because that may be one of the most powerful human emotions that binds us all together.  And we have to look out for that and look out for each other and respect the dignity of our fellow human beings, whatever – whatever their backgrounds.</p>
<p>In a few days, as I think some of you or maybe most of you know, Michael Ratney will join you as your new charge.  He served previously as the deputy assistant secretary of state, and working on Israel-Palestinian affairs, and consul general here in Jerusalem.  So I think he may be personally known to many of you, and he’ll be a great leader.  But again, I, Jonathan, want to thank you so much for your remarkable leadership at this time.</p>
<p>So I also know, finally, that a lot of work goes into even a very short visit, and this one was on particularly short notice.  So to those of you who were working on it, thank you, thank you, thank you.  I suspect there were a couple of all-nighters for a few of you, so you’re very much entitled to a very, very good wheels-up party which won’t be too long to come.  But I know this wouldn’t happen without you, so thank you.</p>
<p>I suspect, though, that we’ll be back, so more work to come.  And meanwhile, thank you for everything you&#8217;re doing.  And I think we have time for a few questions.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Jerusalem, Israel</p>
<p>Embassy Jerusalem</p>
<p><strong>MR SHRIER:</strong>  We have – we are honored with a very special guest, Secretary of State Antony Blinken, and I just want to say in introduction, sir, that you’re looking at a very small part of our embassy staff of nearly 1,500 persons.  And when I look at our staff, what I see is hope – hope because we have a wide diversity of people represented in our embassy staff.  Of course, you have the Americans, who themselves represent the diverse parts of American society.  But we also see hope here because we see Israelis, we see – from all sorts of communities, including Arab citizens of Israel, Jewish citizens of Israel of various backgrounds.  And we also see Palestinians from the West Bank, we see East Jerusalemites, and you met two of our Gaza-based staff.  So you see a diverse community working together for the benefit of U.S. relations with Israel and with the Palestinian Authority.  And so that is what gives me hope.  And with that, sir, I give you the crowd.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Jonathan, thank you.  Thank you so much, not just for the remarks today, but for what you’ve been doing every day, your leadership in a rather challenging time – maybe it’s always a challenging time, but this one in particular is – and we are grateful for that.  And it is wonderful to be with all of you today, and thank you for literally a warm welcome, very much appreciate that.</p>
<p>I really wanted an opportunity, even during this very short trip, to get a chance to visit with some of you in person, and to say very simply thank you.  Thank you on behalf of the United States for serving so capably under such challenging circumstances in what is one of our most important missions in the world.  You know what you feel it, the eyes of the world are often on you, and they certainly have been the last couple of weeks.  And with that, you are still doing your work with remarkable skill, remarkable dedication, remarkable courage through all kinds of disruptions.</p>
<p>Three years ago, the embassy moved from Tel Aviv to Jerusalem.  A year later, the consulate and embassy merged.  Last year, the pandemic.  And of course, the recent hostilities that you have lived through and worked through.  Through all of this, through all of these challenges, you’ve kept going.  This entire community has kept going, carrying out day-to-day responsibilities, solving problems literally on the fly, being a resource, being a mainstay for more than 600,000 American citizens who live in Israel, the West Bank, and Gaza.</p>
<p>I’m here as the head of the State Department, but I really want to applaud everyone who is part of this community from so many other U.S. agencies, whether you work for the Department of Defense, Commerce, Justice, Homeland Security, USAID, the Social Security Administration, the U.S. Security Coordinator, or any other agency that’s part of this community.  Again, on behalf of the President, the Vice President, thank you for everything you do to make this mission work so well.</p>
<p>And as Jonathan mentioned, I also want to say a special thanks to our colleagues who are part of the locally employed staff.  I know from the many embassies I’ve had an opportunity to visit with over many years that the lifeblood of any of our missions is the locally employed staff, more than a thousand of our team here.  And it is extraordinary to think of what so many of our locally employed colleagues have endured.  I heard firsthand some of the stories from some of your colleagues.  I just met with several who had experienced the recent violence in Gaza, outside of Gaza in Israel, successfully evacuated but also with powerful stories about what they had experienced, what their families had experienced.</p>
<p>And as I said to them, this is such an important reminder to all of us who have any responsibility for policy, because one of the things it’s easy to forget is the impact of what you’re doing on real lives, and that what this comes down to – everything we’re doing every single day, everything you’re doing every single day, is going to have an impact on a father, a mother, a son, a daughter, a sister, a brother, an aunt, an uncle, and hopefully – hopefully, a positive one.</p>
<p>Sometimes this all gets reduced to numbers and statistics.  We’ve heard a lot of numbers and statistics the last few weeks, but we can’t lose sight of the profoundly human element of everything that we’re doing and that you’re doing, and I’m really grateful for that reminder today.  And I know that that animates you every single day.</p>
<p>I also hope that you’ll let your family members know how grateful we are to them, because we know that the sacrifices you’re making to serve has an effect on them as well.  And again, I know that for literally – probably literally everyone here – the last few weeks have been particularly stressful.  And I just want to say as well that nothing is more important to us than your safety and the safety of your loved ones.  That is always going to be priority number one.</p>
<p>We’re trying to do a number of things while we’re here just in this short period of time.  We have a strong and abiding commitment to Israel and to its security.  We have a determination to help as effectively as we can deal with the humanitarian crisis in Gaza and also start to build back.  We’re determined as well to re-engage with the Palestinian Authority and with the Palestinian people.  And mostly, we want to try to make a turn after the last couple of weeks to something that is more positive, that actually starts to improve the lives of people, whether they’re Palestinians or Israelis.  And none of this is going to be like flipping a switch.  There is a lot of hard, sustained work ahead but we’re committed to doing that, and it doesn’t work without all of you.</p>
<p>We want to see a future in which Israelis and Palestinians alike know equal measures of peace, security, justice, and maybe most fundamentally of all, dignity, because that may be one of the most powerful human emotions that binds us all together.  And we have to look out for that and look out for each other and respect the dignity of our fellow human beings, whatever – whatever their backgrounds.</p>
<p>In a few days, as I think some of you or maybe most of you know, Michael Ratney will join you as your new charge.  He served previously as the deputy assistant secretary of state, and working on Israel-Palestinian affairs, and consul general here in Jerusalem.  So I think he may be personally known to many of you, and he’ll be a great leader.  But again, I, Jonathan, want to thank you so much for your remarkable leadership at this time.</p>
<p>So I also know, finally, that a lot of work goes into even a very short visit, and this one was on particularly short notice.  So to those of you who were working on it, thank you, thank you, thank you.  I suspect there were a couple of all-nighters for a few of you, so you’re very much entitled to a very, very good wheels-up party which won’t be too long to come.  But I know this wouldn’t happen without you, so thank you.</p>
<p>I suspect, though, that we’ll be back, so more work to come.  And meanwhile, thank you for everything you&#8217;re doing.  And I think we have time for a few questions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Israeli Foreign Minister Gabi Ashkenazi Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-israeli-foreign-minister-gabi-ashkenazi-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 12:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246026</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Jerusalem</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER ASHKENAZI:  </strong>Very briefly.  It’s an honor and pleasure to have my friend the Secretary of State for his first official visit in Israel and welcoming him on behalf of the government and the people of Israel.  The United States is our closest ally.  I’m committed, as I’m sure the Secretary, for expanding the relationship.  It’s an excellent opportunity to thank their President of the United States and the Secretary of State and his team for their unwavering support of the State of Israel.  It was no surprise to me from the day one that we discussed.  Thank you for the dedicated move and the close relation and involvement during the last event.  I wish you a fruitful visit in Israel.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you very, very much.  It&#8217;s wonderful to be here.  It&#8217;s particularly wonderful to get a chance to spend some time with Gabi, with the foreign minister.  We know each other very well because we&#8217;ve spent a lot of time on the phone together over these past months now, and certainly over the last few weeks.  But I&#8217;m particularly pleased to be here and get a chance to spend some time in person.</p>
<p>I think Gabi said it very, very well.  I&#8217;m here, as I said earlier, to reaffirm the strong commitment of United States to Israel&#8217;s security, to the partnership between us, to move forward now on dealing with the humanitarian situation in Gaza and also starting to rebuild, to re-engage with the Palestinian community and Palestinian Authority.  And I hope to start to move things in a positive direction where we can make material progress in the lives of Israelis and Palestinians alike.  We have a lot of work to do, but we&#8217;re grateful to have close parties.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER ASHKENAZI:  </strong>The Secretary has an impossible schedule, so thank you, we have to move.  Thank you very much.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Jerusalem</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER ASHKENAZI:  </strong>Very briefly.  It’s an honor and pleasure to have my friend the Secretary of State for his first official visit in Israel and welcoming him on behalf of the government and the people of Israel.  The United States is our closest ally.  I’m committed, as I’m sure the Secretary, for expanding the relationship.  It’s an excellent opportunity to thank their President of the United States and the Secretary of State and his team for their unwavering support of the State of Israel.  It was no surprise to me from the day one that we discussed.  Thank you for the dedicated move and the close relation and involvement during the last event.  I wish you a fruitful visit in Israel.  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you very, very much.  It&#8217;s wonderful to be here.  It&#8217;s particularly wonderful to get a chance to spend some time with Gabi, with the foreign minister.  We know each other very well because we&#8217;ve spent a lot of time on the phone together over these past months now, and certainly over the last few weeks.  But I&#8217;m particularly pleased to be here and get a chance to spend some time in person.</p>
<p>I think Gabi said it very, very well.  I&#8217;m here, as I said earlier, to reaffirm the strong commitment of United States to Israel&#8217;s security, to the partnership between us, to move forward now on dealing with the humanitarian situation in Gaza and also starting to rebuild, to re-engage with the Palestinian community and Palestinian Authority.  And I hope to start to move things in a positive direction where we can make material progress in the lives of Israelis and Palestinians alike.  We have a lot of work to do, but we&#8217;re grateful to have close parties.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER ASHKENAZI:  </strong>The Secretary has an impossible schedule, so thank you, we have to move.  Thank you very much.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu Statements to the Press</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-israeli-prime-minister-benjamin-netanyahu-statements-to-the-press/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 11:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=246008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Jerusalem</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MININSTER NETANYAHU:</strong>  Secretary Blinken, Tony, welcome to Jerusalem, your first visit as the Secretary of State.  I have – since we’re running – we had a long discussion, and we’re running late, so I want to be very brief and speak about three points.</p>
<p>The first point is a vote of thanks to President Biden and you for firmly supporting Israel’s right of self-defense.  I have to say that Secretary Blinken, in a previous capacity in 2014, when we had another round of engagement against Hamas aggression, supported us by having Iron Dome replenishments, a quarter of a billion dollars, that you personally shepherded through the system very quickly.  And we remember it and we’re very grateful to you.  And you are giving meaning to this now again with replenishments of Iron Dome interceptors that saved civilian lives on both sides, and we’re grateful for that too.  We too will give meaning to our commitment to our self-defense.  If Hamas breaks the calm and attacks Israel, our response will be very powerful.  And we have discussed ways of how to work together to prevent Hamas rearmament with weapons and means of aggression.</p>
<p>The second point is – naturally, is Iran.  We discussed many regional issues, but none is greater than Iran.  And I can tell you that I hope that the United States will not go back to the old JCPOA because we believe that that deal paves the way for Iran to have an arsenal of nuclear weapons with international legitimacy.  We also reiterated that whatever happens, Israel will always reserve the right to defend itself against a regime committed to our destruction, committed to getting the weapons of mass destruction for that end.</p>
<p>The third point is peace.  We need to work together to expand normalization between Israel and the Arab and the Muslim world, and deepen the peace treaties that we already have.  We discussed also how to improve the lives and the conditions of the Palestinians, the humanitarian conditions in Gaza, including the question of the return of our MIAs and two civilians who are there, as well as building economic growth for Judea and Samaria, the West Bank, with international cooperation and participation, and for peace itself with the Palestinians, a formal peace.  I think President Biden was absolutely correct when he said you’re not going to get peace until Israel is recognized as an independent Jewish state.  And that is the key.  I couldn’t agree more with President Biden.</p>
<p>And I couldn’t be happier than welcoming you here and your delegation in Jerusalem.  We have a lot to work for.  We have common goals of peace, security, and prosperity, and I look forward to working with you on those in this visit and more, so welcome.  Welcome.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Prime Minister, thank you.  Thank you very, very much.  Thank you for hosting us today.  Thank you for the very good and lengthy conversation.  I’m looking forward also to spending some more time with some of our colleagues, with Foreign Minister Ashkenazi, Defense Minister Gantz, as well later with President Abbas and other Palestinian leaders.</p>
<p>President Biden asked me to come here today, really, for four reasons:  First, to demonstrate the commitment of the United States to Israel’s security, to start to work toward greater stability and reduce tensions in the West Bank and Jerusalem, to support urgent humanitarian and reconstruction assistance for Gaza, to benefit the Palestinian people, and to continue to rebuild our relationship with the Palestinian people and the Palestinian Authority.  Intense behind-the-scenes diplomacy led by President Biden, working very closely with the prime minister, helped produce last week’s ceasefire.  Now, we believe we must build on it.</p>
<p>That starts with the recognition that losses on both sides were profound. Casualties are often reduced to numbers but behind every number is an individual human being – a daughter, a son, a father, a mother, a grandparent, a best friend.  And as the Talmud teaches, to lose a life is to lose the whole world, whether that life is Palestinian or Israeli.  I underscored to the prime minister something that President Biden made crystal-clear throughout the violence:  The United States fully supports Israel’s right to defend itself against attacks such as the thousands of rockets fired by Hamas indiscriminately against Israeli civilians.</p>
<p>For the President, I think as many of you know, this commitment is personal.  It runs deep.  He has been one of Israel’s most steadfast supporters for the last 50 years, having worked closely with every prime minister starting with Golda Meir and now with Prime Minister Netanyahu.</p>
<p>As the prime minister mentioned, we had a detailed discussion about Israel’s security needs, including replenishing Iron Dome.  We’ll continue to strengthen all aspects of our longstanding partnership.  And that includes consulting closely with Israel, as we did today, on the ongoing negotiations in Vienna around a potential return to the Iran nuclear agreement, at the same time as we continue to work together to counter Iran’s destabilizing actions in the region.</p>
<p>We know that to prevent a return to violence, we have to use the space created to address a larger set of underlying issues and challenges, and that begins with tackling the grave humanitarian situation in Gaza and starting to rebuild.  The United States will work to rally international support around that effort while also making our own significant contributions, including some that I’ll announce later today.  We’ll work with our partners, closely with all to ensure that Hamas does not benefit from the reconstruction assistance.</p>
<p>At the same time, we need to work to expand opportunity for Palestinians in Gaza and in the West Bank, including by strengthening the private sector, expanding trade and investment, and other means.  Assistance and investment like these will help foster a more stable environment that benefits Palestinians and also benefits Israelis.</p>
<p>Prime Minister and I had a chance to discuss other steps that need to be taken by leaders on both sides to set a better course for their shared future.  As President Biden has said, we believe that Palestinians and Israelis equally deserve to live safely and securely; to enjoy equal measures of freedom, opportunity, and democracy; to be treated with dignity.  We also discussed some of the intercommunal violence that erupted in Israel during the conflict, and healing these wounds will take leadership at every level of society, from elected officials to community leaders to neighbors.  And we very much welcome the statements the prime minister made and members of his government made condemning the attacks regardless of whom they targeted.</p>
<p>In our own country, in the United States, we’ve witnessed a shocking eruption of anti-Semitic attacks.  As President Biden said just yesterday, they are despicable and they must stop.  There’s a lot of hard work ahead to restore hope, respect, and some trust across communities.  But we’ve seen the alternative, and I think that should cause all of us to redouble our efforts to preserve the peace and improve the lives of Israelis and Palestinians alike.</p>
<p>But Prime Minister, again, thank you so much for all the time, thank you for the very, very good conversation, and we look forward to doing a lot of work together.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER NETANYAHU:</strong>  And thank you and the President for your strong statements against anti-Semitism masquerading as anti-Zionism, but it’s anti-Semitism, and you took a bold position, clear position, and we appreciate it.  I think all decent people, decent people everywhere appreciate that stance.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Jerusalem</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MININSTER NETANYAHU:</strong>  Secretary Blinken, Tony, welcome to Jerusalem, your first visit as the Secretary of State.  I have – since we’re running – we had a long discussion, and we’re running late, so I want to be very brief and speak about three points.</p>
<p>The first point is a vote of thanks to President Biden and you for firmly supporting Israel’s right of self-defense.  I have to say that Secretary Blinken, in a previous capacity in 2014, when we had another round of engagement against Hamas aggression, supported us by having Iron Dome replenishments, a quarter of a billion dollars, that you personally shepherded through the system very quickly.  And we remember it and we’re very grateful to you.  And you are giving meaning to this now again with replenishments of Iron Dome interceptors that saved civilian lives on both sides, and we’re grateful for that too.  We too will give meaning to our commitment to our self-defense.  If Hamas breaks the calm and attacks Israel, our response will be very powerful.  And we have discussed ways of how to work together to prevent Hamas rearmament with weapons and means of aggression.</p>
<p>The second point is – naturally, is Iran.  We discussed many regional issues, but none is greater than Iran.  And I can tell you that I hope that the United States will not go back to the old JCPOA because we believe that that deal paves the way for Iran to have an arsenal of nuclear weapons with international legitimacy.  We also reiterated that whatever happens, Israel will always reserve the right to defend itself against a regime committed to our destruction, committed to getting the weapons of mass destruction for that end.</p>
<p>The third point is peace.  We need to work together to expand normalization between Israel and the Arab and the Muslim world, and deepen the peace treaties that we already have.  We discussed also how to improve the lives and the conditions of the Palestinians, the humanitarian conditions in Gaza, including the question of the return of our MIAs and two civilians who are there, as well as building economic growth for Judea and Samaria, the West Bank, with international cooperation and participation, and for peace itself with the Palestinians, a formal peace.  I think President Biden was absolutely correct when he said you’re not going to get peace until Israel is recognized as an independent Jewish state.  And that is the key.  I couldn’t agree more with President Biden.</p>
<p>And I couldn’t be happier than welcoming you here and your delegation in Jerusalem.  We have a lot to work for.  We have common goals of peace, security, and prosperity, and I look forward to working with you on those in this visit and more, so welcome.  Welcome.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  Prime Minister, thank you.  Thank you very, very much.  Thank you for hosting us today.  Thank you for the very good and lengthy conversation.  I’m looking forward also to spending some more time with some of our colleagues, with Foreign Minister Ashkenazi, Defense Minister Gantz, as well later with President Abbas and other Palestinian leaders.</p>
<p>President Biden asked me to come here today, really, for four reasons:  First, to demonstrate the commitment of the United States to Israel’s security, to start to work toward greater stability and reduce tensions in the West Bank and Jerusalem, to support urgent humanitarian and reconstruction assistance for Gaza, to benefit the Palestinian people, and to continue to rebuild our relationship with the Palestinian people and the Palestinian Authority.  Intense behind-the-scenes diplomacy led by President Biden, working very closely with the prime minister, helped produce last week’s ceasefire.  Now, we believe we must build on it.</p>
<p>That starts with the recognition that losses on both sides were profound. Casualties are often reduced to numbers but behind every number is an individual human being – a daughter, a son, a father, a mother, a grandparent, a best friend.  And as the Talmud teaches, to lose a life is to lose the whole world, whether that life is Palestinian or Israeli.  I underscored to the prime minister something that President Biden made crystal-clear throughout the violence:  The United States fully supports Israel’s right to defend itself against attacks such as the thousands of rockets fired by Hamas indiscriminately against Israeli civilians.</p>
<p>For the President, I think as many of you know, this commitment is personal.  It runs deep.  He has been one of Israel’s most steadfast supporters for the last 50 years, having worked closely with every prime minister starting with Golda Meir and now with Prime Minister Netanyahu.</p>
<p>As the prime minister mentioned, we had a detailed discussion about Israel’s security needs, including replenishing Iron Dome.  We’ll continue to strengthen all aspects of our longstanding partnership.  And that includes consulting closely with Israel, as we did today, on the ongoing negotiations in Vienna around a potential return to the Iran nuclear agreement, at the same time as we continue to work together to counter Iran’s destabilizing actions in the region.</p>
<p>We know that to prevent a return to violence, we have to use the space created to address a larger set of underlying issues and challenges, and that begins with tackling the grave humanitarian situation in Gaza and starting to rebuild.  The United States will work to rally international support around that effort while also making our own significant contributions, including some that I’ll announce later today.  We’ll work with our partners, closely with all to ensure that Hamas does not benefit from the reconstruction assistance.</p>
<p>At the same time, we need to work to expand opportunity for Palestinians in Gaza and in the West Bank, including by strengthening the private sector, expanding trade and investment, and other means.  Assistance and investment like these will help foster a more stable environment that benefits Palestinians and also benefits Israelis.</p>
<p>Prime Minister and I had a chance to discuss other steps that need to be taken by leaders on both sides to set a better course for their shared future.  As President Biden has said, we believe that Palestinians and Israelis equally deserve to live safely and securely; to enjoy equal measures of freedom, opportunity, and democracy; to be treated with dignity.  We also discussed some of the intercommunal violence that erupted in Israel during the conflict, and healing these wounds will take leadership at every level of society, from elected officials to community leaders to neighbors.  And we very much welcome the statements the prime minister made and members of his government made condemning the attacks regardless of whom they targeted.</p>
<p>In our own country, in the United States, we’ve witnessed a shocking eruption of anti-Semitic attacks.  As President Biden said just yesterday, they are despicable and they must stop.  There’s a lot of hard work ahead to restore hope, respect, and some trust across communities.  But we’ve seen the alternative, and I think that should cause all of us to redouble our efforts to preserve the peace and improve the lives of Israelis and Palestinians alike.</p>
<p>But Prime Minister, again, thank you so much for all the time, thank you for the very, very good conversation, and we look forward to doing a lot of work together.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER NETANYAHU:</strong>  And thank you and the President for your strong statements against anti-Semitism masquerading as anti-Zionism, but it’s anti-Semitism, and you took a bold position, clear position, and we appreciate it.  I think all decent people, decent people everywhere appreciate that stance.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Irish Minister for Foreign Affairs and Defense Minister Coveney</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-irish-minister-for-foreign-affairs-and-defense-minister-coveney/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=245949</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Irish Minister for Foreign Affairs and Defense Simon Coveney.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Coveney reaffirmed the strong bilateral relationship between the United States and Ireland and Ireland’s role as an enduring Transatlantic partner.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister condemned the outrageous diversion of Ryanair Flight 4978 in Belarus, and they discussed the status of JCPOA negotiations, Ireland’s role on the UN Security Council as a non-permanent member, and other shared foreign policy priorities.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Irish Minister for Foreign Affairs and Defense Simon Coveney.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Coveney reaffirmed the strong bilateral relationship between the United States and Ireland and Ireland’s role as an enduring Transatlantic partner.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister condemned the outrageous diversion of Ryanair Flight 4978 in Belarus, and they discussed the status of JCPOA negotiations, Ireland’s role on the UN Security Council as a non-permanent member, and other shared foreign policy priorities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
