<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 18:41:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Leader of the Democratic Opposition of Belarus Tsikhanouskaya</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-leader-of-the-democratic-opposition-of-belarus-tsikhanouskaya/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 18:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=339604</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met yesterday with Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya, leader of the democratic opposition of Belarus.  They discussed the Lukashenka regime’s continued support of Russia’s unprovoked war against Ukraine and U.S. efforts to hold the regime accountable for its complicity, as well as for its sustained crackdown on human rights and democratic freedoms. Secretary of State Antony Blinken joined the group for part of the meeting.  Deputy Secretary Sherman, together with Ms. Tsikhanouskaya, called for an end to the Lukashenka regime’s ongoing crackdown on democratic voices and for the unconditional release of all political prisoners in Belarus and emphasized the United States’ enduring support for the Belarusian people’s democratic aspirations.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met yesterday with Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya, leader of the democratic opposition of Belarus.  They discussed the Lukashenka regime’s continued support of Russia’s unprovoked war against Ukraine and U.S. efforts to hold the regime accountable for its complicity, as well as for its sustained crackdown on human rights and democratic freedoms. Secretary of State Antony Blinken joined the group for part of the meeting.  Deputy Secretary Sherman, together with Ms. Tsikhanouskaya, called for an end to the Lukashenka regime’s ongoing crackdown on democratic voices and for the unconditional release of all political prisoners in Belarus and emphasized the United States’ enduring support for the Belarusian people’s democratic aspirations.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel J. Kritenbrink’s Travel to Cambodia and Laos</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-of-state-for-east-asian-and-pacific-affairs-daniel-j-kritenbrinks-travel-to-cambodia-and-laos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 17:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=339538</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel J. Kritenbrink will travel to Cambodia and Laos May 1-7.  The visits will highlight U.S. commitment to two of the youngest and most dynamic societies in the region, reinforcing ASEAN centrality, underscoring the United States’ commitment to the Mekong-U.S. Partnership to address transboundary challenges, and promoting a secure, open and prosperous Mekong sub-region.</p>
<p>In Cambodia, Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink will meet with Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Prak Sokhonn and other senior officials, and youth and civil society leaders to discuss our bilateral relationship and U.S. support for Cambodia’s year as ASEAN Chair.</p>
<p>In Laos, Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink will lead the U.S.-Laos Comprehensive Bilateral Dialogue to discuss closer U.S.-Laos cooperation and forge deeper connection with Laos as the 2022 Mekong-U.S. Partnership co-chair.  He will meet with Foreign Minister Saleumxay Kommasith, Vice Foreign Minister Thongphane Savanphet, and officials from the Mekong River Commission.  The Assistant Secretary will also engage with alumni of Department of State exchange programs.</p>
<p>In both countries, Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink will discuss the upcoming U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit that President Biden will host in Washington May 12-13.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel J. Kritenbrink will travel to Cambodia and Laos May 1-7.  The visits will highlight U.S. commitment to two of the youngest and most dynamic societies in the region, reinforcing ASEAN centrality, underscoring the United States’ commitment to the Mekong-U.S. Partnership to address transboundary challenges, and promoting a secure, open and prosperous Mekong sub-region.</p>
<p>In Cambodia, Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink will meet with Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Prak Sokhonn and other senior officials, and youth and civil society leaders to discuss our bilateral relationship and U.S. support for Cambodia’s year as ASEAN Chair.</p>
<p>In Laos, Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink will lead the U.S.-Laos Comprehensive Bilateral Dialogue to discuss closer U.S.-Laos cooperation and forge deeper connection with Laos as the 2022 Mekong-U.S. Partnership co-chair.  He will meet with Foreign Minister Saleumxay Kommasith, Vice Foreign Minister Thongphane Savanphet, and officials from the Mekong River Commission.  The Assistant Secretary will also engage with alumni of Department of State exchange programs.</p>
<p>In both countries, Assistant Secretary Kritenbrink will discuss the upcoming U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit that President Biden will host in Washington May 12-13.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twenty-fifth Anniversary of the Chemical Weapons Convention’s Entry into Force</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/twenty-fifth-anniversary-of-the-chemical-weapons-conventions-entry-into-force/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=339403</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Today marks the twenty-fifth anniversary of the entry into force of the Chemical Weapons Convention (CWC).  For a quarter of a century, the United States has worked with its Allies and partners to help rid the world of chemical weapons and deter their use by anyone, anywhere, and under any circumstances.  Our collective goal is to exclude completely the possibility of the use of chemical weapons, which are abhorrent tools of war.  On this anniversary, we renew our commitment to upholding the CWC and note the Convention’s important role in contributing to U.S. national security.  Unfortunately, this anniversary reminds us that the world continues to be threatened by the specter of these weapons.</p>
<p>In recent years, the world has witnessed chemical weapons use that challenges the CWC’s core prohibitions: by the Assad regime and ISIS in Syria, by Russian government operatives against the Skripals in the UK and Aleksey Navalny in Russia, and by the DPRK against Kim Jong Nam in Malaysia.  Syria remains in noncompliance with the CWC, and we will continue to work to hold the Assad regime accountable for its repeated use of chemical weapons against its own people.  We will also continue our efforts to hold the Kremlin accountable for its noncompliance with the CWC, repeated use of chemical weapons, and ongoing efforts to shield the Assad regime from accountability for its CW use.  Further, we have made very clear that the Russian government would face profound consequences were it to use chemical weapons in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Despite these challenges, the Convention, which President Biden has championed since his time in the U.S. Senate, has shown time and again its utility, demonstrated by the commitment of the majority of States Parties to compliance and their willingness to take actions to uphold it and hold accountable those who violate it.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Today marks the twenty-fifth anniversary of the entry into force of the Chemical Weapons Convention (CWC).  For a quarter of a century, the United States has worked with its Allies and partners to help rid the world of chemical weapons and deter their use by anyone, anywhere, and under any circumstances.  Our collective goal is to exclude completely the possibility of the use of chemical weapons, which are abhorrent tools of war.  On this anniversary, we renew our commitment to upholding the CWC and note the Convention’s important role in contributing to U.S. national security.  Unfortunately, this anniversary reminds us that the world continues to be threatened by the specter of these weapons.</p>
<p>In recent years, the world has witnessed chemical weapons use that challenges the CWC’s core prohibitions: by the Assad regime and ISIS in Syria, by Russian government operatives against the Skripals in the UK and Aleksey Navalny in Russia, and by the DPRK against Kim Jong Nam in Malaysia.  Syria remains in noncompliance with the CWC, and we will continue to work to hold the Assad regime accountable for its repeated use of chemical weapons against its own people.  We will also continue our efforts to hold the Kremlin accountable for its noncompliance with the CWC, repeated use of chemical weapons, and ongoing efforts to shield the Assad regime from accountability for its CW use.  Further, we have made very clear that the Russian government would face profound consequences were it to use chemical weapons in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Despite these challenges, the Convention, which President Biden has championed since his time in the U.S. Senate, has shown time and again its utility, demonstrated by the commitment of the majority of States Parties to compliance and their willingness to take actions to uphold it and hold accountable those who violate it.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Republic of the Marshall Islands, National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/republic-of-the-marshall-islands-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 12:40:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=339262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate the citizens of the Republic of the Marshall Islands on your 43rd Constitution Day. We are grateful the Marshall Islands and the United States continues to enjoy such a unique and historic friendship, epitomized by our Compact of Free Association.</p>
<p>We also appreciate our longstanding collaboration with the Marshall Islands. Together, we promote the security, economic development, public health, and climate resilience of the Marshall Islands. By extension, our cooperation advances a free and open, connected, prosperous, secure, and resilient Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>I send my warmest wishes to all people of the Marshall Islands, at home and abroad.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate the citizens of the Republic of the Marshall Islands on your 43rd Constitution Day. We are grateful the Marshall Islands and the United States continues to enjoy such a unique and historic friendship, epitomized by our Compact of Free Association.</p>
<p>We also appreciate our longstanding collaboration with the Marshall Islands. Together, we promote the security, economic development, public health, and climate resilience of the Marshall Islands. By extension, our cooperation advances a free and open, connected, prosperous, secure, and resilient Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>I send my warmest wishes to all people of the Marshall Islands, at home and abroad.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Irish Foreign Minister Coveney</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-irish-foreign-minister-coveney/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=339172</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Irish Foreign Minister Simon Coveney today in Washington, D.C.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Coveney reaffirmed their unwavering support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Moscow’s war of choice.  They discussed the need to continue providing humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and to increase pressure on the Kremlin.  Deputy Secretary Sherman reiterated U.S. support for the Belfast/Good Friday Agreement.  The two also discussed Ireland’s important role as an elected member of the UN Security Council and other shared foreign policy priorities.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Irish Foreign Minister Simon Coveney today in Washington, D.C.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Coveney reaffirmed their unwavering support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Moscow’s war of choice.  They discussed the need to continue providing humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and to increase pressure on the Kremlin.  Deputy Secretary Sherman reiterated U.S. support for the Belfast/Good Friday Agreement.  The two also discussed Ireland’s important role as an elected member of the UN Security Council and other shared foreign policy priorities.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opening Remarks by Secretary Antony J. Blinken Before the House Committee on Foreign Affairs</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/opening-remarks-by-secretary-antony-j-blinken-before-the-house-committee-on-foreign-affairs-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 19:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=339091</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Rayburn House Office Building</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Chairman Meeks, Ranking Member McCaul, thank you.  Thank you for having me here today to speak about the administration’s proposed budget for the State Department, but thank you more broadly &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR CHABOT:</strong>  Secretary, could you pull the mike a little closer, maybe?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yes, sorry.  That better?  Let me try that.</p>
<p>But thank you as well for your partnership and also for your leadership.  That CODEL that both of you led in Poland at a critical moment made a big difference, and it’s been gratifying to be able to work with both of you and other members on this urgent issue but also on many others.  And I deeply appreciate it.</p>
<p>And I did recently get back from Kyiv with Secretary Austin, where we wanted to show as well as deliver on America’s commitment to the Government and to the people of Ukraine.  This brutal war of aggression against Ukraine has underscored to me the power and the purpose of American diplomacy.  Our diplomacy is rallying allies and partners around the world to join us in supporting Ukraine with security, economic, humanitarian assistance, to impose massive costs on Russia for its aggression, to strengthen our collective security and defense, and to address the war’s mounting global consequences, including the refugee and food crises that have flown from it.</p>
<p>We have to continue to drive this diplomacy forward, also to seize the strategic opportunities and address some of the risks that are presented by Russia’s overreach as countries reconsider their policies, their priorities, their relationships.</p>
<p>The budget request before you predates the crisis, but fully funding it and the new emergency resources that the President requested earlier today is critical to ensuring that Russia’s war in Ukraine is a strategic failure for the Kremlin and serves as a powerful lesson to those who might consider following its path.</p>
<p>The supplemental resources Congress provided in March have made a decisive difference on the battlefield, helping Ukrainians defend their country and win the battle for Kyiv.  Your support also helped meet the mounting costs caused by the Kremlin’s brutal invasion in Ukraine itself, across Europe, around the world, while bolstering the security of our allies and partners.</p>
<p>This assistance was provided with broad bipartisan support and sent a clear signal of the United States commitment to the Ukrainian Government and to its people.  We ask that Congress do the same with the emergency request that’s before you as of today, which seeks $20.5 billion for security assistance, $8.5 billion for economic assistance, and $3 billion for humanitarian aid, including to address the growing global food security crisis, which is a direct result of Russia’s aggression.  Approximately $14 billion of this request would be directed to the State Department and to USAID.</p>
<p>Let me just underscore: We can’t take our progress so far for granted.  Ukraine’s enduring independence and sovereignty depends in no small part on ensuring that the country’s brave defenders have what they need to keep up the fight and meet the urgent needs of their people.</p>
<p>But Mr. Chairman, to your point, as we focus on this urgent crisis, the State Department continues to carry out missions that are front and center to our diplomacy, like responsibly managing great power competition with China, facilitating a halt to fighting in Yemen and Ethiopia, pushing back against the rising tide of authoritarianism and the threat that it poses to democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>We also have evolving challenges that require us to develop new capabilities, like the emergence and re-emergence of infectious disease, an accelerating climate crisis, a digital revolution that holds enormous promise but also real peril.</p>
<p>Last fall, I had a chance to set out a modernization agenda for the department and for U.S. diplomacy to enable us to even more effectively respond to many of these complex demands.  And in no small part thanks to the FY22 budget approved by Congress, we’ve been able to make real progress on this agenda, though much remains to be done.</p>
<p>To give just a few quick examples, we’ve strengthened our capacity to shape the ongoing technological revolution so that it actually protects our interests, it boosts American competitiveness, it upholds our values.  With bipartisan Congressional support and encouragement, we just launched a new bureau for cyberspace and digital policy, with 60 team members to start.  And I am grateful for the support and the advice that we got along the way.</p>
<p>We’re also making headway on ensuring our diplomats reflect America’s remarkable diversity.  This is a tremendous source of strength for our diplomacy.  The department’s first ever chief diversity and inclusion officer has spearheaded an effort to analyze and address the obstacles that have been preventing under-represented groups from joining but also advancing at the State Department.  We’ve expanded the Pickering and Rangel fellowship programs and, Mr. Chairman, as you said, paid internships at State, again with strong Congressional input and support.</p>
<p>My first 15 months on this job have only strengthened my conviction that these and other reforms aren’t just worthwhile, they’re essential to delivering for the American people.</p>
<p>Ensuring we can deliver on this agenda will require sustained funding, some new authorities, and most importantly, partnership from Congress.  That’s why I’m grateful to have worked with Congress to re-establish a formal dialogue on the State Department authorization.  Last month, we sent congressional staff the first package of legislative authorities required to meet the challenges we face, and we expect to send more in the coming weeks and to working with you on State authorization.</p>
<p>If we want to deepen our capability in key areas like climate and multilateral diplomacy; if we want to expand on Secretary Powell’s vision of a Foreign Service training float; if we want to strengthen global health security and the capacity to prevent, to detect, and respond to future outbreaks – we’ll need some additional resources.</p>
<p>If we want to be able to swiftly stand up new missions, to deploy our diplomats when and where they’re needed, and make these decisions based on risk management, not risk aversion, we’ll need to reform the Secure Embassy Construction and Counterterrorism Act.</p>
<p>There are other things that I would point to that we need to do, but we look forward to working with you on that.</p>
<p>So in the interest of time, let me stop there.  And of course, we can address these and many other issues throughout the course of the testimony.  Thank you.  Very good to be with everyone.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Rayburn House Office Building</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Chairman Meeks, Ranking Member McCaul, thank you.  Thank you for having me here today to speak about the administration’s proposed budget for the State Department, but thank you more broadly &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR CHABOT:</strong>  Secretary, could you pull the mike a little closer, maybe?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yes, sorry.  That better?  Let me try that.</p>
<p>But thank you as well for your partnership and also for your leadership.  That CODEL that both of you led in Poland at a critical moment made a big difference, and it’s been gratifying to be able to work with both of you and other members on this urgent issue but also on many others.  And I deeply appreciate it.</p>
<p>And I did recently get back from Kyiv with Secretary Austin, where we wanted to show as well as deliver on America’s commitment to the Government and to the people of Ukraine.  This brutal war of aggression against Ukraine has underscored to me the power and the purpose of American diplomacy.  Our diplomacy is rallying allies and partners around the world to join us in supporting Ukraine with security, economic, humanitarian assistance, to impose massive costs on Russia for its aggression, to strengthen our collective security and defense, and to address the war’s mounting global consequences, including the refugee and food crises that have flown from it.</p>
<p>We have to continue to drive this diplomacy forward, also to seize the strategic opportunities and address some of the risks that are presented by Russia’s overreach as countries reconsider their policies, their priorities, their relationships.</p>
<p>The budget request before you predates the crisis, but fully funding it and the new emergency resources that the President requested earlier today is critical to ensuring that Russia’s war in Ukraine is a strategic failure for the Kremlin and serves as a powerful lesson to those who might consider following its path.</p>
<p>The supplemental resources Congress provided in March have made a decisive difference on the battlefield, helping Ukrainians defend their country and win the battle for Kyiv.  Your support also helped meet the mounting costs caused by the Kremlin’s brutal invasion in Ukraine itself, across Europe, around the world, while bolstering the security of our allies and partners.</p>
<p>This assistance was provided with broad bipartisan support and sent a clear signal of the United States commitment to the Ukrainian Government and to its people.  We ask that Congress do the same with the emergency request that’s before you as of today, which seeks $20.5 billion for security assistance, $8.5 billion for economic assistance, and $3 billion for humanitarian aid, including to address the growing global food security crisis, which is a direct result of Russia’s aggression.  Approximately $14 billion of this request would be directed to the State Department and to USAID.</p>
<p>Let me just underscore: We can’t take our progress so far for granted.  Ukraine’s enduring independence and sovereignty depends in no small part on ensuring that the country’s brave defenders have what they need to keep up the fight and meet the urgent needs of their people.</p>
<p>But Mr. Chairman, to your point, as we focus on this urgent crisis, the State Department continues to carry out missions that are front and center to our diplomacy, like responsibly managing great power competition with China, facilitating a halt to fighting in Yemen and Ethiopia, pushing back against the rising tide of authoritarianism and the threat that it poses to democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>We also have evolving challenges that require us to develop new capabilities, like the emergence and re-emergence of infectious disease, an accelerating climate crisis, a digital revolution that holds enormous promise but also real peril.</p>
<p>Last fall, I had a chance to set out a modernization agenda for the department and for U.S. diplomacy to enable us to even more effectively respond to many of these complex demands.  And in no small part thanks to the FY22 budget approved by Congress, we’ve been able to make real progress on this agenda, though much remains to be done.</p>
<p>To give just a few quick examples, we’ve strengthened our capacity to shape the ongoing technological revolution so that it actually protects our interests, it boosts American competitiveness, it upholds our values.  With bipartisan Congressional support and encouragement, we just launched a new bureau for cyberspace and digital policy, with 60 team members to start.  And I am grateful for the support and the advice that we got along the way.</p>
<p>We’re also making headway on ensuring our diplomats reflect America’s remarkable diversity.  This is a tremendous source of strength for our diplomacy.  The department’s first ever chief diversity and inclusion officer has spearheaded an effort to analyze and address the obstacles that have been preventing under-represented groups from joining but also advancing at the State Department.  We’ve expanded the Pickering and Rangel fellowship programs and, Mr. Chairman, as you said, paid internships at State, again with strong Congressional input and support.</p>
<p>My first 15 months on this job have only strengthened my conviction that these and other reforms aren’t just worthwhile, they’re essential to delivering for the American people.</p>
<p>Ensuring we can deliver on this agenda will require sustained funding, some new authorities, and most importantly, partnership from Congress.  That’s why I’m grateful to have worked with Congress to re-establish a formal dialogue on the State Department authorization.  Last month, we sent congressional staff the first package of legislative authorities required to meet the challenges we face, and we expect to send more in the coming weeks and to working with you on State authorization.</p>
<p>If we want to deepen our capability in key areas like climate and multilateral diplomacy; if we want to expand on Secretary Powell’s vision of a Foreign Service training float; if we want to strengthen global health security and the capacity to prevent, to detect, and respond to future outbreaks – we’ll need some additional resources.</p>
<p>If we want to be able to swiftly stand up new missions, to deploy our diplomats when and where they’re needed, and make these decisions based on risk management, not risk aversion, we’ll need to reform the Secure Embassy Construction and Counterterrorism Act.</p>
<p>There are other things that I would point to that we need to do, but we look forward to working with you on that.</p>
<p>So in the interest of time, let me stop there.  And of course, we can address these and many other issues throughout the course of the testimony.  Thank you.  Very good to be with everyone.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Briefing with Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Jessica Stern On the First Annual Interagency Report on Implementation of the Presidential Memorandum on Advancing the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Around the World</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-with-special-envoy-to-advance-the-human-rights-of-lgbtqi-persons-jessica-stern-on-the-first-annual-interagency-report-on-implementation-of-the-presidential-memorandum-on-advancing-the-human/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jessica Stern, U.S. Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer and Intersex (LGBTQI+) PersonsBureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 18:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=338968</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jessica Stern, U.S. Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer and Intersex (LGBTQI+) PersonsBureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE: </b> Well, good afternoon, everyone.  Thank you very much for joining us.  And I’m especially pleased to introduce Jessica Stern – as you know, she’s our Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ persons – on this momentous occasion.</p>
<p>As you know, the administration has placed human rights at the center of our foreign policy.  And a year ago, in February of last year, President Biden issued his Memorandum on Advancing Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Around the World.  And last June, he appointed Jessica to this very important position.  And now today, Special Envoy Stern is with us to unveil the <a href="https://www.state.gov/lgbtqi-human-rights/">first annual interagency report</a> on the implementation of the Presidential Memorandum.  This is a product reflecting a whole-of-government approach, led by the State Department.</p>
<p>And Special Envoy Stern will offer brief remarks and then will have an opportunity to take some of your questions.  So without further ado, I will turn it over to the Special Envoy.</p>
<p><b>MS STERN:</b>  Thank you, Ned, for the very kind introduction.  And good afternoon to everyone, if it’s afternoon where you are, or hello if you’re in a different time zone.</p>
<p>As Ned noted, in his first weeks in office, President Biden signed a Presidential Memorandum entitled, quote, “Advancing the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Around the World.”  This memorandum makes clear that promoting and protecting the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons is a U.S. foreign policy priority.</p>
<p>And today, I’m really happy to talk to you about the first interagency report, outlining how the U.S. Government has worked collectively towards fulfilling the memorandum’s goals.</p>
<p>This is a historic first for the United States.  The report outlines how U.S. Government agencies engaged abroad are working to become more LGBTQI+-inclusive.  And it shows that many individual actions across the U.S. Government, taken together as a whole, create institutional change and improve the daily lives of LGBTQI+ persons.  The report highlights the progress that is possible when we actively reach out to other governments, multilateral institutions, and civil society.</p>
<p>This work is essential, because LGBTQI+ persons face violence, stigma, lack of access to basic services, and, in approximately 70 countries, criminalization of their status or behavior.  And in many places, LGBTQI+ persons are targeted as a way of undermining democracy itself.</p>
<p>Through determined diplomacy and targeted foreign assistance, the United States is combating the criminalization of LGBTQI+ status or conduct, promoting protection of vulnerable LGBTQI+ refugees and asylum seekers, responding to human rights abuses committed against LGBTQI+ persons, strengthening relationships with like-minded governments, engaging international organizations on the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons, and working to rescind policies inconsistent with our nation’s values.</p>
<p>So that being said, I want to highlight several successes, starting with the Department of State, which set a historic precedent as the first federal government agency to offer the X gender marker on an identity document by providing, as of April 11th, the X gender marker as an option on U.S. passport applications. The X signifies unspecified or another gender identity.</p>
<p>The Department of State also launched a flagship program as part of the Biden administration’s Presidential Initiative for Democracy Renewal – the Global LGBTQI+ Inclusive Democracy and Empowerment Initiative, also known as GLIDE, that seeks to ensure democracies are inclusive of LGBTQI+ persons, representative of their communities and families, and responsive to their needs and concerns.  The new initiative builds on the track record of success under the Global Equality Fund, which has provided over $100 million in financial support to protect and promote the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons in more than 100 countries since its inception.</p>
<p>The Department of State also led the successful expansion of a United Nations resolution on elections to include sexual orientation and gender identity, becoming only the second resolution in the history of the General Assembly to do so and the very first via consensus.</p>
<p>From the Department of State, I want to move on to the Peace Corps, where approximately 60 percent of Peace Corps posts reported implementing specific LGBTQI+ equity practices within their operations, like hosting LGBTQI+ human rights organizations to inform in-country strategy and volunteer placement.</p>
<p>From there, we move on to the Department of Health and Human Services, which now ensures that its Notice of Funding Award Guidance includes clear guidance to support nondiscrimination.</p>
<p>And then on to USAID, which reinstated a reporting mechanism to track overall foreign assistance which advances LGBTQI+ human rights.</p>
<p>And next onto the Department of Treasury, which is pursuing how to win shareholder support to promote strengthened safeguard protections for LGBTQI+ persons and how to foster stronger multilateral development bank implementation of existing safeguard policies for LGBTQI+ persons.</p>
<p>And then my last example for you comes from the Department of Homeland Security, which issued revised guidance to recognize informal same-sex marriages for the purposes of obtaining refugee or asylee status, even if they are not officially recognized by officials in countries of origin.</p>
<p>And as I draw towards my conclusion, I just want to say our work has only just begun, and throughout my time serving as the U.S. Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons – which I think is the longest title in the State Department, but Ned can correct me if I’m wrong – I have found that colleagues at the Department of State and really at each agency to be eager and ready to advance the cause of protecting and promoting the dignity, inclusion, and human rights of every LGBTQI+ person.  And simply put, in the darkest places, we are finding the brightest lights.  Thank you.</p>
<p>And with that, I’m happy to take your questions.  Back to you, Ned.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b>Thanks very much.  It’s a long title but – and a very important one, an important position.  Operator, do you mind repeating the instructions to ask a question?</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:  </b>Thank you.  And ladies and gentlemen, if you wish to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 on your touchtone phone.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b>We’ll give it just a moment for people to filter into the queue.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:  </b>Again, if you do have a question, please press a 1 then 0.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b>We’ll go to the line of Bianca Hillier, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Hello, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b>Yes.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Hi.  Thank you so much, Special Envoy Stern, for speaking with us today.  I have a question:  What did those informal marriages to refugees and asylum seekers grant those people the ability to do?  How directly does that help people?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS STERN:  </b>Hi, Bianca.  I’ve followed your work but never met you.  Great to hear your voice.</p>
<p>It was a fact that stood out to me when I read the report as well, because I think it’s really significant.  As you’re probably aware, in approximately 70 countries worldwide, homosexual status or conduct is criminalized.  And the number of countries globally that have any form of recognition of equal marriage, civil unions, or family recognition in other forms for LGBTQI couples is few and far between.</p>
<p>So although I’m not versed in the technical specifications of the DHS policy, I can tell you this is a very important form of recognition.  And what it means is that for the sake of LGBTQI couples and their families, who have no access to legal recognition by their own government, the United States is recognizing grounds of persecution on the basis of sexual orientation and recognizing that their families are valid and valuable.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Thank you so much.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b>Great.  We’ll give it just another moment.  If anyone else wishes to ask a question, please raise your hand now.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:  </b>And again, if you do have a question, please press 1 0.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b> Okay.  Well, seeing no additional questions, I want to thank the Special Envoy.  I want to thank all of you for joining today’s call.  For those of you who have questions you wish to ask offline, I think you know how to contact us.  Please do reach out and we’d be happy to work with you from there.  Thank you very much.  Have a good day.</p>
<p><b>MS STERN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jessica Stern, U.S. Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer and Intersex (LGBTQI+) PersonsBureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE: </b> Well, good afternoon, everyone.  Thank you very much for joining us.  And I’m especially pleased to introduce Jessica Stern – as you know, she’s our Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ persons – on this momentous occasion.</p>
<p>As you know, the administration has placed human rights at the center of our foreign policy.  And a year ago, in February of last year, President Biden issued his Memorandum on Advancing Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Around the World.  And last June, he appointed Jessica to this very important position.  And now today, Special Envoy Stern is with us to unveil the <a href="https://www.state.gov/lgbtqi-human-rights/">first annual interagency report</a> on the implementation of the Presidential Memorandum.  This is a product reflecting a whole-of-government approach, led by the State Department.</p>
<p>And Special Envoy Stern will offer brief remarks and then will have an opportunity to take some of your questions.  So without further ado, I will turn it over to the Special Envoy.</p>
<p><b>MS STERN:</b>  Thank you, Ned, for the very kind introduction.  And good afternoon to everyone, if it’s afternoon where you are, or hello if you’re in a different time zone.</p>
<p>As Ned noted, in his first weeks in office, President Biden signed a Presidential Memorandum entitled, quote, “Advancing the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Around the World.”  This memorandum makes clear that promoting and protecting the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons is a U.S. foreign policy priority.</p>
<p>And today, I’m really happy to talk to you about the first interagency report, outlining how the U.S. Government has worked collectively towards fulfilling the memorandum’s goals.</p>
<p>This is a historic first for the United States.  The report outlines how U.S. Government agencies engaged abroad are working to become more LGBTQI+-inclusive.  And it shows that many individual actions across the U.S. Government, taken together as a whole, create institutional change and improve the daily lives of LGBTQI+ persons.  The report highlights the progress that is possible when we actively reach out to other governments, multilateral institutions, and civil society.</p>
<p>This work is essential, because LGBTQI+ persons face violence, stigma, lack of access to basic services, and, in approximately 70 countries, criminalization of their status or behavior.  And in many places, LGBTQI+ persons are targeted as a way of undermining democracy itself.</p>
<p>Through determined diplomacy and targeted foreign assistance, the United States is combating the criminalization of LGBTQI+ status or conduct, promoting protection of vulnerable LGBTQI+ refugees and asylum seekers, responding to human rights abuses committed against LGBTQI+ persons, strengthening relationships with like-minded governments, engaging international organizations on the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons, and working to rescind policies inconsistent with our nation’s values.</p>
<p>So that being said, I want to highlight several successes, starting with the Department of State, which set a historic precedent as the first federal government agency to offer the X gender marker on an identity document by providing, as of April 11th, the X gender marker as an option on U.S. passport applications. The X signifies unspecified or another gender identity.</p>
<p>The Department of State also launched a flagship program as part of the Biden administration’s Presidential Initiative for Democracy Renewal – the Global LGBTQI+ Inclusive Democracy and Empowerment Initiative, also known as GLIDE, that seeks to ensure democracies are inclusive of LGBTQI+ persons, representative of their communities and families, and responsive to their needs and concerns.  The new initiative builds on the track record of success under the Global Equality Fund, which has provided over $100 million in financial support to protect and promote the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons in more than 100 countries since its inception.</p>
<p>The Department of State also led the successful expansion of a United Nations resolution on elections to include sexual orientation and gender identity, becoming only the second resolution in the history of the General Assembly to do so and the very first via consensus.</p>
<p>From the Department of State, I want to move on to the Peace Corps, where approximately 60 percent of Peace Corps posts reported implementing specific LGBTQI+ equity practices within their operations, like hosting LGBTQI+ human rights organizations to inform in-country strategy and volunteer placement.</p>
<p>From there, we move on to the Department of Health and Human Services, which now ensures that its Notice of Funding Award Guidance includes clear guidance to support nondiscrimination.</p>
<p>And then on to USAID, which reinstated a reporting mechanism to track overall foreign assistance which advances LGBTQI+ human rights.</p>
<p>And next onto the Department of Treasury, which is pursuing how to win shareholder support to promote strengthened safeguard protections for LGBTQI+ persons and how to foster stronger multilateral development bank implementation of existing safeguard policies for LGBTQI+ persons.</p>
<p>And then my last example for you comes from the Department of Homeland Security, which issued revised guidance to recognize informal same-sex marriages for the purposes of obtaining refugee or asylee status, even if they are not officially recognized by officials in countries of origin.</p>
<p>And as I draw towards my conclusion, I just want to say our work has only just begun, and throughout my time serving as the U.S. Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons – which I think is the longest title in the State Department, but Ned can correct me if I’m wrong – I have found that colleagues at the Department of State and really at each agency to be eager and ready to advance the cause of protecting and promoting the dignity, inclusion, and human rights of every LGBTQI+ person.  And simply put, in the darkest places, we are finding the brightest lights.  Thank you.</p>
<p>And with that, I’m happy to take your questions.  Back to you, Ned.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b>Thanks very much.  It’s a long title but – and a very important one, an important position.  Operator, do you mind repeating the instructions to ask a question?</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:  </b>Thank you.  And ladies and gentlemen, if you wish to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 on your touchtone phone.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b>We’ll give it just a moment for people to filter into the queue.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:  </b>Again, if you do have a question, please press a 1 then 0.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b>We’ll go to the line of Bianca Hillier, please.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Hello, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b>Yes.  Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Hi.  Thank you so much, Special Envoy Stern, for speaking with us today.  I have a question:  What did those informal marriages to refugees and asylum seekers grant those people the ability to do?  How directly does that help people?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MS STERN:  </b>Hi, Bianca.  I’ve followed your work but never met you.  Great to hear your voice.</p>
<p>It was a fact that stood out to me when I read the report as well, because I think it’s really significant.  As you’re probably aware, in approximately 70 countries worldwide, homosexual status or conduct is criminalized.  And the number of countries globally that have any form of recognition of equal marriage, civil unions, or family recognition in other forms for LGBTQI couples is few and far between.</p>
<p>So although I’m not versed in the technical specifications of the DHS policy, I can tell you this is a very important form of recognition.  And what it means is that for the sake of LGBTQI couples and their families, who have no access to legal recognition by their own government, the United States is recognizing grounds of persecution on the basis of sexual orientation and recognizing that their families are valid and valuable.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Thank you so much.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b>Great.  We’ll give it just another moment.  If anyone else wishes to ask a question, please raise your hand now.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:  </b>And again, if you do have a question, please press 1 0.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:  </b> Okay.  Well, seeing no additional questions, I want to thank the Special Envoy.  I want to thank all of you for joining today’s call.  For those of you who have questions you wish to ask offline, I think you know how to contact us.  Please do reach out and we’d be happy to work with you from there.  Thank you very much.  Have a good day.</p>
<p><b>MS STERN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opening Remarks by Secretary Antony J. Blinken Before the House Subcommittee on State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/opening-remarks-by-secretary-antony-j-blinken-before-the-house-subcommittee-on-state-foreign-operations-and-related-programs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 16:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=338893</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>HT-2 The Capitol</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much, Chairwoman Lee.  It’s great to see you.  Ranking Member Rogers, Ranking Member Granger, thank you for being here today as well.  It’s very good to be with you, and I’m really grateful for this opportunity to speak to you about the administration’s proposed budget for the State Department.</p>
<p>As you know, I recently returned from Kyiv with Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin, where we sought to demonstrate, by our presence as well as by our actions, the United States commitment to Ukraine and its people.</p>
<p>This brutal war of aggression being committed by Russia against Ukraine has brought into sharp focus the power and purpose of American diplomacy.  Our diplomacy is rallying allies and partners around the world to join us in supporting Ukraine militarily, economically, and with humanitarian assistance to impose massive costs on the Kremlin for its aggression, while strengthening our collective security and defense, and addressing the war’s mounting global consequences, including the refugee and food crises that you’ve alluded to.</p>
<p>We have to continue to drive that diplomacy forward to also seize the strategic opportunities and address the risks presented by Russia’s overreach, as countries are reconsidering their policies, their priorities, and their relationships.</p>
<p>The budget request that you have before you actually predates the crisis, but fully funding it is critical to ensuring that Russia’s war in Ukraine is a strategic failure for the Kremlin and also serves as a powerful lesson for those who might consider following the same path.</p>
<p>As we’re focused on this urgent crisis, the State Department continues to carry out the missions traditionally associated with diplomacy, particularly responsibly managing great power competition with China, also facilitating a halt to fighting in places like Yemen and Ethiopia, pushing back against the rising tide of authoritarianism and the threat that it poses to democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>We also face evolving challenges that require us to develop new capabilities: the emergence and re-emergence of infectious disease, an accelerated climate crisis, and a digital revolution that holds both enormous promise but also peril if not managed correctly.</p>
<p>A few months ago, in the fall, I had a chance to set out a modernization agenda for the State Department and for U.S. diplomacy to respond to all of these demands and all of these needs.</p>
<p>And in no small part thanks to the significant FY22 budget that was approved by Congress, we’ve been able to make real progress on this agenda, but much remains to be done.</p>
<p>Just to give you a few quick examples, we’ve strengthened our capacity to shape the ongoing technological revolution so that it protects our interests, it boosts our competitiveness, it upholds our values.  With bipartisan congressional support and encouragement, we recently launched a new Bureau for Cyberspace and Digital Policy, with 60 team members to start.  And this is something that was done very much in collaboration with and with the counsel of Congress.</p>
<p>We’re also making headway on ensuring our diplomats reflect America’s remarkable diversity, which is one of our greatest strengths.  As the Chairwoman said, our department’s first ever Chief Diversity and Inclusion Officer, Ambassador Gina Abercrombie-Winstanley, has spearheaded an effort to analyze and address the obstacles that prevent under-represented groups from joining and advancing at the department.  We’ve expanded the Pickering and Rangel fellowship programs, and we have paid internships at State – again, strong congressional input and support for these initiatives.</p>
<p>We recently welcomed a new cohort of 179 exceptional Foreign Service professionals.  That puts us on track for our largest annual intake in a decade.</p>
<p>These first 15 months on the job for me have only strengthened my conviction that these and other reforms are not just worthwhile, they’re essential to delivering for the American people.</p>
<p>Today’s meeting, by our count, marks the 103rd time that I’ve had the opportunity to brief Congress in one way or another – meetings, calls – which is one of the ways that I’ve worked to meet the commitment I made in my confirmation, to ensure that Congress’s role as a partner, both in our foreign policymaking and in modernizing the State Department, is realized.</p>
<p>Ensuring that we can deliver on this agenda requires sustained funding, requires some new authorities – most importantly, it requires our partnership.</p>
<p>If we want to deepen our capability in areas like climate, like public health, like multilateral diplomacy; if we want to expand on Secretary Powell’s vision of a Foreign Service training float; if we want to strengthen global health security to prevent, detect, and respond to future outbreaks – we need these additional resources.</p>
<p>If we want to be able to swiftly stand up new missions, to deploy diplomats when and where they are needed, and make these decisions based on risk management rather than risk aversion – we need to reform the security – the Secure Embassy Construction and Counterterrorism Act and the Accountability Review Board statute.</p>
<p>If we want to rapidly scale up the response to crises like refugee surges and epidemics, while also avoiding costly overhead, we need more flexible domestic hiring authorities.</p>
<p>These are just a few examples, and I just want to stress in closing:  This is not about advancing the goals of any one administration or any one party.  It’s about refocusing our mission and our purpose on the forces that are affecting the lives of all of our fellow citizens – their livelihoods, their security – for decades to come.</p>
<p>So I really appreciate the opportunity to speak today about why this matters, and look forward to working with this committee, the subcommittee, Congress as a whole, as a partner in these efforts.</p>
<p>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>HT-2 The Capitol</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much, Chairwoman Lee.  It’s great to see you.  Ranking Member Rogers, Ranking Member Granger, thank you for being here today as well.  It’s very good to be with you, and I’m really grateful for this opportunity to speak to you about the administration’s proposed budget for the State Department.</p>
<p>As you know, I recently returned from Kyiv with Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin, where we sought to demonstrate, by our presence as well as by our actions, the United States commitment to Ukraine and its people.</p>
<p>This brutal war of aggression being committed by Russia against Ukraine has brought into sharp focus the power and purpose of American diplomacy.  Our diplomacy is rallying allies and partners around the world to join us in supporting Ukraine militarily, economically, and with humanitarian assistance to impose massive costs on the Kremlin for its aggression, while strengthening our collective security and defense, and addressing the war’s mounting global consequences, including the refugee and food crises that you’ve alluded to.</p>
<p>We have to continue to drive that diplomacy forward to also seize the strategic opportunities and address the risks presented by Russia’s overreach, as countries are reconsidering their policies, their priorities, and their relationships.</p>
<p>The budget request that you have before you actually predates the crisis, but fully funding it is critical to ensuring that Russia’s war in Ukraine is a strategic failure for the Kremlin and also serves as a powerful lesson for those who might consider following the same path.</p>
<p>As we’re focused on this urgent crisis, the State Department continues to carry out the missions traditionally associated with diplomacy, particularly responsibly managing great power competition with China, also facilitating a halt to fighting in places like Yemen and Ethiopia, pushing back against the rising tide of authoritarianism and the threat that it poses to democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>We also face evolving challenges that require us to develop new capabilities: the emergence and re-emergence of infectious disease, an accelerated climate crisis, and a digital revolution that holds both enormous promise but also peril if not managed correctly.</p>
<p>A few months ago, in the fall, I had a chance to set out a modernization agenda for the State Department and for U.S. diplomacy to respond to all of these demands and all of these needs.</p>
<p>And in no small part thanks to the significant FY22 budget that was approved by Congress, we’ve been able to make real progress on this agenda, but much remains to be done.</p>
<p>Just to give you a few quick examples, we’ve strengthened our capacity to shape the ongoing technological revolution so that it protects our interests, it boosts our competitiveness, it upholds our values.  With bipartisan congressional support and encouragement, we recently launched a new Bureau for Cyberspace and Digital Policy, with 60 team members to start.  And this is something that was done very much in collaboration with and with the counsel of Congress.</p>
<p>We’re also making headway on ensuring our diplomats reflect America’s remarkable diversity, which is one of our greatest strengths.  As the Chairwoman said, our department’s first ever Chief Diversity and Inclusion Officer, Ambassador Gina Abercrombie-Winstanley, has spearheaded an effort to analyze and address the obstacles that prevent under-represented groups from joining and advancing at the department.  We’ve expanded the Pickering and Rangel fellowship programs, and we have paid internships at State – again, strong congressional input and support for these initiatives.</p>
<p>We recently welcomed a new cohort of 179 exceptional Foreign Service professionals.  That puts us on track for our largest annual intake in a decade.</p>
<p>These first 15 months on the job for me have only strengthened my conviction that these and other reforms are not just worthwhile, they’re essential to delivering for the American people.</p>
<p>Today’s meeting, by our count, marks the 103rd time that I’ve had the opportunity to brief Congress in one way or another – meetings, calls – which is one of the ways that I’ve worked to meet the commitment I made in my confirmation, to ensure that Congress’s role as a partner, both in our foreign policymaking and in modernizing the State Department, is realized.</p>
<p>Ensuring that we can deliver on this agenda requires sustained funding, requires some new authorities – most importantly, it requires our partnership.</p>
<p>If we want to deepen our capability in areas like climate, like public health, like multilateral diplomacy; if we want to expand on Secretary Powell’s vision of a Foreign Service training float; if we want to strengthen global health security to prevent, detect, and respond to future outbreaks – we need these additional resources.</p>
<p>If we want to be able to swiftly stand up new missions, to deploy diplomats when and where they are needed, and make these decisions based on risk management rather than risk aversion – we need to reform the security – the Secure Embassy Construction and Counterterrorism Act and the Accountability Review Board statute.</p>
<p>If we want to rapidly scale up the response to crises like refugee surges and epidemics, while also avoiding costly overhead, we need more flexible domestic hiring authorities.</p>
<p>These are just a few examples, and I just want to stress in closing:  This is not about advancing the goals of any one administration or any one party.  It’s about refocusing our mission and our purpose on the forces that are affecting the lives of all of our fellow citizens – their livelihoods, their security – for decades to come.</p>
<p>So I really appreciate the opportunity to speak today about why this matters, and look forward to working with this committee, the subcommittee, Congress as a whole, as a partner in these efforts.</p>
<p>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Commemorating the Day of Holocaust Remembrance</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/commemorating-the-day-of-holocaust-remembrance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 15:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=338846</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Under the theme “Courage Facing Evil,” today we mark the Day of Holocaust Remembrance and honor the victims and survivors of the Holocaust.</p>
<p>As we remember the horrors of that dark chapter, we are surrounded by descendants of Holocaust survivors who were inspired by their family’s suffering and courage to dedicate themselves to public service. It is a sentiment I share from my own family’s story. They are public servants like U.S. Ambassador Michèle Taylor, whose parents and grandparents managed to escape the Holocaust before the Nazis murdered her extended family. This terrible loss of loved ones and her family’s will to survive were catalysts for the Ambassador’s long career defending and advancing the cause of human rights. Today, she is the U.S. representative to the United Nations Human Rights Council, where she stands up for the freedom, equal rights and dignity of all, and where she is working to rally the world in support of Ukraine against Russia’s brutal war of aggression.</p>
<p>Our charge remains to stand united against tyranny, lies, and hatred in all their forms. We must confront rising antisemitism. We must ensure that current and future generations learn the history and lessons of and from the Holocaust, so they feel a responsibility to stand up to injustice and take action against atrocities wherever they occur. This work is urgent. Fewer and fewer survivors are still with us, while those who deny and distort the history of the Holocaust are finding insidious new ways to spread their lies.</p>
<p>Today we remember all Holocaust survivors, the six million Jewish men, women and children who were murdered, and the millions of others who were killed or suffered persecution and horrific inhumanity, including Roma, persons with disabilities, and LGTBQI+ persons who were targeted in the Nazis’ campaign of dehumanization. Their precious lives and memory teach us why it is important not only to remember, but also to act. Every act of courage in the face of evil gives meaning to our sacred vow “Never Again.”</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Under the theme “Courage Facing Evil,” today we mark the Day of Holocaust Remembrance and honor the victims and survivors of the Holocaust.</p>
<p>As we remember the horrors of that dark chapter, we are surrounded by descendants of Holocaust survivors who were inspired by their family’s suffering and courage to dedicate themselves to public service. It is a sentiment I share from my own family’s story. They are public servants like U.S. Ambassador Michèle Taylor, whose parents and grandparents managed to escape the Holocaust before the Nazis murdered her extended family. This terrible loss of loved ones and her family’s will to survive were catalysts for the Ambassador’s long career defending and advancing the cause of human rights. Today, she is the U.S. representative to the United Nations Human Rights Council, where she stands up for the freedom, equal rights and dignity of all, and where she is working to rally the world in support of Ukraine against Russia’s brutal war of aggression.</p>
<p>Our charge remains to stand united against tyranny, lies, and hatred in all their forms. We must confront rising antisemitism. We must ensure that current and future generations learn the history and lessons of and from the Holocaust, so they feel a responsibility to stand up to injustice and take action against atrocities wherever they occur. This work is urgent. Fewer and fewer survivors are still with us, while those who deny and distort the history of the Holocaust are finding insidious new ways to spread their lies.</p>
<p>Today we remember all Holocaust survivors, the six million Jewish men, women and children who were murdered, and the millions of others who were killed or suffered persecution and horrific inhumanity, including Roma, persons with disabilities, and LGTBQI+ persons who were targeted in the Nazis’ campaign of dehumanization. Their precious lives and memory teach us why it is important not only to remember, but also to act. Every act of courage in the face of evil gives meaning to our sacred vow “Never Again.”</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the United States – Iceland Strategic Dialogue</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-the-united-states-iceland-strategic-dialogue-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 13:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=338764</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is the text of a joint statement by the Governments of the United States of America and Iceland following their strategic dialogue in Reykjavik, Iceland on April 26.</p>
<p><i>Begin text:</i></p>
<p>As close NATO Allies, the United States and Iceland discussed a range of issues pertinent to each country’s national security and to the security of the North Atlantic at the annual strategic dialogue on April 26. The two countries reiterated their condemnation of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustifiable war of aggression, while reaffirming their steadfast support for Ukraine. As part of the dialogue, the Allies reviewed cooperation at NATO and the bilateral security relationship. They also discussed continued cooperation on issues including safeguarding the international rules-based order, People’s Republic of China influence in Europe, the Arctic and measures to address climate change, cybersecurity, and global human rights. The bilateral defense agreement between the United States and Iceland, in place since 1951, continues to contribute to the security of our two democracies.</p>
<p>The United States was represented by the Department of State, the Department of Defense (Office of the Secretary Defense, Joint Staff, and U.S. European Command), the U.S. Coast Guard, the Department of Homeland Security, and the U.S. Embassy in Reykjavik. Iceland was represented by the Ministry for Foreign Affairs, the Prime Minister’s Office, the Icelandic Coast Guard, and the Icelandic Embassy in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><i>End text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is the text of a joint statement by the Governments of the United States of America and Iceland following their strategic dialogue in Reykjavik, Iceland on April 26.</p>
<p><i>Begin text:</i></p>
<p>As close NATO Allies, the United States and Iceland discussed a range of issues pertinent to each country’s national security and to the security of the North Atlantic at the annual strategic dialogue on April 26. The two countries reiterated their condemnation of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustifiable war of aggression, while reaffirming their steadfast support for Ukraine. As part of the dialogue, the Allies reviewed cooperation at NATO and the bilateral security relationship. They also discussed continued cooperation on issues including safeguarding the international rules-based order, People’s Republic of China influence in Europe, the Arctic and measures to address climate change, cybersecurity, and global human rights. The bilateral defense agreement between the United States and Iceland, in place since 1951, continues to contribute to the security of our two democracies.</p>
<p>The United States was represented by the Department of State, the Department of Defense (Office of the Secretary Defense, Joint Staff, and U.S. European Command), the U.S. Coast Guard, the Department of Homeland Security, and the U.S. Embassy in Reykjavik. Iceland was represented by the Ministry for Foreign Affairs, the Prime Minister’s Office, the Icelandic Coast Guard, and the Icelandic Embassy in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><i>End text.</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
