<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 23:09:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; July 12, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-july-12-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 23:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=258592</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>3:15 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thank you, everyone, for bearing with us today. I’m sorry we got a late start. I just have a few things at the top before we take some questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-MODOLVA"></a> First, today is an important day for Moldova. We are pleased to announce that the United States has donated 500,000 doses of the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine to Moldova, the first shipment to arrive today, July 12th. This donation, which was announced Friday, July 9th, will increase the number of vaccinated Moldovans by more than 100 percent, and it comes in addition to over $7 million in U.S. aid provided to Moldova since the beginning of the pandemic last year.</p>
<p>Separately, the United States congratulates the people of Moldova on their July 11th early parliamentary elections. We echo the preliminary findings of the OSCE and ODIHR, which found that the elections were well administered, they were competitive, and that the fundamental freedoms were largely respected. We urge Moldovan authorities to address concerns raised by ODIHR in its report, including enhancing full impartiality of the Central Election Commission and effective campaign finance oversight, and addressing the insufficient legal framework to regulate electoral dispute resolution.</p>
<p>We are committed to strengthening our partnership with Moldova based on shared democratic values and we look forward to working with the new government to grow our bilateral relationship and our cooperation.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-PHILIPPINESCHINA"></a> Today marks the fifth anniversary of the landmark decision in the arbitration between the Philippines and China on the South China Sea.</p>
<p>Five years ago, the Arbitral Tribunal, constituted under the 1982 Law of the Sea Convention, delivered a unanimous and enduring decision firmly rejecting the PRC’s expansive South China Sea maritime claims as having no basis in international law.</p>
<p>Yesterday evening, as you probably saw, Secretary Blinken released an official statement supporting this important ruling.</p>
<p>Many of our partners and allies, including Australia, Canada, Denmark, France, Germany, Japan, New Zealand, the Philippines, and the EU, issued statements or took to social media to demonstrate global support for the rules-based maritime order.</p>
<p>As Secretary Blinken told senior PRC officials in Anchorage early this year, quote, “The alternative to a rules-based order is a world in which might makes right and winners take all, and that would be a far more violent and unstable world for all of us.”</p>
<p>We call on the PRC to abide by its obligations under international law, to cease its provocative behavior, and to demonstrate respect for the rights of all countries, those both big and small.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-ETHIOPIATIGRAY"></a> Next, the United States is gravely concerned by reports of ongoing hostilities in western Tigray and evidence of escalating military conflict there. Escalating fighting will undermine critical ongoing efforts to deliver humanitarian relief to famine-affected populations in Tigray.</p>
<p>We again call on the Tigrayan Defense Forces, the Amhara regional forces, and Ethiopian National Defense Forces to move towards a negotiated ceasefire in the interests of civilians in the region and to preserve the unity of the Ethiopian state. We strongly condemn any retaliatory attacks that have been or may be directed against civilians in the Tigray region, whether by organized military or security forces or by rogue elements. The United States further calls on all armed actors to comply with their international humanitarian legal obligations, including regarding the protection of civilians. All those who are responsible for violations of international humanitarian law and human rights abuses must be held accountable.</p>
<p>As we have consistently said, any effort to change the internal boundaries of Ethiopia by force is unacceptable. Any issue of such national importance, like borders, would be an issue for the Ethiopian people to decide through consensual dialogue, not by the barrel of a gun.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-MOROCCO"></a> The United States is disappointed by reports that a court in Morocco has sentenced journalist Soulaiman Raissouni to five years in prison. We note Mr. Raissouni has alleged there were violations of fair trial guarantees. We believe the judicial process that led to his verdict contradicts the Moroccan system’s fundamental promise of fair trials for individuals accused of crimes, and it is inconsistent with the promise of the 2011 constitution and His Majesty King Mohammed VI’s reform agenda.</p>
<p>We also have concerns about the case’s negative impact on freedom of expression and freedom of association in Morocco. Press freedom is foundational to prosperous and secure societies, and governments must ensure that journalists can safely perform their essential roles without fear of unjust detention, violence, or threats. We are following this case closely as well as those of other detained journalists in Morocco, including Omar Radi, and we have raised these concerns with the Moroccan Government and we will continue to do so.</p>
<p>With that, I am happy to move to your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-AFGHANISTAN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. In addition – on Afghanistan, in addition to the change in command that happened earlier today, the embassy announced overnight that it’s going to resume immigrant visa processing. And I am just wondering, is this resumption going to make a dent in the backlog, or how much of a dent will it make in the backlog? Does it affect the relocation plans or the option for relocation, and is anything – has anything been decided on that front?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, you are correct that the embassy has announced over Twitter that it will resume immigrant visa interviews this week, and that does include the SIV process. As you know, the SIV process is written into law. It was designed by Congress and involves more than a dozen steps, and that includes both a role for the Department of State as well as for the Department of Homeland Security. As we’ve said before, there are approximately 18,000 Afghan principal applicants at some stage of this process as of May of 2021.</p>
<p>Approximately half of those applicants are at some stage of the process pending applicant action, so in other words, approximately 9,000 or half of these applicants need to take action before the U.S. Government can begin processing their case. About 30 percent of these applicants are awaiting a decision at the chief of mission stage and the final 20 percent were approved by the chief of mission stage and they’re moving through the application process, either in the petition or the visa processing stages.</p>
<p>You are also right in your question that we have mobilized significant resources to do all we can to make a dent in the applicants. As you know, we have been very clear and consistent that we have – the United States has – a special responsibility to those who have assisted us in different ways over the years, often at great risk to themselves, sometimes to their families as well. That is also why we have identified a group of SIV applicants – that is to say, individuals who were already somewhere in that SIV processing chain – whom at the right time before the military withdrawal is complete later this year relocate or at least offer to relocate to a third country as they go through their SIV application processing. We have been in conversations, diplomatic discussions with a number of countries around the world. These have – discussions have occurred at any number of levels, to include senior levels, but we don’t have any updates for you regarding that.</p>
<p>The other point I would make is that throughout this process, we have prioritized the safety and the security of those who, often at great risk to themselves, have helped the United States over the years. And so we will be in some cases constrained in terms of what we can say publicly about relocation, about numbers, about certain details. But as soon as we have more to share on that front, we will do so.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, but how much of a – once the interviews resume, how many can they do? How many can – how much of a dent do you think you can make in the backlog?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, look, we are moving just as quickly as we can. The &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You can’t say – just say that so I don’t keep – because I’m going to keep asking the question until you – if you don’t know, that’s fine. But I’m just – that’s my question.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, we have already made significant progress in shortening the period it requires for an applicant to go from the start of the process to – through the visa provision stage. We have shortened that by a number of months and we have done that by surging individuals, by – through operations in Kabul, but the other important point is that much of this adjudication and processing that takes place at the chief of mission stage need not and does not take place in Kabul. This is a point that we have made in terms of our embassy staffing posture in Kabul. We are able to process individuals at the chief of mission stage from here in Washington.</p>
<p>And the other point I would make – again, this program is defined in statute. It was passed by Congress, designed by Congress. We will continue to work with Congress to find ways that we could potentially streamline these operations, knowing that there are to date more than 18,000 people who have – who are somewhere in that process. Again, our goal is to shorten that process as much as we can in a way that is pursuant to the safety and security needs of these individuals but also responsible in the way that we are processing the individuals.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So since the President’s announcement that all troops would be gone by the end – by September 11th and now August 31st – but since the initial announcement back in May, how many SIV applicants – applications have been approved, and how many of those approved visa holders have been admitted to the United States? May, June, July – that’s three months.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We can see if we can provide a snapshot of that three-month period. I don’t have that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, is it more than zero? I don’t know. I’m &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll see if we can provide specific numbers.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Anything else on Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can we stay on this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure, sure. Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> If it’s on Afghanistan, yeah, yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, I’ve just got one on Afghanistan.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. Yeah.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-AFGHANISTANTURKEY"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Turkish President Erdogan says Turkey and the U.S. have reached an agreement on security for HKIA. Is this true? Can we get details if it is? The 2020 Doha agreement says no U.S. military can remain in Afghanistan. Will any U.S. military personnel assigned to airport security be rebranded as diplomats and given diplomatic passports?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, what I can say is that we have had discussions with our Turkish partners in the context of broader cooperation in Afghanistan. Those discussions are ongoing. We don’t have anything to announce today. I know that last week the Department of Defense read out a couple of those conversations, but I don’t have any additional details to share for you now.</p>
<p>We certainly welcome Turkey’s constructive role when it comes to the withdrawal and the – and the broader safety and security situation in Afghanistan, also with support for the diplomatic process.</p>
<p>When it comes to U.S. personnel on the ground, I would need to refer you to DOD for details of that.</p>
<p>Connor.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-AFGHANISTAN2"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just on SIVs.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Mm-hmm.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thinking of what you said about the limited commentary you can give us on numbers and everything, can you give us any sense of the scale of how many people are in this group that you’ve identified? Is it in the hundreds? As you’ve said, there are 18,000 applicants in total. How many of them would be expected to be relocated?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, we are making an assessment based on the needs, based on the safety and security of those applicants. We don’t have numbers to share. And again, we’re going to be limited in the details that we ultimately will be able to share. But as we do, we will do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You can’t give us any sense of like hundreds, thousands?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>At this point, I don’t have any specific numbers to share.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And then on Ambassador Khalilzad’s travel to the region, which was announced on Saturday, does he have a specific message he’s bringing to the Taliban? Is he going to offer incentives or give them a warning if they don’t cooperate in peace negotiations?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think his message will be consistent with the message that we have reiterated all along, and that is that we continue to call for an end to ongoing violence. We know that violence has been driven largely by the Taliban. We know that a negotiated settlement between the Islamic Republic and the Taliban is really the only way to end 40 years of violence and, importantly, to bring to Afghanistan’s people the safety and security and the peace that they seek.</p>
<p>And as so as Ambassador Khalilzad is there, he will urge the sides to engage in serious negotiations, to try to determine that political roadmap for a future for Afghanistan that leads to a just and durable settlement. Both of those are very important to us. A settlement cannot be durable if it is not just, and that has been a guiding principle of us all along – of ours all along.</p>
<p>We also know in the context of the recent uptick in violence – we’ve made this point before, but the world will not accept the imposition by force of a government in Afghanistan. Importantly, legitimacy and assistance and popular mandate within Afghanistan for any Afghan Government can only be possible if that government, again, has the support of the people, and for the United States and for the international community, if it has a fundamental and basic respect for human rights. For us that’s non-negotiable.</p>
<p>In the interim, we’ll continue, as you’ve heard, to support the ANDSF. That support will transition and form over time. But what won’t transition and form over time is the partnership, the partnership we will maintain with the Afghan people, with Afghanistan’s leaders, as we support this diplomacy seeking a just and durable political settlement.</p>
<p>Missy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just to add on Afghanistan, I don’t know if this is – if you all do this here, so hopefully this isn’t out of school. But would it be possible at some point to get someone to walk us through the process that the SIVs undergo just while all the details and the destinations are being worked out? Because then we can write about it with – from a place of greater understanding of what the challenges and the whole process and the parameters will be that apply to all these applicants.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That is something we do here, and happy to take that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; and take that back. I think there would be some good utility. Again, it’s a process, and there would be good utility because it’s a process that is not uncomplicated. There are a number of steps that take place in country, that take place back here. And so we’ll take that back and let you know.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Ned, can I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Anything else?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong> Ned, yeah, just one on Afghanistan.  I just can’t – what does it mean, “the world will not accept the imposition of a government by force?”  And you say that – for that – for us that’s non-negotiable.  But what does that mean?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The basic respect for human rights.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But what does that mean &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>In any &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; that it’s non-negotiable? What are you going to do if and when that happens, when there is the government imposed by force?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt, I think this goes back to the two criteria that we’ve spoken to: it’s just and it’s durable.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>In order for any government &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But you seem to – you seem to think that the Taliban care about being named and shamed.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I seem to think &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And I don’t – I just don’t &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I seem to think – and more importantly, this department and our allies and partners around the world think – that any government that might come to power in Afghanistan will require not an insignificant degree of assistance from the international community. And the international community has been very clear that any government that doesn’t respect the basic and the fundamental rights of its people won’t be in a position to accrue that international support. That is what we’re calling for: a just settlement.</p>
<p>If a settlement is not just, it won’t be durable. And it may not be durable in large part because the international community won’t be there to offer it the backing that successive – well, certainly that in the past 20 years – central governments in Afghanistan have required.</p>
<p>Said.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-ISPAL"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you, Ned. Moving on to the Palestinian issue, today the special rapporteur for human rights for the Palestinian territories, Michael Lynk, called the occupation a war crime. Do you agree that the occupation is a war crime, I mean, in the spirit of this presentation today?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’ve seen those comments. We aren’t going to evaluate or respond to every statement. To be clear, the State Department has never used such terminology. We are committed to promoting respect for human rights in Israel and the West Bank and the Gaza Strip. We have an enduring partnership with Israel, and we discuss a wide range of issues with the Israeli Government, and that includes human rights. We discuss them with Israel just as we do with other – every other partner around the world.</p>
<p>We continue to emphasize to both Israel and to the Palestinian Authority the need to refrain from unilateral action that exacerbates tension. This includes annexation of territory. It includes settlement activity. It includes demolitions. It includes incitement of violence. It includes support for terrorism, and that includes providing compensation to individual imprisoned for acts of terrorism.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, let me ask you about this specific case. There is a Palestinian feminist and leader and known leftist, Khalida Jarrar, who has been in and out of prison for the past 10 years. There are never any charges. She is a Palestinian legislator. She is guilty of being a leftie or maybe even a communist, and she is boisterous in her speech and so on, but that’s why she has been in prison.</p>
<p>Well, yesterday – she is prison now – she is supposed to be let out next October. Yesterday her daughter died. She is 30 years told. They are preventing her from going – joining in the funeral. Would you call on the Israelis to allow her to go and be in the funeral procession of her daughter?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Said, I am not in a position to weigh in on the merits of any particular case today. Again, what – the point I’ve made before is the operative one, that whether it is our Israeli partners, whether it’s a partner around the world, we consistently raise human rights. We also, importantly, remain committed to – in seeing to it that Palestinians are able to live equally in peace, in security, in dignity.</p>
<p>That is incredibly important to us. It is really at the foundation of our approach to this conflict – the idea that both Israelis and Palestinians deserve equal measures of these elements, of these very important elements. And it is why, as you’ve seen, we have already begun to re-establish that partnership with the Palestinian people. We are moving ahead with re-establishing our ties with the Palestinian Authority. Of course, Secretary Blinken has had an opportunity not only to speak with President Abbas but also to meet in person with him.</p>
<p>As you know, DAS, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State, Hady Amr is in the region right now. He is meeting with and will be meeting in the coming days with Israeli officials, with Palestinian officials, but also with elements of civil society. And his interaction and his upcoming, forthcoming meetings with elements of civil society are important to us because that is what we know needs to be empowered through all of this. And so Deputy Assistant Secretary Amr will have a series of meetings where he’ll be – will be able to push forward with some of this important work.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> We understand. But on this issue of administrative detention which is practiced by Israel time and time and time again without any charge. I mean, when people are charged with something, that is clear, but they keep arresting people and sometimes they go on for 20 years, 15 years, under administrative detention. Does that – doesn’t that bother you as a basic violation of a very basic human right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Said, we have spoken about administrative detention before. We have made clear that whether it’s our closest friends or other partners around the world we don’t shy away from raising issues of human rights. In the case of Israeli and Palestinians, again, our policy is predicated on the idea that Palestinians deserve equal measures of freedom, of safety, of security, and dignity. And this gets to your question.</p>
<p>Yes, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-CHINA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you for taking my question. So the Chinese Government came out strongly against Secretary Blinken’s statement regarding the fifth anniversary of the international tribunal’s ruling on the – China’s – at The Hague, China’s expansive claims in South China Sea. It was foreign ministry spokesman Zhao Lijian called it – called the ruling a waste of paper.</p>
<p>So my question is: Wouldn’t it be easier for the U.S. State Department to push its position on this ruling if the U.S. Government ratifies UNCLOS, the UN Convention on the Law of the Seas? And so – and with that – and further to that question, is there – is there an effort underway within the U.S. Government to ratify UNCLOS? Is it under consideration? Is it a priority for this administration to ratify it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the point I would make is that since UNCLOS was adopted, every U.S. administration has recognized its provisions on traditional uses of the ocean as reflecting customary international law and has recognized that the United States would abide by UNCLOS with respect to traditional uses of the sea. And that includes the assertion of rights in maritime spaces.</p>
<p>Now, for the PRC, the PRC is a state party to UNCLOS. The PRC has agreed to abide by compulsory dispute settlement with regard to arbitration. But by ignoring the 2016 arbitral tribunal ruling on the South China Sea and dismissing it, as you said, as a mere scrap of paper, Beijing is in clear violation of its obligations under UNCLOS.</p>
<p>Look, for us, this is not a question of the United States against the People’s Republic of China or any other country. For us, this is an affirmative policy of the free and open Indo-Pacific and beyond that, the rules-based international system that every country in the world, big and small, has an obligation to abide by.</p>
<p>So again, when it comes to territorial claims, for example, the United States doesn’t take a position on that. When it comes to these maritime claims, we do endorse the unanimous, decisive ruling that was put forward by the arbitral council. So if you want to ask about which country is being more faithful to the principles that undergird UNCLOS, I think you have a pretty clear answer.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But it’s – it is or is not a commitment of this administration to get the Senate to ratify it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I don’t have an update for you on potential Senate ratification, but again, every administration since UNCLOS has gone into effect has abided by its core underlying principles.</p>
<p>Nadia.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-DISIS"></a><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>And Nadia, while I’m thinking of it, you asked earlier about ISIS. I’m happy to offer some &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; context there and perhaps save my colleagues some response.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Some emailing.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The Secretary had an opportunity – I guess it was late last month – to travel to Italy and to join his Italian counterpart, Luigi Di Maio, as a co-host of the D-ISIS coalition ministerial. And that coalition remains critically important to our efforts, and the coalition, we heard in Italy, is united in its determination to see ISIS destroyed.</p>
<p>On that, the global coalition has destroyed 100 percent of ISIS’s fraudulent territorial so-called caliphate. The ISIS leader, Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi, of course, is no longer with us. We have heard a clear determination from the global coalition to see to it that ISIS won’t be allowed to reconstitute that territorial caliphate. Through our diplomatic efforts, this global coalition has continued to grow and now stands at, I believe, 83 members. There are 78 countries and five international organizations. And this includes a broad swath of regions: 26 members from Africa and Asia as well. And we continue to expand that partnership and cooperation against a common enemy.</p>
<p>Of course, that is not to say that ISIS does not continue to pose a threat, and we have continued to work through the coalition bilaterally, multilaterally, and in other forms to provide support to our partners in the Middle East, in Africa, who are facing these horrific attacks from the terrorist group.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-IRAN"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you for that. I have two questions on Iran and Yemen. On Iran, Iran Foreign Minister Mr. Javad Zarif said that the talks in Vienna is nearing an end, and apparently he gave a very comprehensive report to the Shura Council talking about what he called illegal U.S. sanctions and the impact on the oil and on the banking sectors.</p>
<p>Does the administration share his view that, actually, the talks are about to be concluded and you’re going to reach an agreement? What is he basing his assessment on?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I cannot speak to what he’s basing his assessment on. I can speak to our – where we stand on this, and that is that Special Envoy Malley and his team are prepared to return to Vienna for a seventh round of talks as soon as they are scheduled. Look, questions about when or whether Iran would be prepared to start a seventh round or reach an understanding on a mutual return to the JCPOA, those can only be addressed by Tehran. They can’t be routed here. We’ve made very clear that we are prepared to return to a seventh round. Again, we’re not imposing a deadline on these talks, but Secretary Blinken has made the point, I’ve made the point from here as well, that we are conscious that as time proceeds, Iran’s nuclear advances will have a bearing on our view of ultimately returning to the JCPOA.</p>
<p>So again, we stand ready to resume negotiations. We continue to believe that diplomacy is the most effective means at our disposal to achieve what we seek, and that is verifiably and – verifiably and permanently ensuring that Iran can never acquire a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And on Yemen quickly, can you brief us on what’s the latest the administration is doing to encourage the Houthis to come back to the negotiation table? There was a time when Mr. Lenderking will go to the region very often, and there were some encouraging signs, but now it seems to be silent. So are – these talks are kind of hitting a dead end? Would you say that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I’m sorry, what was the final part of your question?</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-YEMEN"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The talks, are they hitting a dead end? Are we not going anywhere, in any direction?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, absolutely not. And Special Envoy Lenderking and his team continue to work very closely with the UN special envoy, continue to work very closely with our partners in the region. Of course, you know last week Special Envoy Lenderking met with the Saudi deputy minister of defense. He has recently undertaken a series of meetings to continue this diplomatic push. There is a serious proposal on the table. The Houthis are the ones who – despite these constructive ideas that have been put forward, the Houthis are the ones who continue to perpetrate these horrifying attacks, including on Yemeni civilians. Just in Marib on – late last month, June 29th, the horrific attack that took the life of a child.</p>
<p>We also know that the Houthi offensive only exacerbates the humanitarian crisis that Yemen is in right now. We are supporting this diplomacy as a means to bring about an end to this long-running conflict, but also knowing that this diplomacy is the most effective means to mitigate and to ease the humanitarian burden on the Yemeni people. And so we are working urgently. Special Envoy Lenderking is working urgently. We know that our partners in the UN are doing the same, and we’ll continue to do that with a combination of both carrots and sticks.</p>
<p>And as you know, we continue to apply pressure to the Houthis in the context of both domestic and international sanctions. Just on June 10th we sanctioned 12 individuals and entities and a vessel related to an international network used to facilitate the provision of – I believe it is millions of dollars to Houthis in cooperation with the Qods Force. This was in addition to the designation in May of two Houthi leaders, both of whom have played a significant role in this offensive against Marib.</p>
<p>So our message is very clear. The Houthis need to show us that they are serious about diplomacy, and they can do that by ceasing this offensive and by easing the humanitarian plight on their own people. And this is something we have been working very concertedly with our partners and allies towards.</p>
<p>Yes, Tracy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-HAITI"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Can I ask a Haiti question, please?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The Secretary again reiterated the importance of elections before the end of the year. Elections have never solved Haiti’s problems, ever, so I’m just wondering if you could explain to me the thinking behind this imperative that there be elections to settle Haiti.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, I would start with the proposition that for us, this is about institutions. It’s about Haiti’s institutions. We continue to support the Haitian people and their constitution, knowing that the constitution needs to be an enduring framework for what happens next. And so yes, in our view there need to be free and fair elections. They need to happen this year – legislative elections, presidential elections – pursuant to the Haitian constitution. And that is precisely why we have continued to support them.</p>
<p>We have continued even in recent hours. And as you know, there was an interagency delegation that was in Port-au-Prince yesterday. It included representation from the Department of State. And the delegation continued to encourage Haiti’s political actors and its stakeholders to build an inclusive Haitian consensus to peacefully navigate and overcome this crisis. And to do that, we continue to believe that what needs to govern this is the Haitian constitution and Haiti’s institutions, and ultimately, in an effort to bolster Haiti’s democracy.</p>
<p>Yes, Missy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Quick follow-up on Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Haiti still? Or – Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Conor, go for it, yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Could I just ask about the security assistance aspect of that? That’s something that apparently was discussed yesterday. Is there any timeframe for the administration to make a decision on potential security assistance? What, if anything, could be in the cards?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure. So our immediate focus – and this was a focus of the delegation that was in Port-au-Prince yesterday – is determining the assistance that Haiti may need with this investigation. And after close consultation with Haitian officials in recent days and again on Sunday, we believe our focus should be assisting the Haitian Government with navigating the investigation into the assassination of President Moise, determining who is culpable, and supporting the Haitian Government as it seeks justice in this case. And FBI and DHS officials have also traveled to Port-au-Prince. They’re working to determine what assistance the United States can provide to the Haitian Government in its time of need.</p>
<p>The delegation that was there yesterday did commit to support the Haitian people in the aftermath of the assassination. That includes with a review of security of critical infrastructure with Haitian Government officials. So we’ve been in close contact with Haitian Government officials. We are reviewing the request for assistance that they have sent in, and we’re also doing our own assessment of what would be most beneficial to the people of Haiti.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just briefly, one more thing on Haiti. The Americans there who have been accused in the assassination, has – is there any update on consular access or any type of view about whether they – about their treatment and their – whether they’re culpable?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So we are aware of detention of a third U.S. citizen. We continue to monitor the situation closely. As in all cases, we will provide appropriate consular services to detained U.S. citizens. Obviously privacy considerations preclude us from saying much more, but I do suspect that once we have had access to all three American citizens who are detained, we’ll be in a position to confirm that.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-JORDAN"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Speaking of detained U.S. citizens, there was a verdict and a sentence handed down in Jordan today against two people, one of whom is an American citizen. I’m wondering if you have anything to say about that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, we are closely monitoring the case of Bassem Awadallah in Jordan. We take seriously any allegation of abuse, and we always emphasize the importance of respecting fair trial guarantees, humane treatment. We’re providing all appropriate consular assistance in line with our commitment to assisting U.S. citizens abroad. We have, in fact, visited Mr. Awadallah five times since April of this year. The most recent visit occurred just a few days ago, on July 11th.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Right, but that doesn’t speak to the actual verdict and sentence, which is what I’m asking you about.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I don’t have any comment on the verdict. But as I’ve said before, we always emphasize – and this goes back to Said’s question earlier – the importance of fair trials and guarantees of humane treatment around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The journalist in Morocco who you talked about at the very beginning, right, was he – is he an American citizen?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I don’t have any indication he is an American citizen.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But – and yet you have a position on the verdict in that case, but none in this. So what do we – what do we read into that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You think that this – the guy in Jordan could be guilty?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Each case is different.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I know.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We are &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So that’s why I’m asking you why you don’t have anything to say about the verdict.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We are going to – we are going to speak based on the facts and the circumstances as they are known to us, but obviously these cases are &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So does that mean that you’re not clear on the facts and circumstances of Mr. Awadallah’s case?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think what is very clear to us is that journalists, and hopefully everyone here can agree with this, don’t belong behind bars, that they &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah, no, I agree with that. I’m not talking about the Morocco case.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That they shouldn’t &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I’m talking about case in Jordan. Is it the case that in this situation you do not have all the facts or you – you’re not clear enough on the facts and circumstances of the verdict, of the trial that you will – that you’re not clear enough so that you can’t render an opinion on &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>What is fair to say is that when the facts and the circumstances are clear to us and when we determine that we can best move the ball forward by speaking publicly, we will never hesitate to do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-CUBA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Cuba, real quick?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. Back in 2015, July 2015 when relations were restored and President Obama said that it was – the policy of sanctions and so on was a failed policy. And then there was a great deal of hope and so on. But then the preceding administration collapsed all that hope down. But you guys seem to be following the same kind of policy as the previous administration. What are you doing, let’s say, to show people that there are actually – there are benefits to good governance and all that stuff?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I certainly would not say that we are following the previous – the policy of the previous administration. As you know, our Cuba policy is under review. But importantly – and I think this is a pivotal distinction – our policy, as you heard from the Secretary, it focuses on the wellbeing of the Cuban people, and at the center of that policy are democracy and our human rights.</p>
<p>And what we are assessing in the context of that policy review is how the United States can best support the aspirations of the Cuban people. So that policy review remains ongoing. It is something – the issue of human rights on the island is very important to us, and we’re seeing yesterday and today in the streets all throughout Cuba that it is very important, as you might expect, to the Cuban people as well. And as we undertake this review, at the center of that review will be the welfare and the wellbeing of those Cuban people.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>That’s exactly what the previous administration said their policy was towards Cuba, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Again, we haven’t spoken – we haven’t spoken &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So until your review is complete, why is Said incorrect in saying that you’re following – you’re doing the exact same thing that the Trump administration did?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, he was speaking of our policies towards Cuba. And again, our &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, yeah. You haven’t changed the previous administration’s policies, right, so until that review is complete, you’re doing the same thing, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, I can assure you that we are going about this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You’re doing the same thing as the previous administration did, right? You haven’t changed the policy.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We have not announced our Cuba policy, but what we have said is that democracy and human rights are at the center of it.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just on that, does the administration still consider Cuba a state sponsor of terrorism?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We – there’s been no change. As you know, the state sponsor of terrorism list is –it’s evaluated, and the report is released once a year. When we have a new report to release, we’ll do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So that’s part of the policy review in general of – for Cuba policy?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We are always reviewing issues of state sponsorship for countries around the world pursuant to the requirement to put forward the state sponsor of terrorism list. Our review of Cuba and Cuba policy, it is taking place in parallel to that.</p>
<p>Thank &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So separate, but parallel?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think that is a fair characterization.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Do you have time for one &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure, one last question.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-ETHIOPIA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ethiopia. The election results came out this past weekend. The United States has voiced concern previously about the atmosphere in which the elections were to be held. What’s your view on the election results? Do you think they confer legitimacy on Prime Minister Abiy?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, the Secretary himself has spoken to this. It was late last month, June 21st, he issued a statement noting that the elections took place against the backdrop of grave instability, including increasing interethnic and intercommunal conflicts and an electoral process that was not free or fair for all Ethiopians.</p>
<p>The boycott of the elections by opposition parties, the detention of vocal political leaders, the ongoing violence in multiple parts of the country – look, all of this underscores the need to launch an inclusive effort to build a national consensus on the governance of Ethiopia that, importantly, preserves the sovereignty and the unity of the state and strengthens rather than undermines the constitutional order.</p>
<p>In this period following the election, it’s critical that Ethiopians come together to confront growing divisions. We urge politicians and community leaders to reject violence and to refrain from inciting others to violence. And we’ll be watching the situation very carefully going forward. Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:57 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>3:15 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Thank you, everyone, for bearing with us today. I’m sorry we got a late start. I just have a few things at the top before we take some questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-MODOLVA"></a> First, today is an important day for Moldova. We are pleased to announce that the United States has donated 500,000 doses of the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine to Moldova, the first shipment to arrive today, July 12th. This donation, which was announced Friday, July 9th, will increase the number of vaccinated Moldovans by more than 100 percent, and it comes in addition to over $7 million in U.S. aid provided to Moldova since the beginning of the pandemic last year.</p>
<p>Separately, the United States congratulates the people of Moldova on their July 11th early parliamentary elections. We echo the preliminary findings of the OSCE and ODIHR, which found that the elections were well administered, they were competitive, and that the fundamental freedoms were largely respected. We urge Moldovan authorities to address concerns raised by ODIHR in its report, including enhancing full impartiality of the Central Election Commission and effective campaign finance oversight, and addressing the insufficient legal framework to regulate electoral dispute resolution.</p>
<p>We are committed to strengthening our partnership with Moldova based on shared democratic values and we look forward to working with the new government to grow our bilateral relationship and our cooperation.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-PHILIPPINESCHINA"></a> Today marks the fifth anniversary of the landmark decision in the arbitration between the Philippines and China on the South China Sea.</p>
<p>Five years ago, the Arbitral Tribunal, constituted under the 1982 Law of the Sea Convention, delivered a unanimous and enduring decision firmly rejecting the PRC’s expansive South China Sea maritime claims as having no basis in international law.</p>
<p>Yesterday evening, as you probably saw, Secretary Blinken released an official statement supporting this important ruling.</p>
<p>Many of our partners and allies, including Australia, Canada, Denmark, France, Germany, Japan, New Zealand, the Philippines, and the EU, issued statements or took to social media to demonstrate global support for the rules-based maritime order.</p>
<p>As Secretary Blinken told senior PRC officials in Anchorage early this year, quote, “The alternative to a rules-based order is a world in which might makes right and winners take all, and that would be a far more violent and unstable world for all of us.”</p>
<p>We call on the PRC to abide by its obligations under international law, to cease its provocative behavior, and to demonstrate respect for the rights of all countries, those both big and small.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-ETHIOPIATIGRAY"></a> Next, the United States is gravely concerned by reports of ongoing hostilities in western Tigray and evidence of escalating military conflict there. Escalating fighting will undermine critical ongoing efforts to deliver humanitarian relief to famine-affected populations in Tigray.</p>
<p>We again call on the Tigrayan Defense Forces, the Amhara regional forces, and Ethiopian National Defense Forces to move towards a negotiated ceasefire in the interests of civilians in the region and to preserve the unity of the Ethiopian state. We strongly condemn any retaliatory attacks that have been or may be directed against civilians in the Tigray region, whether by organized military or security forces or by rogue elements. The United States further calls on all armed actors to comply with their international humanitarian legal obligations, including regarding the protection of civilians. All those who are responsible for violations of international humanitarian law and human rights abuses must be held accountable.</p>
<p>As we have consistently said, any effort to change the internal boundaries of Ethiopia by force is unacceptable. Any issue of such national importance, like borders, would be an issue for the Ethiopian people to decide through consensual dialogue, not by the barrel of a gun.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-MOROCCO"></a> The United States is disappointed by reports that a court in Morocco has sentenced journalist Soulaiman Raissouni to five years in prison. We note Mr. Raissouni has alleged there were violations of fair trial guarantees. We believe the judicial process that led to his verdict contradicts the Moroccan system’s fundamental promise of fair trials for individuals accused of crimes, and it is inconsistent with the promise of the 2011 constitution and His Majesty King Mohammed VI’s reform agenda.</p>
<p>We also have concerns about the case’s negative impact on freedom of expression and freedom of association in Morocco. Press freedom is foundational to prosperous and secure societies, and governments must ensure that journalists can safely perform their essential roles without fear of unjust detention, violence, or threats. We are following this case closely as well as those of other detained journalists in Morocco, including Omar Radi, and we have raised these concerns with the Moroccan Government and we will continue to do so.</p>
<p>With that, I am happy to move to your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-AFGHANISTAN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. In addition – on Afghanistan, in addition to the change in command that happened earlier today, the embassy announced overnight that it’s going to resume immigrant visa processing. And I am just wondering, is this resumption going to make a dent in the backlog, or how much of a dent will it make in the backlog? Does it affect the relocation plans or the option for relocation, and is anything – has anything been decided on that front?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, you are correct that the embassy has announced over Twitter that it will resume immigrant visa interviews this week, and that does include the SIV process. As you know, the SIV process is written into law. It was designed by Congress and involves more than a dozen steps, and that includes both a role for the Department of State as well as for the Department of Homeland Security. As we’ve said before, there are approximately 18,000 Afghan principal applicants at some stage of this process as of May of 2021.</p>
<p>Approximately half of those applicants are at some stage of the process pending applicant action, so in other words, approximately 9,000 or half of these applicants need to take action before the U.S. Government can begin processing their case. About 30 percent of these applicants are awaiting a decision at the chief of mission stage and the final 20 percent were approved by the chief of mission stage and they’re moving through the application process, either in the petition or the visa processing stages.</p>
<p>You are also right in your question that we have mobilized significant resources to do all we can to make a dent in the applicants. As you know, we have been very clear and consistent that we have – the United States has – a special responsibility to those who have assisted us in different ways over the years, often at great risk to themselves, sometimes to their families as well. That is also why we have identified a group of SIV applicants – that is to say, individuals who were already somewhere in that SIV processing chain – whom at the right time before the military withdrawal is complete later this year relocate or at least offer to relocate to a third country as they go through their SIV application processing. We have been in conversations, diplomatic discussions with a number of countries around the world. These have – discussions have occurred at any number of levels, to include senior levels, but we don’t have any updates for you regarding that.</p>
<p>The other point I would make is that throughout this process, we have prioritized the safety and the security of those who, often at great risk to themselves, have helped the United States over the years. And so we will be in some cases constrained in terms of what we can say publicly about relocation, about numbers, about certain details. But as soon as we have more to share on that front, we will do so.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, but how much of a – once the interviews resume, how many can they do? How many can – how much of a dent do you think you can make in the backlog?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, look, we are moving just as quickly as we can. The &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You can’t say – just say that so I don’t keep – because I’m going to keep asking the question until you – if you don’t know, that’s fine. But I’m just – that’s my question.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, we have already made significant progress in shortening the period it requires for an applicant to go from the start of the process to – through the visa provision stage. We have shortened that by a number of months and we have done that by surging individuals, by – through operations in Kabul, but the other important point is that much of this adjudication and processing that takes place at the chief of mission stage need not and does not take place in Kabul. This is a point that we have made in terms of our embassy staffing posture in Kabul. We are able to process individuals at the chief of mission stage from here in Washington.</p>
<p>And the other point I would make – again, this program is defined in statute. It was passed by Congress, designed by Congress. We will continue to work with Congress to find ways that we could potentially streamline these operations, knowing that there are to date more than 18,000 people who have – who are somewhere in that process. Again, our goal is to shorten that process as much as we can in a way that is pursuant to the safety and security needs of these individuals but also responsible in the way that we are processing the individuals.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So since the President’s announcement that all troops would be gone by the end – by September 11th and now August 31st – but since the initial announcement back in May, how many SIV applicants – applications have been approved, and how many of those approved visa holders have been admitted to the United States? May, June, July – that’s three months.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We can see if we can provide a snapshot of that three-month period. I don’t have that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, is it more than zero? I don’t know. I’m &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll see if we can provide specific numbers.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (Off-mike.)</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Anything else on Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can we stay on this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure, sure. Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> If it’s on Afghanistan, yeah, yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, I’ve just got one on Afghanistan.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. Yeah.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-AFGHANISTANTURKEY"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Turkish President Erdogan says Turkey and the U.S. have reached an agreement on security for HKIA. Is this true? Can we get details if it is? The 2020 Doha agreement says no U.S. military can remain in Afghanistan. Will any U.S. military personnel assigned to airport security be rebranded as diplomats and given diplomatic passports?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, what I can say is that we have had discussions with our Turkish partners in the context of broader cooperation in Afghanistan. Those discussions are ongoing. We don’t have anything to announce today. I know that last week the Department of Defense read out a couple of those conversations, but I don’t have any additional details to share for you now.</p>
<p>We certainly welcome Turkey’s constructive role when it comes to the withdrawal and the – and the broader safety and security situation in Afghanistan, also with support for the diplomatic process.</p>
<p>When it comes to U.S. personnel on the ground, I would need to refer you to DOD for details of that.</p>
<p>Connor.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-AFGHANISTAN2"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just on SIVs.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Mm-hmm.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thinking of what you said about the limited commentary you can give us on numbers and everything, can you give us any sense of the scale of how many people are in this group that you’ve identified? Is it in the hundreds? As you’ve said, there are 18,000 applicants in total. How many of them would be expected to be relocated?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, we are making an assessment based on the needs, based on the safety and security of those applicants. We don’t have numbers to share. And again, we’re going to be limited in the details that we ultimately will be able to share. But as we do, we will do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You can’t give us any sense of like hundreds, thousands?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>At this point, I don’t have any specific numbers to share.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And then on Ambassador Khalilzad’s travel to the region, which was announced on Saturday, does he have a specific message he’s bringing to the Taliban? Is he going to offer incentives or give them a warning if they don’t cooperate in peace negotiations?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think his message will be consistent with the message that we have reiterated all along, and that is that we continue to call for an end to ongoing violence. We know that violence has been driven largely by the Taliban. We know that a negotiated settlement between the Islamic Republic and the Taliban is really the only way to end 40 years of violence and, importantly, to bring to Afghanistan’s people the safety and security and the peace that they seek.</p>
<p>And as so as Ambassador Khalilzad is there, he will urge the sides to engage in serious negotiations, to try to determine that political roadmap for a future for Afghanistan that leads to a just and durable settlement. Both of those are very important to us. A settlement cannot be durable if it is not just, and that has been a guiding principle of us all along – of ours all along.</p>
<p>We also know in the context of the recent uptick in violence – we’ve made this point before, but the world will not accept the imposition by force of a government in Afghanistan. Importantly, legitimacy and assistance and popular mandate within Afghanistan for any Afghan Government can only be possible if that government, again, has the support of the people, and for the United States and for the international community, if it has a fundamental and basic respect for human rights. For us that’s non-negotiable.</p>
<p>In the interim, we’ll continue, as you’ve heard, to support the ANDSF. That support will transition and form over time. But what won’t transition and form over time is the partnership, the partnership we will maintain with the Afghan people, with Afghanistan’s leaders, as we support this diplomacy seeking a just and durable political settlement.</p>
<p>Missy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just to add on Afghanistan, I don’t know if this is – if you all do this here, so hopefully this isn’t out of school. But would it be possible at some point to get someone to walk us through the process that the SIVs undergo just while all the details and the destinations are being worked out? Because then we can write about it with – from a place of greater understanding of what the challenges and the whole process and the parameters will be that apply to all these applicants.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That is something we do here, and happy to take that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; and take that back. I think there would be some good utility. Again, it’s a process, and there would be good utility because it’s a process that is not uncomplicated. There are a number of steps that take place in country, that take place back here. And so we’ll take that back and let you know.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Ned, can I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Anything else?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong> Ned, yeah, just one on Afghanistan.  I just can’t – what does it mean, “the world will not accept the imposition of a government by force?”  And you say that – for that – for us that’s non-negotiable.  But what does that mean?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The basic respect for human rights.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But what does that mean &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>In any &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; that it’s non-negotiable? What are you going to do if and when that happens, when there is the government imposed by force?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt, I think this goes back to the two criteria that we’ve spoken to: it’s just and it’s durable.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>In order for any government &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But you seem to – you seem to think that the Taliban care about being named and shamed.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I seem to think &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And I don’t – I just don’t &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I seem to think – and more importantly, this department and our allies and partners around the world think – that any government that might come to power in Afghanistan will require not an insignificant degree of assistance from the international community. And the international community has been very clear that any government that doesn’t respect the basic and the fundamental rights of its people won’t be in a position to accrue that international support. That is what we’re calling for: a just settlement.</p>
<p>If a settlement is not just, it won’t be durable. And it may not be durable in large part because the international community won’t be there to offer it the backing that successive – well, certainly that in the past 20 years – central governments in Afghanistan have required.</p>
<p>Said.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-ISPAL"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you, Ned. Moving on to the Palestinian issue, today the special rapporteur for human rights for the Palestinian territories, Michael Lynk, called the occupation a war crime. Do you agree that the occupation is a war crime, I mean, in the spirit of this presentation today?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’ve seen those comments. We aren’t going to evaluate or respond to every statement. To be clear, the State Department has never used such terminology. We are committed to promoting respect for human rights in Israel and the West Bank and the Gaza Strip. We have an enduring partnership with Israel, and we discuss a wide range of issues with the Israeli Government, and that includes human rights. We discuss them with Israel just as we do with other – every other partner around the world.</p>
<p>We continue to emphasize to both Israel and to the Palestinian Authority the need to refrain from unilateral action that exacerbates tension. This includes annexation of territory. It includes settlement activity. It includes demolitions. It includes incitement of violence. It includes support for terrorism, and that includes providing compensation to individual imprisoned for acts of terrorism.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, let me ask you about this specific case. There is a Palestinian feminist and leader and known leftist, Khalida Jarrar, who has been in and out of prison for the past 10 years. There are never any charges. She is a Palestinian legislator. She is guilty of being a leftie or maybe even a communist, and she is boisterous in her speech and so on, but that’s why she has been in prison.</p>
<p>Well, yesterday – she is prison now – she is supposed to be let out next October. Yesterday her daughter died. She is 30 years told. They are preventing her from going – joining in the funeral. Would you call on the Israelis to allow her to go and be in the funeral procession of her daughter?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Said, I am not in a position to weigh in on the merits of any particular case today. Again, what – the point I’ve made before is the operative one, that whether it is our Israeli partners, whether it’s a partner around the world, we consistently raise human rights. We also, importantly, remain committed to – in seeing to it that Palestinians are able to live equally in peace, in security, in dignity.</p>
<p>That is incredibly important to us. It is really at the foundation of our approach to this conflict – the idea that both Israelis and Palestinians deserve equal measures of these elements, of these very important elements. And it is why, as you’ve seen, we have already begun to re-establish that partnership with the Palestinian people. We are moving ahead with re-establishing our ties with the Palestinian Authority. Of course, Secretary Blinken has had an opportunity not only to speak with President Abbas but also to meet in person with him.</p>
<p>As you know, DAS, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State, Hady Amr is in the region right now. He is meeting with and will be meeting in the coming days with Israeli officials, with Palestinian officials, but also with elements of civil society. And his interaction and his upcoming, forthcoming meetings with elements of civil society are important to us because that is what we know needs to be empowered through all of this. And so Deputy Assistant Secretary Amr will have a series of meetings where he’ll be – will be able to push forward with some of this important work.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> We understand. But on this issue of administrative detention which is practiced by Israel time and time and time again without any charge. I mean, when people are charged with something, that is clear, but they keep arresting people and sometimes they go on for 20 years, 15 years, under administrative detention. Does that – doesn’t that bother you as a basic violation of a very basic human right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Said, we have spoken about administrative detention before. We have made clear that whether it’s our closest friends or other partners around the world we don’t shy away from raising issues of human rights. In the case of Israeli and Palestinians, again, our policy is predicated on the idea that Palestinians deserve equal measures of freedom, of safety, of security, and dignity. And this gets to your question.</p>
<p>Yes, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-CHINA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you for taking my question. So the Chinese Government came out strongly against Secretary Blinken’s statement regarding the fifth anniversary of the international tribunal’s ruling on the – China’s – at The Hague, China’s expansive claims in South China Sea. It was foreign ministry spokesman Zhao Lijian called it – called the ruling a waste of paper.</p>
<p>So my question is: Wouldn’t it be easier for the U.S. State Department to push its position on this ruling if the U.S. Government ratifies UNCLOS, the UN Convention on the Law of the Seas? And so – and with that – and further to that question, is there – is there an effort underway within the U.S. Government to ratify UNCLOS? Is it under consideration? Is it a priority for this administration to ratify it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the point I would make is that since UNCLOS was adopted, every U.S. administration has recognized its provisions on traditional uses of the ocean as reflecting customary international law and has recognized that the United States would abide by UNCLOS with respect to traditional uses of the sea. And that includes the assertion of rights in maritime spaces.</p>
<p>Now, for the PRC, the PRC is a state party to UNCLOS. The PRC has agreed to abide by compulsory dispute settlement with regard to arbitration. But by ignoring the 2016 arbitral tribunal ruling on the South China Sea and dismissing it, as you said, as a mere scrap of paper, Beijing is in clear violation of its obligations under UNCLOS.</p>
<p>Look, for us, this is not a question of the United States against the People’s Republic of China or any other country. For us, this is an affirmative policy of the free and open Indo-Pacific and beyond that, the rules-based international system that every country in the world, big and small, has an obligation to abide by.</p>
<p>So again, when it comes to territorial claims, for example, the United States doesn’t take a position on that. When it comes to these maritime claims, we do endorse the unanimous, decisive ruling that was put forward by the arbitral council. So if you want to ask about which country is being more faithful to the principles that undergird UNCLOS, I think you have a pretty clear answer.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But it’s – it is or is not a commitment of this administration to get the Senate to ratify it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I don’t have an update for you on potential Senate ratification, but again, every administration since UNCLOS has gone into effect has abided by its core underlying principles.</p>
<p>Nadia.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-DISIS"></a><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>And Nadia, while I’m thinking of it, you asked earlier about ISIS. I’m happy to offer some &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>&#8212; context there and perhaps save my colleagues some response.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Some emailing.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The Secretary had an opportunity – I guess it was late last month – to travel to Italy and to join his Italian counterpart, Luigi Di Maio, as a co-host of the D-ISIS coalition ministerial. And that coalition remains critically important to our efforts, and the coalition, we heard in Italy, is united in its determination to see ISIS destroyed.</p>
<p>On that, the global coalition has destroyed 100 percent of ISIS’s fraudulent territorial so-called caliphate. The ISIS leader, Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi, of course, is no longer with us. We have heard a clear determination from the global coalition to see to it that ISIS won’t be allowed to reconstitute that territorial caliphate. Through our diplomatic efforts, this global coalition has continued to grow and now stands at, I believe, 83 members. There are 78 countries and five international organizations. And this includes a broad swath of regions: 26 members from Africa and Asia as well. And we continue to expand that partnership and cooperation against a common enemy.</p>
<p>Of course, that is not to say that ISIS does not continue to pose a threat, and we have continued to work through the coalition bilaterally, multilaterally, and in other forms to provide support to our partners in the Middle East, in Africa, who are facing these horrific attacks from the terrorist group.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-IRAN"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you for that. I have two questions on Iran and Yemen. On Iran, Iran Foreign Minister Mr. Javad Zarif said that the talks in Vienna is nearing an end, and apparently he gave a very comprehensive report to the Shura Council talking about what he called illegal U.S. sanctions and the impact on the oil and on the banking sectors.</p>
<p>Does the administration share his view that, actually, the talks are about to be concluded and you’re going to reach an agreement? What is he basing his assessment on?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I cannot speak to what he’s basing his assessment on. I can speak to our – where we stand on this, and that is that Special Envoy Malley and his team are prepared to return to Vienna for a seventh round of talks as soon as they are scheduled. Look, questions about when or whether Iran would be prepared to start a seventh round or reach an understanding on a mutual return to the JCPOA, those can only be addressed by Tehran. They can’t be routed here. We’ve made very clear that we are prepared to return to a seventh round. Again, we’re not imposing a deadline on these talks, but Secretary Blinken has made the point, I’ve made the point from here as well, that we are conscious that as time proceeds, Iran’s nuclear advances will have a bearing on our view of ultimately returning to the JCPOA.</p>
<p>So again, we stand ready to resume negotiations. We continue to believe that diplomacy is the most effective means at our disposal to achieve what we seek, and that is verifiably and – verifiably and permanently ensuring that Iran can never acquire a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And on Yemen quickly, can you brief us on what’s the latest the administration is doing to encourage the Houthis to come back to the negotiation table? There was a time when Mr. Lenderking will go to the region very often, and there were some encouraging signs, but now it seems to be silent. So are – these talks are kind of hitting a dead end? Would you say that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I’m sorry, what was the final part of your question?</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-YEMEN"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The talks, are they hitting a dead end? Are we not going anywhere, in any direction?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>No, absolutely not. And Special Envoy Lenderking and his team continue to work very closely with the UN special envoy, continue to work very closely with our partners in the region. Of course, you know last week Special Envoy Lenderking met with the Saudi deputy minister of defense. He has recently undertaken a series of meetings to continue this diplomatic push. There is a serious proposal on the table. The Houthis are the ones who – despite these constructive ideas that have been put forward, the Houthis are the ones who continue to perpetrate these horrifying attacks, including on Yemeni civilians. Just in Marib on – late last month, June 29th, the horrific attack that took the life of a child.</p>
<p>We also know that the Houthi offensive only exacerbates the humanitarian crisis that Yemen is in right now. We are supporting this diplomacy as a means to bring about an end to this long-running conflict, but also knowing that this diplomacy is the most effective means to mitigate and to ease the humanitarian burden on the Yemeni people. And so we are working urgently. Special Envoy Lenderking is working urgently. We know that our partners in the UN are doing the same, and we’ll continue to do that with a combination of both carrots and sticks.</p>
<p>And as you know, we continue to apply pressure to the Houthis in the context of both domestic and international sanctions. Just on June 10th we sanctioned 12 individuals and entities and a vessel related to an international network used to facilitate the provision of – I believe it is millions of dollars to Houthis in cooperation with the Qods Force. This was in addition to the designation in May of two Houthi leaders, both of whom have played a significant role in this offensive against Marib.</p>
<p>So our message is very clear. The Houthis need to show us that they are serious about diplomacy, and they can do that by ceasing this offensive and by easing the humanitarian plight on their own people. And this is something we have been working very concertedly with our partners and allies towards.</p>
<p>Yes, Tracy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-HAITI"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Can I ask a Haiti question, please?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The Secretary again reiterated the importance of elections before the end of the year. Elections have never solved Haiti’s problems, ever, so I’m just wondering if you could explain to me the thinking behind this imperative that there be elections to settle Haiti.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, I would start with the proposition that for us, this is about institutions. It’s about Haiti’s institutions. We continue to support the Haitian people and their constitution, knowing that the constitution needs to be an enduring framework for what happens next. And so yes, in our view there need to be free and fair elections. They need to happen this year – legislative elections, presidential elections – pursuant to the Haitian constitution. And that is precisely why we have continued to support them.</p>
<p>We have continued even in recent hours. And as you know, there was an interagency delegation that was in Port-au-Prince yesterday. It included representation from the Department of State. And the delegation continued to encourage Haiti’s political actors and its stakeholders to build an inclusive Haitian consensus to peacefully navigate and overcome this crisis. And to do that, we continue to believe that what needs to govern this is the Haitian constitution and Haiti’s institutions, and ultimately, in an effort to bolster Haiti’s democracy.</p>
<p>Yes, Missy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Quick follow-up on Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Haiti still? Or – Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Conor, go for it, yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Could I just ask about the security assistance aspect of that? That’s something that apparently was discussed yesterday. Is there any timeframe for the administration to make a decision on potential security assistance? What, if anything, could be in the cards?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure. So our immediate focus – and this was a focus of the delegation that was in Port-au-Prince yesterday – is determining the assistance that Haiti may need with this investigation. And after close consultation with Haitian officials in recent days and again on Sunday, we believe our focus should be assisting the Haitian Government with navigating the investigation into the assassination of President Moise, determining who is culpable, and supporting the Haitian Government as it seeks justice in this case. And FBI and DHS officials have also traveled to Port-au-Prince. They’re working to determine what assistance the United States can provide to the Haitian Government in its time of need.</p>
<p>The delegation that was there yesterday did commit to support the Haitian people in the aftermath of the assassination. That includes with a review of security of critical infrastructure with Haitian Government officials. So we’ve been in close contact with Haitian Government officials. We are reviewing the request for assistance that they have sent in, and we’re also doing our own assessment of what would be most beneficial to the people of Haiti.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just briefly, one more thing on Haiti. The Americans there who have been accused in the assassination, has – is there any update on consular access or any type of view about whether they – about their treatment and their – whether they’re culpable?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So we are aware of detention of a third U.S. citizen. We continue to monitor the situation closely. As in all cases, we will provide appropriate consular services to detained U.S. citizens. Obviously privacy considerations preclude us from saying much more, but I do suspect that once we have had access to all three American citizens who are detained, we’ll be in a position to confirm that.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-JORDAN"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Speaking of detained U.S. citizens, there was a verdict and a sentence handed down in Jordan today against two people, one of whom is an American citizen. I’m wondering if you have anything to say about that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, we are closely monitoring the case of Bassem Awadallah in Jordan. We take seriously any allegation of abuse, and we always emphasize the importance of respecting fair trial guarantees, humane treatment. We’re providing all appropriate consular assistance in line with our commitment to assisting U.S. citizens abroad. We have, in fact, visited Mr. Awadallah five times since April of this year. The most recent visit occurred just a few days ago, on July 11th.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Right, but that doesn’t speak to the actual verdict and sentence, which is what I’m asking you about.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I don’t have any comment on the verdict. But as I’ve said before, we always emphasize – and this goes back to Said’s question earlier – the importance of fair trials and guarantees of humane treatment around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>The journalist in Morocco who you talked about at the very beginning, right, was he – is he an American citizen?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I don’t have any indication he is an American citizen.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But – and yet you have a position on the verdict in that case, but none in this. So what do we – what do we read into that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You think that this – the guy in Jordan could be guilty?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Each case is different.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I know.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We are &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So that’s why I’m asking you why you don’t have anything to say about the verdict.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We are going to – we are going to speak based on the facts and the circumstances as they are known to us, but obviously these cases are &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So does that mean that you’re not clear on the facts and circumstances of Mr. Awadallah’s case?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think what is very clear to us is that journalists, and hopefully everyone here can agree with this, don’t belong behind bars, that they &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah, no, I agree with that. I’m not talking about the Morocco case.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>That they shouldn’t &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I’m talking about case in Jordan. Is it the case that in this situation you do not have all the facts or you – you’re not clear enough on the facts and circumstances of the verdict, of the trial that you will – that you’re not clear enough so that you can’t render an opinion on &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>What is fair to say is that when the facts and the circumstances are clear to us and when we determine that we can best move the ball forward by speaking publicly, we will never hesitate to do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-CUBA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Cuba, real quick?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay. Back in 2015, July 2015 when relations were restored and President Obama said that it was – the policy of sanctions and so on was a failed policy. And then there was a great deal of hope and so on. But then the preceding administration collapsed all that hope down. But you guys seem to be following the same kind of policy as the previous administration. What are you doing, let’s say, to show people that there are actually – there are benefits to good governance and all that stuff?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I certainly would not say that we are following the previous – the policy of the previous administration. As you know, our Cuba policy is under review. But importantly – and I think this is a pivotal distinction – our policy, as you heard from the Secretary, it focuses on the wellbeing of the Cuban people, and at the center of that policy are democracy and our human rights.</p>
<p>And what we are assessing in the context of that policy review is how the United States can best support the aspirations of the Cuban people. So that policy review remains ongoing. It is something – the issue of human rights on the island is very important to us, and we’re seeing yesterday and today in the streets all throughout Cuba that it is very important, as you might expect, to the Cuban people as well. And as we undertake this review, at the center of that review will be the welfare and the wellbeing of those Cuban people.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>That’s exactly what the previous administration said their policy was towards Cuba, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Again, we haven’t spoken – we haven’t spoken &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So until your review is complete, why is Said incorrect in saying that you’re following – you’re doing the exact same thing that the Trump administration did?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, he was speaking of our policies towards Cuba. And again, our &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well, yeah. You haven’t changed the previous administration’s policies, right, so until that review is complete, you’re doing the same thing, right?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, I can assure you that we are going about this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You’re doing the same thing as the previous administration did, right? You haven’t changed the policy.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We have not announced our Cuba policy, but what we have said is that democracy and human rights are at the center of it.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just on that, does the administration still consider Cuba a state sponsor of terrorism?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We – there’s been no change. As you know, the state sponsor of terrorism list is –it’s evaluated, and the report is released once a year. When we have a new report to release, we’ll do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So that’s part of the policy review in general of – for Cuba policy?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>We are always reviewing issues of state sponsorship for countries around the world pursuant to the requirement to put forward the state sponsor of terrorism list. Our review of Cuba and Cuba policy, it is taking place in parallel to that.</p>
<p>Thank &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So separate, but parallel?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I think that is a fair characterization.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Do you have time for one &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure, one last question.</p>
<p><a id="post-258592-ETHIOPIA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ethiopia. The election results came out this past weekend. The United States has voiced concern previously about the atmosphere in which the elections were to be held. What’s your view on the election results? Do you think they confer legitimacy on Prime Minister Abiy?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, the Secretary himself has spoken to this. It was late last month, June 21st, he issued a statement noting that the elections took place against the backdrop of grave instability, including increasing interethnic and intercommunal conflicts and an electoral process that was not free or fair for all Ethiopians.</p>
<p>The boycott of the elections by opposition parties, the detention of vocal political leaders, the ongoing violence in multiple parts of the country – look, all of this underscores the need to launch an inclusive effort to build a national consensus on the governance of Ethiopia that, importantly, preserves the sovereignty and the unity of the state and strengthens rather than undermines the constitutional order.</p>
<p>In this period following the election, it’s critical that Ethiopians come together to confront growing divisions. We urge politicians and community leaders to reject violence and to refrain from inciting others to violence. And we’ll be watching the situation very carefully going forward. Thank you all very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:57 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Briefing with Acting Assistant Secretary for Conflict and Stabilization Operations Robert Faucher On Release of the 2021 Congressional Report Pursuant to the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-with-acting-assistant-secretary-for-conflict-and-stabilization-operations-robert-faucher-on-release-of-the-2021-congressional-report-pursuant-to-the-elie-wiesel-genocide-and-atrocities-p/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robert J. Faucher, Acting Assistant SecretaryBureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 21:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Robert J. Faucher, Acting Assistant SecretaryBureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>Press Briefing Room</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Thank you, Secretary Blinken. It’s an honor to have the Secretary announce the submission of the annual report to Congress pursuant to the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act of 2018.</p>
<p>Today, we honor the life and memory of Elie Wiesel, a Holocaust survivor who reminded us that our commitment to “never again” requires persistent determination.</p>
<p>As the Secretary mentioned, yesterday marked the 26<sup>th</sup> anniversary of genocide in Srebrenica. Atrocities unfortunately continue to unfold on our watch.</p>
<p>This report serves as a reminder that while we are making progress on preventing atrocity crimes such as genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes, we still have much more work to do.</p>
<p>This year’s report details a few specific country cases where the department has determined or acknowledged that atrocities have occurred in recent years, and thus are at risk of further atrocities.</p>
<p>For example, the report draws attention to Xinjiang, where the People’s Republic of China has committed and continues to commit genocide and crimes against humanity, against Uyghurs and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups.</p>
<p>The report draws attention to the heinous acts of sexual violence and gross human rights violations that have been reported in Tigray, Ethiopia, including indiscriminate attacks on civilians, medical personnel, and humanitarian workers.<u></u></p>
<p>And the report also calls attention to the brutal crackdown on peaceful protestors and human rights defenders in Burma by a military regime whose leadership includes many individuals responsible for ethnic cleansing against the predominantly Muslim Rohingya, and appalling violence against ethnic and religious minorities.</p>
<p>With the submission of this report, the United States reaffirms that atrocity prevention must remain at the forefront of international peace and security efforts. Atrocity crimes pose some of the gravest threats to the rules-based international order that has helped bring peace and prosperity for more than seven decades. Importantly, this report is about continuous improvement in U.S. efforts to uphold that order by preventing atrocities from occurring.</p>
<p>To carry out this important work, the White House-led Atrocity Early Warning Task Force continues to coordinate a whole-of-government approach to prevent, mitigate, and respond to atrocities.</p>
<p>In the three years since the Elie Wiesel Act became law, we have trained thousands of diplomatic, development, and defense professionals to do the crucial work of prevention. We are innovating by piloting new systems that uses – that use satellite imagery to give early warning of potential violent events to groups on-the-ground. And we have deployed life-saving aid to human rights defenders and civil society leaders threatened by and in danger from repressive regimes.</p>
<p>This report makes clear that the United States will continue to redouble its efforts to prevent, mitigate, and respond to atrocities with more timely and effective actions in coordination with likeminded partners in multilateral fora, such as the International Atrocity Prevention Working Group. We will continue to actively solicit vital input from civil society on atrocity risk analysis, prevention strategies, and methods to address grievances and community recovery.</p>
<p>These steps taken together move us one step closer to “never again.”</p>
<p>The United States Government is committed to reducing the risk of future atrocities, and, with persistent determination, create conditions for a more peaceful and prosperous world.</p>
<p>Thank you, and I’m happy to take a few questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. So a lot of this talk here has been about early warning and prevention, and yet the countries that you’ve identified, it’s kind of a – it’s too late for early warning. It’s already happened and you didn’t prevent anything. So can you give us an example or two of a country in which there was – an early warning bell went off and you did something that prevented it? Yeah, that’s &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER:</strong> Sure. Let me try and answer that question. We working in – we are working in many countries where we have indicators that basically lead us to believe that there’s a possibility of an atrocity event. These can range from a variety of kind of different kinds of situations. When we take that up, we talk to those countries, we develop programs in response to those indicators, and we work with our international partners to address that.</p>
<p>So, for example, in the Central African Republic we’ve been training women there in four states on conflict mitigation, trying to help them understand how to better bring their society together rather than let it divide itself among the people in that society.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, but the situation in the CAR is pretty bad &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>It is pretty bad, and &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; as it is throughout West Africa. So can you give us an example of – I mean, I understand that this report is important. But again, I have to point out that every country that you named, with the exception of CAR just now, has already been through atrocities. So I don’t see where the – where is the early warning system working?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Well, the early warning can &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Because it hasn’t – it might be &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Oh, sorry.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You might be doing it in CAR but &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; it hasn’t stopped the atrocities from happening.</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Well, at this point in the CAR, we haven’t made any determination of atrocity occurring there. But in other countries, including those countries that are listed here that had a history of atrocity, our efforts are to stop atrocity either from recurring or from occurring at all. And so our efforts – as the Secretary said, this is a tough, tough challenge. These are not easy things to do. And we&#8217;re trying to take all steps that we can using our entire toolbox of diplomatic, financial, and other resources to prevent these events from occurring in those – in whatever country we’re talking about.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you, Ned. Thank you, sir. My question is really on the definition of atrocity. I think it covers war crimes, crimes against humanity, and so on. What is your definition? And are you, like, in tandem with the United Nations, other countries, and so on? And how do you go about enforcing this since you’re not, let’s say, a member of the ICC? Thank you, sir.</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Sure. First of all, the definition of atrocity – the Elie Wiesel Atrocity and Genocide Prevention Act – or Genocide and Atrocity Prevention Act defines atrocity very clearly as including genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes. And that’s the definition that we are using for the work we’re doing under that law.</p>
<p>Now, when we are facing those situations, we are working with our international partners basically to develop a response to countries or regions of concern where we think these things might be developing.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you, sir.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Other question? Yes, please. Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you. You mentioned in the report that the administration is committing to combating ISIS in Iraq and Syria. Can you tell us if this constant attack by the pro-Iran militias, specifically in Iraq, is hindering your efforts to confront ISIS? And can you give us an assessment, if possible – I know it might not be your domain – on the strength of ISIS as we speak now?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>So for the latter point, yes, I’m afraid I’m – that is not my area of expertise, so I wouldn’t be able to give you an accurate response, but we can refer that to our experts and we’ll get back to on the strength of ISIS right now. But I think it’s fair to say the attacks that are occurring in Syria at a minimum complicate our ability to work towards atrocity prevention and atrocity response that has occurred in that area. So it’s definitely a very unwelcome development. It’s something that we urge the parties to desist from doing.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Kylie.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Could I just ask you with regard to prevention and also getting in the way of these atrocities continuing to be carried out, how important is it to deny the perpetrators of access to the U.S. economy?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Well, we think this is one of the key tools that we have. This is more in response – or in response to atrocities that have occurred. Obviously, we want to hold the perpetrators accountable through transitional justice or international justice systems as well as prevent them from having access to U.S. markets or to the United States in general. And I think you’ll see in the report itself this year the Department of Homeland Security mentions that they stopped at least 24 people from entering the United States who had been accused of atrocity crimes in the past.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And can I just follow up on that? Then specifically looking at the genocide in Xinjiang in China, we all know that solar panels are key to the Biden administration’s energy plan, and so I know that there have been some restrictions put on companies operating in that region who exploit the Uyghur population there, but is there a policy at large that the Biden administration is going to implement that will deny any of those companies from selling their goods to the United States?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER:</strong> It’s very difficult for me to speculate as to what our policy will be if you’re asking, “Where is the policy going?” But right now, yes, we have prevented certain products from Xinjiang from coming into the United States, and I know there is a consistent and constant review of those kind of policies and how they should be expanded or changed.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And why can’t you just make a broad determination if that, as you said, is a key tool that can be employed and this has been defined as a genocide?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER:</strong> I don’t think I fully understand your question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m just wondering why that isn’t just kind of a holistic policy not to import any of the goods from those companies using Uyghur population if we know that a genocide is occurring there?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER:</strong> Again, I think we have our specific policies that we put into place that are under review and will be adjusted as appropriate. I think other departments in the government are involved in those decisions as well as our partners. And its a – as you know, a very fluid and complicated situation. To date though, we don’t have sort of a blanket policy that you’re referring to. We have more specific policy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Missy Ryan, <em>Washington Post</em>. I just wanted to ask, if possible, about the early warning system and Afghanistan. As the United States withdraws or ends its military mission in Afghanistan, there is a lot of concern about civil war and particularly the Taliban taking over areas of the country where previously in the 1990s they were accused of war crimes and targeting certain ethnicities and religious minorities, specifically the Hazara. And I’m just wondering what you guys are doing for – in regards to Afghanistan right now and how the State Department will do it given the reduced visibility that it probably is going to have in Afghanistan without the eyes across the country in different places.</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER:</strong> It is – the situation in Afghanistan is of grave concern for the United States. In terms of the activities of the Taliban, we are working with our international partners. We’ll keep our eyes on their activities. We will call them out if they engage in kind of atrocity events as they are working in the country or fighting in the country. And we will bring all the diplomatic tools and other tools we have at our disposal to protest and to try to stop or prevent those things from occurring.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. You and also the Secretary were talking about how you’re trying to improve the mechanisms or the tools that you have in order to stop genocide activity, and some of those means would be independent fact-finding missions. With regard to China, it seems clear that the Chinese Government has no inclination of allowing any sort of independent and fact-finding missions that would sort of satisfy both the U.S. State Department and also perhaps EU or Canada.</p>
<p>So what’s the strategy then? If you’re trying to improve the means by which the U.S. tries to stop what’s going on Xinjiang, and if the Chinese Government is apparently completely stonewalling any attempt to get in there, what – is it just a matter of trying to let that pressure, international pressure, push them to eventually relent? If not, what – how can you get on the ground in Xinjiang?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Sure. We – I think we totally regret the refusal of the Chinese Government, number one, to let people in to look at what’s happening in that situation. We are maintaining, as you mentioned, pressure with our international partners on China both to let people in and to change its behavior so that we could stop what we consider to be the atrocities that are happening there from occurring or continuing to occur into the future.</p>
<p>So the strategy is a diplomatic strategy that continues to build pressure on China using whatever tools we have at our disposal. And it cannot be just by the United States alone. It has to be with our partners around the world.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Any other questions? Shaun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Sure. Can I ask you further about the situation in Tigray? I was wondering what your assessment right now of – I mean, and the report, of course, is talking about the grave concerns there, but in recent weeks, of course, there’s been a change on the ground there with the – some of the government troops leaving. What’s your assessment of how things stand now? Do you see any hope of resolution for this? And the Ethiopian elections, how if anything does that affect the situation there?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Sure. Well, let me try and – first of all, the Ethiopia elections, I’m not the – obviously the expert on Ethiopia, so I feel reluctant to talk about that.</p>
<p>In terms of the situation in Tigray and what we – what’s represented in the report, the report goes through May of this year, and there have been developments since May in Tigray and among – with the election and various other things that have occurred. We are still very concerned about the situation there. We’re calling for all parties to respect the ceasefire. We’re calling for full humanitarian access into that region. It is very concerning to see what’s going on for the people there.</p>
<p>We are also asking for full cooperation with the Ethiopian Human Rights Commission and the UN Human Rights Council – their investigations into the allegations that are being made about what is going on there. And at the same time, we want the Eritrean forces to withdraw and the full scope of the situation to basically be brought down several notches.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Tracy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>This is a slightly procedural question and forgive my ignorance, but in your report, you name, I think, five or six cases. Does – is that it? Is that – is that all that you’re studying in this particular report, or is there a broader review of other cases?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>The – under the law, the Congress has asked us to do a global assessment of atrocity risk throughout the entire world, so we’re looking at the entire world. We wanted to highlight those six countries or those six instances in this report basically to show that we have had in the past the ability to make determinations that atrocities have occurred and that we have ways of responding to that.</p>
<p>We believe it’s important, as I think the Secretary has said it several times, to shine – to put a spotlight on these activities. That’s one of the best ways from preventing them from happening again in the future. And so this report is meant to put a spotlight on bad behaviors that we hope to stop.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> If nothing further, thank you Acting Assistant Secretary Faucher. Appreciate it. Congratulations on the report.</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Thank you. Thank you very – thank you all very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Robert J. Faucher, Acting Assistant SecretaryBureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>Press Briefing Room</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Thank you, Secretary Blinken. It’s an honor to have the Secretary announce the submission of the annual report to Congress pursuant to the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act of 2018.</p>
<p>Today, we honor the life and memory of Elie Wiesel, a Holocaust survivor who reminded us that our commitment to “never again” requires persistent determination.</p>
<p>As the Secretary mentioned, yesterday marked the 26<sup>th</sup> anniversary of genocide in Srebrenica. Atrocities unfortunately continue to unfold on our watch.</p>
<p>This report serves as a reminder that while we are making progress on preventing atrocity crimes such as genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes, we still have much more work to do.</p>
<p>This year’s report details a few specific country cases where the department has determined or acknowledged that atrocities have occurred in recent years, and thus are at risk of further atrocities.</p>
<p>For example, the report draws attention to Xinjiang, where the People’s Republic of China has committed and continues to commit genocide and crimes against humanity, against Uyghurs and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups.</p>
<p>The report draws attention to the heinous acts of sexual violence and gross human rights violations that have been reported in Tigray, Ethiopia, including indiscriminate attacks on civilians, medical personnel, and humanitarian workers.<u></u></p>
<p>And the report also calls attention to the brutal crackdown on peaceful protestors and human rights defenders in Burma by a military regime whose leadership includes many individuals responsible for ethnic cleansing against the predominantly Muslim Rohingya, and appalling violence against ethnic and religious minorities.</p>
<p>With the submission of this report, the United States reaffirms that atrocity prevention must remain at the forefront of international peace and security efforts. Atrocity crimes pose some of the gravest threats to the rules-based international order that has helped bring peace and prosperity for more than seven decades. Importantly, this report is about continuous improvement in U.S. efforts to uphold that order by preventing atrocities from occurring.</p>
<p>To carry out this important work, the White House-led Atrocity Early Warning Task Force continues to coordinate a whole-of-government approach to prevent, mitigate, and respond to atrocities.</p>
<p>In the three years since the Elie Wiesel Act became law, we have trained thousands of diplomatic, development, and defense professionals to do the crucial work of prevention. We are innovating by piloting new systems that uses – that use satellite imagery to give early warning of potential violent events to groups on-the-ground. And we have deployed life-saving aid to human rights defenders and civil society leaders threatened by and in danger from repressive regimes.</p>
<p>This report makes clear that the United States will continue to redouble its efforts to prevent, mitigate, and respond to atrocities with more timely and effective actions in coordination with likeminded partners in multilateral fora, such as the International Atrocity Prevention Working Group. We will continue to actively solicit vital input from civil society on atrocity risk analysis, prevention strategies, and methods to address grievances and community recovery.</p>
<p>These steps taken together move us one step closer to “never again.”</p>
<p>The United States Government is committed to reducing the risk of future atrocities, and, with persistent determination, create conditions for a more peaceful and prosperous world.</p>
<p>Thank you, and I’m happy to take a few questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. So a lot of this talk here has been about early warning and prevention, and yet the countries that you’ve identified, it’s kind of a – it’s too late for early warning. It’s already happened and you didn’t prevent anything. So can you give us an example or two of a country in which there was – an early warning bell went off and you did something that prevented it? Yeah, that’s &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER:</strong> Sure. Let me try and answer that question. We working in – we are working in many countries where we have indicators that basically lead us to believe that there’s a possibility of an atrocity event. These can range from a variety of kind of different kinds of situations. When we take that up, we talk to those countries, we develop programs in response to those indicators, and we work with our international partners to address that.</p>
<p>So, for example, in the Central African Republic we’ve been training women there in four states on conflict mitigation, trying to help them understand how to better bring their society together rather than let it divide itself among the people in that society.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Okay, but the situation in the CAR is pretty bad &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>It is pretty bad, and &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; as it is throughout West Africa. So can you give us an example of – I mean, I understand that this report is important. But again, I have to point out that every country that you named, with the exception of CAR just now, has already been through atrocities. So I don’t see where the – where is the early warning system working?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Well, the early warning can &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Because it hasn’t – it might be &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Oh, sorry.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>You might be doing it in CAR but &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; it hasn’t stopped the atrocities from happening.</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Well, at this point in the CAR, we haven’t made any determination of atrocity occurring there. But in other countries, including those countries that are listed here that had a history of atrocity, our efforts are to stop atrocity either from recurring or from occurring at all. And so our efforts – as the Secretary said, this is a tough, tough challenge. These are not easy things to do. And we&#8217;re trying to take all steps that we can using our entire toolbox of diplomatic, financial, and other resources to prevent these events from occurring in those – in whatever country we’re talking about.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you, Ned. Thank you, sir. My question is really on the definition of atrocity. I think it covers war crimes, crimes against humanity, and so on. What is your definition? And are you, like, in tandem with the United Nations, other countries, and so on? And how do you go about enforcing this since you’re not, let’s say, a member of the ICC? Thank you, sir.</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Sure. First of all, the definition of atrocity – the Elie Wiesel Atrocity and Genocide Prevention Act – or Genocide and Atrocity Prevention Act defines atrocity very clearly as including genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes. And that’s the definition that we are using for the work we’re doing under that law.</p>
<p>Now, when we are facing those situations, we are working with our international partners basically to develop a response to countries or regions of concern where we think these things might be developing.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you, sir.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Other question? Yes, please. Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you. You mentioned in the report that the administration is committing to combating ISIS in Iraq and Syria. Can you tell us if this constant attack by the pro-Iran militias, specifically in Iraq, is hindering your efforts to confront ISIS? And can you give us an assessment, if possible – I know it might not be your domain – on the strength of ISIS as we speak now?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>So for the latter point, yes, I’m afraid I’m – that is not my area of expertise, so I wouldn’t be able to give you an accurate response, but we can refer that to our experts and we’ll get back to on the strength of ISIS right now. But I think it’s fair to say the attacks that are occurring in Syria at a minimum complicate our ability to work towards atrocity prevention and atrocity response that has occurred in that area. So it’s definitely a very unwelcome development. It’s something that we urge the parties to desist from doing.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Kylie.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Could I just ask you with regard to prevention and also getting in the way of these atrocities continuing to be carried out, how important is it to deny the perpetrators of access to the U.S. economy?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Well, we think this is one of the key tools that we have. This is more in response – or in response to atrocities that have occurred. Obviously, we want to hold the perpetrators accountable through transitional justice or international justice systems as well as prevent them from having access to U.S. markets or to the United States in general. And I think you’ll see in the report itself this year the Department of Homeland Security mentions that they stopped at least 24 people from entering the United States who had been accused of atrocity crimes in the past.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And can I just follow up on that? Then specifically looking at the genocide in Xinjiang in China, we all know that solar panels are key to the Biden administration’s energy plan, and so I know that there have been some restrictions put on companies operating in that region who exploit the Uyghur population there, but is there a policy at large that the Biden administration is going to implement that will deny any of those companies from selling their goods to the United States?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER:</strong> It’s very difficult for me to speculate as to what our policy will be if you’re asking, “Where is the policy going?” But right now, yes, we have prevented certain products from Xinjiang from coming into the United States, and I know there is a consistent and constant review of those kind of policies and how they should be expanded or changed.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And why can’t you just make a broad determination if that, as you said, is a key tool that can be employed and this has been defined as a genocide?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER:</strong> I don’t think I fully understand your question.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m just wondering why that isn’t just kind of a holistic policy not to import any of the goods from those companies using Uyghur population if we know that a genocide is occurring there?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER:</strong> Again, I think we have our specific policies that we put into place that are under review and will be adjusted as appropriate. I think other departments in the government are involved in those decisions as well as our partners. And its a – as you know, a very fluid and complicated situation. To date though, we don’t have sort of a blanket policy that you’re referring to. We have more specific policy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Missy Ryan, <em>Washington Post</em>. I just wanted to ask, if possible, about the early warning system and Afghanistan. As the United States withdraws or ends its military mission in Afghanistan, there is a lot of concern about civil war and particularly the Taliban taking over areas of the country where previously in the 1990s they were accused of war crimes and targeting certain ethnicities and religious minorities, specifically the Hazara. And I’m just wondering what you guys are doing for – in regards to Afghanistan right now and how the State Department will do it given the reduced visibility that it probably is going to have in Afghanistan without the eyes across the country in different places.</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER:</strong> It is – the situation in Afghanistan is of grave concern for the United States. In terms of the activities of the Taliban, we are working with our international partners. We’ll keep our eyes on their activities. We will call them out if they engage in kind of atrocity events as they are working in the country or fighting in the country. And we will bring all the diplomatic tools and other tools we have at our disposal to protest and to try to stop or prevent those things from occurring.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. You and also the Secretary were talking about how you’re trying to improve the mechanisms or the tools that you have in order to stop genocide activity, and some of those means would be independent fact-finding missions. With regard to China, it seems clear that the Chinese Government has no inclination of allowing any sort of independent and fact-finding missions that would sort of satisfy both the U.S. State Department and also perhaps EU or Canada.</p>
<p>So what’s the strategy then? If you’re trying to improve the means by which the U.S. tries to stop what’s going on Xinjiang, and if the Chinese Government is apparently completely stonewalling any attempt to get in there, what – is it just a matter of trying to let that pressure, international pressure, push them to eventually relent? If not, what – how can you get on the ground in Xinjiang?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Sure. We – I think we totally regret the refusal of the Chinese Government, number one, to let people in to look at what’s happening in that situation. We are maintaining, as you mentioned, pressure with our international partners on China both to let people in and to change its behavior so that we could stop what we consider to be the atrocities that are happening there from occurring or continuing to occur into the future.</p>
<p>So the strategy is a diplomatic strategy that continues to build pressure on China using whatever tools we have at our disposal. And it cannot be just by the United States alone. It has to be with our partners around the world.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Any other questions? Shaun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Sure. Can I ask you further about the situation in Tigray? I was wondering what your assessment right now of – I mean, and the report, of course, is talking about the grave concerns there, but in recent weeks, of course, there’s been a change on the ground there with the – some of the government troops leaving. What’s your assessment of how things stand now? Do you see any hope of resolution for this? And the Ethiopian elections, how if anything does that affect the situation there?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Sure. Well, let me try and – first of all, the Ethiopia elections, I’m not the – obviously the expert on Ethiopia, so I feel reluctant to talk about that.</p>
<p>In terms of the situation in Tigray and what we – what’s represented in the report, the report goes through May of this year, and there have been developments since May in Tigray and among – with the election and various other things that have occurred. We are still very concerned about the situation there. We’re calling for all parties to respect the ceasefire. We’re calling for full humanitarian access into that region. It is very concerning to see what’s going on for the people there.</p>
<p>We are also asking for full cooperation with the Ethiopian Human Rights Commission and the UN Human Rights Council – their investigations into the allegations that are being made about what is going on there. And at the same time, we want the Eritrean forces to withdraw and the full scope of the situation to basically be brought down several notches.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Tracy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>This is a slightly procedural question and forgive my ignorance, but in your report, you name, I think, five or six cases. Does – is that it? Is that – is that all that you’re studying in this particular report, or is there a broader review of other cases?</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>The – under the law, the Congress has asked us to do a global assessment of atrocity risk throughout the entire world, so we’re looking at the entire world. We wanted to highlight those six countries or those six instances in this report basically to show that we have had in the past the ability to make determinations that atrocities have occurred and that we have ways of responding to that.</p>
<p>We believe it’s important, as I think the Secretary has said it several times, to shine – to put a spotlight on these activities. That’s one of the best ways from preventing them from happening again in the future. And so this report is meant to put a spotlight on bad behaviors that we hope to stop.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> If nothing further, thank you Acting Assistant Secretary Faucher. Appreciate it. Congratulations on the report.</p>
<p><strong>MR FAUCHER: </strong>Thank you. Thank you very – thank you all very much.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Remarks to the Press on Release of the 2021 Congressional Report Pursuant to the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-remarks-to-the-press-on-release-of-the-2021-congressional-report-pursuant-to-the-elie-wiesel-genocide-and-atrocities-prevention-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 20:35:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258567</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Press Briefing Room</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Good afternoon, everyone.  I’m very pleased that today Secretary Blinken is joining us to unveil the 2021 Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act Report.  Secretary Blinken will have a statement.  He’ll take a question or two before he has to depart.  At that point, we’ll turn to Acting Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations Rob Faucher, who will also make a brief statement and he’ll stay to take additional questions.  After that, we will proceed to our normally scheduled program.</p>
<p>With that, over to you, Secretary Blinken.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Ned, thanks very much.</p>
<p>Good afternoon, everyone.  Good to see you all.  Let me just say, before turning to today’s report, I want to speak briefly to the situation in two countries in the hemisphere.</p>
<p>Over the weekend, tens of thousands of Cubans took to the streets on the island to exercise their rights to assemble peacefully and express their views.  The protesters called for freedom and human rights.  They criticized Cuba’s authoritarian regime for failing to meet people’s most basic needs, including food and medicine.</p>
<p>In many instances, peaceful protesters were met with repression and violence.  The Biden-Harris administration stands by the Cuban people and people around the world who demand their human rights and who expect governments to listen to and serve them rather than try to silence them.  Peaceful protesters are not criminals, and we join partners across the hemisphere and around the world in urging the Cuban regime to respect the rights of the Cuban people to determine their own future, something they have been denied for far too long.</p>
<p>Second, the United States is in close consultations with our Haitian and international partners to support the Haitian people in the aftermath of the assassination of President Moise.  We urge the country’s political leaders to bring the country together around a more inclusive, peaceful, and secure vision and pave the road toward free and fair elections this year.  Yesterday we sent an interagency delegation to Port-au-Prince to assess the situation, which, together with our constant contact with Haitian officials and other stakeholders, will help determine how the United States can best support Haiti in a very difficult time.</p>
<p>I want to reiterate our deepest condolences to the family of President Moise and to the Haitian people and wish First Lady Martine Moise a swift recovery.</p>
<p>Now let me turn to the reason we’re actually here today.</p>
<p>Elie Wiesel said that the opposite of love isn’t hate.  It’s indifference.</p>
<p>The report that we release today represents a stand against indifference and a commitment to do more to prevent and respond to atrocities, including genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes.</p>
<p>It’s fitting that we’re meeting today.  Yesterday was the 26th anniversary of the genocide at Srebenica, when more than 8,000 Bosniak Muslim boys and men were slaughtered.  The American people join the people of Bosnia and Herzegovina in solemn remembrance of those victims and in solidarity with their families.  We’re reminded of how important it is to do all we can to prevent atrocities like this from ever occurring.</p>
<p>I want to thank Assistant Secretary Rob Faucher and the entire Conflict and Stabilization Operations team for leading the effort to produce this report, as well as the members of the interagency Atrocity Early Warning Task Force, led by the White House, and the hundreds of American diplomats around the world whose reporting, insights, and efforts are reflected here.</p>
<p>Let me just take a moment to put this report in context.</p>
<p>Over the past decade and a half, the United States has steadily and systematically increased our efforts to stop mass atrocities.</p>
<p>In 2008, a bipartisan Genocide Prevention Task Force, chaired by former Secretary of State Madeleine Albright and former Secretary of Defense Bill Cohen, produced a blueprint for U.S. policymakers, with 34 recommendations for how to identify and avert genocide.</p>
<p>In 2011, President Obama issued a presidential study directive on mass atrocities, writing, and I quote, “Preventing mass atrocities and genocide is a core national security interest and a core moral responsibility of the United States.”</p>
<p>To deliver on that core interest, we created the Atrocities Prevention Board at the NSC – it’s now called the Atrocity Early Warning Task Force – and soon after, the Bureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations here at the State Department.</p>
<p>And in 2018, Congress passed the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act.</p>
<p>It codified atrocity prevention as an American priority.</p>
<p>It directed the United States Government to enhance its capacity to prevent, mitigate, and respond to atrocities.</p>
<p>It required the State Department to provide additional training to our teams in Washington and around the world on how to spot warning signs of potential atrocities and early prevention steps to take.</p>
<p>And it mandated the annual report that we’re releasing today.</p>
<p>All this work – under both Democratic and Republican presidents, with bipartisan support from Congress – reflects our hope that, with the right tools, resources, and commitment, we can ward off atrocities before they lead to mass human suffering.</p>
<p>We want to change the story that we’ve seen play out too many times – that by the time senior policymakers are fully engaged, many people have died, the costs of taking action have risen, opportunities for early intervention have been missed.</p>
<p>I say all this with humility, as someone who has served in senior levels of government before, and has been in rooms when we grappled with what to do when political unrest somewhere in the world gave way to mass violence toward civilians.</p>
<p>This is an incredibly difficult challenge.  My friend and colleague Samantha Power described it as a “problem from hell.”  You’ll recall her groundbreaking book on the subject.  And we haven’t cracked it yet.  But we continue to believe that it’s possible, and that training, preparation, resources, cooperation – within governments and among governments – are key.  And so, of course, is determination.</p>
<p>This year, for the first time, the report provides direct, detailed accounts of atrocities taking place in specific countries, including Burma, Ethiopia, China, and Syria.  These places represent some of the toughest foreign policy challenges on our agenda, and we’ll keep working toward resolutions that reflect our commitment to human rights and democratic values.</p>
<p>We’ll use all of the tools at our disposal – including diplomacy, foreign assistance, investigations and fact-finding missions, financial tools and engagements, reports like this one which raise awareness and allow us to generate coordinated international pressure in response – in a whole-of-government approach to preventing and mitigating atrocities around the globe.</p>
<p>At our best, the United States helps bring peace and stability to places where people are suffering.  Our work on preventing atrocities represents our highest ideals in action.  And the Biden-Harris administration will build upon the work of past administrations to bring us closer to a future in which atrocities are never allowed to happen again.</p>
<p>Thanks very much.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Shaun.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thanks, Mr. Secretary.  Could I follow up on your remarks on Cuba?  I was wondering what implications this has for U.S. policy.  There’s a policy review underway.  Does this affect the timeline and when do you expect that to be finished?  Ideas like remittances, travel, things that were – that took place under Obama, are those still on the cards now after this?</p>
<p>And on that note, the president of Cuba today said that the U.S. was provoking social unrest.  Do you have any response to that?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  The policy review that you point to focuses on the political and economic well-being of the Cuban people, and obviously we’re looking carefully and closely at what has just happened, what indeed is happening.  And as we stated many times, at the heart of the review and at the heart of the policy that would result are democracy and human rights.  That’s core to our efforts.  That will be reflected in the policy.</p>
<p>I think it would be a grievous mistake for the Cuban regime to interpret what is happening in dozens of towns and cities across the island as the result or product of anything the United States has done.  It would be a grievous mistake because it would show that they simply are not hearing the voices and will of the Cuban people – people deeply, deeply, deeply tired of the repression that has gone on for far too long, tired of the mismanagement of the Cuban economy, tired of the lack of adequate food, and of course, inadequate response to the COVID pandemic.  That is what we are hearing and seeing in Cuba, and that is a reflection of the Cuban people, not of the United States or any other outside actor.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  (Off-mike.)</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  On Ethiopia, do you have an update on the assessment of whether to call events in Tigray crimes against humanity, genocide, or war crimes?</p>
<p>And if I may on Myanmar, can you update us on the review of whether genocide and crimes against humanity were committed against the Rohingya?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Yeah, appreciate it.  Look, both reviews are ongoing.  We’re bringing together the facts, the legal assessments, and both are being very actively considered.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Press Briefing Room</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Good afternoon, everyone.  I’m very pleased that today Secretary Blinken is joining us to unveil the 2021 Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act Report.  Secretary Blinken will have a statement.  He’ll take a question or two before he has to depart.  At that point, we’ll turn to Acting Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations Rob Faucher, who will also make a brief statement and he’ll stay to take additional questions.  After that, we will proceed to our normally scheduled program.</p>
<p>With that, over to you, Secretary Blinken.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Ned, thanks very much.</p>
<p>Good afternoon, everyone.  Good to see you all.  Let me just say, before turning to today’s report, I want to speak briefly to the situation in two countries in the hemisphere.</p>
<p>Over the weekend, tens of thousands of Cubans took to the streets on the island to exercise their rights to assemble peacefully and express their views.  The protesters called for freedom and human rights.  They criticized Cuba’s authoritarian regime for failing to meet people’s most basic needs, including food and medicine.</p>
<p>In many instances, peaceful protesters were met with repression and violence.  The Biden-Harris administration stands by the Cuban people and people around the world who demand their human rights and who expect governments to listen to and serve them rather than try to silence them.  Peaceful protesters are not criminals, and we join partners across the hemisphere and around the world in urging the Cuban regime to respect the rights of the Cuban people to determine their own future, something they have been denied for far too long.</p>
<p>Second, the United States is in close consultations with our Haitian and international partners to support the Haitian people in the aftermath of the assassination of President Moise.  We urge the country’s political leaders to bring the country together around a more inclusive, peaceful, and secure vision and pave the road toward free and fair elections this year.  Yesterday we sent an interagency delegation to Port-au-Prince to assess the situation, which, together with our constant contact with Haitian officials and other stakeholders, will help determine how the United States can best support Haiti in a very difficult time.</p>
<p>I want to reiterate our deepest condolences to the family of President Moise and to the Haitian people and wish First Lady Martine Moise a swift recovery.</p>
<p>Now let me turn to the reason we’re actually here today.</p>
<p>Elie Wiesel said that the opposite of love isn’t hate.  It’s indifference.</p>
<p>The report that we release today represents a stand against indifference and a commitment to do more to prevent and respond to atrocities, including genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes.</p>
<p>It’s fitting that we’re meeting today.  Yesterday was the 26th anniversary of the genocide at Srebenica, when more than 8,000 Bosniak Muslim boys and men were slaughtered.  The American people join the people of Bosnia and Herzegovina in solemn remembrance of those victims and in solidarity with their families.  We’re reminded of how important it is to do all we can to prevent atrocities like this from ever occurring.</p>
<p>I want to thank Assistant Secretary Rob Faucher and the entire Conflict and Stabilization Operations team for leading the effort to produce this report, as well as the members of the interagency Atrocity Early Warning Task Force, led by the White House, and the hundreds of American diplomats around the world whose reporting, insights, and efforts are reflected here.</p>
<p>Let me just take a moment to put this report in context.</p>
<p>Over the past decade and a half, the United States has steadily and systematically increased our efforts to stop mass atrocities.</p>
<p>In 2008, a bipartisan Genocide Prevention Task Force, chaired by former Secretary of State Madeleine Albright and former Secretary of Defense Bill Cohen, produced a blueprint for U.S. policymakers, with 34 recommendations for how to identify and avert genocide.</p>
<p>In 2011, President Obama issued a presidential study directive on mass atrocities, writing, and I quote, “Preventing mass atrocities and genocide is a core national security interest and a core moral responsibility of the United States.”</p>
<p>To deliver on that core interest, we created the Atrocities Prevention Board at the NSC – it’s now called the Atrocity Early Warning Task Force – and soon after, the Bureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations here at the State Department.</p>
<p>And in 2018, Congress passed the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act.</p>
<p>It codified atrocity prevention as an American priority.</p>
<p>It directed the United States Government to enhance its capacity to prevent, mitigate, and respond to atrocities.</p>
<p>It required the State Department to provide additional training to our teams in Washington and around the world on how to spot warning signs of potential atrocities and early prevention steps to take.</p>
<p>And it mandated the annual report that we’re releasing today.</p>
<p>All this work – under both Democratic and Republican presidents, with bipartisan support from Congress – reflects our hope that, with the right tools, resources, and commitment, we can ward off atrocities before they lead to mass human suffering.</p>
<p>We want to change the story that we’ve seen play out too many times – that by the time senior policymakers are fully engaged, many people have died, the costs of taking action have risen, opportunities for early intervention have been missed.</p>
<p>I say all this with humility, as someone who has served in senior levels of government before, and has been in rooms when we grappled with what to do when political unrest somewhere in the world gave way to mass violence toward civilians.</p>
<p>This is an incredibly difficult challenge.  My friend and colleague Samantha Power described it as a “problem from hell.”  You’ll recall her groundbreaking book on the subject.  And we haven’t cracked it yet.  But we continue to believe that it’s possible, and that training, preparation, resources, cooperation – within governments and among governments – are key.  And so, of course, is determination.</p>
<p>This year, for the first time, the report provides direct, detailed accounts of atrocities taking place in specific countries, including Burma, Ethiopia, China, and Syria.  These places represent some of the toughest foreign policy challenges on our agenda, and we’ll keep working toward resolutions that reflect our commitment to human rights and democratic values.</p>
<p>We’ll use all of the tools at our disposal – including diplomacy, foreign assistance, investigations and fact-finding missions, financial tools and engagements, reports like this one which raise awareness and allow us to generate coordinated international pressure in response – in a whole-of-government approach to preventing and mitigating atrocities around the globe.</p>
<p>At our best, the United States helps bring peace and stability to places where people are suffering.  Our work on preventing atrocities represents our highest ideals in action.  And the Biden-Harris administration will build upon the work of past administrations to bring us closer to a future in which atrocities are never allowed to happen again.</p>
<p>Thanks very much.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Shaun.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thanks, Mr. Secretary.  Could I follow up on your remarks on Cuba?  I was wondering what implications this has for U.S. policy.  There’s a policy review underway.  Does this affect the timeline and when do you expect that to be finished?  Ideas like remittances, travel, things that were – that took place under Obama, are those still on the cards now after this?</p>
<p>And on that note, the president of Cuba today said that the U.S. was provoking social unrest.  Do you have any response to that?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  The policy review that you point to focuses on the political and economic well-being of the Cuban people, and obviously we’re looking carefully and closely at what has just happened, what indeed is happening.  And as we stated many times, at the heart of the review and at the heart of the policy that would result are democracy and human rights.  That’s core to our efforts.  That will be reflected in the policy.</p>
<p>I think it would be a grievous mistake for the Cuban regime to interpret what is happening in dozens of towns and cities across the island as the result or product of anything the United States has done.  It would be a grievous mistake because it would show that they simply are not hearing the voices and will of the Cuban people – people deeply, deeply, deeply tired of the repression that has gone on for far too long, tired of the mismanagement of the Cuban economy, tired of the lack of adequate food, and of course, inadequate response to the COVID pandemic.  That is what we are hearing and seeing in Cuba, and that is a reflection of the Cuban people, not of the United States or any other outside actor.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  (Off-mike.)</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  On Ethiopia, do you have an update on the assessment of whether to call events in Tigray crimes against humanity, genocide, or war crimes?</p>
<p>And if I may on Myanmar, can you update us on the review of whether genocide and crimes against humanity were committed against the Rohingya?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Yeah, appreciate it.  Look, both reviews are ongoing.  We’re bringing together the facts, the legal assessments, and both are being very actively considered.</p>
<p><b>MR PRICE:</b>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meeting of the Advisory Committee on International Postal and Delivery Services</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/meeting-of-the-advisory-committee-on-international-postal-and-delivery-services/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 20:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258559</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On July 15, 2021, the Department of State’s Advisory Committee on International Postal and Delivery Services (IPoDS) will meet to discuss U.S. positions on issues for the 27<sup>th</sup> Congress of the Universal Postal Union (UPU), currently scheduled for August 9-27 in Abidjan, Cote d’Ivoire.  Issues under consideration at the Congress include modifications to the rules of procedure to allow hybrid (i.e., mixed virtual and physically present) meetings, as well as the opening of the UPU to wider postal sector actors, reform of the system of member countries’ contributions, and interpretation of the 2019 Geneva accord on compensation for E-format items.</p>
<p>The meeting will take place virtually from 1:00 p.m. to 5:00 p.m. Eastern Time, hosted on a Webex platform, meeting number 199 494 5652, access code ddMnU572653 (33668572 from phones).</p>
<p>The public may attend this meeting.</p>
<p>For questions concerning the meeting or access to the meeting documents please contact <a href="mailto:IO-Press-DL@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IO-Press-DL@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On July 15, 2021, the Department of State’s Advisory Committee on International Postal and Delivery Services (IPoDS) will meet to discuss U.S. positions on issues for the 27<sup>th</sup> Congress of the Universal Postal Union (UPU), currently scheduled for August 9-27 in Abidjan, Cote d’Ivoire.  Issues under consideration at the Congress include modifications to the rules of procedure to allow hybrid (i.e., mixed virtual and physically present) meetings, as well as the opening of the UPU to wider postal sector actors, reform of the system of member countries’ contributions, and interpretation of the 2019 Geneva accord on compensation for E-format items.</p>
<p>The meeting will take place virtually from 1:00 p.m. to 5:00 p.m. Eastern Time, hosted on a Webex platform, meeting number 199 494 5652, access code ddMnU572653 (33668572 from phones).</p>
<p>The public may attend this meeting.</p>
<p>For questions concerning the meeting or access to the meeting documents please contact <a href="mailto:IO-Press-DL@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IO-Press-DL@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States Restricts Visas of 100 Nicaraguans Affiliated with Ortega-Murillo Regime</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-restricts-visas-of-100-nicaraguans-affiliated-with-ortega-murillo-regime/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 15:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258461</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The Department of State has imposed visa restrictions on 100 members of the Nicaraguan National Assembly and Nicaraguan judicial system, including prosecutors and judges, as well as some of their family members.  The Department has revoked any U.S. visas held by these individuals.</p>
<p>In the context of Nicaragua, the Department’s visa restriction policy applies to Nicaraguans believed to be responsible for, or complicit in, undermining democracy, including those with responsibility for, or complicity in, the suppression of peaceful protests or abuse of human rights, and the immediate family members of such persons. Specifically, those targeted in today’s action helped to enable the Ortega-Murillo regime’s attacks on democracy and human rights, including by:</p>
<ul>
<li>Arresting 26 political opponents and pro-democracy actors, including six presidential contenders, student activists, private sector leaders, and other political actors;</li>
<li>Passing repressive laws, including electoral legislation, a “cybercrimes” law, a “foreign agents” law, and a “sovereignty” law, which have all served to restrict and criminalize speech, dissent, and political participation;</li>
<li>Seeking to harass and silence civil society and independent media; and</li>
<li>Undermining democratic institutions and processes in Nicaragua.</li>
</ul>
<p>These visa revocations demonstrate that the United States will promote accountability not only for regime leaders but also for officials who enable the regime’s assaults on democracy and human rights.  The United States will continue to use the diplomatic and economic tools at our disposal to push for the release of political prisoners and to support Nicaraguans’ calls for greater freedom, accountability, and free and fair elections.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The Department of State has imposed visa restrictions on 100 members of the Nicaraguan National Assembly and Nicaraguan judicial system, including prosecutors and judges, as well as some of their family members.  The Department has revoked any U.S. visas held by these individuals.</p>
<p>In the context of Nicaragua, the Department’s visa restriction policy applies to Nicaraguans believed to be responsible for, or complicit in, undermining democracy, including those with responsibility for, or complicity in, the suppression of peaceful protests or abuse of human rights, and the immediate family members of such persons. Specifically, those targeted in today’s action helped to enable the Ortega-Murillo regime’s attacks on democracy and human rights, including by:</p>
<ul>
<li>Arresting 26 political opponents and pro-democracy actors, including six presidential contenders, student activists, private sector leaders, and other political actors;</li>
<li>Passing repressive laws, including electoral legislation, a “cybercrimes” law, a “foreign agents” law, and a “sovereignty” law, which have all served to restrict and criminalize speech, dissent, and political participation;</li>
<li>Seeking to harass and silence civil society and independent media; and</li>
<li>Undermining democratic institutions and processes in Nicaragua.</li>
</ul>
<p>These visa revocations demonstrate that the United States will promote accountability not only for regime leaders but also for officials who enable the regime’s assaults on democracy and human rights.  The United States will continue to use the diplomatic and economic tools at our disposal to push for the release of political prisoners and to support Nicaraguans’ calls for greater freedom, accountability, and free and fair elections.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fifth Anniversary of the Arbitral Tribunal Ruling on the South China Sea</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/fifth-anniversary-of-the-arbitral-tribunal-ruling-on-the-south-china-sea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Freedom of the seas is an enduring interest of all nations and is vital to global peace and prosperity.  The international community has long benefited from the rules-based maritime order, where international law, as reflected in the UN Law of the Sea Convention, sets out the legal framework for all activities in the oceans and seas.  This body of international law forms the basis for national, regional, and global action and cooperation in the maritime sector and is vital to ensuring the free flow of global commerce.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nowhere is the rules-based maritime order under greater threat than in the South China Sea.  The People’s Republic of China (PRC) continues to coerce and intimidate Southeast Asian coastal states, threatening freedom of navigation in this critical global throughway.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Five years ago, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">an Arbitral Tribunal constituted under the 1982 Law of the Sea Convention delivered a unanimous and enduring decision firmly rejecting the PRC’s expansive South China Sea maritime claims as having no basis in international law.  The Tribunal stated that the PRC has no lawful claim to the area determined by the Arbitral Tribunal to be part of the Philippines’ exclusive economic zone and continental shelf.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">  The PRC and the Philippines, pursuant to their treaty obligations under the Law of the Sea Convention, are legally bound to comply with this decision.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States reaffirms its</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://2017-2021.state.gov/u-s-position-on-maritime-claims-in-the-south-china-sea/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">July 13, 2020 policy</a> regarding maritime claims in the South China Sea.  We also reaffirm that an armed attack on Philippine armed forces, public vessels, or aircraft in the South China Sea would invoke U.S. mutual defense commitments under Article IV of the 1951 U.S.-Philippines Mutual Defense Treaty.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We call on the PRC to abide by its obligations under international law, cease its provocative behavior, and take steps to reassure the international community that it is committed to the rules-based maritime order that respects the rights of all countries, big and small.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Freedom of the seas is an enduring interest of all nations and is vital to global peace and prosperity.  The international community has long benefited from the rules-based maritime order, where international law, as reflected in the UN Law of the Sea Convention, sets out the legal framework for all activities in the oceans and seas.  This body of international law forms the basis for national, regional, and global action and cooperation in the maritime sector and is vital to ensuring the free flow of global commerce.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nowhere is the rules-based maritime order under greater threat than in the South China Sea.  The People’s Republic of China (PRC) continues to coerce and intimidate Southeast Asian coastal states, threatening freedom of navigation in this critical global throughway.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Five years ago, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">an Arbitral Tribunal constituted under the 1982 Law of the Sea Convention delivered a unanimous and enduring decision firmly rejecting the PRC’s expansive South China Sea maritime claims as having no basis in international law.  The Tribunal stated that the PRC has no lawful claim to the area determined by the Arbitral Tribunal to be part of the Philippines’ exclusive economic zone and continental shelf.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">  The PRC and the Philippines, pursuant to their treaty obligations under the Law of the Sea Convention, are legally bound to comply with this decision.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States reaffirms its</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://2017-2021.state.gov/u-s-position-on-maritime-claims-in-the-south-china-sea/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">July 13, 2020 policy</a> regarding maritime claims in the South China Sea.  We also reaffirm that an armed attack on Philippine armed forces, public vessels, or aircraft in the South China Sea would invoke U.S. mutual defense commitments under Article IV of the 1951 U.S.-Philippines Mutual Defense Treaty.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We call on the PRC to abide by its obligations under international law, cease its provocative behavior, and take steps to reassure the international community that it is committed to the rules-based maritime order that respects the rights of all countries, big and small.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken to Release the 2021 Congressional Report Pursuant to the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinken-to-release-the-2021-congressional-report-pursuant-to-the-elie-wiesel-genocide-and-atrocities-prevention-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258362</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will deliver on-camera remarks to release the 2021 Congressional Report Pursuant to the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act on Monday, July 12, 2021, at 2:00 p.m. in the Press Briefing Room at the Department of State.</p>
<p>Acting Assistant Secretary for Conflict and Stabilization Operations Robert Faucher will deliver remarks and take questions in the Briefing Room immediately following Secretary Blinken’s remarks.</p>
<p>The 2021 Elie Wiesel Act report is the third since the law’s signing on January 14, 2019.  It provides a required update on the U.S. government’s efforts to prevent and respond to atrocities based on a global assessment of ongoing atrocities and countries at risk of atrocities.  The report covers the period from July 2020 to May 2021.</p>
<p>Instructions for embargoed access to the report will be sent to members of the press on Monday, July 12, at approximately 9:30 a.m. The entire report is EMBARGOED until the start of the press briefing. The report will be available to the public on <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA1MTEuNDAyOTg3MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvIn0.Tj_X3efD_yni0O5U0RD_3Qt7Csv2bD0ekOxTl9OSTNg%2Fs%2F402704355%2Fbr%2F106213315704-l&amp;data=04%7C01%7CLaineAJ%40state.gov%7C1fd2e7c1abdb4fe8995508d943160207%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637614584065325335%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&amp;sdata=E3%2FD%2B3r9b3DzcV4AjqRCzoFI5M%2F%2FCpimj9RRxhU3kYg%3D&amp;reserved=0">www.state.gov</a> following the Secretary’s remarks.</p>
<p>This event will be pooled press coverage only and livestreamed on <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA1MTEuNDAyOTg3MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvIn0.weRHwfBYCSRy9bvqjU7Hvq4DxsjU8JBh9DoG_t0nea8%2Fs%2F402704355%2Fbr%2F106213315704-l&amp;data=04%7C01%7CLaineAJ%40state.gov%7C1fd2e7c1abdb4fe8995508d943160207%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637614584065335289%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&amp;sdata=%2BczLxYqmsGuwLYePxVwd78Df%2F4oXUkAS5zoVowryBco%3D&amp;reserved=0">www.state.gov</a>.</p>
<p>The Department Press Briefing with Spokesperson Ned Price will immediately follow this event.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact the Office of Press Relations at <a href="mailto:PAPressDuty@state.gov">PAPressDuty@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will deliver on-camera remarks to release the 2021 Congressional Report Pursuant to the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act on Monday, July 12, 2021, at 2:00 p.m. in the Press Briefing Room at the Department of State.</p>
<p>Acting Assistant Secretary for Conflict and Stabilization Operations Robert Faucher will deliver remarks and take questions in the Briefing Room immediately following Secretary Blinken’s remarks.</p>
<p>The 2021 Elie Wiesel Act report is the third since the law’s signing on January 14, 2019.  It provides a required update on the U.S. government’s efforts to prevent and respond to atrocities based on a global assessment of ongoing atrocities and countries at risk of atrocities.  The report covers the period from July 2020 to May 2021.</p>
<p>Instructions for embargoed access to the report will be sent to members of the press on Monday, July 12, at approximately 9:30 a.m. The entire report is EMBARGOED until the start of the press briefing. The report will be available to the public on <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA1MTEuNDAyOTg3MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvIn0.Tj_X3efD_yni0O5U0RD_3Qt7Csv2bD0ekOxTl9OSTNg%2Fs%2F402704355%2Fbr%2F106213315704-l&amp;data=04%7C01%7CLaineAJ%40state.gov%7C1fd2e7c1abdb4fe8995508d943160207%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637614584065325335%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&amp;sdata=E3%2FD%2B3r9b3DzcV4AjqRCzoFI5M%2F%2FCpimj9RRxhU3kYg%3D&amp;reserved=0">www.state.gov</a> following the Secretary’s remarks.</p>
<p>This event will be pooled press coverage only and livestreamed on <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Flnks.gd%2Fl%2FeyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA1MTEuNDAyOTg3MTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvIn0.weRHwfBYCSRy9bvqjU7Hvq4DxsjU8JBh9DoG_t0nea8%2Fs%2F402704355%2Fbr%2F106213315704-l&amp;data=04%7C01%7CLaineAJ%40state.gov%7C1fd2e7c1abdb4fe8995508d943160207%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637614584065335289%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&amp;sdata=%2BczLxYqmsGuwLYePxVwd78Df%2F4oXUkAS5zoVowryBco%3D&amp;reserved=0">www.state.gov</a>.</p>
<p>The Department Press Briefing with Spokesperson Ned Price will immediately follow this event.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact the Office of Press Relations at <a href="mailto:PAPressDuty@state.gov">PAPressDuty@state.gov</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Media Freedom Coalition Statement on Hong Kong’s Apple Daily</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/media-freedom-coalition-statement-on-hong-kongs-apple-daily/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 15:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The undersigned members of the Media Freedom Coalition express their strong concerns about the forced closure of the Apple Daily newspaper, and the arrest of its staff by the Hong Kong authorities. The use of the National Security Law to suppress journalism is a serious and negative step which undermines Hong Kong’s high degree of autonomy and the rights and freedoms of people in Hong Kong, as provided for in the Hong Kong Basic Law and the Sino-British Joint Declaration.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The action against Apple Daily comes against a backdrop of increased media censorship in Hong Kong, including pressure on the independence of the public broadcaster and recent legal action by the Hong Kong authorities against journalists.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are highly concerned by the possible introduction of new legislation that is intended or could risk being used to eliminate scrutiny and criticism by the media of the government’s policies and actions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Freedom of the press has been central to Hong Kong’s success and international reputation over many years.  Hong Kong and mainland Chinese authorities should fully respect and uphold this important right, in line with China’s international legal obligations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Signed by the Governments of Australia, Austria, Canada, Czech Republic, Denmark, Estonia, Finland, France, Germany, Iceland, Italy, Japan, Latvia, Lithuania, Luxembourg, Netherlands, New Zealand, Slovakia, Switzerland, United Kingdom, United States of America.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The undersigned members of the Media Freedom Coalition express their strong concerns about the forced closure of the Apple Daily newspaper, and the arrest of its staff by the Hong Kong authorities. The use of the National Security Law to suppress journalism is a serious and negative step which undermines Hong Kong’s high degree of autonomy and the rights and freedoms of people in Hong Kong, as provided for in the Hong Kong Basic Law and the Sino-British Joint Declaration.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The action against Apple Daily comes against a backdrop of increased media censorship in Hong Kong, including pressure on the independence of the public broadcaster and recent legal action by the Hong Kong authorities against journalists.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are highly concerned by the possible introduction of new legislation that is intended or could risk being used to eliminate scrutiny and criticism by the media of the government’s policies and actions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Freedom of the press has been central to Hong Kong’s success and international reputation over many years.  Hong Kong and mainland Chinese authorities should fully respect and uphold this important right, in line with China’s international legal obligations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Signed by the Governments of Australia, Austria, Canada, Czech Republic, Denmark, Estonia, Finland, France, Germany, Iceland, Italy, Japan, Latvia, Lithuania, Luxembourg, Netherlands, New Zealand, Slovakia, Switzerland, United Kingdom, United States of America.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Representative Khalilzad Travels to Qatar, Pakistan, and Uzbekistan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-representative-khalilzad-travels-to-qatar-pakistan-and-uzbekistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258316</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">U.S. Special Representative for Afghanistan Reconciliation Ambassador Zalmay Khalilzad departed for travel to South and Central Asia as well as the Middle East on July 9.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In his travel, Ambassador Khalilzad will continue to engage in determined diplomacy and the pursuit of a peace agreement between the Islamic Republic and the Taliban. As part of the United States’ ongoing support of the peace process, he will work with all parties and with regional and international stakeholders to further advance a consensus on a political settlement. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Political accommodation on the part of all sides remains urgent. The sooner the sides can agree to a negotiated settlement, the sooner Afghanistan and the region can reap the benefits of peace, including expanded regional connectivity, trade, and development.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Tashkent, Ambassador Khalilzad will participate in an international conference hosted by the Government of Uzbekistan on regional connectivity.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">U.S. Special Representative for Afghanistan Reconciliation Ambassador Zalmay Khalilzad departed for travel to South and Central Asia as well as the Middle East on July 9.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In his travel, Ambassador Khalilzad will continue to engage in determined diplomacy and the pursuit of a peace agreement between the Islamic Republic and the Taliban. As part of the United States’ ongoing support of the peace process, he will work with all parties and with regional and international stakeholders to further advance a consensus on a political settlement. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Political accommodation on the part of all sides remains urgent. The sooner the sides can agree to a negotiated settlement, the sooner Afghanistan and the region can reap the benefits of peace, including expanded regional connectivity, trade, and development.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Tashkent, Ambassador Khalilzad will participate in an international conference hosted by the Government of Uzbekistan on regional connectivity.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Bahamas Independence Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-bahamas-independence-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 04:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258293</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the Commonwealth of The Bahamas as you celebrate your independence.</p>
<p>The longstanding partnership between the United States and The Bahamas has never been stronger.  While the COVID-19 pandemic has challenged both our countries, our people have risen to that challenge.  There is still much to do, in The Bahamas and throughout the Caribbean, and the United States will remain a steadfast and reliable partner as we work together to advance our shared priorities.</p>
<p>We will stand with you as you continue to address the pandemic, as you rebuild from Hurricane Dorian, and as you work to support human rights in the region.  Efforts such as the U.S.-Caribbean Resilience Partnership, the Caribbean Energy Security Initiative, and the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative are testament to our willingness to bolster cooperation on renewable energy, regional security, and resilience to the climate crisis.</p>
<p>On the occasion of your 48th year as an independent nation, the United States and its people wish the people of The Bahamas prosperity and happiness over the year to come.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the Commonwealth of The Bahamas as you celebrate your independence.</p>
<p>The longstanding partnership between the United States and The Bahamas has never been stronger.  While the COVID-19 pandemic has challenged both our countries, our people have risen to that challenge.  There is still much to do, in The Bahamas and throughout the Caribbean, and the United States will remain a steadfast and reliable partner as we work together to advance our shared priorities.</p>
<p>We will stand with you as you continue to address the pandemic, as you rebuild from Hurricane Dorian, and as you work to support human rights in the region.  Efforts such as the U.S.-Caribbean Resilience Partnership, the Caribbean Energy Security Initiative, and the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative are testament to our willingness to bolster cooperation on renewable energy, regional security, and resilience to the climate crisis.</p>
<p>On the occasion of your 48th year as an independent nation, the United States and its people wish the people of The Bahamas prosperity and happiness over the year to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
