<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 23:41:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>U.S.-EU Joint Press Release by the EEAS and Department of State on the First U.S.-EU High-Level Dialogue on Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-eu-joint-press-release-by-the-eeas-and-department-of-state-on-the-first-u-s-eu-high-level-dialogue-on-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 23:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329924</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is the text of a joint press release by the U.S. Department of State and the European External Action Service.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The European Union and the United States held today in Washington, D.C., the first U.S.-EU High-Level Dialogue on Russia.  Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland represented the United States and European External Action Service Deputy Secretary General for Political Affairs Enrique Mora represented the European Union.  This high-level meeting follows the commitments taken at the June 2021 U.S.-EU Summit, where both sides resolved to coordinate U.S. and EU policies and actions related to Russia.  This inaugural session focused on U.S. and EU strategic objectives and policy coordination aimed at ending Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Nuland and Deputy Secretary General Mora welcomed the exceptional unity shown at the recent European Council, extraordinary NATO Leaders’ Meeting, and G7 Leaders’ Meeting.  They condemned the Kremlin’s unprovoked, unjustifiable, and barbaric war against Ukraine, also enabled by the Belarusian government.  The Russian military attacks striking civilians are causing massive loss of life and injury to civilians and must stop immediately.  They noted that the United States and the European Union will work to track reports of war crimes and will share information gathered with allies, partners, international institutions and organizations, as appropriate, and use every tool available to hold the perpetrators to account.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Nuland and Deputy Secretary General Mora welcomed the coordination between the United States and the European Union in implementing unprecedented sanctions and export control measures in response to Russia’s aggression and discussed continued close cooperation in coordination with the G7 to ensure stringent implementation of these measures.  They also discussed additional steps to isolate Russia further from the U.S. and EU economies and the international financial system to impose severe costs on Russia for its actions.</p>
<p>The two sides emphasized the necessity of consolidating international support for the government and people of Ukraine and of holding the government of Russia to account.  They welcomed the growing number of countries applying sanctions and export control measures since Russia’s invasion, including countries implementing them for the first time, and reiterated their commitment to further expanding the coalition and strengthening enforcement of these measures.  They underlined the importance of insisting that China supports an immediate end to hostilities, the establishment of humanitarian corridors, and preventing any risks of further escalation.  They also underscored that they will continue to urge China not to circumvent nor undermine sanctions against Russia, and not to provide any form of support to Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Nuland and Deputy Secretary General Mora discussed U.S. and EU efforts to increase humanitarian support to all people who have been internally displaced or forced to flee as a result of Putin’s war.  They briefed on U.S. and EU initiatives to provide coordinated political, financial, material and humanitarian support to the government and people of Ukraine.  They recognized the need to maintain high-level attention and support to the Republic of Moldova and to work together to strengthen its resilience.  They also discussed their ongoing efforts to support the democratic forces inside and outside of Belarus in defending and advancing human rights, including freedom of expression, and free and fair elections under international observation.</p>
<p>They took stock of U.S. and EU efforts to counter the Kremlin’s propaganda and disinformation and to reduce Europe’s reliance on Russian energy.  They underscored that the United States and EU stand with Russian civil society, independent journalists, and youth whose future and voices are under increasing threat within Russia and with those who have been forced to flee the country.   They also recognized continued U.S.-EU cooperation toward long-term peace, resilience, and stability in the wider region, including South Caucasus.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Nuland and Deputy Secretary General Mora decided to continue meetings in this dialogue, with the next high-level meeting to take place in late 2022.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is the text of a joint press release by the U.S. Department of State and the European External Action Service.</p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The European Union and the United States held today in Washington, D.C., the first U.S.-EU High-Level Dialogue on Russia.  Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland represented the United States and European External Action Service Deputy Secretary General for Political Affairs Enrique Mora represented the European Union.  This high-level meeting follows the commitments taken at the June 2021 U.S.-EU Summit, where both sides resolved to coordinate U.S. and EU policies and actions related to Russia.  This inaugural session focused on U.S. and EU strategic objectives and policy coordination aimed at ending Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Nuland and Deputy Secretary General Mora welcomed the exceptional unity shown at the recent European Council, extraordinary NATO Leaders’ Meeting, and G7 Leaders’ Meeting.  They condemned the Kremlin’s unprovoked, unjustifiable, and barbaric war against Ukraine, also enabled by the Belarusian government.  The Russian military attacks striking civilians are causing massive loss of life and injury to civilians and must stop immediately.  They noted that the United States and the European Union will work to track reports of war crimes and will share information gathered with allies, partners, international institutions and organizations, as appropriate, and use every tool available to hold the perpetrators to account.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Nuland and Deputy Secretary General Mora welcomed the coordination between the United States and the European Union in implementing unprecedented sanctions and export control measures in response to Russia’s aggression and discussed continued close cooperation in coordination with the G7 to ensure stringent implementation of these measures.  They also discussed additional steps to isolate Russia further from the U.S. and EU economies and the international financial system to impose severe costs on Russia for its actions.</p>
<p>The two sides emphasized the necessity of consolidating international support for the government and people of Ukraine and of holding the government of Russia to account.  They welcomed the growing number of countries applying sanctions and export control measures since Russia’s invasion, including countries implementing them for the first time, and reiterated their commitment to further expanding the coalition and strengthening enforcement of these measures.  They underlined the importance of insisting that China supports an immediate end to hostilities, the establishment of humanitarian corridors, and preventing any risks of further escalation.  They also underscored that they will continue to urge China not to circumvent nor undermine sanctions against Russia, and not to provide any form of support to Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Nuland and Deputy Secretary General Mora discussed U.S. and EU efforts to increase humanitarian support to all people who have been internally displaced or forced to flee as a result of Putin’s war.  They briefed on U.S. and EU initiatives to provide coordinated political, financial, material and humanitarian support to the government and people of Ukraine.  They recognized the need to maintain high-level attention and support to the Republic of Moldova and to work together to strengthen its resilience.  They also discussed their ongoing efforts to support the democratic forces inside and outside of Belarus in defending and advancing human rights, including freedom of expression, and free and fair elections under international observation.</p>
<p>They took stock of U.S. and EU efforts to counter the Kremlin’s propaganda and disinformation and to reduce Europe’s reliance on Russian energy.  They underscored that the United States and EU stand with Russian civil society, independent journalists, and youth whose future and voices are under increasing threat within Russia and with those who have been forced to flee the country.   They also recognized continued U.S.-EU cooperation toward long-term peace, resilience, and stability in the wider region, including South Caucasus.</p>
<p>Under Secretary Nuland and Deputy Secretary General Mora decided to continue meetings in this dialogue, with the next high-level meeting to take place in late 2022.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Algerian President Abdelmadjid Tebboune Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-algerian-president-abdelmadjid-tebboune-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 22:49:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329918</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Algiers, Algeria</p>
<p>El Mouradia Palace, Official Residence</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT TEBBOUNE:  </strong>(Via translation) Welcome, and I hope this trip will allow better rapprochement than what we already have.  Algerian-American meetings always had a certain intensity or weight – they were always good and understanding because there are so many similarities, enormous similarities among them, our liberation struggle.  The independence day for our nations is only separated by a few hours.  For you it is the fourth of July while for us it is the fifth of July.</p>
<p>American Democracy cannot be disputed by anyone: a people built on democracy.  We are trying to build our own democracy with our own values and our own history that come together, democracy being the fact that institutions are truly representative of a people.  In matters of arbitration of the United States, in all international disputes, we are with it.  We may be dreamers, but we dream of a more balanced world, of a world where freedoms are better defended.  We do our best with our means and in our environment – sometimes we are understood; sometimes we are not.</p>
<p>This is our environment: we are surrounded by countries that are not very similar to us with the exception of Tunisia.  That’s why we do have very close relations with Tunisia because we have similarities in many areas.  Otherwise, all our borders are in flames: destabilized Libya; after Libya, of course there is the entire Sahel like Chad, Burkina Faso, Mali, Niger; and even Mauritania is not that strong.  And next door we have the Moroccan Kingdom where our relations have always witnessed ups and downs since our independence.  It is not recent; it is not due to the Western Sahara issue.</p>
<p>There are two mindsets, two ways of seeing things.  We respect all people – we respect people’s borders while they can expand.  You know that no one has forgotten, no Algerian will forget, that Morocco attacked us in 1963.  At that time we didn’t have even a regular army, and they attacked with special forces, helicopters, and airplanes.  We had 850 casualties.  They aimed to take a part of our territory.  Later on they refused to acknowledge the independence of Mauritania since 1960, when Mauritania was a member of the United Nations and had its own ambassadors, et cetera.  But Morocco had territorial claims over all Mauritania.  They had to wait until 1972 when the Moroccan king accepted to shake hands with the Mauritanian president whom he recognized after 12 years of independence.</p>
<p>During those 12 years, the Moroccan Government had a minister of Mauritanian territories.  Afterwards was the famous story of the Western Sahara.  What they said is completely in contradiction with what they signed.  Maybe our mistake is the consistency in managing this question, even before 1975.  But with the tensions that exist between us, we are not what they say.  We definitely have no intentions in Western Sahara.  It is their problem.  They always wanted to destabilize Algeria.  There are other issues – they always wanted to destabilize Algeria and I don’t know the reason for that, although we have always protected Morocco.  We have never been careful about our relationships – however, it is not normal that within 50 years of independence the borders stay closed for 40 years.</p>
<p>The Western Sahara issue started in 1975 and afterwards.  I think that the foreign minister has many documents, signed by the King of Morocco Hassan II – may his soul rest in peace – who insisted on the self-determination of the Western Sahara.  Our position is towards Western Sahara – not towards Morocco – and everyone knows that this has always been our approach – like towards Timor-Leste, for example, we ended up convincing our Indonesian friends with whom we have a strong relationship that they had to release Timor-Leste and grant them independence, and we remained very close despite that.  Same situation with the Comoros Islands.</p>
<p>All the Algerian diplomatic efforts were made to destroy apartheid.  We also took advantage of our presidency of the UN General Assembly to exclude South Africa from all the international organizations.  When Nelson Mandela was released from prison and apartheid fell, Algeria created a strong alliance between Pretoria and Algiers.  So this is not new for us.  This is not about Western Sahara only – this has always been our position approach.</p>
<p>We have always treated the Western Sahara issue and the Palestinian issue equally.  Regarding the Palestinian issue, the Algerian position remains unchanged.  A decision has been taken at the Arab League to make peace with Israel, and that Israel recognizes the state of Palestine, and this is what we are following at the moment.  So it’s peace among all territories, but we have nothing against them – the only problem that we have is Palestine and absolutely nothing else.</p>
<p>Here are some points about Libya.  We’re against the presence of all mercenaries, whoever they are.  We don’t accept them anywhere near our borders.  We did everything so our Libyan brothers and sisters would have the chance to express themselves, and it’s been two years now that we’ve been battling for these elections in Libya, because we came to the conclusion that the ones who have been elected represent no one.  Every time there is an election, they only represent themselves.  So we do it again and again and again until the last circle between Dabaiba and the one who have been named by the so-called National Assembly, and it will continue.  It will continue because none of them are representatives.</p>
<p>The worst part is that in Libya there are forces who are getting into wars by proxy, and when we’re facing such strong adversaries, it’s not up to Libyans to kick them out.  When I met with Libya in Berlin, we agreed that all countries involved in the Libyan case should agree on never let either guns or mercenaries inside the country.  We should disarm them.  Two months later there was 3,000 tons of arms, which means that the solution is elsewhere.  In my view, it can be through the UN.</p>
<p>We have the presence of Wagner, the presence of Syrians who are our brothers and sisters, Turkish people, people from Sudan, the mobilized from Chad, and there are three or four countries getting into war in Libya, a war that is not the Libyans’ and has nothing to do with them.  That’s why we said that if Libya wants to be built again democratically, we need elections from scratch.  We can help them organize it.  What I am saying is very feasible – we only need the political will to do it.  We will end up with an elected assembly, and then everybody can help rebuilding Libya with an assembly, the government, and the president.  Those who have hidden agendas to replace the late former president are the ones who would like to solve the issue from the top by designating a president.  Elect a president so that he can do what he wants and move towards this or that.  This is not democracy.  That’s for the Libyan problem.</p>
<p>For the Chadian problem, Chad has been used for three decades and it is not recent.  They were used by the Libyans.  Today they have created forces capable of fighting and capable of destabilizing, which makes Nigeria very fragile, and even more fragile Burkina Faso and Mali.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, I would like to speak to you with an open heart.  I could never understand how we arrived at this situation.  It all added up with the fall of Libya and the flow of weapons into the Sahel.  Everyone could see what happened.  No one stopped it until there was Barkhane to prevent Bamako from being taken by terrorists.  I can talk about the Malian problem because it is the problem that is the closest to us, close even since our independence in 1962.  We have never stopped interceding and intervening between the Malian tribes, as it is our border residents.  There are a lot of Malians who have Algerian origin, and there are a lot of Algerians who have Malian origins, which means that we intervene every time to calm the tribal quarrels, from Modibo Keita until today.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, there was a lot of interference, which did not allow us to act as you arrive at the Algiers agreements which settled the self-contradictory problems between northern Mali and southern Mali.  There was interference and we could not implement it, and it has not yet been implemented, and they are doing everything so that it will never be implemented.  They are changing the data.  All the signatories have come to Algiers so far, and they are in contact with Algiers, and they are keen on the implementation of this agreement which is not the opinion of the current Malian prime minister, appointed by the people, who does not recognize it.  He is even against it, he says and writes, and this is where we are at.</p>
<p>There were misunderstandings with our French friends, and we never wanted to intervene.  There is mutual aid in the field of security, and we have always said that force aims to establish peace not to seek peace – once peace has returned it must be reinforced with force, but in the meantime we must look elsewhere.  A military presence in such a large Sahara and with this multiplicity of ethnic problems can only be used as an air call for terrorism in one form or another.  We also suffered what we have suffered.  They took our diplomats away from us and killed two of them.  We don’t even know where they are buried.  This is the price we have paid and we continue to pay for Mali and for the unification of Mali, and there is certainty that will never change for us.  It is the territorial unity of Mali, the people of Mali.  We will try to ensure that we come back with more understanding of this problem.</p>
<p>This is not a problem of geopolitical powers.  What we want is that our borders be calm and what we spend currently to protect our borders, we would like to use for the development of our youth and for the development of our territory.  We don’t need that many weapons and this is meant to defend ourselves.  We have a defensive military theory.  We have never had a theory of attack or of going elsewhere.</p>
<p>On top of this, we have to deal with our domestic problems.  During my presidential campaign I was very clear.  It is rare that a candidate for the presidential election spells out his platform, and I am committed to what I wrote.  We say that promises are only valid for those who believe in them – I wrote them, and we are pursuing them.  It’s a very young country, and I have worked – and I will continue to work – until the end of my term to empower more youth, to hand over power to the youth.  I eliminated everything distorting the elections at home, money, cheating et cetera.</p>
<p>The elections that we had, including the presidential elections, legislative and local ones, we gained one thing.  For the first time, opposition or not, no one said that the election was rigged.  This is already a big benefit for a third-world country.  So we could introduce a lot of youth into the local assembly so that they learn how to legislate and how politics works.  We are doing it and we also did it for local elections – we encouraged a lot of youth to run for the management of local collectivities and wilaya assemblies.</p>
<p>We have set up the civil society observatory.  We have been talking about it for four decades now.  It is there; it has even been constitutionalized.  We are in full preparations for the national council and the youth superior council, which will practically be a youth parliament to discuss  what concerns them.  On the economic plan, we fight with all the necessary energy against corruption and everything dirtying our country and which has diverted the country’s money, whereas it could have moved towards the people and towards the development of this country.  We continue to fight like that.</p>
<p>In terms of investment we are preparing maybe for having the investment code in maybe a month or a month and a half.  I have given instructions that this code will be valid for 10 years.  For 10 years we will not have the right to touch a comma, to free up foreign investment and even domestic investment as much as possible.  Put all the necessary barriers so that we move away definitely of everything that was done by the oligarchy who left, which linked to the Russian mafia, Italian mafia, and every mafia.  They embezzled all the money from the country; we try to benefit the youth.</p>
<p>The vision is that this young country must be supported by young people both politically and economically, and that is why we favor startups, and we have a very young minister who is 26 years old and is in charge of startups and doing a great job.  We can feel that there is a movement of startups among young people and younger persons.  We are here for the small and micro companies, and we are investing in them more than ever.  We are very credible because we have financial resources to transfer donations for companies.  It doesn’t bother us at all.</p>
<p>The economic management of the country that we are trying to strengthen daily today in Africa and the whole Maghreb – we are the only county that is dynamic in fighting against corruption, and we take responsibility in every political action.  We are the only country that is  going to have a big project structuring the country.  The first project is agricultural.  With a very vast country we can help Africa in terms of providing grains.  We can do it.  It is technically feasible to achieve production of 30 million tons.  We need 9 million tons and can export 21 million tons to Morocco, Tunisia, and Egypt without facing any issues.</p>
<p>In terms of cattle, we are facing a deficiency when it comes to milk material.  We are importing milk powder and we reproduce it here mixed with water.  In terms of transport, currently we are establishing an Algerian naval and air fleet.  Until now we are having the half of terrestre that we can not access.  We need to have access everywhere now.</p>
<p>In terms of railway transport, it is one of the basis of my programs to have an Algerian port to transport shipments by railways to Mali and Niger.  We have worked on this with our own mains.  Currently we are in Béchar having a railways, and it is located in 500 kilometers away from Algiers in the southeast.  And we still have to each Adrar – approximately 500 to 600 kilometers from Adrar.  We will go straight to Mali from Bordj Bardji Mokhtar.</p>
<p>There is a company named Mer Nijer that will link Béchar by train, then Mali and Niger by trucks.  Generally, it is successful, and Algeria can make an impact.</p>
<p>The floor is all yours.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>(Via translation) Mr. President, thank you for this detailed and interesting conversation.  I had the chance to meet with my friend the minister, and I’m glad to be back to Algeria to strengthen the ties between our countries by working on security and common economic opportunities such as investments and trades between the countries.  I believe it will make progress in investing thanks to young businesspeople that need to be built up.</p>
<p>(In English) But in any event, it is wonderful to be back in Algeria after last being here in 2016.  Thank you for sharing this wonderful tour of the region, the world, and our relationship.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Algiers, Algeria</p>
<p>El Mouradia Palace, Official Residence</p>
<p><strong>PRESIDENT TEBBOUNE:  </strong>(Via translation) Welcome, and I hope this trip will allow better rapprochement than what we already have.  Algerian-American meetings always had a certain intensity or weight – they were always good and understanding because there are so many similarities, enormous similarities among them, our liberation struggle.  The independence day for our nations is only separated by a few hours.  For you it is the fourth of July while for us it is the fifth of July.</p>
<p>American Democracy cannot be disputed by anyone: a people built on democracy.  We are trying to build our own democracy with our own values and our own history that come together, democracy being the fact that institutions are truly representative of a people.  In matters of arbitration of the United States, in all international disputes, we are with it.  We may be dreamers, but we dream of a more balanced world, of a world where freedoms are better defended.  We do our best with our means and in our environment – sometimes we are understood; sometimes we are not.</p>
<p>This is our environment: we are surrounded by countries that are not very similar to us with the exception of Tunisia.  That’s why we do have very close relations with Tunisia because we have similarities in many areas.  Otherwise, all our borders are in flames: destabilized Libya; after Libya, of course there is the entire Sahel like Chad, Burkina Faso, Mali, Niger; and even Mauritania is not that strong.  And next door we have the Moroccan Kingdom where our relations have always witnessed ups and downs since our independence.  It is not recent; it is not due to the Western Sahara issue.</p>
<p>There are two mindsets, two ways of seeing things.  We respect all people – we respect people’s borders while they can expand.  You know that no one has forgotten, no Algerian will forget, that Morocco attacked us in 1963.  At that time we didn’t have even a regular army, and they attacked with special forces, helicopters, and airplanes.  We had 850 casualties.  They aimed to take a part of our territory.  Later on they refused to acknowledge the independence of Mauritania since 1960, when Mauritania was a member of the United Nations and had its own ambassadors, et cetera.  But Morocco had territorial claims over all Mauritania.  They had to wait until 1972 when the Moroccan king accepted to shake hands with the Mauritanian president whom he recognized after 12 years of independence.</p>
<p>During those 12 years, the Moroccan Government had a minister of Mauritanian territories.  Afterwards was the famous story of the Western Sahara.  What they said is completely in contradiction with what they signed.  Maybe our mistake is the consistency in managing this question, even before 1975.  But with the tensions that exist between us, we are not what they say.  We definitely have no intentions in Western Sahara.  It is their problem.  They always wanted to destabilize Algeria.  There are other issues – they always wanted to destabilize Algeria and I don’t know the reason for that, although we have always protected Morocco.  We have never been careful about our relationships – however, it is not normal that within 50 years of independence the borders stay closed for 40 years.</p>
<p>The Western Sahara issue started in 1975 and afterwards.  I think that the foreign minister has many documents, signed by the King of Morocco Hassan II – may his soul rest in peace – who insisted on the self-determination of the Western Sahara.  Our position is towards Western Sahara – not towards Morocco – and everyone knows that this has always been our approach – like towards Timor-Leste, for example, we ended up convincing our Indonesian friends with whom we have a strong relationship that they had to release Timor-Leste and grant them independence, and we remained very close despite that.  Same situation with the Comoros Islands.</p>
<p>All the Algerian diplomatic efforts were made to destroy apartheid.  We also took advantage of our presidency of the UN General Assembly to exclude South Africa from all the international organizations.  When Nelson Mandela was released from prison and apartheid fell, Algeria created a strong alliance between Pretoria and Algiers.  So this is not new for us.  This is not about Western Sahara only – this has always been our position approach.</p>
<p>We have always treated the Western Sahara issue and the Palestinian issue equally.  Regarding the Palestinian issue, the Algerian position remains unchanged.  A decision has been taken at the Arab League to make peace with Israel, and that Israel recognizes the state of Palestine, and this is what we are following at the moment.  So it’s peace among all territories, but we have nothing against them – the only problem that we have is Palestine and absolutely nothing else.</p>
<p>Here are some points about Libya.  We’re against the presence of all mercenaries, whoever they are.  We don’t accept them anywhere near our borders.  We did everything so our Libyan brothers and sisters would have the chance to express themselves, and it’s been two years now that we’ve been battling for these elections in Libya, because we came to the conclusion that the ones who have been elected represent no one.  Every time there is an election, they only represent themselves.  So we do it again and again and again until the last circle between Dabaiba and the one who have been named by the so-called National Assembly, and it will continue.  It will continue because none of them are representatives.</p>
<p>The worst part is that in Libya there are forces who are getting into wars by proxy, and when we’re facing such strong adversaries, it’s not up to Libyans to kick them out.  When I met with Libya in Berlin, we agreed that all countries involved in the Libyan case should agree on never let either guns or mercenaries inside the country.  We should disarm them.  Two months later there was 3,000 tons of arms, which means that the solution is elsewhere.  In my view, it can be through the UN.</p>
<p>We have the presence of Wagner, the presence of Syrians who are our brothers and sisters, Turkish people, people from Sudan, the mobilized from Chad, and there are three or four countries getting into war in Libya, a war that is not the Libyans’ and has nothing to do with them.  That’s why we said that if Libya wants to be built again democratically, we need elections from scratch.  We can help them organize it.  What I am saying is very feasible – we only need the political will to do it.  We will end up with an elected assembly, and then everybody can help rebuilding Libya with an assembly, the government, and the president.  Those who have hidden agendas to replace the late former president are the ones who would like to solve the issue from the top by designating a president.  Elect a president so that he can do what he wants and move towards this or that.  This is not democracy.  That’s for the Libyan problem.</p>
<p>For the Chadian problem, Chad has been used for three decades and it is not recent.  They were used by the Libyans.  Today they have created forces capable of fighting and capable of destabilizing, which makes Nigeria very fragile, and even more fragile Burkina Faso and Mali.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, I would like to speak to you with an open heart.  I could never understand how we arrived at this situation.  It all added up with the fall of Libya and the flow of weapons into the Sahel.  Everyone could see what happened.  No one stopped it until there was Barkhane to prevent Bamako from being taken by terrorists.  I can talk about the Malian problem because it is the problem that is the closest to us, close even since our independence in 1962.  We have never stopped interceding and intervening between the Malian tribes, as it is our border residents.  There are a lot of Malians who have Algerian origin, and there are a lot of Algerians who have Malian origins, which means that we intervene every time to calm the tribal quarrels, from Modibo Keita until today.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, there was a lot of interference, which did not allow us to act as you arrive at the Algiers agreements which settled the self-contradictory problems between northern Mali and southern Mali.  There was interference and we could not implement it, and it has not yet been implemented, and they are doing everything so that it will never be implemented.  They are changing the data.  All the signatories have come to Algiers so far, and they are in contact with Algiers, and they are keen on the implementation of this agreement which is not the opinion of the current Malian prime minister, appointed by the people, who does not recognize it.  He is even against it, he says and writes, and this is where we are at.</p>
<p>There were misunderstandings with our French friends, and we never wanted to intervene.  There is mutual aid in the field of security, and we have always said that force aims to establish peace not to seek peace – once peace has returned it must be reinforced with force, but in the meantime we must look elsewhere.  A military presence in such a large Sahara and with this multiplicity of ethnic problems can only be used as an air call for terrorism in one form or another.  We also suffered what we have suffered.  They took our diplomats away from us and killed two of them.  We don’t even know where they are buried.  This is the price we have paid and we continue to pay for Mali and for the unification of Mali, and there is certainty that will never change for us.  It is the territorial unity of Mali, the people of Mali.  We will try to ensure that we come back with more understanding of this problem.</p>
<p>This is not a problem of geopolitical powers.  What we want is that our borders be calm and what we spend currently to protect our borders, we would like to use for the development of our youth and for the development of our territory.  We don’t need that many weapons and this is meant to defend ourselves.  We have a defensive military theory.  We have never had a theory of attack or of going elsewhere.</p>
<p>On top of this, we have to deal with our domestic problems.  During my presidential campaign I was very clear.  It is rare that a candidate for the presidential election spells out his platform, and I am committed to what I wrote.  We say that promises are only valid for those who believe in them – I wrote them, and we are pursuing them.  It’s a very young country, and I have worked – and I will continue to work – until the end of my term to empower more youth, to hand over power to the youth.  I eliminated everything distorting the elections at home, money, cheating et cetera.</p>
<p>The elections that we had, including the presidential elections, legislative and local ones, we gained one thing.  For the first time, opposition or not, no one said that the election was rigged.  This is already a big benefit for a third-world country.  So we could introduce a lot of youth into the local assembly so that they learn how to legislate and how politics works.  We are doing it and we also did it for local elections – we encouraged a lot of youth to run for the management of local collectivities and wilaya assemblies.</p>
<p>We have set up the civil society observatory.  We have been talking about it for four decades now.  It is there; it has even been constitutionalized.  We are in full preparations for the national council and the youth superior council, which will practically be a youth parliament to discuss  what concerns them.  On the economic plan, we fight with all the necessary energy against corruption and everything dirtying our country and which has diverted the country’s money, whereas it could have moved towards the people and towards the development of this country.  We continue to fight like that.</p>
<p>In terms of investment we are preparing maybe for having the investment code in maybe a month or a month and a half.  I have given instructions that this code will be valid for 10 years.  For 10 years we will not have the right to touch a comma, to free up foreign investment and even domestic investment as much as possible.  Put all the necessary barriers so that we move away definitely of everything that was done by the oligarchy who left, which linked to the Russian mafia, Italian mafia, and every mafia.  They embezzled all the money from the country; we try to benefit the youth.</p>
<p>The vision is that this young country must be supported by young people both politically and economically, and that is why we favor startups, and we have a very young minister who is 26 years old and is in charge of startups and doing a great job.  We can feel that there is a movement of startups among young people and younger persons.  We are here for the small and micro companies, and we are investing in them more than ever.  We are very credible because we have financial resources to transfer donations for companies.  It doesn’t bother us at all.</p>
<p>The economic management of the country that we are trying to strengthen daily today in Africa and the whole Maghreb – we are the only county that is dynamic in fighting against corruption, and we take responsibility in every political action.  We are the only country that is  going to have a big project structuring the country.  The first project is agricultural.  With a very vast country we can help Africa in terms of providing grains.  We can do it.  It is technically feasible to achieve production of 30 million tons.  We need 9 million tons and can export 21 million tons to Morocco, Tunisia, and Egypt without facing any issues.</p>
<p>In terms of cattle, we are facing a deficiency when it comes to milk material.  We are importing milk powder and we reproduce it here mixed with water.  In terms of transport, currently we are establishing an Algerian naval and air fleet.  Until now we are having the half of terrestre that we can not access.  We need to have access everywhere now.</p>
<p>In terms of railway transport, it is one of the basis of my programs to have an Algerian port to transport shipments by railways to Mali and Niger.  We have worked on this with our own mains.  Currently we are in Béchar having a railways, and it is located in 500 kilometers away from Algiers in the southeast.  And we still have to each Adrar – approximately 500 to 600 kilometers from Adrar.  We will go straight to Mali from Bordj Bardji Mokhtar.</p>
<p>There is a company named Mer Nijer that will link Béchar by train, then Mali and Niger by trucks.  Generally, it is successful, and Algeria can make an impact.</p>
<p>The floor is all yours.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>(Via translation) Mr. President, thank you for this detailed and interesting conversation.  I had the chance to meet with my friend the minister, and I’m glad to be back to Algeria to strengthen the ties between our countries by working on security and common economic opportunities such as investments and trades between the countries.  I believe it will make progress in investing thanks to young businesspeople that need to be built up.</p>
<p>(In English) But in any event, it is wonderful to be back in Algeria after last being here in 2016.  Thank you for sharing this wonderful tour of the region, the world, and our relationship.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate Kerry’s Travel to Mexico</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-presidential-envoy-for-climate-kerrys-travel-to-mexico-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 21:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329873</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Mexico City March 31 to continue ongoing engagement to accelerate cooperation in tackling the climate crisis. Secretary Kerry will meet with President Andrés Manuel López Obrador, other government officials, and members of the U.S. business community.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:ClimateComms@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ClimateComms@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Mexico City March 31 to continue ongoing engagement to accelerate cooperation in tackling the climate crisis. Secretary Kerry will meet with President Andrés Manuel López Obrador, other government officials, and members of the U.S. business community.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:ClimateComms@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ClimateComms@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary Medina’s Travel to Houston, Texas</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-medinas-travel-to-houston-texas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 20:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329830</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica P. Medina will travel to Houston, Texas, from March 31 to April 1, to participate in discussions on protecting our ocean and fighting plastic pollution at the 31st Annual Conference of the Society of Environmental Journalists (SEJ).  These discussions will set the stage for the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> which the United States will co-host with Palau in Koror, April 13-14.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">OES-PA-DG@state.gov.</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica P. Medina will travel to Houston, Texas, from March 31 to April 1, to participate in discussions on protecting our ocean and fighting plastic pollution at the 31st Annual Conference of the Society of Environmental Journalists (SEJ).  These discussions will set the stage for the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> which the United States will co-host with Palau in Koror, April 13-14.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">OES-PA-DG@state.gov.</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary of State Blinken’s Call with Indian External Affairs Minister Jaishankar</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-of-state-blinkens-call-with-indian-external-affairs-minister-jaishankar/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 19:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony Blinken spoke with Indian External Affairs Minister Dr. Subrahmanyam Jaishankar today to review regional priorities, including the worsening humanitarian situation in Ukraine and our shared efforts to promote a free, open, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific, in which the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states is respected.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony Blinken spoke with Indian External Affairs Minister Dr. Subrahmanyam Jaishankar today to review regional priorities, including the worsening humanitarian situation in Ukraine and our shared efforts to promote a free, open, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific, in which the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states is respected.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at a Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-press-availability-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 18:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329717</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Algiers, Algeria</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy Algiers</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone.  I’d like to begin by announcing another five stops on this trip.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Not funny.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yeah.  (Laughter.)  In all seriousness, I am very glad to be back in Algeria.  I visited in 2016 when I was the deputy secretary, but this is the first trip that I’m making here as Secretary.  If you’ve noticed over the last weeks, every country in the Maghreb has hosted at least one high-ranking American official, and I think that is a signal, among others, of the importance that we place on these relationships and on the region.</p>
<p>Let me just take a moment as I start to recognize our relatively new ambassador here, Elizabeth Aubin, who arrived last month.  Ambassador Aubin is very uniquely suited for this role.  She previously served as the deputy chief of mission here, and three decades of experience in the Foreign Service.  She is truly the best of our department.  We’re grateful to have you here.</p>
<p>So over the course of this trip, we have visited Israel, the West Bank, Morocco, now Algeria.  And at every stop, we dealt with critical security issues, urgent regional and global challenges, and a shared desire to create more opportunities for our people.</p>
<p>Here in Algeria, the ties between our countries go back a long time – 1795, at a time when most of the world still didn’t recognize our then-young country.  And Hassan Bashaw Dey, who ruled what was then called the Deylik of Algiers, signed a treaty of peace with our first president, George Washington.  Since then, Algerians and Americans have developed our economic, educational, cultural connections, and our countries work closely together on issues that matter to the security and well-being of our people, and many others.</p>
<p>As I said today to President Tebboune and Foreign Minister Lamamra, Algeria’s efforts are critical to improving regional security and stability.  That includes its counterterrorism expertise, the humanitarian and security assistance that it provides to neighbors in the Sahel, its demonstrated leadership in finding regional and African-led solutions to challenges.</p>
<p>On Libya, Algeria has been a critical voice in international efforts to advance the UN political process and promote Libyan elections as quickly as possible.  And as the broker of the Algiers Accords, Algeria continues to play an important role in Mali, where we both support a return to democratic rule.</p>
<p>Algeria has also emerged in the region as a leader in preserving cultural heritage sites, which terrorists and organized crime groups have increasingly looted to finance their illicit activities.  Last year we joined Algeria in bringing together government officials, archaeologists, cultural site managers from Algeria, Libya, Tunisia, and Egypt, to discuss how to keep these sites secure and successfully prosecute looters of cultural property.</p>
<p>On the matter of Western Sahara, the United States supports the work of the UN personal envoy of the secretary general, Staffan de Mistura, in leading the political process under the auspices of the United Nations to promote a peaceful and prosperous future for the people living there.</p>
<p>I also reaffirmed to the president and the foreign minister the importance of concrete progress on human rights, including freedom of religion for all faiths, freedom of expression, especially political speech.</p>
<p>And we talked about ways to build on our robust trade and investment ties.  American companies here are helping to diversify Algeria’s economy – training local employees, sharing knowledge, building long-term partnerships that are of benefit to both of our countries.  I spoke to a number of those businesses today – I think some of you were there – in advance of the Algiers International Trade Fair that’ll take place this summer, the largest in Africa, where the United States is proud to be the country of honor.</p>
<p>Algeria and the United States have worked together to beat back the COVID-19 pandemic.  We’ve donated more than 600,000 vaccine doses to Algeria as well as a 35-bed state-of-the-art field hospital, and a second donated field hospital will be up and running in the coming months.</p>
<p>Likewise, Algeria has been there for its neighbors.  When COVID disrupted tourism and other vital trades in Tunisia, Algeria provided critical financial support and donated more than 250,000 vaccine doses.</p>
<p>Now, as you all know, I came on here to this region after a trip to Brussels with – and Poland with President Biden, where we saw the extraordinary unity and determination among allies and partners to stand with the Ukrainian people and bring an end to Russia’s unjust and brutal war in Ukraine.  The countries of North Africa and the Middle East have experienced themselves the consequences of Russian military campaigns before – for example, in Syria and Libya, where Russian military and paramilitary forces exploited conflicts for Moscow’s gain, with deadly consequences for citizens and communities.</p>
<p>Now, many in this region are feeling the pain of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine in another way, with rising food prices, especially wheat.  Farmers in Ukraine, instead of tending to their crops, have been forced to either fight for their country’s future and independence, or to flee.  Ships with grain are not getting out from Black Sea ports because they’re blocked by Russia’s aggression.  Countries around the world, including North Africa and the Middle East, import significant amounts of wheat from Ukraine, and of course, when food prices rise, so do the numbers of people suffering from hunger.  This is just one more reason why the international community must increase the pressure on Russia to end this unprovoked and unjustified war.</p>
<p>So let me conclude simply by saying thank you to our colleagues in Algeria for hosting us today, and <em>Ramadan Kareem</em> to all of those who will soon celebrate the Ramadan.</p>
<p>With that, I will happily take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll start with Matt Lee of the AP, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, (inaudible).  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, how are you?  Hi.  Thank you.  Are you at all concerned with Algeria’s relationship – Algeria in particular and its relationship with Russia?  And should – do you think that it should be doing more to re-evaluate its ties with the Russians?</p>
<p>And also, given where you’ve been so far on this portion of the trip, the Middle East and North Africa, and what you attended, what you participated in on Monday, are you concerned at all, especially given the president’s comments to you a little bit earlier, that Algeria is in danger of missing out on the kind of benefits, the kind of changes that you’ve talked – you and others have talked about in terms of the region?</p>
<p>And then if I could just ask one last thing on Ukraine and Russia, and that is there are officials in Washington who are saying that the U.S. believes that President Putin has been misled by his top military advisors.  Is this something that is shared administration-wide, or at least by you?  Do you believe that to be the case?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> Thanks, Matt.  So on the first part of the question, look, I think it’s a reality that different countries have different historical relationships with Russia.  But there are times when one issue emerges that is so clearly black and white, and in this case of Ukraine a clear aggressor and a clear victim, that it’s important to stand with the victim and to stand for the principles that have also been violated, principles that should matter to countries around the world, principles about sovereignty, about independence.  And I know that that’s something that Algerians feel strongly about, given their own history.</p>
<p>And I think countries in the region as well have seen the damaging effects of Russia’s military campaigns before.  I alluded to that a moment ago.  In Syria and Libya, as I mentioned, the Russian military and paramilitary forces have exploited conflicts for Moscow’s gain.  And that in turn has actually posed great threats to security in the region and stability and commerce.  And as I mentioned as well, these actions have had deadly consequences for citizens in the region.  They’ve disrupted the peace and prosperity of communities.  They’ve intruded into the lives of families and individuals who are simply trying to live peacefully in their own countries.</p>
<p>And then again, I think the impact that’s being felt, even if what seems very distant as a conflict to people in this region because it is half a world away or almost half a world away in Europe, it’s having a direct impact on their lives right now, particularly with regard to rising food prices, something that everyone is feeling, especially wheat.  So my sense from having talked to a lot of colleagues over the last days is that a lot of this pain is keenly felt in this region.  Most of the countries import half their wheat or more.  And so we see them taking stock of that, and that’s factoring into their thinking.</p>
<p>But mostly, I think you’re seeing that countries understand that what’s happening in Ukraine matters, of course, first and foremost to the people in Ukraine.  But it also matters to them because, as I said, principles that matter to them – the UN charter, sovereignty, independence – are also the victims of aggression.</p>
<p>With regard to the Negev and the countries participating in the normalization process with Israel, look, these are decisions for countries to make.  They have to decide what’s in the best interests of their own people.  I think what we’re trying to show through the countries that are participating in the Negev process, since we’re now giving it that name, is that this is going to have real, practical benefits for the people in the countries participating in that effort who have normalized their relations with Israel.</p>
<p>And we’re seeing that take life in terms of connections that have grown very rapidly between people, between businesses, between students, tourists; all of that, even with COVID, has gone up dramatically.  At the same time, what we’re doing as governments is looking at how we can work together to make the kinds of investments in infrastructure, in global health, in science, in dealing with climate, that are going to have real benefits for people.  My bet is that as other countries that are not part of that process see this take shape, they will conclude that this is something they want to be a part of.  And that’ll happen at different paces for different countries.  But, of course, it’s on us to demonstrate that it really works and that it produces results.  I believe that it will.</p>
<p>And finally, with regard to President Putin, look, what I can tell you is this, and I said this before:  One of the Achilles heels of autocracies is that you don’t have people in those systems who speak truth to power or who have the ability to speak truth to power.  And I think that is something that we’re seeing in Russia.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We’ll turn to Abderrahim Kachour.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary of State.  United States is adopting an advance position against Russian military aggression in Ukraine based on the principle of violence against international law.  But the same thing is happening in Palestine, in (inaudible), as well in Western Sahara.  But United States didn’t show the same fairness, the same resolve, as that one in Ukraine.  And in the same context, is Biden administration still adopting the proclamation of the ex-President Donald Trump recognizing Moroccan sovereignty over the Western Sahara?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>  Thank you very much.  When President Biden took office, we and he made two principal commitments in terms of our foreign policy and how we would engage the world.  We made a commitment to re-engage with partners – and international institutions and organizations – and we made a commitment to lead with diplomacy, and that’s what we’ve done.  Part of that means that when the basic rules of diplomacy and the international system that are necessary to try to keep peace and security are being violated, we will stand up with other countries to defend them.  And that’s what we’re doing.  That’s what we’re doing in the case of this aggression.  But the centrality of diplomacy to this effort is critical.</p>
<p>And so when it comes to Israel and the Palestinians, we have remained very engaged with our diplomacy to try and advance prospects for getting back to a two-state solution, to negotiating that, and in the meantime doing everything that we can to help the Palestinian people improve their lives.  We’ve committed half a billion dollars in assistance to the Palestinians over the last year.  We’ve re-engaged with UNRWA.  And, of course, I was just up in Ramallah.  And by the way, we were talking about the Negev Summit and the countries participating in that – one of the things that we spent some time talking about is how we could use that grouping of countries to focus on helping Palestinians improve their lives.  And we also made clear – and I certainly made clear – that as committed as we are to supporting normalization and to having more countries join in, that is not a substitute for dealing with the conflict between Israelis and Palestinians, and not a substitute for two states.</p>
<p>Similarly, with regard to Western Sahara, we’re very focused on diplomacy and on advancing a resolution through diplomacy, including through the efforts of Staffan de Mistura, the envoy from the United Nations.</p>
<p>So I think these things are very consistent.  In each case, we are working through diplomacy, working with other countries to uphold the basic principles of the international system.  And again, on Morocco, on Western Sahara, we are continuing to support the efforts of the UN.  There’s been no change in our position otherwise.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Peter Martin of Bloomberg.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, thank you.   Yesterday you met with Crown Prince Mohammed bin Zayed.  Did you ask him to increase oil production to help bring down gas prices?  And did you offer any specific assurances about the UAE’s security?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thanks.  Well, first, let me just say we had what I thought was an excellent and lengthy discussion.  And we always benefit, and I certainly always benefit, from getting the crown prince’s perspective.  And we had what I thought was a very meaningful, heartfelt exchange that covered really the breadth of our partnership and did it in a strategic way as well as a specific way.</p>
<p>One of the things I made very clear to him is the value that we attach to that partnership, and that we are a true partner for the UAE.  The UAE has been with us around the world, including in Afghanistan, fighting side by side.  In fact, the crown prince had some of his sons in attendance who had fought with us, and one indeed who was injured.  That’s a very powerful thing.  And we’ll continue to stand by them.</p>
<p>One of the things I told them was that the United States remains committed to helping the UAE defend itself against threats from Yemen, from the Houthis, even as we work to try to bring that conflict to a close.  In fact, we have our Special Envoy Tim Lenderking in the region as we speak, and we very much welcome the UAE support for a truce that could lead to a ceasefire.  I also took the opportunity to commend the crown prince for his vision, his courage, his leadership in normalizing ties with Israel, and we talked about the opportunities that can bring for all of our people.</p>
<p>We had a very constructive discussion as well about the war in Ukraine and the Russian aggression there.  We talked about Syria, the status of our talks with Iran on the possible return of the JCPOA, and a number of other things.  It was really a lengthy and detailed conversation as well as one that looked at the relationship from a strategic perspective.  So we will continue to be in very close touch with our Emirati partners on all of these issues and more.  Our teams are following up on many of the things that we discussed yesterday.</p>
<p>As to energy, we believe it’s critical that there be abundant supplies of energy on markets now and that there also be a steady supply.  But as it happens, we didn’t focus on that issue specifically.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll take a final question from Amel Blidi, <em>El Watan</em>.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.  We’d like to know:  How do you perceive Algeria, and what’s your assessment towards the situation in North Africa, especially with deep crisis between Algeria and Morocco and the complex question in Libya?  So do you feel (inaudible) &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.  As I said at the outset, we have a relationship that runs back a long way in our history and one that’s meaningful precisely because Algeria was among the first countries to recognize the United States.  This goes back to our founding president, George Washington.  And in ways over the years, we have tried to build on that founding moment with security ties, economic ties, cultural ties connecting our people.  We are very grateful for Algeria’s important and ongoing diplomatic efforts to try to advance peace and security in the region.  It’s playing an important role and one that we count on.  We – as I mentioned, we talked a lot today about Libya and we are working very much in common to try to advance a truly democratic transition there through elections and a new government.</p>
<p>My sense is that building on this foundation of existing work together on security, deepening cooperation economically with trade and investment – I mentioned some of the numbers earlier today having increased significantly even during COVID.  And I think particularly with President Tebboune’s economic plan, one that offers the prospect I think of creating an even more favorable investment climate here for American companies through clear rules and regulations and predictability, I think you’re going to see that grow.  And as I mentioned, we have the international fair of which we’re the guest of honor this summer.  That’s a good opportunity to continue to bring American companies and Algerian businesses and people together.</p>
<p>We’ve been working very closely on counterterrorism and regional security, and we’re learning from each other in that process and strengthening our respective defense capabilities.  We were very proud – coming back to the connections between us in different ways, we just signed recently a three-year agreement with Columbia University, a university I happened to attend, and the Algerian Ministry of Higher Education and Scientific Research that will help revamp Algeria’s curriculum for teaching English language in universities.  And we, as I said, have been increasing these business and commercial ties in ways that will have very practical benefits to the lives of Algerians and Americans alike creating opportunity, creating jobs, advancing progress in everything from agriculture to IT to energy.</p>
<p>So what I’m seeing is a good foundation that we’re now building upon and that we’re very much looking forward to doing.  At the same time, to further address the second part of your question, we share real concerns about security in the region, particularly in the Sahel.  And we exchanged I think important, useful ideas about what we can do more effectively to deal with the challenges posed to security in the Sahel, but also to try to bring people there more opportunity, more hope, which is ultimately the best answer to dealing with security challenges.</p>
<p>So across the board, this was a very good day.  It’s building on a number of days that other senior officials have had here.  And of course, it’s building on the work that’s being done every day by our embassy and by private American citizens, businesses, students, et cetera.  All of that I think will increase in the months and years ahead.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  All right.  Thank you all.  See you at the next stop.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Algiers, Algeria</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy Algiers</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone.  I’d like to begin by announcing another five stops on this trip.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Not funny.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yeah.  (Laughter.)  In all seriousness, I am very glad to be back in Algeria.  I visited in 2016 when I was the deputy secretary, but this is the first trip that I’m making here as Secretary.  If you’ve noticed over the last weeks, every country in the Maghreb has hosted at least one high-ranking American official, and I think that is a signal, among others, of the importance that we place on these relationships and on the region.</p>
<p>Let me just take a moment as I start to recognize our relatively new ambassador here, Elizabeth Aubin, who arrived last month.  Ambassador Aubin is very uniquely suited for this role.  She previously served as the deputy chief of mission here, and three decades of experience in the Foreign Service.  She is truly the best of our department.  We’re grateful to have you here.</p>
<p>So over the course of this trip, we have visited Israel, the West Bank, Morocco, now Algeria.  And at every stop, we dealt with critical security issues, urgent regional and global challenges, and a shared desire to create more opportunities for our people.</p>
<p>Here in Algeria, the ties between our countries go back a long time – 1795, at a time when most of the world still didn’t recognize our then-young country.  And Hassan Bashaw Dey, who ruled what was then called the Deylik of Algiers, signed a treaty of peace with our first president, George Washington.  Since then, Algerians and Americans have developed our economic, educational, cultural connections, and our countries work closely together on issues that matter to the security and well-being of our people, and many others.</p>
<p>As I said today to President Tebboune and Foreign Minister Lamamra, Algeria’s efforts are critical to improving regional security and stability.  That includes its counterterrorism expertise, the humanitarian and security assistance that it provides to neighbors in the Sahel, its demonstrated leadership in finding regional and African-led solutions to challenges.</p>
<p>On Libya, Algeria has been a critical voice in international efforts to advance the UN political process and promote Libyan elections as quickly as possible.  And as the broker of the Algiers Accords, Algeria continues to play an important role in Mali, where we both support a return to democratic rule.</p>
<p>Algeria has also emerged in the region as a leader in preserving cultural heritage sites, which terrorists and organized crime groups have increasingly looted to finance their illicit activities.  Last year we joined Algeria in bringing together government officials, archaeologists, cultural site managers from Algeria, Libya, Tunisia, and Egypt, to discuss how to keep these sites secure and successfully prosecute looters of cultural property.</p>
<p>On the matter of Western Sahara, the United States supports the work of the UN personal envoy of the secretary general, Staffan de Mistura, in leading the political process under the auspices of the United Nations to promote a peaceful and prosperous future for the people living there.</p>
<p>I also reaffirmed to the president and the foreign minister the importance of concrete progress on human rights, including freedom of religion for all faiths, freedom of expression, especially political speech.</p>
<p>And we talked about ways to build on our robust trade and investment ties.  American companies here are helping to diversify Algeria’s economy – training local employees, sharing knowledge, building long-term partnerships that are of benefit to both of our countries.  I spoke to a number of those businesses today – I think some of you were there – in advance of the Algiers International Trade Fair that’ll take place this summer, the largest in Africa, where the United States is proud to be the country of honor.</p>
<p>Algeria and the United States have worked together to beat back the COVID-19 pandemic.  We’ve donated more than 600,000 vaccine doses to Algeria as well as a 35-bed state-of-the-art field hospital, and a second donated field hospital will be up and running in the coming months.</p>
<p>Likewise, Algeria has been there for its neighbors.  When COVID disrupted tourism and other vital trades in Tunisia, Algeria provided critical financial support and donated more than 250,000 vaccine doses.</p>
<p>Now, as you all know, I came on here to this region after a trip to Brussels with – and Poland with President Biden, where we saw the extraordinary unity and determination among allies and partners to stand with the Ukrainian people and bring an end to Russia’s unjust and brutal war in Ukraine.  The countries of North Africa and the Middle East have experienced themselves the consequences of Russian military campaigns before – for example, in Syria and Libya, where Russian military and paramilitary forces exploited conflicts for Moscow’s gain, with deadly consequences for citizens and communities.</p>
<p>Now, many in this region are feeling the pain of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine in another way, with rising food prices, especially wheat.  Farmers in Ukraine, instead of tending to their crops, have been forced to either fight for their country’s future and independence, or to flee.  Ships with grain are not getting out from Black Sea ports because they’re blocked by Russia’s aggression.  Countries around the world, including North Africa and the Middle East, import significant amounts of wheat from Ukraine, and of course, when food prices rise, so do the numbers of people suffering from hunger.  This is just one more reason why the international community must increase the pressure on Russia to end this unprovoked and unjustified war.</p>
<p>So let me conclude simply by saying thank you to our colleagues in Algeria for hosting us today, and <em>Ramadan Kareem</em> to all of those who will soon celebrate the Ramadan.</p>
<p>With that, I will happily take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll start with Matt Lee of the AP, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, (inaudible).  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, how are you?  Hi.  Thank you.  Are you at all concerned with Algeria’s relationship – Algeria in particular and its relationship with Russia?  And should – do you think that it should be doing more to re-evaluate its ties with the Russians?</p>
<p>And also, given where you’ve been so far on this portion of the trip, the Middle East and North Africa, and what you attended, what you participated in on Monday, are you concerned at all, especially given the president’s comments to you a little bit earlier, that Algeria is in danger of missing out on the kind of benefits, the kind of changes that you’ve talked – you and others have talked about in terms of the region?</p>
<p>And then if I could just ask one last thing on Ukraine and Russia, and that is there are officials in Washington who are saying that the U.S. believes that President Putin has been misled by his top military advisors.  Is this something that is shared administration-wide, or at least by you?  Do you believe that to be the case?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> Thanks, Matt.  So on the first part of the question, look, I think it’s a reality that different countries have different historical relationships with Russia.  But there are times when one issue emerges that is so clearly black and white, and in this case of Ukraine a clear aggressor and a clear victim, that it’s important to stand with the victim and to stand for the principles that have also been violated, principles that should matter to countries around the world, principles about sovereignty, about independence.  And I know that that’s something that Algerians feel strongly about, given their own history.</p>
<p>And I think countries in the region as well have seen the damaging effects of Russia’s military campaigns before.  I alluded to that a moment ago.  In Syria and Libya, as I mentioned, the Russian military and paramilitary forces have exploited conflicts for Moscow’s gain.  And that in turn has actually posed great threats to security in the region and stability and commerce.  And as I mentioned as well, these actions have had deadly consequences for citizens in the region.  They’ve disrupted the peace and prosperity of communities.  They’ve intruded into the lives of families and individuals who are simply trying to live peacefully in their own countries.</p>
<p>And then again, I think the impact that’s being felt, even if what seems very distant as a conflict to people in this region because it is half a world away or almost half a world away in Europe, it’s having a direct impact on their lives right now, particularly with regard to rising food prices, something that everyone is feeling, especially wheat.  So my sense from having talked to a lot of colleagues over the last days is that a lot of this pain is keenly felt in this region.  Most of the countries import half their wheat or more.  And so we see them taking stock of that, and that’s factoring into their thinking.</p>
<p>But mostly, I think you’re seeing that countries understand that what’s happening in Ukraine matters, of course, first and foremost to the people in Ukraine.  But it also matters to them because, as I said, principles that matter to them – the UN charter, sovereignty, independence – are also the victims of aggression.</p>
<p>With regard to the Negev and the countries participating in the normalization process with Israel, look, these are decisions for countries to make.  They have to decide what’s in the best interests of their own people.  I think what we’re trying to show through the countries that are participating in the Negev process, since we’re now giving it that name, is that this is going to have real, practical benefits for the people in the countries participating in that effort who have normalized their relations with Israel.</p>
<p>And we’re seeing that take life in terms of connections that have grown very rapidly between people, between businesses, between students, tourists; all of that, even with COVID, has gone up dramatically.  At the same time, what we’re doing as governments is looking at how we can work together to make the kinds of investments in infrastructure, in global health, in science, in dealing with climate, that are going to have real benefits for people.  My bet is that as other countries that are not part of that process see this take shape, they will conclude that this is something they want to be a part of.  And that’ll happen at different paces for different countries.  But, of course, it’s on us to demonstrate that it really works and that it produces results.  I believe that it will.</p>
<p>And finally, with regard to President Putin, look, what I can tell you is this, and I said this before:  One of the Achilles heels of autocracies is that you don’t have people in those systems who speak truth to power or who have the ability to speak truth to power.  And I think that is something that we’re seeing in Russia.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We’ll turn to Abderrahim Kachour.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary of State.  United States is adopting an advance position against Russian military aggression in Ukraine based on the principle of violence against international law.  But the same thing is happening in Palestine, in (inaudible), as well in Western Sahara.  But United States didn’t show the same fairness, the same resolve, as that one in Ukraine.  And in the same context, is Biden administration still adopting the proclamation of the ex-President Donald Trump recognizing Moroccan sovereignty over the Western Sahara?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>  Thank you very much.  When President Biden took office, we and he made two principal commitments in terms of our foreign policy and how we would engage the world.  We made a commitment to re-engage with partners – and international institutions and organizations – and we made a commitment to lead with diplomacy, and that’s what we’ve done.  Part of that means that when the basic rules of diplomacy and the international system that are necessary to try to keep peace and security are being violated, we will stand up with other countries to defend them.  And that’s what we’re doing.  That’s what we’re doing in the case of this aggression.  But the centrality of diplomacy to this effort is critical.</p>
<p>And so when it comes to Israel and the Palestinians, we have remained very engaged with our diplomacy to try and advance prospects for getting back to a two-state solution, to negotiating that, and in the meantime doing everything that we can to help the Palestinian people improve their lives.  We’ve committed half a billion dollars in assistance to the Palestinians over the last year.  We’ve re-engaged with UNRWA.  And, of course, I was just up in Ramallah.  And by the way, we were talking about the Negev Summit and the countries participating in that – one of the things that we spent some time talking about is how we could use that grouping of countries to focus on helping Palestinians improve their lives.  And we also made clear – and I certainly made clear – that as committed as we are to supporting normalization and to having more countries join in, that is not a substitute for dealing with the conflict between Israelis and Palestinians, and not a substitute for two states.</p>
<p>Similarly, with regard to Western Sahara, we’re very focused on diplomacy and on advancing a resolution through diplomacy, including through the efforts of Staffan de Mistura, the envoy from the United Nations.</p>
<p>So I think these things are very consistent.  In each case, we are working through diplomacy, working with other countries to uphold the basic principles of the international system.  And again, on Morocco, on Western Sahara, we are continuing to support the efforts of the UN.  There’s been no change in our position otherwise.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Peter Martin of Bloomberg.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, thank you.   Yesterday you met with Crown Prince Mohammed bin Zayed.  Did you ask him to increase oil production to help bring down gas prices?  And did you offer any specific assurances about the UAE’s security?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thanks.  Well, first, let me just say we had what I thought was an excellent and lengthy discussion.  And we always benefit, and I certainly always benefit, from getting the crown prince’s perspective.  And we had what I thought was a very meaningful, heartfelt exchange that covered really the breadth of our partnership and did it in a strategic way as well as a specific way.</p>
<p>One of the things I made very clear to him is the value that we attach to that partnership, and that we are a true partner for the UAE.  The UAE has been with us around the world, including in Afghanistan, fighting side by side.  In fact, the crown prince had some of his sons in attendance who had fought with us, and one indeed who was injured.  That’s a very powerful thing.  And we’ll continue to stand by them.</p>
<p>One of the things I told them was that the United States remains committed to helping the UAE defend itself against threats from Yemen, from the Houthis, even as we work to try to bring that conflict to a close.  In fact, we have our Special Envoy Tim Lenderking in the region as we speak, and we very much welcome the UAE support for a truce that could lead to a ceasefire.  I also took the opportunity to commend the crown prince for his vision, his courage, his leadership in normalizing ties with Israel, and we talked about the opportunities that can bring for all of our people.</p>
<p>We had a very constructive discussion as well about the war in Ukraine and the Russian aggression there.  We talked about Syria, the status of our talks with Iran on the possible return of the JCPOA, and a number of other things.  It was really a lengthy and detailed conversation as well as one that looked at the relationship from a strategic perspective.  So we will continue to be in very close touch with our Emirati partners on all of these issues and more.  Our teams are following up on many of the things that we discussed yesterday.</p>
<p>As to energy, we believe it’s critical that there be abundant supplies of energy on markets now and that there also be a steady supply.  But as it happens, we didn’t focus on that issue specifically.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll take a final question from Amel Blidi, <em>El Watan</em>.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.  We’d like to know:  How do you perceive Algeria, and what’s your assessment towards the situation in North Africa, especially with deep crisis between Algeria and Morocco and the complex question in Libya?  So do you feel (inaudible) &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.  As I said at the outset, we have a relationship that runs back a long way in our history and one that’s meaningful precisely because Algeria was among the first countries to recognize the United States.  This goes back to our founding president, George Washington.  And in ways over the years, we have tried to build on that founding moment with security ties, economic ties, cultural ties connecting our people.  We are very grateful for Algeria’s important and ongoing diplomatic efforts to try to advance peace and security in the region.  It’s playing an important role and one that we count on.  We – as I mentioned, we talked a lot today about Libya and we are working very much in common to try to advance a truly democratic transition there through elections and a new government.</p>
<p>My sense is that building on this foundation of existing work together on security, deepening cooperation economically with trade and investment – I mentioned some of the numbers earlier today having increased significantly even during COVID.  And I think particularly with President Tebboune’s economic plan, one that offers the prospect I think of creating an even more favorable investment climate here for American companies through clear rules and regulations and predictability, I think you’re going to see that grow.  And as I mentioned, we have the international fair of which we’re the guest of honor this summer.  That’s a good opportunity to continue to bring American companies and Algerian businesses and people together.</p>
<p>We’ve been working very closely on counterterrorism and regional security, and we’re learning from each other in that process and strengthening our respective defense capabilities.  We were very proud – coming back to the connections between us in different ways, we just signed recently a three-year agreement with Columbia University, a university I happened to attend, and the Algerian Ministry of Higher Education and Scientific Research that will help revamp Algeria’s curriculum for teaching English language in universities.  And we, as I said, have been increasing these business and commercial ties in ways that will have very practical benefits to the lives of Algerians and Americans alike creating opportunity, creating jobs, advancing progress in everything from agriculture to IT to energy.</p>
<p>So what I’m seeing is a good foundation that we’re now building upon and that we’re very much looking forward to doing.  At the same time, to further address the second part of your question, we share real concerns about security in the region, particularly in the Sahel.  And we exchanged I think important, useful ideas about what we can do more effectively to deal with the challenges posed to security in the Sahel, but also to try to bring people there more opportunity, more hope, which is ultimately the best answer to dealing with security challenges.</p>
<p>So across the board, this was a very good day.  It’s building on a number of days that other senior officials have had here.  And of course, it’s building on the work that’s being done every day by our embassy and by private American citizens, businesses, students, et cetera.  All of that I think will increase in the months and years ahead.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  All right.  Thank you all.  See you at the next stop.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary for Arms Control and International Security Bonnie D. Jenkins Announces Kenneth D. Ward as U.S. Special Representative to the Biological Weapons Convention</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-for-arms-control-and-international-security-bonnie-d-jenkins-announces-kenneth-d-ward-as-u-s-special-representative-to-the-biological-weapons-convention/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 18:45:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary of State for Arms Control and International Security Bonnie D. Jenkins is pleased to announce Kenneth D. Ward as the U.S. Special Representative to the Biological Weapons Convention.  The Administration is deeply committed to countering the full range of present and future biological threats.  This includes upholding and strengthening the Biological Weapons Convention (BWC).  We look forward to Mr. Ward leading U.S. efforts in this important area and heading up our team of experts at the BWC Review Conference later this year.</p>
<p>Mr. Ward comes to this position with 30 years’ experience in arms control and nonproliferation with the U.S. Department of State and the former U.S. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency.  He most recently served as the U.S. Ambassador to the Organization for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons in The Hague, Netherlands, with previous assignments as the Director of the Office of Chemical and Biological Weapons Affairs in State’s Bureau of Arms Control, Verification, and Compliance, and the Deputy Negotiator during the 2004-2007 WMD elimination effort in Libya.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary of State for Arms Control and International Security Bonnie D. Jenkins is pleased to announce Kenneth D. Ward as the U.S. Special Representative to the Biological Weapons Convention.  The Administration is deeply committed to countering the full range of present and future biological threats.  This includes upholding and strengthening the Biological Weapons Convention (BWC).  We look forward to Mr. Ward leading U.S. efforts in this important area and heading up our team of experts at the BWC Review Conference later this year.</p>
<p>Mr. Ward comes to this position with 30 years’ experience in arms control and nonproliferation with the U.S. Department of State and the former U.S. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency.  He most recently served as the U.S. Ambassador to the Organization for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons in The Hague, Netherlands, with previous assignments as the Director of the Office of Chemical and Biological Weapons Affairs in State’s Bureau of Arms Control, Verification, and Compliance, and the Deputy Negotiator during the 2004-2007 WMD elimination effort in Libya.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Remarks to Mission Algeria</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-remarks-to-mission-algeria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 18:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329690</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Algiers, Algeria</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy Algiers</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR AUBIN:</b>  (In progress) you’ve been here since then as deputy, and we are so thrilled that you could be here today as the Secretary of State.</p>
<p>On February 1st, I met with Secretary Blinken and asked him if he would please come to Algeria.  And when this opportunity came up less than two months later I was thrilled because, of course, it continues – his visit drives forward our policy objectives of working with Algeria on regional stability, economic cooperation, and all of our cultural activities, including and especially English-language learning.</p>
<p>So since I gotten here we’ve had OneBeat Sahara.  How many of you went to OneBeat?  Yeah.  A lot of you.  Very good.  (Applause.)  We’ve had the Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman visit.  We’ve had a joint military dialogue with an interagency group from Washington.  And now you, the absolute kind of cherry on the ice cream sundae.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>So without further ado, Mr. Secretary, I commend this fantastic team to you.  Over the last 18 months, before my arrival, they didn’t have an ambassador, but Gautam Rana as chargé led, drove the bilateral objectives forward.  There was no kind of holding down the fort; they really moved forward.  And I’ve walked into the very best embassy that I’ve ever seen in 32 years in the Foreign Service.  So thank you for being with us today.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, first of all, this is the best first row I’ve ever had – (laughter) – at an embassy event anywhere, so thank you guys for being here.  Actually, I’d really like – maybe I could sit down there and we can just talk.  (Laughter.)  We’ll do that afterward.</p>
<p>Elizabeth, it is so wonderful to have you here and to be able to see you early in your tenure.  We’re grateful for your leadership, and it’s at such a critical time.  So thank you.  And Gautam, thank you for your extraordinary leadership during the 19 or so months you were leading the mission.  We’re grateful for that.  And to each and every one of you, thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>
<p>A few things I want to say before we get to a couple of questions.</p>
<p>You’re at the heart of a place in the world that is vital to our interests – the Middle East and North Africa – and we have in Algeria a partner on so many different security issues, a growing partner I think on economic issues as well, where there’s tremendous opportunity, which I’ll come to it in a minute, and you are the ones who are making that work, growing that, building that every single day, and I’m grateful for that.</p>
<p>As the ambassador said, we’ve had a lot of visits here.  I know that puts a little bit of a strain on the embassy.  I also know that in two, three hours, you’ll be having a wheels-up party.  (Laughter.)  So there’s at least that to look forward to.</p>
<p>But I had a very long and good report from Wendy Sherman when she came back to hear about her visit.  I’m glad I was able to follow up and pursue some of the things that she and the team have been working on.  But we’ve had the fifth strategic dialogue; that is terrific and a strong foundation for the work we’re doing together.  We had the military dialogue as well.  And to the ambassador’s point, a whole number of practical deliverables that will strengthen the relationship and strengthen us going forward.</p>
<p>I am especially excited about the English-language program.  I think as I’ve seen around the world, this is one of the single best things that we export and there’s a real thirst and demand for it.  So I really appreciate that.  And having Algerian Government leaders take part in that I think is really a wonderful thing.  A new research collaboration between the ministry of higher education, the University of Notre Dame, connecting our people at all different levels, not only business to business but university to university, student to student and traveler to traveler, as hopefully that picks up with COVID.</p>
<p>And then there are these growing cultural ties.  I am incredibly upset that I missed out on the OneBeat Sahara music festival.  (Laughter.)  So as I understand it, there were 23 musicians across seven Saharan nations, plus the United States.  Everything from experimental hip-hop to nawa to jazz to electronic.  So if that happens again, please, let me know in advance.  (Laughter.)  And let me simply say a special thanks to all of you who worked on it, the folks in Public Affairs.  Adam Sigelman, is he here somewhere?  All right.  (Applause.)  Job very well done.  Thank you.</p>
<p>And as I mentioned, these growing economic ties that I hope will reach a new moment when we have this international fair in June, for which we are the honored nation.  I think that’s an important moment.  We’ll have some 30-plus U.S. companies there.  In fact, I met with most of them today.  And then a lot of work has already gone into this.  We actually saw the video showing the pavilion-to-be.  Planning for that is a whole-of-embassy effort, and I want to thank you for doing that.  Michele Smith – is Michele here anywhere?</p>
<p><b>PARTICIPANT:</b>  Yes.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  All right.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Thank you for your great efforts.</p>
<p>So much of what you’ve done, though, has been done during a very difficult time for all of us, including folks at this mission, and that is the time of COVID – two-plus difficult years.  I know that some of you have experienced this in a very personal way, not just a professional way, the loss of – sickness of family members, of friends.  One staff member lost here, Hassan Berriche, and I understand that there’s a fountain that was named in his honor.  But I know how deeply felt this is.</p>
<p>But I really want to say to you as well thank you for looking out for each other, thank you for having each other’s backs during this difficult time.  So many different parts of this embassy came together to do what was necessary, the health unit in particular keeping people safe.  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  Human resources keeping people updated, the community liaison office – and is Ikram McRiffey here anywhere?  Right there.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Well done.  Just keeping people connected and having that sense of community, especially in a time like that, is so important, whether it’s trivia nights or now going kayaking in some places.  That makes a real difference, so thank you for doing that.</p>
<p>And then to the locally employed staff association implementing supplemental health insurance for LES, looking out for each other too, I’m grateful to you.  And let me close with this while I’m on the locally employed staff:  As I say everywhere I go, you are the lifeblood of this mission.  We could not do our work without you.  And more than anything else, there’s a powerful connection that you make between us and the country that we’re serving in.</p>
<p>And there are a few folks I just want to mention by name because they’ve been here working side by side for a long, long time, and it’s really extraordinary.  Arezki Benzamouche, are you here?  You are.  Thirty-nine years of service.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Nabila Hales, 38 years of service.  (Applause.)  Abdelkader Hadjel, 37 years of service.  (Applause.)  Abdelkrim Boumazouza, 37 years of service as well.  (Applause.)  So to each of you, thank you, and to every member of the locally employed staff team, thank you for what you’re doing to bring us closer together, to bring our countries closer together, to help us do the vital work of this mission.</p>
<p>But whether you’re local staff, whether you’re a family member, whether you’re an FSO, whether you’re a civil servant, whether you’re here with the State Department, Defense, Foreign Commercial Service, Foreign Agricultural Service, any of the other agencies that we have, mostly I wanted to come by, as I said at the start, with two words:  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Algiers, Algeria</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy Algiers</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR AUBIN:</b>  (In progress) you’ve been here since then as deputy, and we are so thrilled that you could be here today as the Secretary of State.</p>
<p>On February 1st, I met with Secretary Blinken and asked him if he would please come to Algeria.  And when this opportunity came up less than two months later I was thrilled because, of course, it continues – his visit drives forward our policy objectives of working with Algeria on regional stability, economic cooperation, and all of our cultural activities, including and especially English-language learning.</p>
<p>So since I gotten here we’ve had OneBeat Sahara.  How many of you went to OneBeat?  Yeah.  A lot of you.  Very good.  (Applause.)  We’ve had the Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman visit.  We’ve had a joint military dialogue with an interagency group from Washington.  And now you, the absolute kind of cherry on the ice cream sundae.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>So without further ado, Mr. Secretary, I commend this fantastic team to you.  Over the last 18 months, before my arrival, they didn’t have an ambassador, but Gautam Rana as chargé led, drove the bilateral objectives forward.  There was no kind of holding down the fort; they really moved forward.  And I’ve walked into the very best embassy that I’ve ever seen in 32 years in the Foreign Service.  So thank you for being with us today.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, first of all, this is the best first row I’ve ever had – (laughter) – at an embassy event anywhere, so thank you guys for being here.  Actually, I’d really like – maybe I could sit down there and we can just talk.  (Laughter.)  We’ll do that afterward.</p>
<p>Elizabeth, it is so wonderful to have you here and to be able to see you early in your tenure.  We’re grateful for your leadership, and it’s at such a critical time.  So thank you.  And Gautam, thank you for your extraordinary leadership during the 19 or so months you were leading the mission.  We’re grateful for that.  And to each and every one of you, thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>
<p>A few things I want to say before we get to a couple of questions.</p>
<p>You’re at the heart of a place in the world that is vital to our interests – the Middle East and North Africa – and we have in Algeria a partner on so many different security issues, a growing partner I think on economic issues as well, where there’s tremendous opportunity, which I’ll come to it in a minute, and you are the ones who are making that work, growing that, building that every single day, and I’m grateful for that.</p>
<p>As the ambassador said, we’ve had a lot of visits here.  I know that puts a little bit of a strain on the embassy.  I also know that in two, three hours, you’ll be having a wheels-up party.  (Laughter.)  So there’s at least that to look forward to.</p>
<p>But I had a very long and good report from Wendy Sherman when she came back to hear about her visit.  I’m glad I was able to follow up and pursue some of the things that she and the team have been working on.  But we’ve had the fifth strategic dialogue; that is terrific and a strong foundation for the work we’re doing together.  We had the military dialogue as well.  And to the ambassador’s point, a whole number of practical deliverables that will strengthen the relationship and strengthen us going forward.</p>
<p>I am especially excited about the English-language program.  I think as I’ve seen around the world, this is one of the single best things that we export and there’s a real thirst and demand for it.  So I really appreciate that.  And having Algerian Government leaders take part in that I think is really a wonderful thing.  A new research collaboration between the ministry of higher education, the University of Notre Dame, connecting our people at all different levels, not only business to business but university to university, student to student and traveler to traveler, as hopefully that picks up with COVID.</p>
<p>And then there are these growing cultural ties.  I am incredibly upset that I missed out on the OneBeat Sahara music festival.  (Laughter.)  So as I understand it, there were 23 musicians across seven Saharan nations, plus the United States.  Everything from experimental hip-hop to nawa to jazz to electronic.  So if that happens again, please, let me know in advance.  (Laughter.)  And let me simply say a special thanks to all of you who worked on it, the folks in Public Affairs.  Adam Sigelman, is he here somewhere?  All right.  (Applause.)  Job very well done.  Thank you.</p>
<p>And as I mentioned, these growing economic ties that I hope will reach a new moment when we have this international fair in June, for which we are the honored nation.  I think that’s an important moment.  We’ll have some 30-plus U.S. companies there.  In fact, I met with most of them today.  And then a lot of work has already gone into this.  We actually saw the video showing the pavilion-to-be.  Planning for that is a whole-of-embassy effort, and I want to thank you for doing that.  Michele Smith – is Michele here anywhere?</p>
<p><b>PARTICIPANT:</b>  Yes.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  All right.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Thank you for your great efforts.</p>
<p>So much of what you’ve done, though, has been done during a very difficult time for all of us, including folks at this mission, and that is the time of COVID – two-plus difficult years.  I know that some of you have experienced this in a very personal way, not just a professional way, the loss of – sickness of family members, of friends.  One staff member lost here, Hassan Berriche, and I understand that there’s a fountain that was named in his honor.  But I know how deeply felt this is.</p>
<p>But I really want to say to you as well thank you for looking out for each other, thank you for having each other’s backs during this difficult time.  So many different parts of this embassy came together to do what was necessary, the health unit in particular keeping people safe.  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  Human resources keeping people updated, the community liaison office – and is Ikram McRiffey here anywhere?  Right there.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Well done.  Just keeping people connected and having that sense of community, especially in a time like that, is so important, whether it’s trivia nights or now going kayaking in some places.  That makes a real difference, so thank you for doing that.</p>
<p>And then to the locally employed staff association implementing supplemental health insurance for LES, looking out for each other too, I’m grateful to you.  And let me close with this while I’m on the locally employed staff:  As I say everywhere I go, you are the lifeblood of this mission.  We could not do our work without you.  And more than anything else, there’s a powerful connection that you make between us and the country that we’re serving in.</p>
<p>And there are a few folks I just want to mention by name because they’ve been here working side by side for a long, long time, and it’s really extraordinary.  Arezki Benzamouche, are you here?  You are.  Thirty-nine years of service.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Nabila Hales, 38 years of service.  (Applause.)  Abdelkader Hadjel, 37 years of service.  (Applause.)  Abdelkrim Boumazouza, 37 years of service as well.  (Applause.)  So to each of you, thank you, and to every member of the locally employed staff team, thank you for what you’re doing to bring us closer together, to bring our countries closer together, to help us do the vital work of this mission.</p>
<p>But whether you’re local staff, whether you’re a family member, whether you’re an FSO, whether you’re a civil servant, whether you’re here with the State Department, Defense, Foreign Commercial Service, Foreign Agricultural Service, any of the other agencies that we have, mostly I wanted to come by, as I said at the start, with two words:  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with North Macedonia Prime Minister Kovachevski</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-north-macedonia-prime-minister-kovachevski/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 17:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with North Macedonia Prime Minister Dimitar Kovachevski.  Secretary Blinken congratulated Prime Minister Kovachevski on his new position and on the formation of the new cabinet.  The Secretary thanked North Macedonia for its unwavering and steadfast support for Ukraine in the face of President Putin’s continued brutal war of aggression.  The Secretary also underscored strong U.S. support for North Macedonia’s expeditious European Union accession.  The Secretary personally thanked the Prime Minister for North Macedonia’s commitment to the NATO Alliance as its newest member, as well as for hosting Afghan evacuees.  The Secretary expressed that the United States looks forward to further close cooperation on a range of regional, security, and defense issues to promote democracy and stability in the region.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with North Macedonia Prime Minister Dimitar Kovachevski.  Secretary Blinken congratulated Prime Minister Kovachevski on his new position and on the formation of the new cabinet.  The Secretary thanked North Macedonia for its unwavering and steadfast support for Ukraine in the face of President Putin’s continued brutal war of aggression.  The Secretary also underscored strong U.S. support for North Macedonia’s expeditious European Union accession.  The Secretary personally thanked the Prime Minister for North Macedonia’s commitment to the NATO Alliance as its newest member, as well as for hosting Afghan evacuees.  The Secretary expressed that the United States looks forward to further close cooperation on a range of regional, security, and defense issues to promote democracy and stability in the region.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States Imposes Sanctions on Iran’s Ballistic Missile-Related Activities</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-imposes-sanctions-on-irans-ballistic-missile-related-activities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 17:34:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is designating five Iranian individuals and entities for sanctions pursuant to Executive Order (E.O.) 13382, which targets proliferators of weapons of mass destruction and their means of delivery for their involvement in Iran’s ballistic missile-related activities. We have taken this action following Iran’s recent missile attack on Erbil, Iraq, as well as missile attacks by Iranian proxies against Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates. These attacks are a reminder that Iran’s development and proliferation of ballistic missiles pose a serious threat to regional and international security.</p>
<p>Iranian procurement agent Mohammad Ali Hosseini and four companies in his network, Iran-based Jestar Sanat Delijan, Sina Composite Delijan Company, Sayehban Sepehr Delijan,<b> </b>and P.B. Sadr Company, have been involved in efforts to procure equipment used to produce ballistic missile propellant and related materials in support of Iran’s missile program.</p>
<p>This international procurement network operated on behalf of the IRGC Research and Self-Sufficiency Jihad Organization (RSSJO) and Parchin Chemical Industries (PCI) – which is designated for sanctions by the United Nations under United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231. The United States will not stand by while Iranian networks support UN-designated entities such as PCI.</p>
<p>Iran’s ballistic missile-related activities continue to destabilize the Middle East region, and the United States will continue to use every tool at our disposal to disrupt them. We will also continue working with others in the region to hold Iran accountable for its actions, including violations of the sovereignty of its neighbors.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0689" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is designating five Iranian individuals and entities for sanctions pursuant to Executive Order (E.O.) 13382, which targets proliferators of weapons of mass destruction and their means of delivery for their involvement in Iran’s ballistic missile-related activities. We have taken this action following Iran’s recent missile attack on Erbil, Iraq, as well as missile attacks by Iranian proxies against Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates. These attacks are a reminder that Iran’s development and proliferation of ballistic missiles pose a serious threat to regional and international security.</p>
<p>Iranian procurement agent Mohammad Ali Hosseini and four companies in his network, Iran-based Jestar Sanat Delijan, Sina Composite Delijan Company, Sayehban Sepehr Delijan,<b> </b>and P.B. Sadr Company, have been involved in efforts to procure equipment used to produce ballistic missile propellant and related materials in support of Iran’s missile program.</p>
<p>This international procurement network operated on behalf of the IRGC Research and Self-Sufficiency Jihad Organization (RSSJO) and Parchin Chemical Industries (PCI) – which is designated for sanctions by the United Nations under United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231. The United States will not stand by while Iranian networks support UN-designated entities such as PCI.</p>
<p>Iran’s ballistic missile-related activities continue to destabilize the Middle East region, and the United States will continue to use every tool at our disposal to disrupt them. We will also continue working with others in the region to hold Iran accountable for its actions, including violations of the sovereignty of its neighbors.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0689" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
