<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 20:14:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Robinson’s Travel to Poland, Latvia, and Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-for-international-narcotics-and-law-enforcement-robinsons-travel-to-poland-latvia-and-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 20:14:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330855</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement (INL) Todd D. Robinson traveled to Poland March 30 – April 2. While in Warsaw, Assistant Secretary Robinson met with Ukrainian civil society organizations. During his visit to Rzeszow, Assistant Secretary Robinson met with the Ukrainian Border Guard Service and National Police, as well as members of the Embassy Kyiv team who are on the frontlines of the response to the crisis caused by Putin’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine. He underscored the Department of State’s commitment to providing emergency medical and protective equipment to the Ukrainian Border Guard Service and National Police to support their efforts to rescue and protect civilians.</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary Robinson is traveling to Riga, Latvia April 3-5. While in Riga, the Assistant Secretary is meeting with Latvian government officials to discuss border security and efforts to further combat corruption and transnational organized crime.</p>
<p>Finally, Assistant Secretary Robinson will travel to Berlin, Germany April 5-6 where he will participate in a ministerial support conference on Moldova. The Assistant Secretary will co-chair a roundtable focused on effective border management and preventing trafficking in persons.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:INL-PAPD@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">INL-PAPD@state.gov</a> or visit @StateINL on Twitter.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement (INL) Todd D. Robinson traveled to Poland March 30 – April 2. While in Warsaw, Assistant Secretary Robinson met with Ukrainian civil society organizations. During his visit to Rzeszow, Assistant Secretary Robinson met with the Ukrainian Border Guard Service and National Police, as well as members of the Embassy Kyiv team who are on the frontlines of the response to the crisis caused by Putin’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine. He underscored the Department of State’s commitment to providing emergency medical and protective equipment to the Ukrainian Border Guard Service and National Police to support their efforts to rescue and protect civilians.</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary Robinson is traveling to Riga, Latvia April 3-5. While in Riga, the Assistant Secretary is meeting with Latvian government officials to discuss border security and efforts to further combat corruption and transnational organized crime.</p>
<p>Finally, Assistant Secretary Robinson will travel to Berlin, Germany April 5-6 where he will participate in a ministerial support conference on Moldova. The Assistant Secretary will co-chair a roundtable focused on effective border management and preventing trafficking in persons.</p>
<p>For further information, please contact <a href="mailto:INL-PAPD@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">INL-PAPD@state.gov</a> or visit @StateINL on Twitter.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Delivery of Humanitarian Assistance to Tigray and Afar Regions</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/delivery-of-humanitarian-assistance-to-tigray-and-afar-regions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 20:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330684</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes steps by the Government of Ethiopia and regional authorities to implement a cessation of hostilities. We commend them on the delivery of humanitarian assistance over recent days to Ethiopians in the Tigray and Afar regions. Over one hundred thousand Ethiopians will receive life-saving food from the two initial convoys that have mobilized in the past three days. This is an important step toward implementing the cessation of hostilities and addressing the urgent humanitarian needs in both regions. Now, we urge all stakeholders to make every effort possible to sustain the delivery of life-saving assistance.</p>
<p>The United States appreciates the extraordinary efforts of humanitarian actors to enable this delivery of humanitarian assistance. Operating in difficult circumstances across Ethiopia, humanitarian actors continue to show their agility, dedication, and commitment to serving those in need. We call on all parties in conflict-affected regions to ensure the safety of humanitarian staff. The United States supports and acknowledges the positive undertakings in this regard made by the Government of Ethiopia and the regional authorities in Tigray and Afar.</p>
<p>We urge all parties to build upon this positive humanitarian development to take the difficult next steps to realize peace in northern Ethiopia. The United States will continue to do everything within our power to assist all Ethiopians in need throughout the country and support an inclusive political process to achieve progress toward common security and prosperity for all Ethiopians.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes steps by the Government of Ethiopia and regional authorities to implement a cessation of hostilities. We commend them on the delivery of humanitarian assistance over recent days to Ethiopians in the Tigray and Afar regions. Over one hundred thousand Ethiopians will receive life-saving food from the two initial convoys that have mobilized in the past three days. This is an important step toward implementing the cessation of hostilities and addressing the urgent humanitarian needs in both regions. Now, we urge all stakeholders to make every effort possible to sustain the delivery of life-saving assistance.</p>
<p>The United States appreciates the extraordinary efforts of humanitarian actors to enable this delivery of humanitarian assistance. Operating in difficult circumstances across Ethiopia, humanitarian actors continue to show their agility, dedication, and commitment to serving those in need. We call on all parties in conflict-affected regions to ensure the safety of humanitarian staff. The United States supports and acknowledges the positive undertakings in this regard made by the Government of Ethiopia and the regional authorities in Tigray and Afar.</p>
<p>We urge all parties to build upon this positive humanitarian development to take the difficult next steps to realize peace in northern Ethiopia. The United States will continue to do everything within our power to assist all Ethiopians in need throughout the country and support an inclusive political process to achieve progress toward common security and prosperity for all Ethiopians.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Israeli Minister of Regional Cooperation Esawi Frej</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-israeli-minister-of-regional-cooperation-esawi-frej/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 20:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Israeli Minister of Regional Cooperation Esawi Frej earlier today in Washington and expressed her condolences regarding the recent wave of terrorist attacks in Israel. They discussed efforts to strengthen Israeli-Palestinian economic relations in a way that brings tangible improvements to the quality of life of the Palestinian people while also enhancing and deepening Israel’s integration in the region. They also spoke about efforts to expand normalization and the importance of building on normalization agreements to further progress on the Israeli-Palestinian peace track. They discussed the importance of all Palestinians and Israelis living safely and securely with equal measures of freedom, dignity, and prosperity. The Deputy Secretary reaffirmed the administration’s commitment to a two-state solution, and the importance of reducing intercommunal tensions in Israel ahead of the religious holidays.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Israeli Minister of Regional Cooperation Esawi Frej earlier today in Washington and expressed her condolences regarding the recent wave of terrorist attacks in Israel. They discussed efforts to strengthen Israeli-Palestinian economic relations in a way that brings tangible improvements to the quality of life of the Palestinian people while also enhancing and deepening Israel’s integration in the region. They also spoke about efforts to expand normalization and the importance of building on normalization agreements to further progress on the Israeli-Palestinian peace track. They discussed the importance of all Palestinians and Israelis living safely and securely with equal measures of freedom, dignity, and prosperity. The Deputy Secretary reaffirmed the administration’s commitment to a two-state solution, and the importance of reducing intercommunal tensions in Israel ahead of the religious holidays.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Jordanian Foreign Minister Safadi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-jordanian-foreign-minister-safadi-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 19:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330655</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Jordanian Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Ayman H. Safadi to reaffirm the deep strategic relationship between the United States and the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan. The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed the need for calm in Jerusalem during April as Muslims, Jews, and Christians celebrate Ramadan, Passover, and Easter. The Secretary also spoke of his recent participation in the Negev Summit and ways regional partners can work together to support the Palestinian people. The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Jordan’s steadfast support for Ukraine, especially in the United Nations.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Jordanian Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Ayman H. Safadi to reaffirm the deep strategic relationship between the United States and the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan. The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed the need for calm in Jerusalem during April as Muslims, Jews, and Christians celebrate Ramadan, Passover, and Easter. The Secretary also spoke of his recent participation in the Negev Summit and ways regional partners can work together to support the Palestinian people. The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Jordan’s steadfast support for Ukraine, especially in the United Nations.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Kuleba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-ukrainian-foreign-minister-kuleba-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 18:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to follow up on their recent meeting in Warsaw, Poland. The Secretary highlighted U.S. efforts to provide Ukraine the support it needs to defend against the Russian Federation’s unprovoked, unjustified, and brutal war. The Secretary emphasized the United States’ unyielding and steadfast support for Ukraine, and lauded Ukraine’s commitment to engaging in diplomacy. He stressed that the United States, Allies, and partners will continue to hold accountable those responsible for atrocities committed in Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to follow up on their recent meeting in Warsaw, Poland. The Secretary highlighted U.S. efforts to provide Ukraine the support it needs to defend against the Russian Federation’s unprovoked, unjustified, and brutal war. The Secretary emphasized the United States’ unyielding and steadfast support for Ukraine, and lauded Ukraine’s commitment to engaging in diplomacy. He stressed that the United States, Allies, and partners will continue to hold accountable those responsible for atrocities committed in Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Briefing on the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-on-the-u-s-strategy-to-prevent-conflict-and-promote-stability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 17:40:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330610</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Thank you so much, Cynthia.  And I’ll let everybody know that while we called this a State Department briefing, it’s actually an interagency briefing today with our colleagues from USAID and the Department of Defense, whom we’re very glad to do this with today.</p>
<p>So good morning once again, everyone, and thank you for joining us.  Today we will be discussing what we can describe as the latest progress in implementing the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.  As a quick reminder here at the top, this morning’s briefing is on the record but its contents are embargoed until the end of the call.</p>
<p>Okay.  It is my pleasure to let everyone on the line know that we are joined today by Assistant Secretary of State for Conflict and Stabilization Operations Anne Witkowsky; we’re also joined by Assistant to the USAID Administrator for Conflict Prevention and Stabilization Robert Jenkins; and Principal Director of Counternarcotics and Stabilization Policy at the Department of Defense Joseph McMenamin; and also from here at State, Managing Director for Policy Roman Napoli from the Office of Foreign Assistance.</p>
<p>We’re going to start off with some opening remarks from several of our briefers today, and then we’ll open it up to just a few of your questions.  Okay.  And with that, I’d like to go ahead and turn it over to Assistant Secretary Witkowsky.  Ma’am.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY WITKOWSKY:  </b>Thank you, J.T., and hello to those who have joined.  I’m Anne Witkowsky, Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations.</p>
<p>The President, with support of the U.S. Congress, has initiated a new stage in our implementation of the Global Fragility Act of 2019 and the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.  We are moving forward in a spirit of partnership to implement the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability – Haiti, Libya, Mozambique, Papua New Guinea, and the coastal West Africa region, which is Benin, Cote d’Ivoire, Ghana, Guinea, and Togo.</p>
<p>Under the strategy, we’ll begin developing comprehensive 10-year plans for each location.  These plans will emphasize locally driven solutions, long-term visions for our combined efforts, and evidence-based learning.  We recognize that close cooperation between the United States and likeminded regional, national, and local actors, including civil society, will be key to the success of the strategy.  We will tailor our shared approaches to the unique circumstances of local and regional contexts.</p>
<p>A decade-long outlook supports greater consistency across U.S. administrations and commitment to working with partners over the long term.  We will create feedback loops through monitoring and evaluations that will inform learning as we implement the plans with our partners.  In this way, the strategy presents the U.S. Government with a unique opportunity to balance a long-term view with near-term adaptation.</p>
<p>With a focus on locally driven efforts and solutions tailored to local contexts, planning under the strategy will seek to address emerging threats and address the underlying causes of violence and instability.  Our objective is to build resilience to prevent conflicts and crises from breaking out or deteriorating further.</p>
<p>This strategy requires a whole-of-government effort to integrated diplomacy, development, security-sector engagement.  We reflect this whole-of-government approach in our representation here on the call with USAID’s Rob Jenkins; Joe McMenamin, my colleague from the Defense Department; as well as Roman Napoli from the State Department’s Office of Foreign Assistance.</p>
<p>In sum, with the announcement of these priority countries, we are taking the next step to chart a new way forward in how the United States partners with other nations to address the challenges of conflict and instability.  The announcement today is also the next critical step in translating the ambitious goals of the bipartisan Global Fragility Act into reality.  Implementing the strategy will prove challenging, but it also affords us an opportunity to bring new ideas, resources, and collective action to some very pressing and important problems.  Our prosperity and security depend on peaceful, self-reliant, and stable economic and security partners.</p>
<p>With that, I will turn it over to Rob.</p>
<p><b>MR JENKINS:</b>  Well, thank you, Anne, and good morning, everyone.  An important part of the strategy and its implementation will be partnerships.  As the President has said, our diplomats, officers, and experts will work in close cooperation with multilateral organizations and a wide variety of local partners in each nation where these efforts will be pursued, including civil society organizations, community leaders, businesses, and government officials.  Those who are closest and most vulnerable to these challenges know best where the opportunities for peace and stability lie.  They represent the strongest source of promise and immunity from destabilizing forces, and we must support their strength and their resilience.</p>
<p>We know not only is going it alone not smart, it doesn’t work.  My administrator, Samantha Power of USAID, has challenged all of us to maximize the extent to which we can work directly with local partners, working in true, respectful, and effective partnership with the governments, communities and people we are trying to help.  We have learned many lessons in the last two decades, and some of them are very hard lessons.  One of them is we’re not only wasting time if we think we can impose our plan on a situation and expect to achieve success by force of will, number of boots on the ground, or amounts of dollars spent.  We’re wasting time, energy, money, and goodwill to do it alone.</p>
<p>Our lodestar must be inclusive development, working with governments and the people we’re there to help and working with on true partnerships, respectful partnerships as equals.  And inclusive development is co-creation, joint implementation, and acknowledging that we’re in support, helping our friends and partners where they are and where they live.</p>
<p>Thank you.  And with that, I’ll hand it over to Joe at the Department of Defense.</p>
<p><b>MR MCMENAMIN:</b>  Thank you, Rob.  My name, just a refresher, Joe McMenamin, and I serve as the principal director for counternarcotics and stabilization policy under the assistant secretary of defense for special operations and low-intensity conflict in the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy.  I’d like to thank you all for the opportunity to talk about Department of Defense efforts and (inaudible) in support of the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.</p>
<p>Our counternarcotics and stabilization policy office is the lead for the department’s implementation of the Global Fragility Act and is responsible for a vast set of policy issues including counternarcotics, stabilization, UN peacekeeping, and civil affairs.  Several of these areas touch Global Fragility Act issues.  The department is proud to support and has been working closely with the Department of State, USAID, and other agencies well before the Global Fragility Act was passed in December 2019.</p>
<p>We have been joined at the hip for many years, to include laying the groundwork for eventually what became the Stabilization Assistance Review, written together in a collaborative fashion.  Specific to the Global Fragility Act, we worked closely on the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability, the prologue, and the country selection.  Such efforts will continue as the Global Fragility Act implementation begins.</p>
<p>The Global Fragility Act reflects the administration’s view of emerging threats and opportunities and outlines guiding principles to inform our whole-of-government work in partnership with other countries, institutions, and organizations.  We too have learned a lot from our past stabilization experiences around the world.  One example of the lessons has been the importance of the interagency working closely together in unstable spaces to consolidate gains for long-lasting effects.  When the interagency isn’t coordinated or present, stabilization efforts are not lasting.  We, DOD, are in support of State and USAID, but it’s really a government approach to prevent conflict and promote stability.  I believe this is where the Global Fragility Act will be invaluable in achieving long-term success.</p>
<p>In the department, we’re still concerned about violent extremist organizations, as they often pose as supporters and providers of stability to the citizenry while obviously actually undermining stability of the state as a whole.  Long-term partner engagement will build resilience against violent extremist recruitment and the spread of terrorism.  DOD has a strong and lasting bilateral relationship with a lot of the Global Fragility Act selected countries led by our office, the joint staff regional offices, as well as the combatant commands.  Our combatant commands will play a key role in the implementation of this activity.</p>
<p>USAID’s Bureau of Conflict Prevention and Stabilization often assigns and has assigned liaison officers in our office, Counternarcotics and Stabilization Policy, to the combatant commands to facilitate interagency coordination.  Likewise, DOD assigns military officers at State and USAID.  Diplomacy, development, and defense cooperation are at an all-time high.</p>
<p>Finally, preventing, promoting stability, and trying to get ahead of challenges before they arise is important and difficult work.  The Global Fragility Act success depends on close cooperation and coordination between U.S. Government agencies.  And I think this is a great step forward in that endeavor.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Thank you so much, Joe.  At this point, Cynthia, would you go ahead and give the instructions again for getting into the question queue?</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Certainly, and once again, ladies and gentlemen, if you wish to ask a question, please press 1 and then 0.  You will hear a tone acknowledging that you are in queue.  We will take the questions in the order that they queue up.  You may remove yourself from queue by pressing the same 1-0 command.  So once again, 1 and then 0 for any questions or comments, and one moment, please.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Thank you so much, Cynthia.  Okay.  Let’s go for our first question to Daphne Psaledakis.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi, thank you for doing this.  The text released today mentioned the conflict in Ukraine.  How do you expect that will influence your strategy with the partner countries named today?  And along those lines, will USAID help Taiwan deliver its humanitarian assistance to Ukraine?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY WITKOWSKY:</b>  Thank you for that question.  First of all, on the selection of countries, I want to underscore that the set of countries and sub-regions illustrates our commitment to partnering with a variety of countries to respond to a variety of challenges that are weakening state capacity and legitimacy.  We want to acknowledge the complexity of these challenges in different contexts and want to work together with our partner countries, their governments, their civil society, and their private sectors to bolster their abilities and resources to resist these threats.</p>
<p>As we watch the conflict deepen and expand, the shocks of the war in Ukraine are being felt beyond Ukraine’s borders.  We are seeing it as millions have fled Ukraine to seek safe refuge and the real threat to food security for millions and millions of people worldwide in places that are already quite vulnerable to hunger.  So the effects are the – of the conflict are complex, and it will touch all aspects of affected countries, but the point here is that the strategy elevates conflict prevention as a priority and will unite our actions – our U.S. actions – in the diplomatic, development, and security sector spheres.  The events we’re seeing today reiterate the importance of an integrated U.S. whole-of-government approach tailored to these most pressing challenges in our partner countries.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR JENKINS:</b>  Thank you for the question about Ukraine.  As you probably know, USAID and our State Department colleagues are doing an amazing amount of work both inside Ukraine and outside to help IDPs, refugees; continue our support to the Ukrainian Government and communities inside Ukraine.  Unfortunately, I’m not aware of any planning regarding Taiwan and assistance to Ukraine, so I’d have to get back to you through my press office on that.  I – my not being aware does not necessarily mean there isn’t some planning going on.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Okay, let’s go to the line of Kemi Osukoya.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello?</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Yes, go ahead.  We can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Oh, okay, thank you.  I was wondering if you could talk more about your plan – your strategic plan in Africa, in particular in West Africa, in Sudan, and also Somalia.</p>
<p>Hello?  Hello, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY WITKOWSKY:</b>  Yes.  Yes, thank you very much.  Yes, thank you very much for the question.  The – yes, thank you.</p>
<p>The decisions that were taken, the selection of partner countries that we’re going forward with today within Africa, are within coastal West Africa and in Mozambique.  So we’re going to be focusing under the U.S. strategy on those countries, building on our lessons learned, and moving forward with our whole-of-government, 10-year, locally led plans.  It is, however, the case that our effort under this strategy will help us learn lessons not only as they apply to the countries that we have announced today in moving forward under the Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability, but also, we hope, in the future will be applicable to places such as the countries that you’ve identified.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  And – great.  Once again, if you’d like to get into our question queue with our briefers, dial 1 then 0.  We’ll stand by just a moment.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  And once again, that is 1 and then 0 for your questions or comments.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Okay, folks.  Well, once again, thank you so much for dialing in today.  We appreciate your participation in our briefing this afternoon.  I do want to take this opportunity to once again thank our briefers from here at the Department of State’s Bureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations, Assistant Secretary Witkowsky; our colleague from USAID, the Bureau for Conflict Prevention and Stabilization, Assistant to the Administrator Rob Jenkins; and from over at DOD, Principal Director of Counternarcotics and Stabilization Policy Joe McMenamin; and again, from here at the State Department’s Office of Foreign Assistance, Managing Director for Policy Roman Napoli.</p>
<p>Again, appreciate everyone calling in.  At this point the briefing is ended and the embargo is lifted.  Have a nice rest of your day and a nice weekend.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Thank you so much, Cynthia.  And I’ll let everybody know that while we called this a State Department briefing, it’s actually an interagency briefing today with our colleagues from USAID and the Department of Defense, whom we’re very glad to do this with today.</p>
<p>So good morning once again, everyone, and thank you for joining us.  Today we will be discussing what we can describe as the latest progress in implementing the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.  As a quick reminder here at the top, this morning’s briefing is on the record but its contents are embargoed until the end of the call.</p>
<p>Okay.  It is my pleasure to let everyone on the line know that we are joined today by Assistant Secretary of State for Conflict and Stabilization Operations Anne Witkowsky; we’re also joined by Assistant to the USAID Administrator for Conflict Prevention and Stabilization Robert Jenkins; and Principal Director of Counternarcotics and Stabilization Policy at the Department of Defense Joseph McMenamin; and also from here at State, Managing Director for Policy Roman Napoli from the Office of Foreign Assistance.</p>
<p>We’re going to start off with some opening remarks from several of our briefers today, and then we’ll open it up to just a few of your questions.  Okay.  And with that, I’d like to go ahead and turn it over to Assistant Secretary Witkowsky.  Ma’am.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY WITKOWSKY:  </b>Thank you, J.T., and hello to those who have joined.  I’m Anne Witkowsky, Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations.</p>
<p>The President, with support of the U.S. Congress, has initiated a new stage in our implementation of the Global Fragility Act of 2019 and the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.  We are moving forward in a spirit of partnership to implement the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability – Haiti, Libya, Mozambique, Papua New Guinea, and the coastal West Africa region, which is Benin, Cote d’Ivoire, Ghana, Guinea, and Togo.</p>
<p>Under the strategy, we’ll begin developing comprehensive 10-year plans for each location.  These plans will emphasize locally driven solutions, long-term visions for our combined efforts, and evidence-based learning.  We recognize that close cooperation between the United States and likeminded regional, national, and local actors, including civil society, will be key to the success of the strategy.  We will tailor our shared approaches to the unique circumstances of local and regional contexts.</p>
<p>A decade-long outlook supports greater consistency across U.S. administrations and commitment to working with partners over the long term.  We will create feedback loops through monitoring and evaluations that will inform learning as we implement the plans with our partners.  In this way, the strategy presents the U.S. Government with a unique opportunity to balance a long-term view with near-term adaptation.</p>
<p>With a focus on locally driven efforts and solutions tailored to local contexts, planning under the strategy will seek to address emerging threats and address the underlying causes of violence and instability.  Our objective is to build resilience to prevent conflicts and crises from breaking out or deteriorating further.</p>
<p>This strategy requires a whole-of-government effort to integrated diplomacy, development, security-sector engagement.  We reflect this whole-of-government approach in our representation here on the call with USAID’s Rob Jenkins; Joe McMenamin, my colleague from the Defense Department; as well as Roman Napoli from the State Department’s Office of Foreign Assistance.</p>
<p>In sum, with the announcement of these priority countries, we are taking the next step to chart a new way forward in how the United States partners with other nations to address the challenges of conflict and instability.  The announcement today is also the next critical step in translating the ambitious goals of the bipartisan Global Fragility Act into reality.  Implementing the strategy will prove challenging, but it also affords us an opportunity to bring new ideas, resources, and collective action to some very pressing and important problems.  Our prosperity and security depend on peaceful, self-reliant, and stable economic and security partners.</p>
<p>With that, I will turn it over to Rob.</p>
<p><b>MR JENKINS:</b>  Well, thank you, Anne, and good morning, everyone.  An important part of the strategy and its implementation will be partnerships.  As the President has said, our diplomats, officers, and experts will work in close cooperation with multilateral organizations and a wide variety of local partners in each nation where these efforts will be pursued, including civil society organizations, community leaders, businesses, and government officials.  Those who are closest and most vulnerable to these challenges know best where the opportunities for peace and stability lie.  They represent the strongest source of promise and immunity from destabilizing forces, and we must support their strength and their resilience.</p>
<p>We know not only is going it alone not smart, it doesn’t work.  My administrator, Samantha Power of USAID, has challenged all of us to maximize the extent to which we can work directly with local partners, working in true, respectful, and effective partnership with the governments, communities and people we are trying to help.  We have learned many lessons in the last two decades, and some of them are very hard lessons.  One of them is we’re not only wasting time if we think we can impose our plan on a situation and expect to achieve success by force of will, number of boots on the ground, or amounts of dollars spent.  We’re wasting time, energy, money, and goodwill to do it alone.</p>
<p>Our lodestar must be inclusive development, working with governments and the people we’re there to help and working with on true partnerships, respectful partnerships as equals.  And inclusive development is co-creation, joint implementation, and acknowledging that we’re in support, helping our friends and partners where they are and where they live.</p>
<p>Thank you.  And with that, I’ll hand it over to Joe at the Department of Defense.</p>
<p><b>MR MCMENAMIN:</b>  Thank you, Rob.  My name, just a refresher, Joe McMenamin, and I serve as the principal director for counternarcotics and stabilization policy under the assistant secretary of defense for special operations and low-intensity conflict in the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy.  I’d like to thank you all for the opportunity to talk about Department of Defense efforts and (inaudible) in support of the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.</p>
<p>Our counternarcotics and stabilization policy office is the lead for the department’s implementation of the Global Fragility Act and is responsible for a vast set of policy issues including counternarcotics, stabilization, UN peacekeeping, and civil affairs.  Several of these areas touch Global Fragility Act issues.  The department is proud to support and has been working closely with the Department of State, USAID, and other agencies well before the Global Fragility Act was passed in December 2019.</p>
<p>We have been joined at the hip for many years, to include laying the groundwork for eventually what became the Stabilization Assistance Review, written together in a collaborative fashion.  Specific to the Global Fragility Act, we worked closely on the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability, the prologue, and the country selection.  Such efforts will continue as the Global Fragility Act implementation begins.</p>
<p>The Global Fragility Act reflects the administration’s view of emerging threats and opportunities and outlines guiding principles to inform our whole-of-government work in partnership with other countries, institutions, and organizations.  We too have learned a lot from our past stabilization experiences around the world.  One example of the lessons has been the importance of the interagency working closely together in unstable spaces to consolidate gains for long-lasting effects.  When the interagency isn’t coordinated or present, stabilization efforts are not lasting.  We, DOD, are in support of State and USAID, but it’s really a government approach to prevent conflict and promote stability.  I believe this is where the Global Fragility Act will be invaluable in achieving long-term success.</p>
<p>In the department, we’re still concerned about violent extremist organizations, as they often pose as supporters and providers of stability to the citizenry while obviously actually undermining stability of the state as a whole.  Long-term partner engagement will build resilience against violent extremist recruitment and the spread of terrorism.  DOD has a strong and lasting bilateral relationship with a lot of the Global Fragility Act selected countries led by our office, the joint staff regional offices, as well as the combatant commands.  Our combatant commands will play a key role in the implementation of this activity.</p>
<p>USAID’s Bureau of Conflict Prevention and Stabilization often assigns and has assigned liaison officers in our office, Counternarcotics and Stabilization Policy, to the combatant commands to facilitate interagency coordination.  Likewise, DOD assigns military officers at State and USAID.  Diplomacy, development, and defense cooperation are at an all-time high.</p>
<p>Finally, preventing, promoting stability, and trying to get ahead of challenges before they arise is important and difficult work.  The Global Fragility Act success depends on close cooperation and coordination between U.S. Government agencies.  And I think this is a great step forward in that endeavor.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Thank you so much, Joe.  At this point, Cynthia, would you go ahead and give the instructions again for getting into the question queue?</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Certainly, and once again, ladies and gentlemen, if you wish to ask a question, please press 1 and then 0.  You will hear a tone acknowledging that you are in queue.  We will take the questions in the order that they queue up.  You may remove yourself from queue by pressing the same 1-0 command.  So once again, 1 and then 0 for any questions or comments, and one moment, please.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Thank you so much, Cynthia.  Okay.  Let’s go for our first question to Daphne Psaledakis.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi, thank you for doing this.  The text released today mentioned the conflict in Ukraine.  How do you expect that will influence your strategy with the partner countries named today?  And along those lines, will USAID help Taiwan deliver its humanitarian assistance to Ukraine?  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY WITKOWSKY:</b>  Thank you for that question.  First of all, on the selection of countries, I want to underscore that the set of countries and sub-regions illustrates our commitment to partnering with a variety of countries to respond to a variety of challenges that are weakening state capacity and legitimacy.  We want to acknowledge the complexity of these challenges in different contexts and want to work together with our partner countries, their governments, their civil society, and their private sectors to bolster their abilities and resources to resist these threats.</p>
<p>As we watch the conflict deepen and expand, the shocks of the war in Ukraine are being felt beyond Ukraine’s borders.  We are seeing it as millions have fled Ukraine to seek safe refuge and the real threat to food security for millions and millions of people worldwide in places that are already quite vulnerable to hunger.  So the effects are the – of the conflict are complex, and it will touch all aspects of affected countries, but the point here is that the strategy elevates conflict prevention as a priority and will unite our actions – our U.S. actions – in the diplomatic, development, and security sector spheres.  The events we’re seeing today reiterate the importance of an integrated U.S. whole-of-government approach tailored to these most pressing challenges in our partner countries.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR JENKINS:</b>  Thank you for the question about Ukraine.  As you probably know, USAID and our State Department colleagues are doing an amazing amount of work both inside Ukraine and outside to help IDPs, refugees; continue our support to the Ukrainian Government and communities inside Ukraine.  Unfortunately, I’m not aware of any planning regarding Taiwan and assistance to Ukraine, so I’d have to get back to you through my press office on that.  I – my not being aware does not necessarily mean there isn’t some planning going on.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Okay, let’s go to the line of Kemi Osukoya.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hello?</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Yes, go ahead.  We can hear you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Oh, okay, thank you.  I was wondering if you could talk more about your plan – your strategic plan in Africa, in particular in West Africa, in Sudan, and also Somalia.</p>
<p>Hello?  Hello, can you hear me?</p>
<p><b>ASSISTANT SECRETARY WITKOWSKY:</b>  Yes.  Yes, thank you very much.  Yes, thank you very much for the question.  The – yes, thank you.</p>
<p>The decisions that were taken, the selection of partner countries that we’re going forward with today within Africa, are within coastal West Africa and in Mozambique.  So we’re going to be focusing under the U.S. strategy on those countries, building on our lessons learned, and moving forward with our whole-of-government, 10-year, locally led plans.  It is, however, the case that our effort under this strategy will help us learn lessons not only as they apply to the countries that we have announced today in moving forward under the Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability, but also, we hope, in the future will be applicable to places such as the countries that you’ve identified.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  And – great.  Once again, if you’d like to get into our question queue with our briefers, dial 1 then 0.  We’ll stand by just a moment.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  And once again, that is 1 and then 0 for your questions or comments.</p>
<p><b>MR ICE:</b>  Okay, folks.  Well, once again, thank you so much for dialing in today.  We appreciate your participation in our briefing this afternoon.  I do want to take this opportunity to once again thank our briefers from here at the Department of State’s Bureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations, Assistant Secretary Witkowsky; our colleague from USAID, the Bureau for Conflict Prevention and Stabilization, Assistant to the Administrator Rob Jenkins; and from over at DOD, Principal Director of Counternarcotics and Stabilization Policy Joe McMenamin; and again, from here at the State Department’s Office of Foreign Assistance, Managing Director for Policy Roman Napoli.</p>
<p>Again, appreciate everyone calling in.  At this point the briefing is ended and the embargo is lifted.  Have a nice rest of your day and a nice weekend.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with UK Foreign Secretary Truss</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-uk-foreign-secretary-truss-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 17:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330597</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Truss emphasized the continued importance of Transatlantic unity to support Ukraine and coordinate further swift, consequential actions against those who support President Putin’s war of choice on Ukraine. The two discussed the upcoming NATO Foreign Ministerial meeting and developing additional possible actions to ratchet up our response to Putin’s continued assault on the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with UK Foreign Secretary Elizabeth Truss. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Truss emphasized the continued importance of Transatlantic unity to support Ukraine and coordinate further swift, consequential actions against those who support President Putin’s war of choice on Ukraine. The two discussed the upcoming NATO Foreign Ministerial meeting and developing additional possible actions to ratchet up our response to Putin’s continued assault on the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Jamaican Prime Minister Andrew Holness Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-jamaican-prime-minister-andrew-holness-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 15:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330557</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong>ECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good morning, everyone.  It’s a great pleasure to welcome Prime Minister Holness to Washington, to the State Department.  Great to have you here.  We now 60 years of independence to celebrate, 60 years of our own diplomatic relationship, but especially the work that we’re doing together, today, that really is making a difference and making a difference in the lives of people in both our countries.</p>
<p>I really want to applaud, Mr. Prime Minister, your very strong economic leadership in Jamaica, and our partnership in the Caribbean, which I think is never been better, and that’s in large part due to your engagement and your leadership.  So, we’re very pleased to have you here to talk about many of the issues that bring us together in our own region, but also issues that are affecting people globally – from climate to COVID, to other things.  And we’re of course, very much forward to working together on the Summit of the Americas, which is coming up.</p>
<p>So thank you very much for being here.  I’m looking forward to a good conversation.  Welcome.</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER HOLNESS:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. President, for your warm – Mr. – I keep making this (inaudible).  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>I won’t tell my boss.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for the warm welcome for me and my delegation.  We have had several meetings, which have gone very well, including a meeting with the Vice President.</p>
<p>Jamaica and the United States have had a very long and strong relationship, particularly on the people-to-people side of things.  From government-to-government perspective, Jamaica and the United States have shared values and needs.  We’re both strong democracies.  And in an era where democracy is not necessarily (inaudible) state of nations, it is very important that democracies work together to strengthen their partnerships and to explore ways in which we can help each other.</p>
<p>I am pleased to report that Jamaica has made significant progress in its microeconomic development, particularly with its fiscal stability and sustainability and debt reduction.  We were able to do this with significant help and facilitation by the United States, and we are here to express our gratitude for that help.</p>
<p>We are now at a point where we can pivot to other areas of our economic and social development, our human capital development.  Jamaica has been a net exporter of talent to the United States, and I think our longstanding people-to-people relationship, with migration back and forth, would have been mutually beneficial.  But Jamaica is in a state now where its growth potential, its growth horizon, could potentially be limited by its human resource development.  And this is an area in which we want to explore ways in which we can further partnership.</p>
<p>The present global and geopolitical instabilities have highlighted the vulnerabilities of small island developing states.  We take great note of yesterday’s announcement by President Biden regarding the release of strategic reserves.  We hope that that will have a positive effect on the reduction of oil prices, and hopefully it will be beneficial to small island countries and developing states, like Jamaica, who are facing a really very difficult time just coming out of the pandemic and then being hit with these other geopolitical issues over which we have no control or (inaudible).  We have to also discuss matters of climate change.  We met in COP, and we had very good discussions as to how small island, developing countries could be assisted and facilitated.</p>
<p>And then there is always the issue of our national security and your security interests in the region.  We are in a region which is considered near third world, and the ability of states within the region to control their domain, control their maritime borders and their land borders, is critical.  Obviously, crime and violence, (inaudible) – these are areas in which we can have great discussions and great partnerships.</p>
<p>And then there is the issue of how do we convert our democracies into prosperous economies.  That is the real challenge.  How do we get our democracies to be prosperous for our people? And And I think for smaller and developing states like Jamaica, a small shift in policy – economic policy, could result in gains that are significant both for our economies, but for your economies as well.  Jamaica considers itself to be a friendly near-shore destination for investments and production capacity.  And I think that it would be in the U.S.’s interest to look at countries like Jamaica, to position strategic production capacity which could be beneficial for the stability of production chains and supply of goods and services.</p>
<p>So Mr. President – Mr. Vice President – (laughter).  Mr. Secretary.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>PARTICIPANT:</strong>  You’re almost there.  (Laughter.)  One more step.</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER HOLNESS:</strong>  We look forward to the Summit of the Americas, and Jamaica will be attending in full force.  And I must say that we were very happy to be invited and participate in the Summit for Democracy.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong>ECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good morning, everyone.  It’s a great pleasure to welcome Prime Minister Holness to Washington, to the State Department.  Great to have you here.  We now 60 years of independence to celebrate, 60 years of our own diplomatic relationship, but especially the work that we’re doing together, today, that really is making a difference and making a difference in the lives of people in both our countries.</p>
<p>I really want to applaud, Mr. Prime Minister, your very strong economic leadership in Jamaica, and our partnership in the Caribbean, which I think is never been better, and that’s in large part due to your engagement and your leadership.  So, we’re very pleased to have you here to talk about many of the issues that bring us together in our own region, but also issues that are affecting people globally – from climate to COVID, to other things.  And we’re of course, very much forward to working together on the Summit of the Americas, which is coming up.</p>
<p>So thank you very much for being here.  I’m looking forward to a good conversation.  Welcome.</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER HOLNESS:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. President, for your warm – Mr. – I keep making this (inaudible).  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>I won’t tell my boss.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for the warm welcome for me and my delegation.  We have had several meetings, which have gone very well, including a meeting with the Vice President.</p>
<p>Jamaica and the United States have had a very long and strong relationship, particularly on the people-to-people side of things.  From government-to-government perspective, Jamaica and the United States have shared values and needs.  We’re both strong democracies.  And in an era where democracy is not necessarily (inaudible) state of nations, it is very important that democracies work together to strengthen their partnerships and to explore ways in which we can help each other.</p>
<p>I am pleased to report that Jamaica has made significant progress in its microeconomic development, particularly with its fiscal stability and sustainability and debt reduction.  We were able to do this with significant help and facilitation by the United States, and we are here to express our gratitude for that help.</p>
<p>We are now at a point where we can pivot to other areas of our economic and social development, our human capital development.  Jamaica has been a net exporter of talent to the United States, and I think our longstanding people-to-people relationship, with migration back and forth, would have been mutually beneficial.  But Jamaica is in a state now where its growth potential, its growth horizon, could potentially be limited by its human resource development.  And this is an area in which we want to explore ways in which we can further partnership.</p>
<p>The present global and geopolitical instabilities have highlighted the vulnerabilities of small island developing states.  We take great note of yesterday’s announcement by President Biden regarding the release of strategic reserves.  We hope that that will have a positive effect on the reduction of oil prices, and hopefully it will be beneficial to small island countries and developing states, like Jamaica, who are facing a really very difficult time just coming out of the pandemic and then being hit with these other geopolitical issues over which we have no control or (inaudible).  We have to also discuss matters of climate change.  We met in COP, and we had very good discussions as to how small island, developing countries could be assisted and facilitated.</p>
<p>And then there is always the issue of our national security and your security interests in the region.  We are in a region which is considered near third world, and the ability of states within the region to control their domain, control their maritime borders and their land borders, is critical.  Obviously, crime and violence, (inaudible) – these are areas in which we can have great discussions and great partnerships.</p>
<p>And then there is the issue of how do we convert our democracies into prosperous economies.  That is the real challenge.  How do we get our democracies to be prosperous for our people? And And I think for smaller and developing states like Jamaica, a small shift in policy – economic policy, could result in gains that are significant both for our economies, but for your economies as well.  Jamaica considers itself to be a friendly near-shore destination for investments and production capacity.  And I think that it would be in the U.S.’s interest to look at countries like Jamaica, to position strategic production capacity which could be beneficial for the stability of production chains and supply of goods and services.</p>
<p>So Mr. President – Mr. Vice President – (laughter).  Mr. Secretary.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>PARTICIPANT:</strong>  You’re almost there.  (Laughter.)  One more step.</p>
<p><strong>PRIME MINISTER HOLNESS:</strong>  We look forward to the Summit of the Americas, and Jamaica will be attending in full force.  And I must say that we were very happy to be invited and participate in the Summit for Democracy.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Recognizing National Arab American Heritage Month</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/recognizing-national-arab-american-heritage-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 15:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>This month, we recognize National Arab American Heritage Month and honor the contributions of this diverse community to America. Immigrants with origins from the Arab world have been arriving to the United States since before our country’s independence and have contributed to our nation’s advancements in science, business, technology, foreign policy, and national security. The litany is long and includes Private Nathan Badeen, a Syrian immigrant who fought and gave his life during the American Revolution. At the State Department, we recognize tremendous diplomats such as Ambassador Philip Habib, former Under Secretary for Political Affairs, who played a prominent role in the Vietnam peace talks resulting in the 1973 Paris Peace Accords and later successfully pursued a ceasefire in Lebanon. We also recognize Ambassador Selwa “Lucky” Roosevelt, who served the President and Secretary of State as the Chief of Protocol of the United States from 1982-1989, nearly 7 years and longer than anyone else prior. The Department is fortunate to have had these and so many other talented Arab American colleagues, who strive every day to protect and promote the interests and values of the American people, while representing the United States to the world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>This month, we recognize National Arab American Heritage Month and honor the contributions of this diverse community to America. Immigrants with origins from the Arab world have been arriving to the United States since before our country’s independence and have contributed to our nation’s advancements in science, business, technology, foreign policy, and national security. The litany is long and includes Private Nathan Badeen, a Syrian immigrant who fought and gave his life during the American Revolution. At the State Department, we recognize tremendous diplomats such as Ambassador Philip Habib, former Under Secretary for Political Affairs, who played a prominent role in the Vietnam peace talks resulting in the 1973 Paris Peace Accords and later successfully pursued a ceasefire in Lebanon. We also recognize Ambassador Selwa “Lucky” Roosevelt, who served the President and Secretary of State as the Chief of Protocol of the United States from 1982-1989, nearly 7 years and longer than anyone else prior. The Department is fortunate to have had these and so many other talented Arab American colleagues, who strive every day to protect and promote the interests and values of the American people, while representing the United States to the world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability: Priority Countries and Region</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-u-s-strategy-to-prevent-conflict-and-promote-stability-priority-countries-and-region/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 13:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330519</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is being released jointly by the U.S. Department of State, the U.S. Department of the Treasury, the U.S. Department of Defense, and the U.S. Agency for International Development.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The U.S. Government is moving forward in the spirit of partnership with four countries and a regional grouping of countries to implement the ten-year U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.  This represents an important milestone and next step in the realization of the goals of the landmark Global Fragility Act, which continues to enjoy strong bipartisan Congressional support for innovative efforts to foster a more peaceful and stable world.  In light of the horrific events unfolding in Ukraine caused by Putin’s unprovoked and brutal war, the United States reaffirms its commitment to strengthen global resiliency and democratic renewal, and promote peaceful, self-reliant nations that become U.S. economic and security partners.</p>
<p>Our partner countries under the Strategy include Haiti, Libya, Mozambique, Papua New Guinea, and a grouping of Coastal West African countries comprised of Benin, Côte d’Ivoire, Ghana, Guinea, and Togo.  Each collaboration presents a unique opportunity to leverage lessons learned from decades of U.S. involvement overseas, to enhance the way the U.S. Government engages in challenging environments, and to jointly build resilience against political, economic, and natural shocks.</p>
<p>The U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability outlines a ten-year, whole-of-government effort to foster peace and long-term stability through integrated diplomacy, development, and security-sector engagement.  The Strategy builds upon and strengthens the work done to implement the U.S. Strategy on Women, Peace, and Security, the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act, and ongoing efforts to prevent and counter violent extremism.  It will leverage and advance other priorities, such as to promote democracy, good governance, and respect for human rights; advance gender equality; counter corruption; reduce the risks of the climate crisis; and bring an end to the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>The Strategy’s flexible approach is designed to take into account and address the underlying causes of violence and instability before conflicts and crises can break out or deteriorate.  The Strategy seeks to tailor our shared approach to the unique circumstances of each local and regional context, and to elevate local voices to jointly seek on-the-ground solutions to prevent conflict.  The United States will take a long-term view, working closely with like-minded and committed local partners.  Pursuant to the Strategy, we will support stabilization in areas where violence impedes development and threatens U.S. and partner strategic interests.  These efforts will improve lives and livelihoods in the process.</p>
<p>Our work is rooted in a deep and abiding commitment to put diplomacy and shared values first.  Success will require strong leadership, patience, creativity, and a constructive relationship with our international and local partners.  Peacebuilding and conflict prevention are needed now more than ever, and the United States looks forward to working with others to create a more peaceful world.</p>
<p>The full Strategy can be viewed at <a href="https://www.state.gov/stability-strategy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.state.gov/stability-strategy/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1648905471357000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3lbRpBvdN7fpQzGLzjFm3l">https://www.state.gov/<wbr />stability-strategy/</a>.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p>FOR MORE INFORMATION, MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT <a href="mailto:CSOPublicAffairs1@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSOPublicAffairs1@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is being released jointly by the U.S. Department of State, the U.S. Department of the Treasury, the U.S. Department of Defense, and the U.S. Agency for International Development.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>The U.S. Government is moving forward in the spirit of partnership with four countries and a regional grouping of countries to implement the ten-year U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.  This represents an important milestone and next step in the realization of the goals of the landmark Global Fragility Act, which continues to enjoy strong bipartisan Congressional support for innovative efforts to foster a more peaceful and stable world.  In light of the horrific events unfolding in Ukraine caused by Putin’s unprovoked and brutal war, the United States reaffirms its commitment to strengthen global resiliency and democratic renewal, and promote peaceful, self-reliant nations that become U.S. economic and security partners.</p>
<p>Our partner countries under the Strategy include Haiti, Libya, Mozambique, Papua New Guinea, and a grouping of Coastal West African countries comprised of Benin, Côte d’Ivoire, Ghana, Guinea, and Togo.  Each collaboration presents a unique opportunity to leverage lessons learned from decades of U.S. involvement overseas, to enhance the way the U.S. Government engages in challenging environments, and to jointly build resilience against political, economic, and natural shocks.</p>
<p>The U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability outlines a ten-year, whole-of-government effort to foster peace and long-term stability through integrated diplomacy, development, and security-sector engagement.  The Strategy builds upon and strengthens the work done to implement the U.S. Strategy on Women, Peace, and Security, the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act, and ongoing efforts to prevent and counter violent extremism.  It will leverage and advance other priorities, such as to promote democracy, good governance, and respect for human rights; advance gender equality; counter corruption; reduce the risks of the climate crisis; and bring an end to the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>The Strategy’s flexible approach is designed to take into account and address the underlying causes of violence and instability before conflicts and crises can break out or deteriorate.  The Strategy seeks to tailor our shared approach to the unique circumstances of each local and regional context, and to elevate local voices to jointly seek on-the-ground solutions to prevent conflict.  The United States will take a long-term view, working closely with like-minded and committed local partners.  Pursuant to the Strategy, we will support stabilization in areas where violence impedes development and threatens U.S. and partner strategic interests.  These efforts will improve lives and livelihoods in the process.</p>
<p>Our work is rooted in a deep and abiding commitment to put diplomacy and shared values first.  Success will require strong leadership, patience, creativity, and a constructive relationship with our international and local partners.  Peacebuilding and conflict prevention are needed now more than ever, and the United States looks forward to working with others to create a more peaceful world.</p>
<p>The full Strategy can be viewed at <a href="https://www.state.gov/stability-strategy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.state.gov/stability-strategy/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1648905471357000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3lbRpBvdN7fpQzGLzjFm3l">https://www.state.gov/<wbr />stability-strategy/</a>.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p>FOR MORE INFORMATION, MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT <a href="mailto:CSOPublicAffairs1@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSOPublicAffairs1@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
