<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 18:58:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken to Participate in a Conversation on 21st Century Diplomacy and Global Challenges with University of Michigan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinken-to-participate-in-a-conversation-on-21st-century-diplomacy-and-global-challenges-with-university-of-michigan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 18:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=334046</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will participate in a virtual, moderated conversation on 21st century diplomacy and global challenges at 1:15 p.m. on Thursday, April 14, 2022.  The Gerald R. Ford School of Public Policy at the University of Michigan will host Secretary Blinken.  The event comprises the Ford School’s fourth annual Vandenberg Lecture.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken’s remarks will be live-streamed on <a href="http://state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTMuNTYzNzY2MzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi8ifQ.qj_yVuRbJowYan1VHeHz2oJs4I5Dd9AnJc6ESIIE8RM/s/1006560560/br/129766124885-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649962422313000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2KwVpYxrtmu8IO90IKMLof">www.state.gov</a> and <a class="external-link" href="http://www.YouTube.com/statedept" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">www.YouTube.com/statedept</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact the Office of Press Relations at <a href="mailto:EventsandTravel@State.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EventsandTravel@State.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will participate in a virtual, moderated conversation on 21st century diplomacy and global challenges at 1:15 p.m. on Thursday, April 14, 2022.  The Gerald R. Ford School of Public Policy at the University of Michigan will host Secretary Blinken.  The event comprises the Ford School’s fourth annual Vandenberg Lecture.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken’s remarks will be live-streamed on <a href="http://state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTMuNTYzNzY2MzEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnN0YXRlLmdvdi8ifQ.qj_yVuRbJowYan1VHeHz2oJs4I5Dd9AnJc6ESIIE8RM/s/1006560560/br/129766124885-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649962422313000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2KwVpYxrtmu8IO90IKMLof">www.state.gov</a> and <a class="external-link" href="http://www.YouTube.com/statedept" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">www.YouTube.com/statedept</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact the Office of Press Relations at <a href="mailto:EventsandTravel@State.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EventsandTravel@State.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement by Secretary Antony Blinken and Foreign Minister Francisco Bustillo</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-by-secretary-antony-blinken-and-foreign-minister-francisco-bustillo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 17:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=334010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and Uruguay:</p>
<p><i>Begin Text.</i></p>
<p>At the invitation of Secretary of State Antony Blinken, Uruguayan Foreign Minister Francisco Bustillo traveled to Washington D.C. on Tuesday April 12, 2022.</p>
<p>During their meeting, they reviewed the U.S.-Uruguay bilateral relationship and discussed various global issues, including Russia’s unjustified, unprovoked war against Ukraine.  In addition to the tragic human toll of the conflict, both parties are concerned about the disruption to the global food supply chain and potential global food crisis.</p>
<p>They also spoke about the importance of bilateral trade and pandemic recovery for the region.  They expressed mutual support for the successful conclusion of the negotiations between Uruguay and the U.S. Trade Representative to update and modernize the Trade and Investment Framework.  These updates can deepen commercial ties, improve the investment climate, and enhance opportunities for small businesses.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Bustillo agreed to launch an annual bilateral Interministerial Dialogue to coordinate on priority areas such as political, economic-commercial, investment, technology, cultural and academic, among others.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minster Bustillo also discussed the upcoming Ninth Summit of the Americas in June as well as commitments to improve democratic governance throughout the 2022 Year of Action made during the December 2021 Summit for Democracy.</p>
<p>This meeting demonstrated that the United States and Uruguay share similar values and highlighted our strong cooperation in areas such as multilateralism, climate change, peacekeeping and cybersecurity.</p>
<p><i>End Text. </i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and Uruguay:</p>
<p><i>Begin Text.</i></p>
<p>At the invitation of Secretary of State Antony Blinken, Uruguayan Foreign Minister Francisco Bustillo traveled to Washington D.C. on Tuesday April 12, 2022.</p>
<p>During their meeting, they reviewed the U.S.-Uruguay bilateral relationship and discussed various global issues, including Russia’s unjustified, unprovoked war against Ukraine.  In addition to the tragic human toll of the conflict, both parties are concerned about the disruption to the global food supply chain and potential global food crisis.</p>
<p>They also spoke about the importance of bilateral trade and pandemic recovery for the region.  They expressed mutual support for the successful conclusion of the negotiations between Uruguay and the U.S. Trade Representative to update and modernize the Trade and Investment Framework.  These updates can deepen commercial ties, improve the investment climate, and enhance opportunities for small businesses.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Bustillo agreed to launch an annual bilateral Interministerial Dialogue to coordinate on priority areas such as political, economic-commercial, investment, technology, cultural and academic, among others.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minster Bustillo also discussed the upcoming Ninth Summit of the Americas in June as well as commitments to improve democratic governance throughout the 2022 Year of Action made during the December 2021 Summit for Democracy.</p>
<p>This meeting demonstrated that the United States and Uruguay share similar values and highlighted our strong cooperation in areas such as multilateralism, climate change, peacekeeping and cybersecurity.</p>
<p><i>End Text. </i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Egyptian Foreign Minister Sameh Shoukry before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-egyptian-foreign-minister-sameh-shoukry-before-their-meeting-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 15:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Good morning, everyone.  And Minister Sameh, welcome.  It’s wonderful, as always, to have you here.</p>
<p>It’s a particular pleasure for me to be able to welcome the foreign minister.  We were together<b> </b>just a few weeks ago in the Negev for what was an extraordinary occasion, a meeting with our counterparts from Israel, the UAE, Morocco, Bahrain, our two countries – a picture that would have been hard to imagine just a few years ago, except that, actually, Egypt would have imagined it, because Egypt was, many, many years ago, the groundbreaker in establishing its relationship with Israel and, in so many ways since then, has been at the heart of stability in the region, working for peace, working for security, and doing so in strategic partnership with the United States, something that we deeply value and deeply appreciate.</p>
<p>So this is – we – when we saw each other we agreed it would be a good time to pursue our own conversations about that partnership that we will do today.</p>
<p>This happens to mark, as well, the centennial of diplomatic relations between Egypt and the United States.  There is a lot of history but, I hope, a lot of good history we can actually make together in the months and years ahead.</p>
<p>So a lot to talk about across the region and globally.  It’s very good to have you here, and I welcome you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER SHOUKRY:</b>  Well, Secretary Blinken, Tony, it is great to be here.  It’s always a pleasure to be back in Washington and to be working on strengthening what is an important relationship for Egypt.</p>
<p>The strategic partnership that exists now between Egypt and the United States over four decades has been mutually beneficial, and I believe there is much more work for both of us to do to further strengthen the relationship, and also to deal with the various challenges that I believe we can only meet through the continuing of our cooperation and our interaction.</p>
<p>And I am happy to have this opportunity to be with you again after our previous discussions when we met, and certainly this is a good opportunity for our third meeting this year, as a matter of honoring the centennial, and I’m sure that there will be further opportunities as the year progresses.</p>
<p>But once again, to highlight the importance that Egypt attaches to the multifaceted and very deep relationship that exists between Egypt and the United States, and our commitment to continue to work on strengthening that relationship and finding new areas of cooperation.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.  Thank you all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Good morning, everyone.  And Minister Sameh, welcome.  It’s wonderful, as always, to have you here.</p>
<p>It’s a particular pleasure for me to be able to welcome the foreign minister.  We were together<b> </b>just a few weeks ago in the Negev for what was an extraordinary occasion, a meeting with our counterparts from Israel, the UAE, Morocco, Bahrain, our two countries – a picture that would have been hard to imagine just a few years ago, except that, actually, Egypt would have imagined it, because Egypt was, many, many years ago, the groundbreaker in establishing its relationship with Israel and, in so many ways since then, has been at the heart of stability in the region, working for peace, working for security, and doing so in strategic partnership with the United States, something that we deeply value and deeply appreciate.</p>
<p>So this is – we – when we saw each other we agreed it would be a good time to pursue our own conversations about that partnership that we will do today.</p>
<p>This happens to mark, as well, the centennial of diplomatic relations between Egypt and the United States.  There is a lot of history but, I hope, a lot of good history we can actually make together in the months and years ahead.</p>
<p>So a lot to talk about across the region and globally.  It’s very good to have you here, and I welcome you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER SHOUKRY:</b>  Well, Secretary Blinken, Tony, it is great to be here.  It’s always a pleasure to be back in Washington and to be working on strengthening what is an important relationship for Egypt.</p>
<p>The strategic partnership that exists now between Egypt and the United States over four decades has been mutually beneficial, and I believe there is much more work for both of us to do to further strengthen the relationship, and also to deal with the various challenges that I believe we can only meet through the continuing of our cooperation and our interaction.</p>
<p>And I am happy to have this opportunity to be with you again after our previous discussions when we met, and certainly this is a good opportunity for our third meeting this year, as a matter of honoring the centennial, and I’m sure that there will be further opportunities as the year progresses.</p>
<p>But once again, to highlight the importance that Egypt attaches to the multifaceted and very deep relationship that exists between Egypt and the United States, and our commitment to continue to work on strengthening that relationship and finding new areas of cooperation.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.  Thank you all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Remarks with Indian External Affairs Minister Dr. S. Jaishankar As Part of the U.S.-India Higher Education Discussion</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-remarks-with-indian-external-affairs-minister-dr-s-jaishankar-as-part-of-the-u-s-india-higher-education-discussion/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 02:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333832</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Howard University</p>
<p><strong>MR WUTOH:</strong>  Good afternoon.  Secretary of State Antony Blinken, Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs Ms. Lee Satterfield, Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs Donald Lu, Ambassador of India to the United States of America Ambassador Sandhu, Minister of External Affairs of the Government of India Minister Jaishankar, staff members of the Department of State, employees of the Embassy of India, alumni of exchange programs of the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs, Howard University students, faculty, staff, and distinguished visitors, I’m Dr. Anthony Wutoh.  I’m provost and chief academic officer of Howard University.</p>
<p>And it is certainly my pleasure to welcome you to the historic Founders Library, the national treasure of Howard University.  The library is the home of the university’s museum and Moorland-Spingarn Research Center, one of the world’s largest repositories dedicated to the history and culture of people of African descent.  It is also home to the bust of Mahatma Gandhi the Government of India gave to Dr. Martin Luther King when he was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1964.  The King family donated it to Howard University upon his death.</p>
<p>It is fitting that Howard is the setting in which to celebrate the educational and cultural exchanges that undergird the strong bilateral relationship between India and the United States of America.  Indian and Indian American students and faculty have called Howard alma mater since the turn of the last century, including perhaps our most celebrated Indian American alumna, Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>
<p>This year, JSS Academy of Higher Education &amp; Research and Howard University celebrated the tenth anniversary of our partnership.  Our schools work cooperatively on curriculum development and conduct faculty exchanges.  Pharmacy students and students from other disciplines from both schools conduct clinical rotations at our respective hospitals in Washington and in Mysore.  And Howard’s relationship with the Department of State is just as rich.</p>
<p>I am proud to note Howard is a Historically Black College and University institutional leader, a major producer of Fulbright scholars and researchers.  All of the Howard undergraduate students in the audience today are Larry Palmer envoys.  The Palmer envoys program is named after Ambassador Larry Palmer, who served as Howard’s ambassador of residence from 2018 until his unfortunate passing last April.</p>
<p>Selected from HBCUs across the country, Palmer envoys are students interested in international affairs.  The biweekly sessions demystify the State Department and make it more accessible to exceptional students who might not otherwise consider State Department exchanges, fellowships, and employment.  Ambassador Palmer also oversaw all of the diplomatic fellowships administered by Howard University – the Pickering, Rangel, and Payne fellowship programs.  His envoys are a tribute to his commitment and to the future of the diplomatic corps.  I’ll ask for a second if the Palmer envoys will please stand and be recognized.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>It is now my pleasure to invite to the podium the 75th United States Secretary of State, Secretary Antony Blinken.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good afternoon, everyone, and it is absolutely wonderful to be in this incredible setting with so much history as well as such an extraordinary future here with our Palmer colleagues.  I actually was going to ask if we could have class outside – (laughter) – but, and I should point out that I changed my pin.  I’ve been pinned by Howard University and I’m honored by that.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>So Mr. Provost, thank you so much for the introduction and for your leadership here at Howard.  And to my good friend, to my colleague, the Foreign Minister of India Jaishankar, thank you for being with us today for now the second day in a row.  We spent all day yesterday together, starting at breakfast, ending at dinner.  We had an incredibly productive session of what we call our 2+2, the foreign ministers and defense ministers of both of our countries working together on a common agenda and punctuated, I would say, by a really important virtual meeting between Prime Minister Modi and President Biden.</p>
<p>So we’re grateful and I am also so pleased to have our friend and colleague, the Indian ambassador here, Ambassador Sandhu, Assistant Secretary Satterfield, Assistant Secretary Lu, and many colleagues from the department.  Thank you, each and every one of you, for being here today and also for helping bring us together today.</p>
<p>It is incredibly fitting that we’re meeting at Howard University to talk about how to deepen the educational ties between India and the United States.  As I have come to learn, and as we heard a little bit about, throughout its history this institution has played an important role in building bonds between our countries.  And really, it’s hard to overstate the importance of those bonds not just as we look back but, I believe, as we go forward.</p>
<p>Let me tell you about one key figure from what has been already a very storied past.  Howard Thurman, former dean of Rankin Chapel here at Howard, I’m sure familiar to many of you.  Going back to September of 1935, Thurman led a four-member delegation on what was a monthslong pilgrimage to India.  He was trying to find lessons from the country’s independence movement that might be relevant to the racial justice movement in the United States.</p>
<p>Near the end of the trip, Thurman met with Mahatma Gandhi.  They talked, the books record, for about three hours, covering a wide range of issues: segregation, faith, nonviolent resistance.  The conversation and the trip made a lasting impression on Thurman.  So when he came back to Howard, he developed his interpretation of nonviolence – not as a political tactic, but as a spiritual lifestyle.  He shared his views with sermons, speeches, and eventually what came to be an incredibly influential book, <em>Jesus and the Disinherited</em>.</p>
<p>So Gandhi’s views and Thurman’s interpretation of those views – of nonviolence – they, of course, would influence one of the greatest figures in our nation’s journey, Martin Luther King, Jr.  As he traveled the country laying bare the sins of segregation, Dr. King carried two books with him.  One was the Bible, the other <em>Jesus and the Disinherited</em>.</p>
<p>These connections and so many others across our shared history make clear that our people do share a special bond, and that as the world’s oldest and largest democracies, our countries always have something to learn from each other.</p>
<p>That’s why we see our cultural and educational ties continue to grow every single year.  We’re incredibly fortunate in the United States to have 200,000 Indians studying at our universities, enriching our campuses, enriching our fellow citizens.  And we see many American students studying and working in India through programs like Fulbright, the Gilman fellowships, including some who are here today.</p>
<p>To make it easier for people to continue learning from each other, Jai and I announced yesterday a working group, a Working Group on Education and Skill Training, which will bring academic institutions in the United States and India together to develop new joint research programs.  The group will also focus on creating more opportunities for universities to partner on exchange programs that Assistant Secretary Satterfield runs so that ultimately more of our people can learn alongside each other.</p>
<p>Now, I know I don’t need to tell this group about the importance of building stronger bonds between our higher education systems.  Many of you have benefited from studying in each other’s countries.  And you’re using that knowledge now to teach in the other’s country.  That’s a very powerful thing.  You’re developing recommendations on how India and the United States can support each other’s clean energy transitions.  You’re promoting trade between our countries and more equitable opportunities that flow from that trade.  And that’s just to name a few examples of the things that people are working on.</p>
<p>So in foreign policy, one of the things we talk a lot about is the importance, the strength, the imperative of people-to-people ties.  We do a lot of work as diplomats between our countries, but ultimately what really matters are those bonds between our people – between students, between businessmen and women, between academics, between tourists and others.  This is what really brings us together.</p>
<p>And when we’re talking about that, in effect we’re talking about you: those who do the daily work of sharing their perspectives, sharing their knowledge with each other, and in so doing, building what are really lifelong personal and professional relationships with each other.  That’s what makes all the difference because these kinds of connections, the people-to-people connections, many of them fostered by the exchange programs that we run, they actually build lifelong connections and a lifelong appreciation for each other’s countries, cultures, histories, and futures.  And as a result, we are better able to take on shared challenges together.</p>
<p>I believe firmly that we will need your continued collaboration, your hard work, your leadership for the biggest challenges we face, whether it’s combating COVID, whether it’s building a more inclusive global economy, whether it’s tackling the climate crisis.</p>
<p>To put it another way, the U.S.-India Strategic Partnership, I am convinced, is absolutely crucial, essential, for addressing the problems of the 21st century, and your work is at the heart of that relationship.</p>
<p>So I’m really anxious to hear about some of the experiences that you’ve had, your ideas for how we can better develop, better deepen the educational and cultural ties between India and the United States.</p>
<p>Before we do that, though, it’s a great pleasure to turn it over to my friend, Foreign Minister Jaishankar.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</strong>  Secretary of State Tony Blinken, Ambassador Sandhu, Assistant Secretary Satterfield, Assistant Secretary Lu, my colleague, additional Secretary Vani Rao, Honorable Provost, faculty, students:  Let me say what a great pleasure it is to join you all today at this education event at Howard University.  And I really thank the Department of State and the Indian Embassy for this initiative and, of course, the university for hosting us.</p>
<p>Many of you would be wondering why two foreign ministers who clearly had a fairly busy day yesterday chose to meet again at an education event at a university.  And the answer is that our business as foreign ministers, as diplomats, is about connecting countries, connecting societies, and we do that through connecting people.</p>
<p>And when it comes to people, the most natural place to focus is on young minds with a curiosity about the world, of people whose lives are still very much ahead of them.  If our presence today enhances your interest in India-U.S. relations, then I can say, and I’m sure, Tony, you would agree with this, that it’s a good day’s work for us.</p>
<p>But there is also a particular reason why I think the Howard University is a appropriate venue for this exercise.  When we speak about the India-U.S. connect, the most powerful symbol of that is the inspirational bond between Mahatma Gandhi and Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., that Secretary Blinken also spoke about.  And as he told us, that bond was forged through the relationship which was build by Howard Thurman, the dean of the chapel, and later by Dr. William Stuart Nelson, who was the dean of the School of Religion.  It is also fitting that this university hosted in September last year the Gandhi-King Lecture, which was delivered by Ambassador Sandhu here, and is currently celebrating the India Hawadiya.</p>
<p>But Howard University is not just a part of our shared past.  It is very much part of the future that awaits us.  As we contemplate that future, a big part of that, a big role in that, is going to be played by the relationship between our two countries, and that relationship has undergone a real transformation in the last two decades.  Whether it is our strategic and security cooperation or our economic or technology partnerships, it is making its weight increasingly felt in world affairs.</p>
<p>A key driver of this change has been its human element.  The 4.4 million Indian diaspora has literally defined our image in this society and helped forge relationships that are an enormous source of strength for us in our work.  At its center are students, academics, researchers, and professionals who have contributed to America’s progress even as they remain the bridge between our two societies.</p>
<p>For our ties to grow it is equally necessary that there is a better understanding of India and the world on the part of young Americans.  Your appreciation of a civilizational state and a democratic – and a fellow democratic polity that is daily overcoming enormous odds is essential.  After all, we are natural partners only when our people have a strong sense of connect.</p>
<p>And that is why Secretary Blinken and I were especially pleased yesterday to launch the Working Group on Education and Skill Development that he spoke about.  It will enable us to explore a range of opportunities that exist in the field of education, research, innovation, and entrepreneurship.</p>
<p>We are also committed to taking forward the proposal for the Gandhi-King Development Foundation to implement social development projects in India.  And in doing so, we would help realize the vision of Congressman John Lewis, who initiated congressional legislation in that regard.</p>
<p>Policymakers in both countries are sharply aware of the immense difference that our educational collaboration can make.  On the Indian side, our 2020 National Education Policy contemplates, indeed prioritizes, international cooperation in education.</p>
<p>At the American end, we recognize the renewed focus on the STEM sector, including in activities that a group which we are both part of called the Quad.  The Quad is – among its many activities is focused on STEM fellowships.  I know that my colleague, Education Minister Dharmendra Pradhan, is looking forward to engaging more intensively on developing this important facet of our relationship.</p>
<p>So let me conclude by once again underlining how important it is to develop and nurture these people-to-people linkages.  I’m confident that Howard University and other educational institutions will be enthusiastic partners in this endeavor.  Thank you very much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:  </strong>And thank you, Mr. Secretary, Minister Jaishankar.  I’m Lee Satterfield, the assistant secretary of state for Educational and Cultural Affairs.  Our bureau’s mission is to increase mutual understanding between people in the United States and people of other countries.  Today, we have a host of students, faculty, and staff with us who have an outsized interest in international affairs.  In fact, some of our academic exchange scholars are here today, past participants of the Fulbright program, the Benjamin Gilman program, and the Critical Language Scholarship program.  I’m so pleased to be able to moderate today’s discussion, so let’s get started.</p>
<p>I want to first call on Angel Bryant.  Angel is sophomore International Affairs major who is a 2019-2020 Global Citizen Year India Fellow and a 2021-22 Palmer Envoy.  Angel has a question for both of you.  Angel.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>My question is:  What made you all interested in international relations?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>I’m anxious to hear the answer, too.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER JAISHANKAR:  </strong>I really have to think for a moment because it’s been so long a part of my life.  Why did I start getting interested in the world?  I think part of it was probably an interest in music that – you heard music beyond your own, and then you wondered: what kind of music, where is it from, what kind of people?  I think the food part of it came much later.  (Laughter.)  It was easier to afford music than food when you were younger.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Some of it really – I also came from a family environment, which was a little bit international.  In fact, I mean, we talk of educational professional exchanges.  My father came here when I was about 10 years old on a fellowship – in fact, on a Rockefeller Fellowship – to study and to do some sort of professional training here.  So I think, again, there’s a little bit of parental influence.</p>
<p>And I guess, in a way this – I’m talking now of the 1960s, ‘70s.  It may sound like prehistory to you.  (Laughter.)  But it was really a time when the world was beginning to globalize much more.  I mean, there were more tourists, people – the idea of traveling abroad, of seeing other cultures come – I mean, every time actually you would have something foreign happen in your school or university, there’d be tremendous excitement about it.</p>
<p>I guess it was a combination of all those things.  And I still – the first music album that – foreign music album that I ever heard, which actually was a American album, a 1959 album called The Hitmakers.  I actually now have it in Spotify.  (Laughter.)  And I still listen to it for reasons of nostalgia.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, thank you for sharing that, and thanks for the question.  It’s interesting because you hear these stories about what drove people to do a certain thing, to pursue a certain career, and I think for a lot of us there is often – not always, but often – a connection of what you hear around the breakfast table at home.</p>
<p>And in my case, I had parents and grandparents who in one way or another were relatively recent immigrants to the United States and had stories of one kind or another that I think really put in a sort of spotlight for me what our country at its best – which is not always the case – can represent to the world.  And I heard that from a very young age.  I had my grandfather who fled pogroms in, interestingly enough, what is now Ukraine back at the turn of the last century; later, a stepmother who fled communists from Hungary; a stepfather who survived the concentration camps and was liberated by the United States.  And these stories and others were a big part of it.</p>
<p>But then I had an experience at a young age that also ties into what we’re talking about, and that is the experience of actually living abroad as an American.  When I was nine years old, we moved to France, and I moved there with my mom and my stepdad.  And I spent nine years in France from age nine to 18, all the way through high school.  And that experience – actually living abroad, seeing your own country through the eyes of others, expanding your own horizons to a different country, culture – and being, of course, in France, that opened up all of Europe with a Eurail pass and a few other things back in the day – that had a profound impact.</p>
<p>And one of the things that happens when you’re an American abroad – and this was roughly the same period as Jai was talking about – for me, this was – we moved in 1971.  There was a lot going on in the world in the ’70s, as there is today.  And whether it was the Vietnam War which was still happening, whether it was the Cold War which remained – what seemed to be its height, whether it was conflict in the Middle East, all of these things were part of the conversations that we were having in school.  And because America, one way or another, was often in the middle of these things, you’d find yourself almost acting like a junior diplomat, somehow representing your country, defending it, getting into conversations, discussions, arguments.</p>
<p>And I think that as much as anything else really got me interested in foreign policy generally and in diplomacy.  How do we find ways to have these conversations?  How do we find ways to try to bring people together who are bringing so many different perspectives to bear on the questions of the day?  And so that was really, I think, what drove me.</p>
<p>But I’ll say one last thing because I think it’s important especially to folks who are just starting out.  I managed to try a whole bunch of different things before I wound up doing what I’m doing, and finding that I had virtually no talent for any of them – (laughter) – wound up where I am.  But it’s important if you have the opportunity to try different things because you may not figure out what it is that you want to do right away.  If you’re fortunate, you will figure it out.  And for those of you who are pursuing the international fellowships and exchanges, you probably already have a pretty decent idea.  That’s a great thing, it’s a powerful thing, but don’t panic if you don’t figure it out exactly right away.  If you have the luxury of being able to try these things, experience these things, open yourselves to the world, that in and of itself is a great thing.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  Wonderful perspectives, thank you.  Thank you, Angel, for that question.</p>
<p>Now I’d like to call on Jasdeep Matharu, a first generation Indian American and proud Howard alumnae.  He has a question for the minister.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  My question is the COVID-19 pandemic saw an effective India-U.S. research cooperation in the health care sector.  Do you expect this STEM research cooperation to strengthen in the coming days, and if so, which are the priority areas for you?</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</strong>  The COVID experience, which has been enormously stressful and in many ways scarring for all of us, if there was a silver lining to it, it actually also showed what friendships and relationships across the world could do.  So again, when we speak about you discovered the world, you made friends, you went abroad, a lot of that is personal when you begin out.  They can make a huge difference for your country or, frankly, for the world when you start doing it as a policy or as a – as part of your work.</p>
<p>Now, the case of the COVID, we actually have three vaccines in India which we are producing which are a direct outcome of our relationship with the United States – the Novovax, the Corbevax, and the Janssen.  The – but it wasn’t, again, just the vaccines.  In fact, during that period, I must share with you a episode when we – everybody was – everybody who could make vaccines was busy making vaccines, so it then became difficult to get the supply chain going because it would tend to get disproportionately kind of sucked in by – in some places.</p>
<p>And I remember at that time reaching out to Tony Blinken and coming here and sharing with him what were all the things we needed in India so that the supply chains which are coming out of the United States would function smoothly and allow for the vaccines to be made.  And really, I counted as one of the great achievements in that year that we could actually scale up vaccine production in that way, and it wouldn’t have happened if we had not known.  And I will say, I mean, at the risk of embarrassing him, that he really went out of his way to move the American system and get things done.</p>
<p>Now, last year – some of you would remember last summer – in India we went through a very severe, severe wave of COVID due to the Delta wave.  And the Delta wave attacked the respiratory system in a much more aggressive fashion, so we had enormous demand for oxygen, for respirators, for certain drugs which were particularly effective for Delta treatment.  And there again, I mean, a lot of countries came forward, but I would say the country which really stood out there was the United States.</p>
<p>So the point I am making is, I mean, you can look at it from many angles.  Okay.  When I look at students coming here, right, I’ve heard, for example, to the focus on STEM.  Now, when students come here, they become part of a research community.  A lot of it gets into breakthroughs and innovations in various fields.  It ends up as inventions, as contributions which affect daily life, especially in a crisis situation like this.  So you can see what’s an ordinary person’s normal activity which suddenly translates cumulatively into something very big for countries.  And how to actually make that unfold, a lot of that depends on the comfort levels we have, the relationships we’ve built.</p>
<p>And today, I think a part of the very strong trust and bonding between our two countries is this human element that I spoke to in my remarks, the fact that four and a half million Indian diaspora lives here, that people travel back and forth, that there – and often there are students and professionals who have spent time here and gone back to India.  And again, on our side, I mean, we would like, for example, to see many more American students come and study in India, many more American businesses come there, more tourists come there.  Because all of this in some way adds to the real sort of, I would say, chemistry and – between our countries.</p>
<p>So the COVID’s really been, to me, very instructive – what relationships can mean, how they can really deliver at a time of need.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  Thank you so much, and thank you for that question.  I’d now like to call on Savon Jackson.  He is the program manager for the Charles B. Rangel International Affairs Program here at Howard.  He has a question for the Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  So my question is:  So while programs like the Fulbright and Gilman scholarships have been great entry points for individuals like myself to learn about India, how else can the U.S. and India partner to encourage more American students to pursue studies within India?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  And first of all, congratulations on what you’re doing and what you’ve achieved.  It’s a great thing.  And I should really probably turn that over to Assistant Secretary Satterfield, because this is exactly the focus of her activities.</p>
<p>But we are looking across all different pursuits how we can find ways to connect our countries, including through exchange programs, through fellowship programs, through academic programs, to make that easier and to try to open minds to the prospect of the possibility of doing that.  I think you heard very eloquently from Foreign Minister Jaishankar why that matters and why that makes such a difference.</p>
<p>I would just say from my own experience – and I said this before, and this is one of the things that we’re going to spend some time talking about over the next few years – if we can find more ways to give people the opportunity to experience the rest of the world, and especially one of the most vibrant, vital partners and, of course, democracies in the world like India, that’s ultimately going to redound to, I think, the personal benefit of the people who have that experience, but honestly, it’s going to redound to the benefit of our country as a whole.  And I want to make sure that we’re doing a good job both in getting that message out but also in finding ways to support it.</p>
<p>So the assistant secretary runs an extraordinary part of the State Department that’s responsible for building exactly these kinds of programs.  And so one of the things we’re doing, especially as we emerge from COVID, is finding ways to further revitalize, re-energize, and carry forward all these programs.</p>
<p>Now, one of the things that’s really helpful is actually when we get good ideas, because we don’t have a monopoly on ideas, never mind good ideas.  So there may be things that are missing that people identify as, well, here is an area where we really could pursue an interesting exchange, and then we need to know that.  We need to get your input.  We need to get your ideas, your thoughts.  And some of that is going to just come from your own experience, from what you’re hearing from your friends and fellow students, and we want to find ways to bring that to the department to try to explore that.</p>
<p>So we’ve got, Lee, I don’t know how many different ongoing things that we’re doing, but a lot, but we’re trying to build on them.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  Hundreds.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Hundreds literally.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>So here’s one of the interesting things too, and I’ve said this a lot and it goes both ways.  One of the extraordinary things about the exchange programs that we have when we bring, for example, young Indians to the United States, but also from countries around the world, is we’ve been pretty good over the years in identifying the rising generation of people.  And when we’ve gone back and looked at the numbers – and these numbers are a little out of date, but for people participating in our exchange programs over the years coming from other countries, usually at a young age, they went – they would then eventually go back home, and of those over the many years we’ve had more than 50 who went on to win Nobel Prizes; more than 350 who went on to become the leaders, the presidents, the prime ministers of their countries; thousands who went on to lead companies, academic institutions, become prominent in culture and the arts.  And I think the same thing is also true, I suspect, of the many people that we – many Americans that we send to engage in these programs.</p>
<p>And then what happens is, is it builds connections between our people and our countries that outlast any particular government or administration and that build a lasting foundation for our countries to come together.</p>
<p>The last thing I’ll say is this, and here’s the way we look at it, and again, it’s why I think this foundation is so important.  When we’re thinking about the problems that we have to try to tackle that are actually affecting the lives of virtually every American in one way or another, the first realization you come to is that we simply can’t effectively deal with these problems alone, that we need to be working in collaboration, in cooperation, in coordination with other countries.</p>
<p>Climate:  We are 15 percent of global emissions.  We also have a long historic legacy of having built up emissions, but we’re 15 percent.  Even if we do everything right at home, that still leaves 85 percent of emissions from other parts of the world.  So we have a strong interest in trying to find ways to work cooperatively as well as to help countries that need the support to adapt, to build resilience, as they’re making their own transitions.</p>
<p>And COVID, where this part – the work that we’ve done together, it hasn’t simply been to the benefit of both of our countries.  It has increasingly been to the benefit of countries throughout the Indo-Pacific region and beyond.  The Quad partnership that we put together: 500 million vaccines being donated, distributed, particularly in the Indo-Pacific region.  But on COVID, if we’re not working together with other countries – again, even if we did everything right at home, if there is another – if the virus keeps percolating out there somewhere and new variants develop, one of those variants may come back and bite us.  So we have a strong interest in it, but we can’t do it without this collaboration.  This is a powerful thing that we did.  We had the United States, India, Japan, Australia come together and say we’re going to take pieces of this together, we’re going to manufacture, we’re going to help finance, we’re going to help distribute, and we’re going to get vaccines to people.</p>
<p>And then finally, on all of the emerging technologies, which is something that the United States and India have to work on together, we have to do everything we can to try to shape the rules and the norms and the standards by which these technologies are used because, maybe more than anything else, these phones in our pockets shape our lives – in good ways and sometimes in bad ways.</p>
<p>I say all of that because, again, it starts – our ability to do that starts with you.  It starts with these exchange programs.  It starts with building these connections, building these relationships, building these friendships, building this appreciation for different countries and cultures.  If we get that right, then I’m convinced that no matter what you do in your career or your lives, in some way it’s going to be beneficial not just to you but to the relationship between our countries, relationships that are more necessary than ever if we’re really going to meet the problems that all of our countries face, and maybe find some real opportunity in them too.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.  And you’ll be glad to know, to your point about where good ideas are generated, already some students and members of the faculty here at Howard have already approached me with ideas about more exchanges that we can do and ideas that they have that they’ve already shared with me.  So thank you for that.</p>
<p>And the Secretary has also made it a priority for my bureau to make it possible for more Americans to participate in study abroad and programs like that you’ve had the experience to do.  So to that point, it’s through strategic partnerships with Howard University and others all across the country, and he’s asked us to look at creating more of those around the United States.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  And Lee, can I just say – because I really – this is so important to those of you who have done this, who participate in it.  President Biden likes to say – I’ve often heard him say this – don’t just keep the faith, spread the faith.  (Laughter.)  So if you’ve done it, if you know it, if it’s been a good experience for you, share that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  Exactly.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  &#8212; with your friends.  Share that with your fellow students.  Open their eyes, open their minds, to that possibility.  And that, more than anything else, is also what’s going to encourage people to take that chance, take that opportunity.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  Absolutely.</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</strong>  By the way, I must tell you.  You know Prime Minister Modi was one of those who came on an exchange &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  That’s right, that’s right.</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</strong>  Yes, on an exchange program.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  IVLP.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So we were pretty good.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  Thank you.  So next I’d like to ask Lyndsie Whitehead.  She’s a Presidential Award of Service recipient and a globally-minded educator.  She has the next question for the minister.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you both so much for such a robust conversation today.  My question is as follows:  India has announced the new National Education Policy 2020.  How do you intend to attract U.S. students to the study in – to study in India and also to participate in the Study in India program?</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</strong>  Well, the Study in India program has been there for some time.  The education policy came into being in 2020.  Of course, after that we had the COVID.  So it’s interesting it’s now that we are really focusing on how do we attract more international students and obviously among them more American students.</p>
<p>It’s still, quite honestly, work in progress, but the – what has changed is a much stronger appreciation of the need to have international students.  I think the view – we have long had a tradition, but we haven’t scaled it up the way many countries have.  We realize you can’t necessarily leave it to students themselves.  There have got to be programs.  There have got to be mechanisms, efforts which would actually – there’s got to be a strong pull factor.</p>
<p>So part of what we are hoping to do with the working group that we announced yesterday is to address exactly this problem that we would definitely like to see many more international students.  We believe it’s good for our universities.  We believe it’s good for our students.  And as all of us have clearly recognized today, these exchange programs have a benefit which is way beyond actually the takeaways of the person concerned.  The consequence is huge.</p>
<p>So in different ways we would try to encourage.  It could be short-term exchanges.  It could be having students do their degree in India, create fellowships which would facilitate that.  So I think there’s a whole sort of menu there in the making, and I hope a lot of what we have done in recent years has been to grow our relationship.  And to me the education part of it, particularly the idea of more Americans studying in India, that’s one area where we have not done as well as we would have liked to.  I think it’s something – it’s time to address that more effectively, and I’m very sure that we will do so.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  Thank you.  And Mr. Minister, I will work on that.  (Laughter.)  Thank you.  And unfortunately, we’re out of time.  This conversation could go on forever.  It’s been so terrific.  I want to thank you for your thoughtful questions and thank the Secretary and the minister for their insights and discussion.  It’s been a robust discussion.  On behalf of our distinguished guests, I want to thank you all for being here.  Have a good day.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you all.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Howard University</p>
<p><strong>MR WUTOH:</strong>  Good afternoon.  Secretary of State Antony Blinken, Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs Ms. Lee Satterfield, Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs Donald Lu, Ambassador of India to the United States of America Ambassador Sandhu, Minister of External Affairs of the Government of India Minister Jaishankar, staff members of the Department of State, employees of the Embassy of India, alumni of exchange programs of the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs, Howard University students, faculty, staff, and distinguished visitors, I’m Dr. Anthony Wutoh.  I’m provost and chief academic officer of Howard University.</p>
<p>And it is certainly my pleasure to welcome you to the historic Founders Library, the national treasure of Howard University.  The library is the home of the university’s museum and Moorland-Spingarn Research Center, one of the world’s largest repositories dedicated to the history and culture of people of African descent.  It is also home to the bust of Mahatma Gandhi the Government of India gave to Dr. Martin Luther King when he was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1964.  The King family donated it to Howard University upon his death.</p>
<p>It is fitting that Howard is the setting in which to celebrate the educational and cultural exchanges that undergird the strong bilateral relationship between India and the United States of America.  Indian and Indian American students and faculty have called Howard alma mater since the turn of the last century, including perhaps our most celebrated Indian American alumna, Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>
<p>This year, JSS Academy of Higher Education &amp; Research and Howard University celebrated the tenth anniversary of our partnership.  Our schools work cooperatively on curriculum development and conduct faculty exchanges.  Pharmacy students and students from other disciplines from both schools conduct clinical rotations at our respective hospitals in Washington and in Mysore.  And Howard’s relationship with the Department of State is just as rich.</p>
<p>I am proud to note Howard is a Historically Black College and University institutional leader, a major producer of Fulbright scholars and researchers.  All of the Howard undergraduate students in the audience today are Larry Palmer envoys.  The Palmer envoys program is named after Ambassador Larry Palmer, who served as Howard’s ambassador of residence from 2018 until his unfortunate passing last April.</p>
<p>Selected from HBCUs across the country, Palmer envoys are students interested in international affairs.  The biweekly sessions demystify the State Department and make it more accessible to exceptional students who might not otherwise consider State Department exchanges, fellowships, and employment.  Ambassador Palmer also oversaw all of the diplomatic fellowships administered by Howard University – the Pickering, Rangel, and Payne fellowship programs.  His envoys are a tribute to his commitment and to the future of the diplomatic corps.  I’ll ask for a second if the Palmer envoys will please stand and be recognized.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>It is now my pleasure to invite to the podium the 75th United States Secretary of State, Secretary Antony Blinken.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good afternoon, everyone, and it is absolutely wonderful to be in this incredible setting with so much history as well as such an extraordinary future here with our Palmer colleagues.  I actually was going to ask if we could have class outside – (laughter) – but, and I should point out that I changed my pin.  I’ve been pinned by Howard University and I’m honored by that.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>So Mr. Provost, thank you so much for the introduction and for your leadership here at Howard.  And to my good friend, to my colleague, the Foreign Minister of India Jaishankar, thank you for being with us today for now the second day in a row.  We spent all day yesterday together, starting at breakfast, ending at dinner.  We had an incredibly productive session of what we call our 2+2, the foreign ministers and defense ministers of both of our countries working together on a common agenda and punctuated, I would say, by a really important virtual meeting between Prime Minister Modi and President Biden.</p>
<p>So we’re grateful and I am also so pleased to have our friend and colleague, the Indian ambassador here, Ambassador Sandhu, Assistant Secretary Satterfield, Assistant Secretary Lu, and many colleagues from the department.  Thank you, each and every one of you, for being here today and also for helping bring us together today.</p>
<p>It is incredibly fitting that we’re meeting at Howard University to talk about how to deepen the educational ties between India and the United States.  As I have come to learn, and as we heard a little bit about, throughout its history this institution has played an important role in building bonds between our countries.  And really, it’s hard to overstate the importance of those bonds not just as we look back but, I believe, as we go forward.</p>
<p>Let me tell you about one key figure from what has been already a very storied past.  Howard Thurman, former dean of Rankin Chapel here at Howard, I’m sure familiar to many of you.  Going back to September of 1935, Thurman led a four-member delegation on what was a monthslong pilgrimage to India.  He was trying to find lessons from the country’s independence movement that might be relevant to the racial justice movement in the United States.</p>
<p>Near the end of the trip, Thurman met with Mahatma Gandhi.  They talked, the books record, for about three hours, covering a wide range of issues: segregation, faith, nonviolent resistance.  The conversation and the trip made a lasting impression on Thurman.  So when he came back to Howard, he developed his interpretation of nonviolence – not as a political tactic, but as a spiritual lifestyle.  He shared his views with sermons, speeches, and eventually what came to be an incredibly influential book, <em>Jesus and the Disinherited</em>.</p>
<p>So Gandhi’s views and Thurman’s interpretation of those views – of nonviolence – they, of course, would influence one of the greatest figures in our nation’s journey, Martin Luther King, Jr.  As he traveled the country laying bare the sins of segregation, Dr. King carried two books with him.  One was the Bible, the other <em>Jesus and the Disinherited</em>.</p>
<p>These connections and so many others across our shared history make clear that our people do share a special bond, and that as the world’s oldest and largest democracies, our countries always have something to learn from each other.</p>
<p>That’s why we see our cultural and educational ties continue to grow every single year.  We’re incredibly fortunate in the United States to have 200,000 Indians studying at our universities, enriching our campuses, enriching our fellow citizens.  And we see many American students studying and working in India through programs like Fulbright, the Gilman fellowships, including some who are here today.</p>
<p>To make it easier for people to continue learning from each other, Jai and I announced yesterday a working group, a Working Group on Education and Skill Training, which will bring academic institutions in the United States and India together to develop new joint research programs.  The group will also focus on creating more opportunities for universities to partner on exchange programs that Assistant Secretary Satterfield runs so that ultimately more of our people can learn alongside each other.</p>
<p>Now, I know I don’t need to tell this group about the importance of building stronger bonds between our higher education systems.  Many of you have benefited from studying in each other’s countries.  And you’re using that knowledge now to teach in the other’s country.  That’s a very powerful thing.  You’re developing recommendations on how India and the United States can support each other’s clean energy transitions.  You’re promoting trade between our countries and more equitable opportunities that flow from that trade.  And that’s just to name a few examples of the things that people are working on.</p>
<p>So in foreign policy, one of the things we talk a lot about is the importance, the strength, the imperative of people-to-people ties.  We do a lot of work as diplomats between our countries, but ultimately what really matters are those bonds between our people – between students, between businessmen and women, between academics, between tourists and others.  This is what really brings us together.</p>
<p>And when we’re talking about that, in effect we’re talking about you: those who do the daily work of sharing their perspectives, sharing their knowledge with each other, and in so doing, building what are really lifelong personal and professional relationships with each other.  That’s what makes all the difference because these kinds of connections, the people-to-people connections, many of them fostered by the exchange programs that we run, they actually build lifelong connections and a lifelong appreciation for each other’s countries, cultures, histories, and futures.  And as a result, we are better able to take on shared challenges together.</p>
<p>I believe firmly that we will need your continued collaboration, your hard work, your leadership for the biggest challenges we face, whether it’s combating COVID, whether it’s building a more inclusive global economy, whether it’s tackling the climate crisis.</p>
<p>To put it another way, the U.S.-India Strategic Partnership, I am convinced, is absolutely crucial, essential, for addressing the problems of the 21st century, and your work is at the heart of that relationship.</p>
<p>So I’m really anxious to hear about some of the experiences that you’ve had, your ideas for how we can better develop, better deepen the educational and cultural ties between India and the United States.</p>
<p>Before we do that, though, it’s a great pleasure to turn it over to my friend, Foreign Minister Jaishankar.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</strong>  Secretary of State Tony Blinken, Ambassador Sandhu, Assistant Secretary Satterfield, Assistant Secretary Lu, my colleague, additional Secretary Vani Rao, Honorable Provost, faculty, students:  Let me say what a great pleasure it is to join you all today at this education event at Howard University.  And I really thank the Department of State and the Indian Embassy for this initiative and, of course, the university for hosting us.</p>
<p>Many of you would be wondering why two foreign ministers who clearly had a fairly busy day yesterday chose to meet again at an education event at a university.  And the answer is that our business as foreign ministers, as diplomats, is about connecting countries, connecting societies, and we do that through connecting people.</p>
<p>And when it comes to people, the most natural place to focus is on young minds with a curiosity about the world, of people whose lives are still very much ahead of them.  If our presence today enhances your interest in India-U.S. relations, then I can say, and I’m sure, Tony, you would agree with this, that it’s a good day’s work for us.</p>
<p>But there is also a particular reason why I think the Howard University is a appropriate venue for this exercise.  When we speak about the India-U.S. connect, the most powerful symbol of that is the inspirational bond between Mahatma Gandhi and Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., that Secretary Blinken also spoke about.  And as he told us, that bond was forged through the relationship which was build by Howard Thurman, the dean of the chapel, and later by Dr. William Stuart Nelson, who was the dean of the School of Religion.  It is also fitting that this university hosted in September last year the Gandhi-King Lecture, which was delivered by Ambassador Sandhu here, and is currently celebrating the India Hawadiya.</p>
<p>But Howard University is not just a part of our shared past.  It is very much part of the future that awaits us.  As we contemplate that future, a big part of that, a big role in that, is going to be played by the relationship between our two countries, and that relationship has undergone a real transformation in the last two decades.  Whether it is our strategic and security cooperation or our economic or technology partnerships, it is making its weight increasingly felt in world affairs.</p>
<p>A key driver of this change has been its human element.  The 4.4 million Indian diaspora has literally defined our image in this society and helped forge relationships that are an enormous source of strength for us in our work.  At its center are students, academics, researchers, and professionals who have contributed to America’s progress even as they remain the bridge between our two societies.</p>
<p>For our ties to grow it is equally necessary that there is a better understanding of India and the world on the part of young Americans.  Your appreciation of a civilizational state and a democratic – and a fellow democratic polity that is daily overcoming enormous odds is essential.  After all, we are natural partners only when our people have a strong sense of connect.</p>
<p>And that is why Secretary Blinken and I were especially pleased yesterday to launch the Working Group on Education and Skill Development that he spoke about.  It will enable us to explore a range of opportunities that exist in the field of education, research, innovation, and entrepreneurship.</p>
<p>We are also committed to taking forward the proposal for the Gandhi-King Development Foundation to implement social development projects in India.  And in doing so, we would help realize the vision of Congressman John Lewis, who initiated congressional legislation in that regard.</p>
<p>Policymakers in both countries are sharply aware of the immense difference that our educational collaboration can make.  On the Indian side, our 2020 National Education Policy contemplates, indeed prioritizes, international cooperation in education.</p>
<p>At the American end, we recognize the renewed focus on the STEM sector, including in activities that a group which we are both part of called the Quad.  The Quad is – among its many activities is focused on STEM fellowships.  I know that my colleague, Education Minister Dharmendra Pradhan, is looking forward to engaging more intensively on developing this important facet of our relationship.</p>
<p>So let me conclude by once again underlining how important it is to develop and nurture these people-to-people linkages.  I’m confident that Howard University and other educational institutions will be enthusiastic partners in this endeavor.  Thank you very much.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:  </strong>And thank you, Mr. Secretary, Minister Jaishankar.  I’m Lee Satterfield, the assistant secretary of state for Educational and Cultural Affairs.  Our bureau’s mission is to increase mutual understanding between people in the United States and people of other countries.  Today, we have a host of students, faculty, and staff with us who have an outsized interest in international affairs.  In fact, some of our academic exchange scholars are here today, past participants of the Fulbright program, the Benjamin Gilman program, and the Critical Language Scholarship program.  I’m so pleased to be able to moderate today’s discussion, so let’s get started.</p>
<p>I want to first call on Angel Bryant.  Angel is sophomore International Affairs major who is a 2019-2020 Global Citizen Year India Fellow and a 2021-22 Palmer Envoy.  Angel has a question for both of you.  Angel.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>My question is:  What made you all interested in international relations?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>I’m anxious to hear the answer, too.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER JAISHANKAR:  </strong>I really have to think for a moment because it’s been so long a part of my life.  Why did I start getting interested in the world?  I think part of it was probably an interest in music that – you heard music beyond your own, and then you wondered: what kind of music, where is it from, what kind of people?  I think the food part of it came much later.  (Laughter.)  It was easier to afford music than food when you were younger.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Some of it really – I also came from a family environment, which was a little bit international.  In fact, I mean, we talk of educational professional exchanges.  My father came here when I was about 10 years old on a fellowship – in fact, on a Rockefeller Fellowship – to study and to do some sort of professional training here.  So I think, again, there’s a little bit of parental influence.</p>
<p>And I guess, in a way this – I’m talking now of the 1960s, ‘70s.  It may sound like prehistory to you.  (Laughter.)  But it was really a time when the world was beginning to globalize much more.  I mean, there were more tourists, people – the idea of traveling abroad, of seeing other cultures come – I mean, every time actually you would have something foreign happen in your school or university, there’d be tremendous excitement about it.</p>
<p>I guess it was a combination of all those things.  And I still – the first music album that – foreign music album that I ever heard, which actually was a American album, a 1959 album called The Hitmakers.  I actually now have it in Spotify.  (Laughter.)  And I still listen to it for reasons of nostalgia.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, thank you for sharing that, and thanks for the question.  It’s interesting because you hear these stories about what drove people to do a certain thing, to pursue a certain career, and I think for a lot of us there is often – not always, but often – a connection of what you hear around the breakfast table at home.</p>
<p>And in my case, I had parents and grandparents who in one way or another were relatively recent immigrants to the United States and had stories of one kind or another that I think really put in a sort of spotlight for me what our country at its best – which is not always the case – can represent to the world.  And I heard that from a very young age.  I had my grandfather who fled pogroms in, interestingly enough, what is now Ukraine back at the turn of the last century; later, a stepmother who fled communists from Hungary; a stepfather who survived the concentration camps and was liberated by the United States.  And these stories and others were a big part of it.</p>
<p>But then I had an experience at a young age that also ties into what we’re talking about, and that is the experience of actually living abroad as an American.  When I was nine years old, we moved to France, and I moved there with my mom and my stepdad.  And I spent nine years in France from age nine to 18, all the way through high school.  And that experience – actually living abroad, seeing your own country through the eyes of others, expanding your own horizons to a different country, culture – and being, of course, in France, that opened up all of Europe with a Eurail pass and a few other things back in the day – that had a profound impact.</p>
<p>And one of the things that happens when you’re an American abroad – and this was roughly the same period as Jai was talking about – for me, this was – we moved in 1971.  There was a lot going on in the world in the ’70s, as there is today.  And whether it was the Vietnam War which was still happening, whether it was the Cold War which remained – what seemed to be its height, whether it was conflict in the Middle East, all of these things were part of the conversations that we were having in school.  And because America, one way or another, was often in the middle of these things, you’d find yourself almost acting like a junior diplomat, somehow representing your country, defending it, getting into conversations, discussions, arguments.</p>
<p>And I think that as much as anything else really got me interested in foreign policy generally and in diplomacy.  How do we find ways to have these conversations?  How do we find ways to try to bring people together who are bringing so many different perspectives to bear on the questions of the day?  And so that was really, I think, what drove me.</p>
<p>But I’ll say one last thing because I think it’s important especially to folks who are just starting out.  I managed to try a whole bunch of different things before I wound up doing what I’m doing, and finding that I had virtually no talent for any of them – (laughter) – wound up where I am.  But it’s important if you have the opportunity to try different things because you may not figure out what it is that you want to do right away.  If you’re fortunate, you will figure it out.  And for those of you who are pursuing the international fellowships and exchanges, you probably already have a pretty decent idea.  That’s a great thing, it’s a powerful thing, but don’t panic if you don’t figure it out exactly right away.  If you have the luxury of being able to try these things, experience these things, open yourselves to the world, that in and of itself is a great thing.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  Wonderful perspectives, thank you.  Thank you, Angel, for that question.</p>
<p>Now I’d like to call on Jasdeep Matharu, a first generation Indian American and proud Howard alumnae.  He has a question for the minister.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  My question is the COVID-19 pandemic saw an effective India-U.S. research cooperation in the health care sector.  Do you expect this STEM research cooperation to strengthen in the coming days, and if so, which are the priority areas for you?</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</strong>  The COVID experience, which has been enormously stressful and in many ways scarring for all of us, if there was a silver lining to it, it actually also showed what friendships and relationships across the world could do.  So again, when we speak about you discovered the world, you made friends, you went abroad, a lot of that is personal when you begin out.  They can make a huge difference for your country or, frankly, for the world when you start doing it as a policy or as a – as part of your work.</p>
<p>Now, the case of the COVID, we actually have three vaccines in India which we are producing which are a direct outcome of our relationship with the United States – the Novovax, the Corbevax, and the Janssen.  The – but it wasn’t, again, just the vaccines.  In fact, during that period, I must share with you a episode when we – everybody was – everybody who could make vaccines was busy making vaccines, so it then became difficult to get the supply chain going because it would tend to get disproportionately kind of sucked in by – in some places.</p>
<p>And I remember at that time reaching out to Tony Blinken and coming here and sharing with him what were all the things we needed in India so that the supply chains which are coming out of the United States would function smoothly and allow for the vaccines to be made.  And really, I counted as one of the great achievements in that year that we could actually scale up vaccine production in that way, and it wouldn’t have happened if we had not known.  And I will say, I mean, at the risk of embarrassing him, that he really went out of his way to move the American system and get things done.</p>
<p>Now, last year – some of you would remember last summer – in India we went through a very severe, severe wave of COVID due to the Delta wave.  And the Delta wave attacked the respiratory system in a much more aggressive fashion, so we had enormous demand for oxygen, for respirators, for certain drugs which were particularly effective for Delta treatment.  And there again, I mean, a lot of countries came forward, but I would say the country which really stood out there was the United States.</p>
<p>So the point I am making is, I mean, you can look at it from many angles.  Okay.  When I look at students coming here, right, I’ve heard, for example, to the focus on STEM.  Now, when students come here, they become part of a research community.  A lot of it gets into breakthroughs and innovations in various fields.  It ends up as inventions, as contributions which affect daily life, especially in a crisis situation like this.  So you can see what’s an ordinary person’s normal activity which suddenly translates cumulatively into something very big for countries.  And how to actually make that unfold, a lot of that depends on the comfort levels we have, the relationships we’ve built.</p>
<p>And today, I think a part of the very strong trust and bonding between our two countries is this human element that I spoke to in my remarks, the fact that four and a half million Indian diaspora lives here, that people travel back and forth, that there – and often there are students and professionals who have spent time here and gone back to India.  And again, on our side, I mean, we would like, for example, to see many more American students come and study in India, many more American businesses come there, more tourists come there.  Because all of this in some way adds to the real sort of, I would say, chemistry and – between our countries.</p>
<p>So the COVID’s really been, to me, very instructive – what relationships can mean, how they can really deliver at a time of need.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  Thank you so much, and thank you for that question.  I’d now like to call on Savon Jackson.  He is the program manager for the Charles B. Rangel International Affairs Program here at Howard.  He has a question for the Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  So my question is:  So while programs like the Fulbright and Gilman scholarships have been great entry points for individuals like myself to learn about India, how else can the U.S. and India partner to encourage more American students to pursue studies within India?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.  And first of all, congratulations on what you’re doing and what you’ve achieved.  It’s a great thing.  And I should really probably turn that over to Assistant Secretary Satterfield, because this is exactly the focus of her activities.</p>
<p>But we are looking across all different pursuits how we can find ways to connect our countries, including through exchange programs, through fellowship programs, through academic programs, to make that easier and to try to open minds to the prospect of the possibility of doing that.  I think you heard very eloquently from Foreign Minister Jaishankar why that matters and why that makes such a difference.</p>
<p>I would just say from my own experience – and I said this before, and this is one of the things that we’re going to spend some time talking about over the next few years – if we can find more ways to give people the opportunity to experience the rest of the world, and especially one of the most vibrant, vital partners and, of course, democracies in the world like India, that’s ultimately going to redound to, I think, the personal benefit of the people who have that experience, but honestly, it’s going to redound to the benefit of our country as a whole.  And I want to make sure that we’re doing a good job both in getting that message out but also in finding ways to support it.</p>
<p>So the assistant secretary runs an extraordinary part of the State Department that’s responsible for building exactly these kinds of programs.  And so one of the things we’re doing, especially as we emerge from COVID, is finding ways to further revitalize, re-energize, and carry forward all these programs.</p>
<p>Now, one of the things that’s really helpful is actually when we get good ideas, because we don’t have a monopoly on ideas, never mind good ideas.  So there may be things that are missing that people identify as, well, here is an area where we really could pursue an interesting exchange, and then we need to know that.  We need to get your input.  We need to get your ideas, your thoughts.  And some of that is going to just come from your own experience, from what you’re hearing from your friends and fellow students, and we want to find ways to bring that to the department to try to explore that.</p>
<p>So we’ve got, Lee, I don’t know how many different ongoing things that we’re doing, but a lot, but we’re trying to build on them.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  Hundreds.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Hundreds literally.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>So here’s one of the interesting things too, and I’ve said this a lot and it goes both ways.  One of the extraordinary things about the exchange programs that we have when we bring, for example, young Indians to the United States, but also from countries around the world, is we’ve been pretty good over the years in identifying the rising generation of people.  And when we’ve gone back and looked at the numbers – and these numbers are a little out of date, but for people participating in our exchange programs over the years coming from other countries, usually at a young age, they went – they would then eventually go back home, and of those over the many years we’ve had more than 50 who went on to win Nobel Prizes; more than 350 who went on to become the leaders, the presidents, the prime ministers of their countries; thousands who went on to lead companies, academic institutions, become prominent in culture and the arts.  And I think the same thing is also true, I suspect, of the many people that we – many Americans that we send to engage in these programs.</p>
<p>And then what happens is, is it builds connections between our people and our countries that outlast any particular government or administration and that build a lasting foundation for our countries to come together.</p>
<p>The last thing I’ll say is this, and here’s the way we look at it, and again, it’s why I think this foundation is so important.  When we’re thinking about the problems that we have to try to tackle that are actually affecting the lives of virtually every American in one way or another, the first realization you come to is that we simply can’t effectively deal with these problems alone, that we need to be working in collaboration, in cooperation, in coordination with other countries.</p>
<p>Climate:  We are 15 percent of global emissions.  We also have a long historic legacy of having built up emissions, but we’re 15 percent.  Even if we do everything right at home, that still leaves 85 percent of emissions from other parts of the world.  So we have a strong interest in trying to find ways to work cooperatively as well as to help countries that need the support to adapt, to build resilience, as they’re making their own transitions.</p>
<p>And COVID, where this part – the work that we’ve done together, it hasn’t simply been to the benefit of both of our countries.  It has increasingly been to the benefit of countries throughout the Indo-Pacific region and beyond.  The Quad partnership that we put together: 500 million vaccines being donated, distributed, particularly in the Indo-Pacific region.  But on COVID, if we’re not working together with other countries – again, even if we did everything right at home, if there is another – if the virus keeps percolating out there somewhere and new variants develop, one of those variants may come back and bite us.  So we have a strong interest in it, but we can’t do it without this collaboration.  This is a powerful thing that we did.  We had the United States, India, Japan, Australia come together and say we’re going to take pieces of this together, we’re going to manufacture, we’re going to help finance, we’re going to help distribute, and we’re going to get vaccines to people.</p>
<p>And then finally, on all of the emerging technologies, which is something that the United States and India have to work on together, we have to do everything we can to try to shape the rules and the norms and the standards by which these technologies are used because, maybe more than anything else, these phones in our pockets shape our lives – in good ways and sometimes in bad ways.</p>
<p>I say all of that because, again, it starts – our ability to do that starts with you.  It starts with these exchange programs.  It starts with building these connections, building these relationships, building these friendships, building this appreciation for different countries and cultures.  If we get that right, then I’m convinced that no matter what you do in your career or your lives, in some way it’s going to be beneficial not just to you but to the relationship between our countries, relationships that are more necessary than ever if we’re really going to meet the problems that all of our countries face, and maybe find some real opportunity in them too.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.  And you’ll be glad to know, to your point about where good ideas are generated, already some students and members of the faculty here at Howard have already approached me with ideas about more exchanges that we can do and ideas that they have that they’ve already shared with me.  So thank you for that.</p>
<p>And the Secretary has also made it a priority for my bureau to make it possible for more Americans to participate in study abroad and programs like that you’ve had the experience to do.  So to that point, it’s through strategic partnerships with Howard University and others all across the country, and he’s asked us to look at creating more of those around the United States.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  And Lee, can I just say – because I really – this is so important to those of you who have done this, who participate in it.  President Biden likes to say – I’ve often heard him say this – don’t just keep the faith, spread the faith.  (Laughter.)  So if you’ve done it, if you know it, if it’s been a good experience for you, share that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  Exactly.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  &#8212; with your friends.  Share that with your fellow students.  Open their eyes, open their minds, to that possibility.  And that, more than anything else, is also what’s going to encourage people to take that chance, take that opportunity.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  Absolutely.</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</strong>  By the way, I must tell you.  You know Prime Minister Modi was one of those who came on an exchange &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  That’s right, that’s right.</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</strong>  Yes, on an exchange program.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  IVLP.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  So we were pretty good.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  Thank you.  So next I’d like to ask Lyndsie Whitehead.  She’s a Presidential Award of Service recipient and a globally-minded educator.  She has the next question for the minister.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you both so much for such a robust conversation today.  My question is as follows:  India has announced the new National Education Policy 2020.  How do you intend to attract U.S. students to the study in – to study in India and also to participate in the Study in India program?</p>
<p><strong>MINISTER JAISHANKAR:</strong>  Well, the Study in India program has been there for some time.  The education policy came into being in 2020.  Of course, after that we had the COVID.  So it’s interesting it’s now that we are really focusing on how do we attract more international students and obviously among them more American students.</p>
<p>It’s still, quite honestly, work in progress, but the – what has changed is a much stronger appreciation of the need to have international students.  I think the view – we have long had a tradition, but we haven’t scaled it up the way many countries have.  We realize you can’t necessarily leave it to students themselves.  There have got to be programs.  There have got to be mechanisms, efforts which would actually – there’s got to be a strong pull factor.</p>
<p>So part of what we are hoping to do with the working group that we announced yesterday is to address exactly this problem that we would definitely like to see many more international students.  We believe it’s good for our universities.  We believe it’s good for our students.  And as all of us have clearly recognized today, these exchange programs have a benefit which is way beyond actually the takeaways of the person concerned.  The consequence is huge.</p>
<p>So in different ways we would try to encourage.  It could be short-term exchanges.  It could be having students do their degree in India, create fellowships which would facilitate that.  So I think there’s a whole sort of menu there in the making, and I hope a lot of what we have done in recent years has been to grow our relationship.  And to me the education part of it, particularly the idea of more Americans studying in India, that’s one area where we have not done as well as we would have liked to.  I think it’s something – it’s time to address that more effectively, and I’m very sure that we will do so.</p>
<p><strong>ASSISTANT SECRETARY SATTERFIELD:</strong>  Thank you.  And Mr. Minister, I will work on that.  (Laughter.)  Thank you.  And unfortunately, we’re out of time.  This conversation could go on forever.  It’s been so terrific.  I want to thank you for your thoughtful questions and thank the Secretary and the minister for their insights and discussion.  It’s been a robust discussion.  On behalf of our distinguished guests, I want to thank you all for being here.  Have a good day.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you all.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with Australian DFAT Secretary Kathryn Campbell</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-australian-dfat-secretary-kathryn-campbell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333825</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Australian Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade Secretary Kathryn Campbell to discuss actions allies and partners are taking to hold Russian President Vladimir Putin and his enablers to account for the unprovoked and brutal war against Ukraine, as well as ongoing efforts to provide support to Ukraine.  They condemned the horrific atrocities committed by members of Russia’s forces and expressed resolve to ensure those responsible are held accountable.  Both welcomed the recent AUKUS Leaders’ Statement and the continued close cooperation the partnership represents.  The Deputy Secretary highlighted her concern about recent developments in the Indo-Pacific and discussed opportunities to continue collaborating with partners and allies to advance peace and stability in the region, including in the Taiwan Strait.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Australian Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade Secretary Kathryn Campbell to discuss actions allies and partners are taking to hold Russian President Vladimir Putin and his enablers to account for the unprovoked and brutal war against Ukraine, as well as ongoing efforts to provide support to Ukraine.  They condemned the horrific atrocities committed by members of Russia’s forces and expressed resolve to ensure those responsible are held accountable.  Both welcomed the recent AUKUS Leaders’ Statement and the continued close cooperation the partnership represents.  The Deputy Secretary highlighted her concern about recent developments in the Indo-Pacific and discussed opportunities to continue collaborating with partners and allies to advance peace and stability in the region, including in the Taiwan Strait.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Envoy for the Horn of Africa Satterfield’s Travel to Ethiopia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-envoy-for-the-horn-of-africa-satterfields-travel-to-ethiopia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333812</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Envoy for the Horn of Africa David Satterfield and Deputy Special Envoy Payton Knopf will arrive in Ethiopia April 13 for meetings with Ethiopian government officials, representatives of humanitarian organizations, and diplomatic partners. Their visit continues U.S. efforts towards ceasing hostilities, unhindered humanitarian access, transparent investigations into human rights abuses and violations by all actors, and a negotiated resolution to the conflict in Ethiopia.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Envoy for the Horn of Africa David Satterfield and Deputy Special Envoy Payton Knopf will arrive in Ethiopia April 13 for meetings with Ethiopian government officials, representatives of humanitarian organizations, and diplomatic partners. Their visit continues U.S. efforts towards ceasing hostilities, unhindered humanitarian access, transparent investigations into human rights abuses and violations by all actors, and a negotiated resolution to the conflict in Ethiopia.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with Solomon Islands Foreign Minister Jeremiah Manele</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-solomon-islands-foreign-minister-jeremiah-manele/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333805</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Solomon Islands Foreign Minister Jeremiah Manele about plans to open the U.S. Embassy in Honiara and our joint efforts to broaden and deepen engagement between our countries in support of a free and open Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Solomon Islands Foreign Minister Jeremiah Manele about plans to open the U.S. Embassy in Honiara and our joint efforts to broaden and deepen engagement between our countries in support of a free and open Indo-Pacific region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement of the United States of America and Sweden on Cooperation in Quantum Information Science and Technology</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-of-the-united-states-of-america-and-sweden-on-cooperation-in-quantum-information-science-and-technology/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 23:33:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333798</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following joint statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and the Kingdom of Sweden on the occasion of an April 8 meeting at the Swedish Ministry of Education and Research.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>The United States of America and Sweden,</p>
<p>Recognizing that science, technology, and innovation have enabled transformative capabilities across multiple sectors, from energy to health and communications to transportation, and that the foundation of this progress is the global research enterprise, and its constant creation of new knowledge, understanding, and insights;</p>
<p>Appreciating that quantum information science and technology (QIST) revolutionizes both our understanding of fundamental phenomena as well as the development of powerful computers, rapid communication, and sensors with unprecedented precision, accuracy, and modalities;</p>
<p>Understanding that the emergence of such robust technologies depends on an intensive effort to expand theoretical and practical understandings of QIST and to develop new tools for characterization, validation, and verification purposes; and</p>
<p>Acknowledging that international partnerships are key to combine the expertise, ingenuity, and creativity of our countries to expand our fundamental understanding of QIST and thereby accelerate the realization of new technologies for the benefit of humanity.</p>
<p>The United States of America and Sweden intend to harness the spirit of science, technology, and innovation to pursue cooperation and the mutual respect it confers, and to promote QIST including but not limited to quantum computing, quantum networking, and quantum sensing, which underpins the development of society and industry.</p>
<p>We intend to advance this agenda by:</p>
<ul>
<li>Embarking on good-faith cooperation that is underpinned by our shared principles, including freedom of inquiry, openness, transparency, honesty, equity, fair competition, objectivity, and democratic values.</li>
<li>Committing to create inclusive scientific research communities and tackle cross-cutting issues of common interest such as equity, diversity, inclusion, and accessibility, so that every person is able to fully participate and have an equal opportunity to succeed.</li>
<li>Collaborating in venues such as workshops, seminars, and conferences to discuss and recognize the progress of research in QIST, which in turn will lead to the identification of overlapping interests and opportunities for future scientific cooperation.</li>
<li>Promoting avenues to encourage a respectful and inclusive research environment, to facilitate multidisciplinary research, and to openly share research methodologies, infrastructure and data, when appropriate.</li>
<li>Enabling opportunities to build a trusted global market and supply chain for QIST R&amp;D, and supporting economic growth, by engaging stakeholders including industry consortia, research leaders, policy makers, and business security stakeholders to grow the future QIST marketplace based on shared engagement principles.</li>
<li>Supporting the development of the next generation of scientists and engineers necessary to expand the field, which could include personnel exchanges.</li>
<li>Leveraging regular multilateral opportunities to discuss QIST matters of international importance and respective policy issues.</li>
<li>Exploring other potential activities to be decided upon by participating countries.</li>
</ul>
<p>We confirm our intent that cooperation enabled by this Statement will be pursuant to the Agreement on Science and Technology Cooperation between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Kingdom of Sweden, and that the terms of the S&amp;T Agreement and related agreements govern such cooperation.</p>
<p>Taking into account that QIST ecosystems will rely on close international connections and collaboration with partners, we intend to focus on cooperation in QIST as outlined in this vision for the mutual benefit of participating countries and continue to enhance scientific cooperation under our respective leaderships.</p>
<p><em>End text</em></p>
<p>The Joint Statement will enable both countries to leverage their strengths in QIST to pursue innovative research, grow the future marketplace and necessary supply chain, and grow the future generation of skills and talent.</p>
<p>Erik D. Ramanathan, United States Ambassador to Sweden, signed the joint statement in Stockholm for the United States.</p>
<p>Anna Ekström, Minister for Education in the Ministry of Education and Research, signed the joint statement for Sweden.</p>
<p>For more information, please visit: <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTIuNTYzMjcxMDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5xdWFudHVtLmdvdi90aGUtdW5pdGVkLXN0YXRlcy1hbmQtc3dlZGVuLXNpZ24tcXVhbnR1bS1jb29wZXJhdGlvbi1zdGF0ZW1lbnQvIn0.YmhNWCBdQ2OzObOmdLhST1mL0bEhPG3K01Du0dQu0S4/s/1250718950/br/129729972808-l">https://www.quantum.gov/the-united-states-and-sweden-sign-quantum-cooperation-statement/</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following joint statement was released by the Governments of the United States of America and the Kingdom of Sweden on the occasion of an April 8 meeting at the Swedish Ministry of Education and Research.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>The United States of America and Sweden,</p>
<p>Recognizing that science, technology, and innovation have enabled transformative capabilities across multiple sectors, from energy to health and communications to transportation, and that the foundation of this progress is the global research enterprise, and its constant creation of new knowledge, understanding, and insights;</p>
<p>Appreciating that quantum information science and technology (QIST) revolutionizes both our understanding of fundamental phenomena as well as the development of powerful computers, rapid communication, and sensors with unprecedented precision, accuracy, and modalities;</p>
<p>Understanding that the emergence of such robust technologies depends on an intensive effort to expand theoretical and practical understandings of QIST and to develop new tools for characterization, validation, and verification purposes; and</p>
<p>Acknowledging that international partnerships are key to combine the expertise, ingenuity, and creativity of our countries to expand our fundamental understanding of QIST and thereby accelerate the realization of new technologies for the benefit of humanity.</p>
<p>The United States of America and Sweden intend to harness the spirit of science, technology, and innovation to pursue cooperation and the mutual respect it confers, and to promote QIST including but not limited to quantum computing, quantum networking, and quantum sensing, which underpins the development of society and industry.</p>
<p>We intend to advance this agenda by:</p>
<ul>
<li>Embarking on good-faith cooperation that is underpinned by our shared principles, including freedom of inquiry, openness, transparency, honesty, equity, fair competition, objectivity, and democratic values.</li>
<li>Committing to create inclusive scientific research communities and tackle cross-cutting issues of common interest such as equity, diversity, inclusion, and accessibility, so that every person is able to fully participate and have an equal opportunity to succeed.</li>
<li>Collaborating in venues such as workshops, seminars, and conferences to discuss and recognize the progress of research in QIST, which in turn will lead to the identification of overlapping interests and opportunities for future scientific cooperation.</li>
<li>Promoting avenues to encourage a respectful and inclusive research environment, to facilitate multidisciplinary research, and to openly share research methodologies, infrastructure and data, when appropriate.</li>
<li>Enabling opportunities to build a trusted global market and supply chain for QIST R&amp;D, and supporting economic growth, by engaging stakeholders including industry consortia, research leaders, policy makers, and business security stakeholders to grow the future QIST marketplace based on shared engagement principles.</li>
<li>Supporting the development of the next generation of scientists and engineers necessary to expand the field, which could include personnel exchanges.</li>
<li>Leveraging regular multilateral opportunities to discuss QIST matters of international importance and respective policy issues.</li>
<li>Exploring other potential activities to be decided upon by participating countries.</li>
</ul>
<p>We confirm our intent that cooperation enabled by this Statement will be pursuant to the Agreement on Science and Technology Cooperation between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Kingdom of Sweden, and that the terms of the S&amp;T Agreement and related agreements govern such cooperation.</p>
<p>Taking into account that QIST ecosystems will rely on close international connections and collaboration with partners, we intend to focus on cooperation in QIST as outlined in this vision for the mutual benefit of participating countries and continue to enhance scientific cooperation under our respective leaderships.</p>
<p><em>End text</em></p>
<p>The Joint Statement will enable both countries to leverage their strengths in QIST to pursue innovative research, grow the future marketplace and necessary supply chain, and grow the future generation of skills and talent.</p>
<p>Erik D. Ramanathan, United States Ambassador to Sweden, signed the joint statement in Stockholm for the United States.</p>
<p>Anna Ekström, Minister for Education in the Ministry of Education and Research, signed the joint statement for Sweden.</p>
<p>For more information, please visit: <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MTIuNTYzMjcxMDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5xdWFudHVtLmdvdi90aGUtdW5pdGVkLXN0YXRlcy1hbmQtc3dlZGVuLXNpZ24tcXVhbnR1bS1jb29wZXJhdGlvbi1zdGF0ZW1lbnQvIn0.YmhNWCBdQ2OzObOmdLhST1mL0bEhPG3K01Du0dQu0S4/s/1250718950/br/129729972808-l">https://www.quantum.gov/the-united-states-and-sweden-sign-quantum-cooperation-statement/</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Uruguayan Foreign Minister Francisco Bustillo Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-uruguayan-foreign-minister-francisco-bustillo-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 23:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong></strong>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a real pleasure to welcome Foreign Minister Bustillo here.  Francisco, welcome.  It’s great to have you.</p>
<p>Uruguay is a strong, democratic partner of the United States with a strong voice in the OAS, at the United Nations, one that we greatly value.</p>
<p>Indeed, we call clearly together for an end to Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>We already have a very strong commercial relationship, but one that we’ll talk about deepening today.</p>
<p>And we’ll have an opportunity to plan together for the upcoming Summit of the Americas at a critical moment for our hemisphere and for the work that we have to do together.  Uruguay is the chair of the Health Resilience Group for the summit.  This is critical for our future, and it is well placed to do that among other things because of its extraordinarily effective response to COVID-19.</p>
<p>So there is lots to talk about.  Without further ado, Francisco, again, welcome.  Over to you.</p>
<p><strong><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER BUSTILLO:</strong></strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you very much.  It is such an honor to be here with the Secretary of State Antony Blinken and with your team, and I am so pleased to see so many friendly faces among them.  It is very much an honor to be here with the Uruguayan Ambassador to the United States Andrés Durán, with the Chief of Cabinet Fernando Fabregat, as well as our Minister Adviser Gerardo Ruiz.</p>
<p>And of course, this is a great time for the United States and Uruguay to come together as we share traditional values that we have cultivated over the years.  So once again, I would like to thank you.  And I’m asked to slow down my sentences.</p>
<p>We are here at such a crucial time and we share such principles and values, so it is a pleasure to meet with you here today, Mr. Secretary.  Uruguay over the last century has had a history of being a Francophone country, and we are part of that international community.  And I believe that based on your past and growing up in France that it is very easy to locate ourselves within our shared principles and values.</p>
<p>As I said just a moment ago, we are in a very particular time in history for humanity, and as men of diplomacy, I know that this is a crucial moment where the United States has a role to play in the international scenario, and a lot of work to do, and specifically in this case with Uruguay.</p>
<p>We have great expectations for our meeting today, and we will discuss many issues, including the Summit of the Americas which is to be held in June in Los Angeles.  So without a doubt, this is a time to work together for the benefit of both of our countries and for humanity.</p>
<p>Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong></strong>  Thank you all.</p>
<p><strong><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER BUSTILLO:</strong></strong>  Thanks very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong></strong>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a real pleasure to welcome Foreign Minister Bustillo here.  Francisco, welcome.  It’s great to have you.</p>
<p>Uruguay is a strong, democratic partner of the United States with a strong voice in the OAS, at the United Nations, one that we greatly value.</p>
<p>Indeed, we call clearly together for an end to Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.</p>
<p>We already have a very strong commercial relationship, but one that we’ll talk about deepening today.</p>
<p>And we’ll have an opportunity to plan together for the upcoming Summit of the Americas at a critical moment for our hemisphere and for the work that we have to do together.  Uruguay is the chair of the Health Resilience Group for the summit.  This is critical for our future, and it is well placed to do that among other things because of its extraordinarily effective response to COVID-19.</p>
<p>So there is lots to talk about.  Without further ado, Francisco, again, welcome.  Over to you.</p>
<p><strong><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER BUSTILLO:</strong></strong>  (Via interpreter) Thank you very much.  It is such an honor to be here with the Secretary of State Antony Blinken and with your team, and I am so pleased to see so many friendly faces among them.  It is very much an honor to be here with the Uruguayan Ambassador to the United States Andrés Durán, with the Chief of Cabinet Fernando Fabregat, as well as our Minister Adviser Gerardo Ruiz.</p>
<p>And of course, this is a great time for the United States and Uruguay to come together as we share traditional values that we have cultivated over the years.  So once again, I would like to thank you.  And I’m asked to slow down my sentences.</p>
<p>We are here at such a crucial time and we share such principles and values, so it is a pleasure to meet with you here today, Mr. Secretary.  Uruguay over the last century has had a history of being a Francophone country, and we are part of that international community.  And I believe that based on your past and growing up in France that it is very easy to locate ourselves within our shared principles and values.</p>
<p>As I said just a moment ago, we are in a very particular time in history for humanity, and as men of diplomacy, I know that this is a crucial moment where the United States has a role to play in the international scenario, and a lot of work to do, and specifically in this case with Uruguay.</p>
<p>We have great expectations for our meeting today, and we will discuss many issues, including the Summit of the Americas which is to be held in June in Los Angeles.  So without a doubt, this is a time to work together for the benefit of both of our countries and for humanity.</p>
<p>Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong></strong>  Thank you all.</p>
<p><strong><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER BUSTILLO:</strong></strong>  Thanks very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Acting Assistant Secretary for Democracy, Human Rights and Labor Lisa Peterson on the Release of the 2021 Country Reports on Human Rights Practices</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/acting-assistant-secretary-for-democracy-human-rights-and-labor-lisa-peterson-on-the-release-of-the-2021-country-reports-on-human-rights-practices/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lisa Peterson, Acting Assistant SecretaryBureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 20:47:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=333761</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Lisa Peterson, Acting Assistant SecretaryBureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Press Briefing Room</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:</strong>  It’s a privilege to be here for the release of the 46th Human Rights Report, which we submitted to the U.S. Congress earlier today.</p>
<p>For nearly five decades, the United States has issued the Country Reports on Human Rights Practices, addressing the status of internationally recognized human rights in all countries that are members of the United Nations.</p>
<p>The Annual Human Rights Report includes 198 reports on individual countries and territories, and provides an objective record of whether and how human rights and fundamental freedoms are protected by law and in practice around the world.  The individual reports draw on information from a range of governmental, nongovernmental, and media sources.  The Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor, which I currently lead, is at the forefront of preparing these reports along with colleagues across the department and our embassies in the field, and I am proud to note that this June we will mark our 45th anniversary.</p>
<p>In 1977, the Carter administration oversaw the establishment of what is now the DRL Bureau, with the mission of advancing individual liberty and democratic freedoms around the world, and upholding the truth enshrined in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights that all individuals are born equal in dignity and rights.</p>
<p>Over those four and a half decades, DRL has rolled up our sleeves alongside U.S. Government colleagues as well as countless brave human rights defenders and other civil society leaders to promote our namesake values of democracy, human rights, and labor.</p>
<p>Despite innumerable achievements over that period to defend and strengthen democracy and to promote and protect human rights and labor rights, serious challenges persist.  Some of today’s challenges to democracy and human rights are longstanding and familiar; others are new and evolving.  All demand continued leadership from the United States in close collaboration with our partners and allies across the globe.</p>
<p>On the home front, strengthening our democracy in the United States and ensuring that the fundamental freedoms and human rights of all people are protected and advanced is a critical part of the Biden-Harris administration’s commitment to global leadership on human rights.  We can’t be credible advocates for human rights abroad if we don’t live up to the same principles at home.  We do not claim a moral high ground, but we do, in the words of our Constitution, resolve “to form a more perfect union,” which means we must continue to address the many human rights challenges in our own country.</p>
<p>The Summit for Democracy held this past December served as a rallying point to address these challenges, both new and old.  President Biden brought together world leaders, civil society, and private sector representatives in a shared commitment to push back against authoritarianism, fight corruption, and advance respect for human rights.</p>
<p>We’re taking forward the momentum of the first summit through a year of action in which governments, including the United States, are working to fulfill our commitments and tackle human rights challenges at home and globally in partnership with civil society.</p>
<p>The yearly Human Rights Report speaks to the importance that we place on these goals.  The report does not attempt to catalog every human rights related incident.  It is not an effort by the U.S. Government to judge others.  It does not reach legal conclusions, rank countries, or draw comparisons.</p>
<p>We’ve seen all too well in recent years that around the world, democracy and human rights have been threatened and undermined by disinformation, misinformation, and outright lies.  So our objective with the Human Rights Report is simple: bring the facts to the table.  It is only when we’re armed with the truth that the United States can most effectively use our voice and our influence to call attention to violations and abuses of human rights worldwide, and press the perpetrators of these violations and abuses to change course and end their egregious conduct.</p>
<p>At the conclusion of this press briefing, the 2021 Human Rights Report will be available to the public on the State Department website at <a href="http://www.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649882169935000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0Uk4X6h8Vb1L2CEV1R66H_">www.state.gov</a>.</p>
<p>Thank you for being here today, and with that, I am happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello.  Guita Aryan, Voice of America, Persian service.  The Secretary just mentioned Iran as one of the examples of countries where human rights violation is rampant, and he referred to abduction or attempt to abduct dissidents overseas.  A little over a year ago the Secretary also issued a statement designating a number of IRGC commanders for having a hand in the arrest, imprisonment, and torture of protesters a couple of a years ago.  And in continuation of that statement, the Secretary said that the U.S. will continue to support the Iranian people.  Now how has the Biden administration helped or supported the Iranian people during this past year, given that the list of violations of human rights on Iran in the report is, I don’t know, 10, 15 lines long?</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:</strong>  So we continue to find ways, both in public and in very discreet manners, to support people who are trying to advance the human rights situation in Iran.  As you note, we have also put into play a variety of sanctions tools.  I am sorry, I don’t have details in front of me at this moment, but it is something that I would be happy to circle back to you on.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Janne.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  On the North Korean human rights issues.  Human rights violation are currently ongoing in North Korea, and North Korean leader Kim Jong-un is – massacred their own citizens.  What is the final destination for the United States to resolve the North Korean human rights problem?</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:</strong>  So we do recognize that the DPRK is among the most repressive, authoritarian states in the world.  And obviously, we remain deeply concerned about reports of systemic, widespread, and gross human rights violations and abuses committed by the DPRK Government.  And we certainly hope that one day justice may be achieved for the people of North Korea.</p>
<p>Similar to the very difficult operating circumstances with Iran, we continue to work with the international community to raise awareness, document and preserve information on human rights abuses and violations, and increase access to independent information.  We also seek to impose sanctions on those who are complicit in abuses and violations, and as always, promote respect for human rights within the DPRK.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Do you have any tools use for the – resolve this human rights issue in North Korea, or you don’t have anything?  Because this is long time being the North Koreans in human right – abuse the human rights.</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:</strong>  Obviously, that is an extremely difficult environment to be able to influence, but it is an area that we continue to focus our efforts on to try to raise awareness around the issues within North Korea.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Yeah, how do you assess the human rights record in the Middle East?  Are they deteriorated, or how do you – how do you see that?</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:  </strong>I would hesitate to speak to the Middle East as a region as a whole.  Each country has its individual circumstances.  Some have progress, some less so.  So I would hesitate to speak on an entire region.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>On Russia, the report obviously covers the 2021 period, but Russia seems to be committing even worse atrocities this year in Ukraine and its repression at home.  I would wonder if you would agree with that characterization.  And then secondly, if you could expand on why that would be the case – do you think that Vladimir Putin has a sense of impunity because he hasn’t faced repercussions in the past?</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:  </strong>So I will share that because the report does focus on 2021 and a lot of the preparation is very focused on what went into those reports, I was struck by the manner in which the listing of issues with Russia have simply been amplified in the context of the Russia-Ukraine context.  As to why that has happened, I will not speculate on what is motivating Putin.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Sir.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.  On Georgia, there are some serious concerns about Georgia’s human rights record.  Many believe within the country and by respondents here in DC, former diplomats, that Georgia is leaning towards illiberalism.  Secretary Blinken mentioned that it’s irrespective to friends or not friendly countries, that applies – that human rights – human rights standard applies equally to everyone.  I just want to gather your thoughts how far – is the United States willing to go further if the former partners – and Georgia has been partnering with the U.S. for the last 30 years – is violating systematically human rights within its territory?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:  </strong>So, clearly, we do have a list of human rights concerns with Georgia.  I will also note that we have been following actions such as the October elections.  And they’re – while those were characterized as candidates generally being able to campaign freely, but there were observations from OSCE observers that the competitive environment was marred by widespread and consistent allegations of intimidation.  I do think that this is an appropriate example of how we do see problems in countries and we use the human rights reports to analyze and understand those problems, but in understanding and analyzing we try to find ways to move forward, and as long as there is opportunity for engagement with a government we will continue to engage on those human rights issues.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Humeyra.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, thank you.  I know that the report covers last year, but I just wanted to ask you something a little bit more contemporary.  There has been a lot of reporting – an increase in reporting of accounts of rape and sexual violence from Ukraine.  UN human rights monitors are seeking to verify these allegations of sexual violence by Russian forces.  Is that something the United States is picking up, and do you think that it has reached a level where rape is used as a weapon of war?</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:  </strong>So the reports of sexual violence are certainly something that we are tracking, both in our own efforts to understand what is happening in Ukraine, in our own efforts to catalogue what is happening there, and through the various citizen-level mechanisms and multilateral approaches that are all gathering information.  We are hearing horrific stories; I’m sure you are hearing horrific stories as well.  And that is something that we will come continue to gather and ultimately, ideally, have it feed into transitional justice mechanisms.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.  Following up a bit on that as well – sorry to bring it back to Ukraine.  There’s also been a claim by the Ukraine’s UN ambassador that Russia has taken more than 121,000 children out of Ukraine and is reportedly drafting a bill to simply and accelerate adoption procedures for orphans.  This is something obviously coming from the Ukrainian side.  Is this something that the U.S. is also tracking and looking into in terms of the kind of behavior that has been reported by the Ukrainians?</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:  </strong>This is certainly something that we have heard about.  This is something that we will continue to try to learn more about and try to determine what action may be possible.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Final question?  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Yes.<strong>  </strong>These reports every year include a lot of details about LGBTQ rights abroad.  And I’m just wondering if you have any thoughts about folks who might be critical of that in the context of what’s happening here in the United States with bills like the “Don’t say gay” bill in Florida, efforts to discriminate against transgender folks, et cetera.  Any thoughts on that point?</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:  </strong>So this will not be the first issue on which people will say, well, what about your own country?  I do think – again, within the framing of the Summit for Democracy and the approach that this administration has taken, we’re not trying to pretend that these are not issues that we are grappling with here in the United States.  This report, because it is very clearly focused on the rest of the world, we do dig in on other countries.  We do not have a mandate to do a report on our own circumstances.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Final question, Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi there.  Any comment on Russia’s arrest of Kara-Murza just hours after he appeared on two American networks from Moscow speaking out against the Russian war?</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:  </strong>I would speak in general about Russia’s crackdown – further crackdown on freedom of information, freedom of expression in Russia in the context of the Ukraine conflict.  This was space that they were closing even before the conflict started.  Their efforts to close down that space have simply grown exponentially since the start of the conflict, and we would want to see that space reopened so that Russians can understand what is happening within their neighborhood and what their government is doing.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thank you very much, Assistant Secretary Peterson.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lisa Peterson, Acting Assistant SecretaryBureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Press Briefing Room</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:</strong>  It’s a privilege to be here for the release of the 46th Human Rights Report, which we submitted to the U.S. Congress earlier today.</p>
<p>For nearly five decades, the United States has issued the Country Reports on Human Rights Practices, addressing the status of internationally recognized human rights in all countries that are members of the United Nations.</p>
<p>The Annual Human Rights Report includes 198 reports on individual countries and territories, and provides an objective record of whether and how human rights and fundamental freedoms are protected by law and in practice around the world.  The individual reports draw on information from a range of governmental, nongovernmental, and media sources.  The Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor, which I currently lead, is at the forefront of preparing these reports along with colleagues across the department and our embassies in the field, and I am proud to note that this June we will mark our 45th anniversary.</p>
<p>In 1977, the Carter administration oversaw the establishment of what is now the DRL Bureau, with the mission of advancing individual liberty and democratic freedoms around the world, and upholding the truth enshrined in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights that all individuals are born equal in dignity and rights.</p>
<p>Over those four and a half decades, DRL has rolled up our sleeves alongside U.S. Government colleagues as well as countless brave human rights defenders and other civil society leaders to promote our namesake values of democracy, human rights, and labor.</p>
<p>Despite innumerable achievements over that period to defend and strengthen democracy and to promote and protect human rights and labor rights, serious challenges persist.  Some of today’s challenges to democracy and human rights are longstanding and familiar; others are new and evolving.  All demand continued leadership from the United States in close collaboration with our partners and allies across the globe.</p>
<p>On the home front, strengthening our democracy in the United States and ensuring that the fundamental freedoms and human rights of all people are protected and advanced is a critical part of the Biden-Harris administration’s commitment to global leadership on human rights.  We can’t be credible advocates for human rights abroad if we don’t live up to the same principles at home.  We do not claim a moral high ground, but we do, in the words of our Constitution, resolve “to form a more perfect union,” which means we must continue to address the many human rights challenges in our own country.</p>
<p>The Summit for Democracy held this past December served as a rallying point to address these challenges, both new and old.  President Biden brought together world leaders, civil society, and private sector representatives in a shared commitment to push back against authoritarianism, fight corruption, and advance respect for human rights.</p>
<p>We’re taking forward the momentum of the first summit through a year of action in which governments, including the United States, are working to fulfill our commitments and tackle human rights challenges at home and globally in partnership with civil society.</p>
<p>The yearly Human Rights Report speaks to the importance that we place on these goals.  The report does not attempt to catalog every human rights related incident.  It is not an effort by the U.S. Government to judge others.  It does not reach legal conclusions, rank countries, or draw comparisons.</p>
<p>We’ve seen all too well in recent years that around the world, democracy and human rights have been threatened and undermined by disinformation, misinformation, and outright lies.  So our objective with the Human Rights Report is simple: bring the facts to the table.  It is only when we’re armed with the truth that the United States can most effectively use our voice and our influence to call attention to violations and abuses of human rights worldwide, and press the perpetrators of these violations and abuses to change course and end their egregious conduct.</p>
<p>At the conclusion of this press briefing, the 2021 Human Rights Report will be available to the public on the State Department website at <a href="http://www.state.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.state.gov&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649882169935000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0Uk4X6h8Vb1L2CEV1R66H_">www.state.gov</a>.</p>
<p>Thank you for being here today, and with that, I am happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hello.  Guita Aryan, Voice of America, Persian service.  The Secretary just mentioned Iran as one of the examples of countries where human rights violation is rampant, and he referred to abduction or attempt to abduct dissidents overseas.  A little over a year ago the Secretary also issued a statement designating a number of IRGC commanders for having a hand in the arrest, imprisonment, and torture of protesters a couple of a years ago.  And in continuation of that statement, the Secretary said that the U.S. will continue to support the Iranian people.  Now how has the Biden administration helped or supported the Iranian people during this past year, given that the list of violations of human rights on Iran in the report is, I don’t know, 10, 15 lines long?</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:</strong>  So we continue to find ways, both in public and in very discreet manners, to support people who are trying to advance the human rights situation in Iran.  As you note, we have also put into play a variety of sanctions tools.  I am sorry, I don’t have details in front of me at this moment, but it is something that I would be happy to circle back to you on.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Janne.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you.  On the North Korean human rights issues.  Human rights violation are currently ongoing in North Korea, and North Korean leader Kim Jong-un is – massacred their own citizens.  What is the final destination for the United States to resolve the North Korean human rights problem?</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:</strong>  So we do recognize that the DPRK is among the most repressive, authoritarian states in the world.  And obviously, we remain deeply concerned about reports of systemic, widespread, and gross human rights violations and abuses committed by the DPRK Government.  And we certainly hope that one day justice may be achieved for the people of North Korea.</p>
<p>Similar to the very difficult operating circumstances with Iran, we continue to work with the international community to raise awareness, document and preserve information on human rights abuses and violations, and increase access to independent information.  We also seek to impose sanctions on those who are complicit in abuses and violations, and as always, promote respect for human rights within the DPRK.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Do you have any tools use for the – resolve this human rights issue in North Korea, or you don’t have anything?  Because this is long time being the North Koreans in human right – abuse the human rights.</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:</strong>  Obviously, that is an extremely difficult environment to be able to influence, but it is an area that we continue to focus our efforts on to try to raise awareness around the issues within North Korea.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Yeah, how do you assess the human rights record in the Middle East?  Are they deteriorated, or how do you – how do you see that?</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:  </strong>I would hesitate to speak to the Middle East as a region as a whole.  Each country has its individual circumstances.  Some have progress, some less so.  So I would hesitate to speak on an entire region.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>On Russia, the report obviously covers the 2021 period, but Russia seems to be committing even worse atrocities this year in Ukraine and its repression at home.  I would wonder if you would agree with that characterization.  And then secondly, if you could expand on why that would be the case – do you think that Vladimir Putin has a sense of impunity because he hasn’t faced repercussions in the past?</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:  </strong>So I will share that because the report does focus on 2021 and a lot of the preparation is very focused on what went into those reports, I was struck by the manner in which the listing of issues with Russia have simply been amplified in the context of the Russia-Ukraine context.  As to why that has happened, I will not speculate on what is motivating Putin.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Sir.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.  On Georgia, there are some serious concerns about Georgia’s human rights record.  Many believe within the country and by respondents here in DC, former diplomats, that Georgia is leaning towards illiberalism.  Secretary Blinken mentioned that it’s irrespective to friends or not friendly countries, that applies – that human rights – human rights standard applies equally to everyone.  I just want to gather your thoughts how far – is the United States willing to go further if the former partners – and Georgia has been partnering with the U.S. for the last 30 years – is violating systematically human rights within its territory?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:  </strong>So, clearly, we do have a list of human rights concerns with Georgia.  I will also note that we have been following actions such as the October elections.  And they’re – while those were characterized as candidates generally being able to campaign freely, but there were observations from OSCE observers that the competitive environment was marred by widespread and consistent allegations of intimidation.  I do think that this is an appropriate example of how we do see problems in countries and we use the human rights reports to analyze and understand those problems, but in understanding and analyzing we try to find ways to move forward, and as long as there is opportunity for engagement with a government we will continue to engage on those human rights issues.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Humeyra.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, thank you.  I know that the report covers last year, but I just wanted to ask you something a little bit more contemporary.  There has been a lot of reporting – an increase in reporting of accounts of rape and sexual violence from Ukraine.  UN human rights monitors are seeking to verify these allegations of sexual violence by Russian forces.  Is that something the United States is picking up, and do you think that it has reached a level where rape is used as a weapon of war?</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:  </strong>So the reports of sexual violence are certainly something that we are tracking, both in our own efforts to understand what is happening in Ukraine, in our own efforts to catalogue what is happening there, and through the various citizen-level mechanisms and multilateral approaches that are all gathering information.  We are hearing horrific stories; I’m sure you are hearing horrific stories as well.  And that is something that we will come continue to gather and ultimately, ideally, have it feed into transitional justice mechanisms.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.  Following up a bit on that as well – sorry to bring it back to Ukraine.  There’s also been a claim by the Ukraine’s UN ambassador that Russia has taken more than 121,000 children out of Ukraine and is reportedly drafting a bill to simply and accelerate adoption procedures for orphans.  This is something obviously coming from the Ukrainian side.  Is this something that the U.S. is also tracking and looking into in terms of the kind of behavior that has been reported by the Ukrainians?</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:  </strong>This is certainly something that we have heard about.  This is something that we will continue to try to learn more about and try to determine what action may be possible.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Final question?  Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Yes.<strong>  </strong>These reports every year include a lot of details about LGBTQ rights abroad.  And I’m just wondering if you have any thoughts about folks who might be critical of that in the context of what’s happening here in the United States with bills like the “Don’t say gay” bill in Florida, efforts to discriminate against transgender folks, et cetera.  Any thoughts on that point?</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:  </strong>So this will not be the first issue on which people will say, well, what about your own country?  I do think – again, within the framing of the Summit for Democracy and the approach that this administration has taken, we’re not trying to pretend that these are not issues that we are grappling with here in the United States.  This report, because it is very clearly focused on the rest of the world, we do dig in on other countries.  We do not have a mandate to do a report on our own circumstances.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Final question, Andrea.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi there.  Any comment on Russia’s arrest of Kara-Murza just hours after he appeared on two American networks from Moscow speaking out against the Russian war?</p>
<p><strong>MS PETERSON:  </strong>I would speak in general about Russia’s crackdown – further crackdown on freedom of information, freedom of expression in Russia in the context of the Ukraine conflict.  This was space that they were closing even before the conflict started.  Their efforts to close down that space have simply grown exponentially since the start of the conflict, and we would want to see that space reopened so that Russians can understand what is happening within their neighborhood and what their government is doing.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Thank you very much, Assistant Secretary Peterson.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
