<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 15:15:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Opening of U.S.-Denmark Defense Cooperation Agreement Negotiations</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/opening-of-u-s-denmark-defense-cooperation-agreement-negotiations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 14:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313100</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the offer announced today by Danish Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen to begin negotiating a new Defense Cooperation Agreement. When concluded, this agreement will allow our countries to deepen our close security partnership, further strengthen cooperation in NATO operations, and together, contribute to continued growth in Transatlantic security.</p>
<p>These negotiations represent a natural progression in our decades of security cooperation. In doing so, we look to build on the 1951 NATO Status of Forces Agreement to enhance interoperability to meet shared security challenges more effectively.</p>
<p>Our alliances are a core source of American strength. The United States and Denmark work closely together on a wide range of issues important to both countries, to the NATO Alliance, and to the rest of the world. Opening these consultations with Denmark reflects our commitment to reaffirming and reinvigorating America’s alliances to meet common security challenges while protecting shared interests and values.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the offer announced today by Danish Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen to begin negotiating a new Defense Cooperation Agreement. When concluded, this agreement will allow our countries to deepen our close security partnership, further strengthen cooperation in NATO operations, and together, contribute to continued growth in Transatlantic security.</p>
<p>These negotiations represent a natural progression in our decades of security cooperation. In doing so, we look to build on the 1951 NATO Status of Forces Agreement to enhance interoperability to meet shared security challenges more effectively.</p>
<p>Our alliances are a core source of American strength. The United States and Denmark work closely together on a wide range of issues important to both countries, to the NATO Alliance, and to the rest of the world. Opening these consultations with Denmark reflects our commitment to reaffirming and reinvigorating America’s alliances to meet common security challenges while protecting shared interests and values.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Leigh Sales of ABC’s 730 Report</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-leigh-sales-of-abcs-730-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 13:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313062</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Melbourne, Australia</p>
<p>Royal Botanic Gardens</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Mr. Secretary, thank you very much for your time.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  It’s great to be with you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  How would U.S. intervention in the case of a Russian invasion of Ukraine differ to the case of, say, a Chinese incursion into Taiwan?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, it’s hard to compare very, very different situations, but what we’re committed to in the case of Ukraine is doing everything we can to defend Ukraine’s territorial integrity, its sovereignty, its independence, which unfortunately is being challenged right now by Russia.  We’ve made very clear to Russia that there are two paths going forward: there’s a diplomatic path, a path of diplomacy, dialogue to see if we can find answers to security concerns that Russia has expressed and that we’ve expressed about Russia’s conduct; but equally, if Russia chooses to renew its aggression against Ukraine, we’ve made clear – not just us but countries throughout Europe and even beyond – that there’ll be massive consequences.</p>
<p>So my hope is that Russia will be deterred by the actions that we’ve taken to build &#8212; to bring together many, many countries that stand against renewed aggression by Russia in Ukraine.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  President Biden says that if an invasion occurs, the planned Nord Stream 2 gas pipeline between Russia and Germany won’t go ahead.  The German chancellor has been a bit more vague on that.  How would America stop that pipeline given it’s not on U.S. territory?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, the President has been very clear that if there is renewed aggression by Russia in Ukraine, it’s very hard to see gas ever flowing through that pipeline.  And right now the pipeline is actually a source of leverage for us, not for Russia, precisely because gas has not yet begun to flow through it.  To the extent that President Putin wants to see that happen, the idea that that could happen if he commits aggression against Ukraine is very, very hard to see.  So that may make him think twice about taking action in Ukraine.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Who does the Biden administration view as a bigger threat to global security, Russia or China?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  These are, again, very different challenges.  Russia right now poses an immediate challenge not just to Ukraine through the possibility of renewed aggression, but to some very basic principles that are relevant to the security not just of people in Europe but throughout the world, including in Australia – principles like you can’t just change the borders of another country by force; you can’t decide for another country its choices, its policies, with whom it will associate; you can’t exert a sphere of influence that tries to subjugate your neighbors to your will.  Those are the basic principles that are at stake when it comes to Ukraine and Russia’s aggression, and they’re relevant right here in this part of the world just as they are in Europe.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  You’re here for the meeting.  Is the Quad grouping about countering the influence of China in this region?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  The Quad fundamentally is about presenting an affirmative vision and affirmative action to deal with some of the main challenges of our time as well as to find opportunities and to make the most of them.  So bringing these countries together to deal with something that’s afflicting everyone – COVID – that is again about dealing with something very concrete in people’s lives.  How we think about emerging technology and the rules and norms and standards that shape it – the Quad is coming together on that.  How we make our economies more resilient, not only recovering from COVID but producing greater resiliency over time through diversified supply chains, for example – that’s what the Quad is all about.</p>
<p>So it’s coming together, using the talents, the resources, the different skill sets that we – that these four countries have, as well as potentially working with other countries.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Australia’s Defense Minister Peter Dutton has warned that Australia and its allies will lose the next decade unless they stand up to China in the South China Sea.  What’s your take on that?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  What we have to do and what we are doing is standing up for the norms, the rules, the standards, the values that unite it – that unite us.  So this is not about standing against anyone in particular; it is about standing up for a rules-based order, making sure that we uphold those rules and principles if they’re being challenged.  Because it’s exactly that that’s undergirded peace, security, and opportunity for people for decades.  So when they’re being challenged, we have an obligation to stand up.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Against that backdrop, Russia and China’s leaders met on the sidelines of the Winter Olympics earlier this week and they declared that they have a no-limits partnership.  That has to be of some concern given the context that you just painted there.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  China and Russia have been growing closer over many, many years, so this is not – this is not new.  I have to say, if – and we of course were not in the room when the two leaders met, but I would imagine that, for example, China would have some issues with Russia’s threats to Ukraine’s territorial integrity and sovereignty.  China talks a lot about upholding the principle of sovereignty.  Well, maybe it has something to say about that.  Russian aggression in Ukraine would not be good for anyone.  It wouldn’t be good for China either.  And so one would think that it would have shared some of its concerns with Russia.</p>
<p>Russia and China are talking.  We’re engaged, the United States, with dozens of partners throughout Europe, around the world, NATO, the European Union, the G7, here through the Quad, AUKUS, you name it.  We have a multiplicity of alliances, of partnerships, of coalitions to deal with issues of concern to our people.  That’s actually been our greatest strength.  And these partnerships, these alliances, not only are they voluntary, they’re based on a shared set of values and basic interests.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  You mentioned AUKUS.  The French Government was put out, to say the least, by its submarine contract with Australia being shelved due to the new security pact between Australia, the UK, and the U.S.  The French said that they were blindsided by what happened.  Were they, and who was responsible for that?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Look, I said at the time that we, speaking for ourselves, the United States could have done a better job communicating with our French allies and partners on this.  But we are working incredibly closely together as partners.  We’re doing the same thing through NATO, with the European Union, the G7.  And so I think the strength of that relationship, of that partnership is as good as it’s ever been.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Which country first floated the idea of a security pact between Australia, the U.S., and the UK, including finding a way to have – for Australia to have nuclear submarines?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, I’m not going to go back and revisit the entire history of this, but certainly this is something that was raised early on by Australia, by the United Kingdom.  And of course part of what we’re doing around the world, as I said, is working to revitalize, to re-energize, and, as necessary, to reinvent these alliances and partnerships because for us, as we’re looking at the problems that afflict our people as well as the opportunities, whether it’s dealing with climate, whether it’s dealing with COVID, whether it’s dealing with emerging technologies, whether it’s dealing with security, not a single one of these problems can be effectively addressed by any one of our countries working alone.  We are much stronger when we find ways to work together.  And that’s why we’ve invested so much in not only our traditional alliances, but in creating new coalitions, new partnerships to focus on specific issues.  That’s what AUKUS is about, it’s what the Quad is about, as well as the traditional alliances like NATO and other organizations.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Final question, Mr. Secretary.  The U.S. under Donald Trump’s leadership was beset with internal turmoil and division that hasn’t resolved.  The president ran an erratic foreign and domestic policy, to say the least.  Why would a country like Australia continue to view the U.S. as a reliable ally given that some of those forces that delivered Donald Trump the presidency are still at play?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  No one can say with certainty what the future will bring.  We have to be grounded in the present.  What are the challenges that our people are facing?  How can we best and most effectively deal with them?  We’re convinced that it’s by doing it together, and you start with the countries that share your basic approach, that share your basic interests, that share your basic values.  And nowhere is that more true than between the United States and Australia.  And you go from there.  And ultimately we’re going to be judged, like anyone else is, by what we do and what we achieve.  And we’re living in the present and focused on the – on these challenges, focused on these opportunities, and we start with the conviction that they can best be addressed in partnership, and that’s exactly why we’ve spent a lot of time and effort to re-energize these alliances and these partnerships.  It’s why I’m here.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Secretary Blinken, we really appreciate your time.  Thank you for speaking with us again.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks so much.  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Melbourne, Australia</p>
<p>Royal Botanic Gardens</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Mr. Secretary, thank you very much for your time.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  It’s great to be with you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  How would U.S. intervention in the case of a Russian invasion of Ukraine differ to the case of, say, a Chinese incursion into Taiwan?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, it’s hard to compare very, very different situations, but what we’re committed to in the case of Ukraine is doing everything we can to defend Ukraine’s territorial integrity, its sovereignty, its independence, which unfortunately is being challenged right now by Russia.  We’ve made very clear to Russia that there are two paths going forward: there’s a diplomatic path, a path of diplomacy, dialogue to see if we can find answers to security concerns that Russia has expressed and that we’ve expressed about Russia’s conduct; but equally, if Russia chooses to renew its aggression against Ukraine, we’ve made clear – not just us but countries throughout Europe and even beyond – that there’ll be massive consequences.</p>
<p>So my hope is that Russia will be deterred by the actions that we’ve taken to build &#8212; to bring together many, many countries that stand against renewed aggression by Russia in Ukraine.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  President Biden says that if an invasion occurs, the planned Nord Stream 2 gas pipeline between Russia and Germany won’t go ahead.  The German chancellor has been a bit more vague on that.  How would America stop that pipeline given it’s not on U.S. territory?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, the President has been very clear that if there is renewed aggression by Russia in Ukraine, it’s very hard to see gas ever flowing through that pipeline.  And right now the pipeline is actually a source of leverage for us, not for Russia, precisely because gas has not yet begun to flow through it.  To the extent that President Putin wants to see that happen, the idea that that could happen if he commits aggression against Ukraine is very, very hard to see.  So that may make him think twice about taking action in Ukraine.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Who does the Biden administration view as a bigger threat to global security, Russia or China?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  These are, again, very different challenges.  Russia right now poses an immediate challenge not just to Ukraine through the possibility of renewed aggression, but to some very basic principles that are relevant to the security not just of people in Europe but throughout the world, including in Australia – principles like you can’t just change the borders of another country by force; you can’t decide for another country its choices, its policies, with whom it will associate; you can’t exert a sphere of influence that tries to subjugate your neighbors to your will.  Those are the basic principles that are at stake when it comes to Ukraine and Russia’s aggression, and they’re relevant right here in this part of the world just as they are in Europe.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  You’re here for the meeting.  Is the Quad grouping about countering the influence of China in this region?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  The Quad fundamentally is about presenting an affirmative vision and affirmative action to deal with some of the main challenges of our time as well as to find opportunities and to make the most of them.  So bringing these countries together to deal with something that’s afflicting everyone – COVID – that is again about dealing with something very concrete in people’s lives.  How we think about emerging technology and the rules and norms and standards that shape it – the Quad is coming together on that.  How we make our economies more resilient, not only recovering from COVID but producing greater resiliency over time through diversified supply chains, for example – that’s what the Quad is all about.</p>
<p>So it’s coming together, using the talents, the resources, the different skill sets that we – that these four countries have, as well as potentially working with other countries.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Australia’s Defense Minister Peter Dutton has warned that Australia and its allies will lose the next decade unless they stand up to China in the South China Sea.  What’s your take on that?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  What we have to do and what we are doing is standing up for the norms, the rules, the standards, the values that unite it – that unite us.  So this is not about standing against anyone in particular; it is about standing up for a rules-based order, making sure that we uphold those rules and principles if they’re being challenged.  Because it’s exactly that that’s undergirded peace, security, and opportunity for people for decades.  So when they’re being challenged, we have an obligation to stand up.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Against that backdrop, Russia and China’s leaders met on the sidelines of the Winter Olympics earlier this week and they declared that they have a no-limits partnership.  That has to be of some concern given the context that you just painted there.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  China and Russia have been growing closer over many, many years, so this is not – this is not new.  I have to say, if – and we of course were not in the room when the two leaders met, but I would imagine that, for example, China would have some issues with Russia’s threats to Ukraine’s territorial integrity and sovereignty.  China talks a lot about upholding the principle of sovereignty.  Well, maybe it has something to say about that.  Russian aggression in Ukraine would not be good for anyone.  It wouldn’t be good for China either.  And so one would think that it would have shared some of its concerns with Russia.</p>
<p>Russia and China are talking.  We’re engaged, the United States, with dozens of partners throughout Europe, around the world, NATO, the European Union, the G7, here through the Quad, AUKUS, you name it.  We have a multiplicity of alliances, of partnerships, of coalitions to deal with issues of concern to our people.  That’s actually been our greatest strength.  And these partnerships, these alliances, not only are they voluntary, they’re based on a shared set of values and basic interests.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  You mentioned AUKUS.  The French Government was put out, to say the least, by its submarine contract with Australia being shelved due to the new security pact between Australia, the UK, and the U.S.  The French said that they were blindsided by what happened.  Were they, and who was responsible for that?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Look, I said at the time that we, speaking for ourselves, the United States could have done a better job communicating with our French allies and partners on this.  But we are working incredibly closely together as partners.  We’re doing the same thing through NATO, with the European Union, the G7.  And so I think the strength of that relationship, of that partnership is as good as it’s ever been.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Which country first floated the idea of a security pact between Australia, the U.S., and the UK, including finding a way to have – for Australia to have nuclear submarines?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, I’m not going to go back and revisit the entire history of this, but certainly this is something that was raised early on by Australia, by the United Kingdom.  And of course part of what we’re doing around the world, as I said, is working to revitalize, to re-energize, and, as necessary, to reinvent these alliances and partnerships because for us, as we’re looking at the problems that afflict our people as well as the opportunities, whether it’s dealing with climate, whether it’s dealing with COVID, whether it’s dealing with emerging technologies, whether it’s dealing with security, not a single one of these problems can be effectively addressed by any one of our countries working alone.  We are much stronger when we find ways to work together.  And that’s why we’ve invested so much in not only our traditional alliances, but in creating new coalitions, new partnerships to focus on specific issues.  That’s what AUKUS is about, it’s what the Quad is about, as well as the traditional alliances like NATO and other organizations.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Final question, Mr. Secretary.  The U.S. under Donald Trump’s leadership was beset with internal turmoil and division that hasn’t resolved.  The president ran an erratic foreign and domestic policy, to say the least.  Why would a country like Australia continue to view the U.S. as a reliable ally given that some of those forces that delivered Donald Trump the presidency are still at play?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  No one can say with certainty what the future will bring.  We have to be grounded in the present.  What are the challenges that our people are facing?  How can we best and most effectively deal with them?  We’re convinced that it’s by doing it together, and you start with the countries that share your basic approach, that share your basic interests, that share your basic values.  And nowhere is that more true than between the United States and Australia.  And you go from there.  And ultimately we’re going to be judged, like anyone else is, by what we do and what we achieve.  And we’re living in the present and focused on the – on these challenges, focused on these opportunities, and we start with the conviction that they can best be addressed in partnership, and that’s exactly why we’ve spent a lot of time and effort to re-energize these alliances and these partnerships.  It’s why I’m here.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Secretary Blinken, we really appreciate your time.  Thank you for speaking with us again.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thanks so much.  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Israeli National Security Advisor Hulata</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-israeli-national-security-advisor-hulata/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 13:14:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313057</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Israeli National Security Advisor Eyal Hulata yesterday. The Deputy Secretary and the National Security Advisor discussed U.S.-Israeli coordination on important global security challenges, including Iran and Russia’s unprovoked military build-up on Ukraine’s borders. Deputy Secretary Sherman reiterated the administration’s ironclad commitment to Israel’s security. Deputy Secretary Sherman also emphasized the importance of Israelis and Palestinians enjoying equal measures of security, freedom, and prosperity, and reaffirmed the commitment of the United States to a two-state solution.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met with Israeli National Security Advisor Eyal Hulata yesterday. The Deputy Secretary and the National Security Advisor discussed U.S.-Israeli coordination on important global security challenges, including Iran and Russia’s unprovoked military build-up on Ukraine’s borders. Deputy Secretary Sherman reiterated the administration’s ironclad commitment to Israel’s security. Deputy Secretary Sherman also emphasized the importance of Israelis and Palestinians enjoying equal measures of security, freedom, and prosperity, and reaffirmed the commitment of the United States to a two-state solution.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-nato-secretary-general-stoltenberg-13/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 12:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313053</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg about continued coordination of the Transatlantic response to ongoing Russian threats against Ukraine. Secretary Blinken reaffirmed the United States’ commitment to close cooperation and consultation with Allies and partners. He underscored the U.S. readiness to impose swift, severe costs on Russia, should it pursue further military aggression against Ukraine. Secretary Blinken and Secretary General Stoltenberg discussed diplomatic efforts to urge Russia to de-escalate and engage in meaningful and reciprocal dialogue, as well as United States and Allies’ force posture adjustments to fortify the Alliance’s Eastern Flank.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg about continued coordination of the Transatlantic response to ongoing Russian threats against Ukraine. Secretary Blinken reaffirmed the United States’ commitment to close cooperation and consultation with Allies and partners. He underscored the U.S. readiness to impose swift, severe costs on Russia, should it pursue further military aggression against Ukraine. Secretary Blinken and Secretary General Stoltenberg discussed diplomatic efforts to urge Russia to de-escalate and engage in meaningful and reciprocal dialogue, as well as United States and Allies’ force posture adjustments to fortify the Alliance’s Eastern Flank.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with French Foreign Minister Le Drian</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-french-foreign-minister-le-drian-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 12:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=313050</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian today about joint efforts by NATO Allies, EU partners, G7 members, and other partners to address Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders. They stressed the importance of continuing to support Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and ensuring Russia understands the high costs it would incur if it were to invade Ukraine further. The two spoke about ongoing efforts by the Minsk Group Co-Chairs to help Armenia and Azerbaijan resolve all outstanding issues related to or resulting from the Nagorno-Karabakh conflict. Secretary Blinken and FM Le Drian reviewed ongoing developments in the Sahel region of Africa. Secretary Blinken also raised the importance of NATO’s engagement with Asia-Pacific partners. He noted France’s leadership role in ending the COVID-19 pandemic and discussed additional areas for cooperation on that effort.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with French Foreign Minister Jean-Yves Le Drian today about joint efforts by NATO Allies, EU partners, G7 members, and other partners to address Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders. They stressed the importance of continuing to support Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and ensuring Russia understands the high costs it would incur if it were to invade Ukraine further. The two spoke about ongoing efforts by the Minsk Group Co-Chairs to help Armenia and Azerbaijan resolve all outstanding issues related to or resulting from the Nagorno-Karabakh conflict. Secretary Blinken and FM Le Drian reviewed ongoing developments in the Sahel region of Africa. Secretary Blinken also raised the importance of NATO’s engagement with Asia-Pacific partners. He noted France’s leadership role in ending the COVID-19 pandemic and discussed additional areas for cooperation on that effort.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Remarks at a Health Security Partnerships Roundtable</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-remarks-at-a-health-security-partnerships-roundtable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 02:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Melbourne, Australia</p>
<p>University of Melbourne Biomedical Precinct</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you so much, Dean.  And it’s – thanks to everyone for being here today.  Really, it’s wonderful to be with you, it’s wonderful to be in Melbourne, and it’s wonderful to be at the university in no small measure because of the family connection that we have here.  And I should probably reveal, just cards on the table in case this is a problem for anyone – I have a particular allegiance to Carlton when it comes to (inaudible).  (Laughter.)  I’ve been, I’ve seen them play.  So I just wanted to make sure that I was honest about that.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><b>MS GUNN:</b>  We’ll allow it.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p>I really want to pick up, Dean, where you brought us because, look, as – at a national level between our countries, between Australia and the United States, I think it’s safe to say that we have been leaders, and leaders together, in trying to deal with COVID and also in trying to build back better so that we have an even stronger, more effective global health security system after we get through this.</p>
<p>But of course, we’re not through it yet and the work that we’re doing together, whether it comes to the production of vaccines, the distribution of vaccines, everything that goes into them, trying to get shots into arms, working on therapeutics, making sure that we’re supporting health care workers who are on the front lines of this – all of that is vitally important, and we know and we continue to experience that the cliché that no one is safe until everyone is safe is profoundly true.  And I know that between our governments – and this is something I’ll be spending some time on here – there is a very deep-seated commitment to do as much as we possibly can this year to really once and for all get ahead of this pandemic.  We’ve said – projected of having 70 percent vaccination in every country in the world by year’s end.  We intend to see that through, but we know the challenges that go with getting that done and getting that done effectively, but at the same time, as we’re doing that, we have to be building a stronger global health security system so that next time around we’re better prepared where we can deal more effectively; hopefully we can prevent, we can detect, we can mitigate more effectively.</p>
<p>But for all the work that the governments are doing – and it’s absolutely necessary – I think what gives me the most cause for optimism are the public-private partnerships that we’ve been building and, of course, the work of the private sector to finally get us to a better place.  And part of why I wanted to get together today, and I’m grateful to all of you for doing that, is to put a bit of a spotlight on that, and in particular the fact that America and Australia together are building these across our countries and across our governments and across our private sectors, building exactly these kind of interconnected partnerships where government can be the ultimate – a catalyst and a facilitator, but at the same time the private sector is doing extraordinary work to really advance our progress.</p>
<p>And I’m anxious to hear from all of you today.  I know from the work that’s been done it’s incredibly gratifying to have Moderna, which is I think a household name now literally around the world, and that’s quite extraordinary.  But the partnership with the Australian Government to open what will be the first mRNA facility, production facility here in this part of the world is a perfect example of how free, open societies can actually come together and deliver benefits not only for our own people but this is going to benefit people around the world.  So this will be the first facility in the Southern Hemisphere to manufacture mRNA vaccines, and that’s going to be a very powerful thing.  It&#8217;s also, I’m convinced, going to have a ripple effect – a ripple effect in terms of jobs, a ripple effect in terms of preparing for the future as we need to do, and a ripple effect around the world not just for our two countries but throughout the region and beyond.  And I think it only serves to further solidify Australia’s leadership in dealing with global health security, the pandemic, and the problem.</p>
<p>We have colleagues from Illumina here.  This is another great example of how close-knit our partnership is and doing it in a way that serves the public good.  Even in my short time here today and just in reading about the University of Melbourne and what’s going on here as a remarkable place of knowledge, of learning, of innovation, the genomics hub right here, a partnership again that is going to be serving the public good.  And there, too, the government has a profound role to play in this partnership with the private sector as well as work that’s being done with the university is actually making a difference, and I’m gratified again that American firms are part of this, making these investments, driving these partnerships.</p>
<p>We have IBM, and there again, working on another aspect of things, and that’s the – all the potential of artificial intelligence.  We are developing standards together – our governments are working on this as well – to make sure that as technology emerges, it does so in a way that lifts people up and tries to advance the common good and is not used for repressive or malign interests.</p>
<p>So there are multiple examples of this.  I just thought this was a wonderful way to illustrate how both our countries and governments are working together, but also how we’re doing this in a public-private way, and hopefully to the benefit of a lot of people.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Melbourne, Australia</p>
<p>University of Melbourne Biomedical Precinct</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you so much, Dean.  And it’s – thanks to everyone for being here today.  Really, it’s wonderful to be with you, it’s wonderful to be in Melbourne, and it’s wonderful to be at the university in no small measure because of the family connection that we have here.  And I should probably reveal, just cards on the table in case this is a problem for anyone – I have a particular allegiance to Carlton when it comes to (inaudible).  (Laughter.)  I’ve been, I’ve seen them play.  So I just wanted to make sure that I was honest about that.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><b>MS GUNN:</b>  We’ll allow it.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.</p>
<p>I really want to pick up, Dean, where you brought us because, look, as – at a national level between our countries, between Australia and the United States, I think it’s safe to say that we have been leaders, and leaders together, in trying to deal with COVID and also in trying to build back better so that we have an even stronger, more effective global health security system after we get through this.</p>
<p>But of course, we’re not through it yet and the work that we’re doing together, whether it comes to the production of vaccines, the distribution of vaccines, everything that goes into them, trying to get shots into arms, working on therapeutics, making sure that we’re supporting health care workers who are on the front lines of this – all of that is vitally important, and we know and we continue to experience that the cliché that no one is safe until everyone is safe is profoundly true.  And I know that between our governments – and this is something I’ll be spending some time on here – there is a very deep-seated commitment to do as much as we possibly can this year to really once and for all get ahead of this pandemic.  We’ve said – projected of having 70 percent vaccination in every country in the world by year’s end.  We intend to see that through, but we know the challenges that go with getting that done and getting that done effectively, but at the same time, as we’re doing that, we have to be building a stronger global health security system so that next time around we’re better prepared where we can deal more effectively; hopefully we can prevent, we can detect, we can mitigate more effectively.</p>
<p>But for all the work that the governments are doing – and it’s absolutely necessary – I think what gives me the most cause for optimism are the public-private partnerships that we’ve been building and, of course, the work of the private sector to finally get us to a better place.  And part of why I wanted to get together today, and I’m grateful to all of you for doing that, is to put a bit of a spotlight on that, and in particular the fact that America and Australia together are building these across our countries and across our governments and across our private sectors, building exactly these kind of interconnected partnerships where government can be the ultimate – a catalyst and a facilitator, but at the same time the private sector is doing extraordinary work to really advance our progress.</p>
<p>And I’m anxious to hear from all of you today.  I know from the work that’s been done it’s incredibly gratifying to have Moderna, which is I think a household name now literally around the world, and that’s quite extraordinary.  But the partnership with the Australian Government to open what will be the first mRNA facility, production facility here in this part of the world is a perfect example of how free, open societies can actually come together and deliver benefits not only for our own people but this is going to benefit people around the world.  So this will be the first facility in the Southern Hemisphere to manufacture mRNA vaccines, and that’s going to be a very powerful thing.  It&#8217;s also, I’m convinced, going to have a ripple effect – a ripple effect in terms of jobs, a ripple effect in terms of preparing for the future as we need to do, and a ripple effect around the world not just for our two countries but throughout the region and beyond.  And I think it only serves to further solidify Australia’s leadership in dealing with global health security, the pandemic, and the problem.</p>
<p>We have colleagues from Illumina here.  This is another great example of how close-knit our partnership is and doing it in a way that serves the public good.  Even in my short time here today and just in reading about the University of Melbourne and what’s going on here as a remarkable place of knowledge, of learning, of innovation, the genomics hub right here, a partnership again that is going to be serving the public good.  And there, too, the government has a profound role to play in this partnership with the private sector as well as work that’s being done with the university is actually making a difference, and I’m gratified again that American firms are part of this, making these investments, driving these partnerships.</p>
<p>We have IBM, and there again, working on another aspect of things, and that’s the – all the potential of artificial intelligence.  We are developing standards together – our governments are working on this as well – to make sure that as technology emerges, it does so in a way that lifts people up and tries to advance the common good and is not used for repressive or malign interests.</p>
<p>So there are multiple examples of this.  I just thought this was a wonderful way to illustrate how both our countries and governments are working together, but also how we’re doing this in a public-private way, and hopefully to the benefit of a lot of people.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Opening Remarks at a Conversation at University of Melbourne With Students and U.S. Government and Exchange Alumni </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-opening-remarks-at-a-conversation-at-university-of-melbourne-with-students-and-u-s-government-and-exchange-alumni/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 01:56:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312978</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Melbourne, Australia</p>
<p>University of Melbourne</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good morning.  So wonderful to be with you today, to start the day in Australia, to start the day here at the University of Melbourne.  And I was particularly looking forward to this event, having an opportunity to have a conversation, to hear from you, to exchange some thoughts.  And as the vice chancellor said, there are a lot of reasons why I’m here in Australia, and we can get into those.  But there are a couple of particular reasons why I’m here at the university, on this campus at this time.  One of them has to do with the fact that I really wanted to engage with some of the sharpest and youngest minds in the country and talk about the future that we have, I hope, together between our countries.</p>
<p>But as the vice chancellor said, there’s also something profoundly personal about this for me.  As he noted, my late stepfather, Samuel Pisar, was an alumnus of this institution.  And without going into too many details, let me say this, because I think it resonates profoundly over the years:  He was born in Bialystok, Poland and born before the Second World War.  Bialystok, Poland was a thriving center of Jewish life in Poland before the war.  But he turned out to be the only member of his immediate family to survive.  There were about 900 kids in the school in Bialystok; he’s the only that survived from that school.  His mother, his father, his sister perished in the Holocaust.</p>
<p>He himself, after enduring Soviet occupation of the ghetto, was shipped off to work camps and concentration camps – Auschwitz, Dachau, Majdanek, and others.  After the war though, as it was ending and he was on a death march out of the camps, he made an escape for it and somehow managed to escape, to survive, to be rescued by American GIs, and to be brought back into the world.</p>
<p>But the reason he was brought back into the world was ultimately because of Australia.  He had an aunt who had left Poland before the war to go to Paris, two uncles – Lazar Sokolofsky who came to Australia – and they ultimately brought him in.  And he had had, of course, no education for four years.  He was 16 years old by the time he got to Australia.  And as he put it, as he told us, as he told the family for years, Australia remade him.  It remade him as a person, it remade him as someone who followed intellectual pursuits, it remade him into a human being.</p>
<p>And this institution was fundamental to that.  Sir Zelman Cowen, who was referenced, was his great mentor.  After being here, after going to the law academy, Sir Zelman managed to help him get a scholarship to Harvard Law School in the United States.  He wound up being an advisor to President Kennedy, had an extraordinary career as a writer and as a lawyer.</p>
<p>But for him and thus for our family, Australia has a particularly special place.  It showed, after a demonstration of how humanity is capable of the worst, it’s also capable of the best – literally bringing someone back to life in every aspect of what that means.</p>
<p>And I want to say too, he somehow escaped from the horrors of that time with his best friend, Ben Kaufman, and Ben too came to Australia.  My stepfather insisted that his uncles bring Ben as well.  And Ben stayed in Australia, built an extraordinary life here in Melbourne, a family.  I think somewhere out here is his son Paul Kaufman.  Paul, are you here?  (Applause.)  Ben, his wife Bebka, Paul, Molly, his sister – we’ve all been mates for life, and so good to see you, my friend.</p>
<p>And that brings me to today.  Our countries too, our people too, in an incredibly challenging time I think are also mates for life.  And there’s a simple reason for that.  Despite the vast distance between us geographically, the distance that I traveled yesterday, there’s virtually no distance between us when it comes to our basic outlook, to our basic values, to our basic interests.  And at a time when so many of those values and interests are being challenged, I think there’s more of an imperative than ever that our two countries be together, work together, tackle these challenges together.</p>
<p>And I’ll just say this before we get into the conversation, which is from the perspective of the United States:  As we’re looking out at the things that truly have an effect on all of us, all of our citizens in different ways every day, whether it’s the changing climate, whether it’s this pandemic that we all continue to live through, whether it’s the impact of emerging technologies that are literally shaping our lives, what we know in the United States, half a world away, is that we cannot effectively deal with these challenges alone.  Whatever our power, whatever our resources, whatever our capabilities, we simply can’t do it.</p>
<p>When it comes to climate, we’re 15 percent of global emissions.  Even if we did everything right at home, we still have to deal with the other 85 percent of emissions that are coming from other countries.  So we have an imperative of finding ways to work together.</p>
<p>COVID, as we’ve all been living through – we know this – it may – it may become a cliché, but it is profoundly true.  No one is safe until everyone is safe, and as long as the disease is percolating somewhere and a variant could pop up, you might get a variant that defeats everything you’ve done.  And so we have a profound incentive together in making sure that the world is vaccinated.</p>
<p>And these technologies that we’re all dealing with every day – the phones that I see on everyone’s table, that are in my pocket – we know that the way they’re used – the rules, the norms that shape the way they’re used, are either going to help them be technologies that advance the good in humanity or do the opposite.  And there again, we have a strong incentive in coming together to determine what those rules will be, what those norms will be, what those standards will be.</p>
<p>And that all starts with likeminded countries, countries coming from the same basic value set, the same (inaudible), putting their resources together, putting their thinking together, putting their energies together to try to advance and make progress.  And that’s fundamentally what this relationship between the United States and Australia is all about.  That’s at least what I believe it’s about.  But I’m anxious to hear from you what you think it’s about – what we’re doing right, what we’re doing wrong, and how we should be thinking about it.</p>
<p>So I’m really grateful to start this trip here, to start it with you, and I welcome the conversation.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Melbourne, Australia</p>
<p>University of Melbourne</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good morning.  So wonderful to be with you today, to start the day in Australia, to start the day here at the University of Melbourne.  And I was particularly looking forward to this event, having an opportunity to have a conversation, to hear from you, to exchange some thoughts.  And as the vice chancellor said, there are a lot of reasons why I’m here in Australia, and we can get into those.  But there are a couple of particular reasons why I’m here at the university, on this campus at this time.  One of them has to do with the fact that I really wanted to engage with some of the sharpest and youngest minds in the country and talk about the future that we have, I hope, together between our countries.</p>
<p>But as the vice chancellor said, there’s also something profoundly personal about this for me.  As he noted, my late stepfather, Samuel Pisar, was an alumnus of this institution.  And without going into too many details, let me say this, because I think it resonates profoundly over the years:  He was born in Bialystok, Poland and born before the Second World War.  Bialystok, Poland was a thriving center of Jewish life in Poland before the war.  But he turned out to be the only member of his immediate family to survive.  There were about 900 kids in the school in Bialystok; he’s the only that survived from that school.  His mother, his father, his sister perished in the Holocaust.</p>
<p>He himself, after enduring Soviet occupation of the ghetto, was shipped off to work camps and concentration camps – Auschwitz, Dachau, Majdanek, and others.  After the war though, as it was ending and he was on a death march out of the camps, he made an escape for it and somehow managed to escape, to survive, to be rescued by American GIs, and to be brought back into the world.</p>
<p>But the reason he was brought back into the world was ultimately because of Australia.  He had an aunt who had left Poland before the war to go to Paris, two uncles – Lazar Sokolofsky who came to Australia – and they ultimately brought him in.  And he had had, of course, no education for four years.  He was 16 years old by the time he got to Australia.  And as he put it, as he told us, as he told the family for years, Australia remade him.  It remade him as a person, it remade him as someone who followed intellectual pursuits, it remade him into a human being.</p>
<p>And this institution was fundamental to that.  Sir Zelman Cowen, who was referenced, was his great mentor.  After being here, after going to the law academy, Sir Zelman managed to help him get a scholarship to Harvard Law School in the United States.  He wound up being an advisor to President Kennedy, had an extraordinary career as a writer and as a lawyer.</p>
<p>But for him and thus for our family, Australia has a particularly special place.  It showed, after a demonstration of how humanity is capable of the worst, it’s also capable of the best – literally bringing someone back to life in every aspect of what that means.</p>
<p>And I want to say too, he somehow escaped from the horrors of that time with his best friend, Ben Kaufman, and Ben too came to Australia.  My stepfather insisted that his uncles bring Ben as well.  And Ben stayed in Australia, built an extraordinary life here in Melbourne, a family.  I think somewhere out here is his son Paul Kaufman.  Paul, are you here?  (Applause.)  Ben, his wife Bebka, Paul, Molly, his sister – we’ve all been mates for life, and so good to see you, my friend.</p>
<p>And that brings me to today.  Our countries too, our people too, in an incredibly challenging time I think are also mates for life.  And there’s a simple reason for that.  Despite the vast distance between us geographically, the distance that I traveled yesterday, there’s virtually no distance between us when it comes to our basic outlook, to our basic values, to our basic interests.  And at a time when so many of those values and interests are being challenged, I think there’s more of an imperative than ever that our two countries be together, work together, tackle these challenges together.</p>
<p>And I’ll just say this before we get into the conversation, which is from the perspective of the United States:  As we’re looking out at the things that truly have an effect on all of us, all of our citizens in different ways every day, whether it’s the changing climate, whether it’s this pandemic that we all continue to live through, whether it’s the impact of emerging technologies that are literally shaping our lives, what we know in the United States, half a world away, is that we cannot effectively deal with these challenges alone.  Whatever our power, whatever our resources, whatever our capabilities, we simply can’t do it.</p>
<p>When it comes to climate, we’re 15 percent of global emissions.  Even if we did everything right at home, we still have to deal with the other 85 percent of emissions that are coming from other countries.  So we have an imperative of finding ways to work together.</p>
<p>COVID, as we’ve all been living through – we know this – it may – it may become a cliché, but it is profoundly true.  No one is safe until everyone is safe, and as long as the disease is percolating somewhere and a variant could pop up, you might get a variant that defeats everything you’ve done.  And so we have a profound incentive together in making sure that the world is vaccinated.</p>
<p>And these technologies that we’re all dealing with every day – the phones that I see on everyone’s table, that are in my pocket – we know that the way they’re used – the rules, the norms that shape the way they’re used, are either going to help them be technologies that advance the good in humanity or do the opposite.  And there again, we have a strong incentive in coming together to determine what those rules will be, what those norms will be, what those standards will be.</p>
<p>And that all starts with likeminded countries, countries coming from the same basic value set, the same (inaudible), putting their resources together, putting their thinking together, putting their energies together to try to advance and make progress.  And that’s fundamentally what this relationship between the United States and Australia is all about.  That’s at least what I believe it’s about.  But I’m anxious to hear from you what you think it’s about – what we’re doing right, what we’re doing wrong, and how we should be thinking about it.</p>
<p>So I’m really grateful to start this trip here, to start it with you, and I welcome the conversation.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry’s Travel to France</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-presidential-envoy-for-climate-john-kerrys-travel-to-france-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 21:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312929</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Brest, France February 10-11 to participate in the One Planet Summit for the Ocean (“One Ocean Summit”) sponsored by the Government of France.  Secretary Kerry will engage governments, international institutions, businesses, and civil society organizations to scale up the international community&#8217;s ambition and identify solutions to the greatest challenges facing our ocean.</p>
<p>The One Ocean Summit is the first of several major ocean events in 2022 and an important milestone in the lead-up to the Our Ocean Conference, which will be co-hosted by Palau and the United States and held in Koror, Palau, April 13-14.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:ClimateComms@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">ClimateComms@state.gov</a>.</p>
<div id="mail_footer"></div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Brest, France February 10-11 to participate in the One Planet Summit for the Ocean (“One Ocean Summit”) sponsored by the Government of France.  Secretary Kerry will engage governments, international institutions, businesses, and civil society organizations to scale up the international community&#8217;s ambition and identify solutions to the greatest challenges facing our ocean.</p>
<p>The One Ocean Summit is the first of several major ocean events in 2022 and an important milestone in the lead-up to the Our Ocean Conference, which will be co-hosted by Palau and the United States and held in Koror, Palau, April 13-14.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:ClimateComms@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">ClimateComms@state.gov</a>.</p>
<div id="mail_footer"></div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing – February 9, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-february-9-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 21:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=312922</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hello. Good afternoon. Thank you all for joining today’s State Department press briefing. I don’t have any announcements to make at the top, but I’ll give it a few minutes before I start taking your questions.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Francesco Fontemaggi, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong> Thank you. That line is open.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-Iran"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Happy – what is this – Wednesday. I wanted to know – I know yesterday you guys were saying that you hadn’t had a full readout from France about President Macron visit to Moscow. So do you have now, and do you have something to say about the (inaudible) comments that the President Macron made after his talks with Putin?</p>
<p>And on another side, I just wonder if you have anything new on the Vienna talks to share with us. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Francesco. I’ll start with your second one. Outside of what I shared yesterday, actually, we don’t have anything to read out or update on the Vienna talks. Special Envoy Malley continues to work with partners in the sidelines, and he also continues to brief Congress remotely. But nothing major to read out or share today.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-RussiaFrance"></a> To your first question, we of course typically wouldn’t read out another country’s meeting. But again, we continue to coordinate closely with our allies and partners.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Matt Lee, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong> Thank you. Just as a reminder, everyone, you may press 1 then zero to join the question queue. Matt Lee, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. Hey, there. I hope you can hear me.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yeah, I can hear – it’s a little faint, but I can hear you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-Iran2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Hold on. Let me hold the phone up a little closer. Sorry. I just wanted to follow up on the answer that you gave me yesterday on INARA and the Iran talks and any potential new agreement. You said yesterday, “The administration will carefully consider the facts as well as the circumstances of any U.S. return to the JCPOA to determine what the legal implications, which would include under INARA.” And then you said, “We’re committed to ensuring the requirements of INARA are satisfied.”</p>
<p>I don’t know if you’re going to be able to answer my question in the level of specificity that I think it requires. So if you need to take it, that’s fine. But I would appreciate an answer if you can get one from the lawyers. And my question is this: Does being “committed to ensuring the requirements of INARA are satisfied” – that was your quote – does that mean that you will submit any agreement that is reached in Vienna to Congress for approval? Not just to send them a notification of “Hi there, this is what we just did,” but to fulfill the spirit – the letter and the spirit of the law, which requires a congressional review and a vote?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Matt. I’m not able to make any determinations today on whether we will submit the report to Congress. As I’ve said before and as you know well, that Special Envoy Malley and those of us here continue to coordinate closely with various partners in Congress. And of course we remain committed to those engagements, of course in a bipartisan manner as it relates to – as Iran policy continues to develop. But anything beyond that we’d be happy to get you more details at a later time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Tony Lewis, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong> Thank you. That line is open.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Do we have Tony on the line?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you mean me, Jalina? Simon.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hi. I can hear you now. Thank you.</p>
<p>Tony, do we have you? Mr. Operator, if we can come back to Tony and for now move on to Christina Ruffini, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong> I believe the person on Tony’s line is Simon.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Oh, Simon Lewis. Okay. Well, let’s &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. It’s Simon Lewis, not Tony. I don’t know who Tony Lewis is.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> I don’t, either.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Thanks, Jalina.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> (Inaudible) Simon.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-UkraineRegion"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. I just wanted to follow up on Francesco’s question on some of President Macron’s comments since his meetings in Moscow and Kyiv. There’s a discussion about whether a solution to the current tensions would be a Finlandization of Ukraine, and Macron sort of admitted that that could be – or considered that could be one of the models on the table for defusing the tension. So does the U.S. have a position on whether that’s – whether that is a possibility?</p>
<p>And secondly, there’s been talk of the solution to this could be through the Minsk protocols. I wonder if you could sort of – if you have any kind of new position on that, given these talks that have gone on with the Europeans, the Ukrainians, and the Russians, and whether you could say specifically what is it that both Ukraine – you would expect both Ukraine and Russia to do to kind of get back into line with what they’ve agreed under those protocols. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Simon, to correct for the record – excuse me about that. I will start with your second question. I can’t really speak to any specific expectations of Ukraine and Russia, but what I can say is that the U.S. welcomes calls for diplomatic resolution to the conflict in eastern Ukraine, and measures Ukraine has proposed to lower tensions in and around Donbas to improve prospects or subsequent progress on the implementation of Minsk agreements. Of course, we stand ready to support sincere efforts and progress from all sides, including Ukraine, France, Germany, and Russia to implement Minsk agreements through the work in the Normandy Format.</p>
<p>To your first question on the Finlandization, I would say that President Macron has said that that was not the formulation that he used, and that ending NATO’s “Open Door” policy would actually be a problem, and we agree with that. And as we’ve said previously, we’re committed to the right of sovereign nations to make their own decisions about their security.</p>
<p>Okay, we can continue on to Christina, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you, CBS News.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hello?</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Yes, your line is open.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-Department"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, great. Good afternoon. I’m wondering – and I’m not saying or trying to imply that the security situation is at this level, but should Kyiv become unsafe, is there a plan to relocate the U.S. embassy somewhere else within the country or is the plan to simply close and evacuate the personnel? And could you facilitate that kind of operation with the security and staff you already have in the country? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Christina. We are preparing for a range of contingency plans, but for operational security reason I can’t get into those specific details from here today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Michel Ghandour, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. That line is open.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-Syria"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina. I have two questions. The <em>Foreign Policy</em> has reported that the United States has quietly cut a deal with Russia that eases the political pressure on Syria at the United Nations, and the report said that if the 15-nation Security Council endorses the deal, the UN security body would hold fewer meetings on Syria’s chemical weapons and consolidate separate sessions on humanitarian relief and the political transition. Is this accurate? And if you have any comment on it.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-IsraelLebanon"></a> And my second question is on Senior Advisor Hochstein’s visit to Beirut. Do you have any update? And news reports said that he offered or represented several ideas to the Lebanese officials to bridge the gap between Lebanon and Israel.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Michel. To your first question, I’d say that we continue to be highly engaged in pushing the Security Council to address the crisis in Syria across as many dimensions as possible. The Council’s program of work is a negotiation among all members of the Security Council. We’ve also been engaged in an effort to keep Syria on the agenda in the face of oppression from Russia and others on the Council. We’re fighting to maintain the international community’s focus on the conflict, and will continue to do so.</p>
<p>On your second question, we don’t have many updates from here, but I would just reiterate what we said in the past, in that the Senior Advisor for Global Energy Security continues to work diligently with the two governments, and of course that includes visits to the region. And any other updates we have, we’ll be sure to let you know at the appropriate time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Liz Kim, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. That line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi. Thank you, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-NorthKoreaRegion"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Two questions for you. Coming Saturday, Secretary Blinken’s meeting with his South Korean and Japanese counterparts in Hawaii to discuss North Korea’s recent missile test. And last December, South Korean Secretary Chung Eui-yong told reporters that South Korea and the United States have agreed in principle on a draft to formally end the Korean War. And I was wondering if this is still the case even after a series of missile tests this year, and will the end of war declaration on the agenda for this Saturday meeting?</p>
<p>And my second question is North Korea’s foreign ministry just released a statement boasting that North Korea is the only country on the planet that can shake the world by firing a missile with the U.S. mainland in its range. Could you comment on that?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Liz. To your first question, I certainly won’t get ahead of the Secretary and his meetings. But what I can say from here is that we are committed to security in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>And to your second question, I don’t have anything to offer for you today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Conor Finnegan.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. That line is open.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-Iran3"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey, sorry, I had myself on mute. Iran today unveiled or displayed a new long-range ballistic missile. I’m wondering if you have any response to that, and in particular given the administration’s stated position of trying to address Iran’s ballistic missile program down the line at some point with further talks, whether you take this as sort of a signal that they’re not willing to engage in those kinds of talks. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Conor. Well, I wouldn’t want to comment on their stature or any hypotheticals on if they are willing to talk or not. But what I can say is that Iran’s development and proliferation of ballistic missiles poses a threat to the international security and remains a significant nonproliferation challenge.</p>
<p>We continue to use a variety of nonproliferation tools to prevent and – further advancement of Iran’s missile program and its ability to proliferate technology to others. So an Iran with a nuclear weapon would likely act even more provocatively, and we’re committed to preventing this from happening.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Dukin Han from Radio Free Asia.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-NorthKorea"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, hello. Yes, thank you, Ms. Porter, and good afternoon.</p>
<p>With regard to North Korea, the Chinese foreign ministry spokesperson said during the regular press conference today – to quote him, he said: “The DPRK has long faced external threats to security, which is the crux of the Korean Peninsula issue,” and when saying that, “If the U.S. truly cares about the well-being of the North Korean people, it should not keep pressuring the DPRK with sanctions. Instead it should face up to the denuclearization measures already taken by the DPRK, respond to its legitimate and reasonable concerns, and take measures to ease sanctions on the DPRK.”</p>
<p>My question is: What is your response to the Chinese foreign ministry spokesman’s remark, and what is the United States view on the denuclearization measures already taken by the DPRK so far? Is there anything worth mentioning at this point?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Dukin. Well, I would say to you what we said time and again before, which is our goal remains the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, and we remain prepared to engage in serious and sustained diplomacy without preconditions to achieve that end and to make tangible progress.</p>
<p>Let’s take a final question from Poonam Sharma.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you, and that line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thank you for taking my question. I wanted to ask you about the U.S. group Sikhs for Justice, which calls itself an American human rights advocacy group. They announced a $250,000 bounty for information on the movements of an Indian general, Kuldeep Brar, who survived multiple assassination attempts and still receives death threats. I just wanted to get your comments on that. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Poonam. So we are not aware of these reports, but this is something I’m happy to take back to the team and get you a thorough response on.</p>
<p>Thank you all for joining today’s press briefing. I hope you have a wonderful week ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:22 p.m.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hello. Good afternoon. Thank you all for joining today’s State Department press briefing. I don’t have any announcements to make at the top, but I’ll give it a few minutes before I start taking your questions.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Francesco Fontemaggi, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong> Thank you. That line is open.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-Iran"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Happy – what is this – Wednesday. I wanted to know – I know yesterday you guys were saying that you hadn’t had a full readout from France about President Macron visit to Moscow. So do you have now, and do you have something to say about the (inaudible) comments that the President Macron made after his talks with Putin?</p>
<p>And on another side, I just wonder if you have anything new on the Vienna talks to share with us. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Francesco. I’ll start with your second one. Outside of what I shared yesterday, actually, we don’t have anything to read out or update on the Vienna talks. Special Envoy Malley continues to work with partners in the sidelines, and he also continues to brief Congress remotely. But nothing major to read out or share today.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-RussiaFrance"></a> To your first question, we of course typically wouldn’t read out another country’s meeting. But again, we continue to coordinate closely with our allies and partners.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Matt Lee, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong> Thank you. Just as a reminder, everyone, you may press 1 then zero to join the question queue. Matt Lee, your line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. Hey, there. I hope you can hear me.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yeah, I can hear – it’s a little faint, but I can hear you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-Iran2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Hold on. Let me hold the phone up a little closer. Sorry. I just wanted to follow up on the answer that you gave me yesterday on INARA and the Iran talks and any potential new agreement. You said yesterday, “The administration will carefully consider the facts as well as the circumstances of any U.S. return to the JCPOA to determine what the legal implications, which would include under INARA.” And then you said, “We’re committed to ensuring the requirements of INARA are satisfied.”</p>
<p>I don’t know if you’re going to be able to answer my question in the level of specificity that I think it requires. So if you need to take it, that’s fine. But I would appreciate an answer if you can get one from the lawyers. And my question is this: Does being “committed to ensuring the requirements of INARA are satisfied” – that was your quote – does that mean that you will submit any agreement that is reached in Vienna to Congress for approval? Not just to send them a notification of “Hi there, this is what we just did,” but to fulfill the spirit – the letter and the spirit of the law, which requires a congressional review and a vote?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Matt. I’m not able to make any determinations today on whether we will submit the report to Congress. As I’ve said before and as you know well, that Special Envoy Malley and those of us here continue to coordinate closely with various partners in Congress. And of course we remain committed to those engagements, of course in a bipartisan manner as it relates to – as Iran policy continues to develop. But anything beyond that we’d be happy to get you more details at a later time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Tony Lewis, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong> Thank you. That line is open.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Do we have Tony on the line?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you mean me, Jalina? Simon.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Hi. I can hear you now. Thank you.</p>
<p>Tony, do we have you? Mr. Operator, if we can come back to Tony and for now move on to Christina Ruffini, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong> I believe the person on Tony’s line is Simon.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Oh, Simon Lewis. Okay. Well, let’s &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. It’s Simon Lewis, not Tony. I don’t know who Tony Lewis is.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> I don’t, either.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Thanks, Jalina.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> (Inaudible) Simon.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-UkraineRegion"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. I just wanted to follow up on Francesco’s question on some of President Macron’s comments since his meetings in Moscow and Kyiv. There’s a discussion about whether a solution to the current tensions would be a Finlandization of Ukraine, and Macron sort of admitted that that could be – or considered that could be one of the models on the table for defusing the tension. So does the U.S. have a position on whether that’s – whether that is a possibility?</p>
<p>And secondly, there’s been talk of the solution to this could be through the Minsk protocols. I wonder if you could sort of – if you have any kind of new position on that, given these talks that have gone on with the Europeans, the Ukrainians, and the Russians, and whether you could say specifically what is it that both Ukraine – you would expect both Ukraine and Russia to do to kind of get back into line with what they’ve agreed under those protocols. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Simon, to correct for the record – excuse me about that. I will start with your second question. I can’t really speak to any specific expectations of Ukraine and Russia, but what I can say is that the U.S. welcomes calls for diplomatic resolution to the conflict in eastern Ukraine, and measures Ukraine has proposed to lower tensions in and around Donbas to improve prospects or subsequent progress on the implementation of Minsk agreements. Of course, we stand ready to support sincere efforts and progress from all sides, including Ukraine, France, Germany, and Russia to implement Minsk agreements through the work in the Normandy Format.</p>
<p>To your first question on the Finlandization, I would say that President Macron has said that that was not the formulation that he used, and that ending NATO’s “Open Door” policy would actually be a problem, and we agree with that. And as we’ve said previously, we’re committed to the right of sovereign nations to make their own decisions about their security.</p>
<p>Okay, we can continue on to Christina, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you, CBS News.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hello?</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Yes, your line is open.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-Department"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay, great. Good afternoon. I’m wondering – and I’m not saying or trying to imply that the security situation is at this level, but should Kyiv become unsafe, is there a plan to relocate the U.S. embassy somewhere else within the country or is the plan to simply close and evacuate the personnel? And could you facilitate that kind of operation with the security and staff you already have in the country? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Christina. We are preparing for a range of contingency plans, but for operational security reason I can’t get into those specific details from here today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Michel Ghandour, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. That line is open.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-Syria"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, Jalina. I have two questions. The <em>Foreign Policy</em> has reported that the United States has quietly cut a deal with Russia that eases the political pressure on Syria at the United Nations, and the report said that if the 15-nation Security Council endorses the deal, the UN security body would hold fewer meetings on Syria’s chemical weapons and consolidate separate sessions on humanitarian relief and the political transition. Is this accurate? And if you have any comment on it.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-IsraelLebanon"></a> And my second question is on Senior Advisor Hochstein’s visit to Beirut. Do you have any update? And news reports said that he offered or represented several ideas to the Lebanese officials to bridge the gap between Lebanon and Israel.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Michel. To your first question, I’d say that we continue to be highly engaged in pushing the Security Council to address the crisis in Syria across as many dimensions as possible. The Council’s program of work is a negotiation among all members of the Security Council. We’ve also been engaged in an effort to keep Syria on the agenda in the face of oppression from Russia and others on the Council. We’re fighting to maintain the international community’s focus on the conflict, and will continue to do so.</p>
<p>On your second question, we don’t have many updates from here, but I would just reiterate what we said in the past, in that the Senior Advisor for Global Energy Security continues to work diligently with the two governments, and of course that includes visits to the region. And any other updates we have, we’ll be sure to let you know at the appropriate time.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Liz Kim, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. That line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi. Thank you, can you hear me?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Yes, I can hear you.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-NorthKoreaRegion"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Two questions for you. Coming Saturday, Secretary Blinken’s meeting with his South Korean and Japanese counterparts in Hawaii to discuss North Korea’s recent missile test. And last December, South Korean Secretary Chung Eui-yong told reporters that South Korea and the United States have agreed in principle on a draft to formally end the Korean War. And I was wondering if this is still the case even after a series of missile tests this year, and will the end of war declaration on the agenda for this Saturday meeting?</p>
<p>And my second question is North Korea’s foreign ministry just released a statement boasting that North Korea is the only country on the planet that can shake the world by firing a missile with the U.S. mainland in its range. Could you comment on that?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Liz. To your first question, I certainly won’t get ahead of the Secretary and his meetings. But what I can say from here is that we are committed to security in the Indo-Pacific.</p>
<p>And to your second question, I don’t have anything to offer for you today.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Conor Finnegan.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you. That line is open.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-Iran3"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hey, sorry, I had myself on mute. Iran today unveiled or displayed a new long-range ballistic missile. I’m wondering if you have any response to that, and in particular given the administration’s stated position of trying to address Iran’s ballistic missile program down the line at some point with further talks, whether you take this as sort of a signal that they’re not willing to engage in those kinds of talks. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Conor. Well, I wouldn’t want to comment on their stature or any hypotheticals on if they are willing to talk or not. But what I can say is that Iran’s development and proliferation of ballistic missiles poses a threat to the international security and remains a significant nonproliferation challenge.</p>
<p>We continue to use a variety of nonproliferation tools to prevent and – further advancement of Iran’s missile program and its ability to proliferate technology to others. So an Iran with a nuclear weapon would likely act even more provocatively, and we’re committed to preventing this from happening.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Dukin Han from Radio Free Asia.</p>
<p><a id="post-312922-NorthKorea"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you, hello. Yes, thank you, Ms. Porter, and good afternoon.</p>
<p>With regard to North Korea, the Chinese foreign ministry spokesperson said during the regular press conference today – to quote him, he said: “The DPRK has long faced external threats to security, which is the crux of the Korean Peninsula issue,” and when saying that, “If the U.S. truly cares about the well-being of the North Korean people, it should not keep pressuring the DPRK with sanctions. Instead it should face up to the denuclearization measures already taken by the DPRK, respond to its legitimate and reasonable concerns, and take measures to ease sanctions on the DPRK.”</p>
<p>My question is: What is your response to the Chinese foreign ministry spokesman’s remark, and what is the United States view on the denuclearization measures already taken by the DPRK so far? Is there anything worth mentioning at this point?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Dukin. Well, I would say to you what we said time and again before, which is our goal remains the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, and we remain prepared to engage in serious and sustained diplomacy without preconditions to achieve that end and to make tangible progress.</p>
<p>Let’s take a final question from Poonam Sharma.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Thank you, and that line is open.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, thank you for taking my question. I wanted to ask you about the U.S. group Sikhs for Justice, which calls itself an American human rights advocacy group. They announced a $250,000 bounty for information on the movements of an Indian general, Kuldeep Brar, who survived multiple assassination attempts and still receives death threats. I just wanted to get your comments on that. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Poonam. So we are not aware of these reports, but this is something I’m happy to take back to the team and get you a thorough response on.</p>
<p>Thank you all for joining today’s press briefing. I hope you have a wonderful week ahead.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:22 p.m.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by the Global Coalition on Countering Daesh/ISIS Globally</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/statement-by-the-global-coalition-on-countering-daesh-isis-globally/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 21:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=312914</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Global Coalition to Defeat Daesh/ISIS remains resolutely committed to achieving the enduring defeat of ISIS.  Recent events in Syria underscore both the success we continue to have in degrading Daesh/ISIS leadership and the continuing threat the terrorist group poses in the region and beyond.</p>
<p>The removal of Daesh/ISIS leader Muhammad Said Abd al-Rahman al-Mawla, also known as Abd Ibrahim al-Hashimi al-Qurayshi, from the battlefield was another significant blow to the terrorist organization.  We as a Coalition will sustain the necessary pressure to deny any Daesh/ISIS attempt to reconstitute or to retake and hold territory in Syria and Iraq.</p>
<p>The swift actions of our local partners &#8211; at the cost of casualties to their forces &#8211; to halt the attack against the Hasakah detention center denied Daesh/ISIS’s attempt to replenish its forces with detainees housed there.  The attack highlighted the vulnerability of temporary detention centers and the importance of fully resourcing Coalition initiatives to ensure the secure detention of ISIS fighters.</p>
<p>The enduring defeat of ISIS in Syria and Iraq remains the Coalition’s top priority.  We will continue to leverage the Coalition’s expertise to counter Daesh/ISIS’s global branches and networks, and to bring its members to justice.  We will use all available tools in the pursuit of that goal and we will not relent until ISIS no longer constitutes a threat.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Global Coalition to Defeat Daesh/ISIS remains resolutely committed to achieving the enduring defeat of ISIS.  Recent events in Syria underscore both the success we continue to have in degrading Daesh/ISIS leadership and the continuing threat the terrorist group poses in the region and beyond.</p>
<p>The removal of Daesh/ISIS leader Muhammad Said Abd al-Rahman al-Mawla, also known as Abd Ibrahim al-Hashimi al-Qurayshi, from the battlefield was another significant blow to the terrorist organization.  We as a Coalition will sustain the necessary pressure to deny any Daesh/ISIS attempt to reconstitute or to retake and hold territory in Syria and Iraq.</p>
<p>The swift actions of our local partners &#8211; at the cost of casualties to their forces &#8211; to halt the attack against the Hasakah detention center denied Daesh/ISIS’s attempt to replenish its forces with detainees housed there.  The attack highlighted the vulnerability of temporary detention centers and the importance of fully resourcing Coalition initiatives to ensure the secure detention of ISIS fighters.</p>
<p>The enduring defeat of ISIS in Syria and Iraq remains the Coalition’s top priority.  We will continue to leverage the Coalition’s expertise to counter Daesh/ISIS’s global branches and networks, and to bring its members to justice.  We will use all available tools in the pursuit of that goal and we will not relent until ISIS no longer constitutes a threat.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
