<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 02:32:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with Omani Deputy Foreign Minister Al-Harthy</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-omani-deputy-foreign-minister-al-harthy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 02:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319999</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Omani Deputy Foreign Minister Khalifa al-Harthy. The Deputy Secretary spoke about Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified attack against Ukraine, the importance of the UN Charter’s principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity of states, and coordinating a strong international response at the UN in support of Ukrainian sovereignty. The United States commends Oman for supporting the UN General Assembly resolution condemning Russia’s war on Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Omani Deputy Foreign Minister Khalifa al-Harthy. The Deputy Secretary spoke about Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified attack against Ukraine, the importance of the UN Charter’s principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity of states, and coordinating a strong international response at the UN in support of Ukrainian sovereignty. The United States commends Oman for supporting the UN General Assembly resolution condemning Russia’s war on Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Crown Prince and Prime Minister Salman bin Hamad Al Khalifa of Bahrain</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-crown-prince-and-prime-minister-salman-bin-hamad-al-khalifa-of-bahrain/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 02:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319991</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with the Crown Prince and Prime Minister of Bahrain, His Royal Highness Salman bin Hamad Al Khalifa, in Washington, D.C. The Secretary and Crown Prince welcomed the launch this week of the second U.S.-Bahrain Strategic Dialogue and discussed a range of bilateral and regional policy matters, including joint peace and security initiatives, economic cooperation, people-to-people exchanges, and steps to advance human rights. They discussed Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified attack against Ukraine. Secretary Blinken commended Bahrain for voting in favor of the UN General Assembly resolution condemning Russia’s war on Ukraine. The Secretary also thanked the Crown Prince for Bahrain’s contribution in facilitating the safe transit of evacuees from Afghanistan and commended Bahrain for advancing its ties with Israel under the Abraham Accords.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with the Crown Prince and Prime Minister of Bahrain, His Royal Highness Salman bin Hamad Al Khalifa, in Washington, D.C. The Secretary and Crown Prince welcomed the launch this week of the second U.S.-Bahrain Strategic Dialogue and discussed a range of bilateral and regional policy matters, including joint peace and security initiatives, economic cooperation, people-to-people exchanges, and steps to advance human rights. They discussed Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified attack against Ukraine. Secretary Blinken commended Bahrain for voting in favor of the UN General Assembly resolution condemning Russia’s war on Ukraine. The Secretary also thanked the Crown Prince for Bahrain’s contribution in facilitating the safe transit of evacuees from Afghanistan and commended Bahrain for advancing its ties with Israel under the Abraham Accords.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-Djibouti Bi-National Forum</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-djibouti-bi-national-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 21:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319877</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for African Affairs Molly Phee and Djiboutian Foreign Minister Mahmoud Ali Youssouf concluded the 6th annual U.S.-Djibouti Bi-National Forum today.  In these high-level discussions launched by Secretary of State Anthony Blinken on February 4, Assistant Secretary Phee and Foreign Minister Youssouf reviewed the longstanding bilateral partnership between the United States and Djibouti and the broad range of security, economic, and development cooperation that encompasses the U.S.-Djibouti bilateral relationship.  They also discussed areas of collaboration to further regional peace, stability, and prosperity in the Horn of Africa.</p>
<div id="mail_footer"></div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for African Affairs Molly Phee and Djiboutian Foreign Minister Mahmoud Ali Youssouf concluded the 6th annual U.S.-Djibouti Bi-National Forum today.  In these high-level discussions launched by Secretary of State Anthony Blinken on February 4, Assistant Secretary Phee and Foreign Minister Youssouf reviewed the longstanding bilateral partnership between the United States and Djibouti and the broad range of security, economic, and development cooperation that encompasses the U.S.-Djibouti bilateral relationship.  They also discussed areas of collaboration to further regional peace, stability, and prosperity in the Horn of Africa.</p>
<div id="mail_footer"></div>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Costa Rican Foreign Minister Rodolfo Solano Quirós, Dominican Republic Foreign Minister Roberto Álvarez, and Panamanian Foreign Minister Erika Mouynes Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-costa-rican-foreign-minister-rodolfo-solano-quiros-dominican-republic-foreign-minister-roberto-alvarez-and-panamanian-foreign-minister-erika-mouynes-before-their-mee/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 21:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319858</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Ben Franklin Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good morning, everyone.  It is really a pleasure to be with my friends and colleagues from Panama, from Costa Rica, from the Dominican Republic, and to be here to meet with the Alliance for Development in Democracy.  That alliance is a powerful commitment and an inspiring commitment to strengthening democracies throughout the region, to private sector-led growth and economic development, and to partnership.  And this is what we so appreciate, all of our countries and your countries working together to advance the things that we believe in and to try to improve the lives of our fellow citizens.</p>
<p>So I’m grateful to have all three of my friends and colleagues here.  Also grateful for the strong support that you’ve shown for Ukraine in this very, very difficult moment, faced with the unprovoked aggression from Russia.  It’s important that the international community speak out clearly with one voice, a strong voice, and I very much appreciate our colleagues doing that.</p>
<p>So thank you and welcome.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER SOLANO:</b>  Thank you.  Thank you.  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.  For us it’s very important to be here.  Democracy, human rights, and freedom of press and speech is under attack worldwide and in our region.  Today our four countries are committed to strengthen democracy, to promote human rights, and to defend freedom of press and speech.  And in these tough moments for humanity, our four countries together need to protect those people who are suffering in these moments and to support the international community to face these challenges.</p>
<p>So thank you so much for having us, and thank you so much because this is a clear demonstration that four nations can work together for a bright future for our people.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER ÁLVAREZ:</b>  Thank you, Secretary Blinken, on behalf of President Luis Abinader and our colleagues for this invitation.  We are here today, as you say, as members of the Alliance for Development in Democracy because of our longstanding shared values with the United States, and we are here to try to strengthen and deepen that longstanding relationship in more meaningful ways.  We stand together because we know that today that democracy cannot be taken for granted.  Given our shared values, democratic values and respect for human rights, we must strive to find creative ways to come out of this very difficult moment together as winners.  We firmly believe, as President Biden said last night, that freedom will triumph over tyranny.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you very much, Roberto.</p>
<p>Erika.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER MOUYNES:</b>  Thank you.  As my colleagues mentioned, this is a unique opportunity.  It’s a unique opportunity to stand up for what believe, for the common values that we share, and to clarify for everybody that democracy can deliver and does deliver results, and that idea in moments like this, it’s more important than ever to stand up with action.  So it’s not only to be there, but actually to show up to the table and take the necessary steps to show what you believe for and be the example for the region.</p>
<p>So I think the alliance is trying, and in the few months that we have developed this coordinated work, we’ve already accomplished much.  So an interesting time to be together, to be here, and we’re grateful that with what – everything that is happening, we recognize the importance of, regionally, to stand united and champion democracy.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.  Thank you all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Ben Franklin Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good morning, everyone.  It is really a pleasure to be with my friends and colleagues from Panama, from Costa Rica, from the Dominican Republic, and to be here to meet with the Alliance for Development in Democracy.  That alliance is a powerful commitment and an inspiring commitment to strengthening democracies throughout the region, to private sector-led growth and economic development, and to partnership.  And this is what we so appreciate, all of our countries and your countries working together to advance the things that we believe in and to try to improve the lives of our fellow citizens.</p>
<p>So I’m grateful to have all three of my friends and colleagues here.  Also grateful for the strong support that you’ve shown for Ukraine in this very, very difficult moment, faced with the unprovoked aggression from Russia.  It’s important that the international community speak out clearly with one voice, a strong voice, and I very much appreciate our colleagues doing that.</p>
<p>So thank you and welcome.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER SOLANO:</b>  Thank you.  Thank you.  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.  For us it’s very important to be here.  Democracy, human rights, and freedom of press and speech is under attack worldwide and in our region.  Today our four countries are committed to strengthen democracy, to promote human rights, and to defend freedom of press and speech.  And in these tough moments for humanity, our four countries together need to protect those people who are suffering in these moments and to support the international community to face these challenges.</p>
<p>So thank you so much for having us, and thank you so much because this is a clear demonstration that four nations can work together for a bright future for our people.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER ÁLVAREZ:</b>  Thank you, Secretary Blinken, on behalf of President Luis Abinader and our colleagues for this invitation.  We are here today, as you say, as members of the Alliance for Development in Democracy because of our longstanding shared values with the United States, and we are here to try to strengthen and deepen that longstanding relationship in more meaningful ways.  We stand together because we know that today that democracy cannot be taken for granted.  Given our shared values, democratic values and respect for human rights, we must strive to find creative ways to come out of this very difficult moment together as winners.  We firmly believe, as President Biden said last night, that freedom will triumph over tyranny.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you very much, Roberto.</p>
<p>Erika.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER MOUYNES:</b>  Thank you.  As my colleagues mentioned, this is a unique opportunity.  It’s a unique opportunity to stand up for what believe, for the common values that we share, and to clarify for everybody that democracy can deliver and does deliver results, and that idea in moments like this, it’s more important than ever to stand up with action.  So it’s not only to be there, but actually to show up to the table and take the necessary steps to show what you believe for and be the example for the region.</p>
<p>So I think the alliance is trying, and in the few months that we have developed this coordinated work, we’ve already accomplished much.  So an interesting time to be together, to be here, and we’re grateful that with what – everything that is happening, we recognize the importance of, regionally, to stand united and champion democracy.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.  Thank you all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friends of Sudan Statement on Publication of UNITAMS Summary Report</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/friends-of-sudan-statement-on-publication-of-unitams-summary-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 20:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319866</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Kuwait, the Netherlands, Norway, Saudi Arabia, Spain, Sweden, United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, the United States of America, and the European Union, as members of the Friends of Sudan, welcome the publication by the UN Integrated Transition Assistance Mission in Sudan (UNITAMS) of its summary report on consultations with Sudanese stakeholders, against the backdrop of Sudan’s ongoing political crisis.</p>
<p>The active engagement of a wide range of Sudanese stakeholders in the consultations, including those representing women, youth, and other groups and regions is a strong and encouraging sign of the actors’ unwavering commitment to resolving the political crisis and to paving the way for a democratic and peaceful Sudan. The report reflects their views and demonstrates strong consensus on a number of key issues and principles, including: installation of a transitional cabinet of civilian technocrats; reduction in the size and powers of the transitional Sovereign Council; establishment of a transitional Legislative Assembly composed of civilians; the equitable participation of women in the transitional institutions; the importance of transitional justice and accountability; and the need to establish new electoral laws and bodies which can deliver free and fair elections.</p>
<p>The areas of consensus provide an important basis for further efforts by all Sudanese parties to find a common understanding on the way forward, by agreeing on a new constitutional and legal basis and governance arrangements for the remaining transitional period, pending credible elections. These efforts must remain Sudanese-owned and –led, and we welcome the commitment of UNITAMS, the African Union, and the Inter-Governmental Authority on Development, as well as the EU, the League of Arab States, and Friends of Sudan, to work together to support the process.</p>
<p>The UNITAMS report also notes overwhelming consensus on the need to build a conducive environment for a political process, by stopping violence and killings in the context of protests, lifting the State of Emergency, ending unjust detentions, ceasing attacks on hospitals, and respecting rights to free expression and peaceful assembly.</p>
<p>The Friends of Sudan call on all relevant Sudanese stakeholders to engage in the next phase of a political process to resolve the political crisis in Sudan. We remain committed to supporting the aspirations of the Sudanese people for a free, democratic, peaceful, and prosperous Sudan.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Kuwait, the Netherlands, Norway, Saudi Arabia, Spain, Sweden, United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, the United States of America, and the European Union, as members of the Friends of Sudan, welcome the publication by the UN Integrated Transition Assistance Mission in Sudan (UNITAMS) of its summary report on consultations with Sudanese stakeholders, against the backdrop of Sudan’s ongoing political crisis.</p>
<p>The active engagement of a wide range of Sudanese stakeholders in the consultations, including those representing women, youth, and other groups and regions is a strong and encouraging sign of the actors’ unwavering commitment to resolving the political crisis and to paving the way for a democratic and peaceful Sudan. The report reflects their views and demonstrates strong consensus on a number of key issues and principles, including: installation of a transitional cabinet of civilian technocrats; reduction in the size and powers of the transitional Sovereign Council; establishment of a transitional Legislative Assembly composed of civilians; the equitable participation of women in the transitional institutions; the importance of transitional justice and accountability; and the need to establish new electoral laws and bodies which can deliver free and fair elections.</p>
<p>The areas of consensus provide an important basis for further efforts by all Sudanese parties to find a common understanding on the way forward, by agreeing on a new constitutional and legal basis and governance arrangements for the remaining transitional period, pending credible elections. These efforts must remain Sudanese-owned and –led, and we welcome the commitment of UNITAMS, the African Union, and the Inter-Governmental Authority on Development, as well as the EU, the League of Arab States, and Friends of Sudan, to work together to support the process.</p>
<p>The UNITAMS report also notes overwhelming consensus on the need to build a conducive environment for a political process, by stopping violence and killings in the context of protests, lifting the State of Emergency, ending unjust detentions, ceasing attacks on hospitals, and respecting rights to free expression and peaceful assembly.</p>
<p>The Friends of Sudan call on all relevant Sudanese stakeholders to engage in the next phase of a political process to resolve the political crisis in Sudan. We remain committed to supporting the aspirations of the Sudanese people for a free, democratic, peaceful, and prosperous Sudan.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Travel to Belgium, Poland, Moldova, Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-travel-to-belgium-poland-moldova-latvia-lithuania-and-estonia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 19:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319768</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Belgium, Poland, Moldova, Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia from March 3 to 8, 2022.  The trip continues extensive consultations and coordination with our NATO Allies and European partners about the Russian Federation’s continued premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken will begin his trip in Brussels, Belgium where he will participate in a NATO Foreign Ministerial, meet with EU counterparts, participate in a G7 Ministerial Meeting, and hold additional meetings with partners to discuss the global response to Russia’s invasion, including Allies’ and partners’ continued coordination on imposing massive consequences and severe economic costs on Russia.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Poland on March 5, where he will meet with Polish leaders, including Foreign Minister Zbigniew Rau, to discuss further security assistance in the face of Russia’s continued aggression and unprovoked attack on Ukraine.  He will also thank Poland for generously welcoming hundreds of thousands of displaced persons from Ukraine and discuss how the United States can augment humanitarian assistance efforts for those fleeing Putin’s war.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Chisinau, Moldova to meet with President Maia Sandu, Prime Minister Natalia Gavrilita, and Foreign Minister Nicu Popescu.  During his stop, the Secretary will discuss support for Moldova’s efforts to receive and assist refugees fleeing Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, as well as U.S. support for Moldova’s democracy, sovereignty, and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Vilnius, Lithuania on March 6 to meet with President Gitanas Nauseda, Prime Minister Ingrida Simonyte, and Foreign Minister Gabrielius Landsbergis. On March 7, the Secretary will travel to Riga, Latvia, to meet with President Egils Levits, Prime Minister Krisjanis Karins, and Foreign Minister Edgars Rinkevics. He will travel to Tallinn, Estonia, on March 8 to meet with President Alar Karis, Prime Minister Kaja Kallas, and Foreign Minister Eva-Maria Liimets. During all three stops, he will discuss joint efforts to support Ukraine, strengthen NATO’s deterrence and defense, promote democracy and human rights, and pursue deeper economic and energy cooperation with our Baltic Allies.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Belgium, Poland, Moldova, Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia from March 3 to 8, 2022.  The trip continues extensive consultations and coordination with our NATO Allies and European partners about the Russian Federation’s continued premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken will begin his trip in Brussels, Belgium where he will participate in a NATO Foreign Ministerial, meet with EU counterparts, participate in a G7 Ministerial Meeting, and hold additional meetings with partners to discuss the global response to Russia’s invasion, including Allies’ and partners’ continued coordination on imposing massive consequences and severe economic costs on Russia.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Poland on March 5, where he will meet with Polish leaders, including Foreign Minister Zbigniew Rau, to discuss further security assistance in the face of Russia’s continued aggression and unprovoked attack on Ukraine.  He will also thank Poland for generously welcoming hundreds of thousands of displaced persons from Ukraine and discuss how the United States can augment humanitarian assistance efforts for those fleeing Putin’s war.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Chisinau, Moldova to meet with President Maia Sandu, Prime Minister Natalia Gavrilita, and Foreign Minister Nicu Popescu.  During his stop, the Secretary will discuss support for Moldova’s efforts to receive and assist refugees fleeing Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, as well as U.S. support for Moldova’s democracy, sovereignty, and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>The Secretary will then travel to Vilnius, Lithuania on March 6 to meet with President Gitanas Nauseda, Prime Minister Ingrida Simonyte, and Foreign Minister Gabrielius Landsbergis. On March 7, the Secretary will travel to Riga, Latvia, to meet with President Egils Levits, Prime Minister Krisjanis Karins, and Foreign Minister Edgars Rinkevics. He will travel to Tallinn, Estonia, on March 8 to meet with President Alar Karis, Prime Minister Kaja Kallas, and Foreign Minister Eva-Maria Liimets. During all three stops, he will discuss joint efforts to support Ukraine, strengthen NATO’s deterrence and defense, promote democracy and human rights, and pursue deeper economic and energy cooperation with our Baltic Allies.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Saudi Foreign Minister Prince Faisal bin Farhan Al Saud</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-saudi-foreign-minister-prince-faisal-bin-farhan-al-saud-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 17:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with the Foreign Minister of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, Prince Faisal bin Farhan Al Saud, about Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified attack against Ukraine, the importance of respecting the UN Charter’s principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity of states, and coordinating a strong international response in support of Ukrainian sovereignty.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with the Foreign Minister of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, Prince Faisal bin Farhan Al Saud, about Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified attack against Ukraine, the importance of respecting the UN Charter’s principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity of states, and coordinating a strong international response in support of Ukrainian sovereignty.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-Turkmenistan Annual Bilateral Consultations</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-turkmenistan-annual-bilateral-consultations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 17:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319608</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, virtual United States-Turkmenistan Annual Bilateral Consultations (ABCs) concluded after two days of productive discussions.  A senior U.S. delegation, led by Assistant Secretary of State Donald Lu, hosted Foreign Minister Rashid Meredov and the senior Turkmen delegation.</p>
<p>The ABCs began in 2009 so that our governments could discuss important policy issues. They continue to serve that important role, even as the global and regional situation have evolved.</p>
<p>During the consultations, the U.S. delegation reinforced support for the independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity of Turkmenistan and reiterated our shared commitment to peace, prosperity, and security in Central Asia through the C5+1 diplomatic platform.  The U.S. delegation reiterated the importance of condemning Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine and of maintaining solidarity with the people of Ukraine.  The delegations discussed a wide range of bilateral and regional issues including cooperation on strengthening border security, counternarcotics, and counterterrorism, as well as the need for progress on human rights, including freedom of religion or belief, labor issues, and education opportunities.  Both delegations also discussed their growing engagement on climate action, trade and business, women’s economic empowerment, and regional connectivity of energy resources.</p>
<p>The United States looks forward to strengthening our efforts with Turkmenistan in all of these important areas and deepening the friendship between our peoples.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Today, virtual United States-Turkmenistan Annual Bilateral Consultations (ABCs) concluded after two days of productive discussions.  A senior U.S. delegation, led by Assistant Secretary of State Donald Lu, hosted Foreign Minister Rashid Meredov and the senior Turkmen delegation.</p>
<p>The ABCs began in 2009 so that our governments could discuss important policy issues. They continue to serve that important role, even as the global and regional situation have evolved.</p>
<p>During the consultations, the U.S. delegation reinforced support for the independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity of Turkmenistan and reiterated our shared commitment to peace, prosperity, and security in Central Asia through the C5+1 diplomatic platform.  The U.S. delegation reiterated the importance of condemning Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine and of maintaining solidarity with the people of Ukraine.  The delegations discussed a wide range of bilateral and regional issues including cooperation on strengthening border security, counternarcotics, and counterterrorism, as well as the need for progress on human rights, including freedom of religion or belief, labor issues, and education opportunities.  Both delegations also discussed their growing engagement on climate action, trade and business, women’s economic empowerment, and regional connectivity of energy resources.</p>
<p>The United States looks forward to strengthening our efforts with Turkmenistan in all of these important areas and deepening the friendship between our peoples.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with Indonesian Foreign Minister Marsudi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-indonesian-foreign-minister-marsudi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 14:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319433</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Indonesian Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi.  The Deputy Secretary condemned Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine and thanked the Government of Indonesia for cosponsoring the UN General Assembly resolution on Ukraine.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Marsudi also emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Indonesia Strategic Partnership and discussed ways to ensure the success of the upcoming U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with Indonesian Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi.  The Deputy Secretary condemned Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine and thanked the Government of Indonesia for cosponsoring the UN General Assembly resolution on Ukraine.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Marsudi also emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Indonesia Strategic Partnership and discussed ways to ensure the success of the upcoming U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Mexican Foreign Secretary Ebrard</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-mexican-foreign-secretary-ebrard-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 01:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=319308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Mexican Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard. Secretary Blinken noted Mexico’s strong statements in support of Ukraine and in defense of the UN Charter in its Security Council and General Assembly remarks and as a part of the OAS Joint Declaration in the wake of Russia’s premeditated and unprovoked invasion. The Secretary and Foreign Secretary reaffirmed both countries’ condemnation of Russia’s actions and called for Russia to cease all hostilities. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Ebrard also spoke about the renewed and vibrant U.S.-Mexico partnership and the advances in cooperation over the past year led by President Biden and President Lopez Obrador. Secretary Blinken reiterated his sincere appreciation for our strong partnership with Mexico as we work to advance democracy, economic prosperity, and security in North America and around the world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Mexican Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard. Secretary Blinken noted Mexico’s strong statements in support of Ukraine and in defense of the UN Charter in its Security Council and General Assembly remarks and as a part of the OAS Joint Declaration in the wake of Russia’s premeditated and unprovoked invasion. The Secretary and Foreign Secretary reaffirmed both countries’ condemnation of Russia’s actions and called for Russia to cease all hostilities. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Ebrard also spoke about the renewed and vibrant U.S.-Mexico partnership and the advances in cooperation over the past year led by President Biden and President Lopez Obrador. Secretary Blinken reiterated his sincere appreciation for our strong partnership with Mexico as we work to advance democracy, economic prosperity, and security in North America and around the world.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="1110000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
