<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 20:41:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary Medina’s Travel to Houston, Texas</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-medinas-travel-to-houston-texas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 20:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329830</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica P. Medina will travel to Houston, Texas, from March 31 to April 1, to participate in discussions on protecting our ocean and fighting plastic pollution at the 31st Annual Conference of the Society of Environmental Journalists (SEJ).  These discussions will set the stage for the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> which the United States will co-host with Palau in Koror, April 13-14.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">OES-PA-DG@state.gov.</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs Monica P. Medina will travel to Houston, Texas, from March 31 to April 1, to participate in discussions on protecting our ocean and fighting plastic pollution at the 31st Annual Conference of the Society of Environmental Journalists (SEJ).  These discussions will set the stage for the <a class="external-link" href="https://ourocean2022.pw/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">Our Ocean Conference</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> which the United States will co-host with Palau in Koror, April 13-14.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:OES-PA-DG@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect">OES-PA-DG@state.gov.</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary of State Blinken’s Call with Indian External Affairs Minister Jaishankar</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-of-state-blinkens-call-with-indian-external-affairs-minister-jaishankar/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 19:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony Blinken spoke with Indian External Affairs Minister Dr. Subrahmanyam Jaishankar today to review regional priorities, including the worsening humanitarian situation in Ukraine and our shared efforts to promote a free, open, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific, in which the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states is respected.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony Blinken spoke with Indian External Affairs Minister Dr. Subrahmanyam Jaishankar today to review regional priorities, including the worsening humanitarian situation in Ukraine and our shared efforts to promote a free, open, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific, in which the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states is respected.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at a Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-press-availability-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 18:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329717</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Algiers, Algeria</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy Algiers</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone.  I’d like to begin by announcing another five stops on this trip.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Not funny.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yeah.  (Laughter.)  In all seriousness, I am very glad to be back in Algeria.  I visited in 2016 when I was the deputy secretary, but this is the first trip that I’m making here as Secretary.  If you’ve noticed over the last weeks, every country in the Maghreb has hosted at least one high-ranking American official, and I think that is a signal, among others, of the importance that we place on these relationships and on the region.</p>
<p>Let me just take a moment as I start to recognize our relatively new ambassador here, Elizabeth Aubin, who arrived last month.  Ambassador Aubin is very uniquely suited for this role.  She previously served as the deputy chief of mission here, and three decades of experience in the Foreign Service.  She is truly the best of our department.  We’re grateful to have you here.</p>
<p>So over the course of this trip, we have visited Israel, the West Bank, Morocco, now Algeria.  And at every stop, we dealt with critical security issues, urgent regional and global challenges, and a shared desire to create more opportunities for our people.</p>
<p>Here in Algeria, the ties between our countries go back a long time – 1795, at a time when most of the world still didn’t recognize our then-young country.  And Hassan Bashaw Dey, who ruled what was then called the Deylik of Algiers, signed a treaty of peace with our first president, George Washington.  Since then, Algerians and Americans have developed our economic, educational, cultural connections, and our countries work closely together on issues that matter to the security and well-being of our people, and many others.</p>
<p>As I said today to President Tebboune and Foreign Minister Lamamra, Algeria’s efforts are critical to improving regional security and stability.  That includes its counterterrorism expertise, the humanitarian and security assistance that it provides to neighbors in the Sahel, its demonstrated leadership in finding regional and African-led solutions to challenges.</p>
<p>On Libya, Algeria has been a critical voice in international efforts to advance the UN political process and promote Libyan elections as quickly as possible.  And as the broker of the Algiers Accords, Algeria continues to play an important role in Mali, where we both support a return to democratic rule.</p>
<p>Algeria has also emerged in the region as a leader in preserving cultural heritage sites, which terrorists and organized crime groups have increasingly looted to finance their illicit activities.  Last year we joined Algeria in bringing together government officials, archaeologists, cultural site managers from Algeria, Libya, Tunisia, and Egypt, to discuss how to keep these sites secure and successfully prosecute looters of cultural property.</p>
<p>On the matter of Western Sahara, the United States supports the work of the UN personal envoy of the secretary general, Staffan de Mistura, in leading the political process under the auspices of the United Nations to promote a peaceful and prosperous future for the people living there.</p>
<p>I also reaffirmed to the president and the foreign minister the importance of concrete progress on human rights, including freedom of religion for all faiths, freedom of expression, especially political speech.</p>
<p>And we talked about ways to build on our robust trade and investment ties.  American companies here are helping to diversify Algeria’s economy – training local employees, sharing knowledge, building long-term partnerships that are of benefit to both of our countries.  I spoke to a number of those businesses today – I think some of you were there – in advance of the Algiers International Trade Fair that’ll take place this summer, the largest in Africa, where the United States is proud to be the country of honor.</p>
<p>Algeria and the United States have worked together to beat back the COVID-19 pandemic.  We’ve donated more than 600,000 vaccine doses to Algeria as well as a 35-bed state-of-the-art field hospital, and a second donated field hospital will be up and running in the coming months.</p>
<p>Likewise, Algeria has been there for its neighbors.  When COVID disrupted tourism and other vital trades in Tunisia, Algeria provided critical financial support and donated more than 250,000 vaccine doses.</p>
<p>Now, as you all know, I came on here to this region after a trip to Brussels with – and Poland with President Biden, where we saw the extraordinary unity and determination among allies and partners to stand with the Ukrainian people and bring an end to Russia’s unjust and brutal war in Ukraine.  The countries of North Africa and the Middle East have experienced themselves the consequences of Russian military campaigns before – for example, in Syria and Libya, where Russian military and paramilitary forces exploited conflicts for Moscow’s gain, with deadly consequences for citizens and communities.</p>
<p>Now, many in this region are feeling the pain of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine in another way, with rising food prices, especially wheat.  Farmers in Ukraine, instead of tending to their crops, have been forced to either fight for their country’s future and independence, or to flee.  Ships with grain are not getting out from Black Sea ports because they’re blocked by Russia’s aggression.  Countries around the world, including North Africa and the Middle East, import significant amounts of wheat from Ukraine, and of course, when food prices rise, so do the numbers of people suffering from hunger.  This is just one more reason why the international community must increase the pressure on Russia to end this unprovoked and unjustified war.</p>
<p>So let me conclude simply by saying thank you to our colleagues in Algeria for hosting us today, and <em>Ramadan Kareem</em> to all of those who will soon celebrate the Ramadan.</p>
<p>With that, I will happily take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll start with Matt Lee of the AP, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, (inaudible).  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, how are you?  Hi.  Thank you.  Are you at all concerned with Algeria’s relationship – Algeria in particular and its relationship with Russia?  And should – do you think that it should be doing more to re-evaluate its ties with the Russians?</p>
<p>And also, given where you’ve been so far on this portion of the trip, the Middle East and North Africa, and what you attended, what you participated in on Monday, are you concerned at all, especially given the president’s comments to you a little bit earlier, that Algeria is in danger of missing out on the kind of benefits, the kind of changes that you’ve talked – you and others have talked about in terms of the region?</p>
<p>And then if I could just ask one last thing on Ukraine and Russia, and that is there are officials in Washington who are saying that the U.S. believes that President Putin has been misled by his top military advisors.  Is this something that is shared administration-wide, or at least by you?  Do you believe that to be the case?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> Thanks, Matt.  So on the first part of the question, look, I think it’s a reality that different countries have different historical relationships with Russia.  But there are times when one issue emerges that is so clearly black and white, and in this case of Ukraine a clear aggressor and a clear victim, that it’s important to stand with the victim and to stand for the principles that have also been violated, principles that should matter to countries around the world, principles about sovereignty, about independence.  And I know that that’s something that Algerians feel strongly about, given their own history.</p>
<p>And I think countries in the region as well have seen the damaging effects of Russia’s military campaigns before.  I alluded to that a moment ago.  In Syria and Libya, as I mentioned, the Russian military and paramilitary forces have exploited conflicts for Moscow’s gain.  And that in turn has actually posed great threats to security in the region and stability and commerce.  And as I mentioned as well, these actions have had deadly consequences for citizens in the region.  They’ve disrupted the peace and prosperity of communities.  They’ve intruded into the lives of families and individuals who are simply trying to live peacefully in their own countries.</p>
<p>And then again, I think the impact that’s being felt, even if what seems very distant as a conflict to people in this region because it is half a world away or almost half a world away in Europe, it’s having a direct impact on their lives right now, particularly with regard to rising food prices, something that everyone is feeling, especially wheat.  So my sense from having talked to a lot of colleagues over the last days is that a lot of this pain is keenly felt in this region.  Most of the countries import half their wheat or more.  And so we see them taking stock of that, and that’s factoring into their thinking.</p>
<p>But mostly, I think you’re seeing that countries understand that what’s happening in Ukraine matters, of course, first and foremost to the people in Ukraine.  But it also matters to them because, as I said, principles that matter to them – the UN charter, sovereignty, independence – are also the victims of aggression.</p>
<p>With regard to the Negev and the countries participating in the normalization process with Israel, look, these are decisions for countries to make.  They have to decide what’s in the best interests of their own people.  I think what we’re trying to show through the countries that are participating in the Negev process, since we’re now giving it that name, is that this is going to have real, practical benefits for the people in the countries participating in that effort who have normalized their relations with Israel.</p>
<p>And we’re seeing that take life in terms of connections that have grown very rapidly between people, between businesses, between students, tourists; all of that, even with COVID, has gone up dramatically.  At the same time, what we’re doing as governments is looking at how we can work together to make the kinds of investments in infrastructure, in global health, in science, in dealing with climate, that are going to have real benefits for people.  My bet is that as other countries that are not part of that process see this take shape, they will conclude that this is something they want to be a part of.  And that’ll happen at different paces for different countries.  But, of course, it’s on us to demonstrate that it really works and that it produces results.  I believe that it will.</p>
<p>And finally, with regard to President Putin, look, what I can tell you is this, and I said this before:  One of the Achilles heels of autocracies is that you don’t have people in those systems who speak truth to power or who have the ability to speak truth to power.  And I think that is something that we’re seeing in Russia.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We’ll turn to Abderrahim Kachour.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary of State.  United States is adopting an advance position against Russian military aggression in Ukraine based on the principle of violence against international law.  But the same thing is happening in Palestine, in (inaudible), as well in Western Sahara.  But United States didn’t show the same fairness, the same resolve, as that one in Ukraine.  And in the same context, is Biden administration still adopting the proclamation of the ex-President Donald Trump recognizing Moroccan sovereignty over the Western Sahara?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>  Thank you very much.  When President Biden took office, we and he made two principal commitments in terms of our foreign policy and how we would engage the world.  We made a commitment to re-engage with partners – and international institutions and organizations – and we made a commitment to lead with diplomacy, and that’s what we’ve done.  Part of that means that when the basic rules of diplomacy and the international system that are necessary to try to keep peace and security are being violated, we will stand up with other countries to defend them.  And that’s what we’re doing.  That’s what we’re doing in the case of this aggression.  But the centrality of diplomacy to this effort is critical.</p>
<p>And so when it comes to Israel and the Palestinians, we have remained very engaged with our diplomacy to try and advance prospects for getting back to a two-state solution, to negotiating that, and in the meantime doing everything that we can to help the Palestinian people improve their lives.  We’ve committed half a billion dollars in assistance to the Palestinians over the last year.  We’ve re-engaged with UNRWA.  And, of course, I was just up in Ramallah.  And by the way, we were talking about the Negev Summit and the countries participating in that – one of the things that we spent some time talking about is how we could use that grouping of countries to focus on helping Palestinians improve their lives.  And we also made clear – and I certainly made clear – that as committed as we are to supporting normalization and to having more countries join in, that is not a substitute for dealing with the conflict between Israelis and Palestinians, and not a substitute for two states.</p>
<p>Similarly, with regard to Western Sahara, we’re very focused on diplomacy and on advancing a resolution through diplomacy, including through the efforts of Staffan de Mistura, the envoy from the United Nations.</p>
<p>So I think these things are very consistent.  In each case, we are working through diplomacy, working with other countries to uphold the basic principles of the international system.  And again, on Morocco, on Western Sahara, we are continuing to support the efforts of the UN.  There’s been no change in our position otherwise.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Peter Martin of Bloomberg.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, thank you.   Yesterday you met with Crown Prince Mohammed bin Zayed.  Did you ask him to increase oil production to help bring down gas prices?  And did you offer any specific assurances about the UAE’s security?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thanks.  Well, first, let me just say we had what I thought was an excellent and lengthy discussion.  And we always benefit, and I certainly always benefit, from getting the crown prince’s perspective.  And we had what I thought was a very meaningful, heartfelt exchange that covered really the breadth of our partnership and did it in a strategic way as well as a specific way.</p>
<p>One of the things I made very clear to him is the value that we attach to that partnership, and that we are a true partner for the UAE.  The UAE has been with us around the world, including in Afghanistan, fighting side by side.  In fact, the crown prince had some of his sons in attendance who had fought with us, and one indeed who was injured.  That’s a very powerful thing.  And we’ll continue to stand by them.</p>
<p>One of the things I told them was that the United States remains committed to helping the UAE defend itself against threats from Yemen, from the Houthis, even as we work to try to bring that conflict to a close.  In fact, we have our Special Envoy Tim Lenderking in the region as we speak, and we very much welcome the UAE support for a truce that could lead to a ceasefire.  I also took the opportunity to commend the crown prince for his vision, his courage, his leadership in normalizing ties with Israel, and we talked about the opportunities that can bring for all of our people.</p>
<p>We had a very constructive discussion as well about the war in Ukraine and the Russian aggression there.  We talked about Syria, the status of our talks with Iran on the possible return of the JCPOA, and a number of other things.  It was really a lengthy and detailed conversation as well as one that looked at the relationship from a strategic perspective.  So we will continue to be in very close touch with our Emirati partners on all of these issues and more.  Our teams are following up on many of the things that we discussed yesterday.</p>
<p>As to energy, we believe it’s critical that there be abundant supplies of energy on markets now and that there also be a steady supply.  But as it happens, we didn’t focus on that issue specifically.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll take a final question from Amel Blidi, <em>El Watan</em>.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.  We’d like to know:  How do you perceive Algeria, and what’s your assessment towards the situation in North Africa, especially with deep crisis between Algeria and Morocco and the complex question in Libya?  So do you feel (inaudible) &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.  As I said at the outset, we have a relationship that runs back a long way in our history and one that’s meaningful precisely because Algeria was among the first countries to recognize the United States.  This goes back to our founding president, George Washington.  And in ways over the years, we have tried to build on that founding moment with security ties, economic ties, cultural ties connecting our people.  We are very grateful for Algeria’s important and ongoing diplomatic efforts to try to advance peace and security in the region.  It’s playing an important role and one that we count on.  We – as I mentioned, we talked a lot today about Libya and we are working very much in common to try to advance a truly democratic transition there through elections and a new government.</p>
<p>My sense is that building on this foundation of existing work together on security, deepening cooperation economically with trade and investment – I mentioned some of the numbers earlier today having increased significantly even during COVID.  And I think particularly with President Tebboune’s economic plan, one that offers the prospect I think of creating an even more favorable investment climate here for American companies through clear rules and regulations and predictability, I think you’re going to see that grow.  And as I mentioned, we have the international fair of which we’re the guest of honor this summer.  That’s a good opportunity to continue to bring American companies and Algerian businesses and people together.</p>
<p>We’ve been working very closely on counterterrorism and regional security, and we’re learning from each other in that process and strengthening our respective defense capabilities.  We were very proud – coming back to the connections between us in different ways, we just signed recently a three-year agreement with Columbia University, a university I happened to attend, and the Algerian Ministry of Higher Education and Scientific Research that will help revamp Algeria’s curriculum for teaching English language in universities.  And we, as I said, have been increasing these business and commercial ties in ways that will have very practical benefits to the lives of Algerians and Americans alike creating opportunity, creating jobs, advancing progress in everything from agriculture to IT to energy.</p>
<p>So what I’m seeing is a good foundation that we’re now building upon and that we’re very much looking forward to doing.  At the same time, to further address the second part of your question, we share real concerns about security in the region, particularly in the Sahel.  And we exchanged I think important, useful ideas about what we can do more effectively to deal with the challenges posed to security in the Sahel, but also to try to bring people there more opportunity, more hope, which is ultimately the best answer to dealing with security challenges.</p>
<p>So across the board, this was a very good day.  It’s building on a number of days that other senior officials have had here.  And of course, it’s building on the work that’s being done every day by our embassy and by private American citizens, businesses, students, et cetera.  All of that I think will increase in the months and years ahead.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  All right.  Thank you all.  See you at the next stop.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Algiers, Algeria</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy Algiers</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Good afternoon, everyone.  I’d like to begin by announcing another five stops on this trip.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Not funny.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yeah.  (Laughter.)  In all seriousness, I am very glad to be back in Algeria.  I visited in 2016 when I was the deputy secretary, but this is the first trip that I’m making here as Secretary.  If you’ve noticed over the last weeks, every country in the Maghreb has hosted at least one high-ranking American official, and I think that is a signal, among others, of the importance that we place on these relationships and on the region.</p>
<p>Let me just take a moment as I start to recognize our relatively new ambassador here, Elizabeth Aubin, who arrived last month.  Ambassador Aubin is very uniquely suited for this role.  She previously served as the deputy chief of mission here, and three decades of experience in the Foreign Service.  She is truly the best of our department.  We’re grateful to have you here.</p>
<p>So over the course of this trip, we have visited Israel, the West Bank, Morocco, now Algeria.  And at every stop, we dealt with critical security issues, urgent regional and global challenges, and a shared desire to create more opportunities for our people.</p>
<p>Here in Algeria, the ties between our countries go back a long time – 1795, at a time when most of the world still didn’t recognize our then-young country.  And Hassan Bashaw Dey, who ruled what was then called the Deylik of Algiers, signed a treaty of peace with our first president, George Washington.  Since then, Algerians and Americans have developed our economic, educational, cultural connections, and our countries work closely together on issues that matter to the security and well-being of our people, and many others.</p>
<p>As I said today to President Tebboune and Foreign Minister Lamamra, Algeria’s efforts are critical to improving regional security and stability.  That includes its counterterrorism expertise, the humanitarian and security assistance that it provides to neighbors in the Sahel, its demonstrated leadership in finding regional and African-led solutions to challenges.</p>
<p>On Libya, Algeria has been a critical voice in international efforts to advance the UN political process and promote Libyan elections as quickly as possible.  And as the broker of the Algiers Accords, Algeria continues to play an important role in Mali, where we both support a return to democratic rule.</p>
<p>Algeria has also emerged in the region as a leader in preserving cultural heritage sites, which terrorists and organized crime groups have increasingly looted to finance their illicit activities.  Last year we joined Algeria in bringing together government officials, archaeologists, cultural site managers from Algeria, Libya, Tunisia, and Egypt, to discuss how to keep these sites secure and successfully prosecute looters of cultural property.</p>
<p>On the matter of Western Sahara, the United States supports the work of the UN personal envoy of the secretary general, Staffan de Mistura, in leading the political process under the auspices of the United Nations to promote a peaceful and prosperous future for the people living there.</p>
<p>I also reaffirmed to the president and the foreign minister the importance of concrete progress on human rights, including freedom of religion for all faiths, freedom of expression, especially political speech.</p>
<p>And we talked about ways to build on our robust trade and investment ties.  American companies here are helping to diversify Algeria’s economy – training local employees, sharing knowledge, building long-term partnerships that are of benefit to both of our countries.  I spoke to a number of those businesses today – I think some of you were there – in advance of the Algiers International Trade Fair that’ll take place this summer, the largest in Africa, where the United States is proud to be the country of honor.</p>
<p>Algeria and the United States have worked together to beat back the COVID-19 pandemic.  We’ve donated more than 600,000 vaccine doses to Algeria as well as a 35-bed state-of-the-art field hospital, and a second donated field hospital will be up and running in the coming months.</p>
<p>Likewise, Algeria has been there for its neighbors.  When COVID disrupted tourism and other vital trades in Tunisia, Algeria provided critical financial support and donated more than 250,000 vaccine doses.</p>
<p>Now, as you all know, I came on here to this region after a trip to Brussels with – and Poland with President Biden, where we saw the extraordinary unity and determination among allies and partners to stand with the Ukrainian people and bring an end to Russia’s unjust and brutal war in Ukraine.  The countries of North Africa and the Middle East have experienced themselves the consequences of Russian military campaigns before – for example, in Syria and Libya, where Russian military and paramilitary forces exploited conflicts for Moscow’s gain, with deadly consequences for citizens and communities.</p>
<p>Now, many in this region are feeling the pain of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine in another way, with rising food prices, especially wheat.  Farmers in Ukraine, instead of tending to their crops, have been forced to either fight for their country’s future and independence, or to flee.  Ships with grain are not getting out from Black Sea ports because they’re blocked by Russia’s aggression.  Countries around the world, including North Africa and the Middle East, import significant amounts of wheat from Ukraine, and of course, when food prices rise, so do the numbers of people suffering from hunger.  This is just one more reason why the international community must increase the pressure on Russia to end this unprovoked and unjustified war.</p>
<p>So let me conclude simply by saying thank you to our colleagues in Algeria for hosting us today, and <em>Ramadan Kareem</em> to all of those who will soon celebrate the Ramadan.</p>
<p>With that, I will happily take some questions.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  We’ll start with Matt Lee of the AP, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Hi, (inaudible).  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Matt.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, how are you?  Hi.  Thank you.  Are you at all concerned with Algeria’s relationship – Algeria in particular and its relationship with Russia?  And should – do you think that it should be doing more to re-evaluate its ties with the Russians?</p>
<p>And also, given where you’ve been so far on this portion of the trip, the Middle East and North Africa, and what you attended, what you participated in on Monday, are you concerned at all, especially given the president’s comments to you a little bit earlier, that Algeria is in danger of missing out on the kind of benefits, the kind of changes that you’ve talked – you and others have talked about in terms of the region?</p>
<p>And then if I could just ask one last thing on Ukraine and Russia, and that is there are officials in Washington who are saying that the U.S. believes that President Putin has been misled by his top military advisors.  Is this something that is shared administration-wide, or at least by you?  Do you believe that to be the case?  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong> Thanks, Matt.  So on the first part of the question, look, I think it’s a reality that different countries have different historical relationships with Russia.  But there are times when one issue emerges that is so clearly black and white, and in this case of Ukraine a clear aggressor and a clear victim, that it’s important to stand with the victim and to stand for the principles that have also been violated, principles that should matter to countries around the world, principles about sovereignty, about independence.  And I know that that’s something that Algerians feel strongly about, given their own history.</p>
<p>And I think countries in the region as well have seen the damaging effects of Russia’s military campaigns before.  I alluded to that a moment ago.  In Syria and Libya, as I mentioned, the Russian military and paramilitary forces have exploited conflicts for Moscow’s gain.  And that in turn has actually posed great threats to security in the region and stability and commerce.  And as I mentioned as well, these actions have had deadly consequences for citizens in the region.  They’ve disrupted the peace and prosperity of communities.  They’ve intruded into the lives of families and individuals who are simply trying to live peacefully in their own countries.</p>
<p>And then again, I think the impact that’s being felt, even if what seems very distant as a conflict to people in this region because it is half a world away or almost half a world away in Europe, it’s having a direct impact on their lives right now, particularly with regard to rising food prices, something that everyone is feeling, especially wheat.  So my sense from having talked to a lot of colleagues over the last days is that a lot of this pain is keenly felt in this region.  Most of the countries import half their wheat or more.  And so we see them taking stock of that, and that’s factoring into their thinking.</p>
<p>But mostly, I think you’re seeing that countries understand that what’s happening in Ukraine matters, of course, first and foremost to the people in Ukraine.  But it also matters to them because, as I said, principles that matter to them – the UN charter, sovereignty, independence – are also the victims of aggression.</p>
<p>With regard to the Negev and the countries participating in the normalization process with Israel, look, these are decisions for countries to make.  They have to decide what’s in the best interests of their own people.  I think what we’re trying to show through the countries that are participating in the Negev process, since we’re now giving it that name, is that this is going to have real, practical benefits for the people in the countries participating in that effort who have normalized their relations with Israel.</p>
<p>And we’re seeing that take life in terms of connections that have grown very rapidly between people, between businesses, between students, tourists; all of that, even with COVID, has gone up dramatically.  At the same time, what we’re doing as governments is looking at how we can work together to make the kinds of investments in infrastructure, in global health, in science, in dealing with climate, that are going to have real benefits for people.  My bet is that as other countries that are not part of that process see this take shape, they will conclude that this is something they want to be a part of.  And that’ll happen at different paces for different countries.  But, of course, it’s on us to demonstrate that it really works and that it produces results.  I believe that it will.</p>
<p>And finally, with regard to President Putin, look, what I can tell you is this, and I said this before:  One of the Achilles heels of autocracies is that you don’t have people in those systems who speak truth to power or who have the ability to speak truth to power.  And I think that is something that we’re seeing in Russia.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We’ll turn to Abderrahim Kachour.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary of State.  United States is adopting an advance position against Russian military aggression in Ukraine based on the principle of violence against international law.  But the same thing is happening in Palestine, in (inaudible), as well in Western Sahara.  But United States didn’t show the same fairness, the same resolve, as that one in Ukraine.  And in the same context, is Biden administration still adopting the proclamation of the ex-President Donald Trump recognizing Moroccan sovereignty over the Western Sahara?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN: </strong>  Thank you very much.  When President Biden took office, we and he made two principal commitments in terms of our foreign policy and how we would engage the world.  We made a commitment to re-engage with partners – and international institutions and organizations – and we made a commitment to lead with diplomacy, and that’s what we’ve done.  Part of that means that when the basic rules of diplomacy and the international system that are necessary to try to keep peace and security are being violated, we will stand up with other countries to defend them.  And that’s what we’re doing.  That’s what we’re doing in the case of this aggression.  But the centrality of diplomacy to this effort is critical.</p>
<p>And so when it comes to Israel and the Palestinians, we have remained very engaged with our diplomacy to try and advance prospects for getting back to a two-state solution, to negotiating that, and in the meantime doing everything that we can to help the Palestinian people improve their lives.  We’ve committed half a billion dollars in assistance to the Palestinians over the last year.  We’ve re-engaged with UNRWA.  And, of course, I was just up in Ramallah.  And by the way, we were talking about the Negev Summit and the countries participating in that – one of the things that we spent some time talking about is how we could use that grouping of countries to focus on helping Palestinians improve their lives.  And we also made clear – and I certainly made clear – that as committed as we are to supporting normalization and to having more countries join in, that is not a substitute for dealing with the conflict between Israelis and Palestinians, and not a substitute for two states.</p>
<p>Similarly, with regard to Western Sahara, we’re very focused on diplomacy and on advancing a resolution through diplomacy, including through the efforts of Staffan de Mistura, the envoy from the United Nations.</p>
<p>So I think these things are very consistent.  In each case, we are working through diplomacy, working with other countries to uphold the basic principles of the international system.  And again, on Morocco, on Western Sahara, we are continuing to support the efforts of the UN.  There’s been no change in our position otherwise.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>Peter Martin of Bloomberg.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Hi, thank you.   Yesterday you met with Crown Prince Mohammed bin Zayed.  Did you ask him to increase oil production to help bring down gas prices?  And did you offer any specific assurances about the UAE’s security?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thanks.  Well, first, let me just say we had what I thought was an excellent and lengthy discussion.  And we always benefit, and I certainly always benefit, from getting the crown prince’s perspective.  And we had what I thought was a very meaningful, heartfelt exchange that covered really the breadth of our partnership and did it in a strategic way as well as a specific way.</p>
<p>One of the things I made very clear to him is the value that we attach to that partnership, and that we are a true partner for the UAE.  The UAE has been with us around the world, including in Afghanistan, fighting side by side.  In fact, the crown prince had some of his sons in attendance who had fought with us, and one indeed who was injured.  That’s a very powerful thing.  And we’ll continue to stand by them.</p>
<p>One of the things I told them was that the United States remains committed to helping the UAE defend itself against threats from Yemen, from the Houthis, even as we work to try to bring that conflict to a close.  In fact, we have our Special Envoy Tim Lenderking in the region as we speak, and we very much welcome the UAE support for a truce that could lead to a ceasefire.  I also took the opportunity to commend the crown prince for his vision, his courage, his leadership in normalizing ties with Israel, and we talked about the opportunities that can bring for all of our people.</p>
<p>We had a very constructive discussion as well about the war in Ukraine and the Russian aggression there.  We talked about Syria, the status of our talks with Iran on the possible return of the JCPOA, and a number of other things.  It was really a lengthy and detailed conversation as well as one that looked at the relationship from a strategic perspective.  So we will continue to be in very close touch with our Emirati partners on all of these issues and more.  Our teams are following up on many of the things that we discussed yesterday.</p>
<p>As to energy, we believe it’s critical that there be abundant supplies of energy on markets now and that there also be a steady supply.  But as it happens, we didn’t focus on that issue specifically.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:  </strong>We’ll take a final question from Amel Blidi, <em>El Watan</em>.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you.  We’d like to know:  How do you perceive Algeria, and what’s your assessment towards the situation in North Africa, especially with deep crisis between Algeria and Morocco and the complex question in Libya?  So do you feel (inaudible) &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.  As I said at the outset, we have a relationship that runs back a long way in our history and one that’s meaningful precisely because Algeria was among the first countries to recognize the United States.  This goes back to our founding president, George Washington.  And in ways over the years, we have tried to build on that founding moment with security ties, economic ties, cultural ties connecting our people.  We are very grateful for Algeria’s important and ongoing diplomatic efforts to try to advance peace and security in the region.  It’s playing an important role and one that we count on.  We – as I mentioned, we talked a lot today about Libya and we are working very much in common to try to advance a truly democratic transition there through elections and a new government.</p>
<p>My sense is that building on this foundation of existing work together on security, deepening cooperation economically with trade and investment – I mentioned some of the numbers earlier today having increased significantly even during COVID.  And I think particularly with President Tebboune’s economic plan, one that offers the prospect I think of creating an even more favorable investment climate here for American companies through clear rules and regulations and predictability, I think you’re going to see that grow.  And as I mentioned, we have the international fair of which we’re the guest of honor this summer.  That’s a good opportunity to continue to bring American companies and Algerian businesses and people together.</p>
<p>We’ve been working very closely on counterterrorism and regional security, and we’re learning from each other in that process and strengthening our respective defense capabilities.  We were very proud – coming back to the connections between us in different ways, we just signed recently a three-year agreement with Columbia University, a university I happened to attend, and the Algerian Ministry of Higher Education and Scientific Research that will help revamp Algeria’s curriculum for teaching English language in universities.  And we, as I said, have been increasing these business and commercial ties in ways that will have very practical benefits to the lives of Algerians and Americans alike creating opportunity, creating jobs, advancing progress in everything from agriculture to IT to energy.</p>
<p>So what I’m seeing is a good foundation that we’re now building upon and that we’re very much looking forward to doing.  At the same time, to further address the second part of your question, we share real concerns about security in the region, particularly in the Sahel.  And we exchanged I think important, useful ideas about what we can do more effectively to deal with the challenges posed to security in the Sahel, but also to try to bring people there more opportunity, more hope, which is ultimately the best answer to dealing with security challenges.</p>
<p>So across the board, this was a very good day.  It’s building on a number of days that other senior officials have had here.  And of course, it’s building on the work that’s being done every day by our embassy and by private American citizens, businesses, students, et cetera.  All of that I think will increase in the months and years ahead.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  All right.  Thank you all.  See you at the next stop.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Under Secretary for Arms Control and International Security Bonnie D. Jenkins Announces Kenneth D. Ward as U.S. Special Representative to the Biological Weapons Convention</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/under-secretary-for-arms-control-and-international-security-bonnie-d-jenkins-announces-kenneth-d-ward-as-u-s-special-representative-to-the-biological-weapons-convention/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 18:45:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary of State for Arms Control and International Security Bonnie D. Jenkins is pleased to announce Kenneth D. Ward as the U.S. Special Representative to the Biological Weapons Convention.  The Administration is deeply committed to countering the full range of present and future biological threats.  This includes upholding and strengthening the Biological Weapons Convention (BWC).  We look forward to Mr. Ward leading U.S. efforts in this important area and heading up our team of experts at the BWC Review Conference later this year.</p>
<p>Mr. Ward comes to this position with 30 years’ experience in arms control and nonproliferation with the U.S. Department of State and the former U.S. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency.  He most recently served as the U.S. Ambassador to the Organization for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons in The Hague, Netherlands, with previous assignments as the Director of the Office of Chemical and Biological Weapons Affairs in State’s Bureau of Arms Control, Verification, and Compliance, and the Deputy Negotiator during the 2004-2007 WMD elimination effort in Libya.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Under Secretary of State for Arms Control and International Security Bonnie D. Jenkins is pleased to announce Kenneth D. Ward as the U.S. Special Representative to the Biological Weapons Convention.  The Administration is deeply committed to countering the full range of present and future biological threats.  This includes upholding and strengthening the Biological Weapons Convention (BWC).  We look forward to Mr. Ward leading U.S. efforts in this important area and heading up our team of experts at the BWC Review Conference later this year.</p>
<p>Mr. Ward comes to this position with 30 years’ experience in arms control and nonproliferation with the U.S. Department of State and the former U.S. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency.  He most recently served as the U.S. Ambassador to the Organization for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons in The Hague, Netherlands, with previous assignments as the Director of the Office of Chemical and Biological Weapons Affairs in State’s Bureau of Arms Control, Verification, and Compliance, and the Deputy Negotiator during the 2004-2007 WMD elimination effort in Libya.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Remarks to Mission Algeria</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-remarks-to-mission-algeria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 18:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329690</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Algiers, Algeria</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy Algiers</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR AUBIN:</b>  (In progress) you’ve been here since then as deputy, and we are so thrilled that you could be here today as the Secretary of State.</p>
<p>On February 1st, I met with Secretary Blinken and asked him if he would please come to Algeria.  And when this opportunity came up less than two months later I was thrilled because, of course, it continues – his visit drives forward our policy objectives of working with Algeria on regional stability, economic cooperation, and all of our cultural activities, including and especially English-language learning.</p>
<p>So since I gotten here we’ve had OneBeat Sahara.  How many of you went to OneBeat?  Yeah.  A lot of you.  Very good.  (Applause.)  We’ve had the Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman visit.  We’ve had a joint military dialogue with an interagency group from Washington.  And now you, the absolute kind of cherry on the ice cream sundae.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>So without further ado, Mr. Secretary, I commend this fantastic team to you.  Over the last 18 months, before my arrival, they didn’t have an ambassador, but Gautam Rana as chargé led, drove the bilateral objectives forward.  There was no kind of holding down the fort; they really moved forward.  And I’ve walked into the very best embassy that I’ve ever seen in 32 years in the Foreign Service.  So thank you for being with us today.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, first of all, this is the best first row I’ve ever had – (laughter) – at an embassy event anywhere, so thank you guys for being here.  Actually, I’d really like – maybe I could sit down there and we can just talk.  (Laughter.)  We’ll do that afterward.</p>
<p>Elizabeth, it is so wonderful to have you here and to be able to see you early in your tenure.  We’re grateful for your leadership, and it’s at such a critical time.  So thank you.  And Gautam, thank you for your extraordinary leadership during the 19 or so months you were leading the mission.  We’re grateful for that.  And to each and every one of you, thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>
<p>A few things I want to say before we get to a couple of questions.</p>
<p>You’re at the heart of a place in the world that is vital to our interests – the Middle East and North Africa – and we have in Algeria a partner on so many different security issues, a growing partner I think on economic issues as well, where there’s tremendous opportunity, which I’ll come to it in a minute, and you are the ones who are making that work, growing that, building that every single day, and I’m grateful for that.</p>
<p>As the ambassador said, we’ve had a lot of visits here.  I know that puts a little bit of a strain on the embassy.  I also know that in two, three hours, you’ll be having a wheels-up party.  (Laughter.)  So there’s at least that to look forward to.</p>
<p>But I had a very long and good report from Wendy Sherman when she came back to hear about her visit.  I’m glad I was able to follow up and pursue some of the things that she and the team have been working on.  But we’ve had the fifth strategic dialogue; that is terrific and a strong foundation for the work we’re doing together.  We had the military dialogue as well.  And to the ambassador’s point, a whole number of practical deliverables that will strengthen the relationship and strengthen us going forward.</p>
<p>I am especially excited about the English-language program.  I think as I’ve seen around the world, this is one of the single best things that we export and there’s a real thirst and demand for it.  So I really appreciate that.  And having Algerian Government leaders take part in that I think is really a wonderful thing.  A new research collaboration between the ministry of higher education, the University of Notre Dame, connecting our people at all different levels, not only business to business but university to university, student to student and traveler to traveler, as hopefully that picks up with COVID.</p>
<p>And then there are these growing cultural ties.  I am incredibly upset that I missed out on the OneBeat Sahara music festival.  (Laughter.)  So as I understand it, there were 23 musicians across seven Saharan nations, plus the United States.  Everything from experimental hip-hop to nawa to jazz to electronic.  So if that happens again, please, let me know in advance.  (Laughter.)  And let me simply say a special thanks to all of you who worked on it, the folks in Public Affairs.  Adam Sigelman, is he here somewhere?  All right.  (Applause.)  Job very well done.  Thank you.</p>
<p>And as I mentioned, these growing economic ties that I hope will reach a new moment when we have this international fair in June, for which we are the honored nation.  I think that’s an important moment.  We’ll have some 30-plus U.S. companies there.  In fact, I met with most of them today.  And then a lot of work has already gone into this.  We actually saw the video showing the pavilion-to-be.  Planning for that is a whole-of-embassy effort, and I want to thank you for doing that.  Michele Smith – is Michele here anywhere?</p>
<p><b>PARTICIPANT:</b>  Yes.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  All right.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Thank you for your great efforts.</p>
<p>So much of what you’ve done, though, has been done during a very difficult time for all of us, including folks at this mission, and that is the time of COVID – two-plus difficult years.  I know that some of you have experienced this in a very personal way, not just a professional way, the loss of – sickness of family members, of friends.  One staff member lost here, Hassan Berriche, and I understand that there’s a fountain that was named in his honor.  But I know how deeply felt this is.</p>
<p>But I really want to say to you as well thank you for looking out for each other, thank you for having each other’s backs during this difficult time.  So many different parts of this embassy came together to do what was necessary, the health unit in particular keeping people safe.  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  Human resources keeping people updated, the community liaison office – and is Ikram McRiffey here anywhere?  Right there.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Well done.  Just keeping people connected and having that sense of community, especially in a time like that, is so important, whether it’s trivia nights or now going kayaking in some places.  That makes a real difference, so thank you for doing that.</p>
<p>And then to the locally employed staff association implementing supplemental health insurance for LES, looking out for each other too, I’m grateful to you.  And let me close with this while I’m on the locally employed staff:  As I say everywhere I go, you are the lifeblood of this mission.  We could not do our work without you.  And more than anything else, there’s a powerful connection that you make between us and the country that we’re serving in.</p>
<p>And there are a few folks I just want to mention by name because they’ve been here working side by side for a long, long time, and it’s really extraordinary.  Arezki Benzamouche, are you here?  You are.  Thirty-nine years of service.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Nabila Hales, 38 years of service.  (Applause.)  Abdelkader Hadjel, 37 years of service.  (Applause.)  Abdelkrim Boumazouza, 37 years of service as well.  (Applause.)  So to each of you, thank you, and to every member of the locally employed staff team, thank you for what you’re doing to bring us closer together, to bring our countries closer together, to help us do the vital work of this mission.</p>
<p>But whether you’re local staff, whether you’re a family member, whether you’re an FSO, whether you’re a civil servant, whether you’re here with the State Department, Defense, Foreign Commercial Service, Foreign Agricultural Service, any of the other agencies that we have, mostly I wanted to come by, as I said at the start, with two words:  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Algiers, Algeria</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy Algiers</p>
<p><b>AMBASSADOR AUBIN:</b>  (In progress) you’ve been here since then as deputy, and we are so thrilled that you could be here today as the Secretary of State.</p>
<p>On February 1st, I met with Secretary Blinken and asked him if he would please come to Algeria.  And when this opportunity came up less than two months later I was thrilled because, of course, it continues – his visit drives forward our policy objectives of working with Algeria on regional stability, economic cooperation, and all of our cultural activities, including and especially English-language learning.</p>
<p>So since I gotten here we’ve had OneBeat Sahara.  How many of you went to OneBeat?  Yeah.  A lot of you.  Very good.  (Applause.)  We’ve had the Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman visit.  We’ve had a joint military dialogue with an interagency group from Washington.  And now you, the absolute kind of cherry on the ice cream sundae.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>So without further ado, Mr. Secretary, I commend this fantastic team to you.  Over the last 18 months, before my arrival, they didn’t have an ambassador, but Gautam Rana as chargé led, drove the bilateral objectives forward.  There was no kind of holding down the fort; they really moved forward.  And I’ve walked into the very best embassy that I’ve ever seen in 32 years in the Foreign Service.  So thank you for being with us today.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, first of all, this is the best first row I’ve ever had – (laughter) – at an embassy event anywhere, so thank you guys for being here.  Actually, I’d really like – maybe I could sit down there and we can just talk.  (Laughter.)  We’ll do that afterward.</p>
<p>Elizabeth, it is so wonderful to have you here and to be able to see you early in your tenure.  We’re grateful for your leadership, and it’s at such a critical time.  So thank you.  And Gautam, thank you for your extraordinary leadership during the 19 or so months you were leading the mission.  We’re grateful for that.  And to each and every one of you, thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>
<p>A few things I want to say before we get to a couple of questions.</p>
<p>You’re at the heart of a place in the world that is vital to our interests – the Middle East and North Africa – and we have in Algeria a partner on so many different security issues, a growing partner I think on economic issues as well, where there’s tremendous opportunity, which I’ll come to it in a minute, and you are the ones who are making that work, growing that, building that every single day, and I’m grateful for that.</p>
<p>As the ambassador said, we’ve had a lot of visits here.  I know that puts a little bit of a strain on the embassy.  I also know that in two, three hours, you’ll be having a wheels-up party.  (Laughter.)  So there’s at least that to look forward to.</p>
<p>But I had a very long and good report from Wendy Sherman when she came back to hear about her visit.  I’m glad I was able to follow up and pursue some of the things that she and the team have been working on.  But we’ve had the fifth strategic dialogue; that is terrific and a strong foundation for the work we’re doing together.  We had the military dialogue as well.  And to the ambassador’s point, a whole number of practical deliverables that will strengthen the relationship and strengthen us going forward.</p>
<p>I am especially excited about the English-language program.  I think as I’ve seen around the world, this is one of the single best things that we export and there’s a real thirst and demand for it.  So I really appreciate that.  And having Algerian Government leaders take part in that I think is really a wonderful thing.  A new research collaboration between the ministry of higher education, the University of Notre Dame, connecting our people at all different levels, not only business to business but university to university, student to student and traveler to traveler, as hopefully that picks up with COVID.</p>
<p>And then there are these growing cultural ties.  I am incredibly upset that I missed out on the OneBeat Sahara music festival.  (Laughter.)  So as I understand it, there were 23 musicians across seven Saharan nations, plus the United States.  Everything from experimental hip-hop to nawa to jazz to electronic.  So if that happens again, please, let me know in advance.  (Laughter.)  And let me simply say a special thanks to all of you who worked on it, the folks in Public Affairs.  Adam Sigelman, is he here somewhere?  All right.  (Applause.)  Job very well done.  Thank you.</p>
<p>And as I mentioned, these growing economic ties that I hope will reach a new moment when we have this international fair in June, for which we are the honored nation.  I think that’s an important moment.  We’ll have some 30-plus U.S. companies there.  In fact, I met with most of them today.  And then a lot of work has already gone into this.  We actually saw the video showing the pavilion-to-be.  Planning for that is a whole-of-embassy effort, and I want to thank you for doing that.  Michele Smith – is Michele here anywhere?</p>
<p><b>PARTICIPANT:</b>  Yes.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  All right.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Thank you for your great efforts.</p>
<p>So much of what you’ve done, though, has been done during a very difficult time for all of us, including folks at this mission, and that is the time of COVID – two-plus difficult years.  I know that some of you have experienced this in a very personal way, not just a professional way, the loss of – sickness of family members, of friends.  One staff member lost here, Hassan Berriche, and I understand that there’s a fountain that was named in his honor.  But I know how deeply felt this is.</p>
<p>But I really want to say to you as well thank you for looking out for each other, thank you for having each other’s backs during this difficult time.  So many different parts of this embassy came together to do what was necessary, the health unit in particular keeping people safe.  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  Human resources keeping people updated, the community liaison office – and is Ikram McRiffey here anywhere?  Right there.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Well done.  Just keeping people connected and having that sense of community, especially in a time like that, is so important, whether it’s trivia nights or now going kayaking in some places.  That makes a real difference, so thank you for doing that.</p>
<p>And then to the locally employed staff association implementing supplemental health insurance for LES, looking out for each other too, I’m grateful to you.  And let me close with this while I’m on the locally employed staff:  As I say everywhere I go, you are the lifeblood of this mission.  We could not do our work without you.  And more than anything else, there’s a powerful connection that you make between us and the country that we’re serving in.</p>
<p>And there are a few folks I just want to mention by name because they’ve been here working side by side for a long, long time, and it’s really extraordinary.  Arezki Benzamouche, are you here?  You are.  Thirty-nine years of service.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Nabila Hales, 38 years of service.  (Applause.)  Abdelkader Hadjel, 37 years of service.  (Applause.)  Abdelkrim Boumazouza, 37 years of service as well.  (Applause.)  So to each of you, thank you, and to every member of the locally employed staff team, thank you for what you’re doing to bring us closer together, to bring our countries closer together, to help us do the vital work of this mission.</p>
<p>But whether you’re local staff, whether you’re a family member, whether you’re an FSO, whether you’re a civil servant, whether you’re here with the State Department, Defense, Foreign Commercial Service, Foreign Agricultural Service, any of the other agencies that we have, mostly I wanted to come by, as I said at the start, with two words:  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with North Macedonia Prime Minister Kovachevski</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-north-macedonia-prime-minister-kovachevski/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 17:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with North Macedonia Prime Minister Dimitar Kovachevski.  Secretary Blinken congratulated Prime Minister Kovachevski on his new position and on the formation of the new cabinet.  The Secretary thanked North Macedonia for its unwavering and steadfast support for Ukraine in the face of President Putin’s continued brutal war of aggression.  The Secretary also underscored strong U.S. support for North Macedonia’s expeditious European Union accession.  The Secretary personally thanked the Prime Minister for North Macedonia’s commitment to the NATO Alliance as its newest member, as well as for hosting Afghan evacuees.  The Secretary expressed that the United States looks forward to further close cooperation on a range of regional, security, and defense issues to promote democracy and stability in the region.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with North Macedonia Prime Minister Dimitar Kovachevski.  Secretary Blinken congratulated Prime Minister Kovachevski on his new position and on the formation of the new cabinet.  The Secretary thanked North Macedonia for its unwavering and steadfast support for Ukraine in the face of President Putin’s continued brutal war of aggression.  The Secretary also underscored strong U.S. support for North Macedonia’s expeditious European Union accession.  The Secretary personally thanked the Prime Minister for North Macedonia’s commitment to the NATO Alliance as its newest member, as well as for hosting Afghan evacuees.  The Secretary expressed that the United States looks forward to further close cooperation on a range of regional, security, and defense issues to promote democracy and stability in the region.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States Imposes Sanctions on Iran’s Ballistic Missile-Related Activities</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-imposes-sanctions-on-irans-ballistic-missile-related-activities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 17:34:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is designating five Iranian individuals and entities for sanctions pursuant to Executive Order (E.O.) 13382, which targets proliferators of weapons of mass destruction and their means of delivery for their involvement in Iran’s ballistic missile-related activities. We have taken this action following Iran’s recent missile attack on Erbil, Iraq, as well as missile attacks by Iranian proxies against Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates. These attacks are a reminder that Iran’s development and proliferation of ballistic missiles pose a serious threat to regional and international security.</p>
<p>Iranian procurement agent Mohammad Ali Hosseini and four companies in his network, Iran-based Jestar Sanat Delijan, Sina Composite Delijan Company, Sayehban Sepehr Delijan,<b> </b>and P.B. Sadr Company, have been involved in efforts to procure equipment used to produce ballistic missile propellant and related materials in support of Iran’s missile program.</p>
<p>This international procurement network operated on behalf of the IRGC Research and Self-Sufficiency Jihad Organization (RSSJO) and Parchin Chemical Industries (PCI) – which is designated for sanctions by the United Nations under United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231. The United States will not stand by while Iranian networks support UN-designated entities such as PCI.</p>
<p>Iran’s ballistic missile-related activities continue to destabilize the Middle East region, and the United States will continue to use every tool at our disposal to disrupt them. We will also continue working with others in the region to hold Iran accountable for its actions, including violations of the sovereignty of its neighbors.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0689" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is designating five Iranian individuals and entities for sanctions pursuant to Executive Order (E.O.) 13382, which targets proliferators of weapons of mass destruction and their means of delivery for their involvement in Iran’s ballistic missile-related activities. We have taken this action following Iran’s recent missile attack on Erbil, Iraq, as well as missile attacks by Iranian proxies against Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates. These attacks are a reminder that Iran’s development and proliferation of ballistic missiles pose a serious threat to regional and international security.</p>
<p>Iranian procurement agent Mohammad Ali Hosseini and four companies in his network, Iran-based Jestar Sanat Delijan, Sina Composite Delijan Company, Sayehban Sepehr Delijan,<b> </b>and P.B. Sadr Company, have been involved in efforts to procure equipment used to produce ballistic missile propellant and related materials in support of Iran’s missile program.</p>
<p>This international procurement network operated on behalf of the IRGC Research and Self-Sufficiency Jihad Organization (RSSJO) and Parchin Chemical Industries (PCI) – which is designated for sanctions by the United Nations under United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231. The United States will not stand by while Iranian networks support UN-designated entities such as PCI.</p>
<p>Iran’s ballistic missile-related activities continue to destabilize the Middle East region, and the United States will continue to use every tool at our disposal to disrupt them. We will also continue working with others in the region to hold Iran accountable for its actions, including violations of the sovereignty of its neighbors.</p>
<p>For more information on today’s action, please see the Department of the Treasury’s <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0689" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">press release.</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement from the U.S.-Czech Republic Strategic Dialogue</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-from-the-u-s-czech-republic-strategic-dialogue/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 14:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329572</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>Following is the text of a joint statement by the Governments of the United States of America and of the Czech Republic</em>.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>The Governments of the Czech Republic and the United States renewed the U.S.-Czech Republic Strategic Dialogue in Prague on March 30, 2022, with delegations led by Czech Deputy Foreign Minister Martin Povejsil and U.S. Assistant Secretary of State for European and Eurasian Affairs Karen Donfried.  In conjunction with the Strategic Dialogue, Assistant Secretary Donfried also met with Foreign Minister Jan Lipavsky.</p>
<p>The United States and the Czech Republic have a historic friendship based on common democratic values and an appreciation of our shared responsibility to uphold the rules-based international order in cooperation with our Allies and partners.  This Strategic Dialogue comes at a critical time.  It demonstrates the strength and importance of the bilateral relationship as the United States and the Czech Republic focus on the security challenges on the Eastern Flank of NATO due to the Russian Federation’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine.  We underline our commitment to protect and defend every inch of NATO territory.  The Czech Republic has renewed its commitment to increase its defense spending to two percent of GDP.  A faster pace of modernization of the Czech armed forces is a priority, gaining new capabilities in cooperation with the United States and other Allies.</p>
<p>We stand strong and united in support of the people of Ukraine and the Ukrainian government against Russia’s unprovoked war, which is causing immense human suffering and destruction of civilian infrastructure.  We call on Russia to cease its military offensive and completely withdraw its armed forces from the territories of Ukraine, Moldova, and Georgia and to respect their sovereignty and internationally recognized borders.<strong>  </strong>Beijing’s position on Russia’s war also remains under our close scrutiny.  The United States and the Czech Republic agree that the international community must deepen Russia’s political and economic isolation and apply tougher sanctions against enablers of Russia’s aggression.  The discussion of Ukraine’s post-war recovery must begin now.  We must endeavor to provide Ukraine the political and practical assistance to support and realize its sovereign choice of full integration with Europe and the world’s democracies.</p>
<p>The United States and the Czech Republic emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Czech partnership in addressing common threats and challenges, including in the area of cyber security and resilience to hybrid threats.  The Strategic Dialogue focused on reaffirming the strong, steady, and deepening bilateral cooperation between the United States and the Czech Republic and our joint commitment to enhance cooperation on a broad range of topics, including closer cooperation with partners in the Indo-Pacific region.  We also affirm our commitment to deepen support and cooperation with democratic partners in the region and around the world, such as Taiwan.</p>
<p>We agree current geopolitical developments make enhancing energy security more urgent than ever.  The United States and the Czech Republic are taking steps to reduce reliance on Russian oil, natural gas, and nuclear fuel by diversifying sources of energy, expanding our already strong cooperation on nuclear power, and reducing consumption in line with our shared climate goals.</p>
<p>The United States and the Czech Republic consulted on the importance of strengthening Transatlantic relations, including cooperation between the United States and the EU, during the Czech Republic’s presidency of the Council of the European Union in the second half of 2022.  Both sides expressed a strong interest in deepening the bilateral strategic partnership in the year ahead and through future strategic dialogues.  The parties plan to hold the next annual meeting in Washington in 2023.</p>
<p><em>End Text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>Following is the text of a joint statement by the Governments of the United States of America and of the Czech Republic</em>.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>The Governments of the Czech Republic and the United States renewed the U.S.-Czech Republic Strategic Dialogue in Prague on March 30, 2022, with delegations led by Czech Deputy Foreign Minister Martin Povejsil and U.S. Assistant Secretary of State for European and Eurasian Affairs Karen Donfried.  In conjunction with the Strategic Dialogue, Assistant Secretary Donfried also met with Foreign Minister Jan Lipavsky.</p>
<p>The United States and the Czech Republic have a historic friendship based on common democratic values and an appreciation of our shared responsibility to uphold the rules-based international order in cooperation with our Allies and partners.  This Strategic Dialogue comes at a critical time.  It demonstrates the strength and importance of the bilateral relationship as the United States and the Czech Republic focus on the security challenges on the Eastern Flank of NATO due to the Russian Federation’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine.  We underline our commitment to protect and defend every inch of NATO territory.  The Czech Republic has renewed its commitment to increase its defense spending to two percent of GDP.  A faster pace of modernization of the Czech armed forces is a priority, gaining new capabilities in cooperation with the United States and other Allies.</p>
<p>We stand strong and united in support of the people of Ukraine and the Ukrainian government against Russia’s unprovoked war, which is causing immense human suffering and destruction of civilian infrastructure.  We call on Russia to cease its military offensive and completely withdraw its armed forces from the territories of Ukraine, Moldova, and Georgia and to respect their sovereignty and internationally recognized borders.<strong>  </strong>Beijing’s position on Russia’s war also remains under our close scrutiny.  The United States and the Czech Republic agree that the international community must deepen Russia’s political and economic isolation and apply tougher sanctions against enablers of Russia’s aggression.  The discussion of Ukraine’s post-war recovery must begin now.  We must endeavor to provide Ukraine the political and practical assistance to support and realize its sovereign choice of full integration with Europe and the world’s democracies.</p>
<p>The United States and the Czech Republic emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Czech partnership in addressing common threats and challenges, including in the area of cyber security and resilience to hybrid threats.  The Strategic Dialogue focused on reaffirming the strong, steady, and deepening bilateral cooperation between the United States and the Czech Republic and our joint commitment to enhance cooperation on a broad range of topics, including closer cooperation with partners in the Indo-Pacific region.  We also affirm our commitment to deepen support and cooperation with democratic partners in the region and around the world, such as Taiwan.</p>
<p>We agree current geopolitical developments make enhancing energy security more urgent than ever.  The United States and the Czech Republic are taking steps to reduce reliance on Russian oil, natural gas, and nuclear fuel by diversifying sources of energy, expanding our already strong cooperation on nuclear power, and reducing consumption in line with our shared climate goals.</p>
<p>The United States and the Czech Republic consulted on the importance of strengthening Transatlantic relations, including cooperation between the United States and the EU, during the Czech Republic’s presidency of the Council of the European Union in the second half of 2022.  Both sides expressed a strong interest in deepening the bilateral strategic partnership in the year ahead and through future strategic dialogues.  The parties plan to hold the next annual meeting in Washington in 2023.</p>
<p><em>End Text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at Algiers International Trade Fair Launch Event with U.S. Companies</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-algiers-international-trade-fair-launch-event-with-u-s-companies/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 13:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329478</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Algiers, Algeria</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy Algiers</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s wonderful to be here, wonderful to be back – to be back in this beautiful embassy, and Nawal, thank you so much for your introduction, but also for your leadership at the Women in Business Committee in the American Chamber of Commerce in Algeria.  Grateful for that.</p>
<p><i>Assalamu alaikum</i>, everybody.  This is a dynamic time for business in Algeria.  We’re seeing that in numbers.  In 2020, the two-way trade between the United States and Algeria totaled $1.2 billion.  In 2021, even with COVID, it more than doubled to $2.6 billion.  And in just the month of January this year alone, two-way trade grows to $331 million just for that month.  So we’re on track to continue to see a significant increase.</p>
<p>We see it as well in the more welcoming business environment that President Tebboune is planning to create through his year of the economy in Algeria.  I’ll have a chance to meet with the president a little bit later today, and one of the things I expect to discuss is the strong collaboration that’s happening across Algerian and American businesses, and across a range of sectors, including renewable energy, technology, and others.  And we’ll talk about ways to draw even more American foreign direct investment here including through improvements in Algeria’s investment climate.  The Algiers International Fair this June, with the U.S. as the country of honor, is going to be an opportunity to deepen all of these efforts.</p>
<p>The Algerian-United States relationship would not be as strong and getting stronger without the groundwork that all of you and your companies have been laying over the years.  Some have been operating here for decades, others started working in Algeria more recently, but together, you’re supporting thousands of Algerian and American jobs and families and communities along with them.  You’re investing in the local workforce, sharing knowledge, best practices between Algerian and American businesses, and building sustainable partnerships that are to the benefit of both of our countries.</p>
<p>So for that, I want to say to everyone, <i>sahha</i>, thank you, and what I want to do now is turn it over to a brief video about the U.S. Pavilion.  So over to the video.</p>
<p>(A video was played.)</p>
<p>Thank you all.  I’m really looking forward to seeing you there.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Algiers, Algeria</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy Algiers</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s wonderful to be here, wonderful to be back – to be back in this beautiful embassy, and Nawal, thank you so much for your introduction, but also for your leadership at the Women in Business Committee in the American Chamber of Commerce in Algeria.  Grateful for that.</p>
<p><i>Assalamu alaikum</i>, everybody.  This is a dynamic time for business in Algeria.  We’re seeing that in numbers.  In 2020, the two-way trade between the United States and Algeria totaled $1.2 billion.  In 2021, even with COVID, it more than doubled to $2.6 billion.  And in just the month of January this year alone, two-way trade grows to $331 million just for that month.  So we’re on track to continue to see a significant increase.</p>
<p>We see it as well in the more welcoming business environment that President Tebboune is planning to create through his year of the economy in Algeria.  I’ll have a chance to meet with the president a little bit later today, and one of the things I expect to discuss is the strong collaboration that’s happening across Algerian and American businesses, and across a range of sectors, including renewable energy, technology, and others.  And we’ll talk about ways to draw even more American foreign direct investment here including through improvements in Algeria’s investment climate.  The Algiers International Fair this June, with the U.S. as the country of honor, is going to be an opportunity to deepen all of these efforts.</p>
<p>The Algerian-United States relationship would not be as strong and getting stronger without the groundwork that all of you and your companies have been laying over the years.  Some have been operating here for decades, others started working in Algeria more recently, but together, you’re supporting thousands of Algerian and American jobs and families and communities along with them.  You’re investing in the local workforce, sharing knowledge, best practices between Algerian and American businesses, and building sustainable partnerships that are to the benefit of both of our countries.</p>
<p>So for that, I want to say to everyone, <i>sahha</i>, thank you, and what I want to do now is turn it over to a brief video about the U.S. Pavilion.  So over to the video.</p>
<p>(A video was played.)</p>
<p>Thank you all.  I’m really looking forward to seeing you there.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Commitments to Regional Security and Prosperity Underscore Secretary Blinken’s Travel to Algeria</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/commitments-to-regional-security-and-prosperity-underscore-secretary-blinkens-travel-to-algeria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 11:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329441</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On March 30, Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Algeria for meetings with President Abdelmadjid Tebboune and Foreign Minister Ramtane Lamamra to discuss regional security and stability, economic cooperation, and advancing human rights and fundamental freedoms.  The Secretary will promote America’s role as the Country of Honor at the Algiers International Trade Fair in June, the largest trade show of its kind in Africa.  He will meet with U.S. business representatives in Algeria to discuss deepening economic ties and promoting U.S.-Algeria trade and investment.</p>
<p><b>A DEEP AND LASTING RELATIONSHIP</b></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States and Algeria share a long history – from the 1795 Treaty of Peace and Amity to hosting negotiations to release American hostages from Tehran in 1981 – and our bilateral relationship continues to flourish.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Our security and counterterrorism cooperation remains a cornerstone of our bilateral relationship. We are also encouraged by the deepening economic and cultural ties between the United States and Algeria.  More and more U.S. companies are seeking investment in Algeria, and those already here are creating jobs across a wide range of sectors.  The fact that we are the country of honor at this year’s Algiers International Fair – the largest trade fair of its kind in Africa – demonstrates Algeria’s interest in American products and technology.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>BILATERAL AND REGIONAL POLITICAL ISSUES</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Earlier this month, Deputy Secretary Wendy Sherman and Foreign Minister Lamamra met in Algiers to express strong support for the efforts of Personal Envoy of the UN Secretary General Staffan de Mistura’s leadership in resuming the UN-led political process to advance a durable and dignified resolution to the conflict in Western Sahara that will create a peaceful and prosperous future for the people of Western Sahara and the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>We also agreed on the importance of regional stability for the entire Sahel and the need to counter the destabilizing presence of terrorist groups.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Our relationship is multifaceted.  We work closely with Algeria on counterterrorism and regional security, so that we can learn from one another and strengthen our respective security capabilities. Algeria hosted a Joint Military Dialogue March 14-15, during which we further discussed our commitment to regional security.</li>
<li>The United States and Algeria regularly discuss the importance of protecting and advancing human rights, including freedoms of expression and belief and the important role of independent media and civil society. Human rights are a central pillar of U.S. foreign policy.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>CULTURAL TIES AND EXCHANGES</b></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States shares strong cultural and economic relations with Algeria, which continue to improve at both the government-to-government and people-to-people levels. The OneBeat program in February and March featured 23 musicians from the United States, Algeria, and all of Algeria’s neighbors who created original music together in a three-week musical residency capped by two well-attended public concerts.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>There is no better indicator of the growing partnership between our two countries than our growing cultural ties. Algeria’s continued interest in English-language training and entrepreneurship are key areas where we are already working together.  We are pleased to have launched earlier this month two new programs that will strengthen U.S.-Algerian cooperation.  The State Department initiated the Link Project in Algeria to help 120 Algerian government officials improve their professional English language skills.  This will enable them to participate in international conferences and exchanges, communicate with international counterparts, and engage with English-language reports and other content.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The State Department is also working with the University of Notre Dame in Indiana to implement a three-year project to create a “research hub” to link Algerian research institutions in five key fields – artificial intelligence, applied mathematics, climate change and renewable energies, health and pharmaceutical sciences, and agriculture – with their American counterparts to facilitate the exchange of ideas and people. This project will build the research capacity of Algerian universities and create key linkages between Algerian researchers and the private sector.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>WESTERN SAHARA</b></p>
<ul>
<li>We strongly support the efforts of Staffan de Mistura, the Personal Envoy of the Secretary-General for Western Sahara.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>We are fully engaged diplomatically, in support of the UN and together with our international partners, to reinforce a credible political process leading to an enduring and dignified resolution.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>SAHEL</b></p>
<ul>
<li>We are both very concerned about the destabilizing presence of terrorist groups in the Sahel, and we both want security and prosperity in the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Algeria has played a key role in facilitating this stability through its mediation of the 2015 Algiers Peace Accord and continues to be a regional leader promoting resolution to ongoing conflicts.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>COVID-19 RESPONSE</b></p>
<ul>
<li>We have consulted regularly with the Ministry of Health about COVID-19 risks, and we supplied Algeria with over 600,000 doses of the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine last year through COVAX.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>CLIMATE CHANGE</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Both Algeria and the United States understand the critical importance of working together to tackle climate change.</li>
</ul>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On March 30, Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Algeria for meetings with President Abdelmadjid Tebboune and Foreign Minister Ramtane Lamamra to discuss regional security and stability, economic cooperation, and advancing human rights and fundamental freedoms.  The Secretary will promote America’s role as the Country of Honor at the Algiers International Trade Fair in June, the largest trade show of its kind in Africa.  He will meet with U.S. business representatives in Algeria to discuss deepening economic ties and promoting U.S.-Algeria trade and investment.</p>
<p><b>A DEEP AND LASTING RELATIONSHIP</b></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States and Algeria share a long history – from the 1795 Treaty of Peace and Amity to hosting negotiations to release American hostages from Tehran in 1981 – and our bilateral relationship continues to flourish.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Our security and counterterrorism cooperation remains a cornerstone of our bilateral relationship. We are also encouraged by the deepening economic and cultural ties between the United States and Algeria.  More and more U.S. companies are seeking investment in Algeria, and those already here are creating jobs across a wide range of sectors.  The fact that we are the country of honor at this year’s Algiers International Fair – the largest trade fair of its kind in Africa – demonstrates Algeria’s interest in American products and technology.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>BILATERAL AND REGIONAL POLITICAL ISSUES</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Earlier this month, Deputy Secretary Wendy Sherman and Foreign Minister Lamamra met in Algiers to express strong support for the efforts of Personal Envoy of the UN Secretary General Staffan de Mistura’s leadership in resuming the UN-led political process to advance a durable and dignified resolution to the conflict in Western Sahara that will create a peaceful and prosperous future for the people of Western Sahara and the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>We also agreed on the importance of regional stability for the entire Sahel and the need to counter the destabilizing presence of terrorist groups.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Our relationship is multifaceted.  We work closely with Algeria on counterterrorism and regional security, so that we can learn from one another and strengthen our respective security capabilities. Algeria hosted a Joint Military Dialogue March 14-15, during which we further discussed our commitment to regional security.</li>
<li>The United States and Algeria regularly discuss the importance of protecting and advancing human rights, including freedoms of expression and belief and the important role of independent media and civil society. Human rights are a central pillar of U.S. foreign policy.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>CULTURAL TIES AND EXCHANGES</b></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States shares strong cultural and economic relations with Algeria, which continue to improve at both the government-to-government and people-to-people levels. The OneBeat program in February and March featured 23 musicians from the United States, Algeria, and all of Algeria’s neighbors who created original music together in a three-week musical residency capped by two well-attended public concerts.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>There is no better indicator of the growing partnership between our two countries than our growing cultural ties. Algeria’s continued interest in English-language training and entrepreneurship are key areas where we are already working together.  We are pleased to have launched earlier this month two new programs that will strengthen U.S.-Algerian cooperation.  The State Department initiated the Link Project in Algeria to help 120 Algerian government officials improve their professional English language skills.  This will enable them to participate in international conferences and exchanges, communicate with international counterparts, and engage with English-language reports and other content.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The State Department is also working with the University of Notre Dame in Indiana to implement a three-year project to create a “research hub” to link Algerian research institutions in five key fields – artificial intelligence, applied mathematics, climate change and renewable energies, health and pharmaceutical sciences, and agriculture – with their American counterparts to facilitate the exchange of ideas and people. This project will build the research capacity of Algerian universities and create key linkages between Algerian researchers and the private sector.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>WESTERN SAHARA</b></p>
<ul>
<li>We strongly support the efforts of Staffan de Mistura, the Personal Envoy of the Secretary-General for Western Sahara.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>We are fully engaged diplomatically, in support of the UN and together with our international partners, to reinforce a credible political process leading to an enduring and dignified resolution.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>SAHEL</b></p>
<ul>
<li>We are both very concerned about the destabilizing presence of terrorist groups in the Sahel, and we both want security and prosperity in the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Algeria has played a key role in facilitating this stability through its mediation of the 2015 Algiers Peace Accord and continues to be a regional leader promoting resolution to ongoing conflicts.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>COVID-19 RESPONSE</b></p>
<ul>
<li>We have consulted regularly with the Ministry of Health about COVID-19 risks, and we supplied Algeria with over 600,000 doses of the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine last year through COVAX.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>CLIMATE CHANGE</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Both Algeria and the United States understand the critical importance of working together to tackle climate change.</li>
</ul>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
