<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 02:09:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>United States Welcomes Announcement of Israel and Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan Agreements on Water and West Bank Trade</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-welcomes-announcement-of-israel-and-hashemite-kingdom-of-jordan-agreements-on-water-and-west-bank-trade/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 02:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258055</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Open sans',serif; color: #201f1e;">The United States welcomes the announcement that Israel and the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan agreed to conclude trade agreements that strengthen civilian cooperation between the two countries and will support the Palestinian people by allowing increased trade between Jordan and the West Bank. These agreements will improve Jordan&#8217;s access to fresh water by an additional 50 million cubic meters this year and allow Jordan’s exports to the West Bank to increase from $160 million a year ago to around $700 million.  It is these kinds of tangible steps that increase prosperity for all and advance regional stability. We congratulate His Majesty King Abdullah II and Foreign Minister Safadi of Jordan and Prime Minister Bennett and Foreign Minister Lapid of Israel for concluding these deals.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Open sans',serif; color: #201f1e;">The United States welcomes the announcement that Israel and the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan agreed to conclude trade agreements that strengthen civilian cooperation between the two countries and will support the Palestinian people by allowing increased trade between Jordan and the West Bank. These agreements will improve Jordan&#8217;s access to fresh water by an additional 50 million cubic meters this year and allow Jordan’s exports to the West Bank to increase from $160 million a year ago to around $700 million.  It is these kinds of tangible steps that increase prosperity for all and advance regional stability. We congratulate His Majesty King Abdullah II and Foreign Minister Safadi of Jordan and Prime Minister Bennett and Foreign Minister Lapid of Israel for concluding these deals.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Public Schedule &#8211; July 9, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/public-schedule-july-9-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>                                    ***THE DAILY PUBLIC SCHEDULE IS SUBJECT TO CHANGE***</strong></p>
<p><strong><u>SECRETARY ANTONY J. BLINKEN</u></strong></p>
<p><strong>2:00 p.m.</strong> Secretary Blinken meets virtually with the AFL-CIO Executive Council, from the Department of State.<br />
<strong>(CLOSED PRESS COVERAGE)</strong></p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY WENDY R. SHERMAN</u></strong><br />
Deputy Secretary Sherman has no public appointments.<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY FOR MANAGEMENT AND RESOURCES BRIAN P. MCKEON<br />
</u></strong><strong>10:00 a.m.</strong> Deputy Secretary McKeon delivers remarks at the virtual EU Commission’s High-Level Forum on Resettlement and Refugee Protection, from the Department of State.<br />
<strong>(MEDIA DETERMINED BY HOST)<br />
</strong><em>This event will be live streamed at </em><a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwebcast.ec.europa.eu%2Fhigh-level-resettlement-forum&amp;data=04%7C01%7CFosterBL%40state.gov%7Cb4ab005eed42493697f908d942488502%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637613701493791065%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&amp;sdata=WwSJRdoFR%2BA7Md9szJ7IZyEIetVshNLeeJfPC88sXHw%3D&amp;reserved=0"><em>https://webcast.ec.europa.eu/high-level-resettlement-forum</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<p><strong><u>UNDER SECRETARY FOR POLITICAL AFFAIRS VICTORIA J. NULAND<br />
</u></strong>Under Secretary attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>BRIEFING SCHEDULE<br />
</u></strong><strong>2:00 p.m. </strong>Principal Deputy Spokesperson Jalina Porter holds a telephonic press briefing.<br />
<strong>(OPEN PRESS COVERAGE)</strong></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>                                    ***THE DAILY PUBLIC SCHEDULE IS SUBJECT TO CHANGE***</strong></p>
<p><strong><u>SECRETARY ANTONY J. BLINKEN</u></strong></p>
<p><strong>2:00 p.m.</strong> Secretary Blinken meets virtually with the AFL-CIO Executive Council, from the Department of State.<br />
<strong>(CLOSED PRESS COVERAGE)</strong></p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY WENDY R. SHERMAN</u></strong><br />
Deputy Secretary Sherman has no public appointments.<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY FOR MANAGEMENT AND RESOURCES BRIAN P. MCKEON<br />
</u></strong><strong>10:00 a.m.</strong> Deputy Secretary McKeon delivers remarks at the virtual EU Commission’s High-Level Forum on Resettlement and Refugee Protection, from the Department of State.<br />
<strong>(MEDIA DETERMINED BY HOST)<br />
</strong><em>This event will be live streamed at </em><a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwebcast.ec.europa.eu%2Fhigh-level-resettlement-forum&amp;data=04%7C01%7CFosterBL%40state.gov%7Cb4ab005eed42493697f908d942488502%7C66cf50745afe48d1a691a12b2121f44b%7C0%7C0%7C637613701493791065%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&amp;sdata=WwSJRdoFR%2BA7Md9szJ7IZyEIetVshNLeeJfPC88sXHw%3D&amp;reserved=0"><em>https://webcast.ec.europa.eu/high-level-resettlement-forum</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<p><strong><u>UNDER SECRETARY FOR POLITICAL AFFAIRS VICTORIA J. NULAND<br />
</u></strong>Under Secretary attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>BRIEFING SCHEDULE<br />
</u></strong><strong>2:00 p.m. </strong>Principal Deputy Spokesperson Jalina Porter holds a telephonic press briefing.<br />
<strong>(OPEN PRESS COVERAGE)</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate Kerry&#8217;s Travel to Moscow, Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-presidential-envoy-for-climate-kerrys-travel-to-moscow-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258046</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Open sans',serif; color: #222222;">Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Moscow, Russia, from July 12 to July 15, 2021, to meet with Russian government officials to discuss various means of enhancing global climate ambition. </span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Open sans',serif; color: #222222;">Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Moscow, Russia, from July 12 to July 15, 2021, to meet with Russian government officials to discuss various means of enhancing global climate ambition. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On the 6th Anniversary of the 709 Crackdown in China</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/on-the-6th-anniversary-of-the-709-crackdown-in-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 23:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258039</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>This July 9, we honor the more than 300 lawyers and human rights defenders who were unjustly detained, interrogated, and imprisoned by authorities in the People’s Republic of China (PRC) on July 9, 2015, in what is known as the “709 crackdown.” The government of China targeted these individuals in a campaign to intimidate and silence those who sought to work within the PRC’s legal system to help it live up to its human rights obligations and commitments and to effect positive change in their society.</p>
<p>Six years later, the government continues to hold many of those initially arrested, such as Xu Zhiyong and Ding Jiaxi, in pre-trial detention. Chinese authorities disbarred, detained, and prosecuted others, including lawyers Li Yuhan and Yu Wensheng, when they came forward to represent these brave human rights defenders. We call on the PRC to release those who have been detained or imprisoned in connection with the 709 crackdown, to ensure their family members are free of harassment, and to reinstate the lawyers who were disbarred.</p>
<p>The PRC’s targeting of lawyers and activists who are simply trying to pursue legal redress for their fellow citizens undermines social stability and the rule of law. The United States will always support brave individuals who seek to build a more just, stable, and prosperous society.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>This July 9, we honor the more than 300 lawyers and human rights defenders who were unjustly detained, interrogated, and imprisoned by authorities in the People’s Republic of China (PRC) on July 9, 2015, in what is known as the “709 crackdown.” The government of China targeted these individuals in a campaign to intimidate and silence those who sought to work within the PRC’s legal system to help it live up to its human rights obligations and commitments and to effect positive change in their society.</p>
<p>Six years later, the government continues to hold many of those initially arrested, such as Xu Zhiyong and Ding Jiaxi, in pre-trial detention. Chinese authorities disbarred, detained, and prosecuted others, including lawyers Li Yuhan and Yu Wensheng, when they came forward to represent these brave human rights defenders. We call on the PRC to release those who have been detained or imprisoned in connection with the 709 crackdown, to ensure their family members are free of harassment, and to reinstate the lawyers who were disbarred.</p>
<p>The PRC’s targeting of lawyers and activists who are simply trying to pursue legal redress for their fellow citizens undermines social stability and the rule of law. The United States will always support brave individuals who seek to build a more just, stable, and prosperous society.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kyrgyz Republic’s New Law Directed at NGOs</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/kyrgyz-republics-new-law-directed-at-ngos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 23:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=258035</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Open sans',serif; color: #222222;">The United States expresses its deep concern with the Kyrgyz Republic’s recent approval of a law imposing onerous financial and programmatic reporting requirements on non-governmental organizations (NGOs). The new requirements threaten the ability of NGOs to improve the lives of citizens and impede the vital efforts of NGOs to assist the government in its response to the COVID-19 pandemic. Similar laws have been misused in other countries to target organizations critical of the government and political figures, infringing upon freedom of expression. We urge the nation’s leadership to reconsider the law and its impact on civil society, which has been a cornerstone of Kyrgyz democracy. The Kyrgyz Republic’s strong tradition of pluralism and freedom of association, which it has established since its independence nearly 30 years ago, should be protected and encouraged.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Open sans',serif; color: #222222;">The United States expresses its deep concern with the Kyrgyz Republic’s recent approval of a law imposing onerous financial and programmatic reporting requirements on non-governmental organizations (NGOs). The new requirements threaten the ability of NGOs to improve the lives of citizens and impede the vital efforts of NGOs to assist the government in its response to the COVID-19 pandemic. Similar laws have been misused in other countries to target organizations critical of the government and political figures, infringing upon freedom of expression. We urge the nation’s leadership to reconsider the law and its impact on civil society, which has been a cornerstone of Kyrgyz democracy. The Kyrgyz Republic’s strong tradition of pluralism and freedom of association, which it has established since its independence nearly 30 years ago, should be protected and encouraged.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; July 8, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-july-8-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 22:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=258028</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>2:43 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Good afternoon.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m sorry we’re starting a couple minutes late, but we have a good excuse today, at least.</p>
<p>Just a quick note at the top, and that’s about recent v<a id="post-258028-VACCINES"></a>accine deliveries. The Biden administration continues to deliver on its promise that the United States will be an arsenal of vaccines for the world. By Saturday, we anticipate that we will have shipped approximately nine million doses to Guatemala, Uruguay, Paraguay, Bolivia, Afghanistan, and Vietnam. In the coming weeks, we will keep you updated as additional doses are shipped and the United States Government continues to lead in the fight against COVID-19 both at home and around the world.</p>
<p>So with that, happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. I just want to start before I get – we get any questions, just a propos of nothing in particular, just again to say that the State Department press corps appreciates the fact that you are getting up every day – or almost every day – and answering our questions, whether we like the answers or not. So &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Once again, I’m happy to conclude the briefing there, if no further questions. (Laughter.) So &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, no, you’re not going to be able to get away with that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I appreciate that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So you will have seen the President’s remarks on A<a id="post-258028-AFGHANISTAN"></a>fghanistan just now. The – earlier this week I asked you if you recalled the letter that Sirik Matak had sent to John Gunther Dean, who was the ambassador to Cambodia in 1975. And it doesn’t seem to have gotten that much attention, as opposed to other things. So I’m just going to – it’s eight sentences, so I’m just going to read it:</p>
<p>“Dear Excellency and friend, I thank you sincerely for your letter and your offer to transport me towards freedom. I cannot, alas, leave in such cowardly fashion. As for you and in particular for your great country, I never believed for a moment that you would have this sentiment of abandoning a people which has chosen liberty. You have refused us your protection, and we can do nothing about it. You leave, and my wish is that you and your country will find happiness under the sky. But mark it well, that if I shall die here on this spot and in my country that I love, it is too bad, because we are all born and must die one day. I have committed this mistake of believing in you, the Americans. Regards, Sirik Matak.”</p>
<p>Of course, he was killed by the Khmer Rouge several days later.</p>
<p>Given the President’s comments and intention to withdraw, does this have any impact on you guys at all?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, I would reiterate what it is you just heard moments ago from President Biden, and it is something that you have heard over and over again since the President announced our plans just a couple months ago, and that is the fact that U.S. support for the Afghan people, for the Afghan Government, will endure. And you heard the President very clearly make that point earlier today. He – he –</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You know what? That’s exactly what the American president said in – what President Nixon said, what President Ford said, and now, why should anyone believe you?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Because, Matt, President Biden is a man of his word. This administration is committed to the people of Afghanistan. We – the hard-won gains of the Afghan people over the past 20 years, the amount of suffering that the Afghan people have endured over the past 40 years, this – these are gains that we are going to do everything we can to help preserve. And that is precisely why you heard the President say today that he has asked his team – and that includes, of course, Secretary Blinken; it includes, of course, Ambassador Khalilzad; it includes, of course, our counterparts throughout the government – to work concertedly, diplomatically with the parties, with the international community, with Afghanistan’s neighbors, to bring about a just and durable resolution that includes a comprehensive ceasefire.</p>
<p>So Matt, in all of this, we are not leaving the Afghan people. We are not abandoning the Afghan people. Our goal in all of this is to support the diplomacy that will, we hope and key elements, key Afghan elements hope will bring about a just and durable peace. We hope to help set the conditions so that Afghans can live in their country in safety and security without American military forces there on the ground.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So – okay, all right. So he – so who is it that’s in charge specifically? You mentioned someone was in charge of the – for the SIV applicants, the people who are wanting to get out. Who is that exactly? And then there doesn’t seem to be any definitive resolution as to where people – where those people might be relocated while they await their – the adjudication of their visas. Is there any answer on that at all?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So as you heard from the President, he has asked Secretary Blinken, he has asked Ambassador Khalilzad to hypercharge our diplomacy. That’s something we’ve been engaged in since the earliest days of this administration. Brian McKeon, the Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources, is playing a lead role when it comes to the SIV process. He is working closely not only with Secretary Blinken but with the White House as well.</p>
<p>When it comes to the SIV program, of course this has been a priority of ours even before this military withdrawal began. You heard the President say today that we have been – we have identified locations outside of the continental United States and in third countries. The State Department has been engaged with various countries, a number of countries, diplomatically on this issue. Wouldn’t want to detail beyond that at this point. But you heard the President say today that relocation will begin later this month. So as soon as have more details to provide we certainly will.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So this just – they – so Brian is the point person here?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> That’s right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Abbie?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You said that you’ve identified and engaged diplomatically with third countries. Have you received a commitment from specific countries to take in the SIVs as they finish their application?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have had conversations with a number of countries. Many of those conversations have been very constructive and positive, but I wouldn’t want to detail potential locations at this time.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you expand upon what the President said regarding asking Congress to change the law to allow for them to come to U.S. territories?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So as you know, the SIV program – its requirements are statutorily mandated. As I recall, there are about 12 steps that applicants have to go through. So for the State Department, for the Department of Homeland Security, which also has a role in this, we have done what we can to accelerate the processing time through resources, putting more people on this task, more resources at the chief of mission level as well. And by doing so, we’ve been able to shave significant time off the average processing it takes for each applicant. But there are certain things we can’t do, because again the SIV process is written into statute.</p>
<p>And so for us to fundamentally change that process, it would require cooperation from Congress. Of course, we’ve been heartened that Congress also sees this as a priority; Congress attaches a great deal of importance to this program, as do we. And so we have been really gratified by the cooperation and the interest we’ve seen from Congress on this.</p>
<p>Simon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The President’s repeatedly been calling for the Afghans to be united and for there to be unity among the Afghan Government. Is the U.S. pressing Ghani specifically to form a national unity government?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have always said that this process has to be Afghan-led and Afghan-owned. Whatever endures will be – will have to be, in our view, Afghan-led and Afghan-owned, because only if it is such will it have support of the Afghan people, will it have legitimacy in the eyes of the Afghan people, will it have legitimacy in the eyes of much of the international community. And so that is why we have been engaged in this diplomacy, but we have supported the diplomacy. We’re not a direct party to the intra-Afghan talks. Of course, there was a separate agreement between the United States and the Taliban. But when it comes to the intra-Afghan talks, these are talks between and among the Afghans themselves.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you think that the current administration has that, the qualities you’ve described?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m sorry. Has the what?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Has the – is Afghan-led and Afghan-owned? The current Afghan Government – does it meet the requirements that you’re describing?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Certainly the current Afghan Government is. What comes next, any changes that may come in the coming months or years – those will similarly need to be Afghan-led and Afghan-owned.</p>
<p>Sure, yeah. Christina.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The President just said that about 2,500 of the SIV applicants have gotten their visa but chosen not to come to the U.S. He said they’ve chosen to stay in Afghanistan. How do you know that? And do you know that? Do you know it’s a matter of choice, or is it a matter of not being able to afford a plane ticket, not being able to get to the airport, not to be able to securely leave the country because of fear of – like how are you making that judgment that they are choosing to stay in the country?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, as I said before, the SIV program – there are some 12 steps involved in the program. And some of those steps do entail direct contact with applicants. And so throughout the process, consular officers, State Department officials, do have an opportunity to hear directly from applicants. In fact, it’s required that we are in receipt of a good deal of information from the applicants. So I presume that’s where that comes from.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So you’re (inaudible) of those are a deliberate choice to remain in Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Say that again?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I said so you’re confident that the 2,500 – all of those are making a deliberate choice to stay in Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have no reason to doubt that. As the President said however, that for the group that we have identified, if they so desire to come to the United States, we will see to it that they will have an opportunity to come here upon the completion of their SIV processing.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And with the transports, with the – if it comes to an evacuation or however we’re phrasing that, are you confident that given the military withdrawal, the closing of Bagram, that you will have enough security and resources to be able to carry out the transportation of those people once – if and when they get their visas and if and when there is a third country cleared? Are you worried that there could be a security situation on the ground?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So as we have said, the – we have identified a group of SIV applicants who have served in roles, including interpreters and translators. They and their families will have the option to be relocated to a location outside of Afghanistan before we complete our military drawdown. And so as you heard from the President today, the military drawdown will be complete by the end of August, so we are talking about this process in terms of weeks rather than months and months.</p>
<p>Kylie, yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just move back on that? I’m just curious about you guys continually say this will happen before the drawdown in September, but then you guys also say that approximately 9,000 of these 18,000 are in more progressed positions. So I’m just wondering, does that mean that you’re going to conclude only the 9,000 by September, or does it mean you’re going to conclude the total 18,000 that are on this list?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So we haven’t attached a number to it yet. But as I just reiterated, we have identified a group of these applicants who have assisted us and who are at some degree of risk. That’s who we’re talking about at the moment. That said, we are – and I’ve made this point before – the State Department, the Defense Department, U.S. Government agencies, we are inherently planning organizations, and so we’re planning for all contingencies so that we’re prepared for all scenarios. So I don’t want to rule anything out at the moment, but when we talk about the SIV applicants that we have so far identified, we’re talking about that group.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And so it’s just – it’s defining those who have some risk associated with their situation? That’s how you’re defining a full evacuation or relocation?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, that’s right. The SIV program, it has a number of requirements, again, that, as I understand it, are written into statute. And so the requirements to qualify for this is quite – quite well defined.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Great. So can I follow up on that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yep.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So the pledge the President has made to get all these people out before the military drawdown does not include the entire set of people who are applying for this SIV visa? It is – you’re defining that by this subset of people you believe are at imminent risk?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, we’re preparing for any number of contingencies. What we have done so far, we have identified a group of SIV applicants who are at risk, and we have – we’ll be prepared to transport them along with their families to third locations while they await their SIV processing.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> One more? Is the U.S. looking at expediting visas for some vulnerable Afghan groups that are outside of the SIV applicant pool? And what would those characteristics be, and would they possibly be evacuated as well?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So to my previous comment, the SIV program is intended for a rather narrow group of people, people who have served the United States Government in various capacities, including as interpreters and translators over the years. We are cognizant, however, that a number of brave Afghans – Afghans who have wanted to see a brighter future for their country – have helped us in any number of ways over the years.</p>
<p>And this goes back to the point I was making before: We’re planning for all contingencies, for all scenarios. We don’t have anything to announce when it comes to programs beyond SIV at the moment, but again, we’re taking a close look at all potential scenarios.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> New subject?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. Anything else on Afghanistan? Great.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. Do you have any update &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sorry, (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What – it sounds like we have one quick – yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just – specifically, I just wanted to push one more time. It’s been reported that Kazakhstan, Tajikistan, and Uzbekistan are among countries you’ve been talking to. Can you – are those the countries that we’re talking about here?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have spoken to a number of countries. State Department officials have. Other administration officials have done the same. I’m not going to specify countries at this stage, but as soon as we have more details to share about potential relocation options, we will.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, can you at least say that it makes sense for logistically, distance-wise, to put them somewhere close to Afghanistan rather than – I don’t know, I’m looking at the map up there &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Canada?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; Denmark?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Look, I’m not going to comment &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, let’s go down to Chile, for example. I mean, does it not make sense that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, if the ultimate goal upon processing a successful adjudication of an SIV application is to bring an applicant here to the United States, that speaks to a different theory of the case. So &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, okay. So you’re saying that – you’re saying that – are you saying that Chile makes more sense then, because it’s closer than &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I am not tipping my hand in &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Or to get into something we’ll go into later, maybe Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I am not tipping my hand in any direction. We are speaking to a number – a number of countries about this important topic.</p>
<p>Yes, Michel.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. Do you have any update on the meetings that Ambassador Shea held in <a id="post-258028-LEBANONSAUDI"></a>Saudi Arabia on Lebanon?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So the – I understand these meetings are ongoing or they only recently concluded. I suspect we’ll have more details to share going forward. But I will say that the French Ambassador Anne Grillo and U.S. Ambassador Dorothy Shea, they’ve conducted important trilateral consultations with Saudi Arabia today to discuss the situation in Lebanon and ways in which together we can support the Lebanese people and, very importantly, help to stabilize the Lebanese economy that has placed such a tremendous burden on the Lebanese people. But as we do have additional details to share, we’ll do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes. Ned, you said yesterday in the briefing that in partnership with the – her French and Saudi counterparts, Ambassador Shea will also continue to develop a trilateral diplomatic strategy focused on government formation and the imperative of undertaking urgent and necessary reforms. Do you have any or more clarity on the strategy today, or can you elaborate on that strategy?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the strategy we have called for and the strategy that I think is collectively shared by a number of our partners is one that seeks to have Lebanon’s leaders, again, show sufficient flexibility to support a government that is principally willing and capable of supporting fundamental reform so that the Lebanese people can achieve and have access to some of that humanitarian relief and to achieve their full potential.</p>
<p>They – “they” being the Lebanese people – deserve a government that will urgently implement those necessary reforms, especially given the deteriorating situation of the Lebanese economy. And we talked about the skyrocketing inflation rates yesterday and the burden that that is placing on Lebanese families. It’s in crisis – the Lebanese economy is – because of years, decades even, of mismanagement, of corruption, of impunity, and more recently because of the inability of Lebanon’s leaders to put aside their political bickering and political disagreements to work for the common good of the Lebanese people.</p>
<p>That’s what the international community has been clear about – that Lebanon’s leaders need to put the interests of their people first. And that in turn will lead to, we hope and we seek to help support, concrete reforms that are critical to unlocking longer-term structural support for Lebanon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> One more if you don’t mind. The Saudis washed their hands of Lebanon a long time ago. Is the U.S. trying with France at this time to bring them back to the Lebanese table, and for what goal?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, Saudi Arabia is an important regional player. It has – it is an important stakeholder in Lebanon. What we are trying to do, what any number of partners of ours are trying to do, is to put a spotlight on the humanitarian plight of the Lebanese people. This was a constant topic of discussion when the Secretary was in Europe – last week I suppose it was – and he discussed Lebanon with a number of interlocutors, to include His Holiness Pope Francis.</p>
<p>So this is what we’re trying to do. Obviously, the humanitarian relief that we’re seeking for the Lebanese people will require support from any number of corners, including in the region and beyond. The United States is willing to continue and able to continue to support the Lebanese people, and we are in an effort to galvanize broader international support to provide that relief to the Lebanese people.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I switch to Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Absolutely. And before you do, Beatriz, I know this may be your last day in our briefing room, so I just want to thank you for your several years here in this room and all you’ve done. And I know you will go on to just down Pennsylvania Avenue, but best of luck.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you very much. I wanted to switch to <a id="post-258028-HAITI"></a>Haiti to ask who the United States recognizes as the prime minister currently in Haiti and if there has been any contact with Ariel Henry or his team. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, as you know, the situation on the ground is evolving rapidly. We remain in close contact with Haitian officials and relevant stakeholders. The Secretary, to your question, spoke yesterday with Acting Prime Minister Claude Joseph, and the Secretary reiterated our continued commitment to work with the Government of Haiti in support of the Haitian people and democratic governance, peace, and security.</p>
<p>We know ultimately that preserving Haiti’s democratic institutions is key to restoring peace. The United States, the OAS, our partners in the region and beyond, we have consistently urged the Government of Haiti to organize free and fair presidential and legislative elections. And we continue to urge Haitian Government officials and political stakeholders to dialogue in the best interests of the Haitian people and to refrain from violence.</p>
<p>This is the message we heard – precisely the message we heard yesterday from Acting Prime Minister Claude Joseph. We have, as you alluded to, been in contact with a number of officials and stakeholders. We have also been in contact with Ariel Henry as well.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And do you recognize Claude Joseph as the prime minister?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, Claude Joseph was the incumbent in the position. He was serving as the acting prime minister before the assassination of President Moise. We continue to work with Claude Joseph as such.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And the ambassador, is she back?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> She is back. Ambassador Sison was able to travel back to Haiti, so she is back in Port-au-Prince.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> More on Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The investigation – the Haitian authorities are saying that one of the people arrested in the assassination was a U.S. citizen. Can you confirm that? Do you have any details on that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m not in a position to confirm that, principally because the Haitian authorities are, of course, leading this investigation. It’s still early days. We’re aware of the reports of the arrests that have taken place, but I would need to refer to Haitian authorities for any details.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And you discussed yesterday whether there was a proposal for – from the Haitians for more assistance. Has there been anything more formal? Is the United States going to offer more assistance, whether it’s terms of the investigation or anything else?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, this has developed over the past couple hours, but we are aware that the Haitian National Police – of the Haitian National Police’s request for investigative assistance, and the United States is responding. The situation on the ground, as I said before, is evolving rapidly. We’ve remained in regular contact with Haitian officials, including the investigative authorities, to discuss how the United States can assist going forward.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is that – what is that – sorry. Is that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> At this stage, what does that mean? Is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is that the FBI? Who is that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So we have not – as of – I was coming out here, I did not have a chance to hear the full details of the request from the Haitian National Police, so I’m not in a position to provide any more detail there. But if it is a request for investigative assistance, that would most likely fall within law enforcement channels.</p>
<p>Yes, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I change to the Tokyo Olympics?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh, can I just do one more question on &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So in terms of sending down any other ways of protecting the embassy, are there more Marines going down? Is that needed at this time?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So as you know, we don’t speak to security measures. We are constantly evaluating the security situation on the ground. Of course, that includes in Port-au-Prince. It also is the case all around the world. We have no higher priority than the safety and security of our people there. The U.S. embassy is restricting the movements of direct hire U.S. citizens and their family members until further notice, but for operational security reasons, we’re not in a position to discuss the specifics of our security posture.</p>
<p>Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes. So does the State Department have a comment on the fact that there are – will be no spectators at the<a id="post-258028-JAPAN"></a> Tokyo Olympics?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> For that, we would need to refer you to the Japanese Government. We support Japan’s efforts to hold a safe and secure Olympic and Paralympic Games.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I go to the Middle East?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The Israeli-Palestinian – go ahead if you want.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sorry, just one thing: Is there anyone from State going?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> To the Olympics?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> In an official capacity, I assume you mean.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, Ned, I’m sure that you’re a great high jumper or whatever – I don’t know – gymnast. I’m sure you are, but no, yes, in an official capacity.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have not announced any &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, I know you haven’t announced, but is anyone actually &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Right. Well, if we haven’t announced it, it probably stands to reason that I’m not going to offer anything from the podium just yet.</p>
<p>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I go to the <a id="post-258028-ISPAL"></a>Israeli-Palestinian?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The Israeli destruction of the home of Montaser Shalabi near Ramallah – I know the embassy in Jerusalem put something out earlier, but wanted to see if the U.S. has a stance on this beyond that, and the current Israeli Government, if the United States has had any talks with them to express opposition to this.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. We are closely following reports that the home was demolished. As we’ve said numerous times now, the home of an entire family should not be demolished for the actions of one individual. There is a critical need to lower the temperature in the West Bank. Punitive demolitions exacerbate tensions at a time when everyone should be focused on principally ensuring calm. The Secretary and other senior officials here at the State Department in recent days have raised these concerns directly with senior Israeli officials and we will continue to do so as long as this practice continues.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So the Secretary himself – can you say at what level he raised this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The Secretary himself did raise this broader issue with a senior Israeli counterpart.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are you &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And they declined, I mean, they dismissed the &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m not going to characterize it, but we attach a good deal of priority to this, knowing that the home of an entire family should never be demolished for the action of one individual.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But when you say that you’re following reports that this house was demolished, do you know that it was demolished? I mean, presumably &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have no reason to doubt that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So why do you say you’re following reports? I mean, why don’t you just come out and say that – if you think it was a bad thing, just come out and say that it was a bad thing.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, Matt, we’ve stated on any number of occasions now that the home of an entire family should not be demolished for the actions of one individual.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Is that what happened in this case, according to you?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have no reason to doubt that. We have been in contact with a number of individuals. Not in a position to speak to all of it, including because of privacy concerns.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just stay in the region, on <a id="post-258028-SYRIA"></a>Syria?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Diplomacy at the UN in terms of preserving a border crossing – there was a report that Russia has proposed as a compromise a six-month extension of the Bab al-Hawa crossing. Can you say if the United States would be at all amenable to that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, there’s only one proposal currently before the Security Council put forward by the humanitarian penholders, and it would reauthorize one crossing for 12 months. And we’ve been very clear that continuing cross-border access – it’s a humanitarian imperative, and it&#8217;s a humanitarian imperative because lives are on the line. Millions of lives are on the line. We&#8217;ve heard very clearly from UN agencies, NGOs around the world that 12 months is critical to their work to reliably deliver aid while managing the lengthy procurement process. What we find before us in the coming days is an opportunity for the Security Council and, more broadly, the international community to stand up and show that it is on the side of the beleaguered and food-insecure Syrian people.</p>
<p>Just on that, as of January of this year, to underscore the stakes, approximately 13.4 million Syrians, two-thirds of the country&#8217;s estimated population, require humanitarian assistance. Nearly 60 percent of Syria’s total population, approximately 12.4 million people, were food insecure as of late last year. And that represents an increase of nearly 60 percent, 57 percent since 2019. Approximately 2 million Syrians are now living in extreme poverty. More than 90 percent of the population is estimated to be living below the poverty line. The World Bank reports life expectancy in Syria has decreased by some 13 years since the start of the conflict.</p>
<p>So we spoke about this in some detail yesterday, but again, for us this is not about politics, it&#8217;s not about geopolitics, it&#8217;s not about international politics. It is about saving lives and it is about doing the right thing for the people of Syria. Any and every responsible country around the world should be in favor of an extension for as long as can be achieved.</p>
<p>Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah, thank you. Seungjin from South Korea. Well, recently, S<a id="post-258028-KOREAS"></a>outh Korea found out that its nuclear research center was possibly hacked by North Korea. So what do you think about it and North Korea’s attempt to hack other countries, particularly the U.S. and its allies?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, we&#8217;re aware of the report you reference. For details of that I would need to refer you to the Government of South Korea to comment. As you know, we don&#8217;t comment on matters of intelligence. But what I would say more broadly is that North Korea&#8217;s malicious cyber activities threaten the United States, they threaten our allies and partners, countries around the world. North Korea poses a significant cyber threat to financial institutions, it remains a cyber espionage threat, it retains the ability to conduct disruptive cyber activities as we&#8217;ve seen it do in recent years. It&#8217;s vital for the international community, for network defenders, and the public to stay vigilant and to work together to mitigate the cyber threat posed by North Korea.</p>
<p>Yes, Michel.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, any update on the talks in <a id="post-258028-IRAN"></a>Vienna?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>On the talks in Vienna, I don&#8217;t have any update to offer you today. We obviously spoke to this yesterday. The timing of the seventh round of talks hasn&#8217;t yet been announced. Our understanding is that the Iranian delegation is in Tehran for consultations, as we talked about yesterday. They have not as of yet informed the EU coordinator as to when they will be ready to start the next round of talks. Therefore, the timing for a seventh round has not yet been set, and we&#8217;re not in a position to speculate as to when it might take place. But we&#8217;re also not going to speculate about the Iranian delegation’s current activities, their decision making processes.</p>
<p>As for our delegation, as you know, Special Envoy Malley and much of his team are back here. There is much work to be done outside of Vienna and the talks there, and so Special Envoy Malley and his team are engaged here at the department. They have briefed the Secretary. They’ve briefed other senior officials as they remain fully engaged in this work to see if we can achieve that mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA.</p>
<p>All right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Did you – just what I started off with yesterday, the <a id="post-258028-HONGKONG"></a>Hong Kong consulate, is there anything &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I don’t – I don&#8217;t have an update for you on the COVID situation at the Hong Kong consulate. As you know, we&#8217;re constantly adjusting given conditions in any locale.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:20 p.m.)</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>Washington, DC</p>
<p>2:43 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Good afternoon.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m sorry we’re starting a couple minutes late, but we have a good excuse today, at least.</p>
<p>Just a quick note at the top, and that’s about recent v<a id="post-258028-VACCINES"></a>accine deliveries. The Biden administration continues to deliver on its promise that the United States will be an arsenal of vaccines for the world. By Saturday, we anticipate that we will have shipped approximately nine million doses to Guatemala, Uruguay, Paraguay, Bolivia, Afghanistan, and Vietnam. In the coming weeks, we will keep you updated as additional doses are shipped and the United States Government continues to lead in the fight against COVID-19 both at home and around the world.</p>
<p>So with that, happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. I just want to start before I get – we get any questions, just a propos of nothing in particular, just again to say that the State Department press corps appreciates the fact that you are getting up every day – or almost every day – and answering our questions, whether we like the answers or not. So &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Once again, I’m happy to conclude the briefing there, if no further questions. (Laughter.) So &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, no, you’re not going to be able to get away with that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I appreciate that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So you will have seen the President’s remarks on A<a id="post-258028-AFGHANISTAN"></a>fghanistan just now. The – earlier this week I asked you if you recalled the letter that Sirik Matak had sent to John Gunther Dean, who was the ambassador to Cambodia in 1975. And it doesn’t seem to have gotten that much attention, as opposed to other things. So I’m just going to – it’s eight sentences, so I’m just going to read it:</p>
<p>“Dear Excellency and friend, I thank you sincerely for your letter and your offer to transport me towards freedom. I cannot, alas, leave in such cowardly fashion. As for you and in particular for your great country, I never believed for a moment that you would have this sentiment of abandoning a people which has chosen liberty. You have refused us your protection, and we can do nothing about it. You leave, and my wish is that you and your country will find happiness under the sky. But mark it well, that if I shall die here on this spot and in my country that I love, it is too bad, because we are all born and must die one day. I have committed this mistake of believing in you, the Americans. Regards, Sirik Matak.”</p>
<p>Of course, he was killed by the Khmer Rouge several days later.</p>
<p>Given the President’s comments and intention to withdraw, does this have any impact on you guys at all?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Matt, I would reiterate what it is you just heard moments ago from President Biden, and it is something that you have heard over and over again since the President announced our plans just a couple months ago, and that is the fact that U.S. support for the Afghan people, for the Afghan Government, will endure. And you heard the President very clearly make that point earlier today. He – he –</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You know what? That’s exactly what the American president said in – what President Nixon said, what President Ford said, and now, why should anyone believe you?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Because, Matt, President Biden is a man of his word. This administration is committed to the people of Afghanistan. We – the hard-won gains of the Afghan people over the past 20 years, the amount of suffering that the Afghan people have endured over the past 40 years, this – these are gains that we are going to do everything we can to help preserve. And that is precisely why you heard the President say today that he has asked his team – and that includes, of course, Secretary Blinken; it includes, of course, Ambassador Khalilzad; it includes, of course, our counterparts throughout the government – to work concertedly, diplomatically with the parties, with the international community, with Afghanistan’s neighbors, to bring about a just and durable resolution that includes a comprehensive ceasefire.</p>
<p>So Matt, in all of this, we are not leaving the Afghan people. We are not abandoning the Afghan people. Our goal in all of this is to support the diplomacy that will, we hope and key elements, key Afghan elements hope will bring about a just and durable peace. We hope to help set the conditions so that Afghans can live in their country in safety and security without American military forces there on the ground.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So – okay, all right. So he – so who is it that’s in charge specifically? You mentioned someone was in charge of the – for the SIV applicants, the people who are wanting to get out. Who is that exactly? And then there doesn’t seem to be any definitive resolution as to where people – where those people might be relocated while they await their – the adjudication of their visas. Is there any answer on that at all?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So as you heard from the President, he has asked Secretary Blinken, he has asked Ambassador Khalilzad to hypercharge our diplomacy. That’s something we’ve been engaged in since the earliest days of this administration. Brian McKeon, the Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources, is playing a lead role when it comes to the SIV process. He is working closely not only with Secretary Blinken but with the White House as well.</p>
<p>When it comes to the SIV program, of course this has been a priority of ours even before this military withdrawal began. You heard the President say today that we have been – we have identified locations outside of the continental United States and in third countries. The State Department has been engaged with various countries, a number of countries, diplomatically on this issue. Wouldn’t want to detail beyond that at this point. But you heard the President say today that relocation will begin later this month. So as soon as have more details to provide we certainly will.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So this just – they – so Brian is the point person here?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> That’s right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Abbie?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You said that you’ve identified and engaged diplomatically with third countries. Have you received a commitment from specific countries to take in the SIVs as they finish their application?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have had conversations with a number of countries. Many of those conversations have been very constructive and positive, but I wouldn’t want to detail potential locations at this time.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you expand upon what the President said regarding asking Congress to change the law to allow for them to come to U.S. territories?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So as you know, the SIV program – its requirements are statutorily mandated. As I recall, there are about 12 steps that applicants have to go through. So for the State Department, for the Department of Homeland Security, which also has a role in this, we have done what we can to accelerate the processing time through resources, putting more people on this task, more resources at the chief of mission level as well. And by doing so, we’ve been able to shave significant time off the average processing it takes for each applicant. But there are certain things we can’t do, because again the SIV process is written into statute.</p>
<p>And so for us to fundamentally change that process, it would require cooperation from Congress. Of course, we’ve been heartened that Congress also sees this as a priority; Congress attaches a great deal of importance to this program, as do we. And so we have been really gratified by the cooperation and the interest we’ve seen from Congress on this.</p>
<p>Simon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The President’s repeatedly been calling for the Afghans to be united and for there to be unity among the Afghan Government. Is the U.S. pressing Ghani specifically to form a national unity government?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have always said that this process has to be Afghan-led and Afghan-owned. Whatever endures will be – will have to be, in our view, Afghan-led and Afghan-owned, because only if it is such will it have support of the Afghan people, will it have legitimacy in the eyes of the Afghan people, will it have legitimacy in the eyes of much of the international community. And so that is why we have been engaged in this diplomacy, but we have supported the diplomacy. We’re not a direct party to the intra-Afghan talks. Of course, there was a separate agreement between the United States and the Taliban. But when it comes to the intra-Afghan talks, these are talks between and among the Afghans themselves.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you think that the current administration has that, the qualities you’ve described?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m sorry. Has the what?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Has the – is Afghan-led and Afghan-owned? The current Afghan Government – does it meet the requirements that you’re describing?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Certainly the current Afghan Government is. What comes next, any changes that may come in the coming months or years – those will similarly need to be Afghan-led and Afghan-owned.</p>
<p>Sure, yeah. Christina.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The President just said that about 2,500 of the SIV applicants have gotten their visa but chosen not to come to the U.S. He said they’ve chosen to stay in Afghanistan. How do you know that? And do you know that? Do you know it’s a matter of choice, or is it a matter of not being able to afford a plane ticket, not being able to get to the airport, not to be able to securely leave the country because of fear of – like how are you making that judgment that they are choosing to stay in the country?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, as I said before, the SIV program – there are some 12 steps involved in the program. And some of those steps do entail direct contact with applicants. And so throughout the process, consular officers, State Department officials, do have an opportunity to hear directly from applicants. In fact, it’s required that we are in receipt of a good deal of information from the applicants. So I presume that’s where that comes from.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So you’re (inaudible) of those are a deliberate choice to remain in Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Say that again?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I said so you’re confident that the 2,500 – all of those are making a deliberate choice to stay in Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have no reason to doubt that. As the President said however, that for the group that we have identified, if they so desire to come to the United States, we will see to it that they will have an opportunity to come here upon the completion of their SIV processing.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And with the transports, with the – if it comes to an evacuation or however we’re phrasing that, are you confident that given the military withdrawal, the closing of Bagram, that you will have enough security and resources to be able to carry out the transportation of those people once – if and when they get their visas and if and when there is a third country cleared? Are you worried that there could be a security situation on the ground?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So as we have said, the – we have identified a group of SIV applicants who have served in roles, including interpreters and translators. They and their families will have the option to be relocated to a location outside of Afghanistan before we complete our military drawdown. And so as you heard from the President today, the military drawdown will be complete by the end of August, so we are talking about this process in terms of weeks rather than months and months.</p>
<p>Kylie, yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just move back on that? I’m just curious about you guys continually say this will happen before the drawdown in September, but then you guys also say that approximately 9,000 of these 18,000 are in more progressed positions. So I’m just wondering, does that mean that you’re going to conclude only the 9,000 by September, or does it mean you’re going to conclude the total 18,000 that are on this list?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So we haven’t attached a number to it yet. But as I just reiterated, we have identified a group of these applicants who have assisted us and who are at some degree of risk. That’s who we’re talking about at the moment. That said, we are – and I’ve made this point before – the State Department, the Defense Department, U.S. Government agencies, we are inherently planning organizations, and so we’re planning for all contingencies so that we’re prepared for all scenarios. So I don’t want to rule anything out at the moment, but when we talk about the SIV applicants that we have so far identified, we’re talking about that group.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And so it’s just – it’s defining those who have some risk associated with their situation? That’s how you’re defining a full evacuation or relocation?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, that’s right. The SIV program, it has a number of requirements, again, that, as I understand it, are written into statute. And so the requirements to qualify for this is quite – quite well defined.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Great. So can I follow up on that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yep.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So the pledge the President has made to get all these people out before the military drawdown does not include the entire set of people who are applying for this SIV visa? It is – you’re defining that by this subset of people you believe are at imminent risk?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, we’re preparing for any number of contingencies. What we have done so far, we have identified a group of SIV applicants who are at risk, and we have – we’ll be prepared to transport them along with their families to third locations while they await their SIV processing.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> One more? Is the U.S. looking at expediting visas for some vulnerable Afghan groups that are outside of the SIV applicant pool? And what would those characteristics be, and would they possibly be evacuated as well?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So to my previous comment, the SIV program is intended for a rather narrow group of people, people who have served the United States Government in various capacities, including as interpreters and translators over the years. We are cognizant, however, that a number of brave Afghans – Afghans who have wanted to see a brighter future for their country – have helped us in any number of ways over the years.</p>
<p>And this goes back to the point I was making before: We’re planning for all contingencies, for all scenarios. We don’t have anything to announce when it comes to programs beyond SIV at the moment, but again, we’re taking a close look at all potential scenarios.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> New subject?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. Anything else on Afghanistan? Great.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. Do you have any update &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sorry, (inaudible).</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What – it sounds like we have one quick – yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just – specifically, I just wanted to push one more time. It’s been reported that Kazakhstan, Tajikistan, and Uzbekistan are among countries you’ve been talking to. Can you – are those the countries that we’re talking about here?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have spoken to a number of countries. State Department officials have. Other administration officials have done the same. I’m not going to specify countries at this stage, but as soon as we have more details to share about potential relocation options, we will.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, can you at least say that it makes sense for logistically, distance-wise, to put them somewhere close to Afghanistan rather than – I don’t know, I’m looking at the map up there &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Canada?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; Denmark?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Look, I’m not going to comment &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No, let’s go down to Chile, for example. I mean, does it not make sense that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, if the ultimate goal upon processing a successful adjudication of an SIV application is to bring an applicant here to the United States, that speaks to a different theory of the case. So &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, okay. So you’re saying that – you’re saying that – are you saying that Chile makes more sense then, because it’s closer than &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I am not tipping my hand in &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Or to get into something we’ll go into later, maybe Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I am not tipping my hand in any direction. We are speaking to a number – a number of countries about this important topic.</p>
<p>Yes, Michel.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah. Do you have any update on the meetings that Ambassador Shea held in <a id="post-258028-LEBANONSAUDI"></a>Saudi Arabia on Lebanon?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So the – I understand these meetings are ongoing or they only recently concluded. I suspect we’ll have more details to share going forward. But I will say that the French Ambassador Anne Grillo and U.S. Ambassador Dorothy Shea, they’ve conducted important trilateral consultations with Saudi Arabia today to discuss the situation in Lebanon and ways in which together we can support the Lebanese people and, very importantly, help to stabilize the Lebanese economy that has placed such a tremendous burden on the Lebanese people. But as we do have additional details to share, we’ll do that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes. Ned, you said yesterday in the briefing that in partnership with the – her French and Saudi counterparts, Ambassador Shea will also continue to develop a trilateral diplomatic strategy focused on government formation and the imperative of undertaking urgent and necessary reforms. Do you have any or more clarity on the strategy today, or can you elaborate on that strategy?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the strategy we have called for and the strategy that I think is collectively shared by a number of our partners is one that seeks to have Lebanon’s leaders, again, show sufficient flexibility to support a government that is principally willing and capable of supporting fundamental reform so that the Lebanese people can achieve and have access to some of that humanitarian relief and to achieve their full potential.</p>
<p>They – “they” being the Lebanese people – deserve a government that will urgently implement those necessary reforms, especially given the deteriorating situation of the Lebanese economy. And we talked about the skyrocketing inflation rates yesterday and the burden that that is placing on Lebanese families. It’s in crisis – the Lebanese economy is – because of years, decades even, of mismanagement, of corruption, of impunity, and more recently because of the inability of Lebanon’s leaders to put aside their political bickering and political disagreements to work for the common good of the Lebanese people.</p>
<p>That’s what the international community has been clear about – that Lebanon’s leaders need to put the interests of their people first. And that in turn will lead to, we hope and we seek to help support, concrete reforms that are critical to unlocking longer-term structural support for Lebanon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> One more if you don’t mind. The Saudis washed their hands of Lebanon a long time ago. Is the U.S. trying with France at this time to bring them back to the Lebanese table, and for what goal?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, Saudi Arabia is an important regional player. It has – it is an important stakeholder in Lebanon. What we are trying to do, what any number of partners of ours are trying to do, is to put a spotlight on the humanitarian plight of the Lebanese people. This was a constant topic of discussion when the Secretary was in Europe – last week I suppose it was – and he discussed Lebanon with a number of interlocutors, to include His Holiness Pope Francis.</p>
<p>So this is what we’re trying to do. Obviously, the humanitarian relief that we’re seeking for the Lebanese people will require support from any number of corners, including in the region and beyond. The United States is willing to continue and able to continue to support the Lebanese people, and we are in an effort to galvanize broader international support to provide that relief to the Lebanese people.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I switch to Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Absolutely. And before you do, Beatriz, I know this may be your last day in our briefing room, so I just want to thank you for your several years here in this room and all you’ve done. And I know you will go on to just down Pennsylvania Avenue, but best of luck.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you very much. I wanted to switch to <a id="post-258028-HAITI"></a>Haiti to ask who the United States recognizes as the prime minister currently in Haiti and if there has been any contact with Ariel Henry or his team. Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, as you know, the situation on the ground is evolving rapidly. We remain in close contact with Haitian officials and relevant stakeholders. The Secretary, to your question, spoke yesterday with Acting Prime Minister Claude Joseph, and the Secretary reiterated our continued commitment to work with the Government of Haiti in support of the Haitian people and democratic governance, peace, and security.</p>
<p>We know ultimately that preserving Haiti’s democratic institutions is key to restoring peace. The United States, the OAS, our partners in the region and beyond, we have consistently urged the Government of Haiti to organize free and fair presidential and legislative elections. And we continue to urge Haitian Government officials and political stakeholders to dialogue in the best interests of the Haitian people and to refrain from violence.</p>
<p>This is the message we heard – precisely the message we heard yesterday from Acting Prime Minister Claude Joseph. We have, as you alluded to, been in contact with a number of officials and stakeholders. We have also been in contact with Ariel Henry as well.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And do you recognize Claude Joseph as the prime minister?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, Claude Joseph was the incumbent in the position. He was serving as the acting prime minister before the assassination of President Moise. We continue to work with Claude Joseph as such.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And the ambassador, is she back?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> She is back. Ambassador Sison was able to travel back to Haiti, so she is back in Port-au-Prince.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> More on Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The investigation – the Haitian authorities are saying that one of the people arrested in the assassination was a U.S. citizen. Can you confirm that? Do you have any details on that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m not in a position to confirm that, principally because the Haitian authorities are, of course, leading this investigation. It’s still early days. We’re aware of the reports of the arrests that have taken place, but I would need to refer to Haitian authorities for any details.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And you discussed yesterday whether there was a proposal for – from the Haitians for more assistance. Has there been anything more formal? Is the United States going to offer more assistance, whether it’s terms of the investigation or anything else?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, this has developed over the past couple hours, but we are aware that the Haitian National Police – of the Haitian National Police’s request for investigative assistance, and the United States is responding. The situation on the ground, as I said before, is evolving rapidly. We’ve remained in regular contact with Haitian officials, including the investigative authorities, to discuss how the United States can assist going forward.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is that – what is that – sorry. Is that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> At this stage, what does that mean? Is &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is that the FBI? Who is that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So we have not – as of – I was coming out here, I did not have a chance to hear the full details of the request from the Haitian National Police, so I’m not in a position to provide any more detail there. But if it is a request for investigative assistance, that would most likely fall within law enforcement channels.</p>
<p>Yes, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I change to the Tokyo Olympics?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh, can I just do one more question on &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So in terms of sending down any other ways of protecting the embassy, are there more Marines going down? Is that needed at this time?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So as you know, we don’t speak to security measures. We are constantly evaluating the security situation on the ground. Of course, that includes in Port-au-Prince. It also is the case all around the world. We have no higher priority than the safety and security of our people there. The U.S. embassy is restricting the movements of direct hire U.S. citizens and their family members until further notice, but for operational security reasons, we’re not in a position to discuss the specifics of our security posture.</p>
<p>Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes. So does the State Department have a comment on the fact that there are – will be no spectators at the<a id="post-258028-JAPAN"></a> Tokyo Olympics?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> For that, we would need to refer you to the Japanese Government. We support Japan’s efforts to hold a safe and secure Olympic and Paralympic Games.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I go to the Middle East?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The Israeli-Palestinian – go ahead if you want.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sorry, just one thing: Is there anyone from State going?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> To the Olympics?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> In an official capacity, I assume you mean.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, Ned, I’m sure that you’re a great high jumper or whatever – I don’t know – gymnast. I’m sure you are, but no, yes, in an official capacity.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have not announced any &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, I know you haven’t announced, but is anyone actually &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Right. Well, if we haven’t announced it, it probably stands to reason that I’m not going to offer anything from the podium just yet.</p>
<p>Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I go to the <a id="post-258028-ISPAL"></a>Israeli-Palestinian?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> The Israeli destruction of the home of Montaser Shalabi near Ramallah – I know the embassy in Jerusalem put something out earlier, but wanted to see if the U.S. has a stance on this beyond that, and the current Israeli Government, if the United States has had any talks with them to express opposition to this.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. We are closely following reports that the home was demolished. As we’ve said numerous times now, the home of an entire family should not be demolished for the actions of one individual. There is a critical need to lower the temperature in the West Bank. Punitive demolitions exacerbate tensions at a time when everyone should be focused on principally ensuring calm. The Secretary and other senior officials here at the State Department in recent days have raised these concerns directly with senior Israeli officials and we will continue to do so as long as this practice continues.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So the Secretary himself – can you say at what level he raised this?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The Secretary himself did raise this broader issue with a senior Israeli counterpart.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are you &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And they declined, I mean, they dismissed the &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m not going to characterize it, but we attach a good deal of priority to this, knowing that the home of an entire family should never be demolished for the action of one individual.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But when you say that you’re following reports that this house was demolished, do you know that it was demolished? I mean, presumably &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have no reason to doubt that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So why do you say you’re following reports? I mean, why don’t you just come out and say that – if you think it was a bad thing, just come out and say that it was a bad thing.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, Matt, we’ve stated on any number of occasions now that the home of an entire family should not be demolished for the actions of one individual.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Is that what happened in this case, according to you?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have no reason to doubt that. We have been in contact with a number of individuals. Not in a position to speak to all of it, including because of privacy concerns.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just stay in the region, on <a id="post-258028-SYRIA"></a>Syria?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure. Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Diplomacy at the UN in terms of preserving a border crossing – there was a report that Russia has proposed as a compromise a six-month extension of the Bab al-Hawa crossing. Can you say if the United States would be at all amenable to that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, there’s only one proposal currently before the Security Council put forward by the humanitarian penholders, and it would reauthorize one crossing for 12 months. And we’ve been very clear that continuing cross-border access – it’s a humanitarian imperative, and it&#8217;s a humanitarian imperative because lives are on the line. Millions of lives are on the line. We&#8217;ve heard very clearly from UN agencies, NGOs around the world that 12 months is critical to their work to reliably deliver aid while managing the lengthy procurement process. What we find before us in the coming days is an opportunity for the Security Council and, more broadly, the international community to stand up and show that it is on the side of the beleaguered and food-insecure Syrian people.</p>
<p>Just on that, as of January of this year, to underscore the stakes, approximately 13.4 million Syrians, two-thirds of the country&#8217;s estimated population, require humanitarian assistance. Nearly 60 percent of Syria’s total population, approximately 12.4 million people, were food insecure as of late last year. And that represents an increase of nearly 60 percent, 57 percent since 2019. Approximately 2 million Syrians are now living in extreme poverty. More than 90 percent of the population is estimated to be living below the poverty line. The World Bank reports life expectancy in Syria has decreased by some 13 years since the start of the conflict.</p>
<p>So we spoke about this in some detail yesterday, but again, for us this is not about politics, it&#8217;s not about geopolitics, it&#8217;s not about international politics. It is about saving lives and it is about doing the right thing for the people of Syria. Any and every responsible country around the world should be in favor of an extension for as long as can be achieved.</p>
<p>Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah, thank you. Seungjin from South Korea. Well, recently, S<a id="post-258028-KOREAS"></a>outh Korea found out that its nuclear research center was possibly hacked by North Korea. So what do you think about it and North Korea’s attempt to hack other countries, particularly the U.S. and its allies?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, we&#8217;re aware of the report you reference. For details of that I would need to refer you to the Government of South Korea to comment. As you know, we don&#8217;t comment on matters of intelligence. But what I would say more broadly is that North Korea&#8217;s malicious cyber activities threaten the United States, they threaten our allies and partners, countries around the world. North Korea poses a significant cyber threat to financial institutions, it remains a cyber espionage threat, it retains the ability to conduct disruptive cyber activities as we&#8217;ve seen it do in recent years. It&#8217;s vital for the international community, for network defenders, and the public to stay vigilant and to work together to mitigate the cyber threat posed by North Korea.</p>
<p>Yes, Michel.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, any update on the talks in <a id="post-258028-IRAN"></a>Vienna?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>On the talks in Vienna, I don&#8217;t have any update to offer you today. We obviously spoke to this yesterday. The timing of the seventh round of talks hasn&#8217;t yet been announced. Our understanding is that the Iranian delegation is in Tehran for consultations, as we talked about yesterday. They have not as of yet informed the EU coordinator as to when they will be ready to start the next round of talks. Therefore, the timing for a seventh round has not yet been set, and we&#8217;re not in a position to speculate as to when it might take place. But we&#8217;re also not going to speculate about the Iranian delegation’s current activities, their decision making processes.</p>
<p>As for our delegation, as you know, Special Envoy Malley and much of his team are back here. There is much work to be done outside of Vienna and the talks there, and so Special Envoy Malley and his team are engaged here at the department. They have briefed the Secretary. They’ve briefed other senior officials as they remain fully engaged in this work to see if we can achieve that mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA.</p>
<p>All right.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Did you – just what I started off with yesterday, the <a id="post-258028-HONGKONG"></a>Hong Kong consulate, is there anything &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I don’t – I don&#8217;t have an update for you on the COVID situation at the Hong Kong consulate. As you know, we&#8217;re constantly adjusting given conditions in any locale.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:20 p.m.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Troika Statement South Sudan’s 10 Year Independence Anniversary</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/troika-statement-south-sudans-10-year-independence-anniversary/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 14:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=257850</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Troika (United States, United Kingdom, and Norway) congratulates the people of South Sudan on 10 years of independence.  On July 9, 2011, South Sudanese joined together in unity to celebrate the country’s birth.  It was a joyous occasion, filled with hope and possibility.</p>
<p>The first ten years of this young country’s history have seen much suffering, due to conflict related abuses, famine, flooding, and disease.  Yet through it all, the South Sudanese people have shown resilience.  We commend the commitment many have shown in working together to build a brighter future, so it is deeply saddening that the promise of peace and prosperity that independence represented remains unfulfilled.</p>
<p>The Troika has stood with the people of Sudan and South Sudan through decades of struggle and whilst we join those celebrating today, we grieve for those who have suffered and lost loved ones.  Today, millions do not have enough food to feed themselves or their family.  The Troika urges immediate action to ensure access for humanitarian aid and to end violence against South Sudanese and the aid workers who serve them.</p>
<p>Due to the immense suffering caused by the outbreak of war our aid is now primarily humanitarian, but we want to see South Sudan get back on the road to economic and social development.  After all, South Sudan is rich.  Its riches do not just reside in the oil beneath its land or the lumber in its forests.  South Sudan is rich because of the diverse communities of people that make up this young country.  It is on their behalf that we have been a constant supporter of the implementation of the peace agreement.  However, nearly three years since we commended the signing of the agreement, many tasks remain undelivered.  Few of the tangible benefits of peace are seen by ordinary citizens.  The Troika welcomes the progress that has been made but urges the signatories to accept accountability for their commitments and go much further, much faster.</p>
<p>The great challenge now facing South Sudan is to recapture the sense of unity, strength, and hope that prevailed on this day ten years ago.  With reconciliation through compromise and accelerated implementation of the peace agreement, South Sudan can become a peaceful, democratic country, where human rights and the rule of law are respected – a country where all people have food on their table, where businesses prosper, and where the Government truly serves its people.  To realize that vision, both the politically manipulated and localized communal conflict that tears at the fabric of society itself, needs to stop.  Preparations for peaceful, credible, and inclusive elections must begin in earnest; unified forces must be created; transitional justice mechanisms must be fully established; and key financial reforms need to happen as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>The Troika remains eager to work in close partnership with the transitional government to implement fully the revitalized peace agreement.  We are committed to standing with the South Sudanese people as they work toward their aspirations of peace and prosperity.  We urge the political leadership of South Sudan to take the actions needed to build the country the jubilant crowds of 2011 dreamed was possible.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Troika (United States, United Kingdom, and Norway) congratulates the people of South Sudan on 10 years of independence.  On July 9, 2011, South Sudanese joined together in unity to celebrate the country’s birth.  It was a joyous occasion, filled with hope and possibility.</p>
<p>The first ten years of this young country’s history have seen much suffering, due to conflict related abuses, famine, flooding, and disease.  Yet through it all, the South Sudanese people have shown resilience.  We commend the commitment many have shown in working together to build a brighter future, so it is deeply saddening that the promise of peace and prosperity that independence represented remains unfulfilled.</p>
<p>The Troika has stood with the people of Sudan and South Sudan through decades of struggle and whilst we join those celebrating today, we grieve for those who have suffered and lost loved ones.  Today, millions do not have enough food to feed themselves or their family.  The Troika urges immediate action to ensure access for humanitarian aid and to end violence against South Sudanese and the aid workers who serve them.</p>
<p>Due to the immense suffering caused by the outbreak of war our aid is now primarily humanitarian, but we want to see South Sudan get back on the road to economic and social development.  After all, South Sudan is rich.  Its riches do not just reside in the oil beneath its land or the lumber in its forests.  South Sudan is rich because of the diverse communities of people that make up this young country.  It is on their behalf that we have been a constant supporter of the implementation of the peace agreement.  However, nearly three years since we commended the signing of the agreement, many tasks remain undelivered.  Few of the tangible benefits of peace are seen by ordinary citizens.  The Troika welcomes the progress that has been made but urges the signatories to accept accountability for their commitments and go much further, much faster.</p>
<p>The great challenge now facing South Sudan is to recapture the sense of unity, strength, and hope that prevailed on this day ten years ago.  With reconciliation through compromise and accelerated implementation of the peace agreement, South Sudan can become a peaceful, democratic country, where human rights and the rule of law are respected – a country where all people have food on their table, where businesses prosper, and where the Government truly serves its people.  To realize that vision, both the politically manipulated and localized communal conflict that tears at the fabric of society itself, needs to stop.  Preparations for peaceful, credible, and inclusive elections must begin in earnest; unified forces must be created; transitional justice mechanisms must be fully established; and key financial reforms need to happen as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>The Troika remains eager to work in close partnership with the transitional government to implement fully the revitalized peace agreement.  We are committed to standing with the South Sudanese people as they work toward their aspirations of peace and prosperity.  We urge the political leadership of South Sudan to take the actions needed to build the country the jubilant crowds of 2011 dreamed was possible.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry’s Participation in “The Low Carbon City for All”</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-presidential-envoy-for-climate-john-kerrys-participation-in-the-low-carbon-city-for-all/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 12:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=257823</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will participate in the Université de la Ville de Demain’s &#8220;The Low Carbon City for All&#8221; summit in France on July 8, 2021.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will participate in the Université de la Ville de Demain’s &#8220;The Low Carbon City for All&#8221; summit in France on July 8, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Acting Haitian Prime Minister Joseph</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-acting-haitian-prime-minister-joseph/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 23:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=257783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Acting Haitian Prime Minister Claude Joseph today. Secretary Blinken extended condolences to the family and loved ones of President Moïse and to the people of Haiti. The Secretary also expressed the United States’ wishes for First Lady Martine Moïse’s recovery. Secretary Blinken reiterated the United States’ continued commitment to work with the Government of Haiti in support of the Haitian people and democratic governance, peace, and security.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Acting Haitian Prime Minister Claude Joseph today. Secretary Blinken extended condolences to the family and loved ones of President Moïse and to the people of Haiti. The Secretary also expressed the United States’ wishes for First Lady Martine Moïse’s recovery. Secretary Blinken reiterated the United States’ continued commitment to work with the Government of Haiti in support of the Haitian people and democratic governance, peace, and security.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; July 7, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-july-7-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 22:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=257769</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>2:56 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, a very Lurch-like “good afternoon.” No?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I just want to make sure everyone is paying attention.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-HAITI"></a> I obviously want to stop – start with the situation in Haiti. The United States strongly condemns, as you heard from President Biden earlier today, the assassination of President Jovenel Moise and the attack on First Lady Martine Moise in Haiti. We extend our deepest condolences to President Moise’s family and his loved ones and to the people of Haiti in the midst of this tragedy.</p>
<p>Those who seek to accomplish their political goals through violence and by subverting the rule of law will not succeed in thwarting the Haitian people and their desire for a better – for a brighter future. We urge Haitian authorities to bring those responsible to justice. The United States calls on all political parties, civil society groups, and stakeholders to echo what we’ve heard from Acting Prime Minister Claude Joseph’s call for calm and to work together in the wake of this tragedy to ensure peace and democratic governance.</p>
<p>So with that, I am happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-CHINA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So I – just before returning to Haiti, I got a extremely brief thing. It’s something else, but it’s a logistical thing, kind of, and that is the Hong Kong consulate, which has been closed for a couple days now because of a COVID case. Do – has that spread, do you know? Is there anything more you can say about that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m not in a position &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And I only ask this now because I’m going to forget about it if I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I understand. I’m not in a position to offer an update on the operating status there. As you know, our embassies and posts around the world are constantly calibrating their operations given the state of COVID or any other issue that may affect the workforce. But I don’t have an update to offer.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-HAITI2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. On Haiti, then. Is there any – this isn’t exactly – it’s bad, but it’s not exactly a coup. I mean, it’s a – not a – the government hasn’t been overthrown or anything like that. So is there any implication, assistance-wise, or any other wise, for Haiti related to – the administration policy towards Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There is – Acting Prime Minister Claude Joseph has assumed charge. What we know and what we will continue to do is to preserve Haiti’s democratic institutions. We know that by preserving Haiti’s democratic institutions, that is key to restoring peace. At this time, we don’t have any updates to announce in terms of our assistance, but I can assure you that our partnership with the Haitian people and with their elected government will continue. As you know, that partnership has taken many forms in recent months; in, of course, recent years. In January of this year we announced 75.5 million for – in support for a wide range of issues, and that includes democratic governance, health, education, agricultural development, strengthening pre-election activities through the Consortium for Elections and Political Process Strengthening program.</p>
<p>We have also been a strong partner for Haiti and the Haitian people when it comes to security and when it comes to law enforcement as well. And much of that has been overseen by our Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs. They have provided direct assistance to the Haitian National Police over the years, and as a direct result of this INL support the Haitian National Police have trained officers from a number that was less than 10,000 in 2010 to nearly 15,000 Haitian National Police officers today. We have continued to encourage Haiti to take a holistic approach to countering violence and to countering gangs, and we provided $5 million to strengthen the Haitian National Police’s capacity to work with communities to resist gangs as well.</p>
<p>And I would remiss if I didn’t note our support to Haiti’s pre-election activities. And USAID is providing more than $3 million to the consortium I mentioned before. And those activities for which these funds are earmarked include focusing on improving electoral administration, strengthening the competitiveness of political parties, educating voters on electoral processes, promoting electoral transparency, and ensuring inclusive voter participation as well. So this is just one – these are just several metrics of our support for the Haitian people, and that will not waver in the wake of this.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Given, Ned, the history of U.S. intervention in Haiti – it’s been numerous times over the course of the last century and a half – is there any appetite in this administration for some kind of – to intervene if the situation gets to be dire? This is a relatively close neighbor that has in the past seen massive outflows of people trying to escape, so if it – the situation deteriorates – and I realize this is a hypothetical – but is there any appetite for a return?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> To us, Matt &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; Haiti is a partner, and that is how we will treat this relationship. It is how we have treated Haiti, it is how we will going forward. We would echo what we have heard from the acting prime minister, Claude Joseph, in his calls for calm, his calls for the Haitian people to work together to ensure peace, to ensure democratic government. The United States has and will continue to stand by to provide assistance to the Haitian people.</p>
<p>Humeyra.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So on Haiti, the ambassador told us that they – he has been in touch with the State Department and a number of different agencies in U.S. Government. Can you at least say – you just said that you can’t give an update on the U.S. assistance, but can you at least say perhaps a new package is being formed and you guys are working on something new on top of these quite little numbers – $5 million, $3 million – that you’ve just mentioned?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> $75.5 million.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. I missed that, sorry.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have been in regular contact with the acting prime minister, Claude Joseph. We are prepared to respond to requests for assistance. Our ambassador to Haiti, Ambassador Sison, has been in regular contact with a range of Haitian officials. She has spoken to the acting director general of the Haitian National Police. Of course, Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield at the UN this morning spoke to Haiti’s permanent representative to the UN. We have been, as I said before, in regular contact.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken started his day this morning with a comprehensive update on the situation on the ground, including the latest developments as we knew them at the time, the security situation. He was briefed by Ambassador Sison, who at this moment happens to be in Washington. He was also on the phone with the DCM, who is on the ground in Haiti right now, DCM Nicole Theriot, as well as other members of his team. So we are prepared to receive additional requests for assistance from Haitian authorities.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you also confirm if first lady is being flown to Miami for – to receive medical treatment?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we, of course, are familiar with the reports that the First Lady Martine Moise was injured in the attack. We know that she was taken to receive medical treatment. Out of respect for her privacy, we’re not in a position to comment on – to provide further comment. But as I said, we have made very clear to Haitian authorities the United States is standing ready to provide assistance and we are prepared to provide any and all forms of appropriate assistance to our Haitian partners.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you speak to the DEA element of all of this? You – the ambassador also talked about this footage where they’re identifying themselves as DEA agents, and he said that he doesn’t believe in it. I mean, can you say that that’s not the case, that you have an assessment that those are not DEA officials? Can you sort of set the record straight on that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, as you said, the Haitian ambassador himself has dismissed these allegations. These reports are absolutely false. The United States condemns this heinous act. These false reports are nothing more than that, just false reports.</p>
<p>Shaun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I just follow up on that? Is there any sense of what the motivation would have been for this? And is – do you think there’s any truth to what the government – to what the acting government is saying, that these were mercenaries, that these were foreigners who were in there?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, Shaun, we just don’t have clear answers at the – at this time. What we do know and what I have said is that Haitian authorities are investigating. We stand ready to offer assistance to that investigation, but obviously, we’re going to let that investigation play out. And, of course, the Haitian authorities are in the lead on that investigation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just one more thing on that. You – earlier this year, you were mentioning about the elections in Haiti and you called for them to go on – go ahead and schedule later this year. Is it still the view of the United States that elections in September are a good idea?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It is still the view of the United States that elections this year should proceed. We know that free and fair elections are the democratic path towards ending Haiti’s irregular and prolonged rule by decree and restoring its parliament, which as of now has lapsed. Free and fair presidential elections will facilitate a peaceful transfer of power to a newly elected president as well.</p>
<p>We’ve – as you know and as you have heard me say and others say, we have urged Haitian Government and political stakeholders repeatedly both in public and in private to reach a political accord in order to ensure those legislative and presidential elections take place later this year.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. Nazira Karimi, Afghan independent journalist.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can we stay on Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Sure. Let’s stay on Haiti for just a moment.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> I will come back to you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I change the subject?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well, we’ll – I’ll come back to you if that’s okay.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We’ll take a couple more on Haiti.</p>
<p>Will.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, just two questions on Haiti. I want to ask this a slightly different way. Can you confirm that there currently is a pending request for defense equipment from Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We expect to be in receipt of formal requests. We stand ready to receive them. But as of right now, I’m not in a position to confirm that we’ve received a formal request.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. And what was the administration’s position on the president’s legitimacy as a leader of the country? Obviously, the opposition says his five-year term expired last February.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> The Haitian constitution is clear on this point. As we’ve said, we’ve supported elections later this year. We still support those elections later this year, believing and knowing that President Moise’s term was to end next year.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Quick question on Haiti. The current U.S. ambassador to Haiti has been nominated to a different position in the State Department. Is there any plan to speed up the process to naming a new ambassador to that country?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well, as you know, Ambassador Sison is still in that role. She was actually supposed to travel back to Haiti today after consultations here in Washington. She expects to go back to Haiti just as soon as she is able to travel there. We also are very fortunate to have a very capable DCM in Haiti, Nicole Theriot, whom I mentioned before. So if and when Ambassador Sison moves on to her next role, I can assure you we will have a very capable leader in charge of our post in Port-au-Prince.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And I have a quick question asking slightly different way. So the prime – Haiti’s prime minister and ambassador said the attackers were foreigners. If that is so, does the U.S. have any measure in place to prevent them from escaping to the United States?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> So this is another investigative question and, unfortunately, the investigation of course is in the early phases. We are ready and willing to support Haitian authorities in that investigation which they are leading, but we will have to refer investigative questions to Haitian authorities, again, reiterating that we are willing to cooperate with any requests they may put forward.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Thanks. Yes. Haiti still?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Anything else on Haiti?</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-AFGHANISTAN"></a> I will come back to you on Afghanistan. Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, thank you. Nazira Azim Karimi, Afghan journalist. As you know, sir, since U.S.-NATO withdraw their soldiers in Afghanistan, it’s very complicated. The Afghan people, they are very worried. And recently, Iran hosted the Taliban and Afghan official for a meeting today. They already had a meeting. Any comment about that? In the meantime, Taliban attacked to Badghis Province. Of course, it’s very dangerous. Do you think that it’s not against the agreement between U.S. and Taliban in Doha, Qatar?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well, when it comes to the Iran-hosted talks, we’re of course aware that Iran has hosted a meeting between the Taliban and the Islamic Republic negotiating teams. This is what we’ve always said, that Afghanistan’s neighbors and countries in the region, they too have a stake in Afghanistan’s future. They need to use their influence in ways that are positive, in ways that are constructive, in ways that promote the cause of peace, in ways that support the people of Afghanistan. We know that regional consensus and support for an Afghan-led, Afghan-owned peace process is important for an enduring peace.</p>
<p>When it comes to the recent violence, this is something obviously we have spoken to quite a bit, and the point remains that no government that might come to power in Afghanistan through the use of force, at the barrel of a gun, will have legitimacy or the support – and that can be especially critical – from the international community, nor would a government that comes to power by force have the support of the people of Afghanistan. And what we ultimately hope to help support and will seek to help support is a just and durable settlement. Every party has an interest in a settlement being durable. The Afghan people are – have been burdened and in many cases brutalized by 40 years of civil war. The United States is supporting the efforts ongoing in Doha right now between the parties, where the parties are, in fact, still meeting, still talking, to see to it that we can have a just and durable settlement and a comprehensive ceasefire to finally see an end to this violence.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I understand the conference is still postponed. Are you still optimistic?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, obviously the talks in Doha are ongoing. The parties continue to meet in Doha. We’re grateful for Qatar’s role, and Qatar’s role in hosting that talk – those talks. We do welcome Turkey, Qatar, and the UN’s outstanding offer to host negotiations between the parties, but I don’t have any updates to share at that time, especially knowing that talks are ongoing in Doha.</p>
<p>Will. Or – yes. Yes, please. Go ahead, Will.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On Iran.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Any – sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, it’s sort of on Iran. Go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I just follow up briefly? You mentioned about the Iranian role.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I just pursue that a little bit?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> After September 11th, obviously, there’s some coordination between the United States and Iran regarding Afghanistan. What’s your assessment now of Iran’s role in Afghanistan? Are you at all hopeful for a positive – from the U.S. perspective, a positive role for Iran in Afghanistan in the future?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, look, I wouldn’t characterize us hopeful. I wouldn’t characterize us as pessimistic. I would characterize us as knowing that in order for there to be a just and durable peace in Afghanistan, Afghanistan’s neighbors need to play a constructive role. What Iran is trying to do or in the – is in the process of doing by hosting this meeting may well be constructive. I think the jury is still out. This is obviously not something we are – we have discussed with the Iranians other than by making the point very publicly that Afghanistan’s neighbors need to be responsible stakeholders.</p>
<p>For too long, many of Afghanistan’s neighbors have been happy to see the United States engaged, and the United States alone engaged. If there is to be a just and durable settlement and a comprehensive ceasefire, it needs to be supported – supported by Afghanistan’s neighbors, and we hope to see them act responsibly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just on that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-IRAN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Follow-up on Iran.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You mentioned the talks in Vienna yesterday, the interrupted talks. Are you certain those talks are going to resume? Have they hit a snag? You mentioned consultations. What are the consultations about? Is it about the new President-elect Raisi or some of Iran’s behavior in the region or some of the political backdrop and concerns that are bubbling up? Can we absolutely commit that those talks are going to continue, and when do you think we might see that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I would say is I would need to direct you to the Iranians for feedback on their consultations, what’s going on in their capital. I can tell you from our part, the team has been back here at the department meeting with officials throughout the building, including with Secretary Blinken, updating him on the progress of those talks. Of course, nothing is certain in the world of diplomacy, but I think we have every expectation that there will be a seventh round of talks at the appropriate moment, at the right time, and our team looks forward to being engaged in that next round of talks when it does begin.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So can you –the consultations with the U.S. team in its capital, those are finished now?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We are, I think &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Or you’re just waiting for the Europeans to say, okay, come on, guys, let’s go back to Vienna?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, of course the team continues to remain here, continues to engage in discussions, continues to do important work from the department, but that team will be ready, will be prepared to travel back to Vienna when there’s a seventh round of talks.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-LEBANON"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Secretary Blinken met with French and Saudi counterparts on the sidelines of the G20 regarding Lebanon. But apart from his tweet, new, further details have been provided. Tomorrow the U.S. and French ambassadors to Lebanon are heading to Saudi in what seems to be a rare diplomatic move. Where does this trilateral coordination stand and what’s the U.S. – what’s Washington hoping to convey during these meetings?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, you’re right and I can confirm that our Ambassador to Lebanon Dorothy Shea, will in fact travel alongside the French ambassador to Lebanon, Anne Grillo, to Saudi Arabia for meetings with Saudi officials on July 8th. This visit does follow the trilateral consultation that Secretary Blinken had with his French and Saudi counterparts, Foreign Minister Le Drian and Saudi Foreign Minister bin Farhan on June 29th, when we were in Matera for the G20. During her meetings in Saudi Arabia, I expect Ambassador Shea will discuss the gravity of the situation in Lebanon. She’ll emphasize the importance of humanitarian assistance to the Lebanese people as well as increased support for the Lebanese Armed Forces and international – internal security forces, excuse me.</p>
<p>In partnership with her French and Saudi counterparts, Ambassador Shea will also continue to develop that trilateral diplomatic strategy, and that strategy is focused on government formation, it’s focused on the imperative of undertaking urgent and necessary reforms that the people of Lebanon so desperately need. As we have said before, Lebanon’s leaders need to come together, need to do the right thing, need to put aside political bickering and squabbling for the benefit of the Lebanese people.</p>
<p>Ambassador Shea will also use the occasion to reiterate the commitment of the United States to helping the people of Lebanon, and she will highlight some of the good work of the over $3.7 billion in economic, humanitarian, and security assistance that the United States has contributed since 2016 and what that has supported.</p>
<p>Yes, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-SAUDIARABIA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And separately, yesterday you mentioned the Saudi deputy defense minister would be at State today. Could you confirm any meetings he had or will have today and how those discussions went, or what they’re expected to touch on?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure. So as we did confirm yesterday, the Saudi deputy defense – Defense Minister Khalid bin Salman is in Washington for a series of meetings. He has so far met with our special envoy for the Horn of Africa, Ambassador Feltman. He’s also met with Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking. In terms of the former, Special Envoy Feltman and KBS discussed the situation in Ethiopia, in areas where the United States and Saudi Arabia could potentially cooperate to address the crisis and to mitigate instability in the broader region. They also agreed to continue a dialogue on mechanisms to promote peace, security, and prosperity in the Red Sea. As you know, Ambassador Feltman was recently in the Gulf discussing the situation in the Horn of Africa, and this was a continuation of that.</p>
<p>With Special Envoy Lenderking, he took part in a meeting yesterday to discuss steps to mitigate the ongoing humanitarian crisis in Yemen and steps necessary to end the conflict there, including steps that would ease restrictions at Hudaydah port and Sana’a Airport. Special Envoy Lenderking stressed the need for continued Saudi engagement on Yemen, allowing space for nationwide comprehensive ceasefire followed by a transition to a Yemeni political process that would lead to a permanent solution to this conflict.</p>
<p>Additionally, Special Envoy Lenderking recognized Saudi Arabia for its efforts to improve implementation of the Riyadh Agreement, and he agreed that both the Republic of Yemen Government and the Southern Transition Council must continue to negotiate so that the Yemeni Government can return to Aden to provide the essential services the Yemeni people need and deserve. The deputy defense minister will be in the building later today. He’ll be meeting with a couple senior State Department officials during that session.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Is he &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And with the Secretary?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I expect the Secretary will have a chance to take part in part of that meeting, yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>When you talk about urgent and necessary reforms needed in Lebanon, could you give us an example or two of what the most urgent and most necessary reforms are?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, it’s certainly urgent that Lebanon’s leaders set aside their political differences to form a government that is cohesive and a government that is responsive to the needs of the international people. Corruption, impunity, lawlessness have dogged successive governments, and ultimately and most importantly have drained the Lebanese people of much needed resources. So as an initial and necessary step, Lebanon’s leaders need to put the interests of their people first. That’s what we’re calling for. That’s what we hope to see.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But does that mean – I mean, what you talked about, ending or at least trying to fight corruption and the other – impunity and that kind of thing, those are pretty tall orders and can’t be really done overnight. So am I wrong in thinking that what you’re saying is that the first order of business needs to be the formation of a new government that is – that represents and can respond to the demands of the people?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It’s – it’s &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is that the first thing that needs to be done?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It’s certainly necessary, but not sufficient. We know that Lebanon’s leaders, to the point of government formation, need to show flexibility to form a government that is willing and capable of true and fundamental reform. And this gets to the next step. Government formation is one element, but true and necessary reform is the next, again, so that the people of Lebanon can realize that full potential. They deserve, they need a government that will urgently implement those necessary reforms, including to rescue Lebanon’s deteriorating economy. Lebanon’s economy and the economic condition of the country has imposed huge costs, huge burdens on the people of Lebanon. The inflation that has occurred in recent days and weeks has taken a really profound toll on the people there.</p>
<p>And so, yes, government formation is necessary, but yes, so too is reform.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Did the Secretary discuss Lebanon with the pope when he saw him last week?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I – we issued a readout of that meeting. As I do recall, it was addressed, but I would have to refer you to that readout.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-IRAQ"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just ask about Iraq? There has been quite a bit of an increase in rocket attacks. Iraqi army officials say the pace of recent attacks against U.S. bases and with rockets and drones is unprecedented. Why do you think that is on the rise at this particular moment? What is your assessment on who is behind it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I’d have to correct one thing you said. There are no U.S. bases in Iraq.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sorry.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There are a limited number of U.S. and other coalition advisors &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> U.S. and coalition, yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; at Iraqi bases, at Iraqi Government invitation that, in turn, assist and enable Iraqi Security Forces to confront the remnants of ISIS. Look, I wouldn’t want to speak to the motivation of these attacks. I will say that what we recognize is that these attacks reflect and are representative of the threat that Iran-backed militias present fundamentally to Iraq’s sovereignty and to Iraq’s stability. We &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you know for a fact that they’re carried out by Iranian-backed militias, these attacks over the past couple of days?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So obviously there have been recent attacks, and I wouldn’t want to prejudge investigations that are ongoing. But as we have said in the context of attacks that have taken place in recent months, they have been carried out by Iran-backed militias and President Biden, in turn, has responded – responded in different ways. But of course, perhaps most visibly, by authorizing the military strikes – most recently late last month, but also before that as well – on Iran-backed militia infrastructure in Iraq and Syria.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-BRAZIL"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. I want to confirm information that I got from Brazilian Government. Is the U.S. planning to send more vaccines directly to Brazil in the coming two weeks? If yes, how many vaccines? And when are they getting to Brazil? And also, I would like to know when is the U.S. planning to pick the new ambassador to Brazil and what is the profile that you are looking for, if a political pick or a diplomat – a career diplomat?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, to your first question, we were very pleased to have been able to deliver 3 million doses of Johnson &amp; Johnson COVID vaccines that arrived in Campinas, Brazil, late last month – June 25th I believe it was. Presently, as you know, we’re working to support the delivery of the 80 million doses from our own supply that President Biden pledged to allocate last month, mid-last month. We’ll donate additional doses throughout the summer months as supply becomes available.</p>
<p>In doing so, our principles are standard and transparent, and that includes maximizing the number of safe and effective vaccines available equitably for the greatest number of countries and for those most at risk within their countries. It includes preparing for surges and prioritizing health care workers and other vulnerable populations based on public health data and acknowledged best practices, and helping countries in need, including our neighbors. And, of course, Brazil is an important partner of ours in the hemisphere. We have provided non-vaccine support to Brazil in the context of the COVID pandemic as well.</p>
<p>And that brings me to your second question. Because Brazil is such an important partner of the United States, while I can’t give you a name or I can’t give you a timeframe, I assure you that the next U.S. ambassador to Brazil will be someone who has the trust and confidence of Secretary Blinken and the trust and confidence of President Biden. That person will be charged with an incredibly important relationship, and as soon as we have more details, we’ll be sure to share them.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But is there a timeline for this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That’s as opposed to ambassadors to other countries, who don’t have the – who don’t have the support and – of the President?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I’m – I am speaking in the context of Brazil, an important partner.</p>
<p>Rich in the back.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-CHINA2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. Indo-Pacific coordinator Kurt Campbell said that any Chinese move against Taiwan would be catastrophic and that this administration is sending a clear message of deterrence. China’s Foreign Ministry today responded, warning the U.S. to tread carefully on this issue. Can we expect the U.S. to continue to send this clear message of deterrence or perhaps an even clearer message of deterrence going forward?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the United States will continue to support a peaceful resolution of cross-strait issues, consistent with the longstanding wishes and the best interests of the people on Taiwan. And we have repeatedly urged Beijing to cease its military, its diplomatic, its economic pressure against Taiwan and instead to engage in meaningful dialogue with Taiwan. Secretary Blinken has addressed the question. He has repeatedly said it would be a profound mistake by any party to try and remake that status quo with the use of force. Our commitment to Taiwan is rock solid, and we believe that commitment contributes to the maintenance of peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait and within the broader region.</p>
<p>For four decades, American policy has been consistent. The “one China” policy is guided by the Taiwan Relations Act, the Three Joint Communiques, the Six Assurances provided to Taipei. That has not changed. As you know, Rich, we also did unveil a couple months ago now updated contact guidance that will allow us to deepen our partnership with the people on Taiwan, consistent with that “one China” policy, the Taiwan Relations Act, the Three Joint Communiques, and the Six Assurances.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is the U.S. seeing any evidence that Beijing is ready to cease this pressure?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I wouldn’t want to characterize discussions with Beijing or any other country on this. What I will characterize is what we are making very clear, and that is that our commitment to Taiwan is rock solid. We believe it is in the best interests of the people on Taiwan and the broader region as well.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-UAESAUDIARABIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, any comment on the dispute between the UAE and Saudi (inaudible) over oil and OPEC Plus?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I believe you’ve heard from the White House on this, and I think they had an opportunity to discuss this again yesterday. U.S. officials are closely monitoring these talks, closely watching the progress. We’ve been in touch with several of the parties involved.</p>
<p>Let me move it around. Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-SYRIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On Syria, can you give us an update on negotiations on the cross-border resolution? And given that this is an issue that comes up year after year, has the Biden administration as part of its Syria policy given any consideration to finding a longer-term solution to aid delivery?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So to your second question, this is to us not a question about geopolitics or bilateral relations with any other member of the UN Security Council or political dynamics on the council. To us, this is a – fundamentally a question of the humanitarian interests of the Syrian people. This boils down to a question of livelihoods and a question of lives for the people of Syria, and that’s why we are and have been acting so urgently now that there are just a few days left until the last remaining humanitarian crossing is set to expire. We’ve been very clear, again, because of the human stakes, the human – the potential human costs of this – millions of Syrians – women, children, men – that the Security Council must renew and expand humanitarian access provided by Bab al-Hawa for 12 months. And we know we must do it now because, of course, the expiration is coming up.</p>
<p>The people of Syria have been brutalized by the Assad regime. They have been further buffeted by the COVID pandemic. What we seek to do – and again, this is not about politics. This is not about geopolitics. This is not about inter-state relations. This is not about great powers. But what we seek to do is to help the people of Syria, millions of whom are at risk of starvation if this last remaining humanitarian crossing is shamefully and tragically allowed to expire.</p>
<p>These discussions have been ongoing at the UN. Of course, Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield spoke to this yesterday. She has been engaged privately with the Security Council. And I have every expectation that she will continue to be engaged, as will the broader department and the fuller administration.</p>
<p>As you know, this was one of the issues that President Biden raised directly with President Putin at the summit, again, putting it in terms not of great – not in terms of inter-state relations, but in terms of the human costs and the human toll of this.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On that, has the U.S. actually made any progress in convincing Russia to agree to a renewal?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I wouldn’t want to characterize discussions that have been behind closed doors. I would refer you to the Russian Federation for their position on this. But I think it goes without saying that any responsible country should be in favor of saving lives, and this is what this is about.</p>
<p>Yes, (inaudible).</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-PAKISTAN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, another question about Pakistan policy. Last week, Prime Minister Imran Khan was a little mad and he said that – he criticized United States that United States had been defeated in Afghanistan and he will not allow CIA base in Pakistan. And also he mentioned that we will not anymore control or – yes, control on Pakistan anymore if – if Taliban try to get the power by force, we will not support them. And I don’t know what’s the relationship. Still Pakistan has influence as to Taliban to bring them on the table in this sensitive time in Doha?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I think what is true is that Pakistan is an important partner across any number of fronts. Of course, we have shared interests when it comes to Afghanistan, when it comes to peace and stability in Afghanistan. We have – and this goes over the course of successive administrations now – encouraged Pakistan to be a constructive partner when it comes to Afghanistan and our collective efforts to bring about some semblance of peace and security there. Pakistan has been helpful in – recently when it comes to this shared interest. Our shared interests go well beyond that: broader counterterrorism interests as well, not to mention the people-to-people ties that unite our two countries.</p>
<p>But this also goes back to I think where we started with your earlier question, that what we know to be true is that all of Afghanistan’s neighbors need to play a constructive role in helping to bring about a just and durable political settlement as well as a comprehensive ceasefire. For far too long, some of Afghanistan’s neighbors have not played that role. They had been happy to let – content, I should say, to let other countries take responsibility. And right now, we have made clear that we are going to be working very closely to ensure that Afghanistan’s neighbors do play that constructive role, knowing that it will be a necessary ingredient to what I think we all collectively hope to see in Afghanistan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes, Shaun.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-CHINA3"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Different issue, on China, WeChat, the popular social media forum. There have been reports that there have been the deletion of LGBTQ content from WeChat. Do you have any comment on that? Does this signal at all a worsening of the climate for sexual minorities in China?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we are aware of reports that WeChat has deleted several accounts carrying public views of LGBTQI+ topics, and we’re concerned by – that the PRC has restricted the social media accounts of LGBTQI+ student groups and NGOs that were merely expressing their views, exercising their right to freedom of expression and freedom of speech. We oppose the use of network restrictions to suppress freedom of expression online. It does not matter to us whether that it is in China or anywhere else; we oppose it universally. U.S. content moderation issues are addressed in line with the strong protections under U.S. law that align with international standards for, as I said before, that very freedom of expression. And we encourage other governments to develop similar policies respecting freedom of expression.</p>
<p>More broadly, we&#8217;re committed to fighting for the human rights of all people. And that, of course, includes LGBTQI+ people around the world. This administration is taking measures to ensure that U.S. diplomacy promotes and protects those rights. As you know, on February 5th, President Biden signed a presidential memorandum making it the policy of the United States to protect and to promote LGBTQI+ rights around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, does that – when you talk about universality of this and you oppose the use of network restrictions to block any content related &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, I didn&#8217;t say any content. I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Consistent with the rights of freedom of expression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Right. Okay. Well – and I know this is the State Department and you don&#8217;t – but you do speak on behalf of the administration. But domestically, today, I think somewhere out there a certain former president has filed lawsuits against several companies that are similar to WeChat and what they do for blocking his – so if that was taking place, if that kind of thing was taking place in a foreign – in another country where you had a remit or a responsibility, would you – would you oppose those kinds of restrictions by private companies on free speech?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt, we believe deeply in the principle of freedom of expression, whether that is at home, whether that is around the world. Obviously, your question has a political tint to it, so I will &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I didn’t mean to be – have a political tint. It’s just that it&#8217;s kind of an obvious question to ask, even if the State Department doesn&#8217;t do things domestically. But when you speak on behalf of the administration and talk about the President signing legislation that applies domestically, I just wonder if this is the kind – if there was censorship of political views on the left or the right in another country, you would oppose it, correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well – well, what I mentioned was a presidential memorandum that contours our foreign policy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, no, no, I get that. But if you saw this kind of – when you&#8217;re talking about WeChat, if that was restrictions on political views either on the left or right or radical centrists – I don&#8217;t know, whoever – you would oppose it, correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Freedom of expression is something that we protect and that we promote around the world. The right of people everywhere to live in safety and security is also something we believe deeply in. When it comes to U.S. social media companies or internet service providers, I&#8217;d have to refer you to them to speak to their policies.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:41 p.m.)</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>2:56 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, a very Lurch-like “good afternoon.” No?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I just want to make sure everyone is paying attention.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-HAITI"></a> I obviously want to stop – start with the situation in Haiti. The United States strongly condemns, as you heard from President Biden earlier today, the assassination of President Jovenel Moise and the attack on First Lady Martine Moise in Haiti. We extend our deepest condolences to President Moise’s family and his loved ones and to the people of Haiti in the midst of this tragedy.</p>
<p>Those who seek to accomplish their political goals through violence and by subverting the rule of law will not succeed in thwarting the Haitian people and their desire for a better – for a brighter future. We urge Haitian authorities to bring those responsible to justice. The United States calls on all political parties, civil society groups, and stakeholders to echo what we’ve heard from Acting Prime Minister Claude Joseph’s call for calm and to work together in the wake of this tragedy to ensure peace and democratic governance.</p>
<p>So with that, I am happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-CHINA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So I – just before returning to Haiti, I got a extremely brief thing. It’s something else, but it’s a logistical thing, kind of, and that is the Hong Kong consulate, which has been closed for a couple days now because of a COVID case. Do – has that spread, do you know? Is there anything more you can say about that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m not in a position &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And I only ask this now because I’m going to forget about it if I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I understand. I’m not in a position to offer an update on the operating status there. As you know, our embassies and posts around the world are constantly calibrating their operations given the state of COVID or any other issue that may affect the workforce. But I don’t have an update to offer.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-HAITI2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. On Haiti, then. Is there any – this isn’t exactly – it’s bad, but it’s not exactly a coup. I mean, it’s a – not a – the government hasn’t been overthrown or anything like that. So is there any implication, assistance-wise, or any other wise, for Haiti related to – the administration policy towards Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There is – Acting Prime Minister Claude Joseph has assumed charge. What we know and what we will continue to do is to preserve Haiti’s democratic institutions. We know that by preserving Haiti’s democratic institutions, that is key to restoring peace. At this time, we don’t have any updates to announce in terms of our assistance, but I can assure you that our partnership with the Haitian people and with their elected government will continue. As you know, that partnership has taken many forms in recent months; in, of course, recent years. In January of this year we announced 75.5 million for – in support for a wide range of issues, and that includes democratic governance, health, education, agricultural development, strengthening pre-election activities through the Consortium for Elections and Political Process Strengthening program.</p>
<p>We have also been a strong partner for Haiti and the Haitian people when it comes to security and when it comes to law enforcement as well. And much of that has been overseen by our Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs. They have provided direct assistance to the Haitian National Police over the years, and as a direct result of this INL support the Haitian National Police have trained officers from a number that was less than 10,000 in 2010 to nearly 15,000 Haitian National Police officers today. We have continued to encourage Haiti to take a holistic approach to countering violence and to countering gangs, and we provided $5 million to strengthen the Haitian National Police’s capacity to work with communities to resist gangs as well.</p>
<p>And I would remiss if I didn’t note our support to Haiti’s pre-election activities. And USAID is providing more than $3 million to the consortium I mentioned before. And those activities for which these funds are earmarked include focusing on improving electoral administration, strengthening the competitiveness of political parties, educating voters on electoral processes, promoting electoral transparency, and ensuring inclusive voter participation as well. So this is just one – these are just several metrics of our support for the Haitian people, and that will not waver in the wake of this.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Given, Ned, the history of U.S. intervention in Haiti – it’s been numerous times over the course of the last century and a half – is there any appetite in this administration for some kind of – to intervene if the situation gets to be dire? This is a relatively close neighbor that has in the past seen massive outflows of people trying to escape, so if it – the situation deteriorates – and I realize this is a hypothetical – but is there any appetite for a return?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> To us, Matt &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; Haiti is a partner, and that is how we will treat this relationship. It is how we have treated Haiti, it is how we will going forward. We would echo what we have heard from the acting prime minister, Claude Joseph, in his calls for calm, his calls for the Haitian people to work together to ensure peace, to ensure democratic government. The United States has and will continue to stand by to provide assistance to the Haitian people.</p>
<p>Humeyra.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So on Haiti, the ambassador told us that they – he has been in touch with the State Department and a number of different agencies in U.S. Government. Can you at least say – you just said that you can’t give an update on the U.S. assistance, but can you at least say perhaps a new package is being formed and you guys are working on something new on top of these quite little numbers – $5 million, $3 million – that you’ve just mentioned?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> $75.5 million.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. I missed that, sorry.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have been in regular contact with the acting prime minister, Claude Joseph. We are prepared to respond to requests for assistance. Our ambassador to Haiti, Ambassador Sison, has been in regular contact with a range of Haitian officials. She has spoken to the acting director general of the Haitian National Police. Of course, Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield at the UN this morning spoke to Haiti’s permanent representative to the UN. We have been, as I said before, in regular contact.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken started his day this morning with a comprehensive update on the situation on the ground, including the latest developments as we knew them at the time, the security situation. He was briefed by Ambassador Sison, who at this moment happens to be in Washington. He was also on the phone with the DCM, who is on the ground in Haiti right now, DCM Nicole Theriot, as well as other members of his team. So we are prepared to receive additional requests for assistance from Haitian authorities.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you also confirm if first lady is being flown to Miami for – to receive medical treatment?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we, of course, are familiar with the reports that the First Lady Martine Moise was injured in the attack. We know that she was taken to receive medical treatment. Out of respect for her privacy, we’re not in a position to comment on – to provide further comment. But as I said, we have made very clear to Haitian authorities the United States is standing ready to provide assistance and we are prepared to provide any and all forms of appropriate assistance to our Haitian partners.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you speak to the DEA element of all of this? You – the ambassador also talked about this footage where they’re identifying themselves as DEA agents, and he said that he doesn’t believe in it. I mean, can you say that that’s not the case, that you have an assessment that those are not DEA officials? Can you sort of set the record straight on that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, as you said, the Haitian ambassador himself has dismissed these allegations. These reports are absolutely false. The United States condemns this heinous act. These false reports are nothing more than that, just false reports.</p>
<p>Shaun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I just follow up on that? Is there any sense of what the motivation would have been for this? And is – do you think there’s any truth to what the government – to what the acting government is saying, that these were mercenaries, that these were foreigners who were in there?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, Shaun, we just don’t have clear answers at the – at this time. What we do know and what I have said is that Haitian authorities are investigating. We stand ready to offer assistance to that investigation, but obviously, we’re going to let that investigation play out. And, of course, the Haitian authorities are in the lead on that investigation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just one more thing on that. You – earlier this year, you were mentioning about the elections in Haiti and you called for them to go on – go ahead and schedule later this year. Is it still the view of the United States that elections in September are a good idea?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It is still the view of the United States that elections this year should proceed. We know that free and fair elections are the democratic path towards ending Haiti’s irregular and prolonged rule by decree and restoring its parliament, which as of now has lapsed. Free and fair presidential elections will facilitate a peaceful transfer of power to a newly elected president as well.</p>
<p>We’ve – as you know and as you have heard me say and others say, we have urged Haitian Government and political stakeholders repeatedly both in public and in private to reach a political accord in order to ensure those legislative and presidential elections take place later this year.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. Nazira Karimi, Afghan independent journalist.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can we stay on Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Sure. Let’s stay on Haiti for just a moment.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> I will come back to you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I change the subject?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well, we’ll – I’ll come back to you if that’s okay.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We’ll take a couple more on Haiti.</p>
<p>Will.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, just two questions on Haiti. I want to ask this a slightly different way. Can you confirm that there currently is a pending request for defense equipment from Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We expect to be in receipt of formal requests. We stand ready to receive them. But as of right now, I’m not in a position to confirm that we’ve received a formal request.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. And what was the administration’s position on the president’s legitimacy as a leader of the country? Obviously, the opposition says his five-year term expired last February.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> The Haitian constitution is clear on this point. As we’ve said, we’ve supported elections later this year. We still support those elections later this year, believing and knowing that President Moise’s term was to end next year.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Quick question on Haiti. The current U.S. ambassador to Haiti has been nominated to a different position in the State Department. Is there any plan to speed up the process to naming a new ambassador to that country?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well, as you know, Ambassador Sison is still in that role. She was actually supposed to travel back to Haiti today after consultations here in Washington. She expects to go back to Haiti just as soon as she is able to travel there. We also are very fortunate to have a very capable DCM in Haiti, Nicole Theriot, whom I mentioned before. So if and when Ambassador Sison moves on to her next role, I can assure you we will have a very capable leader in charge of our post in Port-au-Prince.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And I have a quick question asking slightly different way. So the prime – Haiti’s prime minister and ambassador said the attackers were foreigners. If that is so, does the U.S. have any measure in place to prevent them from escaping to the United States?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> So this is another investigative question and, unfortunately, the investigation of course is in the early phases. We are ready and willing to support Haitian authorities in that investigation which they are leading, but we will have to refer investigative questions to Haitian authorities, again, reiterating that we are willing to cooperate with any requests they may put forward.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Thanks. Yes. Haiti still?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Anything else on Haiti?</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-AFGHANISTAN"></a> I will come back to you on Afghanistan. Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, thank you. Nazira Azim Karimi, Afghan journalist. As you know, sir, since U.S.-NATO withdraw their soldiers in Afghanistan, it’s very complicated. The Afghan people, they are very worried. And recently, Iran hosted the Taliban and Afghan official for a meeting today. They already had a meeting. Any comment about that? In the meantime, Taliban attacked to Badghis Province. Of course, it’s very dangerous. Do you think that it’s not against the agreement between U.S. and Taliban in Doha, Qatar?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well, when it comes to the Iran-hosted talks, we’re of course aware that Iran has hosted a meeting between the Taliban and the Islamic Republic negotiating teams. This is what we’ve always said, that Afghanistan’s neighbors and countries in the region, they too have a stake in Afghanistan’s future. They need to use their influence in ways that are positive, in ways that are constructive, in ways that promote the cause of peace, in ways that support the people of Afghanistan. We know that regional consensus and support for an Afghan-led, Afghan-owned peace process is important for an enduring peace.</p>
<p>When it comes to the recent violence, this is something obviously we have spoken to quite a bit, and the point remains that no government that might come to power in Afghanistan through the use of force, at the barrel of a gun, will have legitimacy or the support – and that can be especially critical – from the international community, nor would a government that comes to power by force have the support of the people of Afghanistan. And what we ultimately hope to help support and will seek to help support is a just and durable settlement. Every party has an interest in a settlement being durable. The Afghan people are – have been burdened and in many cases brutalized by 40 years of civil war. The United States is supporting the efforts ongoing in Doha right now between the parties, where the parties are, in fact, still meeting, still talking, to see to it that we can have a just and durable settlement and a comprehensive ceasefire to finally see an end to this violence.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I understand the conference is still postponed. Are you still optimistic?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, obviously the talks in Doha are ongoing. The parties continue to meet in Doha. We’re grateful for Qatar’s role, and Qatar’s role in hosting that talk – those talks. We do welcome Turkey, Qatar, and the UN’s outstanding offer to host negotiations between the parties, but I don’t have any updates to share at that time, especially knowing that talks are ongoing in Doha.</p>
<p>Will. Or – yes. Yes, please. Go ahead, Will.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On Iran.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Any – sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, it’s sort of on Iran. Go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I just follow up briefly? You mentioned about the Iranian role.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I just pursue that a little bit?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> After September 11th, obviously, there’s some coordination between the United States and Iran regarding Afghanistan. What’s your assessment now of Iran’s role in Afghanistan? Are you at all hopeful for a positive – from the U.S. perspective, a positive role for Iran in Afghanistan in the future?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, look, I wouldn’t characterize us hopeful. I wouldn’t characterize us as pessimistic. I would characterize us as knowing that in order for there to be a just and durable peace in Afghanistan, Afghanistan’s neighbors need to play a constructive role. What Iran is trying to do or in the – is in the process of doing by hosting this meeting may well be constructive. I think the jury is still out. This is obviously not something we are – we have discussed with the Iranians other than by making the point very publicly that Afghanistan’s neighbors need to be responsible stakeholders.</p>
<p>For too long, many of Afghanistan’s neighbors have been happy to see the United States engaged, and the United States alone engaged. If there is to be a just and durable settlement and a comprehensive ceasefire, it needs to be supported – supported by Afghanistan’s neighbors, and we hope to see them act responsibly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just on that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-IRAN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Follow-up on Iran.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You mentioned the talks in Vienna yesterday, the interrupted talks. Are you certain those talks are going to resume? Have they hit a snag? You mentioned consultations. What are the consultations about? Is it about the new President-elect Raisi or some of Iran’s behavior in the region or some of the political backdrop and concerns that are bubbling up? Can we absolutely commit that those talks are going to continue, and when do you think we might see that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I would say is I would need to direct you to the Iranians for feedback on their consultations, what’s going on in their capital. I can tell you from our part, the team has been back here at the department meeting with officials throughout the building, including with Secretary Blinken, updating him on the progress of those talks. Of course, nothing is certain in the world of diplomacy, but I think we have every expectation that there will be a seventh round of talks at the appropriate moment, at the right time, and our team looks forward to being engaged in that next round of talks when it does begin.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So can you –the consultations with the U.S. team in its capital, those are finished now?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We are, I think &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Or you’re just waiting for the Europeans to say, okay, come on, guys, let’s go back to Vienna?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, of course the team continues to remain here, continues to engage in discussions, continues to do important work from the department, but that team will be ready, will be prepared to travel back to Vienna when there’s a seventh round of talks.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-LEBANON"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Secretary Blinken met with French and Saudi counterparts on the sidelines of the G20 regarding Lebanon. But apart from his tweet, new, further details have been provided. Tomorrow the U.S. and French ambassadors to Lebanon are heading to Saudi in what seems to be a rare diplomatic move. Where does this trilateral coordination stand and what’s the U.S. – what’s Washington hoping to convey during these meetings?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, you’re right and I can confirm that our Ambassador to Lebanon Dorothy Shea, will in fact travel alongside the French ambassador to Lebanon, Anne Grillo, to Saudi Arabia for meetings with Saudi officials on July 8th. This visit does follow the trilateral consultation that Secretary Blinken had with his French and Saudi counterparts, Foreign Minister Le Drian and Saudi Foreign Minister bin Farhan on June 29th, when we were in Matera for the G20. During her meetings in Saudi Arabia, I expect Ambassador Shea will discuss the gravity of the situation in Lebanon. She’ll emphasize the importance of humanitarian assistance to the Lebanese people as well as increased support for the Lebanese Armed Forces and international – internal security forces, excuse me.</p>
<p>In partnership with her French and Saudi counterparts, Ambassador Shea will also continue to develop that trilateral diplomatic strategy, and that strategy is focused on government formation, it’s focused on the imperative of undertaking urgent and necessary reforms that the people of Lebanon so desperately need. As we have said before, Lebanon’s leaders need to come together, need to do the right thing, need to put aside political bickering and squabbling for the benefit of the Lebanese people.</p>
<p>Ambassador Shea will also use the occasion to reiterate the commitment of the United States to helping the people of Lebanon, and she will highlight some of the good work of the over $3.7 billion in economic, humanitarian, and security assistance that the United States has contributed since 2016 and what that has supported.</p>
<p>Yes, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-SAUDIARABIA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And separately, yesterday you mentioned the Saudi deputy defense minister would be at State today. Could you confirm any meetings he had or will have today and how those discussions went, or what they’re expected to touch on?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure. So as we did confirm yesterday, the Saudi deputy defense – Defense Minister Khalid bin Salman is in Washington for a series of meetings. He has so far met with our special envoy for the Horn of Africa, Ambassador Feltman. He’s also met with Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking. In terms of the former, Special Envoy Feltman and KBS discussed the situation in Ethiopia, in areas where the United States and Saudi Arabia could potentially cooperate to address the crisis and to mitigate instability in the broader region. They also agreed to continue a dialogue on mechanisms to promote peace, security, and prosperity in the Red Sea. As you know, Ambassador Feltman was recently in the Gulf discussing the situation in the Horn of Africa, and this was a continuation of that.</p>
<p>With Special Envoy Lenderking, he took part in a meeting yesterday to discuss steps to mitigate the ongoing humanitarian crisis in Yemen and steps necessary to end the conflict there, including steps that would ease restrictions at Hudaydah port and Sana’a Airport. Special Envoy Lenderking stressed the need for continued Saudi engagement on Yemen, allowing space for nationwide comprehensive ceasefire followed by a transition to a Yemeni political process that would lead to a permanent solution to this conflict.</p>
<p>Additionally, Special Envoy Lenderking recognized Saudi Arabia for its efforts to improve implementation of the Riyadh Agreement, and he agreed that both the Republic of Yemen Government and the Southern Transition Council must continue to negotiate so that the Yemeni Government can return to Aden to provide the essential services the Yemeni people need and deserve. The deputy defense minister will be in the building later today. He’ll be meeting with a couple senior State Department officials during that session.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Is he &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And with the Secretary?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I expect the Secretary will have a chance to take part in part of that meeting, yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>When you talk about urgent and necessary reforms needed in Lebanon, could you give us an example or two of what the most urgent and most necessary reforms are?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, it’s certainly urgent that Lebanon’s leaders set aside their political differences to form a government that is cohesive and a government that is responsive to the needs of the international people. Corruption, impunity, lawlessness have dogged successive governments, and ultimately and most importantly have drained the Lebanese people of much needed resources. So as an initial and necessary step, Lebanon’s leaders need to put the interests of their people first. That’s what we’re calling for. That’s what we hope to see.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But does that mean – I mean, what you talked about, ending or at least trying to fight corruption and the other – impunity and that kind of thing, those are pretty tall orders and can’t be really done overnight. So am I wrong in thinking that what you’re saying is that the first order of business needs to be the formation of a new government that is – that represents and can respond to the demands of the people?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It’s – it’s &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is that the first thing that needs to be done?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It’s certainly necessary, but not sufficient. We know that Lebanon’s leaders, to the point of government formation, need to show flexibility to form a government that is willing and capable of true and fundamental reform. And this gets to the next step. Government formation is one element, but true and necessary reform is the next, again, so that the people of Lebanon can realize that full potential. They deserve, they need a government that will urgently implement those necessary reforms, including to rescue Lebanon’s deteriorating economy. Lebanon’s economy and the economic condition of the country has imposed huge costs, huge burdens on the people of Lebanon. The inflation that has occurred in recent days and weeks has taken a really profound toll on the people there.</p>
<p>And so, yes, government formation is necessary, but yes, so too is reform.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Did the Secretary discuss Lebanon with the pope when he saw him last week?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I – we issued a readout of that meeting. As I do recall, it was addressed, but I would have to refer you to that readout.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-IRAQ"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just ask about Iraq? There has been quite a bit of an increase in rocket attacks. Iraqi army officials say the pace of recent attacks against U.S. bases and with rockets and drones is unprecedented. Why do you think that is on the rise at this particular moment? What is your assessment on who is behind it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I’d have to correct one thing you said. There are no U.S. bases in Iraq.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sorry.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There are a limited number of U.S. and other coalition advisors &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> U.S. and coalition, yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; at Iraqi bases, at Iraqi Government invitation that, in turn, assist and enable Iraqi Security Forces to confront the remnants of ISIS. Look, I wouldn’t want to speak to the motivation of these attacks. I will say that what we recognize is that these attacks reflect and are representative of the threat that Iran-backed militias present fundamentally to Iraq’s sovereignty and to Iraq’s stability. We &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you know for a fact that they’re carried out by Iranian-backed militias, these attacks over the past couple of days?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So obviously there have been recent attacks, and I wouldn’t want to prejudge investigations that are ongoing. But as we have said in the context of attacks that have taken place in recent months, they have been carried out by Iran-backed militias and President Biden, in turn, has responded – responded in different ways. But of course, perhaps most visibly, by authorizing the military strikes – most recently late last month, but also before that as well – on Iran-backed militia infrastructure in Iraq and Syria.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-BRAZIL"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. I want to confirm information that I got from Brazilian Government. Is the U.S. planning to send more vaccines directly to Brazil in the coming two weeks? If yes, how many vaccines? And when are they getting to Brazil? And also, I would like to know when is the U.S. planning to pick the new ambassador to Brazil and what is the profile that you are looking for, if a political pick or a diplomat – a career diplomat?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, to your first question, we were very pleased to have been able to deliver 3 million doses of Johnson &amp; Johnson COVID vaccines that arrived in Campinas, Brazil, late last month – June 25th I believe it was. Presently, as you know, we’re working to support the delivery of the 80 million doses from our own supply that President Biden pledged to allocate last month, mid-last month. We’ll donate additional doses throughout the summer months as supply becomes available.</p>
<p>In doing so, our principles are standard and transparent, and that includes maximizing the number of safe and effective vaccines available equitably for the greatest number of countries and for those most at risk within their countries. It includes preparing for surges and prioritizing health care workers and other vulnerable populations based on public health data and acknowledged best practices, and helping countries in need, including our neighbors. And, of course, Brazil is an important partner of ours in the hemisphere. We have provided non-vaccine support to Brazil in the context of the COVID pandemic as well.</p>
<p>And that brings me to your second question. Because Brazil is such an important partner of the United States, while I can’t give you a name or I can’t give you a timeframe, I assure you that the next U.S. ambassador to Brazil will be someone who has the trust and confidence of Secretary Blinken and the trust and confidence of President Biden. That person will be charged with an incredibly important relationship, and as soon as we have more details, we’ll be sure to share them.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But is there a timeline for this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That’s as opposed to ambassadors to other countries, who don’t have the – who don’t have the support and – of the President?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I’m – I am speaking in the context of Brazil, an important partner.</p>
<p>Rich in the back.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-CHINA2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. Indo-Pacific coordinator Kurt Campbell said that any Chinese move against Taiwan would be catastrophic and that this administration is sending a clear message of deterrence. China’s Foreign Ministry today responded, warning the U.S. to tread carefully on this issue. Can we expect the U.S. to continue to send this clear message of deterrence or perhaps an even clearer message of deterrence going forward?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the United States will continue to support a peaceful resolution of cross-strait issues, consistent with the longstanding wishes and the best interests of the people on Taiwan. And we have repeatedly urged Beijing to cease its military, its diplomatic, its economic pressure against Taiwan and instead to engage in meaningful dialogue with Taiwan. Secretary Blinken has addressed the question. He has repeatedly said it would be a profound mistake by any party to try and remake that status quo with the use of force. Our commitment to Taiwan is rock solid, and we believe that commitment contributes to the maintenance of peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait and within the broader region.</p>
<p>For four decades, American policy has been consistent. The “one China” policy is guided by the Taiwan Relations Act, the Three Joint Communiques, the Six Assurances provided to Taipei. That has not changed. As you know, Rich, we also did unveil a couple months ago now updated contact guidance that will allow us to deepen our partnership with the people on Taiwan, consistent with that “one China” policy, the Taiwan Relations Act, the Three Joint Communiques, and the Six Assurances.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is the U.S. seeing any evidence that Beijing is ready to cease this pressure?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I wouldn’t want to characterize discussions with Beijing or any other country on this. What I will characterize is what we are making very clear, and that is that our commitment to Taiwan is rock solid. We believe it is in the best interests of the people on Taiwan and the broader region as well.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-UAESAUDIARABIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, any comment on the dispute between the UAE and Saudi (inaudible) over oil and OPEC Plus?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I believe you’ve heard from the White House on this, and I think they had an opportunity to discuss this again yesterday. U.S. officials are closely monitoring these talks, closely watching the progress. We’ve been in touch with several of the parties involved.</p>
<p>Let me move it around. Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-SYRIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On Syria, can you give us an update on negotiations on the cross-border resolution? And given that this is an issue that comes up year after year, has the Biden administration as part of its Syria policy given any consideration to finding a longer-term solution to aid delivery?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So to your second question, this is to us not a question about geopolitics or bilateral relations with any other member of the UN Security Council or political dynamics on the council. To us, this is a – fundamentally a question of the humanitarian interests of the Syrian people. This boils down to a question of livelihoods and a question of lives for the people of Syria, and that’s why we are and have been acting so urgently now that there are just a few days left until the last remaining humanitarian crossing is set to expire. We’ve been very clear, again, because of the human stakes, the human – the potential human costs of this – millions of Syrians – women, children, men – that the Security Council must renew and expand humanitarian access provided by Bab al-Hawa for 12 months. And we know we must do it now because, of course, the expiration is coming up.</p>
<p>The people of Syria have been brutalized by the Assad regime. They have been further buffeted by the COVID pandemic. What we seek to do – and again, this is not about politics. This is not about geopolitics. This is not about inter-state relations. This is not about great powers. But what we seek to do is to help the people of Syria, millions of whom are at risk of starvation if this last remaining humanitarian crossing is shamefully and tragically allowed to expire.</p>
<p>These discussions have been ongoing at the UN. Of course, Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield spoke to this yesterday. She has been engaged privately with the Security Council. And I have every expectation that she will continue to be engaged, as will the broader department and the fuller administration.</p>
<p>As you know, this was one of the issues that President Biden raised directly with President Putin at the summit, again, putting it in terms not of great – not in terms of inter-state relations, but in terms of the human costs and the human toll of this.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On that, has the U.S. actually made any progress in convincing Russia to agree to a renewal?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I wouldn’t want to characterize discussions that have been behind closed doors. I would refer you to the Russian Federation for their position on this. But I think it goes without saying that any responsible country should be in favor of saving lives, and this is what this is about.</p>
<p>Yes, (inaudible).</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-PAKISTAN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, another question about Pakistan policy. Last week, Prime Minister Imran Khan was a little mad and he said that – he criticized United States that United States had been defeated in Afghanistan and he will not allow CIA base in Pakistan. And also he mentioned that we will not anymore control or – yes, control on Pakistan anymore if – if Taliban try to get the power by force, we will not support them. And I don’t know what’s the relationship. Still Pakistan has influence as to Taliban to bring them on the table in this sensitive time in Doha?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I think what is true is that Pakistan is an important partner across any number of fronts. Of course, we have shared interests when it comes to Afghanistan, when it comes to peace and stability in Afghanistan. We have – and this goes over the course of successive administrations now – encouraged Pakistan to be a constructive partner when it comes to Afghanistan and our collective efforts to bring about some semblance of peace and security there. Pakistan has been helpful in – recently when it comes to this shared interest. Our shared interests go well beyond that: broader counterterrorism interests as well, not to mention the people-to-people ties that unite our two countries.</p>
<p>But this also goes back to I think where we started with your earlier question, that what we know to be true is that all of Afghanistan’s neighbors need to play a constructive role in helping to bring about a just and durable political settlement as well as a comprehensive ceasefire. For far too long, some of Afghanistan’s neighbors have not played that role. They had been happy to let – content, I should say, to let other countries take responsibility. And right now, we have made clear that we are going to be working very closely to ensure that Afghanistan’s neighbors do play that constructive role, knowing that it will be a necessary ingredient to what I think we all collectively hope to see in Afghanistan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes, Shaun.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-CHINA3"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Different issue, on China, WeChat, the popular social media forum. There have been reports that there have been the deletion of LGBTQ content from WeChat. Do you have any comment on that? Does this signal at all a worsening of the climate for sexual minorities in China?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we are aware of reports that WeChat has deleted several accounts carrying public views of LGBTQI+ topics, and we’re concerned by – that the PRC has restricted the social media accounts of LGBTQI+ student groups and NGOs that were merely expressing their views, exercising their right to freedom of expression and freedom of speech. We oppose the use of network restrictions to suppress freedom of expression online. It does not matter to us whether that it is in China or anywhere else; we oppose it universally. U.S. content moderation issues are addressed in line with the strong protections under U.S. law that align with international standards for, as I said before, that very freedom of expression. And we encourage other governments to develop similar policies respecting freedom of expression.</p>
<p>More broadly, we&#8217;re committed to fighting for the human rights of all people. And that, of course, includes LGBTQI+ people around the world. This administration is taking measures to ensure that U.S. diplomacy promotes and protects those rights. As you know, on February 5th, President Biden signed a presidential memorandum making it the policy of the United States to protect and to promote LGBTQI+ rights around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, does that – when you talk about universality of this and you oppose the use of network restrictions to block any content related &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, I didn&#8217;t say any content. I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Consistent with the rights of freedom of expression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Right. Okay. Well – and I know this is the State Department and you don&#8217;t – but you do speak on behalf of the administration. But domestically, today, I think somewhere out there a certain former president has filed lawsuits against several companies that are similar to WeChat and what they do for blocking his – so if that was taking place, if that kind of thing was taking place in a foreign – in another country where you had a remit or a responsibility, would you – would you oppose those kinds of restrictions by private companies on free speech?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt, we believe deeply in the principle of freedom of expression, whether that is at home, whether that is around the world. Obviously, your question has a political tint to it, so I will &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I didn’t mean to be – have a political tint. It’s just that it&#8217;s kind of an obvious question to ask, even if the State Department doesn&#8217;t do things domestically. But when you speak on behalf of the administration and talk about the President signing legislation that applies domestically, I just wonder if this is the kind – if there was censorship of political views on the left or the right in another country, you would oppose it, correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well – well, what I mentioned was a presidential memorandum that contours our foreign policy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, no, no, I get that. But if you saw this kind of – when you&#8217;re talking about WeChat, if that was restrictions on political views either on the left or right or radical centrists – I don&#8217;t know, whoever – you would oppose it, correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Freedom of expression is something that we protect and that we promote around the world. The right of people everywhere to live in safety and security is also something we believe deeply in. When it comes to U.S. social media companies or internet service providers, I&#8217;d have to refer you to them to speak to their policies.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:41 p.m.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
