<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:04:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Troika Statement South Sudan’s 10 Year Independence Anniversary</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/troika-statement-south-sudans-10-year-independence-anniversary/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 14:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=257850</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Troika (United States, United Kingdom, and Norway) congratulates the people of South Sudan on 10 years of independence.  On July 9, 2011, South Sudanese joined together in unity to celebrate the country’s birth.  It was a joyous occasion, filled with hope and possibility.</p>
<p>The first ten years of this young country’s history have seen much suffering, due to conflict related abuses, famine, flooding, and disease.  Yet through it all, the South Sudanese people have shown resilience.  We commend the commitment many have shown in working together to build a brighter future, so it is deeply saddening that the promise of peace and prosperity that independence represented remains unfulfilled.</p>
<p>The Troika has stood with the people of Sudan and South Sudan through decades of struggle and whilst we join those celebrating today, we grieve for those who have suffered and lost loved ones.  Today, millions do not have enough food to feed themselves or their family.  The Troika urges immediate action to ensure access for humanitarian aid and to end violence against South Sudanese and the aid workers who serve them.</p>
<p>Due to the immense suffering caused by the outbreak of war our aid is now primarily humanitarian, but we want to see South Sudan get back on the road to economic and social development.  After all, South Sudan is rich.  Its riches do not just reside in the oil beneath its land or the lumber in its forests.  South Sudan is rich because of the diverse communities of people that make up this young country.  It is on their behalf that we have been a constant supporter of the implementation of the peace agreement.  However, nearly three years since we commended the signing of the agreement, many tasks remain undelivered.  Few of the tangible benefits of peace are seen by ordinary citizens.  The Troika welcomes the progress that has been made but urges the signatories to accept accountability for their commitments and go much further, much faster.</p>
<p>The great challenge now facing South Sudan is to recapture the sense of unity, strength, and hope that prevailed on this day ten years ago.  With reconciliation through compromise and accelerated implementation of the peace agreement, South Sudan can become a peaceful, democratic country, where human rights and the rule of law are respected – a country where all people have food on their table, where businesses prosper, and where the Government truly serves its people.  To realize that vision, both the politically manipulated and localized communal conflict that tears at the fabric of society itself, needs to stop.  Preparations for peaceful, credible, and inclusive elections must begin in earnest; unified forces must be created; transitional justice mechanisms must be fully established; and key financial reforms need to happen as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>The Troika remains eager to work in close partnership with the transitional government to implement fully the revitalized peace agreement.  We are committed to standing with the South Sudanese people as they work toward their aspirations of peace and prosperity.  We urge the political leadership of South Sudan to take the actions needed to build the country the jubilant crowds of 2011 dreamed was possible.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Troika (United States, United Kingdom, and Norway) congratulates the people of South Sudan on 10 years of independence.  On July 9, 2011, South Sudanese joined together in unity to celebrate the country’s birth.  It was a joyous occasion, filled with hope and possibility.</p>
<p>The first ten years of this young country’s history have seen much suffering, due to conflict related abuses, famine, flooding, and disease.  Yet through it all, the South Sudanese people have shown resilience.  We commend the commitment many have shown in working together to build a brighter future, so it is deeply saddening that the promise of peace and prosperity that independence represented remains unfulfilled.</p>
<p>The Troika has stood with the people of Sudan and South Sudan through decades of struggle and whilst we join those celebrating today, we grieve for those who have suffered and lost loved ones.  Today, millions do not have enough food to feed themselves or their family.  The Troika urges immediate action to ensure access for humanitarian aid and to end violence against South Sudanese and the aid workers who serve them.</p>
<p>Due to the immense suffering caused by the outbreak of war our aid is now primarily humanitarian, but we want to see South Sudan get back on the road to economic and social development.  After all, South Sudan is rich.  Its riches do not just reside in the oil beneath its land or the lumber in its forests.  South Sudan is rich because of the diverse communities of people that make up this young country.  It is on their behalf that we have been a constant supporter of the implementation of the peace agreement.  However, nearly three years since we commended the signing of the agreement, many tasks remain undelivered.  Few of the tangible benefits of peace are seen by ordinary citizens.  The Troika welcomes the progress that has been made but urges the signatories to accept accountability for their commitments and go much further, much faster.</p>
<p>The great challenge now facing South Sudan is to recapture the sense of unity, strength, and hope that prevailed on this day ten years ago.  With reconciliation through compromise and accelerated implementation of the peace agreement, South Sudan can become a peaceful, democratic country, where human rights and the rule of law are respected – a country where all people have food on their table, where businesses prosper, and where the Government truly serves its people.  To realize that vision, both the politically manipulated and localized communal conflict that tears at the fabric of society itself, needs to stop.  Preparations for peaceful, credible, and inclusive elections must begin in earnest; unified forces must be created; transitional justice mechanisms must be fully established; and key financial reforms need to happen as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>The Troika remains eager to work in close partnership with the transitional government to implement fully the revitalized peace agreement.  We are committed to standing with the South Sudanese people as they work toward their aspirations of peace and prosperity.  We urge the political leadership of South Sudan to take the actions needed to build the country the jubilant crowds of 2011 dreamed was possible.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry’s Participation in “The Low Carbon City for All”</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-presidential-envoy-for-climate-john-kerrys-participation-in-the-low-carbon-city-for-all/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 12:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=257823</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will participate in the Université de la Ville de Demain’s &#8220;The Low Carbon City for All&#8221; summit in France on July 8, 2021.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will participate in the Université de la Ville de Demain’s &#8220;The Low Carbon City for All&#8221; summit in France on July 8, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Acting Haitian Prime Minister Joseph</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-acting-haitian-prime-minister-joseph/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 23:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=257783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Acting Haitian Prime Minister Claude Joseph today. Secretary Blinken extended condolences to the family and loved ones of President Moïse and to the people of Haiti. The Secretary also expressed the United States’ wishes for First Lady Martine Moïse’s recovery. Secretary Blinken reiterated the United States’ continued commitment to work with the Government of Haiti in support of the Haitian people and democratic governance, peace, and security.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Acting Haitian Prime Minister Claude Joseph today. Secretary Blinken extended condolences to the family and loved ones of President Moïse and to the people of Haiti. The Secretary also expressed the United States’ wishes for First Lady Martine Moïse’s recovery. Secretary Blinken reiterated the United States’ continued commitment to work with the Government of Haiti in support of the Haitian people and democratic governance, peace, and security.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; July 7, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-july-7-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 22:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=257769</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>2:56 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, a very Lurch-like “good afternoon.” No?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I just want to make sure everyone is paying attention.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-HAITI"></a> I obviously want to stop – start with the situation in Haiti. The United States strongly condemns, as you heard from President Biden earlier today, the assassination of President Jovenel Moise and the attack on First Lady Martine Moise in Haiti. We extend our deepest condolences to President Moise’s family and his loved ones and to the people of Haiti in the midst of this tragedy.</p>
<p>Those who seek to accomplish their political goals through violence and by subverting the rule of law will not succeed in thwarting the Haitian people and their desire for a better – for a brighter future. We urge Haitian authorities to bring those responsible to justice. The United States calls on all political parties, civil society groups, and stakeholders to echo what we’ve heard from Acting Prime Minister Claude Joseph’s call for calm and to work together in the wake of this tragedy to ensure peace and democratic governance.</p>
<p>So with that, I am happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-CHINA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So I – just before returning to Haiti, I got a extremely brief thing. It’s something else, but it’s a logistical thing, kind of, and that is the Hong Kong consulate, which has been closed for a couple days now because of a COVID case. Do – has that spread, do you know? Is there anything more you can say about that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m not in a position &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And I only ask this now because I’m going to forget about it if I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I understand. I’m not in a position to offer an update on the operating status there. As you know, our embassies and posts around the world are constantly calibrating their operations given the state of COVID or any other issue that may affect the workforce. But I don’t have an update to offer.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-HAITI2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. On Haiti, then. Is there any – this isn’t exactly – it’s bad, but it’s not exactly a coup. I mean, it’s a – not a – the government hasn’t been overthrown or anything like that. So is there any implication, assistance-wise, or any other wise, for Haiti related to – the administration policy towards Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There is – Acting Prime Minister Claude Joseph has assumed charge. What we know and what we will continue to do is to preserve Haiti’s democratic institutions. We know that by preserving Haiti’s democratic institutions, that is key to restoring peace. At this time, we don’t have any updates to announce in terms of our assistance, but I can assure you that our partnership with the Haitian people and with their elected government will continue. As you know, that partnership has taken many forms in recent months; in, of course, recent years. In January of this year we announced 75.5 million for – in support for a wide range of issues, and that includes democratic governance, health, education, agricultural development, strengthening pre-election activities through the Consortium for Elections and Political Process Strengthening program.</p>
<p>We have also been a strong partner for Haiti and the Haitian people when it comes to security and when it comes to law enforcement as well. And much of that has been overseen by our Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs. They have provided direct assistance to the Haitian National Police over the years, and as a direct result of this INL support the Haitian National Police have trained officers from a number that was less than 10,000 in 2010 to nearly 15,000 Haitian National Police officers today. We have continued to encourage Haiti to take a holistic approach to countering violence and to countering gangs, and we provided $5 million to strengthen the Haitian National Police’s capacity to work with communities to resist gangs as well.</p>
<p>And I would remiss if I didn’t note our support to Haiti’s pre-election activities. And USAID is providing more than $3 million to the consortium I mentioned before. And those activities for which these funds are earmarked include focusing on improving electoral administration, strengthening the competitiveness of political parties, educating voters on electoral processes, promoting electoral transparency, and ensuring inclusive voter participation as well. So this is just one – these are just several metrics of our support for the Haitian people, and that will not waver in the wake of this.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Given, Ned, the history of U.S. intervention in Haiti – it’s been numerous times over the course of the last century and a half – is there any appetite in this administration for some kind of – to intervene if the situation gets to be dire? This is a relatively close neighbor that has in the past seen massive outflows of people trying to escape, so if it – the situation deteriorates – and I realize this is a hypothetical – but is there any appetite for a return?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> To us, Matt &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; Haiti is a partner, and that is how we will treat this relationship. It is how we have treated Haiti, it is how we will going forward. We would echo what we have heard from the acting prime minister, Claude Joseph, in his calls for calm, his calls for the Haitian people to work together to ensure peace, to ensure democratic government. The United States has and will continue to stand by to provide assistance to the Haitian people.</p>
<p>Humeyra.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So on Haiti, the ambassador told us that they – he has been in touch with the State Department and a number of different agencies in U.S. Government. Can you at least say – you just said that you can’t give an update on the U.S. assistance, but can you at least say perhaps a new package is being formed and you guys are working on something new on top of these quite little numbers – $5 million, $3 million – that you’ve just mentioned?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> $75.5 million.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. I missed that, sorry.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have been in regular contact with the acting prime minister, Claude Joseph. We are prepared to respond to requests for assistance. Our ambassador to Haiti, Ambassador Sison, has been in regular contact with a range of Haitian officials. She has spoken to the acting director general of the Haitian National Police. Of course, Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield at the UN this morning spoke to Haiti’s permanent representative to the UN. We have been, as I said before, in regular contact.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken started his day this morning with a comprehensive update on the situation on the ground, including the latest developments as we knew them at the time, the security situation. He was briefed by Ambassador Sison, who at this moment happens to be in Washington. He was also on the phone with the DCM, who is on the ground in Haiti right now, DCM Nicole Theriot, as well as other members of his team. So we are prepared to receive additional requests for assistance from Haitian authorities.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you also confirm if first lady is being flown to Miami for – to receive medical treatment?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we, of course, are familiar with the reports that the First Lady Martine Moise was injured in the attack. We know that she was taken to receive medical treatment. Out of respect for her privacy, we’re not in a position to comment on – to provide further comment. But as I said, we have made very clear to Haitian authorities the United States is standing ready to provide assistance and we are prepared to provide any and all forms of appropriate assistance to our Haitian partners.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you speak to the DEA element of all of this? You – the ambassador also talked about this footage where they’re identifying themselves as DEA agents, and he said that he doesn’t believe in it. I mean, can you say that that’s not the case, that you have an assessment that those are not DEA officials? Can you sort of set the record straight on that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, as you said, the Haitian ambassador himself has dismissed these allegations. These reports are absolutely false. The United States condemns this heinous act. These false reports are nothing more than that, just false reports.</p>
<p>Shaun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I just follow up on that? Is there any sense of what the motivation would have been for this? And is – do you think there’s any truth to what the government – to what the acting government is saying, that these were mercenaries, that these were foreigners who were in there?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, Shaun, we just don’t have clear answers at the – at this time. What we do know and what I have said is that Haitian authorities are investigating. We stand ready to offer assistance to that investigation, but obviously, we’re going to let that investigation play out. And, of course, the Haitian authorities are in the lead on that investigation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just one more thing on that. You – earlier this year, you were mentioning about the elections in Haiti and you called for them to go on – go ahead and schedule later this year. Is it still the view of the United States that elections in September are a good idea?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It is still the view of the United States that elections this year should proceed. We know that free and fair elections are the democratic path towards ending Haiti’s irregular and prolonged rule by decree and restoring its parliament, which as of now has lapsed. Free and fair presidential elections will facilitate a peaceful transfer of power to a newly elected president as well.</p>
<p>We’ve – as you know and as you have heard me say and others say, we have urged Haitian Government and political stakeholders repeatedly both in public and in private to reach a political accord in order to ensure those legislative and presidential elections take place later this year.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. Nazira Karimi, Afghan independent journalist.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can we stay on Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Sure. Let’s stay on Haiti for just a moment.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> I will come back to you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I change the subject?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well, we’ll – I’ll come back to you if that’s okay.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We’ll take a couple more on Haiti.</p>
<p>Will.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, just two questions on Haiti. I want to ask this a slightly different way. Can you confirm that there currently is a pending request for defense equipment from Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We expect to be in receipt of formal requests. We stand ready to receive them. But as of right now, I’m not in a position to confirm that we’ve received a formal request.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. And what was the administration’s position on the president’s legitimacy as a leader of the country? Obviously, the opposition says his five-year term expired last February.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> The Haitian constitution is clear on this point. As we’ve said, we’ve supported elections later this year. We still support those elections later this year, believing and knowing that President Moise’s term was to end next year.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Quick question on Haiti. The current U.S. ambassador to Haiti has been nominated to a different position in the State Department. Is there any plan to speed up the process to naming a new ambassador to that country?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well, as you know, Ambassador Sison is still in that role. She was actually supposed to travel back to Haiti today after consultations here in Washington. She expects to go back to Haiti just as soon as she is able to travel there. We also are very fortunate to have a very capable DCM in Haiti, Nicole Theriot, whom I mentioned before. So if and when Ambassador Sison moves on to her next role, I can assure you we will have a very capable leader in charge of our post in Port-au-Prince.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And I have a quick question asking slightly different way. So the prime – Haiti’s prime minister and ambassador said the attackers were foreigners. If that is so, does the U.S. have any measure in place to prevent them from escaping to the United States?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> So this is another investigative question and, unfortunately, the investigation of course is in the early phases. We are ready and willing to support Haitian authorities in that investigation which they are leading, but we will have to refer investigative questions to Haitian authorities, again, reiterating that we are willing to cooperate with any requests they may put forward.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Thanks. Yes. Haiti still?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Anything else on Haiti?</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-AFGHANISTAN"></a> I will come back to you on Afghanistan. Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, thank you. Nazira Azim Karimi, Afghan journalist. As you know, sir, since U.S.-NATO withdraw their soldiers in Afghanistan, it’s very complicated. The Afghan people, they are very worried. And recently, Iran hosted the Taliban and Afghan official for a meeting today. They already had a meeting. Any comment about that? In the meantime, Taliban attacked to Badghis Province. Of course, it’s very dangerous. Do you think that it’s not against the agreement between U.S. and Taliban in Doha, Qatar?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well, when it comes to the Iran-hosted talks, we’re of course aware that Iran has hosted a meeting between the Taliban and the Islamic Republic negotiating teams. This is what we’ve always said, that Afghanistan’s neighbors and countries in the region, they too have a stake in Afghanistan’s future. They need to use their influence in ways that are positive, in ways that are constructive, in ways that promote the cause of peace, in ways that support the people of Afghanistan. We know that regional consensus and support for an Afghan-led, Afghan-owned peace process is important for an enduring peace.</p>
<p>When it comes to the recent violence, this is something obviously we have spoken to quite a bit, and the point remains that no government that might come to power in Afghanistan through the use of force, at the barrel of a gun, will have legitimacy or the support – and that can be especially critical – from the international community, nor would a government that comes to power by force have the support of the people of Afghanistan. And what we ultimately hope to help support and will seek to help support is a just and durable settlement. Every party has an interest in a settlement being durable. The Afghan people are – have been burdened and in many cases brutalized by 40 years of civil war. The United States is supporting the efforts ongoing in Doha right now between the parties, where the parties are, in fact, still meeting, still talking, to see to it that we can have a just and durable settlement and a comprehensive ceasefire to finally see an end to this violence.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I understand the conference is still postponed. Are you still optimistic?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, obviously the talks in Doha are ongoing. The parties continue to meet in Doha. We’re grateful for Qatar’s role, and Qatar’s role in hosting that talk – those talks. We do welcome Turkey, Qatar, and the UN’s outstanding offer to host negotiations between the parties, but I don’t have any updates to share at that time, especially knowing that talks are ongoing in Doha.</p>
<p>Will. Or – yes. Yes, please. Go ahead, Will.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On Iran.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Any – sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, it’s sort of on Iran. Go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I just follow up briefly? You mentioned about the Iranian role.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I just pursue that a little bit?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> After September 11th, obviously, there’s some coordination between the United States and Iran regarding Afghanistan. What’s your assessment now of Iran’s role in Afghanistan? Are you at all hopeful for a positive – from the U.S. perspective, a positive role for Iran in Afghanistan in the future?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, look, I wouldn’t characterize us hopeful. I wouldn’t characterize us as pessimistic. I would characterize us as knowing that in order for there to be a just and durable peace in Afghanistan, Afghanistan’s neighbors need to play a constructive role. What Iran is trying to do or in the – is in the process of doing by hosting this meeting may well be constructive. I think the jury is still out. This is obviously not something we are – we have discussed with the Iranians other than by making the point very publicly that Afghanistan’s neighbors need to be responsible stakeholders.</p>
<p>For too long, many of Afghanistan’s neighbors have been happy to see the United States engaged, and the United States alone engaged. If there is to be a just and durable settlement and a comprehensive ceasefire, it needs to be supported – supported by Afghanistan’s neighbors, and we hope to see them act responsibly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just on that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-IRAN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Follow-up on Iran.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You mentioned the talks in Vienna yesterday, the interrupted talks. Are you certain those talks are going to resume? Have they hit a snag? You mentioned consultations. What are the consultations about? Is it about the new President-elect Raisi or some of Iran’s behavior in the region or some of the political backdrop and concerns that are bubbling up? Can we absolutely commit that those talks are going to continue, and when do you think we might see that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I would say is I would need to direct you to the Iranians for feedback on their consultations, what’s going on in their capital. I can tell you from our part, the team has been back here at the department meeting with officials throughout the building, including with Secretary Blinken, updating him on the progress of those talks. Of course, nothing is certain in the world of diplomacy, but I think we have every expectation that there will be a seventh round of talks at the appropriate moment, at the right time, and our team looks forward to being engaged in that next round of talks when it does begin.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So can you –the consultations with the U.S. team in its capital, those are finished now?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We are, I think &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Or you’re just waiting for the Europeans to say, okay, come on, guys, let’s go back to Vienna?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, of course the team continues to remain here, continues to engage in discussions, continues to do important work from the department, but that team will be ready, will be prepared to travel back to Vienna when there’s a seventh round of talks.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-LEBANON"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Secretary Blinken met with French and Saudi counterparts on the sidelines of the G20 regarding Lebanon. But apart from his tweet, new, further details have been provided. Tomorrow the U.S. and French ambassadors to Lebanon are heading to Saudi in what seems to be a rare diplomatic move. Where does this trilateral coordination stand and what’s the U.S. – what’s Washington hoping to convey during these meetings?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, you’re right and I can confirm that our Ambassador to Lebanon Dorothy Shea, will in fact travel alongside the French ambassador to Lebanon, Anne Grillo, to Saudi Arabia for meetings with Saudi officials on July 8th. This visit does follow the trilateral consultation that Secretary Blinken had with his French and Saudi counterparts, Foreign Minister Le Drian and Saudi Foreign Minister bin Farhan on June 29th, when we were in Matera for the G20. During her meetings in Saudi Arabia, I expect Ambassador Shea will discuss the gravity of the situation in Lebanon. She’ll emphasize the importance of humanitarian assistance to the Lebanese people as well as increased support for the Lebanese Armed Forces and international – internal security forces, excuse me.</p>
<p>In partnership with her French and Saudi counterparts, Ambassador Shea will also continue to develop that trilateral diplomatic strategy, and that strategy is focused on government formation, it’s focused on the imperative of undertaking urgent and necessary reforms that the people of Lebanon so desperately need. As we have said before, Lebanon’s leaders need to come together, need to do the right thing, need to put aside political bickering and squabbling for the benefit of the Lebanese people.</p>
<p>Ambassador Shea will also use the occasion to reiterate the commitment of the United States to helping the people of Lebanon, and she will highlight some of the good work of the over $3.7 billion in economic, humanitarian, and security assistance that the United States has contributed since 2016 and what that has supported.</p>
<p>Yes, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-SAUDIARABIA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And separately, yesterday you mentioned the Saudi deputy defense minister would be at State today. Could you confirm any meetings he had or will have today and how those discussions went, or what they’re expected to touch on?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure. So as we did confirm yesterday, the Saudi deputy defense – Defense Minister Khalid bin Salman is in Washington for a series of meetings. He has so far met with our special envoy for the Horn of Africa, Ambassador Feltman. He’s also met with Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking. In terms of the former, Special Envoy Feltman and KBS discussed the situation in Ethiopia, in areas where the United States and Saudi Arabia could potentially cooperate to address the crisis and to mitigate instability in the broader region. They also agreed to continue a dialogue on mechanisms to promote peace, security, and prosperity in the Red Sea. As you know, Ambassador Feltman was recently in the Gulf discussing the situation in the Horn of Africa, and this was a continuation of that.</p>
<p>With Special Envoy Lenderking, he took part in a meeting yesterday to discuss steps to mitigate the ongoing humanitarian crisis in Yemen and steps necessary to end the conflict there, including steps that would ease restrictions at Hudaydah port and Sana’a Airport. Special Envoy Lenderking stressed the need for continued Saudi engagement on Yemen, allowing space for nationwide comprehensive ceasefire followed by a transition to a Yemeni political process that would lead to a permanent solution to this conflict.</p>
<p>Additionally, Special Envoy Lenderking recognized Saudi Arabia for its efforts to improve implementation of the Riyadh Agreement, and he agreed that both the Republic of Yemen Government and the Southern Transition Council must continue to negotiate so that the Yemeni Government can return to Aden to provide the essential services the Yemeni people need and deserve. The deputy defense minister will be in the building later today. He’ll be meeting with a couple senior State Department officials during that session.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Is he &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And with the Secretary?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I expect the Secretary will have a chance to take part in part of that meeting, yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>When you talk about urgent and necessary reforms needed in Lebanon, could you give us an example or two of what the most urgent and most necessary reforms are?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, it’s certainly urgent that Lebanon’s leaders set aside their political differences to form a government that is cohesive and a government that is responsive to the needs of the international people. Corruption, impunity, lawlessness have dogged successive governments, and ultimately and most importantly have drained the Lebanese people of much needed resources. So as an initial and necessary step, Lebanon’s leaders need to put the interests of their people first. That’s what we’re calling for. That’s what we hope to see.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But does that mean – I mean, what you talked about, ending or at least trying to fight corruption and the other – impunity and that kind of thing, those are pretty tall orders and can’t be really done overnight. So am I wrong in thinking that what you’re saying is that the first order of business needs to be the formation of a new government that is – that represents and can respond to the demands of the people?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It’s – it’s &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is that the first thing that needs to be done?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It’s certainly necessary, but not sufficient. We know that Lebanon’s leaders, to the point of government formation, need to show flexibility to form a government that is willing and capable of true and fundamental reform. And this gets to the next step. Government formation is one element, but true and necessary reform is the next, again, so that the people of Lebanon can realize that full potential. They deserve, they need a government that will urgently implement those necessary reforms, including to rescue Lebanon’s deteriorating economy. Lebanon’s economy and the economic condition of the country has imposed huge costs, huge burdens on the people of Lebanon. The inflation that has occurred in recent days and weeks has taken a really profound toll on the people there.</p>
<p>And so, yes, government formation is necessary, but yes, so too is reform.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Did the Secretary discuss Lebanon with the pope when he saw him last week?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I – we issued a readout of that meeting. As I do recall, it was addressed, but I would have to refer you to that readout.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-IRAQ"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just ask about Iraq? There has been quite a bit of an increase in rocket attacks. Iraqi army officials say the pace of recent attacks against U.S. bases and with rockets and drones is unprecedented. Why do you think that is on the rise at this particular moment? What is your assessment on who is behind it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I’d have to correct one thing you said. There are no U.S. bases in Iraq.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sorry.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There are a limited number of U.S. and other coalition advisors &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> U.S. and coalition, yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; at Iraqi bases, at Iraqi Government invitation that, in turn, assist and enable Iraqi Security Forces to confront the remnants of ISIS. Look, I wouldn’t want to speak to the motivation of these attacks. I will say that what we recognize is that these attacks reflect and are representative of the threat that Iran-backed militias present fundamentally to Iraq’s sovereignty and to Iraq’s stability. We &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you know for a fact that they’re carried out by Iranian-backed militias, these attacks over the past couple of days?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So obviously there have been recent attacks, and I wouldn’t want to prejudge investigations that are ongoing. But as we have said in the context of attacks that have taken place in recent months, they have been carried out by Iran-backed militias and President Biden, in turn, has responded – responded in different ways. But of course, perhaps most visibly, by authorizing the military strikes – most recently late last month, but also before that as well – on Iran-backed militia infrastructure in Iraq and Syria.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-BRAZIL"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. I want to confirm information that I got from Brazilian Government. Is the U.S. planning to send more vaccines directly to Brazil in the coming two weeks? If yes, how many vaccines? And when are they getting to Brazil? And also, I would like to know when is the U.S. planning to pick the new ambassador to Brazil and what is the profile that you are looking for, if a political pick or a diplomat – a career diplomat?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, to your first question, we were very pleased to have been able to deliver 3 million doses of Johnson &amp; Johnson COVID vaccines that arrived in Campinas, Brazil, late last month – June 25th I believe it was. Presently, as you know, we’re working to support the delivery of the 80 million doses from our own supply that President Biden pledged to allocate last month, mid-last month. We’ll donate additional doses throughout the summer months as supply becomes available.</p>
<p>In doing so, our principles are standard and transparent, and that includes maximizing the number of safe and effective vaccines available equitably for the greatest number of countries and for those most at risk within their countries. It includes preparing for surges and prioritizing health care workers and other vulnerable populations based on public health data and acknowledged best practices, and helping countries in need, including our neighbors. And, of course, Brazil is an important partner of ours in the hemisphere. We have provided non-vaccine support to Brazil in the context of the COVID pandemic as well.</p>
<p>And that brings me to your second question. Because Brazil is such an important partner of the United States, while I can’t give you a name or I can’t give you a timeframe, I assure you that the next U.S. ambassador to Brazil will be someone who has the trust and confidence of Secretary Blinken and the trust and confidence of President Biden. That person will be charged with an incredibly important relationship, and as soon as we have more details, we’ll be sure to share them.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But is there a timeline for this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That’s as opposed to ambassadors to other countries, who don’t have the – who don’t have the support and – of the President?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I’m – I am speaking in the context of Brazil, an important partner.</p>
<p>Rich in the back.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-CHINA2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. Indo-Pacific coordinator Kurt Campbell said that any Chinese move against Taiwan would be catastrophic and that this administration is sending a clear message of deterrence. China’s Foreign Ministry today responded, warning the U.S. to tread carefully on this issue. Can we expect the U.S. to continue to send this clear message of deterrence or perhaps an even clearer message of deterrence going forward?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the United States will continue to support a peaceful resolution of cross-strait issues, consistent with the longstanding wishes and the best interests of the people on Taiwan. And we have repeatedly urged Beijing to cease its military, its diplomatic, its economic pressure against Taiwan and instead to engage in meaningful dialogue with Taiwan. Secretary Blinken has addressed the question. He has repeatedly said it would be a profound mistake by any party to try and remake that status quo with the use of force. Our commitment to Taiwan is rock solid, and we believe that commitment contributes to the maintenance of peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait and within the broader region.</p>
<p>For four decades, American policy has been consistent. The “one China” policy is guided by the Taiwan Relations Act, the Three Joint Communiques, the Six Assurances provided to Taipei. That has not changed. As you know, Rich, we also did unveil a couple months ago now updated contact guidance that will allow us to deepen our partnership with the people on Taiwan, consistent with that “one China” policy, the Taiwan Relations Act, the Three Joint Communiques, and the Six Assurances.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is the U.S. seeing any evidence that Beijing is ready to cease this pressure?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I wouldn’t want to characterize discussions with Beijing or any other country on this. What I will characterize is what we are making very clear, and that is that our commitment to Taiwan is rock solid. We believe it is in the best interests of the people on Taiwan and the broader region as well.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-UAESAUDIARABIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, any comment on the dispute between the UAE and Saudi (inaudible) over oil and OPEC Plus?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I believe you’ve heard from the White House on this, and I think they had an opportunity to discuss this again yesterday. U.S. officials are closely monitoring these talks, closely watching the progress. We’ve been in touch with several of the parties involved.</p>
<p>Let me move it around. Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-SYRIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On Syria, can you give us an update on negotiations on the cross-border resolution? And given that this is an issue that comes up year after year, has the Biden administration as part of its Syria policy given any consideration to finding a longer-term solution to aid delivery?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So to your second question, this is to us not a question about geopolitics or bilateral relations with any other member of the UN Security Council or political dynamics on the council. To us, this is a – fundamentally a question of the humanitarian interests of the Syrian people. This boils down to a question of livelihoods and a question of lives for the people of Syria, and that’s why we are and have been acting so urgently now that there are just a few days left until the last remaining humanitarian crossing is set to expire. We’ve been very clear, again, because of the human stakes, the human – the potential human costs of this – millions of Syrians – women, children, men – that the Security Council must renew and expand humanitarian access provided by Bab al-Hawa for 12 months. And we know we must do it now because, of course, the expiration is coming up.</p>
<p>The people of Syria have been brutalized by the Assad regime. They have been further buffeted by the COVID pandemic. What we seek to do – and again, this is not about politics. This is not about geopolitics. This is not about inter-state relations. This is not about great powers. But what we seek to do is to help the people of Syria, millions of whom are at risk of starvation if this last remaining humanitarian crossing is shamefully and tragically allowed to expire.</p>
<p>These discussions have been ongoing at the UN. Of course, Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield spoke to this yesterday. She has been engaged privately with the Security Council. And I have every expectation that she will continue to be engaged, as will the broader department and the fuller administration.</p>
<p>As you know, this was one of the issues that President Biden raised directly with President Putin at the summit, again, putting it in terms not of great – not in terms of inter-state relations, but in terms of the human costs and the human toll of this.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On that, has the U.S. actually made any progress in convincing Russia to agree to a renewal?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I wouldn’t want to characterize discussions that have been behind closed doors. I would refer you to the Russian Federation for their position on this. But I think it goes without saying that any responsible country should be in favor of saving lives, and this is what this is about.</p>
<p>Yes, (inaudible).</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-PAKISTAN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, another question about Pakistan policy. Last week, Prime Minister Imran Khan was a little mad and he said that – he criticized United States that United States had been defeated in Afghanistan and he will not allow CIA base in Pakistan. And also he mentioned that we will not anymore control or – yes, control on Pakistan anymore if – if Taliban try to get the power by force, we will not support them. And I don’t know what’s the relationship. Still Pakistan has influence as to Taliban to bring them on the table in this sensitive time in Doha?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I think what is true is that Pakistan is an important partner across any number of fronts. Of course, we have shared interests when it comes to Afghanistan, when it comes to peace and stability in Afghanistan. We have – and this goes over the course of successive administrations now – encouraged Pakistan to be a constructive partner when it comes to Afghanistan and our collective efforts to bring about some semblance of peace and security there. Pakistan has been helpful in – recently when it comes to this shared interest. Our shared interests go well beyond that: broader counterterrorism interests as well, not to mention the people-to-people ties that unite our two countries.</p>
<p>But this also goes back to I think where we started with your earlier question, that what we know to be true is that all of Afghanistan’s neighbors need to play a constructive role in helping to bring about a just and durable political settlement as well as a comprehensive ceasefire. For far too long, some of Afghanistan’s neighbors have not played that role. They had been happy to let – content, I should say, to let other countries take responsibility. And right now, we have made clear that we are going to be working very closely to ensure that Afghanistan’s neighbors do play that constructive role, knowing that it will be a necessary ingredient to what I think we all collectively hope to see in Afghanistan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes, Shaun.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-CHINA3"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Different issue, on China, WeChat, the popular social media forum. There have been reports that there have been the deletion of LGBTQ content from WeChat. Do you have any comment on that? Does this signal at all a worsening of the climate for sexual minorities in China?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we are aware of reports that WeChat has deleted several accounts carrying public views of LGBTQI+ topics, and we’re concerned by – that the PRC has restricted the social media accounts of LGBTQI+ student groups and NGOs that were merely expressing their views, exercising their right to freedom of expression and freedom of speech. We oppose the use of network restrictions to suppress freedom of expression online. It does not matter to us whether that it is in China or anywhere else; we oppose it universally. U.S. content moderation issues are addressed in line with the strong protections under U.S. law that align with international standards for, as I said before, that very freedom of expression. And we encourage other governments to develop similar policies respecting freedom of expression.</p>
<p>More broadly, we&#8217;re committed to fighting for the human rights of all people. And that, of course, includes LGBTQI+ people around the world. This administration is taking measures to ensure that U.S. diplomacy promotes and protects those rights. As you know, on February 5th, President Biden signed a presidential memorandum making it the policy of the United States to protect and to promote LGBTQI+ rights around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, does that – when you talk about universality of this and you oppose the use of network restrictions to block any content related &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, I didn&#8217;t say any content. I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Consistent with the rights of freedom of expression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Right. Okay. Well – and I know this is the State Department and you don&#8217;t – but you do speak on behalf of the administration. But domestically, today, I think somewhere out there a certain former president has filed lawsuits against several companies that are similar to WeChat and what they do for blocking his – so if that was taking place, if that kind of thing was taking place in a foreign – in another country where you had a remit or a responsibility, would you – would you oppose those kinds of restrictions by private companies on free speech?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt, we believe deeply in the principle of freedom of expression, whether that is at home, whether that is around the world. Obviously, your question has a political tint to it, so I will &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I didn’t mean to be – have a political tint. It’s just that it&#8217;s kind of an obvious question to ask, even if the State Department doesn&#8217;t do things domestically. But when you speak on behalf of the administration and talk about the President signing legislation that applies domestically, I just wonder if this is the kind – if there was censorship of political views on the left or the right in another country, you would oppose it, correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well – well, what I mentioned was a presidential memorandum that contours our foreign policy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, no, no, I get that. But if you saw this kind of – when you&#8217;re talking about WeChat, if that was restrictions on political views either on the left or right or radical centrists – I don&#8217;t know, whoever – you would oppose it, correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Freedom of expression is something that we protect and that we promote around the world. The right of people everywhere to live in safety and security is also something we believe deeply in. When it comes to U.S. social media companies or internet service providers, I&#8217;d have to refer you to them to speak to their policies.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:41 p.m.)</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>2:56 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, a very Lurch-like “good afternoon.” No?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I just want to make sure everyone is paying attention.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-HAITI"></a> I obviously want to stop – start with the situation in Haiti. The United States strongly condemns, as you heard from President Biden earlier today, the assassination of President Jovenel Moise and the attack on First Lady Martine Moise in Haiti. We extend our deepest condolences to President Moise’s family and his loved ones and to the people of Haiti in the midst of this tragedy.</p>
<p>Those who seek to accomplish their political goals through violence and by subverting the rule of law will not succeed in thwarting the Haitian people and their desire for a better – for a brighter future. We urge Haitian authorities to bring those responsible to justice. The United States calls on all political parties, civil society groups, and stakeholders to echo what we’ve heard from Acting Prime Minister Claude Joseph’s call for calm and to work together in the wake of this tragedy to ensure peace and democratic governance.</p>
<p>So with that, I am happy to take your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-CHINA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So I – just before returning to Haiti, I got a extremely brief thing. It’s something else, but it’s a logistical thing, kind of, and that is the Hong Kong consulate, which has been closed for a couple days now because of a COVID case. Do – has that spread, do you know? Is there anything more you can say about that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I’m not in a position &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And I only ask this now because I’m going to forget about it if I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I understand. I’m not in a position to offer an update on the operating status there. As you know, our embassies and posts around the world are constantly calibrating their operations given the state of COVID or any other issue that may affect the workforce. But I don’t have an update to offer.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-HAITI2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. On Haiti, then. Is there any – this isn’t exactly – it’s bad, but it’s not exactly a coup. I mean, it’s a – not a – the government hasn’t been overthrown or anything like that. So is there any implication, assistance-wise, or any other wise, for Haiti related to – the administration policy towards Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There is – Acting Prime Minister Claude Joseph has assumed charge. What we know and what we will continue to do is to preserve Haiti’s democratic institutions. We know that by preserving Haiti’s democratic institutions, that is key to restoring peace. At this time, we don’t have any updates to announce in terms of our assistance, but I can assure you that our partnership with the Haitian people and with their elected government will continue. As you know, that partnership has taken many forms in recent months; in, of course, recent years. In January of this year we announced 75.5 million for – in support for a wide range of issues, and that includes democratic governance, health, education, agricultural development, strengthening pre-election activities through the Consortium for Elections and Political Process Strengthening program.</p>
<p>We have also been a strong partner for Haiti and the Haitian people when it comes to security and when it comes to law enforcement as well. And much of that has been overseen by our Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs. They have provided direct assistance to the Haitian National Police over the years, and as a direct result of this INL support the Haitian National Police have trained officers from a number that was less than 10,000 in 2010 to nearly 15,000 Haitian National Police officers today. We have continued to encourage Haiti to take a holistic approach to countering violence and to countering gangs, and we provided $5 million to strengthen the Haitian National Police’s capacity to work with communities to resist gangs as well.</p>
<p>And I would remiss if I didn’t note our support to Haiti’s pre-election activities. And USAID is providing more than $3 million to the consortium I mentioned before. And those activities for which these funds are earmarked include focusing on improving electoral administration, strengthening the competitiveness of political parties, educating voters on electoral processes, promoting electoral transparency, and ensuring inclusive voter participation as well. So this is just one – these are just several metrics of our support for the Haitian people, and that will not waver in the wake of this.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Given, Ned, the history of U.S. intervention in Haiti – it’s been numerous times over the course of the last century and a half – is there any appetite in this administration for some kind of – to intervene if the situation gets to be dire? This is a relatively close neighbor that has in the past seen massive outflows of people trying to escape, so if it – the situation deteriorates – and I realize this is a hypothetical – but is there any appetite for a return?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> To us, Matt &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; Haiti is a partner, and that is how we will treat this relationship. It is how we have treated Haiti, it is how we will going forward. We would echo what we have heard from the acting prime minister, Claude Joseph, in his calls for calm, his calls for the Haitian people to work together to ensure peace, to ensure democratic government. The United States has and will continue to stand by to provide assistance to the Haitian people.</p>
<p>Humeyra.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So on Haiti, the ambassador told us that they – he has been in touch with the State Department and a number of different agencies in U.S. Government. Can you at least say – you just said that you can’t give an update on the U.S. assistance, but can you at least say perhaps a new package is being formed and you guys are working on something new on top of these quite little numbers – $5 million, $3 million – that you’ve just mentioned?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> $75.5 million.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. I missed that, sorry.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have been in regular contact with the acting prime minister, Claude Joseph. We are prepared to respond to requests for assistance. Our ambassador to Haiti, Ambassador Sison, has been in regular contact with a range of Haitian officials. She has spoken to the acting director general of the Haitian National Police. Of course, Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield at the UN this morning spoke to Haiti’s permanent representative to the UN. We have been, as I said before, in regular contact.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken started his day this morning with a comprehensive update on the situation on the ground, including the latest developments as we knew them at the time, the security situation. He was briefed by Ambassador Sison, who at this moment happens to be in Washington. He was also on the phone with the DCM, who is on the ground in Haiti right now, DCM Nicole Theriot, as well as other members of his team. So we are prepared to receive additional requests for assistance from Haitian authorities.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you also confirm if first lady is being flown to Miami for – to receive medical treatment?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we, of course, are familiar with the reports that the First Lady Martine Moise was injured in the attack. We know that she was taken to receive medical treatment. Out of respect for her privacy, we’re not in a position to comment on – to provide further comment. But as I said, we have made very clear to Haitian authorities the United States is standing ready to provide assistance and we are prepared to provide any and all forms of appropriate assistance to our Haitian partners.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you speak to the DEA element of all of this? You – the ambassador also talked about this footage where they’re identifying themselves as DEA agents, and he said that he doesn’t believe in it. I mean, can you say that that’s not the case, that you have an assessment that those are not DEA officials? Can you sort of set the record straight on that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, as you said, the Haitian ambassador himself has dismissed these allegations. These reports are absolutely false. The United States condemns this heinous act. These false reports are nothing more than that, just false reports.</p>
<p>Shaun.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I just follow up on that? Is there any sense of what the motivation would have been for this? And is – do you think there’s any truth to what the government – to what the acting government is saying, that these were mercenaries, that these were foreigners who were in there?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, Shaun, we just don’t have clear answers at the – at this time. What we do know and what I have said is that Haitian authorities are investigating. We stand ready to offer assistance to that investigation, but obviously, we’re going to let that investigation play out. And, of course, the Haitian authorities are in the lead on that investigation.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just one more thing on that. You – earlier this year, you were mentioning about the elections in Haiti and you called for them to go on – go ahead and schedule later this year. Is it still the view of the United States that elections in September are a good idea?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It is still the view of the United States that elections this year should proceed. We know that free and fair elections are the democratic path towards ending Haiti’s irregular and prolonged rule by decree and restoring its parliament, which as of now has lapsed. Free and fair presidential elections will facilitate a peaceful transfer of power to a newly elected president as well.</p>
<p>We’ve – as you know and as you have heard me say and others say, we have urged Haitian Government and political stakeholders repeatedly both in public and in private to reach a political accord in order to ensure those legislative and presidential elections take place later this year.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. Nazira Karimi, Afghan independent journalist.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can we stay on Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Sure. Let’s stay on Haiti for just a moment.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> I will come back to you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I change the subject?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well, we’ll – I’ll come back to you if that’s okay.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We’ll take a couple more on Haiti.</p>
<p>Will.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yeah, just two questions on Haiti. I want to ask this a slightly different way. Can you confirm that there currently is a pending request for defense equipment from Haiti?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> We expect to be in receipt of formal requests. We stand ready to receive them. But as of right now, I’m not in a position to confirm that we’ve received a formal request.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. And what was the administration’s position on the president’s legitimacy as a leader of the country? Obviously, the opposition says his five-year term expired last February.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> The Haitian constitution is clear on this point. As we’ve said, we’ve supported elections later this year. We still support those elections later this year, believing and knowing that President Moise’s term was to end next year.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Quick question on Haiti. The current U.S. ambassador to Haiti has been nominated to a different position in the State Department. Is there any plan to speed up the process to naming a new ambassador to that country?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well, as you know, Ambassador Sison is still in that role. She was actually supposed to travel back to Haiti today after consultations here in Washington. She expects to go back to Haiti just as soon as she is able to travel there. We also are very fortunate to have a very capable DCM in Haiti, Nicole Theriot, whom I mentioned before. So if and when Ambassador Sison moves on to her next role, I can assure you we will have a very capable leader in charge of our post in Port-au-Prince.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And I have a quick question asking slightly different way. So the prime – Haiti’s prime minister and ambassador said the attackers were foreigners. If that is so, does the U.S. have any measure in place to prevent them from escaping to the United States?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> So this is another investigative question and, unfortunately, the investigation of course is in the early phases. We are ready and willing to support Haitian authorities in that investigation which they are leading, but we will have to refer investigative questions to Haitian authorities, again, reiterating that we are willing to cooperate with any requests they may put forward.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Thanks. Yes. Haiti still?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> No &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Anything else on Haiti?</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-AFGHANISTAN"></a> I will come back to you on Afghanistan. Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, thank you. Nazira Azim Karimi, Afghan journalist. As you know, sir, since U.S.-NATO withdraw their soldiers in Afghanistan, it’s very complicated. The Afghan people, they are very worried. And recently, Iran hosted the Taliban and Afghan official for a meeting today. They already had a meeting. Any comment about that? In the meantime, Taliban attacked to Badghis Province. Of course, it’s very dangerous. Do you think that it’s not against the agreement between U.S. and Taliban in Doha, Qatar?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Well, when it comes to the Iran-hosted talks, we’re of course aware that Iran has hosted a meeting between the Taliban and the Islamic Republic negotiating teams. This is what we’ve always said, that Afghanistan’s neighbors and countries in the region, they too have a stake in Afghanistan’s future. They need to use their influence in ways that are positive, in ways that are constructive, in ways that promote the cause of peace, in ways that support the people of Afghanistan. We know that regional consensus and support for an Afghan-led, Afghan-owned peace process is important for an enduring peace.</p>
<p>When it comes to the recent violence, this is something obviously we have spoken to quite a bit, and the point remains that no government that might come to power in Afghanistan through the use of force, at the barrel of a gun, will have legitimacy or the support – and that can be especially critical – from the international community, nor would a government that comes to power by force have the support of the people of Afghanistan. And what we ultimately hope to help support and will seek to help support is a just and durable settlement. Every party has an interest in a settlement being durable. The Afghan people are – have been burdened and in many cases brutalized by 40 years of civil war. The United States is supporting the efforts ongoing in Doha right now between the parties, where the parties are, in fact, still meeting, still talking, to see to it that we can have a just and durable settlement and a comprehensive ceasefire to finally see an end to this violence.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I understand the conference is still postponed. Are you still optimistic?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, obviously the talks in Doha are ongoing. The parties continue to meet in Doha. We’re grateful for Qatar’s role, and Qatar’s role in hosting that talk – those talks. We do welcome Turkey, Qatar, and the UN’s outstanding offer to host negotiations between the parties, but I don’t have any updates to share at that time, especially knowing that talks are ongoing in Doha.</p>
<p>Will. Or – yes. Yes, please. Go ahead, Will.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On Iran.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Any – sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, it’s sort of on Iran. Go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I just follow up briefly? You mentioned about the Iranian role.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Could I just pursue that a little bit?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> After September 11th, obviously, there’s some coordination between the United States and Iran regarding Afghanistan. What’s your assessment now of Iran’s role in Afghanistan? Are you at all hopeful for a positive – from the U.S. perspective, a positive role for Iran in Afghanistan in the future?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, look, I wouldn’t characterize us hopeful. I wouldn’t characterize us as pessimistic. I would characterize us as knowing that in order for there to be a just and durable peace in Afghanistan, Afghanistan’s neighbors need to play a constructive role. What Iran is trying to do or in the – is in the process of doing by hosting this meeting may well be constructive. I think the jury is still out. This is obviously not something we are – we have discussed with the Iranians other than by making the point very publicly that Afghanistan’s neighbors need to be responsible stakeholders.</p>
<p>For too long, many of Afghanistan’s neighbors have been happy to see the United States engaged, and the United States alone engaged. If there is to be a just and durable settlement and a comprehensive ceasefire, it needs to be supported – supported by Afghanistan’s neighbors, and we hope to see them act responsibly.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just on that.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-IRAN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Follow-up on Iran.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You mentioned the talks in Vienna yesterday, the interrupted talks. Are you certain those talks are going to resume? Have they hit a snag? You mentioned consultations. What are the consultations about? Is it about the new President-elect Raisi or some of Iran’s behavior in the region or some of the political backdrop and concerns that are bubbling up? Can we absolutely commit that those talks are going to continue, and when do you think we might see that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> What I would say is I would need to direct you to the Iranians for feedback on their consultations, what’s going on in their capital. I can tell you from our part, the team has been back here at the department meeting with officials throughout the building, including with Secretary Blinken, updating him on the progress of those talks. Of course, nothing is certain in the world of diplomacy, but I think we have every expectation that there will be a seventh round of talks at the appropriate moment, at the right time, and our team looks forward to being engaged in that next round of talks when it does begin.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So can you –the consultations with the U.S. team in its capital, those are finished now?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We are, I think &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Or you’re just waiting for the Europeans to say, okay, come on, guys, let’s go back to Vienna?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, of course the team continues to remain here, continues to engage in discussions, continues to do important work from the department, but that team will be ready, will be prepared to travel back to Vienna when there’s a seventh round of talks.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-LEBANON"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Secretary Blinken met with French and Saudi counterparts on the sidelines of the G20 regarding Lebanon. But apart from his tweet, new, further details have been provided. Tomorrow the U.S. and French ambassadors to Lebanon are heading to Saudi in what seems to be a rare diplomatic move. Where does this trilateral coordination stand and what’s the U.S. – what’s Washington hoping to convey during these meetings?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, you’re right and I can confirm that our Ambassador to Lebanon Dorothy Shea, will in fact travel alongside the French ambassador to Lebanon, Anne Grillo, to Saudi Arabia for meetings with Saudi officials on July 8th. This visit does follow the trilateral consultation that Secretary Blinken had with his French and Saudi counterparts, Foreign Minister Le Drian and Saudi Foreign Minister bin Farhan on June 29th, when we were in Matera for the G20. During her meetings in Saudi Arabia, I expect Ambassador Shea will discuss the gravity of the situation in Lebanon. She’ll emphasize the importance of humanitarian assistance to the Lebanese people as well as increased support for the Lebanese Armed Forces and international – internal security forces, excuse me.</p>
<p>In partnership with her French and Saudi counterparts, Ambassador Shea will also continue to develop that trilateral diplomatic strategy, and that strategy is focused on government formation, it’s focused on the imperative of undertaking urgent and necessary reforms that the people of Lebanon so desperately need. As we have said before, Lebanon’s leaders need to come together, need to do the right thing, need to put aside political bickering and squabbling for the benefit of the Lebanese people.</p>
<p>Ambassador Shea will also use the occasion to reiterate the commitment of the United States to helping the people of Lebanon, and she will highlight some of the good work of the over $3.7 billion in economic, humanitarian, and security assistance that the United States has contributed since 2016 and what that has supported.</p>
<p>Yes, please.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-SAUDIARABIA"></a><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And separately, yesterday you mentioned the Saudi deputy defense minister would be at State today. Could you confirm any meetings he had or will have today and how those discussions went, or what they’re expected to touch on?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure. So as we did confirm yesterday, the Saudi deputy defense – Defense Minister Khalid bin Salman is in Washington for a series of meetings. He has so far met with our special envoy for the Horn of Africa, Ambassador Feltman. He’s also met with Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking. In terms of the former, Special Envoy Feltman and KBS discussed the situation in Ethiopia, in areas where the United States and Saudi Arabia could potentially cooperate to address the crisis and to mitigate instability in the broader region. They also agreed to continue a dialogue on mechanisms to promote peace, security, and prosperity in the Red Sea. As you know, Ambassador Feltman was recently in the Gulf discussing the situation in the Horn of Africa, and this was a continuation of that.</p>
<p>With Special Envoy Lenderking, he took part in a meeting yesterday to discuss steps to mitigate the ongoing humanitarian crisis in Yemen and steps necessary to end the conflict there, including steps that would ease restrictions at Hudaydah port and Sana’a Airport. Special Envoy Lenderking stressed the need for continued Saudi engagement on Yemen, allowing space for nationwide comprehensive ceasefire followed by a transition to a Yemeni political process that would lead to a permanent solution to this conflict.</p>
<p>Additionally, Special Envoy Lenderking recognized Saudi Arabia for its efforts to improve implementation of the Riyadh Agreement, and he agreed that both the Republic of Yemen Government and the Southern Transition Council must continue to negotiate so that the Yemeni Government can return to Aden to provide the essential services the Yemeni people need and deserve. The deputy defense minister will be in the building later today. He’ll be meeting with a couple senior State Department officials during that session.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Is he &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And with the Secretary?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>I expect the Secretary will have a chance to take part in part of that meeting, yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>When you talk about urgent and necessary reforms needed in Lebanon, could you give us an example or two of what the most urgent and most necessary reforms are?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, it’s certainly urgent that Lebanon’s leaders set aside their political differences to form a government that is cohesive and a government that is responsive to the needs of the international people. Corruption, impunity, lawlessness have dogged successive governments, and ultimately and most importantly have drained the Lebanese people of much needed resources. So as an initial and necessary step, Lebanon’s leaders need to put the interests of their people first. That’s what we’re calling for. That’s what we hope to see.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But does that mean – I mean, what you talked about, ending or at least trying to fight corruption and the other – impunity and that kind of thing, those are pretty tall orders and can’t be really done overnight. So am I wrong in thinking that what you’re saying is that the first order of business needs to be the formation of a new government that is – that represents and can respond to the demands of the people?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It’s – it’s &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is that the first thing that needs to be done?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> It’s certainly necessary, but not sufficient. We know that Lebanon’s leaders, to the point of government formation, need to show flexibility to form a government that is willing and capable of true and fundamental reform. And this gets to the next step. Government formation is one element, but true and necessary reform is the next, again, so that the people of Lebanon can realize that full potential. They deserve, they need a government that will urgently implement those necessary reforms, including to rescue Lebanon’s deteriorating economy. Lebanon’s economy and the economic condition of the country has imposed huge costs, huge burdens on the people of Lebanon. The inflation that has occurred in recent days and weeks has taken a really profound toll on the people there.</p>
<p>And so, yes, government formation is necessary, but yes, so too is reform.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Did the Secretary discuss Lebanon with the pope when he saw him last week?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I – we issued a readout of that meeting. As I do recall, it was addressed, but I would have to refer you to that readout.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-IRAQ"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I just ask about Iraq? There has been quite a bit of an increase in rocket attacks. Iraqi army officials say the pace of recent attacks against U.S. bases and with rockets and drones is unprecedented. Why do you think that is on the rise at this particular moment? What is your assessment on who is behind it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I’d have to correct one thing you said. There are no U.S. bases in Iraq.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sorry.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> There are a limited number of U.S. and other coalition advisors &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> U.S. and coalition, yeah.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> &#8212; at Iraqi bases, at Iraqi Government invitation that, in turn, assist and enable Iraqi Security Forces to confront the remnants of ISIS. Look, I wouldn’t want to speak to the motivation of these attacks. I will say that what we recognize is that these attacks reflect and are representative of the threat that Iran-backed militias present fundamentally to Iraq’s sovereignty and to Iraq’s stability. We &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Do you know for a fact that they’re carried out by Iranian-backed militias, these attacks over the past couple of days?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So obviously there have been recent attacks, and I wouldn’t want to prejudge investigations that are ongoing. But as we have said in the context of attacks that have taken place in recent months, they have been carried out by Iran-backed militias and President Biden, in turn, has responded – responded in different ways. But of course, perhaps most visibly, by authorizing the military strikes – most recently late last month, but also before that as well – on Iran-backed militia infrastructure in Iraq and Syria.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-BRAZIL"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. I want to confirm information that I got from Brazilian Government. Is the U.S. planning to send more vaccines directly to Brazil in the coming two weeks? If yes, how many vaccines? And when are they getting to Brazil? And also, I would like to know when is the U.S. planning to pick the new ambassador to Brazil and what is the profile that you are looking for, if a political pick or a diplomat – a career diplomat?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, to your first question, we were very pleased to have been able to deliver 3 million doses of Johnson &amp; Johnson COVID vaccines that arrived in Campinas, Brazil, late last month – June 25th I believe it was. Presently, as you know, we’re working to support the delivery of the 80 million doses from our own supply that President Biden pledged to allocate last month, mid-last month. We’ll donate additional doses throughout the summer months as supply becomes available.</p>
<p>In doing so, our principles are standard and transparent, and that includes maximizing the number of safe and effective vaccines available equitably for the greatest number of countries and for those most at risk within their countries. It includes preparing for surges and prioritizing health care workers and other vulnerable populations based on public health data and acknowledged best practices, and helping countries in need, including our neighbors. And, of course, Brazil is an important partner of ours in the hemisphere. We have provided non-vaccine support to Brazil in the context of the COVID pandemic as well.</p>
<p>And that brings me to your second question. Because Brazil is such an important partner of the United States, while I can’t give you a name or I can’t give you a timeframe, I assure you that the next U.S. ambassador to Brazil will be someone who has the trust and confidence of Secretary Blinken and the trust and confidence of President Biden. That person will be charged with an incredibly important relationship, and as soon as we have more details, we’ll be sure to share them.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But is there a timeline for this &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> That’s as opposed to ambassadors to other countries, who don’t have the – who don’t have the support and – of the President?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I’m – I am speaking in the context of Brazil, an important partner.</p>
<p>Rich in the back.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-CHINA2"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. Indo-Pacific coordinator Kurt Campbell said that any Chinese move against Taiwan would be catastrophic and that this administration is sending a clear message of deterrence. China’s Foreign Ministry today responded, warning the U.S. to tread carefully on this issue. Can we expect the U.S. to continue to send this clear message of deterrence or perhaps an even clearer message of deterrence going forward?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the United States will continue to support a peaceful resolution of cross-strait issues, consistent with the longstanding wishes and the best interests of the people on Taiwan. And we have repeatedly urged Beijing to cease its military, its diplomatic, its economic pressure against Taiwan and instead to engage in meaningful dialogue with Taiwan. Secretary Blinken has addressed the question. He has repeatedly said it would be a profound mistake by any party to try and remake that status quo with the use of force. Our commitment to Taiwan is rock solid, and we believe that commitment contributes to the maintenance of peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait and within the broader region.</p>
<p>For four decades, American policy has been consistent. The “one China” policy is guided by the Taiwan Relations Act, the Three Joint Communiques, the Six Assurances provided to Taipei. That has not changed. As you know, Rich, we also did unveil a couple months ago now updated contact guidance that will allow us to deepen our partnership with the people on Taiwan, consistent with that “one China” policy, the Taiwan Relations Act, the Three Joint Communiques, and the Six Assurances.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is the U.S. seeing any evidence that Beijing is ready to cease this pressure?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I wouldn’t want to characterize discussions with Beijing or any other country on this. What I will characterize is what we are making very clear, and that is that our commitment to Taiwan is rock solid. We believe it is in the best interests of the people on Taiwan and the broader region as well.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-UAESAUDIARABIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, any comment on the dispute between the UAE and Saudi (inaudible) over oil and OPEC Plus?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I believe you’ve heard from the White House on this, and I think they had an opportunity to discuss this again yesterday. U.S. officials are closely monitoring these talks, closely watching the progress. We’ve been in touch with several of the parties involved.</p>
<p>Let me move it around. Yes.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-SYRIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On Syria, can you give us an update on negotiations on the cross-border resolution? And given that this is an issue that comes up year after year, has the Biden administration as part of its Syria policy given any consideration to finding a longer-term solution to aid delivery?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> So to your second question, this is to us not a question about geopolitics or bilateral relations with any other member of the UN Security Council or political dynamics on the council. To us, this is a – fundamentally a question of the humanitarian interests of the Syrian people. This boils down to a question of livelihoods and a question of lives for the people of Syria, and that’s why we are and have been acting so urgently now that there are just a few days left until the last remaining humanitarian crossing is set to expire. We’ve been very clear, again, because of the human stakes, the human – the potential human costs of this – millions of Syrians – women, children, men – that the Security Council must renew and expand humanitarian access provided by Bab al-Hawa for 12 months. And we know we must do it now because, of course, the expiration is coming up.</p>
<p>The people of Syria have been brutalized by the Assad regime. They have been further buffeted by the COVID pandemic. What we seek to do – and again, this is not about politics. This is not about geopolitics. This is not about inter-state relations. This is not about great powers. But what we seek to do is to help the people of Syria, millions of whom are at risk of starvation if this last remaining humanitarian crossing is shamefully and tragically allowed to expire.</p>
<p>These discussions have been ongoing at the UN. Of course, Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield spoke to this yesterday. She has been engaged privately with the Security Council. And I have every expectation that she will continue to be engaged, as will the broader department and the fuller administration.</p>
<p>As you know, this was one of the issues that President Biden raised directly with President Putin at the summit, again, putting it in terms not of great – not in terms of inter-state relations, but in terms of the human costs and the human toll of this.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On that, has the U.S. actually made any progress in convincing Russia to agree to a renewal?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I wouldn’t want to characterize discussions that have been behind closed doors. I would refer you to the Russian Federation for their position on this. But I think it goes without saying that any responsible country should be in favor of saving lives, and this is what this is about.</p>
<p>Yes, (inaudible).</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-PAKISTAN"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes, another question about Pakistan policy. Last week, Prime Minister Imran Khan was a little mad and he said that – he criticized United States that United States had been defeated in Afghanistan and he will not allow CIA base in Pakistan. And also he mentioned that we will not anymore control or – yes, control on Pakistan anymore if – if Taliban try to get the power by force, we will not support them. And I don’t know what’s the relationship. Still Pakistan has influence as to Taliban to bring them on the table in this sensitive time in Doha?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, I think what is true is that Pakistan is an important partner across any number of fronts. Of course, we have shared interests when it comes to Afghanistan, when it comes to peace and stability in Afghanistan. We have – and this goes over the course of successive administrations now – encouraged Pakistan to be a constructive partner when it comes to Afghanistan and our collective efforts to bring about some semblance of peace and security there. Pakistan has been helpful in – recently when it comes to this shared interest. Our shared interests go well beyond that: broader counterterrorism interests as well, not to mention the people-to-people ties that unite our two countries.</p>
<p>But this also goes back to I think where we started with your earlier question, that what we know to be true is that all of Afghanistan’s neighbors need to play a constructive role in helping to bring about a just and durable political settlement as well as a comprehensive ceasefire. For far too long, some of Afghanistan’s neighbors have not played that role. They had been happy to let – content, I should say, to let other countries take responsibility. And right now, we have made clear that we are going to be working very closely to ensure that Afghanistan’s neighbors do play that constructive role, knowing that it will be a necessary ingredient to what I think we all collectively hope to see in Afghanistan.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yes, Shaun.</p>
<p><a id="post-257769-CHINA3"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Different issue, on China, WeChat, the popular social media forum. There have been reports that there have been the deletion of LGBTQ content from WeChat. Do you have any comment on that? Does this signal at all a worsening of the climate for sexual minorities in China?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we are aware of reports that WeChat has deleted several accounts carrying public views of LGBTQI+ topics, and we’re concerned by – that the PRC has restricted the social media accounts of LGBTQI+ student groups and NGOs that were merely expressing their views, exercising their right to freedom of expression and freedom of speech. We oppose the use of network restrictions to suppress freedom of expression online. It does not matter to us whether that it is in China or anywhere else; we oppose it universally. U.S. content moderation issues are addressed in line with the strong protections under U.S. law that align with international standards for, as I said before, that very freedom of expression. And we encourage other governments to develop similar policies respecting freedom of expression.</p>
<p>More broadly, we&#8217;re committed to fighting for the human rights of all people. And that, of course, includes LGBTQI+ people around the world. This administration is taking measures to ensure that U.S. diplomacy promotes and protects those rights. As you know, on February 5th, President Biden signed a presidential memorandum making it the policy of the United States to protect and to promote LGBTQI+ rights around the world.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Ned, does that – when you talk about universality of this and you oppose the use of network restrictions to block any content related &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, I didn&#8217;t say any content. I &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Well &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Consistent with the rights of freedom of expression.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Right. Okay. Well – and I know this is the State Department and you don&#8217;t – but you do speak on behalf of the administration. But domestically, today, I think somewhere out there a certain former president has filed lawsuits against several companies that are similar to WeChat and what they do for blocking his – so if that was taking place, if that kind of thing was taking place in a foreign – in another country where you had a remit or a responsibility, would you – would you oppose those kinds of restrictions by private companies on free speech?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Matt, we believe deeply in the principle of freedom of expression, whether that is at home, whether that is around the world. Obviously, your question has a political tint to it, so I will &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I didn’t mean to be – have a political tint. It’s just that it&#8217;s kind of an obvious question to ask, even if the State Department doesn&#8217;t do things domestically. But when you speak on behalf of the administration and talk about the President signing legislation that applies domestically, I just wonder if this is the kind – if there was censorship of political views on the left or the right in another country, you would oppose it, correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well – well, what I mentioned was a presidential memorandum that contours our foreign policy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>No, no, no, I get that. But if you saw this kind of – when you&#8217;re talking about WeChat, if that was restrictions on political views either on the left or right or radical centrists – I don&#8217;t know, whoever – you would oppose it, correct?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Freedom of expression is something that we protect and that we promote around the world. The right of people everywhere to live in safety and security is also something we believe deeply in. When it comes to U.S. social media companies or internet service providers, I&#8217;d have to refer you to them to speak to their policies.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:41 p.m.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>State Department Meetings with Saudi Deputy Minister of Defense Khalid bin Salman</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/state-department-meetings-with-saudi-deputy-minister-of-defense-khalid-bin-salman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 21:52:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=257757</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Open sans',serif; color: #222222;">Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland and Counselor Derek Chollet met with Saudi Arabia’s Deputy Minister of Defense Khalid bin Salman al Saud today in Washington for discussions on regional security, support for Saudi Arabia to defend itself from cross-border attacks, and improving human rights. Secretary of State Antony Blinken joined the group for part of the meeting to discuss efforts to achieve a comprehensive, nationwide ceasefire and transition to a political process in Yemen, the need for economic reform and humanitarian relief for the Lebanese people, and other key bilateral issues, including human rights.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p style="background: white;"><span style="font-family: 'Open sans',serif; color: #222222;">Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs Victoria Nuland and Counselor Derek Chollet met with Saudi Arabia’s Deputy Minister of Defense Khalid bin Salman al Saud today in Washington for discussions on regional security, support for Saudi Arabia to defend itself from cross-border attacks, and improving human rights. Secretary of State Antony Blinken joined the group for part of the meeting to discuss efforts to achieve a comprehensive, nationwide ceasefire and transition to a political process in Yemen, the need for economic reform and humanitarian relief for the Lebanese people, and other key bilateral issues, including human rights.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On the Occasion of His Holiness the Dalai Lama’s 86th Birthday</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/on-the-occasion-of-his-holiness-the-dalai-lamas-86th-birthday/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 23:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=257552</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>I am delighted to extend warm wishes to His Holiness the Dalai Lama on the occasion of his 86th birthday on July 6. His Holiness is an inspiration to many around the world who are drawn to his messages of compassion, equality, and inclusivity. I have deep respect and appreciation for His Holiness’ grace, wisdom, and humility, as well as his dedication to greater global equality and the equal rights of all people, including his fellow Tibetans. I wish His Holiness the very best.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>I am delighted to extend warm wishes to His Holiness the Dalai Lama on the occasion of his 86th birthday on July 6. His Holiness is an inspiration to many around the world who are drawn to his messages of compassion, equality, and inclusivity. I have deep respect and appreciation for His Holiness’ grace, wisdom, and humility, as well as his dedication to greater global equality and the equal rights of all people, including his fellow Tibetans. I wish His Holiness the very best.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; July 6, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-july-6-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 22:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=257522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:14 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon. Hope everyone had a very good Fourth of July weekend, hopefully back ready and refreshed.</p>
<p>Just one thing at the top today, and that is today <a id="post-257522-DaliLama"></a>we wish a happy birthday to His Holiness the Dalai Lama, whose grace and compassion have served as an inspiration to all of us. We commend his dedication to the global Tibetan community and to all those around the world who share in his important message of peace and kindness and his commitment to equality and, importantly, to human dignity. We join all of those in wishing His Holiness many more years to come.</p>
<p>Matt, would you like to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is that it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> That is it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Well, I thought I was going to be asking a follow-up, because I thought you were going to top – do a topper about the Ethiopia call. Let me just ask that Ethiopia question very briefly and then move on to something else. In the call that you guys read out with Prime Minister Abiy, it talked about Tigray and the troops and all that, but it didn’t mention anything about the GERD, about the dam. And as you probably know, the Ethiopians have begun filling it again, and I’m wondering if that came up in the call. And whether it did or not, do you have anything to say about that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-Ethiopia"></a>Well, we did issue a readout of the call with Prime Minister Abiy. We’ll let that readout speak for itself. When it comes to the GERD, what I will say is that we have continued to support collaborative and constructive efforts by the parties involved – and that’s Ethiopia, it’s Egypt and Sudan – to reach an enduring arrangement on the GERD. We understand, of course, the importance of the Nile waters to all three of these countries, and we continue to encourage a resumption of a dialogue that we hope is productive, and substantive, and constructive. In doing so, all along we’ve supported the AU-led process, a process that aims to lower tensions, that aims to facilitate productive negotiations and to enhance regional cooperation.</p>
<p>We do call on all parties to refrain from unilateral action, any unilateral action, that would raise those tensions, that would put greater distance between where we are now and a peaceful, constructive resolution to this. And we call for all parties to commit themselves to a negotiated solution that is acceptable to all sides.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, so – and this is – this would be a unilateral action that raises tensions, yes?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have continued to encourage all parties to avoid unilateral actions that would raise tensions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And this is or isn’t a unilateral action that raises tensions?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I think it is fair to say that this has the potential to raise tensions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. All right. If no one – I just want to go very briefly. You – it’s tangential to the Dalai Lama &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; although it doesn’t – it has to do with China, but not Tibet. And that is just I’m wondering if you can tell – the meeting with – that the Secretary was having today with the Uyghurs, the Xinjiang internment camp people – it should be over by now, no? Is there anything you can tell us about that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-China1"></a>So we will have a readout of the meeting later today. It started just a little bit – a bit ago, about an hour ago. And so I do expect we’ll be able to offer a readout later today. This was an event that the State Department put together. It was with a number – I believe there were seven participants. These were survivors of the internment camps; these were family members; these were advocates on their behalf. This was something the Secretary wanted to do, to provide him an opportunity to reaffirm the administration’s emphasis on human rights when it comes to our China policy and to reaffirm our engagement with individuals from groups the government of the People’s Republic of China has repressed in Xinjiang. It will also enable – and I suspect it did enable – the members of the advocacy community who were present during this meeting to provide recommendations to the department for responding to the ongoing atrocities in Xinjiang. But again, we will have a readout of this later today.</p>
<p>Humyra. Humeyra, sorry.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. <a id="post-257522-Ethiopia2"></a>Just want to follow up on Tigray, because he started with it. When Secretary Blinken asked Abiy for the withdrawal of the Eritrean troops and – what kind of assurance did he get? Or did he get one?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, again, we’re not going to go into the conversation beyond the readout that we did issue. But what I will say broadly is, of course, we all saw the announcement of the unilateral ceasefire late last month, June 28th I believe it was. What we know is that unilateral announcement needs to be followed up with concrete changes on the ground to end the conflict, to stop the atrocities, and importantly to allow safe and unhindered humanitarian assistance. The people of Tigray have and continue to suffer tremendously, and the ability of this humanitarian assistance to enter the region unimpeded and unhindered is of paramount importance to us. We call on all armed actors to commit to an immediate, indefinite negotiated ceasefire, so as to achieve the shared objectives, and they include to end the violence, to restore stability to Tigray, and going forward to create a context for inclusive dialogue that preserves the unity, the sovereignty, and the territorial integrity of the Ethiopian state. We further urge all actors and all parties to focus efforts toward resolution of the conflict through – as I said before – inclusive dialogue, and to allow fully unhindered humanitarian access to, in fact, expedite the delivery of that humanitarian aid. And access must include – but, of course, not be limited to – open transportation corridors and telecommunications infrastructure that would allow for the delivery of this humanitarian assistance for the civilian population. And that includes the ability of journalists to move about freely in the region as well.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi. Can I move on to Afghanistan if that’s all right with everyone?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hold on. Did you answer my – whether the dam came up in the call, or did it not? Or do you not know?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I said we issued a readout, and we’ll let that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I know, but it’s not in the readout.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll let the readout speak, and I did offer a quick &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I know you did. I just want to know whether he talked to him about it in the call.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I will – I did offer a quick synopsis of our policy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> If we have more to say on the call itself, we will be happy to let you know.</p>
<p>Humeyra.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On Afghanistan, I’m sure you’ve seen the reporting about, like, water being cut off and power being cut off following the departure of U.S. troops. I’m just wondering if U.S. has any response to all of this. And what kind of message does this send to continued – the U.S. pledge of continued engagements in Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-Afghan"></a>Well, that is our message, and that has not changed, and that will not change. The President, from the day he announced that the U.S. military would be withdrawing, except for the troops necessary to protect our diplomatic compounds, was very clear that we have partnered with the Afghan people and with the Afghan Government over the course of some 20 years now; that partnership would not diminish in any way with the withdrawal – with the military withdrawal from Afghanistan. Again, we retain a diplomatic compound in Kabul; that is what we intend to retain going forward as well. We will be able to continue that partnership with the people of Aghanistan, with the Government of Afghanistan going forward, even as the military retrograde takes place.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are you making some updates to your evacuation plans for the embassy, given that Taliban has seized, like, a lot of provinces?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The department is always taking a close look at security conditions around the world. The safety and security of our diplomats, of Foreign Service nationals, of others who are present on our diplomatic compounds is of paramount importance to us. So we are always taking a close look at that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I ask a follow-up on Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are you surprised – is the State Department surprised with the speed with which the Taliban have taken over outposts and roads and entire provinces in Afghanistan? Do you have any assessment on whether the Afghan Government can withstand that onslaught, and will it be viable?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I am not going to offer an assessment or any sort of feedback of our reaction from here. I will say as a matter of policy – and that’s where our focus has been, as a matter of policy – we have continued to call for an end to the ongoing violence, which of course has been driven largely by the Taliban. A negotiated settlement between the parties – in this case, the Islamic Republic and the Taliban – is the only way to end 40 years of war and to bring to Afghanistan the peace that the Afghan people both want and deserve. That’s why we continue to urge all sides to engage in serious negotiations to determine a political roadmap that leads to what we have called for all along and what the international community has called for all along, and that is a just and durable political settlement.</p>
<p>What we know is that the world will not accept an imposition by force of a government in Afghanistan. The legitimacy of any future Afghan government, the ability of that government to receive international assistance – which will be of critical importance – the durability of any future Afghan government can only be possible if that government has a basic respect for human rights.</p>
<p>It’s also worth noting, I think, in this context that it is not just the Government of Afghanistan, it is not just the United States, it’s not just a broad swath of the international community that recognizes that there is no military solution to this conflict. The fact that the Taliban continues to engage in Doha, to engage in intra-Afghan dialogue, is itself most likely a reflection of the fact that the Taliban too understands that only through diplomacy can they garner any sort of legitimacy, can they expect to be accepted by the international community. And it is, in fact, true that dialogue does continue in Doha. The parties have continued to meet (inaudible) goal in mind. And that was to disrupt and ultimately defeat the network of al-Qaida that conducted the 9/11 attacks. Osama bin Laden was brought to justice more than 10 years ago, 10 years ago in May.</p>
<p>And the other important point is that, of course, when we came into office in January there was already an existing agreement between the United States Government and the Taliban. And so like it or not, on May 1st the status quo that would have been in place on April 30th was going to change. And so the administration, the President, was confronted with a situation in which on May 1st, because of an agreement that the previous administration negotiated – I think if you recall, the President said in his remarks when he announced the military withdrawal that it’s not an agreement that this administration necessarily would have designed, but it’s one we inherited – that American troops would potentially come under attack starting on May 1st if they remained in the country.</p>
<p>And so the President faced a decision: potentially recreate the cycle of violence and escalation, or change strategy and continue our partnership with the Afghan Government, continue our partnership with the Afghan people, but removing American service members as bargaining chips, because to President Biden that’s not who they are. Our service members went into Afghanistan; they were successful in the mission they were asked to do by successive U.S. presidents. Of course, a small contingent will remain to provide security at our diplomatic compound. But to continue to have a larger number of U.S. military forces in harm’s way was not something that the President was willing to commit to. It’s not something that the administration felt was necessary to achieve the collective ends there.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But Ned, the problem with the – the problem with that – did someone else want to ask about Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Afghanistan, yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m just wondering if the Taliban continues with its military offenses in the north, will the U.S. continue to diplomatically engage with them?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, right now we are supporting the intra-Afghan dialogue, and a couple things can be true at the same time. It is absolutely true that a political solution is the only way, again, to achieve that just and durable outcome that all parties want and all parties seem to understand is the only end to 40 years of conflict. It’s also true, again, that any government that comes to power at the barrel of a gun, through force, is not one that will have popular support, it is not one that will accrue assistance from the international community, it is not one that will have international legitimacy. And for all those reasons, it is almost certainly not one that will have durability. And what we seek, again, is a just and durable political outcome, and only through dialogue – in this case intra-Afghan dialogue – can that be achieved.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So I guess the answer is yes, as they continue with their military offenses you will continue to engage with them diplomatically.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, wouldn’t want to entertain a hypothetical. But we know in this case &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, it’s not a hypothetical. It’s going on right now.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, you’re asking about something that could continue. We have also seen the statements from the Taliban that I referred to just a moment ago that they intend to intensify that diplomacy. So again, we’ll see if they make good on that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And one quick question. If they take their military offenses to Kabul, will that change the calculation diplomatically between the U.S. and the Taliban?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, I don’t want to entertain the hypothetical. We have – what will remain is our partnership with the Afghan Government, with the Afghan people. We will continue down that path and wouldn’t want to entertain a hypothetical like that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But I mean, there’s going to be – your current assessment, like, things are happening on the ground and they’re seizing district after district. You must have some sort of an assessment, like a cutoff point: if this happens then we’re going to stop disengaging. And the same goes for the evacuation plan as well.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, of course, the State Department, the Department of Defense, these are planning organizations. We’re always planning for any contingency. And so when it comes to the safety and security of our people on the ground, when it comes to our diplomatic approaches, when it comes to our policy, of course, we’re planning for any number of contingencies.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, I don’t understand three things. One, I don’t understand how you’re able to make this claim that the Taliban actually want international acceptance and aid when there is nothing in their history that suggests that they do. I’ve asked you about this before, and I – there is no good answer other than, well, a bunch of them are in Doha talking. But that doesn’t mean anything. They never wanted or cared about – they were perfectly happy when Pakistan was the only country on the planet that recognized them. That’s number one.</p>
<p>Number two, the argument that you guys inherited an agreement with the Taliban that the previous administration concluded and that you had no choice, I don’t understand that either. This administration inherited plenty from the previous administration that it absolutely reversed. Are you saying that you’re not – you have a – you’re not confident in your negotiating skills that you could have renegotiated with – that you couldn’t have renegotiated a deal with the Taliban and that the – and are you saying that the President, in fact, didn’t want to take troops out, didn’t want to withdraw?</p>
<p>And then lastly, the thing I don’t understand – well, maybe not understand, but you don’t want to talk about the historic analogy that Said made to Vietnam. Let’s go next door to Cambodia. Are you familiar at all with the letter that Sirik Matak wrote to John Gunther Dean, who was the U.S. ambassador to Cambodia in April of 1975?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>It’s &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>If you’re not familiar with it &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>It’s been a while.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; I suggest you familiarize yourself with it because it may end up being sadly prescient. But if you could answer the first two, that would be great. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure. Well, on your second question, Matt, I think you’re actually confusing different things here. These are apples and oranges. Yes, we changed quite a few U.S. policies across a number of fronts, but I think you would be hard-pressed to find an international agreement that the United States signed on to during the last administration that this administration has jettisoned, done away with. This is the point that we have made in any number of different &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>How about the Geneva protocol on the anti-abortion stuff?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>This was the point that we have made on any number of steps about the importance of the durability of American foreign policies – American foreign policy across administrations.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>How about the agreements with the Northern Triangle, with Mexico and the Northern Triangle? Those are international agreements that you guys jettisoned.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>These are – Matt, I think &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I mean, you just challenged me to come up with an international agreement that the previous administration signed that you guys have walked away from, and I just gave you, I think, three.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The previous administration had its own policies. This administration has different policies across a number of fronts. But this administration also understands the importance of when the United States signs its name and gives its word in the context of a formal international agreement, especially one where the stakes are profound for American – the American people, including our service members, deployed service members, that’s something that we take very seriously. So the idea that we could have done away with the U.S.-Taliban agreement and that American service members could have remained in Afghanistan on May 1st, as they were on April 30th as they were on December 31st of 2020, is just not something that would have been feasible given where we were.</p>
<p>The idea – your first question, the notion that the Taliban don’t believe in a negotiated political solution – you yourself said that they are engaged in Doha. Again, it’s not just the process. It’s the outcomes that we’re interested in, and that’s what we’ll be watching for. As I said, we have seen statements that at least purport – with which the Taliban at least purport to seek to accelerate that diplomacy. Again, we’ll see if it comes to fruition.</p>
<p>But I think the broader point is that whether the Taliban or any other future Afghan government likes it, they are going to need international assistance; they are going to need international legitimacy; they are going to need the popular support of the Afghan people; and any Afghan government that comes to power at the barrel of a gun, that comes to power through the use of force, is almost certainly going to lack those critical ingredients.</p>
<p>And so when we talk about a just and durable outcome, it is hard if not impossible to envision an outcome that is just, that is durable, without having arrived at – having been arrived at through negotiations and, in this case, through diplomacy.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just on those negotiations, because since they first met last September, they’ve yet to yield anything except an agenda at this point. What are you doing to accelerate that process, especially after the Istanbul conference didn’t happen?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So we have supported this process. Of course, we are not a party to these negotiations. All throughout we have played a supporting role. We have supported the parties in Doha. We have galvanized the international community. We have done so in the context of the UN as well, all the while continuing our partnership with the Government of Afghanistan and the people of Afghanistan.</p>
<p>So again, believe me, I am not out here to offer false hope when it comes to what the Taliban may seek or what they’re up to now. We have seen their statements. We certainly encourage them to follow through on their statements. But again, process is one thing. What matters most is the outcome. And the outcome we seek, the outcome the international community seeks, is a just and a durable political solution, and really, the only way to achieve that, again, is through diplomacy – in this case, diplomacy between the parties – that is now taking place in Doha.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But why even reference their statements when what is happening in Afghanistan is so directly opposed to what they are saying in paper statements?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, we will see. They have an opportunity ahead of them in the coming days, in the coming several weeks, to make good on what they have said. I am not here, again, to offer optimism or to characterize what we make of their statements. That’s to them to make good on.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just one last question: Is Zal in Doha still? Is he playing any sort of shuttle diplomacy role in any of this to try to accelerate the process?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Members of the team have been engaged on the ground in Doha. As I understand it, the – Ambassador Khalilzad is here in Washington, but if there is a need for him to go back to Doha, he will be prepared to do so, yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> In new report with the board of governors in the IAEA, the Director General Grossi today announced that Iran intends to use uranium enriched up to 20 percent. How do you comment on that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-Iran"></a>Well, as I understand it, this report remains restricted until it’s released by the IAEA board of governors, but we’ve seen the media reports that characterize this document. It is worrying that Iran is choosing to continue to escalate its nonperformance of its JCPOA commitments, especially with experiments that have value for nuclear weapons research. It’s another unfortunate step backwards for Iran, particularly as we for our part have demonstrated our sincere intention and willingness to return to the JCPOA and to find more productive and durable ways to deal with the nuclear issue.</p>
<p>We have made clear that such provocative steps would not and will not provide Iran with any leverage in negotiations. Instead, they would only intensify our concerns with Iran’s activities, and we continue to urge Iran to stop this brinksmanship, to return to Vienna prepared for real talks, and to be in a position to be prepared to finish the work that we have started in April that has now taken place over six rounds.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are you considering a new approach? You said diplomacy is the best way. You said now it’s unfortunate step, but you did six rounds of talks. There was an attack against a U.S. airbase yesterday, and also, for example, in Yemen there is no progress. You said you are fed up with the Houthis. How you would proceed?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Right. Well, the talks in Vienna that have now completed six rounds, they’re about one thing and they’re about one thing only, and that is a return to mutual compliance with the JCPOA. And for us, the important consequence of that is a reimposition of the most stringent verification and monitoring regime ever negotiated. So you are right that there are a whole host of other concerns – profound concerns – we have with Iran’s behavior in the region, but we also know that as long as Iran has distanced itself from its JCPOA commitments, as long as Iran is in a position to undertake these provocations, including these nuclear provocations, that all of the other challenges we face with Iran – whether it is its support to proxies, its support to terrorist groups – all of them will be more difficult to confront.</p>
<p>So right now in Vienna, we are focused on seeing if we can effect that mutual return to compliance. The window for diplomacy remains open. The Secretary himself has said that that process won’t be open indefinitely, but for now we continue to see the diplomatic route as the best way and the most effective way to, again, ensure that Iran can never acquire a nuclear weapon. It’s what the JCPOA did. It’s what the JCPOA can once again do if we’re able to effect a return to mutual compliance.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I ask a follow-up on that quick?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah – yep.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> What do you mean by – when you’re stating that the process won’t be open indefinitely? Is there something that Iran is doing now that makes you think that window of opportunity is closing? Do you have a set timeframe or a concern after which Iran does something then the process closes? Can you elaborate a little bit?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we know a couple things. One, the JCPOA, when it was in full effect, lengthened that breakout time – that is to say, the time it would take Iran to acquire enough fissile material necessary to produce a nuclear weapon if it chose to do so and if it successfully undertook a weaponization process. Right now, as Iran has distanced itself from the JCPOA, as it has installed higher-tech centrifuges, as it has taken other provocative steps, including enriching to a higher level, we know that that breakout time has shrunk. And according to public reports, that breakout time has gone from a year, as it was with the JCPOA, to something closer to perhaps a few months, and it will get to a point where Iran’s provocations, Iran’s nuclear steps, that that breakout time and the concern that we have associated with it will potentially cause us to reconsider.</p>
<p>The Secretary has said this process won&#8217;t be open indefinitely. We don&#8217;t have a set timeline. We&#8217;re going to continue to assess the implications of Iran&#8217;s steps. We are going to continue to coordinate closely with other members of the P5+1, with other regional partners who, of course, also have their own profound concerns, as do we, about Iran&#8217;s nuclear activities. But again, for us, we see negotiations and diplomacy, indirect diplomacy in Vienna, as for now the best means to put Iran&#8217;s nuclear program back in a box, to ensure that once again Iran is permanently and verifiably prevented from obtaining a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So – but I mean, essentially, what you&#8217;re saying is there comes a point at which Iran advances so far technologically, whether with centrifuges or know-how, that the one-year breakout time enshrined in the JCPOA just becomes irrelevant and you’ll basically have to start over.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, we&#8217;re – look, again, we’re not imposing a deadline for negotiations. But as you’ve heard from the Secretary, we are, as you alluded to, conscious that as time proceeds, Iran&#8217;s nuclear advances will have a bearing on our view of returning to the JCPOA. And it will have a bearing because one of the chief advantages of the JCPOA was the elongation of that breakout time. If those advantages start to disappear, we&#8217;ll have to reassess where we are in this process.</p>
<p>Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Can I move to another topic?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Anything else on Iran? Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah. Speaking of timelines, when do you expect the seventh round to happen? And why is there a holdup?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, as you know, the parties are back in their capitals for consultations. We understand that those consultations are ongoing. As you know, there is not yet an announced date for the seventh round. But again, we are committed to diplomacy. When there is a seventh round, I would expect that Special Envoy Malley and his team will be present.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But what is the U.S. assessment that it is taking some time?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Again, consultations are ongoing in capitals, so I wouldn&#8217;t want to speak to other parties engaged in this.</p>
<p>Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you, Ned. A couple of quick questions on the Palestinian issue. It’s been reported that Israel and Hamas are edging towards an agreement on a mechanism to dispense or receive the money and distribute it and so on. First, are you part of this? Will you allow, for instance, if Hamas insists on controlling where this money goes or part of it and so on? Would you oppose sending money or sending the funds and so on? What is your position on it? And then I have one more question.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong><a id="post-257522-ISPAL"></a>As we’ve said, Said, we are committed to helping the Palestinian people rebuild from the recent violence. We are committed to providing the Palestinian people with the humanitarian assistance that they need both in the aftermath of the most recent violence, but from years of mismanagement, of neglect, of abuse by Hamas, the de facto governing authority. So we are committed to seeing to it that the humanitarian – that the Palestinian people receive that humanitarian relief, but we’re equally committed to ensuring that whether it’s – that certainly American aid does not in any way empower Hamas – empower Hamas financially, empower Hamas politically. And we have – we will continue to work with our partners, whether that&#8217;s Egypt, whether that&#8217;s the UN and its institutions, to see to it that we can do those two things: to provide that relief to the Palestinian people without that relief making its way into Hamas coffers.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But you will insist on having the UN do it or even the PA for that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> What is what is very clear is that U.S. funds will not be going to Hamas, and we will work with partners to see that it’s distributed effectively.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And another thing on the Palestinian Authority issue. Since June 24, there&#8217;s been demonstrations every day, lots of arrests, a great deal of a rough sort of response by the Palestinian security agencies and so on. And Abbas, for all practical purposes, has been basically besieged and isolated. Are you in touch with him? Do you see – are you pressuring him to sort of relent a little bit this iron-fist kind of approach by the Palestinian security forces?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> The administration has been in regular contact with our Palestinian counterparts, as well as with our Israeli counterparts, of course. We’ve also taken a consistent position that the leadership of the Palestinian Authority, that&#8217;s a matter for the Palestinian people to determine. We strongly encourage the Palestinian Authority, as we do around the world, to respect the right of free expression and the work of civil society.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Are you demanding that they release journalists, for instance, that have been arrested in the last few weeks, in the last couple – couple weeks?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Human rights and civil liberties, including freedom of information, freedom of expression – those are principles that we defend, that we promote around the world in every context. When journalists are detained, when freedom of expression is limited, we will voice our concerns over that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, on Hong Kong and then on Georgia. On Hong Kong, a group of companies, including Twitter, Facebook, and Google are warning that tech companies could stop offering their services in Hong Kong if the authorities there proceed with plans to change privacy laws. Do you have anything on that move?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-China"></a>Well, I would need to refer you to the companies to speak to their positions and their plans going forward. What I will say – that these reports, if verified, they’re yet another example of actions taken by Beijing and by Hong Kong authorities in recent months, over the past year, to undermine transparency, to undermine the rule of law, which have in turn eroded Hong Kong’s status as an international business hub and jeopardized Hong Kong’s long-term stability and prosperity. We have voiced our serious concerns over this. We have voiced those concerns in the context of the decreasing space for civil society and for the rights and freedoms to which the people of Hong Kong are entitled and to which they – and which they deserve, but would need to refer you to any private companies to speak to their plans.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Right. At the beginning of this briefing, you mentioned that there are some recommendation provided by the survivors of the Xinjiang internment camps. How did the firsthand discussion between Secretary Blinken and those survivors pave the way for further U.S. actions? What else is in the U.S. toolbox?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the session with the Xinjiang survivors, family members, and advocates – I didn’t have a chance to sit on it, and it was – it only briefly disbanded, from what I understand, but the Secretary thought it important to meet with these individuals, to hear firsthand their stories, to hear firsthand their impression of the ongoing atrocities in Xinjiang and the interment of a million Uyghurs. As I also mentioned, it’s an opportunity for these participants to offer any recommendations they may have. I don’t have a sense yet as to what they may have passed along, but again, we will issue a readout as soon as we’re able to this afternoon.</p>
<p>When it comes to the U.S. Government’s actions on Xinjiang, we have a pretty full toolkit. We have used a number of those tools effectively, whether that is atrocity determinations; whether that is financial sanctions, including financial sanctions that we have announced in conjunction with our partners and allies; whether that is visa restrictions; whether it’s export restrictions; whether it’s withhold release orders, including the recent withhold release orders that we announced just a couple weeks ago; of course, UN side events, joint statements, and other tools.</p>
<p>This administration – and, frankly, there’s been some continuity across administrations – America has spoken out very clearly and consistently about the abuses, about the atrocities, about the ongoing genocide that is taking place in Xinjiang. And as we deem appropriate, I suspect we’ll be employing additional tools going forward to hold to account those officials responsible for what has taken place there.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On Georgia quickly.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure, sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yesterday you tweeted about – you had a tweet to – about the attackers in Georgia against the LGBT community and the Pride parade. Do you have more to that? Because only three people were arrested. They were those who attacked the campaigners. Do you think the Georgian Government is doing enough? Do you have more to that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-Georgia"></a>Well, as you heard me say yesterday, we do condemn the violent attacks in Georgia that took place on July 5th on civic activists, on community members, on journalists. Georgia’s leaders, its law enforcement officials – they are obligated to protect the constitutional rights to freedom of expression, to freedom of assembly, and to prosecute those perpetrating violence. Georgians, as do people around the world, have a right to express their views, even when in a particular context they may be seen as unpopular or controversial, and we remind Georgia’s political leaders, we remind its law enforcement officials and institutions of that responsibility to protect all of those exercising their constitutional rights, to protect journalists exercising freedom of the press, and to publicly condemn the violence.</p>
<p>The United States Embassy in Georgia signed on to a joint statement along with several other missions on the ground. So it’s not just the United States speaking up about this; it’s several of our likeminded partners as well.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> My sources tell me that the Iraqi prime minister is visiting Washington at the end of this month. Can you confirm that? And will he be meeting with President Biden?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-Iraq"></a>So I don’t have any meetings to confirm at the moment. Of course, any White House meetings, any meetings with President Biden I would need to refer you to the White House for that. But of course, Prime Minister Kadhimi is an important partner. Our partnership with the government, with the people of Iraq is incredibly important to us. We have a number of shared interests, including the continued prosecution of the counter-ISIS campaign. But again, I would need to refer you to the White House for any &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> What about the strategical dialogue? Should it start also the end of this month here in Washington?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have any updates for you there. If we do, we’ll let you know more.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you update us on the Saudi deputy defense minister’s visit, and has he met with State Department officials (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-Saudi"></a>Sure. And I think you heard this from my colleague at the White House earlier today, but we can confirm that the Saudi deputy secretary of defense, Khalid bin Salman, is in Washington for a series of meetings with U.S. officials, and that includes State Department officials as well as NSC and DOD. They’ll be discussing important issues to the bilateral relationship. We do expect some readouts will be issued over the course of that visit, and I can confirm that Khalid bin Salman will be at the Department of State tomorrow.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Lara.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks. On Syria. Ahead of the July 10 deadline to renew the cross-border humanitarian access lanes, I’m just wondering what the discussions look like up in New York at the Security Council right now, what efforts are being made to convince the Russians to not block this, what kind of carrots and sticks might be offered. And then finally, if Russia does block this, how does the United States and the rest of the international community expect to get humanitarian aid to people in Syria?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-Syria"></a>Well, you heard from Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield on this earlier today. I believe she did a stake-out up in New York where she made several important points, and this is something that USUN, the Department of State, President Biden when he met with President Putin, have discussed at all levels, including the highest levels – not only with the Russian Federation, but with other UN Security Council members. Our diplomacy on this has always been concerted, but it has intensified because we have four days left before cross-border access into Syria officially expires. And it’s so important to us because that expiration risks millions of livelihoods and even lives.</p>
<p>Our message has been clear, and that’s that the Security Council must renew and expand the humanitarian access provided by Bab al-Hawa for 12 months. And we must do it now. We know that anything less than that period could severely complicate the ability of NGOs to reliably deliver aid while managing lengthy procurement processes associated with all of this.</p>
<p>We support all modalities of humanitarian aid in Syria. That includes cross-border, cross-border into Syria, and cross-line across the lines of control. And we’d offered to support expanding cross-line aid and we’ll continue to do so in good faith. And in fact, obviously we’re not going to read out all of our consultations in the Security Council or elsewhere, but we have put forward what I believe Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield called “a serious and credible proposal” to expand humanitarian assistance across Syria, and that includes cross-line and cross-border, and also includes much-needed COVID relief – again, to meet the urgent needs of the Syrian people.</p>
<p>We have heard repeatedly – including with increasing urgency from the UN secretary general, from UN aid agencies, from humanitarian organizations and NGOs operating on the ground – that there is no substitute for cross-border mechanisms. And cross-line aid alone we know cannot meet the needs of all Syrians, and those needs have only risen in the past year, including with the onset of COVID.</p>
<p>We also know that this is something the United States cannot do alone, and ultimately it will require the cooperation and active support of all parties on the ground, and that includes the regime, which has unfortunately used assistance to aid its allies and punish its perceived enemies. And so as the Syrian people continue to suffer, as COVID continues to spread, we cannot justify closing a reliable delivery route for humanitarian assistance, for vaccines. We cannot justify cutting off aid for innocent Syrians. And you heard Secretary Blinken address the UN Security Council on this several weeks ago now, but spoke of it in terms that were both urgent and personal, because it is a priority across this administration, it is an urgent priority on the part of Secretary Blinken. As you heard from Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield today, it is an urgent priority of hers and her team, and the administration is working and doing all we can to renew this mandate.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just to clarify, the crossline aid that you’re mentioning to include the COVID aid – would any of that be delivered directly to the Assad regime?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I – we’ll get back to you on that. Again, in any number of contexts, we are in a position through humanitarian organizations, through NGOs, to provide aid directly to those in need. I will say that this administration has no intention at present of normalizing relations with the Assad regime. It is the Assad regime that has brutalized its own people; it is the Assad regime that has weaponized humanitarian access and humanitarian aid deliveries; it’s the Assad regime that is responsible for much of the suffering on the part of the Syrian people. So again, our focus will be providing aid directly to those in need, working in concert with our partners and allies, and ultimately with the renewal, we hope, of the mandate at the UN.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. Earlier today China’s foreign minister released a readout of a phone call that took place between Ambassador Sung Kim and his Chinese counterpart. And I don’t believe the State Department has put anything out, so could you just confirm that that phone call took place, and could you share anything about the conversation? Did the ambassador ask China to use its influence to try and get North Korea to engage directly with the U.S.?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-China3"></a>Well, I can confirm that a call took place. We don’t have a readout to share of the call. But as you know, we have discussed our DPRK policy with the Chinese Government before. Secretary Blinken had an opportunity to speak to Director Yang just a couple weeks ago now, in which Secretary Blinken offered a summary of our DPRK policy review.</p>
<p>Knowing that – I’ve said this before already in this briefing – that the DPRK’s nuclear weapons and ballistic missile programs, these are not challenges that we can take on alone, that we can address alone, that we will need to work in lockstep, of course, with our allies, Japan and the Republic of Korea among others in this case. But of course, China and the PRC has a role to play as well and obviously has influence with the regime, with the DPRK regime. But I wouldn’t want to further characterize the call.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And to date, so far North Korea has not reciprocated or contacted the United States to engage directly?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-NorthKorea"></a>We have made very clear to the DPRK that we are ready to engage in good-faith, constructive diplomacy. We have extended messages and we are awaiting a constructive reply.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:06 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:14 p.m. EDT</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Good afternoon. Hope everyone had a very good Fourth of July weekend, hopefully back ready and refreshed.</p>
<p>Just one thing at the top today, and that is today <a id="post-257522-DaliLama"></a>we wish a happy birthday to His Holiness the Dalai Lama, whose grace and compassion have served as an inspiration to all of us. We commend his dedication to the global Tibetan community and to all those around the world who share in his important message of peace and kindness and his commitment to equality and, importantly, to human dignity. We join all of those in wishing His Holiness many more years to come.</p>
<p>Matt, would you like to &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Is that it?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> That is it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. Well, I thought I was going to be asking a follow-up, because I thought you were going to top – do a topper about the Ethiopia call. Let me just ask that Ethiopia question very briefly and then move on to something else. In the call that you guys read out with Prime Minister Abiy, it talked about Tigray and the troops and all that, but it didn’t mention anything about the GERD, about the dam. And as you probably know, the Ethiopians have begun filling it again, and I’m wondering if that came up in the call. And whether it did or not, do you have anything to say about that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-Ethiopia"></a>Well, we did issue a readout of the call with Prime Minister Abiy. We’ll let that readout speak for itself. When it comes to the GERD, what I will say is that we have continued to support collaborative and constructive efforts by the parties involved – and that’s Ethiopia, it’s Egypt and Sudan – to reach an enduring arrangement on the GERD. We understand, of course, the importance of the Nile waters to all three of these countries, and we continue to encourage a resumption of a dialogue that we hope is productive, and substantive, and constructive. In doing so, all along we’ve supported the AU-led process, a process that aims to lower tensions, that aims to facilitate productive negotiations and to enhance regional cooperation.</p>
<p>We do call on all parties to refrain from unilateral action, any unilateral action, that would raise those tensions, that would put greater distance between where we are now and a peaceful, constructive resolution to this. And we call for all parties to commit themselves to a negotiated solution that is acceptable to all sides.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, so – and this is – this would be a unilateral action that raises tensions, yes?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We have continued to encourage all parties to avoid unilateral actions that would raise tensions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And this is or isn’t a unilateral action that raises tensions?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I think it is fair to say that this has the potential to raise tensions.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. All right. If no one – I just want to go very briefly. You – it’s tangential to the Dalai Lama &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> &#8212; although it doesn’t – it has to do with China, but not Tibet. And that is just I’m wondering if you can tell – the meeting with – that the Secretary was having today with the Uyghurs, the Xinjiang internment camp people – it should be over by now, no? Is there anything you can tell us about that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-China1"></a>So we will have a readout of the meeting later today. It started just a little bit – a bit ago, about an hour ago. And so I do expect we’ll be able to offer a readout later today. This was an event that the State Department put together. It was with a number – I believe there were seven participants. These were survivors of the internment camps; these were family members; these were advocates on their behalf. This was something the Secretary wanted to do, to provide him an opportunity to reaffirm the administration’s emphasis on human rights when it comes to our China policy and to reaffirm our engagement with individuals from groups the government of the People’s Republic of China has repressed in Xinjiang. It will also enable – and I suspect it did enable – the members of the advocacy community who were present during this meeting to provide recommendations to the department for responding to the ongoing atrocities in Xinjiang. But again, we will have a readout of this later today.</p>
<p>Humyra. Humeyra, sorry.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Okay. <a id="post-257522-Ethiopia2"></a>Just want to follow up on Tigray, because he started with it. When Secretary Blinken asked Abiy for the withdrawal of the Eritrean troops and – what kind of assurance did he get? Or did he get one?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, again, we’re not going to go into the conversation beyond the readout that we did issue. But what I will say broadly is, of course, we all saw the announcement of the unilateral ceasefire late last month, June 28th I believe it was. What we know is that unilateral announcement needs to be followed up with concrete changes on the ground to end the conflict, to stop the atrocities, and importantly to allow safe and unhindered humanitarian assistance. The people of Tigray have and continue to suffer tremendously, and the ability of this humanitarian assistance to enter the region unimpeded and unhindered is of paramount importance to us. We call on all armed actors to commit to an immediate, indefinite negotiated ceasefire, so as to achieve the shared objectives, and they include to end the violence, to restore stability to Tigray, and going forward to create a context for inclusive dialogue that preserves the unity, the sovereignty, and the territorial integrity of the Ethiopian state. We further urge all actors and all parties to focus efforts toward resolution of the conflict through – as I said before – inclusive dialogue, and to allow fully unhindered humanitarian access to, in fact, expedite the delivery of that humanitarian aid. And access must include – but, of course, not be limited to – open transportation corridors and telecommunications infrastructure that would allow for the delivery of this humanitarian assistance for the civilian population. And that includes the ability of journalists to move about freely in the region as well.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi. Can I move on to Afghanistan if that’s all right with everyone?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hold on. Did you answer my – whether the dam came up in the call, or did it not? Or do you not know?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I said we issued a readout, and we’ll let that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I know, but it’s not in the readout.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> We’ll let the readout speak, and I did offer a quick &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I know you did. I just want to know whether he talked to him about it in the call.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I will – I did offer a quick synopsis of our policy.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yes.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> If we have more to say on the call itself, we will be happy to let you know.</p>
<p>Humeyra.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On Afghanistan, I’m sure you’ve seen the reporting about, like, water being cut off and power being cut off following the departure of U.S. troops. I’m just wondering if U.S. has any response to all of this. And what kind of message does this send to continued – the U.S. pledge of continued engagements in Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-Afghan"></a>Well, that is our message, and that has not changed, and that will not change. The President, from the day he announced that the U.S. military would be withdrawing, except for the troops necessary to protect our diplomatic compounds, was very clear that we have partnered with the Afghan people and with the Afghan Government over the course of some 20 years now; that partnership would not diminish in any way with the withdrawal – with the military withdrawal from Afghanistan. Again, we retain a diplomatic compound in Kabul; that is what we intend to retain going forward as well. We will be able to continue that partnership with the people of Aghanistan, with the Government of Afghanistan going forward, even as the military retrograde takes place.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are you making some updates to your evacuation plans for the embassy, given that Taliban has seized, like, a lot of provinces?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> The department is always taking a close look at security conditions around the world. The safety and security of our diplomats, of Foreign Service nationals, of others who are present on our diplomatic compounds is of paramount importance to us. So we are always taking a close look at that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I ask a follow-up on Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are you surprised – is the State Department surprised with the speed with which the Taliban have taken over outposts and roads and entire provinces in Afghanistan? Do you have any assessment on whether the Afghan Government can withstand that onslaught, and will it be viable?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I am not going to offer an assessment or any sort of feedback of our reaction from here. I will say as a matter of policy – and that’s where our focus has been, as a matter of policy – we have continued to call for an end to the ongoing violence, which of course has been driven largely by the Taliban. A negotiated settlement between the parties – in this case, the Islamic Republic and the Taliban – is the only way to end 40 years of war and to bring to Afghanistan the peace that the Afghan people both want and deserve. That’s why we continue to urge all sides to engage in serious negotiations to determine a political roadmap that leads to what we have called for all along and what the international community has called for all along, and that is a just and durable political settlement.</p>
<p>What we know is that the world will not accept an imposition by force of a government in Afghanistan. The legitimacy of any future Afghan government, the ability of that government to receive international assistance – which will be of critical importance – the durability of any future Afghan government can only be possible if that government has a basic respect for human rights.</p>
<p>It’s also worth noting, I think, in this context that it is not just the Government of Afghanistan, it is not just the United States, it’s not just a broad swath of the international community that recognizes that there is no military solution to this conflict. The fact that the Taliban continues to engage in Doha, to engage in intra-Afghan dialogue, is itself most likely a reflection of the fact that the Taliban too understands that only through diplomacy can they garner any sort of legitimacy, can they expect to be accepted by the international community. And it is, in fact, true that dialogue does continue in Doha. The parties have continued to meet (inaudible) goal in mind. And that was to disrupt and ultimately defeat the network of al-Qaida that conducted the 9/11 attacks. Osama bin Laden was brought to justice more than 10 years ago, 10 years ago in May.</p>
<p>And the other important point is that, of course, when we came into office in January there was already an existing agreement between the United States Government and the Taliban. And so like it or not, on May 1st the status quo that would have been in place on April 30th was going to change. And so the administration, the President, was confronted with a situation in which on May 1st, because of an agreement that the previous administration negotiated – I think if you recall, the President said in his remarks when he announced the military withdrawal that it’s not an agreement that this administration necessarily would have designed, but it’s one we inherited – that American troops would potentially come under attack starting on May 1st if they remained in the country.</p>
<p>And so the President faced a decision: potentially recreate the cycle of violence and escalation, or change strategy and continue our partnership with the Afghan Government, continue our partnership with the Afghan people, but removing American service members as bargaining chips, because to President Biden that’s not who they are. Our service members went into Afghanistan; they were successful in the mission they were asked to do by successive U.S. presidents. Of course, a small contingent will remain to provide security at our diplomatic compound. But to continue to have a larger number of U.S. military forces in harm’s way was not something that the President was willing to commit to. It’s not something that the administration felt was necessary to achieve the collective ends there.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But Ned, the problem with the – the problem with that – did someone else want to ask about Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Afghanistan, yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> I’m just wondering if the Taliban continues with its military offenses in the north, will the U.S. continue to diplomatically engage with them?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, right now we are supporting the intra-Afghan dialogue, and a couple things can be true at the same time. It is absolutely true that a political solution is the only way, again, to achieve that just and durable outcome that all parties want and all parties seem to understand is the only end to 40 years of conflict. It’s also true, again, that any government that comes to power at the barrel of a gun, through force, is not one that will have popular support, it is not one that will accrue assistance from the international community, it is not one that will have international legitimacy. And for all those reasons, it is almost certainly not one that will have durability. And what we seek, again, is a just and durable political outcome, and only through dialogue – in this case intra-Afghan dialogue – can that be achieved.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> So I guess the answer is yes, as they continue with their military offenses you will continue to engage with them diplomatically.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, wouldn’t want to entertain a hypothetical. But we know in this case &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Well, it’s not a hypothetical. It’s going on right now.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, you’re asking about something that could continue. We have also seen the statements from the Taliban that I referred to just a moment ago that they intend to intensify that diplomacy. So again, we’ll see if they make good on that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And one quick question. If they take their military offenses to Kabul, will that change the calculation diplomatically between the U.S. and the Taliban?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, I don’t want to entertain the hypothetical. We have – what will remain is our partnership with the Afghan Government, with the Afghan people. We will continue down that path and wouldn’t want to entertain a hypothetical like that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But I mean, there’s going to be – your current assessment, like, things are happening on the ground and they’re seizing district after district. You must have some sort of an assessment, like a cutoff point: if this happens then we’re going to stop disengaging. And the same goes for the evacuation plan as well.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, of course, the State Department, the Department of Defense, these are planning organizations. We’re always planning for any contingency. And so when it comes to the safety and security of our people on the ground, when it comes to our diplomatic approaches, when it comes to our policy, of course, we’re planning for any number of contingencies.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, I don’t understand three things. One, I don’t understand how you’re able to make this claim that the Taliban actually want international acceptance and aid when there is nothing in their history that suggests that they do. I’ve asked you about this before, and I – there is no good answer other than, well, a bunch of them are in Doha talking. But that doesn’t mean anything. They never wanted or cared about – they were perfectly happy when Pakistan was the only country on the planet that recognized them. That’s number one.</p>
<p>Number two, the argument that you guys inherited an agreement with the Taliban that the previous administration concluded and that you had no choice, I don’t understand that either. This administration inherited plenty from the previous administration that it absolutely reversed. Are you saying that you’re not – you have a – you’re not confident in your negotiating skills that you could have renegotiated with – that you couldn’t have renegotiated a deal with the Taliban and that the – and are you saying that the President, in fact, didn’t want to take troops out, didn’t want to withdraw?</p>
<p>And then lastly, the thing I don’t understand – well, maybe not understand, but you don’t want to talk about the historic analogy that Said made to Vietnam. Let’s go next door to Cambodia. Are you familiar at all with the letter that Sirik Matak wrote to John Gunther Dean, who was the U.S. ambassador to Cambodia in April of 1975?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>It’s &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>If you’re not familiar with it &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>It’s been a while.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>&#8212; I suggest you familiarize yourself with it because it may end up being sadly prescient. But if you could answer the first two, that would be great. Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Sure. Well, on your second question, Matt, I think you’re actually confusing different things here. These are apples and oranges. Yes, we changed quite a few U.S. policies across a number of fronts, but I think you would be hard-pressed to find an international agreement that the United States signed on to during the last administration that this administration has jettisoned, done away with. This is the point that we have made in any number of different &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>How about the Geneva protocol on the anti-abortion stuff?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>This was the point that we have made on any number of steps about the importance of the durability of American foreign policies – American foreign policy across administrations.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>How about the agreements with the Northern Triangle, with Mexico and the Northern Triangle? Those are international agreements that you guys jettisoned.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>These are – Matt, I think &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>I mean, you just challenged me to come up with an international agreement that the previous administration signed that you guys have walked away from, and I just gave you, I think, three.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>The previous administration had its own policies. This administration has different policies across a number of fronts. But this administration also understands the importance of when the United States signs its name and gives its word in the context of a formal international agreement, especially one where the stakes are profound for American – the American people, including our service members, deployed service members, that’s something that we take very seriously. So the idea that we could have done away with the U.S.-Taliban agreement and that American service members could have remained in Afghanistan on May 1st, as they were on April 30th as they were on December 31st of 2020, is just not something that would have been feasible given where we were.</p>
<p>The idea – your first question, the notion that the Taliban don’t believe in a negotiated political solution – you yourself said that they are engaged in Doha. Again, it’s not just the process. It’s the outcomes that we’re interested in, and that’s what we’ll be watching for. As I said, we have seen statements that at least purport – with which the Taliban at least purport to seek to accelerate that diplomacy. Again, we’ll see if it comes to fruition.</p>
<p>But I think the broader point is that whether the Taliban or any other future Afghan government likes it, they are going to need international assistance; they are going to need international legitimacy; they are going to need the popular support of the Afghan people; and any Afghan government that comes to power at the barrel of a gun, that comes to power through the use of force, is almost certainly going to lack those critical ingredients.</p>
<p>And so when we talk about a just and durable outcome, it is hard if not impossible to envision an outcome that is just, that is durable, without having arrived at – having been arrived at through negotiations and, in this case, through diplomacy.</p>
<p>Conor.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Just on those negotiations, because since they first met last September, they’ve yet to yield anything except an agenda at this point. What are you doing to accelerate that process, especially after the Istanbul conference didn’t happen?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>So we have supported this process. Of course, we are not a party to these negotiations. All throughout we have played a supporting role. We have supported the parties in Doha. We have galvanized the international community. We have done so in the context of the UN as well, all the while continuing our partnership with the Government of Afghanistan and the people of Afghanistan.</p>
<p>So again, believe me, I am not out here to offer false hope when it comes to what the Taliban may seek or what they’re up to now. We have seen their statements. We certainly encourage them to follow through on their statements. But again, process is one thing. What matters most is the outcome. And the outcome we seek, the outcome the international community seeks, is a just and a durable political solution, and really, the only way to achieve that, again, is through diplomacy – in this case, diplomacy between the parties – that is now taking place in Doha.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> But why even reference their statements when what is happening in Afghanistan is so directly opposed to what they are saying in paper statements?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Again, we will see. They have an opportunity ahead of them in the coming days, in the coming several weeks, to make good on what they have said. I am not here, again, to offer optimism or to characterize what we make of their statements. That’s to them to make good on.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just one last question: Is Zal in Doha still? Is he playing any sort of shuttle diplomacy role in any of this to try to accelerate the process?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Members of the team have been engaged on the ground in Doha. As I understand it, the – Ambassador Khalilzad is here in Washington, but if there is a need for him to go back to Doha, he will be prepared to do so, yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> In new report with the board of governors in the IAEA, the Director General Grossi today announced that Iran intends to use uranium enriched up to 20 percent. How do you comment on that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-Iran"></a>Well, as I understand it, this report remains restricted until it’s released by the IAEA board of governors, but we’ve seen the media reports that characterize this document. It is worrying that Iran is choosing to continue to escalate its nonperformance of its JCPOA commitments, especially with experiments that have value for nuclear weapons research. It’s another unfortunate step backwards for Iran, particularly as we for our part have demonstrated our sincere intention and willingness to return to the JCPOA and to find more productive and durable ways to deal with the nuclear issue.</p>
<p>We have made clear that such provocative steps would not and will not provide Iran with any leverage in negotiations. Instead, they would only intensify our concerns with Iran’s activities, and we continue to urge Iran to stop this brinksmanship, to return to Vienna prepared for real talks, and to be in a position to be prepared to finish the work that we have started in April that has now taken place over six rounds.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Are you considering a new approach? You said diplomacy is the best way. You said now it’s unfortunate step, but you did six rounds of talks. There was an attack against a U.S. airbase yesterday, and also, for example, in Yemen there is no progress. You said you are fed up with the Houthis. How you would proceed?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Right. Well, the talks in Vienna that have now completed six rounds, they’re about one thing and they’re about one thing only, and that is a return to mutual compliance with the JCPOA. And for us, the important consequence of that is a reimposition of the most stringent verification and monitoring regime ever negotiated. So you are right that there are a whole host of other concerns – profound concerns – we have with Iran’s behavior in the region, but we also know that as long as Iran has distanced itself from its JCPOA commitments, as long as Iran is in a position to undertake these provocations, including these nuclear provocations, that all of the other challenges we face with Iran – whether it is its support to proxies, its support to terrorist groups – all of them will be more difficult to confront.</p>
<p>So right now in Vienna, we are focused on seeing if we can effect that mutual return to compliance. The window for diplomacy remains open. The Secretary himself has said that that process won’t be open indefinitely, but for now we continue to see the diplomatic route as the best way and the most effective way to, again, ensure that Iran can never acquire a nuclear weapon. It’s what the JCPOA did. It’s what the JCPOA can once again do if we’re able to effect a return to mutual compliance.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can I ask a follow-up on that quick?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Yeah – yep.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> What do you mean by – when you’re stating that the process won’t be open indefinitely? Is there something that Iran is doing now that makes you think that window of opportunity is closing? Do you have a set timeframe or a concern after which Iran does something then the process closes? Can you elaborate a little bit?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, we know a couple things. One, the JCPOA, when it was in full effect, lengthened that breakout time – that is to say, the time it would take Iran to acquire enough fissile material necessary to produce a nuclear weapon if it chose to do so and if it successfully undertook a weaponization process. Right now, as Iran has distanced itself from the JCPOA, as it has installed higher-tech centrifuges, as it has taken other provocative steps, including enriching to a higher level, we know that that breakout time has shrunk. And according to public reports, that breakout time has gone from a year, as it was with the JCPOA, to something closer to perhaps a few months, and it will get to a point where Iran’s provocations, Iran’s nuclear steps, that that breakout time and the concern that we have associated with it will potentially cause us to reconsider.</p>
<p>The Secretary has said this process won&#8217;t be open indefinitely. We don&#8217;t have a set timeline. We&#8217;re going to continue to assess the implications of Iran&#8217;s steps. We are going to continue to coordinate closely with other members of the P5+1, with other regional partners who, of course, also have their own profound concerns, as do we, about Iran&#8217;s nuclear activities. But again, for us, we see negotiations and diplomacy, indirect diplomacy in Vienna, as for now the best means to put Iran&#8217;s nuclear program back in a box, to ensure that once again Iran is permanently and verifiably prevented from obtaining a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>So – but I mean, essentially, what you&#8217;re saying is there comes a point at which Iran advances so far technologically, whether with centrifuges or know-how, that the one-year breakout time enshrined in the JCPOA just becomes irrelevant and you’ll basically have to start over.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, we&#8217;re – look, again, we’re not imposing a deadline for negotiations. But as you’ve heard from the Secretary, we are, as you alluded to, conscious that as time proceeds, Iran&#8217;s nuclear advances will have a bearing on our view of returning to the JCPOA. And it will have a bearing because one of the chief advantages of the JCPOA was the elongation of that breakout time. If those advantages start to disappear, we&#8217;ll have to reassess where we are in this process.</p>
<p>Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Can I move to another topic?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Anything else on Iran? Yeah.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Yeah. Speaking of timelines, when do you expect the seventh round to happen? And why is there a holdup?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Well, as you know, the parties are back in their capitals for consultations. We understand that those consultations are ongoing. As you know, there is not yet an announced date for the seventh round. But again, we are committed to diplomacy. When there is a seventh round, I would expect that Special Envoy Malley and his team will be present.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But what is the U.S. assessment that it is taking some time?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong>Again, consultations are ongoing in capitals, so I wouldn&#8217;t want to speak to other parties engaged in this.</p>
<p>Said.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Thank you, Ned. A couple of quick questions on the Palestinian issue. It’s been reported that Israel and Hamas are edging towards an agreement on a mechanism to dispense or receive the money and distribute it and so on. First, are you part of this? Will you allow, for instance, if Hamas insists on controlling where this money goes or part of it and so on? Would you oppose sending money or sending the funds and so on? What is your position on it? And then I have one more question.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong><a id="post-257522-ISPAL"></a>As we’ve said, Said, we are committed to helping the Palestinian people rebuild from the recent violence. We are committed to providing the Palestinian people with the humanitarian assistance that they need both in the aftermath of the most recent violence, but from years of mismanagement, of neglect, of abuse by Hamas, the de facto governing authority. So we are committed to seeing to it that the humanitarian – that the Palestinian people receive that humanitarian relief, but we’re equally committed to ensuring that whether it’s – that certainly American aid does not in any way empower Hamas – empower Hamas financially, empower Hamas politically. And we have – we will continue to work with our partners, whether that&#8217;s Egypt, whether that&#8217;s the UN and its institutions, to see to it that we can do those two things: to provide that relief to the Palestinian people without that relief making its way into Hamas coffers.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>But you will insist on having the UN do it or even the PA for that &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> What is what is very clear is that U.S. funds will not be going to Hamas, and we will work with partners to see that it’s distributed effectively.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>And another thing on the Palestinian Authority issue. Since June 24, there&#8217;s been demonstrations every day, lots of arrests, a great deal of a rough sort of response by the Palestinian security agencies and so on. And Abbas, for all practical purposes, has been basically besieged and isolated. Are you in touch with him? Do you see – are you pressuring him to sort of relent a little bit this iron-fist kind of approach by the Palestinian security forces?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> The administration has been in regular contact with our Palestinian counterparts, as well as with our Israeli counterparts, of course. We’ve also taken a consistent position that the leadership of the Palestinian Authority, that&#8217;s a matter for the Palestinian people to determine. We strongly encourage the Palestinian Authority, as we do around the world, to respect the right of free expression and the work of civil society.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Are you demanding that they release journalists, for instance, that have been arrested in the last few weeks, in the last couple – couple weeks?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE: </strong> Human rights and civil liberties, including freedom of information, freedom of expression – those are principles that we defend, that we promote around the world in every context. When journalists are detained, when freedom of expression is limited, we will voice our concerns over that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Ned, on Hong Kong and then on Georgia. On Hong Kong, a group of companies, including Twitter, Facebook, and Google are warning that tech companies could stop offering their services in Hong Kong if the authorities there proceed with plans to change privacy laws. Do you have anything on that move?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-China"></a>Well, I would need to refer you to the companies to speak to their positions and their plans going forward. What I will say – that these reports, if verified, they’re yet another example of actions taken by Beijing and by Hong Kong authorities in recent months, over the past year, to undermine transparency, to undermine the rule of law, which have in turn eroded Hong Kong’s status as an international business hub and jeopardized Hong Kong’s long-term stability and prosperity. We have voiced our serious concerns over this. We have voiced those concerns in the context of the decreasing space for civil society and for the rights and freedoms to which the people of Hong Kong are entitled and to which they – and which they deserve, but would need to refer you to any private companies to speak to their plans.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Right. At the beginning of this briefing, you mentioned that there are some recommendation provided by the survivors of the Xinjiang internment camps. How did the firsthand discussion between Secretary Blinken and those survivors pave the way for further U.S. actions? What else is in the U.S. toolbox?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Well, the session with the Xinjiang survivors, family members, and advocates – I didn’t have a chance to sit on it, and it was – it only briefly disbanded, from what I understand, but the Secretary thought it important to meet with these individuals, to hear firsthand their stories, to hear firsthand their impression of the ongoing atrocities in Xinjiang and the interment of a million Uyghurs. As I also mentioned, it’s an opportunity for these participants to offer any recommendations they may have. I don’t have a sense yet as to what they may have passed along, but again, we will issue a readout as soon as we’re able to this afternoon.</p>
<p>When it comes to the U.S. Government’s actions on Xinjiang, we have a pretty full toolkit. We have used a number of those tools effectively, whether that is atrocity determinations; whether that is financial sanctions, including financial sanctions that we have announced in conjunction with our partners and allies; whether that is visa restrictions; whether it’s export restrictions; whether it’s withhold release orders, including the recent withhold release orders that we announced just a couple weeks ago; of course, UN side events, joint statements, and other tools.</p>
<p>This administration – and, frankly, there’s been some continuity across administrations – America has spoken out very clearly and consistently about the abuses, about the atrocities, about the ongoing genocide that is taking place in Xinjiang. And as we deem appropriate, I suspect we’ll be employing additional tools going forward to hold to account those officials responsible for what has taken place there.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> On Georgia quickly.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Sure, sure.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Yesterday you tweeted about – you had a tweet to – about the attackers in Georgia against the LGBT community and the Pride parade. Do you have more to that? Because only three people were arrested. They were those who attacked the campaigners. Do you think the Georgian Government is doing enough? Do you have more to that?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-Georgia"></a>Well, as you heard me say yesterday, we do condemn the violent attacks in Georgia that took place on July 5th on civic activists, on community members, on journalists. Georgia’s leaders, its law enforcement officials – they are obligated to protect the constitutional rights to freedom of expression, to freedom of assembly, and to prosecute those perpetrating violence. Georgians, as do people around the world, have a right to express their views, even when in a particular context they may be seen as unpopular or controversial, and we remind Georgia’s political leaders, we remind its law enforcement officials and institutions of that responsibility to protect all of those exercising their constitutional rights, to protect journalists exercising freedom of the press, and to publicly condemn the violence.</p>
<p>The United States Embassy in Georgia signed on to a joint statement along with several other missions on the ground. So it’s not just the United States speaking up about this; it’s several of our likeminded partners as well.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> My sources tell me that the Iraqi prime minister is visiting Washington at the end of this month. Can you confirm that? And will he be meeting with President Biden?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-Iraq"></a>So I don’t have any meetings to confirm at the moment. Of course, any White House meetings, any meetings with President Biden I would need to refer you to the White House for that. But of course, Prime Minister Kadhimi is an important partner. Our partnership with the government, with the people of Iraq is incredibly important to us. We have a number of shared interests, including the continued prosecution of the counter-ISIS campaign. But again, I would need to refer you to the White House for any &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> What about the strategical dialogue? Should it start also the end of this month here in Washington?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I don’t have any updates for you there. If we do, we’ll let you know more.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Can you update us on the Saudi deputy defense minister’s visit, and has he met with State Department officials (inaudible)?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-Saudi"></a>Sure. And I think you heard this from my colleague at the White House earlier today, but we can confirm that the Saudi deputy secretary of defense, Khalid bin Salman, is in Washington for a series of meetings with U.S. officials, and that includes State Department officials as well as NSC and DOD. They’ll be discussing important issues to the bilateral relationship. We do expect some readouts will be issued over the course of that visit, and I can confirm that Khalid bin Salman will be at the Department of State tomorrow.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> Lara.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks. On Syria. Ahead of the July 10 deadline to renew the cross-border humanitarian access lanes, I’m just wondering what the discussions look like up in New York at the Security Council right now, what efforts are being made to convince the Russians to not block this, what kind of carrots and sticks might be offered. And then finally, if Russia does block this, how does the United States and the rest of the international community expect to get humanitarian aid to people in Syria?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-Syria"></a>Well, you heard from Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield on this earlier today. I believe she did a stake-out up in New York where she made several important points, and this is something that USUN, the Department of State, President Biden when he met with President Putin, have discussed at all levels, including the highest levels – not only with the Russian Federation, but with other UN Security Council members. Our diplomacy on this has always been concerted, but it has intensified because we have four days left before cross-border access into Syria officially expires. And it’s so important to us because that expiration risks millions of livelihoods and even lives.</p>
<p>Our message has been clear, and that’s that the Security Council must renew and expand the humanitarian access provided by Bab al-Hawa for 12 months. And we must do it now. We know that anything less than that period could severely complicate the ability of NGOs to reliably deliver aid while managing lengthy procurement processes associated with all of this.</p>
<p>We support all modalities of humanitarian aid in Syria. That includes cross-border, cross-border into Syria, and cross-line across the lines of control. And we’d offered to support expanding cross-line aid and we’ll continue to do so in good faith. And in fact, obviously we’re not going to read out all of our consultations in the Security Council or elsewhere, but we have put forward what I believe Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield called “a serious and credible proposal” to expand humanitarian assistance across Syria, and that includes cross-line and cross-border, and also includes much-needed COVID relief – again, to meet the urgent needs of the Syrian people.</p>
<p>We have heard repeatedly – including with increasing urgency from the UN secretary general, from UN aid agencies, from humanitarian organizations and NGOs operating on the ground – that there is no substitute for cross-border mechanisms. And cross-line aid alone we know cannot meet the needs of all Syrians, and those needs have only risen in the past year, including with the onset of COVID.</p>
<p>We also know that this is something the United States cannot do alone, and ultimately it will require the cooperation and active support of all parties on the ground, and that includes the regime, which has unfortunately used assistance to aid its allies and punish its perceived enemies. And so as the Syrian people continue to suffer, as COVID continues to spread, we cannot justify closing a reliable delivery route for humanitarian assistance, for vaccines. We cannot justify cutting off aid for innocent Syrians. And you heard Secretary Blinken address the UN Security Council on this several weeks ago now, but spoke of it in terms that were both urgent and personal, because it is a priority across this administration, it is an urgent priority on the part of Secretary Blinken. As you heard from Ambassador Thomas-Greenfield today, it is an urgent priority of hers and her team, and the administration is working and doing all we can to renew this mandate.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Just to clarify, the crossline aid that you’re mentioning to include the COVID aid – would any of that be delivered directly to the Assad regime?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> I – we’ll get back to you on that. Again, in any number of contexts, we are in a position through humanitarian organizations, through NGOs, to provide aid directly to those in need. I will say that this administration has no intention at present of normalizing relations with the Assad regime. It is the Assad regime that has brutalized its own people; it is the Assad regime that has weaponized humanitarian access and humanitarian aid deliveries; it’s the Assad regime that is responsible for much of the suffering on the part of the Syrian people. So again, our focus will be providing aid directly to those in need, working in concert with our partners and allies, and ultimately with the renewal, we hope, of the mandate at the UN.</p>
<p>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks, Ned. Earlier today China’s foreign minister released a readout of a phone call that took place between Ambassador Sung Kim and his Chinese counterpart. And I don’t believe the State Department has put anything out, so could you just confirm that that phone call took place, and could you share anything about the conversation? Did the ambassador ask China to use its influence to try and get North Korea to engage directly with the U.S.?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-China3"></a>Well, I can confirm that a call took place. We don’t have a readout to share of the call. But as you know, we have discussed our DPRK policy with the Chinese Government before. Secretary Blinken had an opportunity to speak to Director Yang just a couple weeks ago now, in which Secretary Blinken offered a summary of our DPRK policy review.</p>
<p>Knowing that – I’ve said this before already in this briefing – that the DPRK’s nuclear weapons and ballistic missile programs, these are not challenges that we can take on alone, that we can address alone, that we will need to work in lockstep, of course, with our allies, Japan and the Republic of Korea among others in this case. But of course, China and the PRC has a role to play as well and obviously has influence with the regime, with the DPRK regime. But I wouldn’t want to further characterize the call.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> And to date, so far North Korea has not reciprocated or contacted the United States to engage directly?</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong> <a id="post-257522-NorthKorea"></a>We have made very clear to the DPRK that we are ready to engage in good-faith, constructive diplomacy. We have extended messages and we are awaiting a constructive reply.</p>
<p>Thank you all very much.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 3:06 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Roundtable with Xinjiang Internment Camp Survivors and Advocates</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-roundtable-with-xinjiang-internment-camp-survivors-and-advocates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 22:11:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=257533</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:‎</p>
<p>Today Secretary Blinken met with seven Uyghur internment camp survivors, advocates, and relatives of individuals detained in Xinjiang to express the United States’ commitment to work with allies and partners in calling for an end to the People’s Republic of China (PRC)’s ongoing crimes against humanity and genocide against Uyghurs and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups in Xinjiang; to prevent the refoulement of such persons to the PRC; and to promote accountability for the PRC government’s actions and justice for victims and their families. The United States will continue to place human rights at the forefront of our China policy and will always support the voices of activists, survivors, and family members of victims who courageously speak out against these atrocities.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:‎</p>
<p>Today Secretary Blinken met with seven Uyghur internment camp survivors, advocates, and relatives of individuals detained in Xinjiang to express the United States’ commitment to work with allies and partners in calling for an end to the People’s Republic of China (PRC)’s ongoing crimes against humanity and genocide against Uyghurs and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups in Xinjiang; to prevent the refoulement of such persons to the PRC; and to promote accountability for the PRC government’s actions and justice for victims and their families. The United States will continue to place human rights at the forefront of our China policy and will always support the voices of activists, survivors, and family members of victims who courageously speak out against these atrocities.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Tanzanian President Hassan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-tanzanian-president-hassan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 17:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=257457</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Tanzanian President Samia Suluhu Hassan today.  They discussed the importance of the ongoing international partnership to combat the COVID-19 pandemic and how the United States can support Tanzania in fighting the pandemic.  Secretary Blinken and President Hassan addressed regional security issues, including Tanzania’s positive role as a peacekeeping contributor and areas for potential future cooperation.  Secretary Blinken and President Hassan also spoke about the importance of political rights and civil liberties, as well as our shared efforts to ensure a democratic, peaceful, free, and prosperous future for all Tanzanians.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Tanzanian President Samia Suluhu Hassan today.  They discussed the importance of the ongoing international partnership to combat the COVID-19 pandemic and how the United States can support Tanzania in fighting the pandemic.  Secretary Blinken and President Hassan addressed regional security issues, including Tanzania’s positive role as a peacekeeping contributor and areas for potential future cooperation.  Secretary Blinken and President Hassan also spoke about the importance of political rights and civil liberties, as well as our shared efforts to ensure a democratic, peaceful, free, and prosperous future for all Tanzanians.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solomon Islands’ National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/solomon-islands-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 14:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=257405</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I extend my best wishes to the people of the Solomon Islands as you celebrate your National Day on July 7<sup>th</sup>.</p>
<p>We are proud of the results of our shared commitment to stability, democracy, and sustainable development.  The launch of the U.S. Agency for International Development’s (USAID) Strengthening Competitiveness, Agribusiness, Livelihoods and Environment (SCALE) program and the Millennium Challenge Corporation Board’s approval of a threshold program are both testaments to the promise and results of our friendship.  Guided by our common values and shared history, we are dedicated to continuing to work together to address the challenges of the climate crisis and COVID-19.  We look forward to the advancement and growth of our partnership in the years to come.</p>
<p>Please accept my warmest regards as you commemorate this historic day of independence.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I extend my best wishes to the people of the Solomon Islands as you celebrate your National Day on July 7<sup>th</sup>.</p>
<p>We are proud of the results of our shared commitment to stability, democracy, and sustainable development.  The launch of the U.S. Agency for International Development’s (USAID) Strengthening Competitiveness, Agribusiness, Livelihoods and Environment (SCALE) program and the Millennium Challenge Corporation Board’s approval of a threshold program are both testaments to the promise and results of our friendship.  Guided by our common values and shared history, we are dedicated to continuing to work together to address the challenges of the climate crisis and COVID-19.  We look forward to the advancement and growth of our partnership in the years to come.</p>
<p>Please accept my warmest regards as you commemorate this historic day of independence.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
