<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 20:32:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Congratulations to Costa Rican President-Elect Rodrigo Chaves</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/congratulations-to-costa-rican-president-elect-rodrigo-chaves/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 20:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=331276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States congratulates Rodrigo Chaves Robles on his election as Costa Rica’s next president.  We also congratulate Costa Ricans for participating in and carrying out an electoral process consistent with Costa Rica’s strong democratic traditions.  Costa Rica represents a beacon of democracy in the Americas and the world, and our bilateral relations remain rooted in shared democratic values embracing freedom, inclusivity, and respect for human rights.  We look forward to strengthening ties between our nations to advance common interests, including humane migration management, protecting the environment, and working with democratic partners in the region toward a more secure, prosperous, and democratic hemisphere.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States congratulates Rodrigo Chaves Robles on his election as Costa Rica’s next president.  We also congratulate Costa Ricans for participating in and carrying out an electoral process consistent with Costa Rica’s strong democratic traditions.  Costa Rica represents a beacon of democracy in the Americas and the world, and our bilateral relations remain rooted in shared democratic values embracing freedom, inclusivity, and respect for human rights.  We look forward to strengthening ties between our nations to advance common interests, including humane migration management, protecting the environment, and working with democratic partners in the region toward a more secure, prosperous, and democratic hemisphere.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Bangladeshi Foreign Minister Abdul Momen Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-bangladeshi-foreign-minister-abdul-momen-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 19:24:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=331205</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a pleasure to have Foreign Minister Momen here and to be able to work together on strengthening more the partnership between the United States and Bangladesh.  We are in fact celebrating 50 years of diplomatic relations.  And even as we think back on those 50 years, we’re really looking ahead to the start of the next 50 and the work that we can do together, as I said, to strengthen our partnership.</p>
<p>Bangladesh has been a leader in rallying other countries to deal with the climate crisis that the planet is facing.  We deeply appreciate that, and we’re working closely together as well on COVID-19, and we’re proud to have been able to contribute through COVAX some 61 million vaccine doses to Bangladesh.</p>
<p>In turn, Bangladesh of course is showing extraordinary humanity and generosity in hosting nearly 1 million Rohingya who have had to flee persecution in Burma.  We’re grateful for that, and the work that you’ve done as one of the strongest supporters of UN peacekeeping around the world, and many other things as well.  But we’ll have an opportunity today to discuss the work we’re doing together bilaterally in the region and indeed even globally.</p>
<p>So Mr. Minister, welcome.  It’s very good to have you.  We look forward to the conversation ahead.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER MOMEN:</b>  Thank you.  Thank you, Excellency.  Thank you for giving me time and this meeting with my colleagues.  And also I’m thankful to you for committing 61 million of the vaccines – the highest among all the countries.  I think Bangladesh is the number one in terms of receiving the vaccine.  And also in addition, the 31 million for the recent economic assistance.  And I also thank you because you have declared the genocide in Myanmar, and we’re so happy you did.  I hope there will be some repatriation of these persecuted people.</p>
<p>And I’m very pleased that today – the other day we received a letter from President Biden.  And it is an excellent letter.  It helps what we want to do.  It talks about the last 50 years; we have done a remarkable achievement.  And U.S. has been always a friend of Bangladesh, during our bad times and our good times.  And we look forward for a bright future, and that’s why I’m here.</p>
<p>And also I would like to say that over the last 50 years, Bangladesh really achieved many – a lot of achievements.  We were known to be a bottomless basket, but now we have a vibrant economy, a land of opportunity.  And the U.S. has been a great partner and friend; over the years   you have supported that, and U.S.-Bangladesh will be – your achievement in Bangladesh will be magnified because the U.S. efforts helped us all the way.</p>
<p>But Bangladesh is doing pretty well.  The U.S. is our – the biggest trading partner, and also accumulated – the investments in Bangladesh, the U.S. is the largest.  But most of the investment has been in the energy sector.  Maybe it is time to look beyond that.  And I am looking forward for more enhanced and solid – rock-solid relationship with the United States of America.</p>
<p>And I always have some indebtedness to you because when I was homeless, jobless, and stateless, it is USA that provided me a home and a job, and I am thankful for that.</p>
<p>Thank you.  Thank you, Excellency.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you, Mr. Minister.  Thank you all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a pleasure to have Foreign Minister Momen here and to be able to work together on strengthening more the partnership between the United States and Bangladesh.  We are in fact celebrating 50 years of diplomatic relations.  And even as we think back on those 50 years, we’re really looking ahead to the start of the next 50 and the work that we can do together, as I said, to strengthen our partnership.</p>
<p>Bangladesh has been a leader in rallying other countries to deal with the climate crisis that the planet is facing.  We deeply appreciate that, and we’re working closely together as well on COVID-19, and we’re proud to have been able to contribute through COVAX some 61 million vaccine doses to Bangladesh.</p>
<p>In turn, Bangladesh of course is showing extraordinary humanity and generosity in hosting nearly 1 million Rohingya who have had to flee persecution in Burma.  We’re grateful for that, and the work that you’ve done as one of the strongest supporters of UN peacekeeping around the world, and many other things as well.  But we’ll have an opportunity today to discuss the work we’re doing together bilaterally in the region and indeed even globally.</p>
<p>So Mr. Minister, welcome.  It’s very good to have you.  We look forward to the conversation ahead.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER MOMEN:</b>  Thank you.  Thank you, Excellency.  Thank you for giving me time and this meeting with my colleagues.  And also I’m thankful to you for committing 61 million of the vaccines – the highest among all the countries.  I think Bangladesh is the number one in terms of receiving the vaccine.  And also in addition, the 31 million for the recent economic assistance.  And I also thank you because you have declared the genocide in Myanmar, and we’re so happy you did.  I hope there will be some repatriation of these persecuted people.</p>
<p>And I’m very pleased that today – the other day we received a letter from President Biden.  And it is an excellent letter.  It helps what we want to do.  It talks about the last 50 years; we have done a remarkable achievement.  And U.S. has been always a friend of Bangladesh, during our bad times and our good times.  And we look forward for a bright future, and that’s why I’m here.</p>
<p>And also I would like to say that over the last 50 years, Bangladesh really achieved many – a lot of achievements.  We were known to be a bottomless basket, but now we have a vibrant economy, a land of opportunity.  And the U.S. has been a great partner and friend; over the years   you have supported that, and U.S.-Bangladesh will be – your achievement in Bangladesh will be magnified because the U.S. efforts helped us all the way.</p>
<p>But Bangladesh is doing pretty well.  The U.S. is our – the biggest trading partner, and also accumulated – the investments in Bangladesh, the U.S. is the largest.  But most of the investment has been in the energy sector.  Maybe it is time to look beyond that.  And I am looking forward for more enhanced and solid – rock-solid relationship with the United States of America.</p>
<p>And I always have some indebtedness to you because when I was homeless, jobless, and stateless, it is USA that provided me a home and a job, and I am thankful for that.</p>
<p>Thank you.  Thank you, Excellency.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you, Mr. Minister.  Thank you all.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken at the Unveiling of a Bronze Bust in Honor of Former Secretary of State James Baker</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-the-unveiling-of-a-bronze-bust-in-honor-of-former-secretary-of-state-james-baker/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 18:08:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=331180</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>National Museum of American Diplomacy</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Ladies and gentlemen, please welcome the Secretary of State accompanied by the 61st Secretary of State, James Baker, and Ms. Susan Cleary.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>MS CLEARY:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, former Secretary of State Baker, Special Envoy Kerry, ambassadors, distinguished guests, colleagues, and friends, we’re so delighted to have you here today and we thank you for your support for the National Museum of American Diplomacy.  I’m Susan Cleary, the acting director.</p>
<p>We are the first and we are the only museum dedicated to the story of American diplomacy, its history, its practice, its challenges, its lessons, and the fascinating people who make it happen.  And we – it is a story we believe is not well-known and not well enough appreciated.</p>
<p>So today we’re here to unveil a specially commissioned bust of former Secretary of State James A. Baker, III, that will be part of our permanent collection.  Secretary Baker, you’ve been a steadfast supporter of the museum, a major donor.  We thank you for being here today; we thank your family and friends for being with us as well.  It’s very meaningful.  Thank you.</p>
<p>Now, our ambition is to complete the long-planned 40,000-square-foot public museum exhibition space here in our nation’s capital, and it’s right here around this wall that our main entry to our exhibitions will be our exhibit halls.  And so, every visitor to the future museum and visitor to the State Department who comes through this door entrance will pass this beautiful work of art that commemorates the historic contributions of Secretary Baker.</p>
<p>Now, we’re delighted to have with us today the talented Swedish artist Johan Falkman, who created this work.  Johan is a renowned portrait painter and sculptor.  Secretary Baker has not yet seen the bust, but I have and I have to say, Johan, it’s beautiful.  Congratulations.  It’s such an accomplishment.</p>
<p>I’d especially like to acknowledge Secretary Baker’s friends, the philanthropists Dan and Christine Olafsson, and it’s through your generosity that this work was commissioned and is donated to our permanent collection.  Thank you so much, Dan and Christine.</p>
<p>And I want to thank, of course, the Diplomacy Center Foundation.  We have the chairman and the president here, and we have so many of the distinguished members who have been with us along the way building this museum.  Thank you all for what you do for our joint project.</p>
<p>And Mr. Secretary, we especially appreciate having you here today with us.  At this moment of heightened awareness of the central importance of U.S. diplomacy to international stability and security, it’s so meaningful that you are able to take time to participate.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken and former Secretary Baker come from different backgrounds, different generations, and, yes, different political parties.  And yet, in their tenures, they’ve been asked to confront momentous challenges that demanded the most of Americans statecraft and diplomatic leadership.</p>
<p>And so, with that, I would like to invite you both up, to come and to unveil the bust of Secretary Baker.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  All right.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>Susan, thank you so much.  And to everyone here today, this is a special moment.  Jim, welcome home.  To the leaders of the Diplomacy Center Foundation, including my longtime colleague and friend Tom Pickering, Ambassador Popadiuk, thank you.  It’s wonderful to have you back in this building as well.  And it is simply an honor to have an opportunity, Mr. Secretary, to hail you in this moment.  To all the Baker family who are here with us today, thank you so much for joining us.  I know your most trusted diplomatic advisor is your wife, Susan.  Grateful for her.  Three of your eight children are with us today: Colter, Doug, and Jamie, and their partners as well.  We so welcome having you back.</p>
<p>I know that the Secretary’s years of public service, not just here but in other institutions in Washington, demanded a lot from all of you.  The sacrifices that you made were major contributions to the success that he had and that our country has had as a result.  So, on behalf of the American people, thank you, each and every one of you, to the Baker family.</p>
<p>S, growing up, as I’ve read it, Jim’s grandfather, Captain Baker, gave him this advice:  Work hard, study hard, and stay out of politics.  (Laughter.)  For four decades he managed to do that, but Jim, by your telling, it was the tragic loss of your first wife, Mary Stuart, and the advice of a dear friend, George H.W. Bush, that led you to break the family maxim and putting you on the path, as my dear friend Tom Donilon once said so aptly, to becoming, simply put, the most important unelected official in America since World War II.</p>
<p>The Secretary is the only person to have served as chief of staff to two presidents.  He directed five presidential campaigns.  He was Secretary of the Treasury in that other building down the street.  (Laughter.)  But, as I’ve seen written, and as I think I know from hearing you speak, there was no job that he loved more than being Secretary of State.  And he showed exceptional leadership in guiding the foreign policy of our country with a lasting impact on this country and on the world.</p>
<p>James Baker served as Secretary of State for 43 months.  I think it’s safe to say that there are few times in history when the world has changed so profoundly – what you called, Jim, a whirlwind of history – or, as you said late one night in April 1991 to a young staffer by the name of Bill Burns, sitting in a rundown hotel in the Caucasus, “Have you ever seen so many things changing so damn fast?”  During that period, the Soviet Union disintegrated without conflict.  The Berlin Wall fell.  The U.S. and the USSR undertook the most significant reduction ever in nuclear arms.  Saddam Hussein’s invasion of Kuwait was swiftly routed.  The Madrid Conference made visible for the first time a horizon of Middle East peace.</p>
<p>We were talking about this just a short while ago:  It’s easy looking back at hinge moments in history to view these seismic shifts as somehow inevitable, particularly when the world moves from conflict and toward peace, away from autocracy and toward democracy.  But to study those 43 months is to learn that these outcomes were anything but certain.  The arc of history bent the way it did because people bent it, and no one more so than Secretary Baker.</p>
<p>Like on November 9th, 1989, when Secretary Baker was hosting a luncheon upstairs in the Ben Franklin Room for President Aquino of the Philippines, he was handed a folded note informing him that the Berlin Wall was coming down.  As he rushed over to the White House, he scribbled notes that read: “Something we wanted for 40 years – Europe that’s whole and free, reunification on the basis of Western values.”</p>
<p>Now, that last part was very uncertain.  Secretary Baker not only immediately saw where he wanted to end up – a democratic, reunited Germany – he cleared the path to get there.  He staked out the principles that Germans, not outside powers, should get to determine their own future, and that Germany should be reunited within NATO, and then methodically brought our allies and the Soviets around to these positions.</p>
<p>President George H.W. Bush, your doubles partner on the Houston tennis courts and professional partner in so much of life, summed up your leadership best.  The President said: “He acted while others were still struggling to comprehend, and he got things done.”</p>
<p>As I’ve tried to look at those who have held this job before me, the thing that struck me so much about you, Jim, is this ability to have a vision for where you wanted to go, and then figuring out a way to get there.  It’s an extraordinary and rare combination, and one that inspires me every single day.</p>
<p>How you got things done is something I try to learn from every day and diplomats will continue to study for generations.  And if I can, I just want to take a moment to suggest at least three lessons that I take from reading and learning about you.</p>
<p>First of all, diplomacy ultimately comes down to relationships.  And building the trust at the core of those relationships takes time.  It takes effort.  It takes empathy.  As you later wrote, “To persuade , it is often helpful to put  in their shoes.”</p>
<p>Now, I had some opportunity also to see that in practice when I served as John Kerry’s deputy.  I saw the kinds of relationships that he built, the effort that, John, you put into this day in and day out.  And it’s a very, very powerful lesson, and I’ve been inspired by both of you in trying to follow in those footsteps.</p>
<p>Jim, you understood that to advance our interests and values, you had to get to know your counterparts beyond the negotiating table, to understand what drove them and what they were up against.</p>
<p>And I think there’s no better example – we had a chance to talk about this a little – than the friendship that you built with the then-Soviet foreign minister, Eduard Shevernadze.</p>
<p>In the summer of 1989, you took the unprecedented step then of inviting him to your ranch in Wyoming.  You met in Washington that fall.  You broke protocol by flying together to Jackson Hole rather than taking separate planes.  And on board, you shared a meal and talked for the hours of that flight.</p>
<p>Over the coming days, the Secretary took Shevardnadze fishing on the Snake River.  I got an account of who caught what, or who didn’t catch what.  (Laughter.)  And as I understand it, gave him a pair of custom black cowboy boots made in Houston.  Shevy, as you took to calling him, later invited you to come fishing with him in Siberia.</p>
<p>That relationship was at the foundation for so many of the historic steps that were taken by our two nations.  And I suggest that if not for the trust that you were able to build, the Soviet foreign minister may not have been willing to stand side by side with you at Moscow airport to jointly denounce Iraq’s invasion of Kuwait – the first time the great powers spoke together on a seminal foreign policy issue, an act that was seen as a bookend to the Cold War.</p>
<p>Second, Secretary Baker understood that while American leadership was indispensable to tackling global challenges, we need allies, we need partners, to get the job done.  And those relationships have to be built.  They have to be nurtured.</p>
<p>That was how Secretary Baker assembled the coalition to stand up to Saddam Hussein’s invasion of Kuwait.  Ahead of the November 1990 vote at the UN Security Council authorizing the use of force against Iraq, the Secretary recognized the importance of rallying the broadest possible coalition.  So, he wanted to meet with every head of state or foreign minister from every country on the Security Council, 15 of them including us.  He had three weeks to do it.</p>
<p>In that time, he traveled to 12 countries on three continents.  And he didn’t just show up; he practiced the five P’s that his father had taught him: “Prior preparation prevents poor performance.”  So that’s another I’m inscribing on my own desk.  That preparation allowed him to meet each country where it was, bringing to bear the right combination of persuasion, charm, and maybe just a little bit of pressure too.</p>
<p>Ultimately, 12 Security Council members voted for the resolution.</p>
<p>Third, while the Secretary was a master at getting things done, he never lost sight of the principles guiding his actions.  He wrote, and I quote, “an American political diplomat should always remember that power divorced from the purposes valued by our democracy will ultimately prove empty.”  Jim, I suspect that’s one of the reasons you loved being Secretary.</p>
<p>You could use that gift for getting things done to advance the values that you believed in most and that represented everything that’s good about this country.  Yes, we all know the secretary could whip votes and run a campaign better than anyone.  I can attest to that.  I worked for Michael Dukakis in 1988.  (Laughter.)  But the greatest campaign he ever waged was for a more secure, a more peaceful world.</p>
<p>So once again we find ourselves in a whirlwind of history.  A more assertive China is challenging the rules-based international order that has long been the foundation of security and prosperity for Americans and people around the world.  The post-Cold War era has ended.  Russia has invaded a neighbor.  It’s reverted to almost totalitarian repression at home.  It’s threatening even to use nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>As we navigate this time, few models are more fitting to follow than the model set by Jim Baker.  In the office that I now have the privilege of occupying, Secretary Baker kept a small plaque on his desk given to him by President Reagan, and it said, “It CAN be done,” with the word “can” in capital letters.  Secretary Baker is, has always been a realist, but he’s never lost faith in America, in our values, and in our capacity when we’re at our best to make the world a little bit better as long as we remember the purpose behind our power.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, today, on behalf of this department, on behalf of our country, thank you.  Thank you for showing us how it can be done.  Thank you for inspiring us across the years and across generations.  Thank you for being such a great leader for this country and for this department.  Mr. Secretary.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BAKER:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for an extraordinarily generous – those extraordinarily generous remarks.  They are – they may very well be over the top.  You were kind to say that I could get some things done.  I didn’t get much done.  I had a really good crew that got things done for me and with me, and some of them are here today and I’m delighted to see them.  I appreciate the fact that all of you are here.  This is a signal honor for me to have my bust in the lobby of the department, and particularly here in the Museum of Diplomacy.</p>
<p>I’m really honored, if I may say so, Tony, that you would take time out of your busy schedule to be here, and I want to thank you for those extraordinarily generous words.  Ladies and gentlemen, I don’t think there’s been a moment in recent history when effective diplomacy has not – has been needed any more than it’s needed right now.  And we were talking about this in the Secretary’s office.  We all know the winds of war are blowing hard in Ukraine, where citizens there are making some quite heroic efforts to maintain their independence.  Protecting their freedoms while also making sure that the violence doesn’t spread – that we don’t trigger something else, is a really daunting task for the West – the West led, as usual, by the United States.</p>
<p>I think this crisis once again proves the critical importance of American leadership, and I told the Secretary that I really support and agree with the steps that have been taken in facing up to this problem.  I think they’ve done a masterful job.  I think it’s too soon to declare victory.  Some people are inclined to declare victory right now, some commentators.  I think it’s too soon for that.  But the fact remains that the United States is and still will remain for some time a force for international peace and stability.</p>
<p>And so, Mr. Secretary, I want you to know that you and our country have my full support as you and the dedicated officers of this wonderful department continue to lead our country’s diplomatic efforts during this challenging time.  And it is a challenging time, and you’re doing a splendid job.</p>
<p>I also want to express my deep appreciation to Dan Olofsson for finally bringing this event to fruition after the COVID pandemic put planning for it on hold for over two years.  I first met Dan when he invited me to Malmö, Sweden in 2017 for a public conversation with Carl Bildt, the former prime minister of that country.  Now, I may be a bit biased, because Dan has commissioned this bust of me, but I want you all to know how much I admire him.  He is a very successful entrepreneur who is interested in building a better world, not just making money.  His philanthropic commitment is best evidenced, I think, by the organization Star for Life, which he and his wife Christin launched in 2005 to prevent AIDS among young people in Africa.  We are also honored, Christin, to have you here today.</p>
<p>Their foundation works to strengthen young people’s self-esteem and belief in the future.  So, congratulations, Dan and Christin, and congratulations as well, Johan Falkman, to you – a sculptor, a talented sculptor.  You have a wonderful gift, Johan: the ability to bring joy and understanding through your art.  So, thank you also for honoring me as one of your subjects.</p>
<p>Now, this event would not be possible without the National Museum of American Diplomacy.  The history, the practice, and the challenges of American diplomacy tell a real success story, I think, of the American experiment.  This museum is going to keep that story alive.</p>
<p>Our nation has long been overdue, I think, for a museum that highlights the important role that diplomacy plays in our foreign and security policy.  I’ve been told that there are 18 large museums dedicated to our armed forces and wars that we have fought, and perhaps as many as 400 smaller ones.  And now I am very, very proud to be associated with this one that recognizes the importance and the success of diplomacy.</p>
<p>And since we’re talking about the importance of diplomacy, I want to recognize my late friend whom the Secretary mentioned and former boss, and yes, former tennis doubles partner, George H.W. Bush.  I told people I had an easy job.  The secretary of state can’t find himself separated from his president, and there was never any chance of that with me, because I had a president who was a friend, close friend, for 40 years.  He was my daughter’s godfather, and I carried him on the tennis courts.  (Laughter.)  So, there was never going to be – not only that, I ran all of his campaigns.  So, he and I were never going to see any space between us.</p>
<p>But I want to say nobody – in my view, nobody understood foreign policy, nor practiced it, as well as President Bush.  He was a star at that.  He knew it, he understood it, and he knew what to do and when to do it.  And were it not for George Bush, this bust of me would not be here today.</p>
<p>I’d like to end my remarks today, sadly, by saying a few words about another friend and great American, one of my successors as secretary of state: the incomparable Madeleine Albright.</p>
<p>Madeleine was intelligent, she was savvy, she was charming, and I can tell you – because she did some politics, too – she could be brutally frank when the moment demanded it.  But above all, she understood the important place that American diplomacy has in global affairs.  We are going to greatly miss Madeleine and her wit and candor.  Most of all, I think we will miss her contribution to our nation and to the practice of diplomacy.</p>
<p>Thank you all for being here.  Thank you for supporting this museum of diplomacy.  Mr. Secretary, thank you again for those extraordinarily generous remarks.  Dan, Christin, and Johan, thank you for being here and making today such a memorable one for me.</p>
<p>Thank you all.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>National Museum of American Diplomacy</p>
<p><strong>MODERATOR:</strong>  Ladies and gentlemen, please welcome the Secretary of State accompanied by the 61st Secretary of State, James Baker, and Ms. Susan Cleary.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>MS CLEARY:</strong>  Mr. Secretary, former Secretary of State Baker, Special Envoy Kerry, ambassadors, distinguished guests, colleagues, and friends, we’re so delighted to have you here today and we thank you for your support for the National Museum of American Diplomacy.  I’m Susan Cleary, the acting director.</p>
<p>We are the first and we are the only museum dedicated to the story of American diplomacy, its history, its practice, its challenges, its lessons, and the fascinating people who make it happen.  And we – it is a story we believe is not well-known and not well enough appreciated.</p>
<p>So today we’re here to unveil a specially commissioned bust of former Secretary of State James A. Baker, III, that will be part of our permanent collection.  Secretary Baker, you’ve been a steadfast supporter of the museum, a major donor.  We thank you for being here today; we thank your family and friends for being with us as well.  It’s very meaningful.  Thank you.</p>
<p>Now, our ambition is to complete the long-planned 40,000-square-foot public museum exhibition space here in our nation’s capital, and it’s right here around this wall that our main entry to our exhibitions will be our exhibit halls.  And so, every visitor to the future museum and visitor to the State Department who comes through this door entrance will pass this beautiful work of art that commemorates the historic contributions of Secretary Baker.</p>
<p>Now, we’re delighted to have with us today the talented Swedish artist Johan Falkman, who created this work.  Johan is a renowned portrait painter and sculptor.  Secretary Baker has not yet seen the bust, but I have and I have to say, Johan, it’s beautiful.  Congratulations.  It’s such an accomplishment.</p>
<p>I’d especially like to acknowledge Secretary Baker’s friends, the philanthropists Dan and Christine Olafsson, and it’s through your generosity that this work was commissioned and is donated to our permanent collection.  Thank you so much, Dan and Christine.</p>
<p>And I want to thank, of course, the Diplomacy Center Foundation.  We have the chairman and the president here, and we have so many of the distinguished members who have been with us along the way building this museum.  Thank you all for what you do for our joint project.</p>
<p>And Mr. Secretary, we especially appreciate having you here today with us.  At this moment of heightened awareness of the central importance of U.S. diplomacy to international stability and security, it’s so meaningful that you are able to take time to participate.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken and former Secretary Baker come from different backgrounds, different generations, and, yes, different political parties.  And yet, in their tenures, they’ve been asked to confront momentous challenges that demanded the most of Americans statecraft and diplomatic leadership.</p>
<p>And so, with that, I would like to invite you both up, to come and to unveil the bust of Secretary Baker.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  All right.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>Susan, thank you so much.  And to everyone here today, this is a special moment.  Jim, welcome home.  To the leaders of the Diplomacy Center Foundation, including my longtime colleague and friend Tom Pickering, Ambassador Popadiuk, thank you.  It’s wonderful to have you back in this building as well.  And it is simply an honor to have an opportunity, Mr. Secretary, to hail you in this moment.  To all the Baker family who are here with us today, thank you so much for joining us.  I know your most trusted diplomatic advisor is your wife, Susan.  Grateful for her.  Three of your eight children are with us today: Colter, Doug, and Jamie, and their partners as well.  We so welcome having you back.</p>
<p>I know that the Secretary’s years of public service, not just here but in other institutions in Washington, demanded a lot from all of you.  The sacrifices that you made were major contributions to the success that he had and that our country has had as a result.  So, on behalf of the American people, thank you, each and every one of you, to the Baker family.</p>
<p>S, growing up, as I’ve read it, Jim’s grandfather, Captain Baker, gave him this advice:  Work hard, study hard, and stay out of politics.  (Laughter.)  For four decades he managed to do that, but Jim, by your telling, it was the tragic loss of your first wife, Mary Stuart, and the advice of a dear friend, George H.W. Bush, that led you to break the family maxim and putting you on the path, as my dear friend Tom Donilon once said so aptly, to becoming, simply put, the most important unelected official in America since World War II.</p>
<p>The Secretary is the only person to have served as chief of staff to two presidents.  He directed five presidential campaigns.  He was Secretary of the Treasury in that other building down the street.  (Laughter.)  But, as I’ve seen written, and as I think I know from hearing you speak, there was no job that he loved more than being Secretary of State.  And he showed exceptional leadership in guiding the foreign policy of our country with a lasting impact on this country and on the world.</p>
<p>James Baker served as Secretary of State for 43 months.  I think it’s safe to say that there are few times in history when the world has changed so profoundly – what you called, Jim, a whirlwind of history – or, as you said late one night in April 1991 to a young staffer by the name of Bill Burns, sitting in a rundown hotel in the Caucasus, “Have you ever seen so many things changing so damn fast?”  During that period, the Soviet Union disintegrated without conflict.  The Berlin Wall fell.  The U.S. and the USSR undertook the most significant reduction ever in nuclear arms.  Saddam Hussein’s invasion of Kuwait was swiftly routed.  The Madrid Conference made visible for the first time a horizon of Middle East peace.</p>
<p>We were talking about this just a short while ago:  It’s easy looking back at hinge moments in history to view these seismic shifts as somehow inevitable, particularly when the world moves from conflict and toward peace, away from autocracy and toward democracy.  But to study those 43 months is to learn that these outcomes were anything but certain.  The arc of history bent the way it did because people bent it, and no one more so than Secretary Baker.</p>
<p>Like on November 9th, 1989, when Secretary Baker was hosting a luncheon upstairs in the Ben Franklin Room for President Aquino of the Philippines, he was handed a folded note informing him that the Berlin Wall was coming down.  As he rushed over to the White House, he scribbled notes that read: “Something we wanted for 40 years – Europe that’s whole and free, reunification on the basis of Western values.”</p>
<p>Now, that last part was very uncertain.  Secretary Baker not only immediately saw where he wanted to end up – a democratic, reunited Germany – he cleared the path to get there.  He staked out the principles that Germans, not outside powers, should get to determine their own future, and that Germany should be reunited within NATO, and then methodically brought our allies and the Soviets around to these positions.</p>
<p>President George H.W. Bush, your doubles partner on the Houston tennis courts and professional partner in so much of life, summed up your leadership best.  The President said: “He acted while others were still struggling to comprehend, and he got things done.”</p>
<p>As I’ve tried to look at those who have held this job before me, the thing that struck me so much about you, Jim, is this ability to have a vision for where you wanted to go, and then figuring out a way to get there.  It’s an extraordinary and rare combination, and one that inspires me every single day.</p>
<p>How you got things done is something I try to learn from every day and diplomats will continue to study for generations.  And if I can, I just want to take a moment to suggest at least three lessons that I take from reading and learning about you.</p>
<p>First of all, diplomacy ultimately comes down to relationships.  And building the trust at the core of those relationships takes time.  It takes effort.  It takes empathy.  As you later wrote, “To persuade , it is often helpful to put  in their shoes.”</p>
<p>Now, I had some opportunity also to see that in practice when I served as John Kerry’s deputy.  I saw the kinds of relationships that he built, the effort that, John, you put into this day in and day out.  And it’s a very, very powerful lesson, and I’ve been inspired by both of you in trying to follow in those footsteps.</p>
<p>Jim, you understood that to advance our interests and values, you had to get to know your counterparts beyond the negotiating table, to understand what drove them and what they were up against.</p>
<p>And I think there’s no better example – we had a chance to talk about this a little – than the friendship that you built with the then-Soviet foreign minister, Eduard Shevernadze.</p>
<p>In the summer of 1989, you took the unprecedented step then of inviting him to your ranch in Wyoming.  You met in Washington that fall.  You broke protocol by flying together to Jackson Hole rather than taking separate planes.  And on board, you shared a meal and talked for the hours of that flight.</p>
<p>Over the coming days, the Secretary took Shevardnadze fishing on the Snake River.  I got an account of who caught what, or who didn’t catch what.  (Laughter.)  And as I understand it, gave him a pair of custom black cowboy boots made in Houston.  Shevy, as you took to calling him, later invited you to come fishing with him in Siberia.</p>
<p>That relationship was at the foundation for so many of the historic steps that were taken by our two nations.  And I suggest that if not for the trust that you were able to build, the Soviet foreign minister may not have been willing to stand side by side with you at Moscow airport to jointly denounce Iraq’s invasion of Kuwait – the first time the great powers spoke together on a seminal foreign policy issue, an act that was seen as a bookend to the Cold War.</p>
<p>Second, Secretary Baker understood that while American leadership was indispensable to tackling global challenges, we need allies, we need partners, to get the job done.  And those relationships have to be built.  They have to be nurtured.</p>
<p>That was how Secretary Baker assembled the coalition to stand up to Saddam Hussein’s invasion of Kuwait.  Ahead of the November 1990 vote at the UN Security Council authorizing the use of force against Iraq, the Secretary recognized the importance of rallying the broadest possible coalition.  So, he wanted to meet with every head of state or foreign minister from every country on the Security Council, 15 of them including us.  He had three weeks to do it.</p>
<p>In that time, he traveled to 12 countries on three continents.  And he didn’t just show up; he practiced the five P’s that his father had taught him: “Prior preparation prevents poor performance.”  So that’s another I’m inscribing on my own desk.  That preparation allowed him to meet each country where it was, bringing to bear the right combination of persuasion, charm, and maybe just a little bit of pressure too.</p>
<p>Ultimately, 12 Security Council members voted for the resolution.</p>
<p>Third, while the Secretary was a master at getting things done, he never lost sight of the principles guiding his actions.  He wrote, and I quote, “an American political diplomat should always remember that power divorced from the purposes valued by our democracy will ultimately prove empty.”  Jim, I suspect that’s one of the reasons you loved being Secretary.</p>
<p>You could use that gift for getting things done to advance the values that you believed in most and that represented everything that’s good about this country.  Yes, we all know the secretary could whip votes and run a campaign better than anyone.  I can attest to that.  I worked for Michael Dukakis in 1988.  (Laughter.)  But the greatest campaign he ever waged was for a more secure, a more peaceful world.</p>
<p>So once again we find ourselves in a whirlwind of history.  A more assertive China is challenging the rules-based international order that has long been the foundation of security and prosperity for Americans and people around the world.  The post-Cold War era has ended.  Russia has invaded a neighbor.  It’s reverted to almost totalitarian repression at home.  It’s threatening even to use nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>As we navigate this time, few models are more fitting to follow than the model set by Jim Baker.  In the office that I now have the privilege of occupying, Secretary Baker kept a small plaque on his desk given to him by President Reagan, and it said, “It CAN be done,” with the word “can” in capital letters.  Secretary Baker is, has always been a realist, but he’s never lost faith in America, in our values, and in our capacity when we’re at our best to make the world a little bit better as long as we remember the purpose behind our power.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, today, on behalf of this department, on behalf of our country, thank you.  Thank you for showing us how it can be done.  Thank you for inspiring us across the years and across generations.  Thank you for being such a great leader for this country and for this department.  Mr. Secretary.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BAKER:</strong>  Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for an extraordinarily generous – those extraordinarily generous remarks.  They are – they may very well be over the top.  You were kind to say that I could get some things done.  I didn’t get much done.  I had a really good crew that got things done for me and with me, and some of them are here today and I’m delighted to see them.  I appreciate the fact that all of you are here.  This is a signal honor for me to have my bust in the lobby of the department, and particularly here in the Museum of Diplomacy.</p>
<p>I’m really honored, if I may say so, Tony, that you would take time out of your busy schedule to be here, and I want to thank you for those extraordinarily generous words.  Ladies and gentlemen, I don’t think there’s been a moment in recent history when effective diplomacy has not – has been needed any more than it’s needed right now.  And we were talking about this in the Secretary’s office.  We all know the winds of war are blowing hard in Ukraine, where citizens there are making some quite heroic efforts to maintain their independence.  Protecting their freedoms while also making sure that the violence doesn’t spread – that we don’t trigger something else, is a really daunting task for the West – the West led, as usual, by the United States.</p>
<p>I think this crisis once again proves the critical importance of American leadership, and I told the Secretary that I really support and agree with the steps that have been taken in facing up to this problem.  I think they’ve done a masterful job.  I think it’s too soon to declare victory.  Some people are inclined to declare victory right now, some commentators.  I think it’s too soon for that.  But the fact remains that the United States is and still will remain for some time a force for international peace and stability.</p>
<p>And so, Mr. Secretary, I want you to know that you and our country have my full support as you and the dedicated officers of this wonderful department continue to lead our country’s diplomatic efforts during this challenging time.  And it is a challenging time, and you’re doing a splendid job.</p>
<p>I also want to express my deep appreciation to Dan Olofsson for finally bringing this event to fruition after the COVID pandemic put planning for it on hold for over two years.  I first met Dan when he invited me to Malmö, Sweden in 2017 for a public conversation with Carl Bildt, the former prime minister of that country.  Now, I may be a bit biased, because Dan has commissioned this bust of me, but I want you all to know how much I admire him.  He is a very successful entrepreneur who is interested in building a better world, not just making money.  His philanthropic commitment is best evidenced, I think, by the organization Star for Life, which he and his wife Christin launched in 2005 to prevent AIDS among young people in Africa.  We are also honored, Christin, to have you here today.</p>
<p>Their foundation works to strengthen young people’s self-esteem and belief in the future.  So, congratulations, Dan and Christin, and congratulations as well, Johan Falkman, to you – a sculptor, a talented sculptor.  You have a wonderful gift, Johan: the ability to bring joy and understanding through your art.  So, thank you also for honoring me as one of your subjects.</p>
<p>Now, this event would not be possible without the National Museum of American Diplomacy.  The history, the practice, and the challenges of American diplomacy tell a real success story, I think, of the American experiment.  This museum is going to keep that story alive.</p>
<p>Our nation has long been overdue, I think, for a museum that highlights the important role that diplomacy plays in our foreign and security policy.  I’ve been told that there are 18 large museums dedicated to our armed forces and wars that we have fought, and perhaps as many as 400 smaller ones.  And now I am very, very proud to be associated with this one that recognizes the importance and the success of diplomacy.</p>
<p>And since we’re talking about the importance of diplomacy, I want to recognize my late friend whom the Secretary mentioned and former boss, and yes, former tennis doubles partner, George H.W. Bush.  I told people I had an easy job.  The secretary of state can’t find himself separated from his president, and there was never any chance of that with me, because I had a president who was a friend, close friend, for 40 years.  He was my daughter’s godfather, and I carried him on the tennis courts.  (Laughter.)  So, there was never going to be – not only that, I ran all of his campaigns.  So, he and I were never going to see any space between us.</p>
<p>But I want to say nobody – in my view, nobody understood foreign policy, nor practiced it, as well as President Bush.  He was a star at that.  He knew it, he understood it, and he knew what to do and when to do it.  And were it not for George Bush, this bust of me would not be here today.</p>
<p>I’d like to end my remarks today, sadly, by saying a few words about another friend and great American, one of my successors as secretary of state: the incomparable Madeleine Albright.</p>
<p>Madeleine was intelligent, she was savvy, she was charming, and I can tell you – because she did some politics, too – she could be brutally frank when the moment demanded it.  But above all, she understood the important place that American diplomacy has in global affairs.  We are going to greatly miss Madeleine and her wit and candor.  Most of all, I think we will miss her contribution to our nation and to the practice of diplomacy.</p>
<p>Thank you all for being here.  Thank you for supporting this museum of diplomacy.  Mr. Secretary, thank you again for those extraordinarily generous remarks.  Dan, Christin, and Johan, thank you for being here and making today such a memorable one for me.</p>
<p>Thank you all.  (Applause.)</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-Turkey Joint Statement on the Strategic Mechanism</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-turkey-joint-statement-on-the-strategic-mechanism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 17:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=331162</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is the text of a joint statement released by the Governments of the United States and Turkey.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text: </em></p>
<p>In keeping with the commitment made by Presidents Biden and Erdogan during their meeting in Rome in October 2021, the United States and Turkey launched the U.S.-Turkey Strategic Mechanism on April 4 in Ankara. Under Secretary of State Victoria Nuland and Deputy Foreign Minister Sedat Onal, with their respective delegations, met in Ankara to review topics of mutual interest, including economic and defense cooperation, counterterrorism, and key areas of shared regional and global interest.  They reiterated their shared commitment to the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine. The United States welcomed Turkey’s efforts to facilitate a just, negotiated diplomatic solution to end the war.</p>
<p>U.S. Department of Commerce Under Secretary Marisa Lago will visit Ankara April 5-6 to advance the economic and trade cooperation goals of the Strategic Mechanism.</p>
<p>The United States and Turkey look forward to a Ministerial-level meeting within the framework of the Strategic Mechanism later in 2022.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is the text of a joint statement released by the Governments of the United States and Turkey.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text: </em></p>
<p>In keeping with the commitment made by Presidents Biden and Erdogan during their meeting in Rome in October 2021, the United States and Turkey launched the U.S.-Turkey Strategic Mechanism on April 4 in Ankara. Under Secretary of State Victoria Nuland and Deputy Foreign Minister Sedat Onal, with their respective delegations, met in Ankara to review topics of mutual interest, including economic and defense cooperation, counterterrorism, and key areas of shared regional and global interest.  They reiterated their shared commitment to the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine. The United States welcomed Turkey’s efforts to facilitate a just, negotiated diplomatic solution to end the war.</p>
<p>U.S. Department of Commerce Under Secretary Marisa Lago will visit Ankara April 5-6 to advance the economic and trade cooperation goals of the Strategic Mechanism.</p>
<p>The United States and Turkey look forward to a Ministerial-level meeting within the framework of the Strategic Mechanism later in 2022.</p>
<p><em>End text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Representative for the DPRK Kim’s Meeting with Republic of Korea (ROK) Special Representative Noh</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-representative-for-the-dprk-kims-meeting-with-republic-of-korea-rok-special-representative-noh/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 16:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=331148</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>On April 4, Special Representative for the DPRK Sung Kim met with ROK Special Representative for Korean Peninsula Peace and Security Affairs Noh Kyu-duk in Washington, D.C.  The two jointly condemned the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea’s March 24 intercontinental ballistic missile launch, which was only the latest in a series of increasingly escalatory DRPK launches this year.  They also reaffirmed the importance of a strong, unified response to these escalatory actions.</p>
<p>The Special Representatives condemned these ballistic missile launches as clear violations of multiple UN Security Council resolutions that posed a serious threat to regional stability.  Special Representative Kim underscored the United States’ ironclad commitment to the security of the ROK, while reaffirming that the United States continues to seek serious and sustained dialogue with the DPRK.  Special Representative Kim stressed the importance of close bilateral coordination with the ROK and other allies and partners as we seek to advance our shared goal of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>On April 4, Special Representative for the DPRK Sung Kim met with ROK Special Representative for Korean Peninsula Peace and Security Affairs Noh Kyu-duk in Washington, D.C.  The two jointly condemned the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea’s March 24 intercontinental ballistic missile launch, which was only the latest in a series of increasingly escalatory DRPK launches this year.  They also reaffirmed the importance of a strong, unified response to these escalatory actions.</p>
<p>The Special Representatives condemned these ballistic missile launches as clear violations of multiple UN Security Council resolutions that posed a serious threat to regional stability.  Special Representative Kim underscored the United States’ ironclad commitment to the security of the ROK, while reaffirming that the United States continues to seek serious and sustained dialogue with the DPRK.  Special Representative Kim stressed the importance of close bilateral coordination with the ROK and other allies and partners as we seek to advance our shared goal of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Department of State Paid Internship Program Now Open</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-department-of-state-paid-internship-program-now-open/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 15:44:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=331106</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State is pleased to announce a new paid student internship program beginning with the Fall 2022 internship season. The program is intended to expand opportunities for students of all backgrounds in post-secondary degree programs to gain experience and insight into the variety of careers available in U.S. foreign policy programs and administration of the U.S. Department of State and its diplomatic missions worldwide. By providing paid internships, the Department seeks to remove barriers for students who may not have the financial means to support themselves during an unpaid, volunteer internship.</p>
<p>The Department is currently accepting applications through April 12, 2022, or until 1,000 applications are received. Up to 200 student applicants will be chosen for the Fall 2022 internship season.</p>
<p>The paid student internship program is part of the Department of State’s continued efforts to reflect the diversity of the United States and to encourage individuals from traditionally underrepresented groups to pursue its student and career opportunities.  The Department intends to make all its internships paid in 2023.</p>
<p>The paid student internship program will consider all qualified applicants for the 10-week internships.</p>
<p>Students must meet all the following requirements:</p>
<ul>
<li>Be a U.S. citizen at the time of application;</li>
<li>Be at least 18 years old;</li>
<li>Be enrolled in an accredited academic institution on at least a part-time basis, pursuing a baccalaureate or graduate degree;</li>
<li>Be in good academic standing with at least a 3.0 GPA;</li>
<li>Be a college junior, senior, or graduate student with at least 60 credit hours completed;</li>
<li>Be able to pass and retain suitability and background clearance requirements.</li>
</ul>
<p>Students selected for the paid internship program will receive pay at the GS-04 level, currently $17.51/hour in the Washington DC locality.  They will also receive transportation to and housing at their duty stations, whether in Washington, D.C. or overseas. As temporary civil service employees of the Department, they will also earn annual leave, sick leave, and time-in-service credit.</p>
<p>For more information about this opportunity, please visit: <a href="https://careers.state.gov/interns-fellows/student-internships/?_ref=a3btmxzbpt0" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDQuNTU4OTkyNDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2NhcmVlcnMuc3RhdGUuZ292L2ludGVybi9zdHVkZW50LWludGVybnNoaXBzLz9fcmVmPWEzYnRteHpicHQwIn0.FD6Qz0Ah8eTiCajJpzMNHcPgS9ojx6n6oUA-Q9nEUjE/s/1006560560/br/129279565002-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649173222970000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0vjBk7Nt8ss3u0NvMcRJvv">https://careers.state.gov/<wbr />intern/student-internships/.</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of State is pleased to announce a new paid student internship program beginning with the Fall 2022 internship season. The program is intended to expand opportunities for students of all backgrounds in post-secondary degree programs to gain experience and insight into the variety of careers available in U.S. foreign policy programs and administration of the U.S. Department of State and its diplomatic missions worldwide. By providing paid internships, the Department seeks to remove barriers for students who may not have the financial means to support themselves during an unpaid, volunteer internship.</p>
<p>The Department is currently accepting applications through April 12, 2022, or until 1,000 applications are received. Up to 200 student applicants will be chosen for the Fall 2022 internship season.</p>
<p>The paid student internship program is part of the Department of State’s continued efforts to reflect the diversity of the United States and to encourage individuals from traditionally underrepresented groups to pursue its student and career opportunities.  The Department intends to make all its internships paid in 2023.</p>
<p>The paid student internship program will consider all qualified applicants for the 10-week internships.</p>
<p>Students must meet all the following requirements:</p>
<ul>
<li>Be a U.S. citizen at the time of application;</li>
<li>Be at least 18 years old;</li>
<li>Be enrolled in an accredited academic institution on at least a part-time basis, pursuing a baccalaureate or graduate degree;</li>
<li>Be in good academic standing with at least a 3.0 GPA;</li>
<li>Be a college junior, senior, or graduate student with at least 60 credit hours completed;</li>
<li>Be able to pass and retain suitability and background clearance requirements.</li>
</ul>
<p>Students selected for the paid internship program will receive pay at the GS-04 level, currently $17.51/hour in the Washington DC locality.  They will also receive transportation to and housing at their duty stations, whether in Washington, D.C. or overseas. As temporary civil service employees of the Department, they will also earn annual leave, sick leave, and time-in-service credit.</p>
<p>For more information about this opportunity, please visit: <a href="https://careers.state.gov/interns-fellows/student-internships/?_ref=a3btmxzbpt0" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDQuNTU4OTkyNDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2NhcmVlcnMuc3RhdGUuZ292L2ludGVybi9zdHVkZW50LWludGVybnNoaXBzLz9fcmVmPWEzYnRteHpicHQwIn0.FD6Qz0Ah8eTiCajJpzMNHcPgS9ojx6n6oUA-Q9nEUjE/s/1006560560/br/129279565002-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649173222970000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0vjBk7Nt8ss3u0NvMcRJvv">https://careers.state.gov/<wbr />intern/student-internships/.</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change Report on Mitigation</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/intergovernmental-panel-on-climate-change-report-on-mitigation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 15:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=331096</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>This morning’s Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) <a class="external-link" href="https://www.ipcc.ch/report/sixth-assessment-report-working-group-3/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">report on mitigation</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> makes clear what we can do to stop or slow planetary warming.  The report also reveals how current global efforts to mitigate the climate crisis fall far short of what is needed.  Without full implementation of current national pledges and robust, aggressive, and ambitious further action we cannot keep the 1.5 degrees Celsius goal within reach.</p>
<p>That is why we have called this the decisive decade.  The IPCC found there are options available now, in all sectors, that can halve global emissions by 2030 – from improving energy efficiency, to halting and reversing global deforestation, to deploying more sustainable transportation and clean energy.  There are ways to improve our chances of success, including more effective decision-making across all levels of government, increased alignment of financial flows with climate outcomes, and enhanced international cooperation.</p>
<p>The report also tells us there is reason for hope.  The IPCC found we are making some progress towards the needed reductions in carbon emissions. With actions already taken, and the pledges made under the Paris Agreement through COP26, we can get closer to limiting warming to 2 degrees Celsius, and with additional effort we can keep 1.5 degrees Celsius within reach.</p>
<p>That is why the Administration has made tackling the climate crisis a central part of its agenda from Day One.  The President’s FY 2023 budget request to Congress includes more than $11 billion in international climate finance to avert the worst impacts of climate change and to support developing countries in taking more ambitious climate action.</p>
<p>This report makes it clear:  the tools to stave off the worst impacts of the climate crisis are firmly within our grasp.  Nations of the world must be brave enough to use them.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>This morning’s Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) <a class="external-link" href="https://www.ipcc.ch/report/sixth-assessment-report-working-group-3/" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">report on mitigation</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> makes clear what we can do to stop or slow planetary warming.  The report also reveals how current global efforts to mitigate the climate crisis fall far short of what is needed.  Without full implementation of current national pledges and robust, aggressive, and ambitious further action we cannot keep the 1.5 degrees Celsius goal within reach.</p>
<p>That is why we have called this the decisive decade.  The IPCC found there are options available now, in all sectors, that can halve global emissions by 2030 – from improving energy efficiency, to halting and reversing global deforestation, to deploying more sustainable transportation and clean energy.  There are ways to improve our chances of success, including more effective decision-making across all levels of government, increased alignment of financial flows with climate outcomes, and enhanced international cooperation.</p>
<p>The report also tells us there is reason for hope.  The IPCC found we are making some progress towards the needed reductions in carbon emissions. With actions already taken, and the pledges made under the Paris Agreement through COP26, we can get closer to limiting warming to 2 degrees Celsius, and with additional effort we can keep 1.5 degrees Celsius within reach.</p>
<p>That is why the Administration has made tackling the climate crisis a central part of its agenda from Day One.  The President’s FY 2023 budget request to Congress includes more than $11 billion in international climate finance to avert the worst impacts of climate change and to support developing countries in taking more ambitious climate action.</p>
<p>This report makes it clear:  the tools to stave off the worst impacts of the climate crisis are firmly within our grasp.  Nations of the world must be brave enough to use them.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>To Walk the Earth in Safety: New Report Showcases U.S. Global Leadership in Landmine Clearance and Conventional Weapons Destruction</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/to-walk-the-earth-in-safety-new-report-showcases-u-s-global-leadership-in-landmine-clearance-and-conventional-weapons-destruction-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 13:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=331037</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On April 4, 2022, the <a href="https://www.state.gov/key-topics-office-of-weapons-removal-and-abatement/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDQuNTU4ODY4MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3Yva2V5LXRvcGljcy1vZmZpY2Utb2Ytd2VhcG9ucy1yZW1vdmFsLWFuZC1hYmF0ZW1lbnQvIn0.nfacEvjLb-FTOdPxHqOaezTcu1oOqUi2Q2_0b8v9P9M/s/2171565732/br/129256398370-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649165891875000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2Rc234o1cp3RA8XuEHJ-wY">Office of Weapons Removal and Abatement</a> in the U.S. Department of State’s Bureau of Political-Military Affairs released the 21st Edition of <em><a href="https://www.state.gov/reports/to-walk-the-earth-in-safety-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDQuNTU4ODY4MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvcmVwb3J0cy90by13YWxrLXRoZS1lYXJ0aC1pbi1zYWZldHktMjAyMi8ifQ.j3qLFN65Cs2Cclr-VIZ1MHAJH-7FwriYavnjg8vW4xc/s/2171565732/br/129256398370-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649165891875000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1gqxYELZxanbUIERS8rTOE">To Walk the Earth in Safety</a></em>, a report underscoring the accomplishments of the U.S. Conventional Weapons Destruction (CWD) Program in 2021.</p>
<p>The United States is the world’s single largest financial supporter of CWD. Since 1993, the United States has invested more than $4.2 billion for the safe clearance of landmines and explosive weapons of war, as well as the securing and safe disposal of excess small arms and light weapons and munitions in more than 100 countries and territories. In 2021, the United States funded CWD efforts in 62 countries with more than $265 million.</p>
<p>Our assistance – that of the United States government and our global partners – is crucial to building a more safe, secure, and prosperous world. Thanks to strong bipartisan funding support from Congress, the Department of State looks forward to continuing this important work with other donor countries, those impacted by conflict, and the brave men and women who work in the field to secure at-risk weapons and munitions and clear landmines and other explosive hazards.</p>
<p>For more information, please consult the PM <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureaus-offices/under-secretary-for-arms-control-and-international-security-affairs/bureau-of-political-military-affairs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDIsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDQuNTU4ODY4MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1cy1vZmZpY2VzL3VuZGVyLXNlY3JldGFyeS1mb3ItYXJtcy1jb250cm9sLWFuZC1pbnRlcm5hdGlvbmFsLXNlY3VyaXR5LWFmZmFpcnMvYnVyZWF1LW9mLXBvbGl0aWNhbC1taWxpdGFyeS1hZmZhaXJzLyJ9.bEEDotiszKd_xWhfCG45cqswc7Bu0iw7RxiJVCMh1Pw/s/2171565732/br/129256398370-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649165891875000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0uWG2sVG9_113xec7kdWav">website</a> or to request a printed copy of <em>To Walk the Earth in Safety</em>, please contact the Bureau of Political-Military Affairs’ Office of Congressional and Public Affairs, at <a href="mailto:pm-cpa@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pm-cpa@state.gov</a>, and follow us on Twitter @<a class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/StateDeptPM" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">StateDeptPM</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On April 4, 2022, the <a href="https://www.state.gov/key-topics-office-of-weapons-removal-and-abatement/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDQuNTU4ODY4MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3Yva2V5LXRvcGljcy1vZmZpY2Utb2Ytd2VhcG9ucy1yZW1vdmFsLWFuZC1hYmF0ZW1lbnQvIn0.nfacEvjLb-FTOdPxHqOaezTcu1oOqUi2Q2_0b8v9P9M/s/2171565732/br/129256398370-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649165891875000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2Rc234o1cp3RA8XuEHJ-wY">Office of Weapons Removal and Abatement</a> in the U.S. Department of State’s Bureau of Political-Military Affairs released the 21st Edition of <em><a href="https://www.state.gov/reports/to-walk-the-earth-in-safety-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDQuNTU4ODY4MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvcmVwb3J0cy90by13YWxrLXRoZS1lYXJ0aC1pbi1zYWZldHktMjAyMi8ifQ.j3qLFN65Cs2Cclr-VIZ1MHAJH-7FwriYavnjg8vW4xc/s/2171565732/br/129256398370-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649165891875000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1gqxYELZxanbUIERS8rTOE">To Walk the Earth in Safety</a></em>, a report underscoring the accomplishments of the U.S. Conventional Weapons Destruction (CWD) Program in 2021.</p>
<p>The United States is the world’s single largest financial supporter of CWD. Since 1993, the United States has invested more than $4.2 billion for the safe clearance of landmines and explosive weapons of war, as well as the securing and safe disposal of excess small arms and light weapons and munitions in more than 100 countries and territories. In 2021, the United States funded CWD efforts in 62 countries with more than $265 million.</p>
<p>Our assistance – that of the United States government and our global partners – is crucial to building a more safe, secure, and prosperous world. Thanks to strong bipartisan funding support from Congress, the Department of State looks forward to continuing this important work with other donor countries, those impacted by conflict, and the brave men and women who work in the field to secure at-risk weapons and munitions and clear landmines and other explosive hazards.</p>
<p>For more information, please consult the PM <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureaus-offices/under-secretary-for-arms-control-and-international-security-affairs/bureau-of-political-military-affairs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDIsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjA0MDQuNTU4ODY4MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvYnVyZWF1cy1vZmZpY2VzL3VuZGVyLXNlY3JldGFyeS1mb3ItYXJtcy1jb250cm9sLWFuZC1pbnRlcm5hdGlvbmFsLXNlY3VyaXR5LWFmZmFpcnMvYnVyZWF1LW9mLXBvbGl0aWNhbC1taWxpdGFyeS1hZmZhaXJzLyJ9.bEEDotiszKd_xWhfCG45cqswc7Bu0iw7RxiJVCMh1Pw/s/2171565732/br/129256398370-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1649165891875000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0uWG2sVG9_113xec7kdWav">website</a> or to request a printed copy of <em>To Walk the Earth in Safety</em>, please contact the Bureau of Political-Military Affairs’ Office of Congressional and Public Affairs, at <a href="mailto:pm-cpa@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pm-cpa@state.gov</a>, and follow us on Twitter @<a class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/StateDeptPM" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">StateDeptPM</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Establishment of the Bureau of Cyberspace and Digital Policy</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/establishment-of-the-bureau-of-cyberspace-and-digital-policy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 11:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330965</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department is pleased to announce that the <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureaus-offices/deputy-secretary-of-state/bureau-of-cyberspace-and-digital-policy/">Bureau of Cyberspace and Digital Policy (CDP)</a> began operations today. A key piece of Secretary Blinken’s modernization agenda, the CDP bureau will address the national security challenges, economic opportunities, and implications for U.S. values associated with cyberspace, digital technologies, and digital policy.</p>
<p>The CDP bureau includes three policy units: International Cyberspace Security, International Information and Communications Policy, and Digital Freedom. Ultimately, the bureau will be led by a Senate-confirmed Ambassador-at-Large. Starting today, Jennifer Bachus, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, is serving as Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for the CDP bureau. PDAS Bachus will serve as Senior Bureau Official until an Ambassador-at-Large is confirmed. Michele Markoff is serving as Acting Deputy Assistant Secretary for International Cyberspace Security, Stephen Anderson is serving as Acting Deputy Assistant Secretary for International Information and Communications Policy, and Blake Peterson is serving as Acting Digital Freedom Coordinator.</p>
<p>The Department appreciates the service and collaboration of all who will work with and within the CDP bureau in the coming months and years to empower it to achieve its vital mission.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department is pleased to announce that the <a href="https://www.state.gov/bureaus-offices/deputy-secretary-of-state/bureau-of-cyberspace-and-digital-policy/">Bureau of Cyberspace and Digital Policy (CDP)</a> began operations today. A key piece of Secretary Blinken’s modernization agenda, the CDP bureau will address the national security challenges, economic opportunities, and implications for U.S. values associated with cyberspace, digital technologies, and digital policy.</p>
<p>The CDP bureau includes three policy units: International Cyberspace Security, International Information and Communications Policy, and Digital Freedom. Ultimately, the bureau will be led by a Senate-confirmed Ambassador-at-Large. Starting today, Jennifer Bachus, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, is serving as Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for the CDP bureau. PDAS Bachus will serve as Senior Bureau Official until an Ambassador-at-Large is confirmed. Michele Markoff is serving as Acting Deputy Assistant Secretary for International Cyberspace Security, Stephen Anderson is serving as Acting Deputy Assistant Secretary for International Information and Communications Policy, and Blake Peterson is serving as Acting Digital Freedom Coordinator.</p>
<p>The Department appreciates the service and collaboration of all who will work with and within the CDP bureau in the coming months and years to empower it to achieve its vital mission.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Assistant Secretary Lee Satterfield Travels to Croatia and Cyprus</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/assistant-secretary-lee-satterfield-travels-to-croatia-and-cyprus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 11:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=330943</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for Educational and Cultural Affairs (ECA) Lee Satterfield is traveling to Croatia and Cyprus from April 3-9, 2022.</p>
<p>In Croatia, Assistant Secretary Satterfield will celebrate the 30-year anniversary of diplomatic relations between the United States and Croatia, following the successful U.S.-Croatia Strategic Dialogue. Assistant Secretary Satterfield will join a senior U.S. delegation participating in the U.S.-Croatia Forum, where she will promote people-to-people ties through engagements with Croatian government officials, youth, civil society leaders, and alumni of U.S. government-sponsored exchange programs.</p>
<p>In Cyprus, Assistant Secretary Satterfield will participate in a historic ceremony with leadership from the Republic of Cyprus and the American University of Beirut (AUB) to celebrate AUB’s decision to open its first campus outside Lebanon. The Assistant Secretary will have bilateral discussions on a range of topics and meet with U.S. exchange students and alumni to highlight the importance of people-to-people relationships in working towards a solution within the framework of a bizonal, bicommunal federation with political equality to benefit all Cypriots. For further information, contact <a href="mailto:ECA-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ECA-Press@state.gov</a>. Follow along on Twitter at @<a class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/eca_as?lang=en" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">ECA_AS</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for Educational and Cultural Affairs (ECA) Lee Satterfield is traveling to Croatia and Cyprus from April 3-9, 2022.</p>
<p>In Croatia, Assistant Secretary Satterfield will celebrate the 30-year anniversary of diplomatic relations between the United States and Croatia, following the successful U.S.-Croatia Strategic Dialogue. Assistant Secretary Satterfield will join a senior U.S. delegation participating in the U.S.-Croatia Forum, where she will promote people-to-people ties through engagements with Croatian government officials, youth, civil society leaders, and alumni of U.S. government-sponsored exchange programs.</p>
<p>In Cyprus, Assistant Secretary Satterfield will participate in a historic ceremony with leadership from the Republic of Cyprus and the American University of Beirut (AUB) to celebrate AUB’s decision to open its first campus outside Lebanon. The Assistant Secretary will have bilateral discussions on a range of topics and meet with U.S. exchange students and alumni to highlight the importance of people-to-people relationships in working towards a solution within the framework of a bizonal, bicommunal federation with political equality to benefit all Cypriots. For further information, contact <a href="mailto:ECA-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ECA-Press@state.gov</a>. Follow along on Twitter at @<a class="external-link" href="https://twitter.com/eca_as?lang=en" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">ECA_AS</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
