<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 21:08:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Additional Humanitarian Assistance for the People of Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/additional-humanitarian-assistance-for-the-people-of-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 20:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is providing over $186 million in additional humanitarian assistance to support internally displaced persons and the more than three million refugees affected by Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war in Ukraine.  This will provide further support for humanitarian organizations responding to the crisis and complement the generosity of the neighboring countries that are welcoming and supporting refugees.</p>
<p>We call for an immediate end to Russia’s continuing war against Ukraine and for Russia to facilitate unhindered humanitarian access in Ukraine and safe passage for those who seek to leave the cities where they are trapped.  Humanitarian aid deliveries must be allowed to continue without interference, and humanitarian workers must have safe passage to deliver aid and assistance to those in need.</p>
<p>The United States is the largest single-country donor of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine, including providing nearly $293 million in humanitarian assistance both inside Ukraine and in the region since late February.  Our funding to-date amounts to nearly $644 million to vulnerable communities in the region since Russia first invaded Ukraine eight years ago.  Our humanitarian assistance flows through independent humanitarian organizations that deliver needs-based assistance with impartiality, humanity, neutrality, and independence.</p>
<p>The additional humanitarian assistance for refugees in Ukraine’s neighboring countries supports the provision of food, safe drinking water, protection, accessible shelter, and emergency health care through the support of our international and non-governmental partners. This funding will also help victims of this conflict maintain contact with family members who have been separated and promote family reunification when possible.</p>
<p>The United States commends the hospitality of the neighboring countries that are hosting those fleeing Ukraine.  As with any refugee situation, we call on the international community to respond to the needs of those seeking protection in a way that is consistent with the principle of non-refoulement and states’ respective obligations under international law.</p>
<p>We welcome the contributions of other donors toward this crisis response and urge still others to generously support the immediate humanitarian needs in Ukraine and the region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is providing over $186 million in additional humanitarian assistance to support internally displaced persons and the more than three million refugees affected by Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war in Ukraine.  This will provide further support for humanitarian organizations responding to the crisis and complement the generosity of the neighboring countries that are welcoming and supporting refugees.</p>
<p>We call for an immediate end to Russia’s continuing war against Ukraine and for Russia to facilitate unhindered humanitarian access in Ukraine and safe passage for those who seek to leave the cities where they are trapped.  Humanitarian aid deliveries must be allowed to continue without interference, and humanitarian workers must have safe passage to deliver aid and assistance to those in need.</p>
<p>The United States is the largest single-country donor of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine, including providing nearly $293 million in humanitarian assistance both inside Ukraine and in the region since late February.  Our funding to-date amounts to nearly $644 million to vulnerable communities in the region since Russia first invaded Ukraine eight years ago.  Our humanitarian assistance flows through independent humanitarian organizations that deliver needs-based assistance with impartiality, humanity, neutrality, and independence.</p>
<p>The additional humanitarian assistance for refugees in Ukraine’s neighboring countries supports the provision of food, safe drinking water, protection, accessible shelter, and emergency health care through the support of our international and non-governmental partners. This funding will also help victims of this conflict maintain contact with family members who have been separated and promote family reunification when possible.</p>
<p>The United States commends the hospitality of the neighboring countries that are hosting those fleeing Ukraine.  As with any refugee situation, we call on the international community to respond to the needs of those seeking protection in a way that is consistent with the principle of non-refoulement and states’ respective obligations under international law.</p>
<p>We welcome the contributions of other donors toward this crisis response and urge still others to generously support the immediate humanitarian needs in Ukraine and the region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Kuleba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-ukrainian-foreign-minister-kuleba-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 20:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324543</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke by phone today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to reiterate the United States’ ironclad commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and our resolve to provide security, economic, and humanitarian support to the people of Ukraine.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Kuleba discussed ongoing diplomatic efforts to stop President Putin’s war of choice. They shared deep concern regarding increasingly significant damage to infrastructure and buildings and resulting civilian deaths and injuries. The Secretary provided an update on the most recent U.S. and global efforts to hold Putin accountable for his unprovoked and brutal war.  He commended the bravery and determination of the Ukrainian people in the fight for their country in the face of the Russian forces’ callous disregard for civilian life.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke by phone today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to reiterate the United States’ ironclad commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and our resolve to provide security, economic, and humanitarian support to the people of Ukraine.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Kuleba discussed ongoing diplomatic efforts to stop President Putin’s war of choice. They shared deep concern regarding increasingly significant damage to infrastructure and buildings and resulting civilian deaths and injuries. The Secretary provided an update on the most recent U.S. and global efforts to hold Putin accountable for his unprovoked and brutal war.  He commended the bravery and determination of the Ukrainian people in the fight for their country in the face of the Russian forces’ callous disregard for civilian life.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General Delattre</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-french-foreign-ministry-secretary-general-delattre-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 16:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324477</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General François Delattre.  The Deputy Secretary and Secretary General Delattre reiterated their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Putin’s war of choice.  They agreed on the need for continued support for Ukraine and committed to continue to impose costs on Russia for its aggression.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General François Delattre.  The Deputy Secretary and Secretary General Delattre reiterated their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Putin’s war of choice.  They agreed on the need for continued support for Ukraine and committed to continue to impose costs on Russia for its aggression.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Azerbaijani President Aliyev</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-azerbaijani-president-aliyev-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 16:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324470</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Azerbaijani President Ilham Aliyev.  Secretary Blinken emphasized the continuing importance of the U.S.-Azerbaijani bilateral partnership and the U.S. commitment to promoting a peaceful, democratic, and prosperous future for the South Caucasus region.  Noting recent reports of escalation between Armenian and Azerbaijani forces, the Secretary called for the sides to show restraint and intensify diplomatic engagement to find comprehensive solutions to all outstanding issues.  He also stressed the importance of respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms in Azerbaijan.  The Secretary highlighted the U.S. commitment, alongside other partners, to continue to hold Moscow and its supporters, including the Lukashenka regime in Belarus, accountable for the Kremlin’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Azerbaijani President Ilham Aliyev.  Secretary Blinken emphasized the continuing importance of the U.S.-Azerbaijani bilateral partnership and the U.S. commitment to promoting a peaceful, democratic, and prosperous future for the South Caucasus region.  Noting recent reports of escalation between Armenian and Azerbaijani forces, the Secretary called for the sides to show restraint and intensify diplomatic engagement to find comprehensive solutions to all outstanding issues.  He also stressed the importance of respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms in Azerbaijan.  The Secretary highlighted the U.S. commitment, alongside other partners, to continue to hold Moscow and its supporters, including the Lukashenka regime in Belarus, accountable for the Kremlin’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the Occasion of the 11-year Anniversary of the Syrian Uprising</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-the-occasion-of-the-11-year-anniversary-of-the-syrian-uprising/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 16:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following statement was released by France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America on the occasion of the 11-year anniversary of the Syrian uprising:</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>Today marks 11 years since the Syrian people courageously and peacefully took to the streets to demand freedom, political reform, and a government that respects and upholds human rights.  The Assad regime met those demands with a brutal assault that continues today against the Syrian people.  After 11 years of death and suffering, it is past time for the regime and its enablers, including Russia and Iran, to halt their ruthless attack on the Syrian people.  The coincidence of this year’s anniversary with the appalling Russian aggression against Ukraine, which constitutes a breach of exceptional gravity to international law and the UN Charter, highlights Russia’s brutal and destructive behavior in both conflicts.  After more than a decade of conflict, the Syrian economic and humanitarian situation is bleak and millions of Syrian refugees hosted generously by Syria’s neighbors, as well as those internally displaced, cannot yet return home in line with UN standards, and without fear of violence, arbitrary arrest, and torture.  Continued conflict has also led to space for terrorists, particularly Daesh (ISIS), to exploit.  Preventing Daesh’s resurgence remains a priority.</p>
<p>We continue to support the UN-facilitated, Syrian-led process outlined within UN Security Council Resolution 2254.  We will continue to call for a nationwide ceasefire, respect for international humanitarian law, and unhindered aid access through all modalities, including through the continued authorization of the cross-border mechanism by the UN Security Council.  We additionally urge the immediate release of those arbitrarily detained and clarification of the fate and whereabouts of those who remain missing.  We do not support efforts to normalize relations with the Assad regime and will not normalize relations ourselves, nor lift sanctions or fund reconstruction until there is irreversible progress towards a political solution.  We encourage all parties, especially the Syrian regime, to participate in the March 21 meeting of the Constitutional Committee in good faith and call for the Committee to deliver on its mandate.</p>
<p>Impunity remains unacceptable.  We will therefore continue to actively promote accountability, including through support to the Commission of Inquiry, the International, Impartial and Independent Mechanism, and the Organization for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons (OPCW).  This also includes supporting organizations, many of which are Syrian-led, in collecting evidence and documenting the atrocities and serious violations of international law committed in Syria, including the use of chemical weapons.  The OPCW’s Investigation and Identification Team’s (IIT) efforts continue to attribute responsibility for the abhorrent use of chemical weapons in Syria.  Despite Syria’s lack of cooperation, the IIT has already confirmed the responsibility of the Assad regime in multiple chemical weapons attacks on the Syrian people. Those responsible for this disregard for the global norm against the use of chemical weapons must be held to account.</p>
<p>We welcome ongoing efforts by national courts to investigate and prosecute crimes within their jurisdiction committed in Syria and encourage increased support for these prosecutions.  As their harrowing testimonies show, justice for victims and their families is long overdue.  Pursuing accountability and justice is essential to building confidence in the political process called for in UNSCR 2254 and securing the stable, just, and enduring peace that Syrians need and deserve.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following statement was released by France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America on the occasion of the 11-year anniversary of the Syrian uprising:</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>Today marks 11 years since the Syrian people courageously and peacefully took to the streets to demand freedom, political reform, and a government that respects and upholds human rights.  The Assad regime met those demands with a brutal assault that continues today against the Syrian people.  After 11 years of death and suffering, it is past time for the regime and its enablers, including Russia and Iran, to halt their ruthless attack on the Syrian people.  The coincidence of this year’s anniversary with the appalling Russian aggression against Ukraine, which constitutes a breach of exceptional gravity to international law and the UN Charter, highlights Russia’s brutal and destructive behavior in both conflicts.  After more than a decade of conflict, the Syrian economic and humanitarian situation is bleak and millions of Syrian refugees hosted generously by Syria’s neighbors, as well as those internally displaced, cannot yet return home in line with UN standards, and without fear of violence, arbitrary arrest, and torture.  Continued conflict has also led to space for terrorists, particularly Daesh (ISIS), to exploit.  Preventing Daesh’s resurgence remains a priority.</p>
<p>We continue to support the UN-facilitated, Syrian-led process outlined within UN Security Council Resolution 2254.  We will continue to call for a nationwide ceasefire, respect for international humanitarian law, and unhindered aid access through all modalities, including through the continued authorization of the cross-border mechanism by the UN Security Council.  We additionally urge the immediate release of those arbitrarily detained and clarification of the fate and whereabouts of those who remain missing.  We do not support efforts to normalize relations with the Assad regime and will not normalize relations ourselves, nor lift sanctions or fund reconstruction until there is irreversible progress towards a political solution.  We encourage all parties, especially the Syrian regime, to participate in the March 21 meeting of the Constitutional Committee in good faith and call for the Committee to deliver on its mandate.</p>
<p>Impunity remains unacceptable.  We will therefore continue to actively promote accountability, including through support to the Commission of Inquiry, the International, Impartial and Independent Mechanism, and the Organization for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons (OPCW).  This also includes supporting organizations, many of which are Syrian-led, in collecting evidence and documenting the atrocities and serious violations of international law committed in Syria, including the use of chemical weapons.  The OPCW’s Investigation and Identification Team’s (IIT) efforts continue to attribute responsibility for the abhorrent use of chemical weapons in Syria.  Despite Syria’s lack of cooperation, the IIT has already confirmed the responsibility of the Assad regime in multiple chemical weapons attacks on the Syrian people. Those responsible for this disregard for the global norm against the use of chemical weapons must be held to account.</p>
<p>We welcome ongoing efforts by national courts to investigate and prosecute crimes within their jurisdiction committed in Syria and encourage increased support for these prosecutions.  As their harrowing testimonies show, justice for victims and their families is long overdue.  Pursuing accountability and justice is essential to building confidence in the political process called for in UNSCR 2254 and securing the stable, just, and enduring peace that Syrians need and deserve.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Promoting Accountability for Human Rights Abuses Perpetrated by the Governments of Russia and Belarus</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/promoting-accountability-for-human-rights-abuses-perpetrated-by-the-governments-of-russia-and-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 15:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States, with support from Allies and partners, is taking action to promote accountability for the Russian and Belarusian governments’ human rights abuses and violations within and outside their borders.  In doing so, we reiterate our condemnation of President Putin’s premeditated, unjustified, and unprovoked war against Ukraine, as well as the Lukashenka regime’s support and facilitation of the Russian Federation’s invasion.  President Putin’s military campaign against Ukraine has caused extensive and needless suffering, many hundreds and likely thousands of civilian casualties, including children, and growing reports of human rights abuses and violations.</p>
<p>At the same time, the Russian government has intensified a crackdown against its own citizens’ freedom of expression, including for members of the press, as well as freedom of association and peaceful assembly.  Today in Russia, those who provide factual reporting on the invasion or criticize Putin face criminal charges. Similarly, the Lukashenka regime in Belarus continues its violent repression against civil society, anti-war protestors, the democratic opposition, independent media, and ordinary Belarusians.</p>
<p>In response, the Department of State is announcing a series of actions to promote accountability for the Russian Federation’s and Government of Belarus’s human rights abuses and violations. These include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Designation of Alyaksandr Lukashenka pursuant to Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2021. Lukashenka was publicly designated for his involvement in gross violations of human rights and significant corruption. Under this authority, Lukashenka and Lukashenka’s immediate family members are ineligible for entry into the United States, to include his wife, Galina Lukashenka, his adult sons, Viktar Lukashenka and Dzmitry Lukashenka, and his minor son.</li>
<li>Designation of 11 senior Russian defense officials by the Department of State pursuant to E.O. 14024.  This includes Viktor Zolotov, the Head of the National Guard of Russia.  Under Zolotov’s leadership, the National Guard has cracked down on Russian citizens who have taken to the streets to protest their government’s brutal campaign in Ukraine. In addition, Zolotov’s troops are responsible for suppressing dissent in occupied areas of Ukraine.  More broadly, the designation of these 11 senior Russian defense leaders continues our imposition of severe costs on Russia’s Ministry of Defense as it pursues its brutal military invasion of Ukraine, which has led to unnecessary casualties and suffering, including the deaths of children. List here: <a href="https://www.state.gov/u-s-announces-sanctions-on-key-members-of-russias-defense-enterprise/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMTUuNTQ5MzU4MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvdS1zLWFubm91bmNlcy1zYW5jdGlvbnMtb24ta2V5LW1lbWJlcnMtb2YtcnVzc2lhcy1kZWZlbnNlLWVudGVycHJpc2UvIn0.2zOCYVpZR_-r0RqZfk2ksnvOg0uNxbNHd6Uo7B9bIJg/s/1039202793/br/128123916353-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1647441876727000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1dH2LbJXV6W4sZToI9AaF5">https://www.state.<wbr />gov/u-s-announces-sanctions-<wbr />on-key-members-of-russias-<wbr />defense-enterprise/</a></li>
<li>A new visa restriction policy under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act that applies to current and former Russian government officials believed to be involved in suppressing dissent in Russia and abroad. Family members of those who fall under the policy will also be ineligible for visas. We have taken our first action pursuant to this new visa authority against 38 individuals, and will continue to implement this policy to demonstrate solidarity with the victims of Russia’s repression.</li>
<li>Designation of two of Russia’s Federal Security Service (FSB) officers in Crimea, Artur Shambazov and <wbr />Andrey Tishenin, pursuant to Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2021.  Shambazov and Tishenin were publicly designated for their involvement in a gross violation of human rights, namely torture.</li>
<li>Action to impose visa restrictions on six individuals who, acting on behalf of the Russian Federation, were involved in attacks on Chechen dissidents living in Europe.  This action is being taken pursuant to the “Khashoggi Ban,” a visa restriction policy the Administration announced last year to counter transnational repression.</li>
<li>Imposition of visa restrictions on 25 individuals responsible for undermining democracy in Belarus pursuant to Presidential Proclamation 8015, including Belarusian nationals involved in the fatal shooting and beating of two peaceful protesters; security forces involved in the violent dispersal of peaceful protests; regime officials responsible for launching politically-motivated cases against members of the opposition and civil society; and individuals engaging in corrupt practices supporting the Lukashenka regime.</li>
</ul>
<p>Additionally, the Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) is imposing sanctions on Kurchaloi District of the Chechen Republic Branch of the Ministry of Internal Affairs of the Russian Federation, two of its officers, a Kurchaloi District prosecutor, and a district court judge in Moscow, pursuant to the Sergei Magnitsky Rule of Law Accountability Act of 2012.  OFAC is also re-designating Alyaksandr <wbr />Lukashenka for his corrupt practices, and, pursuant to E.O. 13405, designating Galina Lukashenka as a member of Lukashenka’s family.</p>
<p>Under President Putin, Russian authorities have repeatedly targeted human rights advocates, peaceful dissenters, and whistleblowers, and they continue to do so amidst their ruthless war on Ukraine.  The Russian government has failed to take adequate steps to identify, investigate, prosecute, or punish most officials who committed abuses or violations, resulting in a climate of impunity.  Likewise, the Lukashenka regime continues its brutal crackdown on peaceful activists while it intensifies its support to the invasion of Ukraine. We are taking action against this autocratic attack on democracy.  The United States will continue to promote accountability for those who support, enable, and perpetrate human rights abuses in Russia, Ukraine, Belarus, and elsewhere.</p>
<p>For a complete list of today’s Department of the Treasury actions, please see this press release: <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0654" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0654</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States, with support from Allies and partners, is taking action to promote accountability for the Russian and Belarusian governments’ human rights abuses and violations within and outside their borders.  In doing so, we reiterate our condemnation of President Putin’s premeditated, unjustified, and unprovoked war against Ukraine, as well as the Lukashenka regime’s support and facilitation of the Russian Federation’s invasion.  President Putin’s military campaign against Ukraine has caused extensive and needless suffering, many hundreds and likely thousands of civilian casualties, including children, and growing reports of human rights abuses and violations.</p>
<p>At the same time, the Russian government has intensified a crackdown against its own citizens’ freedom of expression, including for members of the press, as well as freedom of association and peaceful assembly.  Today in Russia, those who provide factual reporting on the invasion or criticize Putin face criminal charges. Similarly, the Lukashenka regime in Belarus continues its violent repression against civil society, anti-war protestors, the democratic opposition, independent media, and ordinary Belarusians.</p>
<p>In response, the Department of State is announcing a series of actions to promote accountability for the Russian Federation’s and Government of Belarus’s human rights abuses and violations. These include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Designation of Alyaksandr Lukashenka pursuant to Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2021. Lukashenka was publicly designated for his involvement in gross violations of human rights and significant corruption. Under this authority, Lukashenka and Lukashenka’s immediate family members are ineligible for entry into the United States, to include his wife, Galina Lukashenka, his adult sons, Viktar Lukashenka and Dzmitry Lukashenka, and his minor son.</li>
<li>Designation of 11 senior Russian defense officials by the Department of State pursuant to E.O. 14024.  This includes Viktor Zolotov, the Head of the National Guard of Russia.  Under Zolotov’s leadership, the National Guard has cracked down on Russian citizens who have taken to the streets to protest their government’s brutal campaign in Ukraine. In addition, Zolotov’s troops are responsible for suppressing dissent in occupied areas of Ukraine.  More broadly, the designation of these 11 senior Russian defense leaders continues our imposition of severe costs on Russia’s Ministry of Defense as it pursues its brutal military invasion of Ukraine, which has led to unnecessary casualties and suffering, including the deaths of children. List here: <a href="https://www.state.gov/u-s-announces-sanctions-on-key-members-of-russias-defense-enterprise/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMTUuNTQ5MzU4MDEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvdS1zLWFubm91bmNlcy1zYW5jdGlvbnMtb24ta2V5LW1lbWJlcnMtb2YtcnVzc2lhcy1kZWZlbnNlLWVudGVycHJpc2UvIn0.2zOCYVpZR_-r0RqZfk2ksnvOg0uNxbNHd6Uo7B9bIJg/s/1039202793/br/128123916353-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1647441876727000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1dH2LbJXV6W4sZToI9AaF5">https://www.state.<wbr />gov/u-s-announces-sanctions-<wbr />on-key-members-of-russias-<wbr />defense-enterprise/</a></li>
<li>A new visa restriction policy under Section 212(a)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act that applies to current and former Russian government officials believed to be involved in suppressing dissent in Russia and abroad. Family members of those who fall under the policy will also be ineligible for visas. We have taken our first action pursuant to this new visa authority against 38 individuals, and will continue to implement this policy to demonstrate solidarity with the victims of Russia’s repression.</li>
<li>Designation of two of Russia’s Federal Security Service (FSB) officers in Crimea, Artur Shambazov and <wbr />Andrey Tishenin, pursuant to Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2021.  Shambazov and Tishenin were publicly designated for their involvement in a gross violation of human rights, namely torture.</li>
<li>Action to impose visa restrictions on six individuals who, acting on behalf of the Russian Federation, were involved in attacks on Chechen dissidents living in Europe.  This action is being taken pursuant to the “Khashoggi Ban,” a visa restriction policy the Administration announced last year to counter transnational repression.</li>
<li>Imposition of visa restrictions on 25 individuals responsible for undermining democracy in Belarus pursuant to Presidential Proclamation 8015, including Belarusian nationals involved in the fatal shooting and beating of two peaceful protesters; security forces involved in the violent dispersal of peaceful protests; regime officials responsible for launching politically-motivated cases against members of the opposition and civil society; and individuals engaging in corrupt practices supporting the Lukashenka regime.</li>
</ul>
<p>Additionally, the Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) is imposing sanctions on Kurchaloi District of the Chechen Republic Branch of the Ministry of Internal Affairs of the Russian Federation, two of its officers, a Kurchaloi District prosecutor, and a district court judge in Moscow, pursuant to the Sergei Magnitsky Rule of Law Accountability Act of 2012.  OFAC is also re-designating Alyaksandr <wbr />Lukashenka for his corrupt practices, and, pursuant to E.O. 13405, designating Galina Lukashenka as a member of Lukashenka’s family.</p>
<p>Under President Putin, Russian authorities have repeatedly targeted human rights advocates, peaceful dissenters, and whistleblowers, and they continue to do so amidst their ruthless war on Ukraine.  The Russian government has failed to take adequate steps to identify, investigate, prosecute, or punish most officials who committed abuses or violations, resulting in a climate of impunity.  Likewise, the Lukashenka regime continues its brutal crackdown on peaceful activists while it intensifies its support to the invasion of Ukraine. We are taking action against this autocratic attack on democracy.  The United States will continue to promote accountability for those who support, enable, and perpetrate human rights abuses in Russia, Ukraine, Belarus, and elsewhere.</p>
<p>For a complete list of today’s Department of the Treasury actions, please see this press release: <a class="external-link" href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0654" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0654</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Commending New Zealand’s New Sanctions Regime</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/commending-new-zealands-new-sanctions-regime/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 01:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the passage of New Zealand’s new sanctions regime, which allows the imposition of sanctions on those responsible for, or associated with, Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. It also gives the New Zealand government the power to sanction individuals and entities that are of economic or strategic relevance to Russia and will ensure Russia cannot use New Zealand to circumvent sanctions imposed by the international community.  Additionally, the law authorizes the imposition of sanctions on those supporting Russia’s invasion, including members of the regime in Belarus. For the first time, New Zealand has extended its sanctions authorities beyond its UN Security Council obligations.</p>
<p>New Zealand’s announcement underscores its commitment to the freedom, territorial integrity, and sovereignty of Ukraine and illustrates New Zealand’s lasting commitment to preserving the rules-based international order.  Together with the international community, we will hold Russia to account for its aggression.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the passage of New Zealand’s new sanctions regime, which allows the imposition of sanctions on those responsible for, or associated with, Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. It also gives the New Zealand government the power to sanction individuals and entities that are of economic or strategic relevance to Russia and will ensure Russia cannot use New Zealand to circumvent sanctions imposed by the international community.  Additionally, the law authorizes the imposition of sanctions on those supporting Russia’s invasion, including members of the regime in Belarus. For the first time, New Zealand has extended its sanctions authorities beyond its UN Security Council obligations.</p>
<p>New Zealand’s announcement underscores its commitment to the freedom, territorial integrity, and sovereignty of Ukraine and illustrates New Zealand’s lasting commitment to preserving the rules-based international order.  Together with the international community, we will hold Russia to account for its aggression.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Croatian Prime Minister Plenkovic</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-croatian-prime-minister-plenkovic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Croatian Prime Minister Andrej Plenkovic.  Secretary Blinken reaffirmed U.S. support for Ukraine in the face of President Putin’s continued war against Ukraine.  The Secretary expressed his deep appreciation for the strong support of Prime Minister Plenkovic and his government for Ukraine, including providing security assistance and accepting refugees, and for Croatia’s active role in NATO.  Secretary Blinken and Prime Minister Plenkovic also discussed the March 10 drone crash in Zagreb.  The Secretary noted Croatia’s critical role in securing the European future of the entire Western Balkans, including Bosnia and Herzegovina.  The Secretary also welcomed the March 17 U.S.-Croatia Strategic Dialogue, which will bring together senior-level interagency teams to review joint efforts to advance shared priorities.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Croatian Prime Minister Andrej Plenkovic.  Secretary Blinken reaffirmed U.S. support for Ukraine in the face of President Putin’s continued war against Ukraine.  The Secretary expressed his deep appreciation for the strong support of Prime Minister Plenkovic and his government for Ukraine, including providing security assistance and accepting refugees, and for Croatia’s active role in NATO.  Secretary Blinken and Prime Minister Plenkovic also discussed the March 10 drone crash in Zagreb.  The Secretary noted Croatia’s critical role in securing the European future of the entire Western Balkans, including Bosnia and Herzegovina.  The Secretary also welcomed the March 17 U.S.-Croatia Strategic Dialogue, which will bring together senior-level interagency teams to review joint efforts to advance shared priorities.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Armenian Prime Minister Pashinyan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-armenian-prime-minister-pashinyan-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324255</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary Antony J. Blinken spoke with Armenia’s Prime Minister Nikol Pashinyan today.  The Secretary underscored the continuing importance of the U.S. – Armenia bilateral partnership and U.S. commitment to promoting a peaceful, democratic, and prosperous future for the South Caucasus.  Noting recent reports of escalation between Armenian and Azerbaijani forces, the Secretary called for the sides to show restraint and intensify diplomatic engagement to find comprehensive solutions to all outstanding issues.  The Secretary urged continued democratic reforms in Armenia.  The Secretary highlighted the U.S. commitment, alongside other partners, to continue to hold Moscow and its supporters, including the Lukashenka regime in Belarus, accountable for the Kremlin’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary Antony J. Blinken spoke with Armenia’s Prime Minister Nikol Pashinyan today.  The Secretary underscored the continuing importance of the U.S. – Armenia bilateral partnership and U.S. commitment to promoting a peaceful, democratic, and prosperous future for the South Caucasus.  Noting recent reports of escalation between Armenian and Azerbaijani forces, the Secretary called for the sides to show restraint and intensify diplomatic engagement to find comprehensive solutions to all outstanding issues.  The Secretary urged continued democratic reforms in Armenia.  The Secretary highlighted the U.S. commitment, alongside other partners, to continue to hold Moscow and its supporters, including the Lukashenka regime in Belarus, accountable for the Kremlin’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Announces Sanctions on Key Members of Russia’s Defense Enterprise</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-announces-sanctions-on-key-members-of-russias-defense-enterprise/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 23:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324249</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The world has been transfixed as Russia has perpetrated a premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine.  Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine has resulted in widespread human suffering and casualties, including the deaths of innocent civilians, including children. Today, the Department of State is continuing to impose severe costs on Russian military leaders.</p>
<p>Specifically, the following 11 individuals are being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 Section 1(a)(i), as persons who operate or have operated in the defense and related materiel sector of the Russian Federation economy:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>ALEKSEY KRIVORUCHKO</strong> is a Russian Ministry of Defense Deputy Minister of Defense.</li>
<li><strong>TIMUR IVANOV</strong> is a Russian Ministry of Defense Deputy Minister of Defense.</li>
<li><strong>YUNUS-BEK EVKUROV </strong>is a Russian Ministry of Defense Deputy Minister of Defense.</li>
<li><strong>DMITRY BULGAKOV</strong> is a Russian Deputy Minister of Defense and a General of the Army. Bulgakov is the Russian Federation Ministry of Defense’s senior-most officer responsible for logistics matters.</li>
<li><strong>YURIY SADOVENKO </strong>is a Russian Ministry of Defense Deputy Minister of Defense.</li>
<li><strong>NIKOLAY PANKOV </strong>is a Russian Ministry of Defense Deputy Minister of Defense.</li>
<li><strong>RUSLAN TSALIKOV </strong>is a Russian Ministry of Defense Deputy Minister of Defense.</li>
<li><strong>GENNADY ZHIDKO </strong>is a Russian Ministry of Defense Deputy Minister of Defense.</li>
<li><strong>VIKTOR ZOLOTOV </strong>is a Russian General of the Army and Commander-in-Chief of Russia’s National Guard Troops. He is a member of Russia’s Security Council.</li>
<li><strong>DMITRY SHUGAEV </strong>is a senior leader of the Russian Ministry of Defense who is the Director of the Russian Ministry of Defense’s Federal Service for Military Technical Cooperation.</li>
<li><strong>ALEXANDER MIKHEEV</strong> is the Director General of Rosoboronexport, which is Russia’s state-controlled intermediary that carries out foreign trade with respect to military goods. Mikheev has been involved in synchronizing the supplies of weapons and special equipment using the Russian Ministry of Defense’s capabilities; has served as a member of an organizing committee led by Russia’s Minister of Defense of a Russian Ministry of Defense-organized military-focused forum; and has served on a delegation led by Russia’s Minister of Defense.</li>
</ol>
<p>These persons will be added to the list of Specially Designated Nationals and Blocked Persons and all property and interests in property of the individuals above that are in the United States or in the possession or control of U.S. persons are blocked and must be reported to the Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC).  In addition, any entities that are owned, directly or indirectly, 50 percent or more by one or more blocked persons are also blocked.  All transactions by U.S. persons or within (or transiting) the United States that involve any property or interests in property of designated or otherwise blocked persons are prohibited unless authorized by a general or specific license issued by OFAC, or exempt.  These prohibitions include the making of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services by, to, or for the benefit of any blocked person and the receipt of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services from any such person.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The world has been transfixed as Russia has perpetrated a premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified attack on Ukraine.  Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine has resulted in widespread human suffering and casualties, including the deaths of innocent civilians, including children. Today, the Department of State is continuing to impose severe costs on Russian military leaders.</p>
<p>Specifically, the following 11 individuals are being designated pursuant to E.O. 14024 Section 1(a)(i), as persons who operate or have operated in the defense and related materiel sector of the Russian Federation economy:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>ALEKSEY KRIVORUCHKO</strong> is a Russian Ministry of Defense Deputy Minister of Defense.</li>
<li><strong>TIMUR IVANOV</strong> is a Russian Ministry of Defense Deputy Minister of Defense.</li>
<li><strong>YUNUS-BEK EVKUROV </strong>is a Russian Ministry of Defense Deputy Minister of Defense.</li>
<li><strong>DMITRY BULGAKOV</strong> is a Russian Deputy Minister of Defense and a General of the Army. Bulgakov is the Russian Federation Ministry of Defense’s senior-most officer responsible for logistics matters.</li>
<li><strong>YURIY SADOVENKO </strong>is a Russian Ministry of Defense Deputy Minister of Defense.</li>
<li><strong>NIKOLAY PANKOV </strong>is a Russian Ministry of Defense Deputy Minister of Defense.</li>
<li><strong>RUSLAN TSALIKOV </strong>is a Russian Ministry of Defense Deputy Minister of Defense.</li>
<li><strong>GENNADY ZHIDKO </strong>is a Russian Ministry of Defense Deputy Minister of Defense.</li>
<li><strong>VIKTOR ZOLOTOV </strong>is a Russian General of the Army and Commander-in-Chief of Russia’s National Guard Troops. He is a member of Russia’s Security Council.</li>
<li><strong>DMITRY SHUGAEV </strong>is a senior leader of the Russian Ministry of Defense who is the Director of the Russian Ministry of Defense’s Federal Service for Military Technical Cooperation.</li>
<li><strong>ALEXANDER MIKHEEV</strong> is the Director General of Rosoboronexport, which is Russia’s state-controlled intermediary that carries out foreign trade with respect to military goods. Mikheev has been involved in synchronizing the supplies of weapons and special equipment using the Russian Ministry of Defense’s capabilities; has served as a member of an organizing committee led by Russia’s Minister of Defense of a Russian Ministry of Defense-organized military-focused forum; and has served on a delegation led by Russia’s Minister of Defense.</li>
</ol>
<p>These persons will be added to the list of Specially Designated Nationals and Blocked Persons and all property and interests in property of the individuals above that are in the United States or in the possession or control of U.S. persons are blocked and must be reported to the Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC).  In addition, any entities that are owned, directly or indirectly, 50 percent or more by one or more blocked persons are also blocked.  All transactions by U.S. persons or within (or transiting) the United States that involve any property or interests in property of designated or otherwise blocked persons are prohibited unless authorized by a general or specific license issued by OFAC, or exempt.  These prohibitions include the making of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services by, to, or for the benefit of any blocked person and the receipt of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services from any such person.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
