<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 20:16:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>United States Chairs Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development 60th Anniversary Ministerial and Welcomes New Secretary General</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-chairs-organization-for-economic-cooperation-and-development-60th-anniversary-ministerial-and-welcomes-new-secretary-general/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 20:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247969</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is chairing the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development’s (OECD) 60th Anniversary Ministerial Council Meeting, taking place in two parts under the theme, “Shared Values: Building Green and Inclusive Future.” Part One took place May 31-June 1, and Part Two will take place this fall.</p>
<p>The OECD’s 60th anniversary gives its members the opportunity to reflect upon and recommit to the shared values that brought members together six decades ago. It is a timely exercise, as members usher in a new chapter at the OECD with the first change in Secretary General leadership in 15 years. During Part One, Secretary Blinken and OECD members bid farewell to Secretary General Angel Gurria of Mexico and welcomed Secretary General Mathias Cormann of Australia to the organization.</p>
<p>Secretary General Angel Gurria served the organization with dedication during a period of profound change in the world economy. His leadership ensured the OECD was an essential voice in the global economic dialogue and reinforced the importance of producing evidence-based analysis that inspires better policies for better lives. His commitment to the promotion of a rules-based international economy is part of an enduring OECD legacy that the United States will continue to uphold going forward.</p>
<p>The United States welcomes Secretary General Mathias Cormann and looks forward to working together on the second part of the 60th anniversary Ministerial Council Meeting taking place in the fall, and onward throughout his term. Today marks a new era of OECD cooperation, as members work together to address climate change, international taxation, and labor and worker rights, among many other challenges, through the promotion of an inclusive and sustainable global economic recovery.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States is chairing the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development’s (OECD) 60th Anniversary Ministerial Council Meeting, taking place in two parts under the theme, “Shared Values: Building Green and Inclusive Future.” Part One took place May 31-June 1, and Part Two will take place this fall.</p>
<p>The OECD’s 60th anniversary gives its members the opportunity to reflect upon and recommit to the shared values that brought members together six decades ago. It is a timely exercise, as members usher in a new chapter at the OECD with the first change in Secretary General leadership in 15 years. During Part One, Secretary Blinken and OECD members bid farewell to Secretary General Angel Gurria of Mexico and welcomed Secretary General Mathias Cormann of Australia to the organization.</p>
<p>Secretary General Angel Gurria served the organization with dedication during a period of profound change in the world economy. His leadership ensured the OECD was an essential voice in the global economic dialogue and reinforced the importance of producing evidence-based analysis that inspires better policies for better lives. His commitment to the promotion of a rules-based international economy is part of an enduring OECD legacy that the United States will continue to uphold going forward.</p>
<p>The United States welcomes Secretary General Mathias Cormann and looks forward to working together on the second part of the 60th anniversary Ministerial Council Meeting taking place in the fall, and onward throughout his term. Today marks a new era of OECD cooperation, as members work together to address climate change, international taxation, and labor and worker rights, among many other challenges, through the promotion of an inclusive and sustainable global economic recovery.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Republic of Cyprus Foreign Minister Christodoulides</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-republic-of-cyprus-foreign-minister-christodoulides/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 19:06:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247960</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Republic of Cyprus (ROC) Foreign Minister Nikos Christodoulides.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Christodoulides reaffirmed their mutual commitment to deepening the strong U.S.-ROC bilateral relationship.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister agreed on the importance of promoting stability in the Eastern Mediterranean through regional cooperation and peaceful resolution of disagreements.  The Secretary pledged continued U.S. support for Cypriot-led, UN-facilitated efforts to reunify the island as a bizonal, bicommunal federation for the benefit of all Cypriots, as the United States encourages both sides to demonstrate the necessary openness, flexibility, and compromise to find common ground to restart Cyprus settlement talks.  The Secretary expressed support for the 3+1 diplomatic mechanism, which includes the ROC, Greece, Israel, and the United States.   The Secretary stressed the importance of efforts to counter harmful influence from Russia and China in the region.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Republic of Cyprus (ROC) Foreign Minister Nikos Christodoulides.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Christodoulides reaffirmed their mutual commitment to deepening the strong U.S.-ROC bilateral relationship.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister agreed on the importance of promoting stability in the Eastern Mediterranean through regional cooperation and peaceful resolution of disagreements.  The Secretary pledged continued U.S. support for Cypriot-led, UN-facilitated efforts to reunify the island as a bizonal, bicommunal federation for the benefit of all Cypriots, as the United States encourages both sides to demonstrate the necessary openness, flexibility, and compromise to find common ground to restart Cyprus settlement talks.  The Secretary expressed support for the 3+1 diplomatic mechanism, which includes the ROC, Greece, Israel, and the United States.   The Secretary stressed the importance of efforts to counter harmful influence from Russia and China in the region.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Participation in the Virtual NATO Foreign Ministerial</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-participation-in-the-virtual-nato-foreign-ministerial/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 18:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247955</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken participated today in the virtual NATO Foreign Ministerial hosted by NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg.  Secretary Blinken discussed the upcoming NATO Summit and reaffirmed U.S. commitment to NATO, highlighting the Administration’s priority to revitalize our alliances.  The Secretary expressed support for Secretary General Stoltenberg’s efforts to adapt the Alliance through the NATO 2030 initiative, making it more resilient and capable of confronting systemic challenges from Russia and the People&#8217;s Republic of China and responding to emerging and evolving challenges, including climate change and hybrid and cyber threats.  Secretary Blinken underscored the importance of Alliance partnerships, including NATO-EU cooperation, and encouraged NATO to deepen its cooperation with Australia, Japan, New Zealand, and the Republic of Korea.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken participated today in the virtual NATO Foreign Ministerial hosted by NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg.  Secretary Blinken discussed the upcoming NATO Summit and reaffirmed U.S. commitment to NATO, highlighting the Administration’s priority to revitalize our alliances.  The Secretary expressed support for Secretary General Stoltenberg’s efforts to adapt the Alliance through the NATO 2030 initiative, making it more resilient and capable of confronting systemic challenges from Russia and the People&#8217;s Republic of China and responding to emerging and evolving challenges, including climate change and hybrid and cyber threats.  Secretary Blinken underscored the importance of Alliance partnerships, including NATO-EU cooperation, and encouraged NATO to deepen its cooperation with Australia, Japan, New Zealand, and the Republic of Korea.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Tajikistan Foreign Minister Muhriddin</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-tajikistan-foreign-minister-muhriddin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 18:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247941</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Tajikistan Foreign Minister Sirojiddin Muhriddin.  The Secretary affirmed the United States’ continuing support for Tajikistan’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, and independence. The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Tajikistan’s leadership on regional security issues, support for Afghanistan peace negotiations, and continued partnership on counterterrorism efforts, including in the framework of the C5+1.  Expressing condolences for the lives lost during the Kyrgyz and Tajik border clashes in April, the Secretary commended the efforts to de-escalate hostilities, demarcate the border, and achieve a lasting peaceful resolution of the dispute.  The Secretary further noted the importance of advancing regional connectivity, human rights, and fundamental freedoms for all.  Both leaders affirmed the strong U.S.-Tajikistan bilateral relationship and agreed that they would hold the Annual Bilateral Consultations as soon as circumstances permit.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Tajikistan Foreign Minister Sirojiddin Muhriddin.  The Secretary affirmed the United States’ continuing support for Tajikistan’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, and independence. The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Tajikistan’s leadership on regional security issues, support for Afghanistan peace negotiations, and continued partnership on counterterrorism efforts, including in the framework of the C5+1.  Expressing condolences for the lives lost during the Kyrgyz and Tajik border clashes in April, the Secretary commended the efforts to de-escalate hostilities, demarcate the border, and achieve a lasting peaceful resolution of the dispute.  The Secretary further noted the importance of advancing regional connectivity, human rights, and fundamental freedoms for all.  Both leaders affirmed the strong U.S.-Tajikistan bilateral relationship and agreed that they would hold the Annual Bilateral Consultations as soon as circumstances permit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Special Envoy for the Horn of Africa Feltman Visits Qatar, Saudi Arabia, UAE, Kenya</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-special-envoy-for-the-horn-of-africa-feltman-visits-qatar-saudi-arabia-uae-kenya/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 16:55:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247888</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Special Envoy for the Horn of Africa Jeffrey Feltman will travel to Qatar, Saudi Arabia, the United Arab Emirates, and Kenya from May 31 to June 6. Special Envoy Feltman will meet with senior officials of the four countries to discuss cooperative approaches to supporting a stable and prosperous Horn of Africa, including a resolution of the dispute over the Grand Ethiopian Renaissance Dam that is acceptable to all parties.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Special Envoy for the Horn of Africa Jeffrey Feltman will travel to Qatar, Saudi Arabia, the United Arab Emirates, and Kenya from May 31 to June 6. Special Envoy Feltman will meet with senior officials of the four countries to discuss cooperative approaches to supporting a stable and prosperous Horn of Africa, including a resolution of the dispute over the Grand Ethiopian Renaissance Dam that is acceptable to all parties.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Strengthening Democracy in Central America and Addressing Root Causes of Migration at Central American Integration System Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/strengthening-democracy-in-central-america-and-addressing-root-causes-of-migration-at-central-american-integration-system-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 14:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247818</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary Antony J. Blinken is traveling to Central America on June 1-2, 2021 to engage with leaders from the region at a meeting of the Central American Integration System (SICA) in San Jose, Costa Rica.  In its current role as chair of SICA, Costa Rica is inviting senior leaders from Guatemala, Belize, Honduras, El Salvador, Nicaragua, Panama, and the Dominican Republic, as well as Mexico, for this meeting.  They will discuss a collaborative approach to the shared regional challenge of irregular migration and promoting democracy, human rights, prosperity, and rule of law.</p>
<p><strong>Regional Cooperation</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>We increasingly face common challenges requiring collaborative solutions. It is imperative that we work together to promote democracy and good governance, respect for human rights, security, prosperity, and good environmental stewardship.  We must reduce inequality, violations and abuses of human rights, and gender-based violence.</li>
<li>Democratic governance and institutions are vital for achieving a more secure and prosperous Central America. As we celebrate the 20th anniversary of InterAmerican Democratic Charter, it is an opportune time to reaffirm our collective commitment to the integrity and institutions of our democracies.</li>
<li>President Biden has announced a comprehensive collaborative approach that includes a multi-year, $4 billion plan to address the root causes of irregular migration in North and Central America.</li>
<li>In April, Vice President Harris announced $310 million in U.S. funding to address food insecurity, provide life-saving assistance, and support protection for vulnerable people in communities throughout the region. This includes $255 million in humanitarian assistance to respond to immediate needs.</li>
<li>U.S. funding protects and assists vulnerable migrants, internally displaced persons, asylum seekers, and refugees. Our funding includes more than $28 million for programs inside Costa Rica, including those displaced by the political and economic crisis in Venezuela.  We encourage other regional partners to reinforce U.S. efforts to improve access to international protection.</li>
<li>In her role addressing the causes of migration with El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras, as well as with Mexico, Vice President Kamala Harris last month announced a Call to Action for businesses and social enterprises to make new, significant commitments to help send a signal of hope to the people of the region and sustainably address the root causes of migration by promoting economic opportunity. As part of this Call to Action launch, 12 companies and organizations announced commitments to support inclusive economic development in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras, including: Accion, Bancolombia, Chobani, Davivienda, Duolingo, the Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health, Mastercard, Microsoft, Nespresso, Pro Mujer, the Tent Partnership for Refugees, and the World Economic Forum.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary Antony J. Blinken is traveling to Central America on June 1-2, 2021 to engage with leaders from the region at a meeting of the Central American Integration System (SICA) in San Jose, Costa Rica.  In its current role as chair of SICA, Costa Rica is inviting senior leaders from Guatemala, Belize, Honduras, El Salvador, Nicaragua, Panama, and the Dominican Republic, as well as Mexico, for this meeting.  They will discuss a collaborative approach to the shared regional challenge of irregular migration and promoting democracy, human rights, prosperity, and rule of law.</p>
<p><strong>Regional Cooperation</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>We increasingly face common challenges requiring collaborative solutions. It is imperative that we work together to promote democracy and good governance, respect for human rights, security, prosperity, and good environmental stewardship.  We must reduce inequality, violations and abuses of human rights, and gender-based violence.</li>
<li>Democratic governance and institutions are vital for achieving a more secure and prosperous Central America. As we celebrate the 20th anniversary of InterAmerican Democratic Charter, it is an opportune time to reaffirm our collective commitment to the integrity and institutions of our democracies.</li>
<li>President Biden has announced a comprehensive collaborative approach that includes a multi-year, $4 billion plan to address the root causes of irregular migration in North and Central America.</li>
<li>In April, Vice President Harris announced $310 million in U.S. funding to address food insecurity, provide life-saving assistance, and support protection for vulnerable people in communities throughout the region. This includes $255 million in humanitarian assistance to respond to immediate needs.</li>
<li>U.S. funding protects and assists vulnerable migrants, internally displaced persons, asylum seekers, and refugees. Our funding includes more than $28 million for programs inside Costa Rica, including those displaced by the political and economic crisis in Venezuela.  We encourage other regional partners to reinforce U.S. efforts to improve access to international protection.</li>
<li>In her role addressing the causes of migration with El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras, as well as with Mexico, Vice President Kamala Harris last month announced a Call to Action for businesses and social enterprises to make new, significant commitments to help send a signal of hope to the people of the region and sustainably address the root causes of migration by promoting economic opportunity. As part of this Call to Action launch, 12 companies and organizations announced commitments to support inclusive economic development in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras, including: Accion, Bancolombia, Chobani, Davivienda, Duolingo, the Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health, Mastercard, Microsoft, Nespresso, Pro Mujer, the Tent Partnership for Refugees, and the World Economic Forum.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States and Costa Rica: Partners in Democracy and Security</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-and-costa-rica-partners-in-democracy-and-security/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 14:44:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken is traveling to San Jose on June 1-2, 2021, to a meeting of the Central American Integration System (SICA) convened by Costa Rican President Carlos Alvarado Quesada.  In Costa Rica, he will meet with President Alvarado and Foreign Minister Rodolfo Solano Quirós to discuss the strong U.S.-Costa Rica partnership and to advance collaboration on regional and global issues, including migration, counternarcotics, human rights, and climate change.</p>
<p><strong>A Relationship Based on Shared Values and Commitments</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Costa Rica, a strong democracy of more than five million people with deep ties to the United States, is important to key U.S. goals in the region and is committed to continued close cooperation with the United States. It has an open trade and investment climate, and recently became the 38th member of the OECD. It is also one of the strongest and most reliable voices in Latin America on human rights and rule of law, and has been a superb partner in the fight against transnational crime and drug trafficking.</li>
<li>The United States is Costa Rica’s top trading partner, accounting for around 40 percent of both imports and exports. The United States is also Costa Rica’s top source of foreign direct investment, reaching $1.92 billion in 2019 (70% of total FDI) .  There are currently more than 200 U.S. companies in Costa Rica that collectively employ more than 94,000 people, or nearly 84 percent of all jobs created by multinational companies in Costa Rica.</li>
<li>Costa Rica is a champion of human rights and democratic norms across the region, including through its active role in the Organization of American States (OAS). Costa Rica has condemned fraudulent parliamentary elections in Venezuela and supported the OAS resolution calling for electoral reform in Nicaragua. Additionally, Costa Rica hosts more than 450,000 Nicaraguans, including 110,000 people who fled Nicaragua after the 2018 political crisis, many of whom are currently seeking refugee status in Costa Rica. Costa Rica also hosts nearly 30,000 Venezuelan migrants and refugees. The Costa Rican government has extended several additional protections, work permits, and travel documentation to some segments of this population, a valuable humanitarian response to Venezuelans and Nicaraguans who cannot return to their country of origin given continued instability.</li>
<li>Prior to the COVID-19 pandemic, approximately 120,000 private American citizens, including many retirees, resided in the country; more than 1.4 million American citizens visited Costa Rica annually. Pre-pandemic, more than 1,100 Costa Ricans studied at U.S. institutions of higher education annually. More than 8,000 U.S. students study in Costa Rica every year, and Costa Rica is the number one destination in Latin America for U.S. study abroad programs.</li>
<li>Costa Rica is a valuable counter-narcotics partner. In 2020, Costa Rican security services seized more than 71 metric tons of drugs, including a record 18.6 metric tons found in commercial containers. U.S.-donated interceptor vessels, as well as equipment and training provided to the Costa Rican Coast Guard, along with joint operations, led to a record number of maritime seizures in 2020.</li>
<li>The United States has partnered with Costa Rica in an effort to bring the COVID-19 pandemic to a swift end. U.S. assistance of more than $4 million to Costa Rica includes personal protective equipment, medical supplies, hygiene supplies to support in-person education, and mobile hospitals.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken is traveling to San Jose on June 1-2, 2021, to a meeting of the Central American Integration System (SICA) convened by Costa Rican President Carlos Alvarado Quesada.  In Costa Rica, he will meet with President Alvarado and Foreign Minister Rodolfo Solano Quirós to discuss the strong U.S.-Costa Rica partnership and to advance collaboration on regional and global issues, including migration, counternarcotics, human rights, and climate change.</p>
<p><strong>A Relationship Based on Shared Values and Commitments</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Costa Rica, a strong democracy of more than five million people with deep ties to the United States, is important to key U.S. goals in the region and is committed to continued close cooperation with the United States. It has an open trade and investment climate, and recently became the 38th member of the OECD. It is also one of the strongest and most reliable voices in Latin America on human rights and rule of law, and has been a superb partner in the fight against transnational crime and drug trafficking.</li>
<li>The United States is Costa Rica’s top trading partner, accounting for around 40 percent of both imports and exports. The United States is also Costa Rica’s top source of foreign direct investment, reaching $1.92 billion in 2019 (70% of total FDI) .  There are currently more than 200 U.S. companies in Costa Rica that collectively employ more than 94,000 people, or nearly 84 percent of all jobs created by multinational companies in Costa Rica.</li>
<li>Costa Rica is a champion of human rights and democratic norms across the region, including through its active role in the Organization of American States (OAS). Costa Rica has condemned fraudulent parliamentary elections in Venezuela and supported the OAS resolution calling for electoral reform in Nicaragua. Additionally, Costa Rica hosts more than 450,000 Nicaraguans, including 110,000 people who fled Nicaragua after the 2018 political crisis, many of whom are currently seeking refugee status in Costa Rica. Costa Rica also hosts nearly 30,000 Venezuelan migrants and refugees. The Costa Rican government has extended several additional protections, work permits, and travel documentation to some segments of this population, a valuable humanitarian response to Venezuelans and Nicaraguans who cannot return to their country of origin given continued instability.</li>
<li>Prior to the COVID-19 pandemic, approximately 120,000 private American citizens, including many retirees, resided in the country; more than 1.4 million American citizens visited Costa Rica annually. Pre-pandemic, more than 1,100 Costa Ricans studied at U.S. institutions of higher education annually. More than 8,000 U.S. students study in Costa Rica every year, and Costa Rica is the number one destination in Latin America for U.S. study abroad programs.</li>
<li>Costa Rica is a valuable counter-narcotics partner. In 2020, Costa Rican security services seized more than 71 metric tons of drugs, including a record 18.6 metric tons found in commercial containers. U.S.-donated interceptor vessels, as well as equipment and training provided to the Costa Rican Coast Guard, along with joint operations, led to a record number of maritime seizures in 2020.</li>
<li>The United States has partnered with Costa Rica in an effort to bring the COVID-19 pandemic to a swift end. U.S. assistance of more than $4 million to Costa Rica includes personal protective equipment, medical supplies, hygiene supplies to support in-person education, and mobile hospitals.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman’s Visit to Cambodia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-of-state-wendy-shermans-visit-to-cambodia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 12:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman led a delegation to Phnom Penh on Tuesday, June 1.  In a meeting with Prime Minister Hun Sen, Deputy Secretary Sherman stressed the U.S. commitment to the Cambodian people and recalled the important role the United States and other partners played in brokering the 1991 Paris Peace Agreements, which ended decades of civil war.  She noted the more than $3 billion in assistance the United States has provided since then to support the country’s development and generous U.S. trade benefits that have fueled economic growth in the Kingdom.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman highlighted U.S. support for Cambodia during the pandemic, including $11 million to help address economic and health challenges along with expert advice from U.S. health agencies present in Cambodia.  She also noted productive cooperation with Cambodia on implementation of UN sanctions on the DPRK, child protection, UN peacekeeping, POW/MIA accounting, humanitarian demining, public health and education, and other shared interests.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman expressed serious concerns about the PRC’s military presence and construction of facilities at Ream Naval Base on the Gulf of Thailand.  She sought clarification on the demolition of two U.S.-funded buildings at Ream without notification or explanation and observed that a PRC military base in Cambodia would undermine its sovereignty, threaten regional security, and negatively impact U.S.-Cambodia relations.  The Deputy urged Cambodia’s leadership to maintain an independent and balanced foreign policy, in the best interests of the Cambodian people.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman emphasized the importance of human rights and the protection of fundamental freedoms as integral to our bilateral relationship.  She urged the Cambodian government to abide by its international and domestic human rights commitments and to ensure the protection of worker rights.  She called on authorities to promptly drop the politically motivated charges against members of the political opposition, journalists, and activists.  Deputy Secretary Sherman pressed the government to reopen civic and political space in advance of the 2022 commune and 2023 national elections.</p>
<p>While in Cambodia, Deputy Secretary Sherman also held meetings with representatives from civil society as well as leader of the Cambodia National Rescue Party Kem Sokha to discuss issues of shared importance with the United States, including ensuring a peaceful, prosperous, sovereign, and democratic future for Cambodia.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman assured the Prime Minister that the United States intends to work with Cambodia in its role as 2022 ASEAN Chair and help ensure it can play a constructive role in addressing critical regional political and security challenges, including in North Korea, the South China Sea, and the Mekong region.  She also called on Cambodia, as a member of ASEAN, to hold the Burmese military regime accountable to ASEAN’s Five-Point Consensus that seeks to address the ongoing crisis in Burma.  The Deputy expressed appreciation for Cambodia’s work as 2021 co-chair of the Mekong-U.S. Partnership.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman led a delegation to Phnom Penh on Tuesday, June 1.  In a meeting with Prime Minister Hun Sen, Deputy Secretary Sherman stressed the U.S. commitment to the Cambodian people and recalled the important role the United States and other partners played in brokering the 1991 Paris Peace Agreements, which ended decades of civil war.  She noted the more than $3 billion in assistance the United States has provided since then to support the country’s development and generous U.S. trade benefits that have fueled economic growth in the Kingdom.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman highlighted U.S. support for Cambodia during the pandemic, including $11 million to help address economic and health challenges along with expert advice from U.S. health agencies present in Cambodia.  She also noted productive cooperation with Cambodia on implementation of UN sanctions on the DPRK, child protection, UN peacekeeping, POW/MIA accounting, humanitarian demining, public health and education, and other shared interests.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman expressed serious concerns about the PRC’s military presence and construction of facilities at Ream Naval Base on the Gulf of Thailand.  She sought clarification on the demolition of two U.S.-funded buildings at Ream without notification or explanation and observed that a PRC military base in Cambodia would undermine its sovereignty, threaten regional security, and negatively impact U.S.-Cambodia relations.  The Deputy urged Cambodia’s leadership to maintain an independent and balanced foreign policy, in the best interests of the Cambodian people.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman emphasized the importance of human rights and the protection of fundamental freedoms as integral to our bilateral relationship.  She urged the Cambodian government to abide by its international and domestic human rights commitments and to ensure the protection of worker rights.  She called on authorities to promptly drop the politically motivated charges against members of the political opposition, journalists, and activists.  Deputy Secretary Sherman pressed the government to reopen civic and political space in advance of the 2022 commune and 2023 national elections.</p>
<p>While in Cambodia, Deputy Secretary Sherman also held meetings with representatives from civil society as well as leader of the Cambodia National Rescue Party Kem Sokha to discuss issues of shared importance with the United States, including ensuring a peaceful, prosperous, sovereign, and democratic future for Cambodia.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman assured the Prime Minister that the United States intends to work with Cambodia in its role as 2022 ASEAN Chair and help ensure it can play a constructive role in addressing critical regional political and security challenges, including in North Korea, the South China Sea, and the Mekong region.  She also called on Cambodia, as a member of ASEAN, to hold the Burmese military regime accountable to ASEAN’s Five-Point Consensus that seeks to address the ongoing crisis in Burma.  The Deputy expressed appreciation for Cambodia’s work as 2021 co-chair of the Mekong-U.S. Partnership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Pride Month</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/on-pride-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 12:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247758</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>During this year’s Pride Month, we celebrate an important message: “You are Included.” The diverse experiences, perspectives, and contributions of the State Department community make our institution stronger and advance the goals of American diplomacy. Out of many, we are one.</p>
<p>The Department has committed to increasing U.S. engagement on lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex (LGBTQI+) human rights issues abroad. As we do so, we work with partners around the world who bring to bear expertise on their unique challenges and innovative solutions. We recognize that, through these partnerships, we will be able to build a safer, more inclusive global society for all LGBTQI+ persons. We also strive to increase visibility of and address the acute challenges faced by particularly marginalized LGBTQI+ communities, including women and girls; racial and religious minorities; persons with disabilities; and transgender, gender diverse, and intersex persons.</p>
<p>As we celebrate Pride Month this June, let us not only observe how far we have come in the struggle for the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons, but also acknowledge the challenges that remain. LGBTQI+ persons around the world continue to face discrimination, violence, and other forms of persecution because of who they are and whom they love. Although we still have work to do, the Department is proud to lead by the power of example, including the example set by the LGBTQI+ members of our workforce, in the promotion of human rights for all persons.</p>
<p>We are proudly diverse in identity but unified in our shared commitment to the freedom and dignity of all.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>During this year’s Pride Month, we celebrate an important message: “You are Included.” The diverse experiences, perspectives, and contributions of the State Department community make our institution stronger and advance the goals of American diplomacy. Out of many, we are one.</p>
<p>The Department has committed to increasing U.S. engagement on lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex (LGBTQI+) human rights issues abroad. As we do so, we work with partners around the world who bring to bear expertise on their unique challenges and innovative solutions. We recognize that, through these partnerships, we will be able to build a safer, more inclusive global society for all LGBTQI+ persons. We also strive to increase visibility of and address the acute challenges faced by particularly marginalized LGBTQI+ communities, including women and girls; racial and religious minorities; persons with disabilities; and transgender, gender diverse, and intersex persons.</p>
<p>As we celebrate Pride Month this June, let us not only observe how far we have come in the struggle for the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons, but also acknowledge the challenges that remain. LGBTQI+ persons around the world continue to face discrimination, violence, and other forms of persecution because of who they are and whom they love. Although we still have work to do, the Department is proud to lead by the power of example, including the example set by the LGBTQI+ members of our workforce, in the promotion of human rights for all persons.</p>
<p>We are proudly diverse in identity but unified in our shared commitment to the freedom and dignity of all.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Croatia Statehood Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/croatia-statehood-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 04:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=247361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Croatia as you celebrate your Statehood Day.</p>
<p>The United States and Croatia are steadfast Allies and partners, and our relationship is defined by shared values that help us progress on critical fronts, including strengthening trade and investment ties, enhancing energy security, and confronting the climate crisis.</p>
<p>This year, we also commemorate the 30th anniversary of the Croatian Armed Forces, and the United States offers its thanks for the decades of close military cooperation our two countries have enjoyed.  Our thriving defense partnership is evidenced by our continued participation in joint and NATO training exercises, which are again in the spotlight during Defender Europe 2021.  A valued NATO Ally, Croatia is an important contributor to both Transatlantic security and European prosperity.</p>
<p>As we continue to face the challenges posed by the COVID-19 pandemic and deepen our bilateral relationship, the United States stands with Croatia.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the Government of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Croatia as you celebrate your Statehood Day.</p>
<p>The United States and Croatia are steadfast Allies and partners, and our relationship is defined by shared values that help us progress on critical fronts, including strengthening trade and investment ties, enhancing energy security, and confronting the climate crisis.</p>
<p>This year, we also commemorate the 30th anniversary of the Croatian Armed Forces, and the United States offers its thanks for the decades of close military cooperation our two countries have enjoyed.  Our thriving defense partnership is evidenced by our continued participation in joint and NATO training exercises, which are again in the spotlight during Defender Europe 2021.  A valued NATO Ally, Croatia is an important contributor to both Transatlantic security and European prosperity.</p>
<p>As we continue to face the challenges posed by the COVID-19 pandemic and deepen our bilateral relationship, the United States stands with Croatia.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
