<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 22:15:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>G7 Foreign Ministers’ Statement on the Launch of an Intercontinental Ballistic Missile by the DPRK</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/g7-foreign-ministers-statement-on-the-launch-of-an-intercontinental-ballistic-missile-by-the-dprk/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 22:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=348242</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p>We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union, condemn in the strongest terms the test of yet another Intercontinental Ballistic Missile (ICBM) conducted on May 25, 2022, by the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK).  Like a number of ballistic missile launches the DPRK has conducted since the beginning of 2022, this act constitutes a further blatant violation of relevant UN Security Council resolutions and undermines international peace and security as well as the global non-proliferation regime.</p>
<p>We are very concerned by the unprecedented series of ballistic missile tests with increasingly versatile systems across all ranges, building on ballistic missile tests conducted in 2021.  Together with the evidence of ongoing nuclear activities, these acts underscore the DPRK’s determination to advance and diversify its nuclear capabilities.  These reckless actions flagrantly breach the DPRK’s obligations under relevant UN Security Council resolutions, which the Security Council most recently reaffirmed in resolution 2397 (2017).  They also pose a danger and unpredictable risk to international civil aviation and maritime navigation in the region.</p>
<p>We, the G7 Foreign Ministers and the High Representative of the European Union, reiterate our urgent call on the DPRK to abandon its weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs in a complete, verifiable and irreversible manner and to fully comply with all legal obligations arising from the relevant Security Council resolutions.</p>
<p>We deeply regret that the Security Council has failed to adopt the draft resolution aimed at condemning the series of recent ballistic missile launches by the DPRK and strengthening measures against it despite support from 13 members.  We urge all UN Member States, especially Security Council members, to join us in condemning the DPRK´s behavior and reaffirm its obligation to abandon its weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs.  These acts demand a united response by the international community, including a united stance and further significant measures by the UN Security Council.</p>
<p>We reiterate our call on the DPRK to engage in diplomacy toward denuclearization and accept the repeated offers of dialogue put forward by the United States, the Republic of Korea and Japan.  By diverting its resources into weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs the DPRK further aggravates the already dire humanitarian situation in the DPRK.  We urge the DPRK to facilitate access for international humanitarian organizations and for independent assessment of humanitarian needs such as food and medicines as soon as possible.</p>
<p>We also call on all States to fully and effectively implement all relevant Security Council resolutions, and to address the risk of weapons of mass destruction proliferation from the DPRK as an urgent priority.</p>
<p>The G7 remain committed to working with all relevant partners towards the goal of peace and stability on the Korean Peninsula and to upholding the rules-based international order.</p>
<p><i>End Text</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The text of the following statement was released by the G7 foreign ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union.</p>
<p>We, the G7 Foreign Ministers of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America, and the High Representative of the European Union, condemn in the strongest terms the test of yet another Intercontinental Ballistic Missile (ICBM) conducted on May 25, 2022, by the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK).  Like a number of ballistic missile launches the DPRK has conducted since the beginning of 2022, this act constitutes a further blatant violation of relevant UN Security Council resolutions and undermines international peace and security as well as the global non-proliferation regime.</p>
<p>We are very concerned by the unprecedented series of ballistic missile tests with increasingly versatile systems across all ranges, building on ballistic missile tests conducted in 2021.  Together with the evidence of ongoing nuclear activities, these acts underscore the DPRK’s determination to advance and diversify its nuclear capabilities.  These reckless actions flagrantly breach the DPRK’s obligations under relevant UN Security Council resolutions, which the Security Council most recently reaffirmed in resolution 2397 (2017).  They also pose a danger and unpredictable risk to international civil aviation and maritime navigation in the region.</p>
<p>We, the G7 Foreign Ministers and the High Representative of the European Union, reiterate our urgent call on the DPRK to abandon its weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs in a complete, verifiable and irreversible manner and to fully comply with all legal obligations arising from the relevant Security Council resolutions.</p>
<p>We deeply regret that the Security Council has failed to adopt the draft resolution aimed at condemning the series of recent ballistic missile launches by the DPRK and strengthening measures against it despite support from 13 members.  We urge all UN Member States, especially Security Council members, to join us in condemning the DPRK´s behavior and reaffirm its obligation to abandon its weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs.  These acts demand a united response by the international community, including a united stance and further significant measures by the UN Security Council.</p>
<p>We reiterate our call on the DPRK to engage in diplomacy toward denuclearization and accept the repeated offers of dialogue put forward by the United States, the Republic of Korea and Japan.  By diverting its resources into weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs the DPRK further aggravates the already dire humanitarian situation in the DPRK.  We urge the DPRK to facilitate access for international humanitarian organizations and for independent assessment of humanitarian needs such as food and medicines as soon as possible.</p>
<p>We also call on all States to fully and effectively implement all relevant Security Council resolutions, and to address the risk of weapons of mass destruction proliferation from the DPRK as an urgent priority.</p>
<p>The G7 remain committed to working with all relevant partners towards the goal of peace and stability on the Korean Peninsula and to upholding the rules-based international order.</p>
<p><i>End Text</i></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Greek Foreign Minister Dendias</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-greek-foreign-minister-dendias-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 18:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=348238</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Greek Foreign Minister Nikos Dendias to condemn in the strongest terms the May 27 seizure of two Greek-flagged vessels by Iran’s Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps.  Iran’s continued harassment of vessels and interference with navigational rights and freedoms are a threat to maritime security and the global economy.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister agreed that Iran must immediately release the seized vessels, their cargoes, and their crews.</p>
<p>The United States stands with Greece, our key NATO Ally and partner in the face of this unjustified seizure.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Greek Foreign Minister Nikos Dendias to condemn in the strongest terms the May 27 seizure of two Greek-flagged vessels by Iran’s Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps.  Iran’s continued harassment of vessels and interference with navigational rights and freedoms are a threat to maritime security and the global economy.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister agreed that Iran must immediately release the seized vessels, their cargoes, and their crews.</p>
<p>The United States stands with Greece, our key NATO Ally and partner in the face of this unjustified seizure.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Stern’s Travel to Lithuania, the Netherlands, and Sweden</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-special-envoy-to-advance-the-human-rights-of-lgbtqi-persons-sterns-travel-to-lithuania-the-netherlands-and-sweden/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 16:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=348231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Special Envoy Jessica Stern will travel to Lithuania, the Netherlands, and Sweden, May 31-June 8.  During her visits, Special Envoy Stern will engage with local human rights defenders and civil society representatives regarding the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons globally, with a specific focus on LGBTQI+ refugees from Ukraine.</p>
<p>In the Netherlands and Sweden, Special Envoy Stern will meet with government and civil society counterparts to discuss advancing the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons via multilateral institutions and public-private partnerships such as the Global Equality Fund.</p>
<p>In Lithuania, among her engagements, the Special Envoy will participate in Baltic Pride’s Proud Cities Summit, where she will speak in the first session panel discussion on “Equality, Diversity, Inclusion: Transforming Challenges into Opportunities” and engage with youth at an informal Q&amp;A session.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:DRL-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DRL-Press@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>U.S. Special Envoy Jessica Stern will travel to Lithuania, the Netherlands, and Sweden, May 31-June 8.  During her visits, Special Envoy Stern will engage with local human rights defenders and civil society representatives regarding the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons globally, with a specific focus on LGBTQI+ refugees from Ukraine.</p>
<p>In the Netherlands and Sweden, Special Envoy Stern will meet with government and civil society counterparts to discuss advancing the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons via multilateral institutions and public-private partnerships such as the Global Equality Fund.</p>
<p>In Lithuania, among her engagements, the Special Envoy will participate in Baltic Pride’s Proud Cities Summit, where she will speak in the first session panel discussion on “Equality, Diversity, Inclusion: Transforming Challenges into Opportunities” and engage with youth at an informal Q&amp;A session.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:DRL-Press@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DRL-Press@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Croatia Statehood Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/croatia-statehood-day-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 04:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=348201</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Croatia as you celebrate your Statehood Day.</p>
<p>As highlighted during our Strategic Dialogue held in March, the United States looks forward to further deepening our people-to-people connections, strengthening trade and investment ties, enhancing energy security, confronting the climate crisis, and working together to address regional and global challenges, including Putin’s unprovoked, unjust, and premeditated war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>At the dawn of our diplomatic relationship 30 years ago, we were proud to stand with Croatia.  We are proud to stand with Croatia today as NATO Allies, Transatlantic partners, and as two peoples tied strongly to one another by shared values and unbreakable bonds of friendship.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Croatia as you celebrate your Statehood Day.</p>
<p>As highlighted during our Strategic Dialogue held in March, the United States looks forward to further deepening our people-to-people connections, strengthening trade and investment ties, enhancing energy security, confronting the climate crisis, and working together to address regional and global challenges, including Putin’s unprovoked, unjust, and premeditated war against Ukraine.</p>
<p>At the dawn of our diplomatic relationship 30 years ago, we were proud to stand with Croatia.  We are proud to stand with Croatia today as NATO Allies, Transatlantic partners, and as two peoples tied strongly to one another by shared values and unbreakable bonds of friendship.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Concerns with UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Visit to the People’s Republic of China</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/concerns-with-un-high-commissioner-for-human-rights-visit-to-the-peoples-republic-of-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 01:19:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=348182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p align="left">The United States remains concerned about the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Michelle Bachelet and her team’s visit to the People’s Republic of China (PRC) and PRC efforts to restrict and manipulate her visit. While we continue to raise our concerns about China’s human rights abuses directly with Beijing and support others who do so, we are concerned the conditions Beijing authorities imposed on the visit did not enable a complete and independent assessment of the human rights environment in the PRC, including in Xinjiang, where genocide and crimes against humanity are ongoing.</p>
<p align="left">We are further troubled by reports that residents of Xinjiang were warned not to complain or speak openly about conditions in the region, that no insight was provided into the whereabouts of hundreds of missing Uyghurs and conditions for over a million individuals in detention.  The High Commissioner should have been allowed confidential meetings with family members of Uyghur and other ethnic minority diaspora communities in Xinjiang who are not in detention facilities but are forbidden from traveling out of the region.  We also note that the High Commissioner was not allowed access to individuals who were part of the Xinjiang labor transfer program and have been sent to other provinces across China.</p>
<p align="left">The United States remains deeply concerned about the human rights situation in the PRC, particularly in light of new reports that offer further proof of arbitrary detentions among the more than one million people detained in Xinjiang.  Survivors and family members of detainees have described cruel treatment that shocks the conscience, including torture, forced sterilization, state-sponsored forced labor, sexual violence, and forced separation of children from their parents. We also urge the PRC to respect the human rights of Tibetans, those living in Hong Kong, and all others who seek to peacefully exercise their human rights and fundamental freedoms as enshrined in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights. We again call on the PRC to immediately cease its atrocities in Xinjiang release those unjustly detained, account for those disappeared, and allow independent investigators unhindered access to Xinjiang, Tibet, and across China.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p align="left">The United States remains concerned about the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Michelle Bachelet and her team’s visit to the People’s Republic of China (PRC) and PRC efforts to restrict and manipulate her visit. While we continue to raise our concerns about China’s human rights abuses directly with Beijing and support others who do so, we are concerned the conditions Beijing authorities imposed on the visit did not enable a complete and independent assessment of the human rights environment in the PRC, including in Xinjiang, where genocide and crimes against humanity are ongoing.</p>
<p align="left">We are further troubled by reports that residents of Xinjiang were warned not to complain or speak openly about conditions in the region, that no insight was provided into the whereabouts of hundreds of missing Uyghurs and conditions for over a million individuals in detention.  The High Commissioner should have been allowed confidential meetings with family members of Uyghur and other ethnic minority diaspora communities in Xinjiang who are not in detention facilities but are forbidden from traveling out of the region.  We also note that the High Commissioner was not allowed access to individuals who were part of the Xinjiang labor transfer program and have been sent to other provinces across China.</p>
<p align="left">The United States remains deeply concerned about the human rights situation in the PRC, particularly in light of new reports that offer further proof of arbitrary detentions among the more than one million people detained in Xinjiang.  Survivors and family members of detainees have described cruel treatment that shocks the conscience, including torture, forced sterilization, state-sponsored forced labor, sexual violence, and forced separation of children from their parents. We also urge the PRC to respect the human rights of Tibetans, those living in Hong Kong, and all others who seek to peacefully exercise their human rights and fundamental freedoms as enshrined in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights. We again call on the PRC to immediately cease its atrocities in Xinjiang release those unjustly detained, account for those disappeared, and allow independent investigators unhindered access to Xinjiang, Tibet, and across China.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Egyptian Foreign Minister Shoukry</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-egyptian-foreign-minister-shoukry-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 22:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=348179</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Egyptian Foreign Minister Sameh Shoukry today regarding the situation in Yemen and the importance of flights between Sana’a and Cairo.  The Secretary thanked the Government of Egypt for approving these flights and expressed his hope that the first flight will occur in the coming days to allow Yemenis to seek medical care and join loved ones from across the diverse Yemeni diaspora community in Egypt.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister Shoukry also discussed strengthening the bilateral relationship, and cooperation on regional issues as well as the severe impact of Russia’s war against Ukraine on global food security.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Egyptian Foreign Minister Sameh Shoukry today regarding the situation in Yemen and the importance of flights between Sana’a and Cairo.  The Secretary thanked the Government of Egypt for approving these flights and expressed his hope that the first flight will occur in the coming days to allow Yemenis to seek medical care and join loved ones from across the diverse Yemeni diaspora community in Egypt.  The Secretary and Foreign Minister Shoukry also discussed strengthening the bilateral relationship, and cooperation on regional issues as well as the severe impact of Russia’s war against Ukraine on global food security.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Azerbaijan’s National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/azerbaijans-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 13:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=348166</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I wish the people of Azerbaijan a happy Independence Day.</p>
<p>This year, we are celebrating the 30th anniversary of diplomatic relations between the United States and Azerbaijan.  In the three decades since Azerbaijan’s independence from the Soviet Union, we have become strong partners in promoting European energy security, combatting transnational threats, and advancing bilateral trade and investment.  We deeply value Azerbaijan’s contributions to the global fight against terrorism and illicit trade networks, as well as your support for Ukraine, particularly your humanitarian assistance.</p>
<p>The United States is proud to continue to expand our relationship not only through strong economic linkages, but also through our people-to-people ties.  Thousands of Azerbaijani and American citizens have worked and studied together and had the opportunity to innovate, collaborate, and learn from each other.  We look forward to seeing thousands more follow in the years ahead.  We also urge steps toward democratic development, with reforms that protect the human rights and fundamental freedoms provided in Azerbaijan’s constitution.  We are committed to promoting a peaceful, democratic, and prosperous future for Azerbaijan and the South Caucasus region, and we stand ready to help by engaging bilaterally and with like-minded partners, including to help the region find a long-term comprehensive peace.</p>
<p>During this challenging period of global uncertainty, the United States once more reaffirms its commitment to supporting Azerbaijan’s independence and sovereignty, as well as the rights and freedoms of the Azerbaijani people.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>On behalf of the United States of America, I wish the people of Azerbaijan a happy Independence Day.</p>
<p>This year, we are celebrating the 30th anniversary of diplomatic relations between the United States and Azerbaijan.  In the three decades since Azerbaijan’s independence from the Soviet Union, we have become strong partners in promoting European energy security, combatting transnational threats, and advancing bilateral trade and investment.  We deeply value Azerbaijan’s contributions to the global fight against terrorism and illicit trade networks, as well as your support for Ukraine, particularly your humanitarian assistance.</p>
<p>The United States is proud to continue to expand our relationship not only through strong economic linkages, but also through our people-to-people ties.  Thousands of Azerbaijani and American citizens have worked and studied together and had the opportunity to innovate, collaborate, and learn from each other.  We look forward to seeing thousands more follow in the years ahead.  We also urge steps toward democratic development, with reforms that protect the human rights and fundamental freedoms provided in Azerbaijan’s constitution.  We are committed to promoting a peaceful, democratic, and prosperous future for Azerbaijan and the South Caucasus region, and we stand ready to help by engaging bilaterally and with like-minded partners, including to help the region find a long-term comprehensive peace.</p>
<p>During this challenging period of global uncertainty, the United States once more reaffirms its commitment to supporting Azerbaijan’s independence and sovereignty, as well as the rights and freedoms of the Azerbaijani people.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement by Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken, Japanese Minister for Foreign Affairs Hayashi Yoshimasa, and Republic of Korea Minister of Foreign Affairs Park Jin</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-by-secretary-of-state-antony-j-blinken-japanese-minister-for-foreign-affairs-hayashi-yoshimasa-and-republic-of-korea-minister-of-foreign-affairs-park-jin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 01:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=348143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The United States, the Republic of Korea (ROK), and Japan strongly condemn recent Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK) ballistic missile launches, commit to strengthen trilateral cooperation towards the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and full implementation of relevant United Nations Security Council (UNSC) resolutions, and underscore continued openness to meeting with the DPRK without preconditions.</p>
<p align="left">The United States, the ROK, and Japan express deep concern about the May 25 DPRK launches of an intercontinental ballistic missile and shorter-range ballistic missiles. The DPRK has significantly increased the pace and scale of its ballistic missile launches since September 2021. Each of these launches violated multiple UNSC resolutions and posed a grave threat to the region and the international community. We urge the DPRK to abide by its obligations under UNSC resolutions and immediately cease actions that violate international law, escalate tensions, destabilize the region, and endanger the peace and security of all nations.</p>
<p align="left">In response to the DPRK’s unlawful and destabilizing actions, our nations executed coordinated U.S.-ROK and U.S.-Japan exercises, demonstrating our shared, unequivocal commitment to regional security and stability. These launches highlight the importance of further strengthening the U.S.-ROK and U.S.-Japan alliances to ensure peace, security, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region. Our nations are also committed to advance trilateral security cooperation. The United States reaffirms its steadfast commitments to the defense of the Republic of Korea and Japan, including extended deterrence.</p>
<p align="left">In spite of 13 Security Council members’ support, we deeply regret that the UNSC failed to adopt a resolution in response to the DPRK’s blatant and repeated violations of UNSC resolutions. We reaffirm our commitment to further strengthen our coordination with the international community to urge the DPRK to cease its unlawful activities and instead engage in dialogue.</p>
<p align="left">We stress that a path to serious and sustained dialogue remains open and urge the DPRK to return to negotiations.</p>
<p align="left">We express our deep concern at the grave hardship the people in the DPRK are experiencing, including due to the ongoing outbreak of COVID-19, and hope the DPRK will respond positively to international offers of assistance.</p>
<p align="left">We also reaffirm the importance of achieving a swift resolution of the abductions issue.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The United States, the Republic of Korea (ROK), and Japan strongly condemn recent Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK) ballistic missile launches, commit to strengthen trilateral cooperation towards the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and full implementation of relevant United Nations Security Council (UNSC) resolutions, and underscore continued openness to meeting with the DPRK without preconditions.</p>
<p align="left">The United States, the ROK, and Japan express deep concern about the May 25 DPRK launches of an intercontinental ballistic missile and shorter-range ballistic missiles. The DPRK has significantly increased the pace and scale of its ballistic missile launches since September 2021. Each of these launches violated multiple UNSC resolutions and posed a grave threat to the region and the international community. We urge the DPRK to abide by its obligations under UNSC resolutions and immediately cease actions that violate international law, escalate tensions, destabilize the region, and endanger the peace and security of all nations.</p>
<p align="left">In response to the DPRK’s unlawful and destabilizing actions, our nations executed coordinated U.S.-ROK and U.S.-Japan exercises, demonstrating our shared, unequivocal commitment to regional security and stability. These launches highlight the importance of further strengthening the U.S.-ROK and U.S.-Japan alliances to ensure peace, security, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region. Our nations are also committed to advance trilateral security cooperation. The United States reaffirms its steadfast commitments to the defense of the Republic of Korea and Japan, including extended deterrence.</p>
<p align="left">In spite of 13 Security Council members’ support, we deeply regret that the UNSC failed to adopt a resolution in response to the DPRK’s blatant and repeated violations of UNSC resolutions. We reaffirm our commitment to further strengthen our coordination with the international community to urge the DPRK to cease its unlawful activities and instead engage in dialogue.</p>
<p align="left">We stress that a path to serious and sustained dialogue remains open and urge the DPRK to return to negotiations.</p>
<p align="left">We express our deep concern at the grave hardship the people in the DPRK are experiencing, including due to the ongoing outbreak of COVID-19, and hope the DPRK will respond positively to international offers of assistance.</p>
<p align="left">We also reaffirm the importance of achieving a swift resolution of the abductions issue.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States Targets the DPRK’s Ballistic Missile and Weapons of Mass Destruction Programs</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-targets-the-dprks-ballistic-missile-and-weapons-of-mass-destruction-programs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 21:46:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=348112</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p align="left"><span>The Democratic People’s Republic of Korea’s (DPRK’s) series of escalatory ballistic missile launches – including six intercontinental ballistic missile tests this year alone – are in blatant violation of UN Security Council resolutions and pose a grave threat to regional stability and international peace and security.</span></p>
<p align="left"><span></span><span></span><span>Today, the United States is designating for sanctions </span><span>Air Koryo Trading Corporation, </span><span>a DPRK entity that has provided or attempted to provide support to the </span><span>U.S.-designated DPRK Ministry of Rocket Industry; Jong Yong Nam, a DPRK representative for an organization subordinate to the UN- and U.S.-designated Second Academy of Natural Sciences; and Bank Sputnik, a Russian bank that has assisted the UN- and U.S.-designated Foreign Trade Bank, pursuant to Executive Order 13382, which targets proliferators of weapons of mass destruction and their means of delivery.  The United States is also sanctioning Far Eastern Bank, a Russian bank, pursuant to E.O. 13722, which targets the DPRK government and certain activities in the DPRK.</span></p>
<p align="left"><span></span><span>We are taking these actions in response to the DPRK’s ongoing development of its weapons of mass destruction (WMD) and ballistic missile programs in violation of multiple United Nations Security Council resolutions. </span><span> As a result of today’s sanctions, any property or interests in property of the designated persons in the possession or control of U.S. persons or entities or within the United States must be blocked, and U.S. persons are prohibited from dealing with any of the designated parties.</span></p>
<p align="left"><span></span><span>We continue to coordinate closely with our allies and partners to address the threats posed by the DPRK’s destabilizing activities and to advance our shared objective of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  We remain committed to diplomacy with the DPRK and call on the DPRK to engage in dialogue.  At the same time, we continue to urge all UN Member States to fully implement the UN Security Council resolutions addressing the DPRK in order to constrain its ability to advance its unlawful WMD and ballistic missile programs.</span></p>
<p align="left"><span>For more information on today’s action, see the Department of the </span><a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0801" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect"><span>Treasury’s press release</span></a><span>.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p align="left"><span>The Democratic People’s Republic of Korea’s (DPRK’s) series of escalatory ballistic missile launches – including six intercontinental ballistic missile tests this year alone – are in blatant violation of UN Security Council resolutions and pose a grave threat to regional stability and international peace and security.</span></p>
<p align="left"><span></span><span></span><span>Today, the United States is designating for sanctions </span><span>Air Koryo Trading Corporation, </span><span>a DPRK entity that has provided or attempted to provide support to the </span><span>U.S.-designated DPRK Ministry of Rocket Industry; Jong Yong Nam, a DPRK representative for an organization subordinate to the UN- and U.S.-designated Second Academy of Natural Sciences; and Bank Sputnik, a Russian bank that has assisted the UN- and U.S.-designated Foreign Trade Bank, pursuant to Executive Order 13382, which targets proliferators of weapons of mass destruction and their means of delivery.  The United States is also sanctioning Far Eastern Bank, a Russian bank, pursuant to E.O. 13722, which targets the DPRK government and certain activities in the DPRK.</span></p>
<p align="left"><span></span><span>We are taking these actions in response to the DPRK’s ongoing development of its weapons of mass destruction (WMD) and ballistic missile programs in violation of multiple United Nations Security Council resolutions. </span><span> As a result of today’s sanctions, any property or interests in property of the designated persons in the possession or control of U.S. persons or entities or within the United States must be blocked, and U.S. persons are prohibited from dealing with any of the designated parties.</span></p>
<p align="left"><span></span><span>We continue to coordinate closely with our allies and partners to address the threats posed by the DPRK’s destabilizing activities and to advance our shared objective of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  We remain committed to diplomacy with the DPRK and call on the DPRK to engage in dialogue.  At the same time, we continue to urge all UN Member States to fully implement the UN Security Council resolutions addressing the DPRK in order to constrain its ability to advance its unlawful WMD and ballistic missile programs.</span></p>
<p align="left"><span>For more information on today’s action, see the Department of the </span><a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0801" target="_blank" rel="noopener" shape="rect"><span>Treasury’s press release</span></a><span>.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Finnish Foreign Minister Pekka Haavisto At a Joint Press Availability</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-finnish-foreign-minister-pekka-haavisto-at-a-joint-press-availability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 20:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=348017</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s wonderful to be able to host my colleague and friend, the Foreign Minister of Finland, here at the State Department in the Benjamin Franklin Room.  Our partnership, the partnership between Finland and the United States, has been rooted deeply in our shared values of democracy, of human rights, rule of law and a shared commitment to strengthening the international rules-based order.  We’re collaborating on virtually every pressing challenge of our time.  As a result, there’s always a lot to discuss when we get together, and we probably could have spent another hour talking about the many things that we’re working on.</p>
<p>But today, of course, we focused a great deal on Finland’s recent application to join NATO.  The United States fully supports Finland and Sweden joining the Alliance, and I continue to be confident that both countries will soon be NATO Allies.  Finland and Sweden more than meet NATO’s democratic, military, economic criteria for membership.  They’re committed to upholding NATO’s sacred Article 5 guarantee: an attack on one is an attack on all.  And both countries have a proven track record of honoring their commitments.</p>
<p>Since 2014, Finland has been an enhanced opportunities partner of NATO and maintains a high degree of interoperability with the Alliance.  In plain English that means that our militaries work together seamlessly, and the country brings specific military expertise and capabilities in the high north and the Baltic Sea.</p>
<p>But it’s not just Finland’s military capabilities that will make NATO stronger, but its free and open democratic society.  Indeed, we see that in the way that Finland decided to apply for NATO in the first place.  The move was driven by strong public support.  According to recent polls, three-in-four Finns want their country to join the Alliance.  Finnish people, press, and politicians debated the prospect openly.  And when the country’s democratically elected parliament put the issue to a vote, 188 out of 200 members supported applying for membership.  That is what a democratic process looks like.</p>
<p>The decisions by Finland and Sweden continue the trend that we’ve seen since President Putin launched his war of aggression in which he failed to achieve a single one of his strategic aims.  Instead of ending Ukraine’s independence, President Putin has strengthened it.  Instead of asserting Russia’s strength, he’s undermined it.  Instead of dividing NATO, he’s united it and now pushed more countries to apply to join.</p>
<p>Finland and Sweden’s applications also reaffirm NATO’s “Open Door” policy which has been a cornerstone of the Alliance since its very founding.  That door will stay open, reflecting our belief that every country should have the right to choose its allies and partners and to pursue membership if it chooses.  That is not a provocation or a threat to Russia.  We say this often, but it bears repeating: NATO is and always will be a defensive Alliance.  NATO does not seek confrontation with Russia, but rather we aim to prevent it.</p>
<p>The reason that more countries want to join NATO is simple:  They have seen the Russian Federation repeatedly attack its neighbors without provocation.  And so not unreasonably, they’re concerned that they could be next.  The only countries that have anything to fear from NATO are those that plan to attack one of the Allies.  As President Biden made clear last week in his meeting with the Finnish president, during the accession process the United States and our Finnish partners will remain vigilant against threats to our shared security, and we will work together to deter and confront any aggression.  The same holds true for Sweden.</p>
<p>The United States will also maintain our robust exercise activity and presence in the Baltic Sea region.</p>
<p>So simply put, Finland can depend on us, and I’m confident that we can depend on Finland.  The trust is built on experience.  We’ve collaborated for decades on the Arctic Council working together to advance a peaceful region where cooperation prevails on climate, on the environment, on science and safety, and where sustainable economic development benefits the local population.</p>
<p>For years, Finnish troops have served shoulder to shoulder with U.S. and NATO forces in Kosovo, in Afghanistan, in Iraq.  Together, we cofounded the European Center for Excellence for countering hybrid threats, which Finland hosts.  And since February 24, we’ve been closely aligned in our response to Moscow’s war of aggression against Ukraine.  We’ve repeatedly voted together to condemn Russia’s unjust invasion in the UN General Assembly and, of course, in the Human Rights Council, where we voted together to suspend Russia.  We’ve worked together to impose costs on the Russian Government and its proxies for this unjust war and the atrocities they are committing.</p>
<p>As a member of the European Union, Finland has helped craft and support EU sanctions which were closely coordinated with and complementary to our own.  Earlier this week, Finland joined more than 60 countries that have signed on to a roadmap to tackle the growing global food security crisis, which has been significantly worsened by Russia’s aggression in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Pekka and I talked about this at some length in our conversations both with regard to Ukraine and more generally what we can do and what we will do together to address this crisis around the globe.</p>
<p>Finland has also stepped up to provide security assistance and non-lethal aid to the Ukrainian Government.  The Government is committed to take in some 23,000 refugees, and Finnish universities have opened thousands of spots for Ukrainian students fleeing the war.  Finnish schools have opened thousands of chairs to younger Ukrainians, and we’re grateful for that incredible response.</p>
<p>One final point.  Squarely focused as we are today on how NATO can defend members against further Russian aggression, this alliance is also critical for protecting our shared security and values from other threats, including emerging challenges like cyber-attacks, infectious disease, a warming climate.  That’s yet another reason that we look forward to being able to call Finland and Sweden our allies and draw upon their leadership in the years ahead.</p>
<p>So Pekka, we’re already working so closely together, but I suspect that will become even closer with you as we deepen what is already a vital partnership between Finland and the United States.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER HAAVISTO:  </b>Thank you.  And first I want to thank Secretary of State Mr. Blinken, my good friend Tony, for this opportunity of to again meet here in Washington and discuss and exchange views in today’s meeting.  I think we had an excellent discussion.</p>
<p>We highly value our close cooperation between Finland and the United States.  As discussed today, we look forward to further deepening our bilateral engagement and continuing our close consultations on key foreign and security policy questions.</p>
<p>The main topics today were the security situation in Europe, Finland’s NATO membership application, and the war in Ukraine.  First a couple of words about our application.  Finland submitted on May 18<sup>th</sup>, at the same time with Sweden, our application for NATO membership.  Finland’s decision to apply for NATO membership is based on a comprehensive, democratic process and strong support from the people.  Finland’s accession to NATO would strengthen the security and stability of Northern Europe as well as wider transatlantic security.  Finland is a security provider and would further strengthen NATO as an Ally.  We are very grateful for the unwavering and strong support from the United States for our NATO membership bid.  We look forward to taking our excellent relationship to a new level as a NATO Ally.</p>
<p>Turkey has raised questions in conjunction with Finland’s and Sweden’s membership applications.  It is understandable that different issues may be raised by different allies along the process.  Finland has been in active contact with Turkey – I have been visiting Turkey twice this spring – at different levels regarding our NATO membership bid.  We wish to continue our constructive dialogue with allies and are ready to continue discussing the outstanding issues with Turkey.  We take every NATO members’ concerns seriously.  With Turkey we are now in an open, direct, and constructive dialogue process to clarify all issues.  This is important.</p>
<p>We highly appreciate the strong support from the allies along the process.  We also hope for a swift ratification of our membership once the accession protocol has been signed.</p>
<p>Then a couple of words about Russia and Ukraine.  Finland strongly condemns the Russian war of aggression in Ukraine.  We continue to urge Russia to stop the military actions immediately.  We are strongly supporting Ukraine both nationally and through the European Union.  Finland’s support to Ukraine includes humanitarian assistance, development cooperation, and material and arms assistance.  Ordinary Finns have also shown great solidary with Ukraine and Ukrainians who have fled to Finland, as mentioned by Tony.</p>
<p>Russia’s war in Ukraine is an attack against the entire European security order.  It’s a great breach of international law and a violation of the Charter of the United Nations.  Russia is flagrantly violating international law in Ukraine.  We need to ensure accountability for war crimes.  Finland supports the investigation by the International Criminal Court, ICC, by granting financial support and by seconding experts.</p>
<p>The EU and the United States have shown extraordinary speed, determination, and unity as a response to Russia’s actions, including extensive sanctions.  Sanctions have been powerful and hit Russia hard.  I wish to thank the United States for an exceptional collaboration.  Finland is ready to move forward with new sanctions and to consider all options, including energy.  New EU sanctions package is being prepared.</p>
<p>Our multilateral fora, Finland – on multilateral fora, Finland continues its close cooperation with partners and is actively discussing the key matters, for example, global food security, as discussed, and has been raised by United States.  We also thank the United States for active global outreach.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you for joining us this afternoon.  We will now take a question from each side, beginning with Shannon from ABC News.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you.  On expanding NATO, have you seen any progress towards getting Turkey onboard?  And what are you willing to do – what demands are you willing to satisfy – in order to move that process along?</p>
<p>Also, secondly, Mr. Secretary, you spoke with your Ukrainian counterpart today about security assistance.  Is supplying American long-range missile systems on the table?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.  I think as you heard from the Foreign Minister, Finland and Sweden are working directly with Turkey to address some of the concerns that it raised.  We’re also talking to Turkey.  I saw the Turkish Foreign Minister in New York about a week ago, and those conversations continue.</p>
<p>I don’t want to characterize the conversations beyond saying that, first, there is a very strong consensus in NATO for the admission of Finland and Sweden, and I remain confident that we will work through this process swiftly and that things will move forward with both countries.  As Pekka said, it is a process.  In that process, countries raise concerns that they may have.  We work through them; that’s what Finland and Sweden are doing right now with Turkey, and I’m confident that this will move forward.</p>
<p>With regard to security assistance to Ukraine, yes, I spoke to my counterpart, Dmytro Kuleba, this morning.  We speak regularly, and this is a constant conversation about the – among other things, the needs that Ukraine has to make sure that it has in hand what it needs to deal with the Russian aggression as well as, ultimately, to strengthen the hand that it will have at any negotiating table that emerges in the future.  And that’s a constant process.</p>
<p>Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin set up what I think is a very effective mechanism when he brought about 40 countries together at Ramstein, Germany a couple of weeks ago.  So there’s now an active contact group bringing all these countries together to focus the assistance that Ukraine needs and to make sure that countries are doing what they need to do to provide it.  I’m not going to get ahead of that process, including with future deliveries of assistance.  All of that is in train and will unfold in the days and weeks ahead.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER HAAVISTO: </b> Maybe from our side, first just to mention our prime minister, Sanna Marin, visited two days ago Kyiv and also Bucha and, of course, was shocked what they saw there and all the destruction.  And Finland is committed to continue supporting Ukraine and we have been also sending the little packages to Ukraine.  The military support to Ukraine is very important at this moment.</p>
<p>In regarding Turkey, our delegations visit actually Wednesday both from Sweden and Finland.  Turkey had a – good negotiations there, long negotiations, agreed to continue those talks, and of course, we rely on NATO “Open Door” policy, which is also supported by Turkey, and we think that these problems can be solved that – which Turkey has been raising.  And it’s probably very important that some results could be achieved before the Madrid summit, which is an important moment for NATO and also for us as applicant countries, in the end of June.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> Next we’ll turn to Laura from Finnish MTV News.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Secretary Blinken, so what concretely the United States is going to do with Turkey so that they would accept Finland joining NATO?  And what would be the timeline for this?  Do you believe that would really happen before the Madrid summit?</p>
<p>And similar question to Minister Haavisto.  Is it really possible that this could happen before the Madrid summit?  And did you receive any concrete promises what the United States could do to help Finland in this process with Turkey?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.  So again, in the first instance, the most important thing is that Finland and Sweden are speaking directly to and with Turkey, and working through some of the concerns that Turkey has raised and finding ways to address them.  We very much support that process; as I mentioned, we’re engaged with Turkey directly as well.  But the focus is on the work that Finland, Sweden, and Turkey are doing together to address the concerns.</p>
<p>And again, as I said, I’m confident this is going to move forward.  As Pekka alluded to a moment ago, we do have the NATO summit coming up in a few weeks, and our full expectation is that this process will move as we head into the summit as well as at the summit itself.</p>
<p>So again, beyond that I’m not going to get into the specifics.  But there’s an ongoing, very active conversation between Finland, Sweden, and Turkey that we’ll support in any way that we can.  I suspect NATO will do so as well.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER HAAVISTO:</b>  Thank you for the question.  Actually, a couple of weeks ago I participated in Berlin the NATO ministerial meeting.  We were invited by – both Sweden and Finland – there by German host and NATO hosts.  And I have to say that when we had this roundtable discussion about Finnish and Swedish membership, which that day had not yet been decided in our parliament but already could guess what is coming, we got extraordinary support from majority of the NATO members, very open support.  And it looked like countries are competing who will ratify first the applications.  And of course, that was a very positive signal to us.</p>
<p>At the same time, countries have the right to raise concerns.  Turkey has raised some concerns regarding the PKK issue, terrorist issues, and so forth.  The PKK is a forbidden organization in Finland.  We are part of those solutions in the European Union, where terrorist organizations are listed.  It’s the same in Sweden and so forth, and these are the answers that we are giving, of course, in this case to Turkey.  We, of course, hope that the process goes smoothly and rapidly because this – what we call the grey zone between the – putting the application in and finally getting approved as NATO members, of course, includes some security concerns.  We have got extraordinary strong assurances from countries like U.S., UK, and many others during this period, but, of course, it’s not the same as the NATO Article 5 security guarantees, and that’s why we would hope that this process goes smoothly and rapidly.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  That concludes our press conference for today.  Thank you for joining us.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Benjamin Franklin Room</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s wonderful to be able to host my colleague and friend, the Foreign Minister of Finland, here at the State Department in the Benjamin Franklin Room.  Our partnership, the partnership between Finland and the United States, has been rooted deeply in our shared values of democracy, of human rights, rule of law and a shared commitment to strengthening the international rules-based order.  We’re collaborating on virtually every pressing challenge of our time.  As a result, there’s always a lot to discuss when we get together, and we probably could have spent another hour talking about the many things that we’re working on.</p>
<p>But today, of course, we focused a great deal on Finland’s recent application to join NATO.  The United States fully supports Finland and Sweden joining the Alliance, and I continue to be confident that both countries will soon be NATO Allies.  Finland and Sweden more than meet NATO’s democratic, military, economic criteria for membership.  They’re committed to upholding NATO’s sacred Article 5 guarantee: an attack on one is an attack on all.  And both countries have a proven track record of honoring their commitments.</p>
<p>Since 2014, Finland has been an enhanced opportunities partner of NATO and maintains a high degree of interoperability with the Alliance.  In plain English that means that our militaries work together seamlessly, and the country brings specific military expertise and capabilities in the high north and the Baltic Sea.</p>
<p>But it’s not just Finland’s military capabilities that will make NATO stronger, but its free and open democratic society.  Indeed, we see that in the way that Finland decided to apply for NATO in the first place.  The move was driven by strong public support.  According to recent polls, three-in-four Finns want their country to join the Alliance.  Finnish people, press, and politicians debated the prospect openly.  And when the country’s democratically elected parliament put the issue to a vote, 188 out of 200 members supported applying for membership.  That is what a democratic process looks like.</p>
<p>The decisions by Finland and Sweden continue the trend that we’ve seen since President Putin launched his war of aggression in which he failed to achieve a single one of his strategic aims.  Instead of ending Ukraine’s independence, President Putin has strengthened it.  Instead of asserting Russia’s strength, he’s undermined it.  Instead of dividing NATO, he’s united it and now pushed more countries to apply to join.</p>
<p>Finland and Sweden’s applications also reaffirm NATO’s “Open Door” policy which has been a cornerstone of the Alliance since its very founding.  That door will stay open, reflecting our belief that every country should have the right to choose its allies and partners and to pursue membership if it chooses.  That is not a provocation or a threat to Russia.  We say this often, but it bears repeating: NATO is and always will be a defensive Alliance.  NATO does not seek confrontation with Russia, but rather we aim to prevent it.</p>
<p>The reason that more countries want to join NATO is simple:  They have seen the Russian Federation repeatedly attack its neighbors without provocation.  And so not unreasonably, they’re concerned that they could be next.  The only countries that have anything to fear from NATO are those that plan to attack one of the Allies.  As President Biden made clear last week in his meeting with the Finnish president, during the accession process the United States and our Finnish partners will remain vigilant against threats to our shared security, and we will work together to deter and confront any aggression.  The same holds true for Sweden.</p>
<p>The United States will also maintain our robust exercise activity and presence in the Baltic Sea region.</p>
<p>So simply put, Finland can depend on us, and I’m confident that we can depend on Finland.  The trust is built on experience.  We’ve collaborated for decades on the Arctic Council working together to advance a peaceful region where cooperation prevails on climate, on the environment, on science and safety, and where sustainable economic development benefits the local population.</p>
<p>For years, Finnish troops have served shoulder to shoulder with U.S. and NATO forces in Kosovo, in Afghanistan, in Iraq.  Together, we cofounded the European Center for Excellence for countering hybrid threats, which Finland hosts.  And since February 24, we’ve been closely aligned in our response to Moscow’s war of aggression against Ukraine.  We’ve repeatedly voted together to condemn Russia’s unjust invasion in the UN General Assembly and, of course, in the Human Rights Council, where we voted together to suspend Russia.  We’ve worked together to impose costs on the Russian Government and its proxies for this unjust war and the atrocities they are committing.</p>
<p>As a member of the European Union, Finland has helped craft and support EU sanctions which were closely coordinated with and complementary to our own.  Earlier this week, Finland joined more than 60 countries that have signed on to a roadmap to tackle the growing global food security crisis, which has been significantly worsened by Russia’s aggression in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Pekka and I talked about this at some length in our conversations both with regard to Ukraine and more generally what we can do and what we will do together to address this crisis around the globe.</p>
<p>Finland has also stepped up to provide security assistance and non-lethal aid to the Ukrainian Government.  The Government is committed to take in some 23,000 refugees, and Finnish universities have opened thousands of spots for Ukrainian students fleeing the war.  Finnish schools have opened thousands of chairs to younger Ukrainians, and we’re grateful for that incredible response.</p>
<p>One final point.  Squarely focused as we are today on how NATO can defend members against further Russian aggression, this alliance is also critical for protecting our shared security and values from other threats, including emerging challenges like cyber-attacks, infectious disease, a warming climate.  That’s yet another reason that we look forward to being able to call Finland and Sweden our allies and draw upon their leadership in the years ahead.</p>
<p>So Pekka, we’re already working so closely together, but I suspect that will become even closer with you as we deepen what is already a vital partnership between Finland and the United States.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER HAAVISTO:  </b>Thank you.  And first I want to thank Secretary of State Mr. Blinken, my good friend Tony, for this opportunity of to again meet here in Washington and discuss and exchange views in today’s meeting.  I think we had an excellent discussion.</p>
<p>We highly value our close cooperation between Finland and the United States.  As discussed today, we look forward to further deepening our bilateral engagement and continuing our close consultations on key foreign and security policy questions.</p>
<p>The main topics today were the security situation in Europe, Finland’s NATO membership application, and the war in Ukraine.  First a couple of words about our application.  Finland submitted on May 18<sup>th</sup>, at the same time with Sweden, our application for NATO membership.  Finland’s decision to apply for NATO membership is based on a comprehensive, democratic process and strong support from the people.  Finland’s accession to NATO would strengthen the security and stability of Northern Europe as well as wider transatlantic security.  Finland is a security provider and would further strengthen NATO as an Ally.  We are very grateful for the unwavering and strong support from the United States for our NATO membership bid.  We look forward to taking our excellent relationship to a new level as a NATO Ally.</p>
<p>Turkey has raised questions in conjunction with Finland’s and Sweden’s membership applications.  It is understandable that different issues may be raised by different allies along the process.  Finland has been in active contact with Turkey – I have been visiting Turkey twice this spring – at different levels regarding our NATO membership bid.  We wish to continue our constructive dialogue with allies and are ready to continue discussing the outstanding issues with Turkey.  We take every NATO members’ concerns seriously.  With Turkey we are now in an open, direct, and constructive dialogue process to clarify all issues.  This is important.</p>
<p>We highly appreciate the strong support from the allies along the process.  We also hope for a swift ratification of our membership once the accession protocol has been signed.</p>
<p>Then a couple of words about Russia and Ukraine.  Finland strongly condemns the Russian war of aggression in Ukraine.  We continue to urge Russia to stop the military actions immediately.  We are strongly supporting Ukraine both nationally and through the European Union.  Finland’s support to Ukraine includes humanitarian assistance, development cooperation, and material and arms assistance.  Ordinary Finns have also shown great solidary with Ukraine and Ukrainians who have fled to Finland, as mentioned by Tony.</p>
<p>Russia’s war in Ukraine is an attack against the entire European security order.  It’s a great breach of international law and a violation of the Charter of the United Nations.  Russia is flagrantly violating international law in Ukraine.  We need to ensure accountability for war crimes.  Finland supports the investigation by the International Criminal Court, ICC, by granting financial support and by seconding experts.</p>
<p>The EU and the United States have shown extraordinary speed, determination, and unity as a response to Russia’s actions, including extensive sanctions.  Sanctions have been powerful and hit Russia hard.  I wish to thank the United States for an exceptional collaboration.  Finland is ready to move forward with new sanctions and to consider all options, including energy.  New EU sanctions package is being prepared.</p>
<p>Our multilateral fora, Finland – on multilateral fora, Finland continues its close cooperation with partners and is actively discussing the key matters, for example, global food security, as discussed, and has been raised by United States.  We also thank the United States for active global outreach.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Thank you for joining us this afternoon.  We will now take a question from each side, beginning with Shannon from ABC News.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Thank you.  On expanding NATO, have you seen any progress towards getting Turkey onboard?  And what are you willing to do – what demands are you willing to satisfy – in order to move that process along?</p>
<p>Also, secondly, Mr. Secretary, you spoke with your Ukrainian counterpart today about security assistance.  Is supplying American long-range missile systems on the table?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.  I think as you heard from the Foreign Minister, Finland and Sweden are working directly with Turkey to address some of the concerns that it raised.  We’re also talking to Turkey.  I saw the Turkish Foreign Minister in New York about a week ago, and those conversations continue.</p>
<p>I don’t want to characterize the conversations beyond saying that, first, there is a very strong consensus in NATO for the admission of Finland and Sweden, and I remain confident that we will work through this process swiftly and that things will move forward with both countries.  As Pekka said, it is a process.  In that process, countries raise concerns that they may have.  We work through them; that’s what Finland and Sweden are doing right now with Turkey, and I’m confident that this will move forward.</p>
<p>With regard to security assistance to Ukraine, yes, I spoke to my counterpart, Dmytro Kuleba, this morning.  We speak regularly, and this is a constant conversation about the – among other things, the needs that Ukraine has to make sure that it has in hand what it needs to deal with the Russian aggression as well as, ultimately, to strengthen the hand that it will have at any negotiating table that emerges in the future.  And that’s a constant process.</p>
<p>Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin set up what I think is a very effective mechanism when he brought about 40 countries together at Ramstein, Germany a couple of weeks ago.  So there’s now an active contact group bringing all these countries together to focus the assistance that Ukraine needs and to make sure that countries are doing what they need to do to provide it.  I’m not going to get ahead of that process, including with future deliveries of assistance.  All of that is in train and will unfold in the days and weeks ahead.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER HAAVISTO: </b> Maybe from our side, first just to mention our prime minister, Sanna Marin, visited two days ago Kyiv and also Bucha and, of course, was shocked what they saw there and all the destruction.  And Finland is committed to continue supporting Ukraine and we have been also sending the little packages to Ukraine.  The military support to Ukraine is very important at this moment.</p>
<p>In regarding Turkey, our delegations visit actually Wednesday both from Sweden and Finland.  Turkey had a – good negotiations there, long negotiations, agreed to continue those talks, and of course, we rely on NATO “Open Door” policy, which is also supported by Turkey, and we think that these problems can be solved that – which Turkey has been raising.  And it’s probably very important that some results could be achieved before the Madrid summit, which is an important moment for NATO and also for us as applicant countries, in the end of June.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b> Next we’ll turn to Laura from Finnish MTV News.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Secretary Blinken, so what concretely the United States is going to do with Turkey so that they would accept Finland joining NATO?  And what would be the timeline for this?  Do you believe that would really happen before the Madrid summit?</p>
<p>And similar question to Minister Haavisto.  Is it really possible that this could happen before the Madrid summit?  And did you receive any concrete promises what the United States could do to help Finland in this process with Turkey?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Thank you.  So again, in the first instance, the most important thing is that Finland and Sweden are speaking directly to and with Turkey, and working through some of the concerns that Turkey has raised and finding ways to address them.  We very much support that process; as I mentioned, we’re engaged with Turkey directly as well.  But the focus is on the work that Finland, Sweden, and Turkey are doing together to address the concerns.</p>
<p>And again, as I said, I’m confident this is going to move forward.  As Pekka alluded to a moment ago, we do have the NATO summit coming up in a few weeks, and our full expectation is that this process will move as we head into the summit as well as at the summit itself.</p>
<p>So again, beyond that I’m not going to get into the specifics.  But there’s an ongoing, very active conversation between Finland, Sweden, and Turkey that we’ll support in any way that we can.  I suspect NATO will do so as well.</p>
<p><b>FOREIGN MINISTER HAAVISTO:</b>  Thank you for the question.  Actually, a couple of weeks ago I participated in Berlin the NATO ministerial meeting.  We were invited by – both Sweden and Finland – there by German host and NATO hosts.  And I have to say that when we had this roundtable discussion about Finnish and Swedish membership, which that day had not yet been decided in our parliament but already could guess what is coming, we got extraordinary support from majority of the NATO members, very open support.  And it looked like countries are competing who will ratify first the applications.  And of course, that was a very positive signal to us.</p>
<p>At the same time, countries have the right to raise concerns.  Turkey has raised some concerns regarding the PKK issue, terrorist issues, and so forth.  The PKK is a forbidden organization in Finland.  We are part of those solutions in the European Union, where terrorist organizations are listed.  It’s the same in Sweden and so forth, and these are the answers that we are giving, of course, in this case to Turkey.  We, of course, hope that the process goes smoothly and rapidly because this – what we call the grey zone between the – putting the application in and finally getting approved as NATO members, of course, includes some security concerns.  We have got extraordinary strong assurances from countries like U.S., UK, and many others during this period, but, of course, it’s not the same as the NATO Article 5 security guarantees, and that’s why we would hope that this process goes smoothly and rapidly.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  That concludes our press conference for today.  Thank you for joining us.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
