<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 18:47:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>U.S. Delegation on Atrocity Prevention and Response to Travel to The Hague</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-delegation-on-atrocity-prevention-and-response-to-travel-to-the-hague/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 18:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">A U.S. delegation led by Assistant Secretary of State for Conflict and Stabilization Operations Anne A. Witkowsky, Ambassador-at-Large for Global Criminal Justice Beth Van Schaack, and Bureau of International Organization Affairs Deputy Assistant Secretary Allison Lombardo will travel to The Hague, the Netherlands, from May 22 to 25, 2022.</p>
<p align="left">In The Hague, the U.S. delegation will hold high-level talks with allies and partners regarding our responses to atrocities committed in Ukraine, Burma, Ethiopia, and other locations experiencing violence.  They will also examine how to mitigate the drivers of atrocity risk in regions where preventative efforts can effectively preempt atrocities.  The delegation will review support for accountability measures and mechanisms to bring the perpetrators of atrocities to justice, including those committed in the context of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, through the Biden-Harris Administration’s newly announced European Democratic Resilience Initiative (EDRI).</p>
<p align="left">Also in The Hague, Assistant Secretary Witkowsky will meet with Dutch government counterparts to underscore our deep and longstanding transatlantic commitment to European security and coordination.  She will emphasize the need for comprehensive partnerships to address shared security concerns, including to advance implementation of the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.</p>
<p align="left">Follow @StateCSO and @StateDept_GCJ on Twitter for updates.  For more information, please contact CSO Public Affairs at <a href="mailto:CSOPublicAffairs1@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSOPublicAffairs1@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">A U.S. delegation led by Assistant Secretary of State for Conflict and Stabilization Operations Anne A. Witkowsky, Ambassador-at-Large for Global Criminal Justice Beth Van Schaack, and Bureau of International Organization Affairs Deputy Assistant Secretary Allison Lombardo will travel to The Hague, the Netherlands, from May 22 to 25, 2022.</p>
<p align="left">In The Hague, the U.S. delegation will hold high-level talks with allies and partners regarding our responses to atrocities committed in Ukraine, Burma, Ethiopia, and other locations experiencing violence.  They will also examine how to mitigate the drivers of atrocity risk in regions where preventative efforts can effectively preempt atrocities.  The delegation will review support for accountability measures and mechanisms to bring the perpetrators of atrocities to justice, including those committed in the context of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine, through the Biden-Harris Administration’s newly announced European Democratic Resilience Initiative (EDRI).</p>
<p align="left">Also in The Hague, Assistant Secretary Witkowsky will meet with Dutch government counterparts to underscore our deep and longstanding transatlantic commitment to European security and coordination.  She will emphasize the need for comprehensive partnerships to address shared security concerns, including to advance implementation of the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability.</p>
<p align="left">Follow @StateCSO and @StateDept_GCJ on Twitter for updates.  For more information, please contact CSO Public Affairs at <a href="mailto:CSOPublicAffairs1@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSOPublicAffairs1@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ambassador Hussain’s Trip to Saudi Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/ambassador-hussains-trip-to-saudi-arabia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 18:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">U.S. Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom Rashad Hussain traveled to Riyadh and Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, from May 11-15, 2022.</p>
<p align="left">In Riyahd, Ambassador Hussain attended the Forum on Promoting Common Values among the Followers of Religion.  There, he met with ministers of religious affairs and civil society, in attendance, including the Ecumenical Patriarch Bartholomew and the Secretary General of the Muslim World League.  For the first time in Saudi Arabia, the event convened representatives from Christian, Jewish, Hindu and Buddhist faith traditions alongside Islamic leaders to explore shared values and a common global vision for interfaith cooperation.  Leaders from faith communities from around the world, many of whom had never visited Saudi Arabia, also attended.  Ambassador Hussain spoke with attendees on the urgent need for the international community to protect religious freedom worldwide, repeal and cease enforcement of blasphemy and apostasy laws, confront crimes against humanity and genocide against Uyghurs and Rohingya, and support the empowerment of marginalized communities, including women and girls.</p>
<p align="left">Ambassador Hussain also traveled to Jeddah, where he met with Organisation of Islamic Cooperation (OIC) officials and members, including the Secretary General of the OIC and the Islamic Development Bank, to discuss how their organizations can advance religious freedom for all, address the treatment of Muslim minorities including Uyghurs and Rohingya, and respond to the threats to religious freedom in Afghanistan.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">U.S. Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom Rashad Hussain traveled to Riyadh and Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, from May 11-15, 2022.</p>
<p align="left">In Riyahd, Ambassador Hussain attended the Forum on Promoting Common Values among the Followers of Religion.  There, he met with ministers of religious affairs and civil society, in attendance, including the Ecumenical Patriarch Bartholomew and the Secretary General of the Muslim World League.  For the first time in Saudi Arabia, the event convened representatives from Christian, Jewish, Hindu and Buddhist faith traditions alongside Islamic leaders to explore shared values and a common global vision for interfaith cooperation.  Leaders from faith communities from around the world, many of whom had never visited Saudi Arabia, also attended.  Ambassador Hussain spoke with attendees on the urgent need for the international community to protect religious freedom worldwide, repeal and cease enforcement of blasphemy and apostasy laws, confront crimes against humanity and genocide against Uyghurs and Rohingya, and support the empowerment of marginalized communities, including women and girls.</p>
<p align="left">Ambassador Hussain also traveled to Jeddah, where he met with Organisation of Islamic Cooperation (OIC) officials and members, including the Secretary General of the OIC and the Islamic Development Bank, to discuss how their organizations can advance religious freedom for all, address the treatment of Muslim minorities including Uyghurs and Rohingya, and respond to the threats to religious freedom in Afghanistan.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General Delattre</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-french-foreign-ministry-secretary-general-delattre-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 17:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346268</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General François Delattre today to discuss continued coordination to support Ukraine and its sovereignty in the face of Putin’s unprovoked and unjustified war.  In addition, they highlighted the need for swift international action to confront the growing crisis of food insecurity, exacerbated by Russia&#8217;s full-scale invasion.  The two also exchanged views on developments in NATO, including Finland and Sweden’s welcome request to join, and the lead up to the Madrid Summit.  Deputy Secretary Sherman also discussed with Secretary General Delattre France’s plans for the final weeks of France’s presidency of the Council of the European Union, including support for EU accession paths for aspirants willing to do the hard work to qualify for membership.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General François Delattre today to discuss continued coordination to support Ukraine and its sovereignty in the face of Putin’s unprovoked and unjustified war.  In addition, they highlighted the need for swift international action to confront the growing crisis of food insecurity, exacerbated by Russia&#8217;s full-scale invasion.  The two also exchanged views on developments in NATO, including Finland and Sweden’s welcome request to join, and the lead up to the Madrid Summit.  Deputy Secretary Sherman also discussed with Secretary General Delattre France’s plans for the final weeks of France’s presidency of the Council of the European Union, including support for EU accession paths for aspirants willing to do the hard work to qualify for membership.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Kazakhstani Foreign Minister Mukhtar Tileuberdi Before Their Meeting </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-kazakhstani-foreign-minister-mukhtar-tileuberdi-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State, Mukhtar Tileuberdi, Kazakhstani Foreign Minister]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 17:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Mukhtar Tileuberdi, Kazakhstani Foreign Minister</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good morning everyone, and welcome to our friends and colleagues.  It’s very good to have Foreign Minister Tileuberdi here today.  We have been strategic partners with Kazakhstan for 30 years, something that we value very much.  We very much support as well the important efforts at political and economic reform that are taking place now in Kazakhstan.  This long relationship is one girded by our strong commitment to Kazakhstan’s independence, sovereignty, territorial integrity.</p>
<p>We have a lot to talk about today in terms of the region, security.  What we’re seeing among other things from Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine are profound impacts beyond Ukraine, including in Central Asia – food, energy, trade – and we’re working to address all of these second and third order effects of the aggression.</p>
<p>So Mukhtar, it’s very good to have you here.  Thank you for being here, and I look forward to a good conversation.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER TILEUBERDI:</strong>  Dear Secretary of State, thank you for the invitation to visit Washington, D.C., and for the warm welcome.  And I am here today with a special mission to deliver our key messages, to reaffirm our steadfast commitment to further advance our Enhanced Strategic Partnership with the United States.</p>
<p>Just also using this opportunity, I would like to thank you for your initiative to the ministerial meeting on global food security.  I participated in New York this 18 of May, and I believe that it was important and timely event to address the actual issues and the challenges, which is very important especially for our region of Central Asia.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, everyone.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Mukhtar Tileuberdi, Kazakhstani Foreign Minister</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, good morning everyone, and welcome to our friends and colleagues.  It’s very good to have Foreign Minister Tileuberdi here today.  We have been strategic partners with Kazakhstan for 30 years, something that we value very much.  We very much support as well the important efforts at political and economic reform that are taking place now in Kazakhstan.  This long relationship is one girded by our strong commitment to Kazakhstan’s independence, sovereignty, territorial integrity.</p>
<p>We have a lot to talk about today in terms of the region, security.  What we’re seeing among other things from Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine are profound impacts beyond Ukraine, including in Central Asia – food, energy, trade – and we’re working to address all of these second and third order effects of the aggression.</p>
<p>So Mukhtar, it’s very good to have you here.  Thank you for being here, and I look forward to a good conversation.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER TILEUBERDI:</strong>  Dear Secretary of State, thank you for the invitation to visit Washington, D.C., and for the warm welcome.  And I am here today with a special mission to deliver our key messages, to reaffirm our steadfast commitment to further advance our Enhanced Strategic Partnership with the United States.</p>
<p>Just also using this opportunity, I would like to thank you for your initiative to the ministerial meeting on global food security.  I participated in New York this 18 of May, and I believe that it was important and timely event to address the actual issues and the challenges, which is very important especially for our region of Central Asia.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thanks, everyone.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revocation of Five Foreign Terrorist Organizations Designations and the Delisting of Six Deceased Individuals as Specially Designated Global Terrorists</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/revocation-of-five-foreign-terrorist-organizations-designations-and-the-delisting-of-six-deceased-individuals-as-specially-designated-global-terrorists/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 15:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Today, the Department of State is announcing the revocation of five Foreign Terrorist Organization (FTO) designations under the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA): Basque Fatherland and Liberty, Aum Shinrikyo, Mujahidin Shura Council in the Environs of Jerusalem, Kahane Chai, and Gama’a al-Islamiyya.  All five organizations will remain designated as Specially Designated Global Terrorists (SDGT) entities under Executive Order 13224.  The Department is retaining these SDGT designations for a number of reasons, including to support law enforcement actions or ensure frozen assets are not released to still active individual terrorists.</p>
<p align="left">In addition to these five FTO revocations, the Department of State is also announcing the revocation of six now deceased individuals as SDGTs designated under Executive Order 13224: Abu al-Wardah, Mohad Moalim, Farah Mohamed Shirdon, Musa Abu Dawud, Aliaskhab Kebekov, and Ibrahim al-Rubaysh.</p>
<p align="left">As required by the INA, the Department reviews FTO designations every five years to determine if the circumstances that were the basis of the designation have changed in such a manner as to warrant a revocation.  Our review of these five FTO designations determined that, as defined by the INA, the five organizations are no longer engaged in terrorism or terrorist activity and do not retain the capability and intent to do so.  Therefore, as required by the INA, these FTO designations are being revoked.</p>
<p align="left">These actions are intended to reflect the United States’ resolve to comply with legal requirements to review and revoke FTO designations when the facts compel such action.  These revocations do not seek to overlook or excuse the terrorist acts each of these groups previously engaged in or the harm the organizations caused its victims, but rather recognize the success Egypt, Israel, Japan, and Spain have had in defusing the threat of terrorism by these groups.  Revoking FTO designations and the delisting of deceased individuals ensures our terrorism sanctions remain current and credible and does not reflect any change in policy towards the past activities of any of these terrorists or of the organizations in which they were members.</p>
<p align="left">The United States remains committed to combating the activities of terrorists worldwide.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Today, the Department of State is announcing the revocation of five Foreign Terrorist Organization (FTO) designations under the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA): Basque Fatherland and Liberty, Aum Shinrikyo, Mujahidin Shura Council in the Environs of Jerusalem, Kahane Chai, and Gama’a al-Islamiyya.  All five organizations will remain designated as Specially Designated Global Terrorists (SDGT) entities under Executive Order 13224.  The Department is retaining these SDGT designations for a number of reasons, including to support law enforcement actions or ensure frozen assets are not released to still active individual terrorists.</p>
<p align="left">In addition to these five FTO revocations, the Department of State is also announcing the revocation of six now deceased individuals as SDGTs designated under Executive Order 13224: Abu al-Wardah, Mohad Moalim, Farah Mohamed Shirdon, Musa Abu Dawud, Aliaskhab Kebekov, and Ibrahim al-Rubaysh.</p>
<p align="left">As required by the INA, the Department reviews FTO designations every five years to determine if the circumstances that were the basis of the designation have changed in such a manner as to warrant a revocation.  Our review of these five FTO designations determined that, as defined by the INA, the five organizations are no longer engaged in terrorism or terrorist activity and do not retain the capability and intent to do so.  Therefore, as required by the INA, these FTO designations are being revoked.</p>
<p align="left">These actions are intended to reflect the United States’ resolve to comply with legal requirements to review and revoke FTO designations when the facts compel such action.  These revocations do not seek to overlook or excuse the terrorist acts each of these groups previously engaged in or the harm the organizations caused its victims, but rather recognize the success Egypt, Israel, Japan, and Spain have had in defusing the threat of terrorism by these groups.  Revoking FTO designations and the delisting of deceased individuals ensures our terrorism sanctions remain current and credible and does not reflect any change in policy towards the past activities of any of these terrorists or of the organizations in which they were members.</p>
<p align="left">The United States remains committed to combating the activities of terrorists worldwide.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Parliamentary Elections in Lebanon</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/parliamentary-elections-in-lebanon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 15:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346230</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The United States welcomes that parliamentary elections in Lebanon were held on time and without major security incidents.  We congratulate the Lebanese people on their participation despite challenging circumstances.  We also recognize the important role the Lebanese Armed Forces and Internal Security Forces played in supporting the process and maintaining security.</p>
<p align="left">We share the concerns raised by our partners in the international community of allegations of vote buying, clientelism, and reports of intimidation.</p>
<p align="left">As Lebanon looks ahead, we urge those elected and the country’s political leaders to heed the Lebanese people’s call for change and to work seriously, and with urgency, to take the necessary actions to rescue the economy.  We also urge the swift formation of a government capable of and committed to undertaking the hard work required to restore the confidence of the Lebanese people and the international community.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">The United States welcomes that parliamentary elections in Lebanon were held on time and without major security incidents.  We congratulate the Lebanese people on their participation despite challenging circumstances.  We also recognize the important role the Lebanese Armed Forces and Internal Security Forces played in supporting the process and maintaining security.</p>
<p align="left">We share the concerns raised by our partners in the international community of allegations of vote buying, clientelism, and reports of intimidation.</p>
<p align="left">As Lebanon looks ahead, we urge those elected and the country’s political leaders to heed the Lebanese people’s call for change and to work seriously, and with urgency, to take the necessary actions to rescue the economy.  We also urge the swift formation of a government capable of and committed to undertaking the hard work required to restore the confidence of the Lebanese people and the international community.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate Kerry’s Travel to Switzerland and Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-presidential-envoy-for-climate-kerrys-travel-to-switzerland-and-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 12:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346193</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Davos May 21-24 to engage global leaders at the World Economic Forum Annual Meeting on private sector climate action including shipping decarbonization, ocean stewardship, energy security, and long-term sustainable growth.  Secretary Kerry will also join global partners in announcing several expansions of the First Movers Coalition, including new company pledges, government partners, and sectoral commitments.  He will then travel to Berlin May 25–27 for the G7 Climate, Energy, and Environment Ministerial meeting to discuss priorities concerning climate ambition, such as adaptation and rapid emissions reductions, including in sectors such as methane.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:ClimateComms@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ClimateComms@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry will travel to Davos May 21-24 to engage global leaders at the World Economic Forum Annual Meeting on private sector climate action including shipping decarbonization, ocean stewardship, energy security, and long-term sustainable growth.  Secretary Kerry will also join global partners in announcing several expansions of the First Movers Coalition, including new company pledges, government partners, and sectoral commitments.  He will then travel to Berlin May 25–27 for the G7 Climate, Energy, and Environment Ministerial meeting to discuss priorities concerning climate ambition, such as adaptation and rapid emissions reductions, including in sectors such as methane.</p>
<p>For media inquiries, please contact <a href="mailto:ClimateComms@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ClimateComms@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Zambian Foreign Minister Kakubo</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-zambian-foreign-minister-kakubo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Wendy Sherman met today in Washington with a Zambian government delegation that included Foreign Minister Stanley Kakubo, Secretary of the Treasury Felix Nkulukusa, and interim National Security Advisor Lawrence Mwananyanda.  The Deputy Secretary thanked Zambia for its unwavering support against the war on Ukraine, including at the United Nations and other multilateral institutions, and expressed support for Zambia’s political and economic renewal, including ongoing multilateral efforts to restructure Zambia’s external debt.  The officials discussed the strong U.S.-Zambia partnership and opportunities to strengthen the trade and investment relationship, based on mutual prosperity for both countries.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Wendy Sherman met today in Washington with a Zambian government delegation that included Foreign Minister Stanley Kakubo, Secretary of the Treasury Felix Nkulukusa, and interim National Security Advisor Lawrence Mwananyanda.  The Deputy Secretary thanked Zambia for its unwavering support against the war on Ukraine, including at the United Nations and other multilateral institutions, and expressed support for Zambia’s political and economic renewal, including ongoing multilateral efforts to restructure Zambia’s external debt.  The officials discussed the strong U.S.-Zambia partnership and opportunities to strengthen the trade and investment relationship, based on mutual prosperity for both countries.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with UN Secretary-General Guterres</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-un-secretary-general-guterres-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 23:51:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346142</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today in New York City with United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres to discuss President Putin’s brutal war against Ukraine and its devastating effects on global food security. They discussed the Secretary-General’s visit in April to Kyiv and Moscow, noted concerns regarding the humanitarian crisis caused by the war, and shared perspectives on the United Nations’ response to the acute human suffering in and around Ukraine.  They also discussed expanding humanitarian access in Syria.  The Secretary affirmed the United States looks forward to partnering with the UN Secretariat, Member States, and other key stakeholders to advance the Secretary-General&#8217;s<em> Our Common Agenda </em>initiative.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today in New York City with United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres to discuss President Putin’s brutal war against Ukraine and its devastating effects on global food security. They discussed the Secretary-General’s visit in April to Kyiv and Moscow, noted concerns regarding the humanitarian crisis caused by the war, and shared perspectives on the United Nations’ response to the acute human suffering in and around Ukraine.  They also discussed expanding humanitarian access in Syria.  The Secretary affirmed the United States looks forward to partnering with the UN Secretariat, Member States, and other key stakeholders to advance the Secretary-General&#8217;s<em> Our Common Agenda </em>initiative.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken At a Roundtable on Humanitarian Assistance in Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-a-roundtable-on-humanitarian-assistance-in-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 23:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=346139</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>New York, New York</p>
<p>Lotte The Palace New York</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Liz, thank you.  Thank you for those truly overly generous words.  But the one part of that that’s true is that we’ve had a relationship going back many, many years (inaudible).  It’s something that I’ve had the opportunity to be involved in over many years now.  And I have to tell you I think the mission that you’re leading is arguably more important (inaudible).  It’s something that we’ve known (inaudible) for a long, long time, but the fact of the matter is if we’re not engaged, if the United States is not there, then usually there’s a vacuum that’s going to wind up being filled by bad things before it’s filled by good things.  And you have been promoting, advancing the proposition that U.S. leadership, U.S. engagement, matters.  It makes a difference.</p>
<p>And I think we’ve seen that in the case of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.  I’m proud of the fact that we’ve stood up in terms of our support for Ukraine itself – security, economic, and humanitarian.  I’m proud of the fact that we’ve brought dozens of countries along in exerting necessary pressure on Russia to end the aggression.  And I’m proud of the fact that we’ve also been able to strengthen our own Alliance, our defensive Alliance, NATO.</p>
<p>But having said all of that, I’m equally proud of the extraordinary response that we’re seeing from the private sector, a response some of which I’ve seen firsthand, including in Poland – our friend (inaudible), just to cite one of many, many, many examples – but really stepping up for the Ukrainian people, responding to the extraordinary humanitarian needs that exist, but also beginning this conversation about the longer term and how we think about rebuilding, because the devastation that’s been wrought on Ukraine and big parts of its economy are quite staggering and are going to require a lot.</p>
<p>So I was really anxious to get together with this group.  I’m grateful for the fact that you’ve taken the time to do this today, because it’s an opportunity for us to hear a little bit about what the experience has been to date in finding different ways to support Ukrainian people in Ukraine, but also what your thoughts are for going forward and the extent to which this has shaped your own thinking about engagement on these issues, because something as significant, as dramatic, and as deep-rooted as this also gets us thinking about how we do things (inaudible) to do things going forward.</p>
<p>So I’m really grateful for this conversation and anxious to be listening in order to hear from each of you, so thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>New York, New York</p>
<p>Lotte The Palace New York</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Liz, thank you.  Thank you for those truly overly generous words.  But the one part of that that’s true is that we’ve had a relationship going back many, many years (inaudible).  It’s something that I’ve had the opportunity to be involved in over many years now.  And I have to tell you I think the mission that you’re leading is arguably more important (inaudible).  It’s something that we’ve known (inaudible) for a long, long time, but the fact of the matter is if we’re not engaged, if the United States is not there, then usually there’s a vacuum that’s going to wind up being filled by bad things before it’s filled by good things.  And you have been promoting, advancing the proposition that U.S. leadership, U.S. engagement, matters.  It makes a difference.</p>
<p>And I think we’ve seen that in the case of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine.  I’m proud of the fact that we’ve stood up in terms of our support for Ukraine itself – security, economic, and humanitarian.  I’m proud of the fact that we’ve brought dozens of countries along in exerting necessary pressure on Russia to end the aggression.  And I’m proud of the fact that we’ve also been able to strengthen our own Alliance, our defensive Alliance, NATO.</p>
<p>But having said all of that, I’m equally proud of the extraordinary response that we’re seeing from the private sector, a response some of which I’ve seen firsthand, including in Poland – our friend (inaudible), just to cite one of many, many, many examples – but really stepping up for the Ukrainian people, responding to the extraordinary humanitarian needs that exist, but also beginning this conversation about the longer term and how we think about rebuilding, because the devastation that’s been wrought on Ukraine and big parts of its economy are quite staggering and are going to require a lot.</p>
<p>So I was really anxious to get together with this group.  I’m grateful for the fact that you’ve taken the time to do this today, because it’s an opportunity for us to hear a little bit about what the experience has been to date in finding different ways to support Ukrainian people in Ukraine, but also what your thoughts are for going forward and the extent to which this has shaped your own thinking about engagement on these issues, because something as significant, as dramatic, and as deep-rooted as this also gets us thinking about how we do things (inaudible) to do things going forward.</p>
<p>So I’m really grateful for this conversation and anxious to be listening in order to hear from each of you, so thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
