<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 14:20:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Joint Statement from the U.S.-Czech Republic Strategic Dialogue</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-from-the-u-s-czech-republic-strategic-dialogue/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 14:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329572</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>Following is the text of a joint statement by the Governments of the United States of America and of the Czech Republic</em>.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>The Governments of the Czech Republic and the United States renewed the U.S.-Czech Republic Strategic Dialogue in Prague on March 30, 2022, with delegations led by Czech Deputy Foreign Minister Martin Povejsil and U.S. Assistant Secretary of State for European and Eurasian Affairs Karen Donfried.  In conjunction with the Strategic Dialogue, Assistant Secretary Donfried also met with Foreign Minister Jan Lipavsky.</p>
<p>The United States and the Czech Republic have a historic friendship based on common democratic values and an appreciation of our shared responsibility to uphold the rules-based international order in cooperation with our Allies and partners.  This Strategic Dialogue comes at a critical time.  It demonstrates the strength and importance of the bilateral relationship as the United States and the Czech Republic focus on the security challenges on the Eastern Flank of NATO due to the Russian Federation’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine.  We underline our commitment to protect and defend every inch of NATO territory.  The Czech Republic has renewed its commitment to increase its defense spending to two percent of GDP.  A faster pace of modernization of the Czech armed forces is a priority, gaining new capabilities in cooperation with the United States and other Allies.</p>
<p>We stand strong and united in support of the people of Ukraine and the Ukrainian government against Russia’s unprovoked war, which is causing immense human suffering and destruction of civilian infrastructure.  We call on Russia to cease its military offensive and completely withdraw its armed forces from the territories of Ukraine, Moldova, and Georgia and to respect their sovereignty and internationally recognized borders.<strong>  </strong>Beijing’s position on Russia’s war also remains under our close scrutiny.  The United States and the Czech Republic agree that the international community must deepen Russia’s political and economic isolation and apply tougher sanctions against enablers of Russia’s aggression.  The discussion of Ukraine’s post-war recovery must begin now.  We must endeavor to provide Ukraine the political and practical assistance to support and realize its sovereign choice of full integration with Europe and the world’s democracies.</p>
<p>The United States and the Czech Republic emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Czech partnership in addressing common threats and challenges, including in the area of cyber security and resilience to hybrid threats.  The Strategic Dialogue focused on reaffirming the strong, steady, and deepening bilateral cooperation between the United States and the Czech Republic and our joint commitment to enhance cooperation on a broad range of topics, including closer cooperation with partners in the Indo-Pacific region.  We also affirm our commitment to deepen support and cooperation with democratic partners in the region and around the world, such as Taiwan.</p>
<p>We agree current geopolitical developments make enhancing energy security more urgent than ever.  The United States and the Czech Republic are taking steps to reduce reliance on Russian oil, natural gas, and nuclear fuel by diversifying sources of energy, expanding our already strong cooperation on nuclear power, and reducing consumption in line with our shared climate goals.</p>
<p>The United States and the Czech Republic consulted on the importance of strengthening Transatlantic relations, including cooperation between the United States and the EU, during the Czech Republic’s presidency of the Council of the European Union in the second half of 2022.  Both sides expressed a strong interest in deepening the bilateral strategic partnership in the year ahead and through future strategic dialogues.  The parties plan to hold the next annual meeting in Washington in 2023.</p>
<p><em>End Text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>Following is the text of a joint statement by the Governments of the United States of America and of the Czech Republic</em>.</p>
<p><em>Begin Text:</em></p>
<p>The Governments of the Czech Republic and the United States renewed the U.S.-Czech Republic Strategic Dialogue in Prague on March 30, 2022, with delegations led by Czech Deputy Foreign Minister Martin Povejsil and U.S. Assistant Secretary of State for European and Eurasian Affairs Karen Donfried.  In conjunction with the Strategic Dialogue, Assistant Secretary Donfried also met with Foreign Minister Jan Lipavsky.</p>
<p>The United States and the Czech Republic have a historic friendship based on common democratic values and an appreciation of our shared responsibility to uphold the rules-based international order in cooperation with our Allies and partners.  This Strategic Dialogue comes at a critical time.  It demonstrates the strength and importance of the bilateral relationship as the United States and the Czech Republic focus on the security challenges on the Eastern Flank of NATO due to the Russian Federation’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine.  We underline our commitment to protect and defend every inch of NATO territory.  The Czech Republic has renewed its commitment to increase its defense spending to two percent of GDP.  A faster pace of modernization of the Czech armed forces is a priority, gaining new capabilities in cooperation with the United States and other Allies.</p>
<p>We stand strong and united in support of the people of Ukraine and the Ukrainian government against Russia’s unprovoked war, which is causing immense human suffering and destruction of civilian infrastructure.  We call on Russia to cease its military offensive and completely withdraw its armed forces from the territories of Ukraine, Moldova, and Georgia and to respect their sovereignty and internationally recognized borders.<strong>  </strong>Beijing’s position on Russia’s war also remains under our close scrutiny.  The United States and the Czech Republic agree that the international community must deepen Russia’s political and economic isolation and apply tougher sanctions against enablers of Russia’s aggression.  The discussion of Ukraine’s post-war recovery must begin now.  We must endeavor to provide Ukraine the political and practical assistance to support and realize its sovereign choice of full integration with Europe and the world’s democracies.</p>
<p>The United States and the Czech Republic emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Czech partnership in addressing common threats and challenges, including in the area of cyber security and resilience to hybrid threats.  The Strategic Dialogue focused on reaffirming the strong, steady, and deepening bilateral cooperation between the United States and the Czech Republic and our joint commitment to enhance cooperation on a broad range of topics, including closer cooperation with partners in the Indo-Pacific region.  We also affirm our commitment to deepen support and cooperation with democratic partners in the region and around the world, such as Taiwan.</p>
<p>We agree current geopolitical developments make enhancing energy security more urgent than ever.  The United States and the Czech Republic are taking steps to reduce reliance on Russian oil, natural gas, and nuclear fuel by diversifying sources of energy, expanding our already strong cooperation on nuclear power, and reducing consumption in line with our shared climate goals.</p>
<p>The United States and the Czech Republic consulted on the importance of strengthening Transatlantic relations, including cooperation between the United States and the EU, during the Czech Republic’s presidency of the Council of the European Union in the second half of 2022.  Both sides expressed a strong interest in deepening the bilateral strategic partnership in the year ahead and through future strategic dialogues.  The parties plan to hold the next annual meeting in Washington in 2023.</p>
<p><em>End Text.</em></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken At Algiers International Trade Fair Launch Event with U.S. Companies</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-at-algiers-international-trade-fair-launch-event-with-u-s-companies/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 13:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329478</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Algiers, Algeria</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy Algiers</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s wonderful to be here, wonderful to be back – to be back in this beautiful embassy, and Nawal, thank you so much for your introduction, but also for your leadership at the Women in Business Committee in the American Chamber of Commerce in Algeria.  Grateful for that.</p>
<p><i>Assalamu alaikum</i>, everybody.  This is a dynamic time for business in Algeria.  We’re seeing that in numbers.  In 2020, the two-way trade between the United States and Algeria totaled $1.2 billion.  In 2021, even with COVID, it more than doubled to $2.6 billion.  And in just the month of January this year alone, two-way trade grows to $331 million just for that month.  So we’re on track to continue to see a significant increase.</p>
<p>We see it as well in the more welcoming business environment that President Tebboune is planning to create through his year of the economy in Algeria.  I’ll have a chance to meet with the president a little bit later today, and one of the things I expect to discuss is the strong collaboration that’s happening across Algerian and American businesses, and across a range of sectors, including renewable energy, technology, and others.  And we’ll talk about ways to draw even more American foreign direct investment here including through improvements in Algeria’s investment climate.  The Algiers International Fair this June, with the U.S. as the country of honor, is going to be an opportunity to deepen all of these efforts.</p>
<p>The Algerian-United States relationship would not be as strong and getting stronger without the groundwork that all of you and your companies have been laying over the years.  Some have been operating here for decades, others started working in Algeria more recently, but together, you’re supporting thousands of Algerian and American jobs and families and communities along with them.  You’re investing in the local workforce, sharing knowledge, best practices between Algerian and American businesses, and building sustainable partnerships that are to the benefit of both of our countries.</p>
<p>So for that, I want to say to everyone, <i>sahha</i>, thank you, and what I want to do now is turn it over to a brief video about the U.S. Pavilion.  So over to the video.</p>
<p>(A video was played.)</p>
<p>Thank you all.  I’m really looking forward to seeing you there.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Algiers, Algeria</p>
<p>U.S. Embassy Algiers</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s wonderful to be here, wonderful to be back – to be back in this beautiful embassy, and Nawal, thank you so much for your introduction, but also for your leadership at the Women in Business Committee in the American Chamber of Commerce in Algeria.  Grateful for that.</p>
<p><i>Assalamu alaikum</i>, everybody.  This is a dynamic time for business in Algeria.  We’re seeing that in numbers.  In 2020, the two-way trade between the United States and Algeria totaled $1.2 billion.  In 2021, even with COVID, it more than doubled to $2.6 billion.  And in just the month of January this year alone, two-way trade grows to $331 million just for that month.  So we’re on track to continue to see a significant increase.</p>
<p>We see it as well in the more welcoming business environment that President Tebboune is planning to create through his year of the economy in Algeria.  I’ll have a chance to meet with the president a little bit later today, and one of the things I expect to discuss is the strong collaboration that’s happening across Algerian and American businesses, and across a range of sectors, including renewable energy, technology, and others.  And we’ll talk about ways to draw even more American foreign direct investment here including through improvements in Algeria’s investment climate.  The Algiers International Fair this June, with the U.S. as the country of honor, is going to be an opportunity to deepen all of these efforts.</p>
<p>The Algerian-United States relationship would not be as strong and getting stronger without the groundwork that all of you and your companies have been laying over the years.  Some have been operating here for decades, others started working in Algeria more recently, but together, you’re supporting thousands of Algerian and American jobs and families and communities along with them.  You’re investing in the local workforce, sharing knowledge, best practices between Algerian and American businesses, and building sustainable partnerships that are to the benefit of both of our countries.</p>
<p>So for that, I want to say to everyone, <i>sahha</i>, thank you, and what I want to do now is turn it over to a brief video about the U.S. Pavilion.  So over to the video.</p>
<p>(A video was played.)</p>
<p>Thank you all.  I’m really looking forward to seeing you there.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Commitments to Regional Security and Prosperity Underscore Secretary Blinken’s Travel to Algeria</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/commitments-to-regional-security-and-prosperity-underscore-secretary-blinkens-travel-to-algeria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 11:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329441</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On March 30, Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Algeria for meetings with President Abdelmadjid Tebboune and Foreign Minister Ramtane Lamamra to discuss regional security and stability, economic cooperation, and advancing human rights and fundamental freedoms.  The Secretary will promote America’s role as the Country of Honor at the Algiers International Trade Fair in June, the largest trade show of its kind in Africa.  He will meet with U.S. business representatives in Algeria to discuss deepening economic ties and promoting U.S.-Algeria trade and investment.</p>
<p><b>A DEEP AND LASTING RELATIONSHIP</b></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States and Algeria share a long history – from the 1795 Treaty of Peace and Amity to hosting negotiations to release American hostages from Tehran in 1981 – and our bilateral relationship continues to flourish.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Our security and counterterrorism cooperation remains a cornerstone of our bilateral relationship. We are also encouraged by the deepening economic and cultural ties between the United States and Algeria.  More and more U.S. companies are seeking investment in Algeria, and those already here are creating jobs across a wide range of sectors.  The fact that we are the country of honor at this year’s Algiers International Fair – the largest trade fair of its kind in Africa – demonstrates Algeria’s interest in American products and technology.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>BILATERAL AND REGIONAL POLITICAL ISSUES</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Earlier this month, Deputy Secretary Wendy Sherman and Foreign Minister Lamamra met in Algiers to express strong support for the efforts of Personal Envoy of the UN Secretary General Staffan de Mistura’s leadership in resuming the UN-led political process to advance a durable and dignified resolution to the conflict in Western Sahara that will create a peaceful and prosperous future for the people of Western Sahara and the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>We also agreed on the importance of regional stability for the entire Sahel and the need to counter the destabilizing presence of terrorist groups.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Our relationship is multifaceted.  We work closely with Algeria on counterterrorism and regional security, so that we can learn from one another and strengthen our respective security capabilities. Algeria hosted a Joint Military Dialogue March 14-15, during which we further discussed our commitment to regional security.</li>
<li>The United States and Algeria regularly discuss the importance of protecting and advancing human rights, including freedoms of expression and belief and the important role of independent media and civil society. Human rights are a central pillar of U.S. foreign policy.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>CULTURAL TIES AND EXCHANGES</b></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States shares strong cultural and economic relations with Algeria, which continue to improve at both the government-to-government and people-to-people levels. The OneBeat program in February and March featured 23 musicians from the United States, Algeria, and all of Algeria’s neighbors who created original music together in a three-week musical residency capped by two well-attended public concerts.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>There is no better indicator of the growing partnership between our two countries than our growing cultural ties. Algeria’s continued interest in English-language training and entrepreneurship are key areas where we are already working together.  We are pleased to have launched earlier this month two new programs that will strengthen U.S.-Algerian cooperation.  The State Department initiated the Link Project in Algeria to help 120 Algerian government officials improve their professional English language skills.  This will enable them to participate in international conferences and exchanges, communicate with international counterparts, and engage with English-language reports and other content.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The State Department is also working with the University of Notre Dame in Indiana to implement a three-year project to create a “research hub” to link Algerian research institutions in five key fields – artificial intelligence, applied mathematics, climate change and renewable energies, health and pharmaceutical sciences, and agriculture – with their American counterparts to facilitate the exchange of ideas and people. This project will build the research capacity of Algerian universities and create key linkages between Algerian researchers and the private sector.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>WESTERN SAHARA</b></p>
<ul>
<li>We strongly support the efforts of Staffan de Mistura, the Personal Envoy of the Secretary-General for Western Sahara.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>We are fully engaged diplomatically, in support of the UN and together with our international partners, to reinforce a credible political process leading to an enduring and dignified resolution.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>SAHEL</b></p>
<ul>
<li>We are both very concerned about the destabilizing presence of terrorist groups in the Sahel, and we both want security and prosperity in the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Algeria has played a key role in facilitating this stability through its mediation of the 2015 Algiers Peace Accord and continues to be a regional leader promoting resolution to ongoing conflicts.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>COVID-19 RESPONSE</b></p>
<ul>
<li>We have consulted regularly with the Ministry of Health about COVID-19 risks, and we supplied Algeria with over 600,000 doses of the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine last year through COVAX.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>CLIMATE CHANGE</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Both Algeria and the United States understand the critical importance of working together to tackle climate change.</li>
</ul>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>On March 30, Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Algeria for meetings with President Abdelmadjid Tebboune and Foreign Minister Ramtane Lamamra to discuss regional security and stability, economic cooperation, and advancing human rights and fundamental freedoms.  The Secretary will promote America’s role as the Country of Honor at the Algiers International Trade Fair in June, the largest trade show of its kind in Africa.  He will meet with U.S. business representatives in Algeria to discuss deepening economic ties and promoting U.S.-Algeria trade and investment.</p>
<p><b>A DEEP AND LASTING RELATIONSHIP</b></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States and Algeria share a long history – from the 1795 Treaty of Peace and Amity to hosting negotiations to release American hostages from Tehran in 1981 – and our bilateral relationship continues to flourish.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Our security and counterterrorism cooperation remains a cornerstone of our bilateral relationship. We are also encouraged by the deepening economic and cultural ties between the United States and Algeria.  More and more U.S. companies are seeking investment in Algeria, and those already here are creating jobs across a wide range of sectors.  The fact that we are the country of honor at this year’s Algiers International Fair – the largest trade fair of its kind in Africa – demonstrates Algeria’s interest in American products and technology.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>BILATERAL AND REGIONAL POLITICAL ISSUES</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Earlier this month, Deputy Secretary Wendy Sherman and Foreign Minister Lamamra met in Algiers to express strong support for the efforts of Personal Envoy of the UN Secretary General Staffan de Mistura’s leadership in resuming the UN-led political process to advance a durable and dignified resolution to the conflict in Western Sahara that will create a peaceful and prosperous future for the people of Western Sahara and the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>We also agreed on the importance of regional stability for the entire Sahel and the need to counter the destabilizing presence of terrorist groups.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Our relationship is multifaceted.  We work closely with Algeria on counterterrorism and regional security, so that we can learn from one another and strengthen our respective security capabilities. Algeria hosted a Joint Military Dialogue March 14-15, during which we further discussed our commitment to regional security.</li>
<li>The United States and Algeria regularly discuss the importance of protecting and advancing human rights, including freedoms of expression and belief and the important role of independent media and civil society. Human rights are a central pillar of U.S. foreign policy.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>CULTURAL TIES AND EXCHANGES</b></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States shares strong cultural and economic relations with Algeria, which continue to improve at both the government-to-government and people-to-people levels. The OneBeat program in February and March featured 23 musicians from the United States, Algeria, and all of Algeria’s neighbors who created original music together in a three-week musical residency capped by two well-attended public concerts.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>There is no better indicator of the growing partnership between our two countries than our growing cultural ties. Algeria’s continued interest in English-language training and entrepreneurship are key areas where we are already working together.  We are pleased to have launched earlier this month two new programs that will strengthen U.S.-Algerian cooperation.  The State Department initiated the Link Project in Algeria to help 120 Algerian government officials improve their professional English language skills.  This will enable them to participate in international conferences and exchanges, communicate with international counterparts, and engage with English-language reports and other content.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The State Department is also working with the University of Notre Dame in Indiana to implement a three-year project to create a “research hub” to link Algerian research institutions in five key fields – artificial intelligence, applied mathematics, climate change and renewable energies, health and pharmaceutical sciences, and agriculture – with their American counterparts to facilitate the exchange of ideas and people. This project will build the research capacity of Algerian universities and create key linkages between Algerian researchers and the private sector.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>WESTERN SAHARA</b></p>
<ul>
<li>We strongly support the efforts of Staffan de Mistura, the Personal Envoy of the Secretary-General for Western Sahara.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>We are fully engaged diplomatically, in support of the UN and together with our international partners, to reinforce a credible political process leading to an enduring and dignified resolution.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>SAHEL</b></p>
<ul>
<li>We are both very concerned about the destabilizing presence of terrorist groups in the Sahel, and we both want security and prosperity in the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Algeria has played a key role in facilitating this stability through its mediation of the 2015 Algiers Peace Accord and continues to be a regional leader promoting resolution to ongoing conflicts.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>COVID-19 RESPONSE</b></p>
<ul>
<li>We have consulted regularly with the Ministry of Health about COVID-19 risks, and we supplied Algeria with over 600,000 doses of the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine last year through COVAX.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>CLIMATE CHANGE</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Both Algeria and the United States understand the critical importance of working together to tackle climate change.</li>
</ul>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with Khadija Ihsane of Medi 1 TV</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-khadija-ihsane-of-medi-1-tv/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 01:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329342</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rabat, Morocco</p>
<p>Dar Kika Salam</p>
<div>(Via Translation)</div>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Ladies and gentlemen, we are taking advantage of his whirlwind tour of the Middle East and North Africa to receive him for an exclusive interview with Medi 1.  We discussed various topics with the US Secretary of State, such as the goals and challenges of his visit to Morocco, the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, the Iranian nuclear agreement, and of course the war in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Hello, Antony Blinken.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Hello.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you for meeting with us here in Rabat, six years after the interview you agreed to grant to Medi 1 TV in June 2016.  You have just returned from an unprecedented summit held in the Negev desert in Israel, a little over a year after the Abraham Accords.  How did relations evolve after this summit, Mr.  Blinken?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>First of all, this is a pretty remarkable picture.  A picture that we could not have seen four, five years ago.  Not even two years ago.  We could not have seen the leaders of Morocco, Bahrain, the United Arab Emirates, Egypt, the United States, and Israel together in one picture.  And I think this reflects the desire to find the possibility to create together opportunities for the people of each country, because by creating trade links, links between students, between citizens, we will be able to focus together on issues that have an impact on everyday life, such as the investment, the infrastructure.</p>
<p>We are working together on the climate, on global health, and on security issues as well.  This is very powerful.  Of course, we are not setting aside the future of the Palestinian people and the need to also create a country for the Palestinians and try to invest in their future as well in the meantime.  So I think this is very powerful, but it also demonstrates, just like His Majesty the King said, a vision and the courage to no longer accept the barriers of the past, and in fact to overcome them and find a way to bring us together.  This is very powerful.</p>
<p>Lastly, what we are going to do together.  We talked about this in Negev yesterday, we will focus on concrete projects and on how to act together to meet the needs and desires of the people in each of our countries.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Mr. Secretary of State, can we say that today and after this summit in Negev, the relations between the United States and the Gulf countries are at their highest?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>We have partnerships that have existed for many years, and those partnerships are essential and important to us, not only in terms of security issues, but the future of our countries as well.  I think it was an important time as well to not only strengthen those partnerships, but to strengthen the idea that the United States is invested in those partnerships.  This is the message that I wanted to convey to my colleagues.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Very good.  Morocco is the third and penultimate leg of your tour, Mr.  Secretary of State.  It is undeniable that Morocco represents a strategic ally for the United States in the region today, both on security issues, as you so aptly mentioned, and on issues relating to the preservation of peace as well.  In your opinion, what is the role that Morocco is called upon to play in the future, both regionally and in Africa?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Morocco is first and foremost an essential partnership for us, and it has existed for a long time.  It is of the utmost importance to us because we obviously act on various issues bilaterally.  We act together at the regional level where Morocco’s voice and diplomacy have a very significant impact, whether in challenges such as in the Sahel, Libya, but also in Africa, West Africa for example, and what we can achieve together.</p>
<p>It also has an impact at the global level because we are working through this partnership on issues like the COVID pandemic.  Morocco has been very successful in the vaccination campaign for example, and we look at what we can learn, what we can achieve together across the world and in Africa.  Same goes for the climate, where Morocco has very advanced projects to manage what is really an existential dossier for everyone.  So what I see is a partnership that not only acts in the region, but more and more at the global level.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>You mentioned the Sahel.  The stability in the Sahara sub-region depends on the issue of the Moroccan Sahara.  I would like to quote a brief excerpt from the State Department statement on the purpose of your visit to Morocco.  I quote: “We reaffirm the importance of respect for the territorial integrity, sovereignty, and national unity of all member states of the United Nations.”  Knowing that the sovereignty of Morocco has been recognized by the United States, what are the potential future states in this matter today or rather tomorrow?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>We have discussed this issue today, just as we discuss it every time we meet.  We find Morocco’s autonomy plan to be a credible, serious, and realistic plan, and I believe that it can respond to the needs and aspirations of the people of Western Sahara.  The special envoy of the United Nations Secretary General Staffan de Mistura is conducting very important work, and we support him.  We discussed this issue today with my colleague and friend Nasser Bourita.  This is something that we will be following up on in the coming weeks.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>So in the near future.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>We are working on it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Very good.  A new ambassador has just been appointed.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>His Excellency Puneet Talwar.  What would be the roadmap in his new assignments in Morocco, Mr.  Blinken?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Puneet Talwar is the ambassador who was just nominated and he must be approved by the Senate, but I hope that will happen quickly.  He is a friend, a long-time friend, and we have worked together for 20 years.  He is very close to President Biden and worked on his staff when they were in the Senate.  So they worked together, and I know he will be an exceptional ambassador for the United States and that he will be exceptional for the ties between our two countries.  I trust him completely and President Biden trusts him completely.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>And based on your experience with Morocco, is there any advice you can give him?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>How fortunate.  How fortunate to come here to this remarkable country.  How fortunate to be here at a time when our work together is so important.  How fortunate to be here at a time when I see all kinds of possibilities to strengthen what we do together and even to broaden our horizons, in the Negev yesterday and across the world tomorrow.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>The next and final stop in your tour is our eastern neighbor, Algeria.  Given the current situation in Europe and the resulting energy issues, will Algerian gas, and particularly the gas pipeline, be part of the negotiations and discussions that you will have with the Algerian authorities?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Two things.  First, you mention the current situation in Europe, and that is very important because, initially, Russia’s aggression towards Ukraine is creating enormous suffering in Ukraine.  Half of the children in Ukraine are now displaced and had to flee their homes.  Therefore, what is happening is important at that level, but it is also important for two other reasons.</p>
<p>First, there are very important principles at stake, principles that support security and peace throughout the world, not only in Europe, but here as well.  When these principles are attacked as they are by Russia, it poses a problem for everyone.  The principle that a country cannot change the borders of another country by violence, that a country cannot decide for another regarding its policies and future – that is an issue.  But thirdly, we see an impact across the world.  We now have problems in food flows because of this Russian aggression in Ukraine, for the exports of agricultural products are now at stake.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Especially wheat on which many African countries depend, including Morocco.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Exactly, especially wheat.  Farmers in Ukraine are forced to either fight for their country or flee.  The harvest is not completed, and exports are blocked in the ports of south Ukraine.  This creates a problem across the world.  Energy prices are another problem.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>They are exploding.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>They are exploding.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Do you think it is maybe time to seek other alternatives to Russian gas for example, and maybe through the reopening of this Maghreb-Europe gas pipeline?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Europe is very focused on the idea that we now really need to diversify from Russian gas and oil, because Russia is now unfortunately using them as a policy tool.  That is mainly the problem, and it is obviously acting in a totally unacceptable way for everyone.  So I think when you talk to European countries, you know that they are very focused on the need to diversify.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>And the Americans would perhaps plead for this diversification, which would maybe come from these countries.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>A diversification that comes from everywhere in a way, including us.  But not only diversification.  The shift should also be done with a view to this fight for the climate.  This is also very important.  We need to make sure that, amid this diversification, we try to advance the climate issue so that we can prevent the world from getting warmer.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Rabat, Morocco</p>
<p>Dar Kika Salam</p>
<div>(Via Translation)</div>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Ladies and gentlemen, we are taking advantage of his whirlwind tour of the Middle East and North Africa to receive him for an exclusive interview with Medi 1.  We discussed various topics with the US Secretary of State, such as the goals and challenges of his visit to Morocco, the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, the Iranian nuclear agreement, and of course the war in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Hello, Antony Blinken.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Hello.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Thank you for meeting with us here in Rabat, six years after the interview you agreed to grant to Medi 1 TV in June 2016.  You have just returned from an unprecedented summit held in the Negev desert in Israel, a little over a year after the Abraham Accords.  How did relations evolve after this summit, Mr.  Blinken?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>First of all, this is a pretty remarkable picture.  A picture that we could not have seen four, five years ago.  Not even two years ago.  We could not have seen the leaders of Morocco, Bahrain, the United Arab Emirates, Egypt, the United States, and Israel together in one picture.  And I think this reflects the desire to find the possibility to create together opportunities for the people of each country, because by creating trade links, links between students, between citizens, we will be able to focus together on issues that have an impact on everyday life, such as the investment, the infrastructure.</p>
<p>We are working together on the climate, on global health, and on security issues as well.  This is very powerful.  Of course, we are not setting aside the future of the Palestinian people and the need to also create a country for the Palestinians and try to invest in their future as well in the meantime.  So I think this is very powerful, but it also demonstrates, just like His Majesty the King said, a vision and the courage to no longer accept the barriers of the past, and in fact to overcome them and find a way to bring us together.  This is very powerful.</p>
<p>Lastly, what we are going to do together.  We talked about this in Negev yesterday, we will focus on concrete projects and on how to act together to meet the needs and desires of the people in each of our countries.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Mr. Secretary of State, can we say that today and after this summit in Negev, the relations between the United States and the Gulf countries are at their highest?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>We have partnerships that have existed for many years, and those partnerships are essential and important to us, not only in terms of security issues, but the future of our countries as well.  I think it was an important time as well to not only strengthen those partnerships, but to strengthen the idea that the United States is invested in those partnerships.  This is the message that I wanted to convey to my colleagues.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Very good.  Morocco is the third and penultimate leg of your tour, Mr.  Secretary of State.  It is undeniable that Morocco represents a strategic ally for the United States in the region today, both on security issues, as you so aptly mentioned, and on issues relating to the preservation of peace as well.  In your opinion, what is the role that Morocco is called upon to play in the future, both regionally and in Africa?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Morocco is first and foremost an essential partnership for us, and it has existed for a long time.  It is of the utmost importance to us because we obviously act on various issues bilaterally.  We act together at the regional level where Morocco’s voice and diplomacy have a very significant impact, whether in challenges such as in the Sahel, Libya, but also in Africa, West Africa for example, and what we can achieve together.</p>
<p>It also has an impact at the global level because we are working through this partnership on issues like the COVID pandemic.  Morocco has been very successful in the vaccination campaign for example, and we look at what we can learn, what we can achieve together across the world and in Africa.  Same goes for the climate, where Morocco has very advanced projects to manage what is really an existential dossier for everyone.  So what I see is a partnership that not only acts in the region, but more and more at the global level.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>You mentioned the Sahel.  The stability in the Sahara sub-region depends on the issue of the Moroccan Sahara.  I would like to quote a brief excerpt from the State Department statement on the purpose of your visit to Morocco.  I quote: “We reaffirm the importance of respect for the territorial integrity, sovereignty, and national unity of all member states of the United Nations.”  Knowing that the sovereignty of Morocco has been recognized by the United States, what are the potential future states in this matter today or rather tomorrow?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>We have discussed this issue today, just as we discuss it every time we meet.  We find Morocco’s autonomy plan to be a credible, serious, and realistic plan, and I believe that it can respond to the needs and aspirations of the people of Western Sahara.  The special envoy of the United Nations Secretary General Staffan de Mistura is conducting very important work, and we support him.  We discussed this issue today with my colleague and friend Nasser Bourita.  This is something that we will be following up on in the coming weeks.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>So in the near future.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>We are working on it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Very good.  A new ambassador has just been appointed.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Yes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>His Excellency Puneet Talwar.  What would be the roadmap in his new assignments in Morocco, Mr.  Blinken?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Puneet Talwar is the ambassador who was just nominated and he must be approved by the Senate, but I hope that will happen quickly.  He is a friend, a long-time friend, and we have worked together for 20 years.  He is very close to President Biden and worked on his staff when they were in the Senate.  So they worked together, and I know he will be an exceptional ambassador for the United States and that he will be exceptional for the ties between our two countries.  I trust him completely and President Biden trusts him completely.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>And based on your experience with Morocco, is there any advice you can give him?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>How fortunate.  How fortunate to come here to this remarkable country.  How fortunate to be here at a time when our work together is so important.  How fortunate to be here at a time when I see all kinds of possibilities to strengthen what we do together and even to broaden our horizons, in the Negev yesterday and across the world tomorrow.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>The next and final stop in your tour is our eastern neighbor, Algeria.  Given the current situation in Europe and the resulting energy issues, will Algerian gas, and particularly the gas pipeline, be part of the negotiations and discussions that you will have with the Algerian authorities?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Two things.  First, you mention the current situation in Europe, and that is very important because, initially, Russia’s aggression towards Ukraine is creating enormous suffering in Ukraine.  Half of the children in Ukraine are now displaced and had to flee their homes.  Therefore, what is happening is important at that level, but it is also important for two other reasons.</p>
<p>First, there are very important principles at stake, principles that support security and peace throughout the world, not only in Europe, but here as well.  When these principles are attacked as they are by Russia, it poses a problem for everyone.  The principle that a country cannot change the borders of another country by violence, that a country cannot decide for another regarding its policies and future – that is an issue.  But thirdly, we see an impact across the world.  We now have problems in food flows because of this Russian aggression in Ukraine, for the exports of agricultural products are now at stake.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Especially wheat on which many African countries depend, including Morocco.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Exactly, especially wheat.  Farmers in Ukraine are forced to either fight for their country or flee.  The harvest is not completed, and exports are blocked in the ports of south Ukraine.  This creates a problem across the world.  Energy prices are another problem.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>They are exploding.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>They are exploding.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>Do you think it is maybe time to seek other alternatives to Russian gas for example, and maybe through the reopening of this Maghreb-Europe gas pipeline?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Europe is very focused on the idea that we now really need to diversify from Russian gas and oil, because Russia is now unfortunately using them as a policy tool.  That is mainly the problem, and it is obviously acting in a totally unacceptable way for everyone.  So I think when you talk to European countries, you know that they are very focused on the need to diversify.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:  </strong>And the Americans would perhaps plead for this diversification, which would maybe come from these countries.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>A diversification that comes from everywhere in a way, including us.  But not only diversification.  The shift should also be done with a view to this fight for the climate.  This is also very important.  We need to make sure that, amid this diversification, we try to advance the climate issue so that we can prevent the world from getting warmer.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Terrorist Attack in Bnei Brak </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/terrorist-attack-in-bnei-brak/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 23:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329331</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>We strongly condemn today’s terrorist attack in Bnei Brak, Israel, that killed five innocent victims.  This comes after two other recent horrific terrorist attacks in Hadera and Be’er Sheva, Israel.  This violence is unacceptable.  Israelis—like all people around the world—should be able to live in peace and without fear.  Our hearts go out to the families of those killed in the attacks.</p>
<p>May their memories be a blessing.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>We strongly condemn today’s terrorist attack in Bnei Brak, Israel, that killed five innocent victims.  This comes after two other recent horrific terrorist attacks in Hadera and Be’er Sheva, Israel.  This violence is unacceptable.  Israelis—like all people around the world—should be able to live in peace and without fear.  Our hearts go out to the families of those killed in the attacks.</p>
<p>May their memories be a blessing.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friends of Sudan Joint Statement on the UNITAMS-AU-IGAD Facilitated Political Process</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/friends-of-sudan-joint-statement-on-the-unitams-au-igad-facilitated-political-process/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 22:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Following is a joint statement on the UNITAMS-AU-IGAD Facilitated Political Process issued by Canada, France, Germany, Italy, the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, the Netherlands, Norway, Spain, Sweden, United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, the United States of America, and the European Union as members of the Friends of Sudan.</p>
<p>Begin text:</p>
<p>Canada, France, Germany, Italy, the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, the Netherlands, Norway, Spain, Sweden, United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, the United States of America, and the European Union as members of the Friends of Sudan reiterate our strong support for the combined efforts of the UN Integrated Transition Assistance Mission to Sudan (UNITAMS), the African Union (AU), and the Intergovernmental Authority on Development (IGAD) to facilitate a Sudanese-led political process with the aim of restoring a civilian-led transition to democracy. We applaud these actors’ ongoing efforts to consult with a broad range of Sudanese stakeholders. We look forward to the imminent launch of the next phase of the talks with the aim of building consensus around the structure of credible, civilian-led institutions that will lead Sudan through a revived civilian-led transition period, culminating in free and fair democratic elections. The urgency cannot be overstated. We, therefore, urge constructive engagement of all stakeholders in this next phase and underscore the importance of ensuring women, as well as youth, and other historically marginalized groups enjoy full, effective, and meaningful participation and inclusion throughout every stage of the process.</p>
<p>We welcome the progress made so far through the cooperation of Sudanese stakeholders and the combined efforts of UNITAMS, the AU, and IGAD. For this UNITAMS-AU-IGAD-facilitated political process to succeed, an enabling environment that allows all stakeholders to participate and freely express their views must be created, and Sudanese citizens must be protected from all kinds of violence. We welcome the commitments of the Sudanese authorities in this regard and encourage their implementation. Full respect for freedoms of association, expression, and peaceful assembly is vital, as is protection of property.</p>
<p>We are deeply concerned by the immense economic pressures currently facing the Sudanese people and are committed to continuing to provide direct, humanitarian support to them during this difficult period. We look forward to the restoration of a credible transitional government agreed through the UNITAMS-AU-IGAD-facilitated political process, which would pave the way to restore economic assistance and international debt relief.</p>
<p>As members of the Friends of Sudan, we continue to endorse the Sudanese-led political process facilitated by UNITAMS, the AU, and IGAD as the best vehicle to realize the Sudanese people’s aspirations for freedom, peace, and justice and to restore Sudan’s democratic transition. We continue to pledge our full support to the Sudanese people and this process.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Following is a joint statement on the UNITAMS-AU-IGAD Facilitated Political Process issued by Canada, France, Germany, Italy, the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, the Netherlands, Norway, Spain, Sweden, United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, the United States of America, and the European Union as members of the Friends of Sudan.</p>
<p>Begin text:</p>
<p>Canada, France, Germany, Italy, the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, the Netherlands, Norway, Spain, Sweden, United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, the United States of America, and the European Union as members of the Friends of Sudan reiterate our strong support for the combined efforts of the UN Integrated Transition Assistance Mission to Sudan (UNITAMS), the African Union (AU), and the Intergovernmental Authority on Development (IGAD) to facilitate a Sudanese-led political process with the aim of restoring a civilian-led transition to democracy. We applaud these actors’ ongoing efforts to consult with a broad range of Sudanese stakeholders. We look forward to the imminent launch of the next phase of the talks with the aim of building consensus around the structure of credible, civilian-led institutions that will lead Sudan through a revived civilian-led transition period, culminating in free and fair democratic elections. The urgency cannot be overstated. We, therefore, urge constructive engagement of all stakeholders in this next phase and underscore the importance of ensuring women, as well as youth, and other historically marginalized groups enjoy full, effective, and meaningful participation and inclusion throughout every stage of the process.</p>
<p>We welcome the progress made so far through the cooperation of Sudanese stakeholders and the combined efforts of UNITAMS, the AU, and IGAD. For this UNITAMS-AU-IGAD-facilitated political process to succeed, an enabling environment that allows all stakeholders to participate and freely express their views must be created, and Sudanese citizens must be protected from all kinds of violence. We welcome the commitments of the Sudanese authorities in this regard and encourage their implementation. Full respect for freedoms of association, expression, and peaceful assembly is vital, as is protection of property.</p>
<p>We are deeply concerned by the immense economic pressures currently facing the Sudanese people and are committed to continuing to provide direct, humanitarian support to them during this difficult period. We look forward to the restoration of a credible transitional government agreed through the UNITAMS-AU-IGAD-facilitated political process, which would pave the way to restore economic assistance and international debt relief.</p>
<p>As members of the Friends of Sudan, we continue to endorse the Sudanese-led political process facilitated by UNITAMS, the AU, and IGAD as the best vehicle to realize the Sudanese people’s aspirations for freedom, peace, and justice and to restore Sudan’s democratic transition. We continue to pledge our full support to the Sudanese people and this process.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman in Response to Russia at a UN Security Council Briefing on the Humanitarian Impact of Russia&#8217;s War Against Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/remarks-by-deputy-secretary-of-state-wendy-sherman-in-response-to-russia-at-a-un-security-council-briefing-on-the-humanitarian-impact-of-russias-war-against-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 22:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329311</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State</p>
<p>Thank you very much and thank you for giving me this opportunity today. Much appreciated, Madam President. I feel that I must make four critical points.</p>
<p>First, I want to be clear that the conflict that is being suffered by the Ukrainian people is not about the Russian Federation versus the West. One hundred and forty countries, just last week, spoke in support of ending this conflict and the need to end this humanitarian crisis. A hundred and forty-one countries supported the initial resolution in the UN General Assembly, to say that this invasion by Russia should stop.</p>
<p>So, with all due respect, Mr. Ambassador, this is not about Russia versus the West. This is about the support of the UN Charter and the principles of sovereignty, territorial integrity, and the right of all countries – all countries – to choose their political orientation and their foreign policy.</p>
<p>Second, I myself was engaged directly with Russian counterparts to find a peaceful way forward to meet the concerns of the Russian Federation. I sat opposite Russian counterparts and put on the table many options to address the concerns. We provided, as does NATO, a paper of very specific ways in which we could address, reciprocally and mutually, security concerns. President Putin chose an invasion, not diplomacy.</p>
<p>Third, with all due respect, Mr. Ambassador, as a Jewish American, I cannot help but say this is not about Nazis in Ukraine. Last week, former U.S. Secretary of State, and former Permanent Representative to this Council, and one of my most cherished personal friends, Madeleine Albright died. She loved representing the United States here. She would have been outraged by the words of the Russian Federation today.</p>
<p>Later in her life, she learned that her parents raised her as Catholic to protect her from the Nazis because her family was Jewish. She learned that three of her grandparents died at the hands of the Nazis, while in concentration camps. She knew that the Jewish President of Ukraine was certainly not a Nazi. And that the citizens of Ukraine being slaughtered and starving, and without food and medicine, and the subject of this humanitarian dialogue today, are not and never were Nazis.</p>
<p>And finally, this dialogue today is about the humanitarian needs of Ukrainian civilians and humanitarian needs of people around the world, who as David Beasley said so eloquently, “feeding hungry children, to feeding starving children.” It&#8217;s about, as he said, “going from a breadbasket to a breadline.”</p>
<p>We must all do whatever we can, of course, to stop war. But there is an easy choice here. And it is a choice that can be made today in Istanbul, by President Putin, and that is to stop the war. So let us all, over 140 countries around the world, continue to stand with Ukraine.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wendy R. Sherman, Deputy Secretary of State</p>
<p>Thank you very much and thank you for giving me this opportunity today. Much appreciated, Madam President. I feel that I must make four critical points.</p>
<p>First, I want to be clear that the conflict that is being suffered by the Ukrainian people is not about the Russian Federation versus the West. One hundred and forty countries, just last week, spoke in support of ending this conflict and the need to end this humanitarian crisis. A hundred and forty-one countries supported the initial resolution in the UN General Assembly, to say that this invasion by Russia should stop.</p>
<p>So, with all due respect, Mr. Ambassador, this is not about Russia versus the West. This is about the support of the UN Charter and the principles of sovereignty, territorial integrity, and the right of all countries – all countries – to choose their political orientation and their foreign policy.</p>
<p>Second, I myself was engaged directly with Russian counterparts to find a peaceful way forward to meet the concerns of the Russian Federation. I sat opposite Russian counterparts and put on the table many options to address the concerns. We provided, as does NATO, a paper of very specific ways in which we could address, reciprocally and mutually, security concerns. President Putin chose an invasion, not diplomacy.</p>
<p>Third, with all due respect, Mr. Ambassador, as a Jewish American, I cannot help but say this is not about Nazis in Ukraine. Last week, former U.S. Secretary of State, and former Permanent Representative to this Council, and one of my most cherished personal friends, Madeleine Albright died. She loved representing the United States here. She would have been outraged by the words of the Russian Federation today.</p>
<p>Later in her life, she learned that her parents raised her as Catholic to protect her from the Nazis because her family was Jewish. She learned that three of her grandparents died at the hands of the Nazis, while in concentration camps. She knew that the Jewish President of Ukraine was certainly not a Nazi. And that the citizens of Ukraine being slaughtered and starving, and without food and medicine, and the subject of this humanitarian dialogue today, are not and never were Nazis.</p>
<p>And finally, this dialogue today is about the humanitarian needs of Ukrainian civilians and humanitarian needs of people around the world, who as David Beasley said so eloquently, “feeding hungry children, to feeding starving children.” It&#8217;s about, as he said, “going from a breadbasket to a breadline.”</p>
<p>We must all do whatever we can, of course, to stop war. But there is an easy choice here. And it is a choice that can be made today in Istanbul, by President Putin, and that is to stop the war. So let us all, over 140 countries around the world, continue to stand with Ukraine.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed  </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-crown-prince-of-abu-dhabi-sheikh-mohammed-bin-zayed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 22:43:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329300</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with the Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi, Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, in Rabat, Morocco.  The Secretary reaffirmed the countries’ close partnership and reviewed ways to broaden and deepen wide-ranging cooperation. The Secretary underscored that we remain committed to helping the UAE defend itself against threats stemming from Yemen and elsewhere in the region.  He welcomed the UAE&#8217;s support for a truce leading to a ceasefire in Yemen and reiterated that the only path to a durable peace is through dialogue and diplomacy.  They also discussed President Putin&#8217;s unjustified war against the people of Ukraine as well as the conflict in Syria.  The Secretary again commended the UAE’s progress on normalization with Israel through the Abraham Accords and noted that he looks forward to working with the UAE and other partners on the initiatives conceived during the Negev Summit.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken thanked the Crown Prince for the UAE’s generous support in hosting and facilitating the safe transit of people from Afghanistan and commended the UAE for providing humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan as well as to Ukraine.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with the Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi, Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, in Rabat, Morocco.  The Secretary reaffirmed the countries’ close partnership and reviewed ways to broaden and deepen wide-ranging cooperation. The Secretary underscored that we remain committed to helping the UAE defend itself against threats stemming from Yemen and elsewhere in the region.  He welcomed the UAE&#8217;s support for a truce leading to a ceasefire in Yemen and reiterated that the only path to a durable peace is through dialogue and diplomacy.  They also discussed President Putin&#8217;s unjustified war against the people of Ukraine as well as the conflict in Syria.  The Secretary again commended the UAE’s progress on normalization with Israel through the Abraham Accords and noted that he looks forward to working with the UAE and other partners on the initiatives conceived during the Negev Summit.</p>
<p>Secretary Blinken thanked the Crown Prince for the UAE’s generous support in hosting and facilitating the safe transit of people from Afghanistan and commended the UAE for providing humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan as well as to Ukraine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Support of Partners Expelling Russian Intelligence Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/support-of-partners-expelling-russian-intelligence-officials/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 21:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329280</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States applauds recent expulsions of Russian intelligence officers by our partners in Europe and around the world.  As our partners have outlined, these actions are in response to these individuals&#8217; activities, which are in contravention of their diplomatic status, and the Russian Federation’s aggression in Ukraine.</p>
<p>We stand unified with our partners in protecting their national security from the Russian Federation’s intelligence threats and against threats to democracy.  We continue our united support of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>The United States is committed to working with our Allies and partners to keep pressure on the Russian Federation and protect our common national interests from the Russian Federation’s actions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States applauds recent expulsions of Russian intelligence officers by our partners in Europe and around the world.  As our partners have outlined, these actions are in response to these individuals&#8217; activities, which are in contravention of their diplomatic status, and the Russian Federation’s aggression in Ukraine.</p>
<p>We stand unified with our partners in protecting their national security from the Russian Federation’s intelligence threats and against threats to democracy.  We continue our united support of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>The United States is committed to working with our Allies and partners to keep pressure on the Russian Federation and protect our common national interests from the Russian Federation’s actions.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Moroccan Prime Minister Akhannouch   </title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-moroccan-prime-minister-akhannouch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 21:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=329277</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Moroccan Prime Minister Aziz Akhannouch in Rabat. The Secretary thanked the Prime Minister for his and his government&#8217;s hospitality, and they engaged in a wide-ranging discussion regarding bilateral, regional, and international priorities, including the effort to combat the COVID-19 pandemic and the climate crisis. They also discussed King Mohammed VI’s reform agenda and the economic and social challenges Morocco faces. The Secretary remarked on the successes of the five-year, $460 million compact administered by the U.S. Millennium Challenge Corporation and focused on expanding opportunities for people across the Kingdom. They also reviewed our strong economic ties and discussed how we can deepen them. Across all of these efforts, the Secretary noted the importance of advancing human rights and fundamental freedoms, including freedom of expression, in line with Morocco’s international commitments.</p>
<p>The Secretary emphasized the need for President Putin to end his war against the people of Ukraine, which is having tangible implications on the region, including higher food, commodity, and energy prices. The Secretary pledged the United States&#8217; continued support for the Kingdom and its people.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today with Moroccan Prime Minister Aziz Akhannouch in Rabat. The Secretary thanked the Prime Minister for his and his government&#8217;s hospitality, and they engaged in a wide-ranging discussion regarding bilateral, regional, and international priorities, including the effort to combat the COVID-19 pandemic and the climate crisis. They also discussed King Mohammed VI’s reform agenda and the economic and social challenges Morocco faces. The Secretary remarked on the successes of the five-year, $460 million compact administered by the U.S. Millennium Challenge Corporation and focused on expanding opportunities for people across the Kingdom. They also reviewed our strong economic ties and discussed how we can deepen them. Across all of these efforts, the Secretary noted the importance of advancing human rights and fundamental freedoms, including freedom of expression, in line with Morocco’s international commitments.</p>
<p>The Secretary emphasized the need for President Putin to end his war against the people of Ukraine, which is having tangible implications on the region, including higher food, commodity, and energy prices. The Secretary pledged the United States&#8217; continued support for the Kingdom and its people.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
