<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 22:23:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Qatari Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Foreign Affairs Al-Thani</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-qatari-deputy-prime-minister-and-minister-of-foreign-affairs-al-thani/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 22:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261449</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today in Washington D.C. with Qatari Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Foreign Affairs Mohammed bin Abdulrahman Al-Thani to discuss regional security issues, Qatar’s generous pledge of in-kind assistance to the Lebanese Armed Forces, its $100 million contribution to Yemen through the World Food Program, and support for Afghanistan peace negotiations.  The Secretary highlighted the importance of our strategic partnership and our shared commitment to promoting peace and security.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today in Washington D.C. with Qatari Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Foreign Affairs Mohammed bin Abdulrahman Al-Thani to discuss regional security issues, Qatar’s generous pledge of in-kind assistance to the Lebanese Armed Forces, its $100 million contribution to Yemen through the World Food Program, and support for Afghanistan peace negotiations.  The Secretary highlighted the importance of our strategic partnership and our shared commitment to promoting peace and security.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken And Qatari Minister of Foreign Affairs and Deputy Prime Minister Mohammed bin Abdulrahman Al-Thani Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-qatari-minister-of-foreign-affairs-and-deputy-prime-minister-mohammed-bin-abdulrahman-al-thani-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 21:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261437</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Ben Franklin Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you very much.  Good afternoon, everyone.  It is a real pleasure to have Foreign Minister Al-Thani here at the State Department and in Washington. Qatar is a vital partner for the United States in so many different areas: of course, hosting about 12,000 of our service members, a strong economic partner; but beyond that, really a partner in trying to advance peace, trying to advance progress in the region, and of course, to stand against terrorism – a vital ally in the effort against ISIS, hosting intra-Afghan talks, and, of course, working with us, working with Israel, the Palestinians to support people in Gaza.</p>
<p>So I’m grateful to you, Mohammed, for the work that we’re doing together every single day, and very pleased to have you here.  We have a lot to talk about.  Welcome.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY PRIME MINISTER AL-THANI:  </strong>Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  I look forward for our discussion.  Thank you for hosting us here at the State Department.  It&#8217;s an honor for me to be – to meet with you the first time in D.C., but not the first time since you became Secretary of State.  But I really look forward for our discussion that will actually help in advancing this relationship between our two countries.  The relationship between Qatar and the U.S. has been, for decades, nothing but growing.  And we really look forward that our discussion will contribute to the growth of this relationship in advancing peace and security in the region, in helping in mediating some of the conflicts that will help with the stability of the region, cooperating also on other development project to help other countries as well.</p>
<p>So I really look forward for that discussion, Mr. Secretary.  And thank you very much for having us here.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Great to have you.</p>
<p>Thanks, everyone.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Ben Franklin Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you very much.  Good afternoon, everyone.  It is a real pleasure to have Foreign Minister Al-Thani here at the State Department and in Washington. Qatar is a vital partner for the United States in so many different areas: of course, hosting about 12,000 of our service members, a strong economic partner; but beyond that, really a partner in trying to advance peace, trying to advance progress in the region, and of course, to stand against terrorism – a vital ally in the effort against ISIS, hosting intra-Afghan talks, and, of course, working with us, working with Israel, the Palestinians to support people in Gaza.</p>
<p>So I’m grateful to you, Mohammed, for the work that we’re doing together every single day, and very pleased to have you here.  We have a lot to talk about.  Welcome.</p>
<p><strong>DEPUTY PRIME MINISTER AL-THANI:  </strong>Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  I look forward for our discussion.  Thank you for hosting us here at the State Department.  It&#8217;s an honor for me to be – to meet with you the first time in D.C., but not the first time since you became Secretary of State.  But I really look forward for our discussion that will actually help in advancing this relationship between our two countries.  The relationship between Qatar and the U.S. has been, for decades, nothing but growing.  And we really look forward that our discussion will contribute to the growth of this relationship in advancing peace and security in the region, in helping in mediating some of the conflicts that will help with the stability of the region, cooperating also on other development project to help other countries as well.</p>
<p>So I really look forward for that discussion, Mr. Secretary.  And thank you very much for having us here.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Great to have you.</p>
<p>Thanks, everyone.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sanctioning Cuban Security Forces in Response to Violent Repression of Protests</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/sanctioning-cuban-security-forces-in-response-to-violent-repression-of-protests/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 18:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261360</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Starting on July 11, tens of thousands of Cubans in dozens of cities and towns throughout their country took to the streets to peacefully demand respect for their fundamental freedoms and a better future. In response, the Cuban regime violently repressed the protests, arresting hundreds of demonstrators simply for exercising their human rights of freedom of expression and peaceful assembly. The actions of Cuban security forces and violent mobs mobilized by Cuban Communist Party First Secretary Miguel Diaz-Canel lay bare the regime’s fear of its own people and unwillingness to meet their basic needs and aspirations.</p>
<p>Today, the United States is imposing sanctions on Minister of the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Cuba Álvaro López Miera and the Cuban Ministry of the Interior’s Special National Brigade or “Boinas Negras” (Black Berets). López Miera and the Special National Brigade have been involved in suppressing the protests, including through physical violence and intimidation. We take this action pursuant to Executive Order 13818, which builds upon and implements the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act.</p>
<p>We stand with every Cuban seeking a government that respects the human rights and dignity of the Cuban people. We will continue to take action to promote accountability for the Cuban government’s human rights abuses, including through additional sanctions pursuant to Global Magnitsky, as appropriate.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Starting on July 11, tens of thousands of Cubans in dozens of cities and towns throughout their country took to the streets to peacefully demand respect for their fundamental freedoms and a better future. In response, the Cuban regime violently repressed the protests, arresting hundreds of demonstrators simply for exercising their human rights of freedom of expression and peaceful assembly. The actions of Cuban security forces and violent mobs mobilized by Cuban Communist Party First Secretary Miguel Diaz-Canel lay bare the regime’s fear of its own people and unwillingness to meet their basic needs and aspirations.</p>
<p>Today, the United States is imposing sanctions on Minister of the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Cuba Álvaro López Miera and the Cuban Ministry of the Interior’s Special National Brigade or “Boinas Negras” (Black Berets). López Miera and the Special National Brigade have been involved in suppressing the protests, including through physical violence and intimidation. We take this action pursuant to Executive Order 13818, which builds upon and implements the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act.</p>
<p>We stand with every Cuban seeking a government that respects the human rights and dignity of the Cuban people. We will continue to take action to promote accountability for the Cuban government’s human rights abuses, including through additional sanctions pursuant to Global Magnitsky, as appropriate.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Haitian Prime Minister Henry</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-haitian-prime-minister-henry/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 18:10:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261353</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Haitian Prime Minister Dr. Ariel Henry today. Secretary Blinken reiterated the United States’ commitment to supporting the Haitian people following the heinous assassination of President Jovenel Moïse. The Secretary also underscored the need for Prime Minister Henry’s unity government to seek broad political and civil society consensus on government priorities. Secretary Blinken, echoing the international community, emphasized the importance of establishing the conditions necessary for Haitians to vote in free and fair legislative and presidential elections as soon as feasible.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Haitian Prime Minister Dr. Ariel Henry today. Secretary Blinken reiterated the United States’ commitment to supporting the Haitian people following the heinous assassination of President Jovenel Moïse. The Secretary also underscored the need for Prime Minister Henry’s unity government to seek broad political and civil society consensus on government priorities. Secretary Blinken, echoing the international community, emphasized the importance of establishing the conditions necessary for Haitians to vote in free and fair legislative and presidential elections as soon as feasible.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States and Rwanda Host Peacekeeping Ministerial Preparatory Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-and-rwanda-host-peacekeeping-ministerial-preparatory-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 16:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261317</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States and the Government of Rwanda virtually hosted on July 21-22 members of the UN General Assembly Special Committee on Peacekeeping (known as the C-34) for a preparatory meeting focused on capacity-building partnerships ahead of the December 2021 UN Peacekeeping Ministerial in Seoul, Korea.</p>
<p>The U.S.-Rwanda preparatory meeting highlighted the significant contribution that capacity-building partnerships can make in enhancing peacekeeping performance and effectiveness.  The meeting also underscored the importance of partnership-focused pledges at the upcoming UN Peacekeeping Ministerial.</p>
<p>U.S. Representative to the UN Ambassador Linda Thomas-Greenfield, IO Acting Assistant Secretary for International Organization Affairs Erica Barks-Ruggles, and Acting Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for Political Military Affairs Stan Brown reiterated the U.S. commitment to UN peacekeeping, including through capacity-building programs like the U.S. Global Peace Operations Initiative (GPOI) and the International Police Peacekeeping Operations Support program.</p>
<p>Panelists from troop- and police-contributing countries shared their experiences with forming effective capacity-building partnerships.  Leaders from the UN Department of Peace Operations and from UN peacekeeping missions discussed UN efforts to identify and meet the requirements of complex, multidimensional peacekeeping missions.</p>
<p>The United States has long been the largest financial contributor to UN peacekeeping, providing more than a quarter of UN peacekeeping funds, contributing almost twice as much as the second largest contributor.  The United States is also the world’s leading bilateral partner for peacekeeping capacity-building assistance, which enhances peacekeeper performance and accountability.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States and the Government of Rwanda virtually hosted on July 21-22 members of the UN General Assembly Special Committee on Peacekeeping (known as the C-34) for a preparatory meeting focused on capacity-building partnerships ahead of the December 2021 UN Peacekeeping Ministerial in Seoul, Korea.</p>
<p>The U.S.-Rwanda preparatory meeting highlighted the significant contribution that capacity-building partnerships can make in enhancing peacekeeping performance and effectiveness.  The meeting also underscored the importance of partnership-focused pledges at the upcoming UN Peacekeeping Ministerial.</p>
<p>U.S. Representative to the UN Ambassador Linda Thomas-Greenfield, IO Acting Assistant Secretary for International Organization Affairs Erica Barks-Ruggles, and Acting Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for Political Military Affairs Stan Brown reiterated the U.S. commitment to UN peacekeeping, including through capacity-building programs like the U.S. Global Peace Operations Initiative (GPOI) and the International Police Peacekeeping Operations Support program.</p>
<p>Panelists from troop- and police-contributing countries shared their experiences with forming effective capacity-building partnerships.  Leaders from the UN Department of Peace Operations and from UN peacekeeping missions discussed UN efforts to identify and meet the requirements of complex, multidimensional peacekeeping missions.</p>
<p>The United States has long been the largest financial contributor to UN peacekeeping, providing more than a quarter of UN peacekeeping funds, contributing almost twice as much as the second largest contributor.  The United States is also the world’s leading bilateral partner for peacekeeping capacity-building assistance, which enhances peacekeeper performance and accountability.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement by Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken and Treasury Secretary Janet L. Yellen Commending the United Kingdom’s Anti-Corruption Sanctions</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-by-secretary-of-state-antony-j-blinken-and-treasury-secretary-janet-l-yellen-commending-the-united-kingdoms-anti-corruption-sanctions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 14:12:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261277</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Begin text:</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the United Kingdom’s announcement today to impose further sanctions under its Global Anti-Corruption Sanctions (GACS) regime, which is designed to fight corruption and illicit finance. We commend the UK’s actions today against four corrupt individuals already designated by the United States and a fifth whose U.S.-based assets purchased with corrupt proceeds were successfully forfeited in U.S. courts.</p>
<p>Corruption has a corrosive effect on society: it undermines democratic institutions, hinders economic development, drains the wealth of nations, and keeps people in poverty. The United States is committed to working with, and supporting, our partners and allies in the fight against corruption. Today’s action by the United Kingdom is an important step in this effort.</p>
<p>Sanctions regimes such as the UK’s GACS and the U.S. Global Magnitsky sanctions program promote accountability for corrupt actors and help limit their access to the international financial system. Effective implementation of our programs can break the cycle of poor governance and poverty sustained by corruption, while supporting global efforts to address systematic vulnerabilities.</p>
<p>The United States will continue working with the United Kingdom and other likeminded allies and partners to impose tangible and significant consequences on those who engage in corruption, as well as to protect the global financial system.</p>
<p>End text.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Begin text:</p>
<p>The United States welcomes the United Kingdom’s announcement today to impose further sanctions under its Global Anti-Corruption Sanctions (GACS) regime, which is designed to fight corruption and illicit finance. We commend the UK’s actions today against four corrupt individuals already designated by the United States and a fifth whose U.S.-based assets purchased with corrupt proceeds were successfully forfeited in U.S. courts.</p>
<p>Corruption has a corrosive effect on society: it undermines democratic institutions, hinders economic development, drains the wealth of nations, and keeps people in poverty. The United States is committed to working with, and supporting, our partners and allies in the fight against corruption. Today’s action by the United Kingdom is an important step in this effort.</p>
<p>Sanctions regimes such as the UK’s GACS and the U.S. Global Magnitsky sanctions program promote accountability for corrupt actors and help limit their access to the international financial system. Effective implementation of our programs can break the cycle of poor governance and poverty sustained by corruption, while supporting global efforts to address systematic vulnerabilities.</p>
<p>The United States will continue working with the United Kingdom and other likeminded allies and partners to impose tangible and significant consequences on those who engage in corruption, as well as to protect the global financial system.</p>
<p>End text.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Announcement of Daniel Foote as Special Envoy for Haiti</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/announcement-of-daniel-foote-as-special-envoy-for-haiti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 12:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261232</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department of State is pleased to announce that Ambassador Daniel Foote, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, will serve as its Special Envoy for Haiti. The Special Envoy will engage with Haitian and international partners to facilitate long-term peace and stability and support efforts to hold free and fair presidential and legislative elections. He will also work with partners to coordinate assistance efforts in several areas, including humanitarian, security, and investigative assistance. Additionally, the Special Envoy will engage stakeholders in civil society and the private sector as we pursue Haitian-led solutions to the many pressing challenges facing Haiti.</p>
<p>The Special Envoy will, along with the U.S. Ambassador to Haiti, lead U.S. diplomatic efforts and coordinate the effort of U.S. federal agencies in Haiti from Washington, advise the Secretary and Acting Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs, and coordinate closely with the National Security Council staff on the administration’s efforts to support the Haitian people and Haiti’s democratic institutions in the aftermath of the tragic assassination of Jovenel Moïse.</p>
<p>Special Envoy Foote brings extensive diplomatic experience to this role – including as Deputy Chief of Mission in Haiti and as the U.S. Ambassador to Zambia. The Department congratulates Special Envoy Foote as he takes on his new role and thanks him for his continued service to his country.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The Department of State is pleased to announce that Ambassador Daniel Foote, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, will serve as its Special Envoy for Haiti. The Special Envoy will engage with Haitian and international partners to facilitate long-term peace and stability and support efforts to hold free and fair presidential and legislative elections. He will also work with partners to coordinate assistance efforts in several areas, including humanitarian, security, and investigative assistance. Additionally, the Special Envoy will engage stakeholders in civil society and the private sector as we pursue Haitian-led solutions to the many pressing challenges facing Haiti.</p>
<p>The Special Envoy will, along with the U.S. Ambassador to Haiti, lead U.S. diplomatic efforts and coordinate the effort of U.S. federal agencies in Haiti from Washington, advise the Secretary and Acting Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs, and coordinate closely with the National Security Council staff on the administration’s efforts to support the Haitian people and Haiti’s democratic institutions in the aftermath of the tragic assassination of Jovenel Moïse.</p>
<p>Special Envoy Foote brings extensive diplomatic experience to this role – including as Deputy Chief of Mission in Haiti and as the U.S. Ambassador to Zambia. The Department congratulates Special Envoy Foote as he takes on his new role and thanks him for his continued service to his country.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Republic of Korea Foreign Minister Chung</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-republic-of-korea-foreign-minister-chung/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 12:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman met with Republic of Korea (ROK) Foreign Minister Chung Eui-yong in Seoul today.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Chung emphasized the importance of the U.S.-ROK Alliance in achieving our shared vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific, anchored by transparency, respect for human rights, democracy, and the rule of law.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Chung discussed their commitment to the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. The Deputy Secretary expressed U.S. support for efforts to improve inter-Korean relations. The Deputy Secretary and the Foreign Minister also reaffirmed that diplomacy and dialogue are essential to achieving complete denuclearization of and establishing permanent peace on the Korean peninsula. They highlighted the importance of U.S.-ROK-Japan cooperation in addressing the global threats posed by COVID-19 and the climate crisis, and in resisting challenges to the free and open rules-based international order. They discussed efforts to support the people of Burma in promoting a return to democracy.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman met with Republic of Korea (ROK) Foreign Minister Chung Eui-yong in Seoul today.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Chung emphasized the importance of the U.S.-ROK Alliance in achieving our shared vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific, anchored by transparency, respect for human rights, democracy, and the rule of law.  Deputy Secretary Sherman and Foreign Minister Chung discussed their commitment to the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. The Deputy Secretary expressed U.S. support for efforts to improve inter-Korean relations. The Deputy Secretary and the Foreign Minister also reaffirmed that diplomacy and dialogue are essential to achieving complete denuclearization of and establishing permanent peace on the Korean peninsula. They highlighted the importance of U.S.-ROK-Japan cooperation in addressing the global threats posed by COVID-19 and the climate crisis, and in resisting challenges to the free and open rules-based international order. They discussed efforts to support the people of Burma in promoting a return to democracy.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Republic of Korea Minister of Unification Lee and Republic of Korea Vice Minister of Unification Choi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-republic-of-korea-minister-of-unification-lee-and-republic-of-korea-vice-minister-of-unification-choi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 12:21:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman met with Republic of Korea Minister of Unification Lee In-young and Republic of Korea Vice Minister of Unification Choi Young-joon in Seoul today.  Deputy Secretary Sherman, Minister Lee, and Vice Minister Choi emphasized their shared commitment to the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  The Deputy Secretary also expressed U.S. support for inter-Korean dialogue and engagement.  Deputy Secretary Sherman, Minister Lee, and Vice Minister Choi reaffirmed that diplomacy and dialogue are essential to achieving complete denuclearization and to establishing permanent peace on the Korean Peninsula.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy R. Sherman met with Republic of Korea Minister of Unification Lee In-young and Republic of Korea Vice Minister of Unification Choi Young-joon in Seoul today.  Deputy Secretary Sherman, Minister Lee, and Vice Minister Choi emphasized their shared commitment to the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.  The Deputy Secretary also expressed U.S. support for inter-Korean dialogue and engagement.  Deputy Secretary Sherman, Minister Lee, and Vice Minister Choi reaffirmed that diplomacy and dialogue are essential to achieving complete denuclearization and to establishing permanent peace on the Korean Peninsula.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Public Schedule &#8211; July 22, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/public-schedule-july-22-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=261102</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>                                          ***THE DAILY PUBLIC SCHEDULE IS SUBJECT TO CHANGE***</strong></p>
<p><strong><u>SECRETARY ANTONY J. BLINKEN</u></strong></p>
<p><strong>4:00 p.m. </strong>Secretary Blinken meets with Qatari Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Foreign Affairs Mohammed bin Abdulrahman Al-Thani, at the Department of State.<br />
<strong>(POOLED CAMERA SPRAY AT THE TOP)<br />
</strong><em>The camera spray will be live streamed on </em><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/statevideo"><em>https://www.youtube.com/user/statevideo</em></a><em>. </em></p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY WENDY R. SHERMAN</u></strong><br />
Deputy Secretary Sherman is on travel to Japan, Republic of Korea, and Mongolia from July 18-25, 2021. Please click <a href="https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-travel-to-japan-the-republic-of-korea-and-mongolia/">here</a> for more information.</p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY FOR MANAGEMENT AND RESOURCES BRIAN P. MCKEON<br />
</u></strong>Deputy Secretary McKeon attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>UNDER SECRETARY FOR POLITICAL AFFAIRS VICTORIA J. NULAND<br />
</u></strong>Under Secretary Nuland attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>BRIEFING SCHEDULE<br />
</u></strong><strong>2:00 p.m. </strong>Department Press Briefing with Spokesperson Ned Price.<br />
<strong>(POOLED PRESS COVERAGE)<br />
</strong><em>The Department Press Briefing will be live streamed on </em><a style="background-color: #ffffff;" href="http://www.state.gov"><em>www.state.gov</em></a><em>.</em></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><strong>                                          ***THE DAILY PUBLIC SCHEDULE IS SUBJECT TO CHANGE***</strong></p>
<p><strong><u>SECRETARY ANTONY J. BLINKEN</u></strong></p>
<p><strong>4:00 p.m. </strong>Secretary Blinken meets with Qatari Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Foreign Affairs Mohammed bin Abdulrahman Al-Thani, at the Department of State.<br />
<strong>(POOLED CAMERA SPRAY AT THE TOP)<br />
</strong><em>The camera spray will be live streamed on </em><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/statevideo"><em>https://www.youtube.com/user/statevideo</em></a><em>. </em></p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY WENDY R. SHERMAN</u></strong><br />
Deputy Secretary Sherman is on travel to Japan, Republic of Korea, and Mongolia from July 18-25, 2021. Please click <a href="https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-travel-to-japan-the-republic-of-korea-and-mongolia/">here</a> for more information.</p>
<p><strong><u>DEPUTY SECRETARY FOR MANAGEMENT AND RESOURCES BRIAN P. MCKEON<br />
</u></strong>Deputy Secretary McKeon attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>UNDER SECRETARY FOR POLITICAL AFFAIRS VICTORIA J. NULAND<br />
</u></strong>Under Secretary Nuland attends meetings and briefings, from the Department of State.</p>
<p><strong><u>BRIEFING SCHEDULE<br />
</u></strong><strong>2:00 p.m. </strong>Department Press Briefing with Spokesperson Ned Price.<br />
<strong>(POOLED PRESS COVERAGE)<br />
</strong><em>The Department Press Briefing will be live streamed on </em><a style="background-color: #ffffff;" href="http://www.state.gov"><em>www.state.gov</em></a><em>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
