<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 18:19:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Spanish Foreign Minister Albares</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-spanish-foreign-minister-albares/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 18:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263494</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p class="p1">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Spanish Foreign Minister José Manuel Albares and congratulated him on his new position.  The Secretary thanked Spain for the enduring alliance and deep friendship between our two countries.  Recognizing the strong ties between the United States and Spain, the Secretary and the Foreign Minister committed to further developing the Transatlantic relationship and jointly confronting shared challenges.  The Secretary outlined U.S. support for Cuban citizens’ rights to peaceful assembly, free speech, and democracy.  He advocated for comprehensive negotiations leading to free and fair elections in Venezuela, outlined concerns regarding Nicaragua, and affirmed our focus on promoting safe, orderly, and humane migration. The two ministers also discussed our shared interest in addressing the root causes of irregular migration from Central America.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p class="p1">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Spanish Foreign Minister José Manuel Albares and congratulated him on his new position.  The Secretary thanked Spain for the enduring alliance and deep friendship between our two countries.  Recognizing the strong ties between the United States and Spain, the Secretary and the Foreign Minister committed to further developing the Transatlantic relationship and jointly confronting shared challenges.  The Secretary outlined U.S. support for Cuban citizens’ rights to peaceful assembly, free speech, and democracy.  He advocated for comprehensive negotiations leading to free and fair elections in Venezuela, outlined concerns regarding Nicaragua, and affirmed our focus on promoting safe, orderly, and humane migration. The two ministers also discussed our shared interest in addressing the root causes of irregular migration from Central America.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Saad Al-Enezi of Sky News Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-saad-al-enezi-of-sky-news-arabia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 17:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263468</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Kuwait City, Kuwait</p>
<p>The Sheraton Hotel</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  I would like to thank Mr. Antony Blinken, U.S. Secretary of State, and thank you for joining us this brief interview.  Hopefully it will shed a light on some major issues.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Pleasure to be with you.  Thank you.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  First, let’s talk about – start with Tunisia.  It’s like, been political development and it’s – things are moving in different directions.  What’s your take on this?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, Tunisia’s been a strong, remarkable example of democracy in recent years, and I think it sends a strong message to see a strong democracy in Tunisia that represents the will and the interests of the people.  So we’ve been concerned by the steps taken to move out of the constitutional order, and that’s a real concern.  I spoke to the president just a few days ago to express those concerns.  We know the devastation that’s occurred in Tunisia through COVID-19, the economy.  We know that the government needs to be responsive to those challenges and to those problems.  But we – we’re urging our friends in Tunisia to move forward in a way that’s consistent with the constitution, that gets back on the democratic path, follows the democratic order, and including unfreezing the parliament and, of course, establishing a government.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  Okay.  Another very important issue for at least people in the Gulf area is the nuclear Iraqi – I mean, Iranian nuclear deal.  You just talked in the press conference about diplomacy will not be forever.  What are other options if these talks fail?  I mean, is the military option on the table?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, I don’t want to get into hypotheticals other than to say that we are determined that Iran not acquire a nuclear weapon.  And that has been and remains resolutely our policy.  We believe that it’s in our interest and Iran’s interest to come back into compliance with the nuclear agreement, the JCPOA.  But that really depends on Iran making the decision to do so.  It’s not yet made that decision.  Meanwhile, it continues to advance its nuclear program in very dangerous ways, and at some point those advances will be such that returning to compliance with the nuclear agreement won’t solve the problem.  So that’s why I say this can’t go on indefinitely.</p>
<p class="p1">Meanwhile, of course, we’ve seen protests in Iran that started outside of Tehran; they’ve now come to Tehran.  In the first instance they were really about people’s deep frustration with the failure of government to meet their basic needs, including water, mismanagement of the economy.  And now we’ve seen them move to people expressing their larger aspirations for freedom and for a government that respects them and respects their rights.  And, of course, we stand with the people of Iran in the desire to have their voices heard, and we urge – strongly urge the government not to use violence and repression to silence those voices.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  Do you think if the talks succeed, and Iran will actually agree to not only the nuclear deal but also the broader picture of the missile problem and the other issues of its behavior in the area, do you think this would open the door, and do you envision seeing normal relation with Iran or even – in the foreseeable future, or maybe Iran become an ally in distant future?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, we’re focused right now on determining whether Iran is willing to come back into compliance with the nuclear deal, and doing what the nuclear deal did, which is to put its nuclear program in a box and to remove the danger that Iran would be in a position to acquire a nuclear weapon very, very quickly.</p>
<p class="p1">At the same time, we’re determined to address the other challenges posed by Iran to us and to other countries in the region, including its destabilizing actions, its support for proxies and other militia that are engaged in violent action, its support for terrorism.  And that requires Iran’s engagement as well.</p>
<p class="p1">So our hope would be that we can return to the nuclear agreement and use that as a foundation for engaging Iran on these other issues where its actions are of real concern to us and to partners in the region.  Beyond that, it’s very hard to imagine the future.  We need to be focused on what we can do in the time ahead.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  When people in the region now, they are – some people or some allies maybe, they’re concerned about what they see.  I mean, they see – some people are interpreting what’s happening as U.S. pulling away, they’re questioning the commitment of the U.S. to their security, especially after withdrawing from Afghanistan in the manner it’s happened, and also the pact with Iraq which is rebranding the – your operation to an advisory position or an advisory phase and then reducing some of the defensive assets here in the Gulf.  People are a bit worried, even some of them might say they’re not, but that the United States is moving now to confront China, maybe at their own security – at the expense it.  What do – how do you answer such concerns?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, I think you have to look at each situation in its own right, which I’ll come to in a second.  But I also think it’s a mistake to equate engagement to the extent of our military presence in any one place.  We remain and we will remain very much present in the region and committed to the defense of our allies and partners.  That’s not going to change.  But my definition of engagement is much broader than the number of forces we may have in any one place.  It’s our economic engagement, our diplomatic engagement, our political engagement, and that is only increasing, including here in the Middle East.  And deepening, strengthening partnerships with countries throughout the region, to include Kuwait where I am today, is very much part of the agenda.</p>
<p class="p1">Now, the individual cases, it’s important to look at them, as I say, in their own right.  Afghanistan – we – why did we go to Afghanistan in the first place?  It was because we were attacked on 9/11.  We went there to bring to justice those who attacked us and to try to make sure that that could not happen again from Afghanistan soil.  And we largely succeeded in achieving those objectives.  Osama bin Laden was brought to justice 10 years ago, and al-Qaida as a threat from Afghanistan to us and to others has been vastly diminished.  And we’ll keep an eye on things to make sure it doesn’t reemerge, and if it does, we would take action to deal with that.</p>
<p class="p1">And, of course, again, it’s 20 years later, $1 trillion.  Even as we are removing our forces, we’re remaining very much engaged in Afghanistan, supporting Afghanistan economically, development assistance, humanitarian assistance, support for its security forces, and diplomatic engagement to try to bring the parties to the table – the Taliban, the Afghan Government – to negotiate an end to the conflict.  So I think that’s the story on Afghanistan.</p>
<p class="p1">When it comes to Iraq, the success of Iraqi security forces is such that we are able to transition the mission that we have in Iraq so that our focus there is on supporting those forces with training and advice to deal with Daesh and any prospect that might reemerge.  Meanwhile, we have a very broad relationship with Iraq economically, diplomatically, politically.  We just had a Strategic Dialogue in Washington with senior Iraqi leadership that is evidence of that partnership.  So again, I think you have to be very careful with equating our engagement in any particular place just by looking at the numbers of American forces there.  I think we’re much more effective when that engagement is broad-based across the board, and on that basis, our engagement has only deepened.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:  </b>The last question, Mr. Secretary.  China is coming with a – very strongly in this area with the Silk Road initiative.  Do you have a competing vision from the U.S. to compete now with China for the future in the next decade and other decades?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, a few things are important here.  First, this is not a question of having to choose between China and the United States.  We know that people have relationships, economic relationships with a variety of countries, including China, and that includes investments from China.  But I think what’s very important is this:  We all have to look very carefully at the investments that are being made.  First, if they’re in sensitive areas involving sensitive technologies, that’s something people have to look at very carefully.  Unfortunately, when it comes to China, there’s really no difference between its so-called private companies and the state.  The state can order the companies to do anything at any time.  And we know that when it comes to human rights, when it comes to privacy, when it comes to protecting intellectual property, China has a different view of those issues than we do and others do.  So there’s that.</p>
<p class="p1">Second, in terms of investments, and as countries receive them and are in – doing business, they have to look very carefully at what that might involve.  And if it involves, for example, taking on a tremendous amount of debt that you can’t repay, if it involves workers coming in from another country to do the work – in this case, China – as opposed to having local workers do it, if it involves corruption, if it involves a lack of transparency, if it involves building things to bad standards without care for the environment, well, all of those things have to be factored in.  We do, I think, have an alternative vision, and that is to make investments that are, as we would say, a race to the top, not a race to the bottom, with a focus on making sure that countries don’t take on debt that they can’t manage, with a focus on the rights of workers, being attentive to the environment, making sure that we’re building things to high standards.  So, people can decide and make a choice about what makes the most sense for them.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:  </b>Well, thank you very much.  I really appreciate it.  Would love to have more time with you, but our time is out.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:  </b>Appreciate you being with us.  Thank you.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you very much.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Kuwait City, Kuwait</p>
<p>The Sheraton Hotel</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  I would like to thank Mr. Antony Blinken, U.S. Secretary of State, and thank you for joining us this brief interview.  Hopefully it will shed a light on some major issues.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Pleasure to be with you.  Thank you.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  First, let’s talk about – start with Tunisia.  It’s like, been political development and it’s – things are moving in different directions.  What’s your take on this?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, Tunisia’s been a strong, remarkable example of democracy in recent years, and I think it sends a strong message to see a strong democracy in Tunisia that represents the will and the interests of the people.  So we’ve been concerned by the steps taken to move out of the constitutional order, and that’s a real concern.  I spoke to the president just a few days ago to express those concerns.  We know the devastation that’s occurred in Tunisia through COVID-19, the economy.  We know that the government needs to be responsive to those challenges and to those problems.  But we – we’re urging our friends in Tunisia to move forward in a way that’s consistent with the constitution, that gets back on the democratic path, follows the democratic order, and including unfreezing the parliament and, of course, establishing a government.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  Okay.  Another very important issue for at least people in the Gulf area is the nuclear Iraqi – I mean, Iranian nuclear deal.  You just talked in the press conference about diplomacy will not be forever.  What are other options if these talks fail?  I mean, is the military option on the table?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, I don’t want to get into hypotheticals other than to say that we are determined that Iran not acquire a nuclear weapon.  And that has been and remains resolutely our policy.  We believe that it’s in our interest and Iran’s interest to come back into compliance with the nuclear agreement, the JCPOA.  But that really depends on Iran making the decision to do so.  It’s not yet made that decision.  Meanwhile, it continues to advance its nuclear program in very dangerous ways, and at some point those advances will be such that returning to compliance with the nuclear agreement won’t solve the problem.  So that’s why I say this can’t go on indefinitely.</p>
<p class="p1">Meanwhile, of course, we’ve seen protests in Iran that started outside of Tehran; they’ve now come to Tehran.  In the first instance they were really about people’s deep frustration with the failure of government to meet their basic needs, including water, mismanagement of the economy.  And now we’ve seen them move to people expressing their larger aspirations for freedom and for a government that respects them and respects their rights.  And, of course, we stand with the people of Iran in the desire to have their voices heard, and we urge – strongly urge the government not to use violence and repression to silence those voices.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  Do you think if the talks succeed, and Iran will actually agree to not only the nuclear deal but also the broader picture of the missile problem and the other issues of its behavior in the area, do you think this would open the door, and do you envision seeing normal relation with Iran or even – in the foreseeable future, or maybe Iran become an ally in distant future?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  Well, we’re focused right now on determining whether Iran is willing to come back into compliance with the nuclear deal, and doing what the nuclear deal did, which is to put its nuclear program in a box and to remove the danger that Iran would be in a position to acquire a nuclear weapon very, very quickly.</p>
<p class="p1">At the same time, we’re determined to address the other challenges posed by Iran to us and to other countries in the region, including its destabilizing actions, its support for proxies and other militia that are engaged in violent action, its support for terrorism.  And that requires Iran’s engagement as well.</p>
<p class="p1">So our hope would be that we can return to the nuclear agreement and use that as a foundation for engaging Iran on these other issues where its actions are of real concern to us and to partners in the region.  Beyond that, it’s very hard to imagine the future.  We need to be focused on what we can do in the time ahead.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:</b>  When people in the region now, they are – some people or some allies maybe, they’re concerned about what they see.  I mean, they see – some people are interpreting what’s happening as U.S. pulling away, they’re questioning the commitment of the U.S. to their security, especially after withdrawing from Afghanistan in the manner it’s happened, and also the pact with Iraq which is rebranding the – your operation to an advisory position or an advisory phase and then reducing some of the defensive assets here in the Gulf.  People are a bit worried, even some of them might say they’re not, but that the United States is moving now to confront China, maybe at their own security – at the expense it.  What do – how do you answer such concerns?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, I think you have to look at each situation in its own right, which I’ll come to in a second.  But I also think it’s a mistake to equate engagement to the extent of our military presence in any one place.  We remain and we will remain very much present in the region and committed to the defense of our allies and partners.  That’s not going to change.  But my definition of engagement is much broader than the number of forces we may have in any one place.  It’s our economic engagement, our diplomatic engagement, our political engagement, and that is only increasing, including here in the Middle East.  And deepening, strengthening partnerships with countries throughout the region, to include Kuwait where I am today, is very much part of the agenda.</p>
<p class="p1">Now, the individual cases, it’s important to look at them, as I say, in their own right.  Afghanistan – we – why did we go to Afghanistan in the first place?  It was because we were attacked on 9/11.  We went there to bring to justice those who attacked us and to try to make sure that that could not happen again from Afghanistan soil.  And we largely succeeded in achieving those objectives.  Osama bin Laden was brought to justice 10 years ago, and al-Qaida as a threat from Afghanistan to us and to others has been vastly diminished.  And we’ll keep an eye on things to make sure it doesn’t reemerge, and if it does, we would take action to deal with that.</p>
<p class="p1">And, of course, again, it’s 20 years later, $1 trillion.  Even as we are removing our forces, we’re remaining very much engaged in Afghanistan, supporting Afghanistan economically, development assistance, humanitarian assistance, support for its security forces, and diplomatic engagement to try to bring the parties to the table – the Taliban, the Afghan Government – to negotiate an end to the conflict.  So I think that’s the story on Afghanistan.</p>
<p class="p1">When it comes to Iraq, the success of Iraqi security forces is such that we are able to transition the mission that we have in Iraq so that our focus there is on supporting those forces with training and advice to deal with Daesh and any prospect that might reemerge.  Meanwhile, we have a very broad relationship with Iraq economically, diplomatically, politically.  We just had a Strategic Dialogue in Washington with senior Iraqi leadership that is evidence of that partnership.  So again, I think you have to be very careful with equating our engagement in any particular place just by looking at the numbers of American forces there.  I think we’re much more effective when that engagement is broad-based across the board, and on that basis, our engagement has only deepened.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:  </b>The last question, Mr. Secretary.  China is coming with a – very strongly in this area with the Silk Road initiative.  Do you have a competing vision from the U.S. to compete now with China for the future in the next decade and other decades?</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, a few things are important here.  First, this is not a question of having to choose between China and the United States.  We know that people have relationships, economic relationships with a variety of countries, including China, and that includes investments from China.  But I think what’s very important is this:  We all have to look very carefully at the investments that are being made.  First, if they’re in sensitive areas involving sensitive technologies, that’s something people have to look at very carefully.  Unfortunately, when it comes to China, there’s really no difference between its so-called private companies and the state.  The state can order the companies to do anything at any time.  And we know that when it comes to human rights, when it comes to privacy, when it comes to protecting intellectual property, China has a different view of those issues than we do and others do.  So there’s that.</p>
<p class="p1">Second, in terms of investments, and as countries receive them and are in – doing business, they have to look very carefully at what that might involve.  And if it involves, for example, taking on a tremendous amount of debt that you can’t repay, if it involves workers coming in from another country to do the work – in this case, China – as opposed to having local workers do it, if it involves corruption, if it involves a lack of transparency, if it involves building things to bad standards without care for the environment, well, all of those things have to be factored in.  We do, I think, have an alternative vision, and that is to make investments that are, as we would say, a race to the top, not a race to the bottom, with a focus on making sure that countries don’t take on debt that they can’t manage, with a focus on the rights of workers, being attentive to the environment, making sure that we’re building things to high standards.  So, people can decide and make a choice about what makes the most sense for them.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:  </b>Well, thank you very much.  I really appreciate it.  Would love to have more time with you, but our time is out.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>QUESTION:  </b>Appreciate you being with us.  Thank you.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Thank you very much.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Mexican Foreign Secretary Ebrard</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-mexican-foreign-secretary-ebrard-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 17:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263461</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Mexican Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard today.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Ebrard discussed coordinated efforts between the United States and Mexico to address the root causes of irregular migration and to promote fair, orderly, and humane migration in the region.  </span>The United States and Mexico share an interest in sustainable solutions to reduce irregular migration in, from, and through the region and to advance the economic security and prosperity of our region.  Secretary Blinken thanked Foreign Secretary Ebrard for Mexico’s efforts that contribute to coordinated migration management, including its extensive support at the federal, state, and local levels.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Ebrard also discussed efforts to promote democracy and human rights in the region.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Mexican Foreign Secretary Marcelo Ebrard today.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Ebrard discussed coordinated efforts between the United States and Mexico to address the root causes of irregular migration and to promote fair, orderly, and humane migration in the region.  </span>The United States and Mexico share an interest in sustainable solutions to reduce irregular migration in, from, and through the region and to advance the economic security and prosperity of our region.  Secretary Blinken thanked Foreign Secretary Ebrard for Mexico’s efforts that contribute to coordinated migration management, including its extensive support at the federal, state, and local levels.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Secretary Ebrard also discussed efforts to promote democracy and human rights in the region.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with Osman Ayfarah of Al Jazeera</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-osman-ayfarah-of-al-jazeera/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 17:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263446</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Kuwait City, Kuwait</p>
<p>The Sheraton Hotel</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Secretary Blinken, thank you for joining us.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Good to be with you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> At the moment, all eyes are on Tunisia. We know you had a conversation with the Tunisian President Kais Saied. So what did you say to him, if I may ask?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Tunisia’s been a remarkable demonstration of democracy, and it’s really, I think, been a strong example not just for the region but for the world. And we have concerns about deviating from that democratic map, taking actions that run counter to the constitution, including freezing the parliament. We very much recognize that Tunisians are suffering terribly with COVID-19 and a very, very challenging economy. They need a government, of course, that’s responsive to their needs, but that has to happen in a way that is consistent with, respectful of the constitution.</p>
<p>And so I had a long conversation with the president and urged him to make sure that Tunisia returns to the democratic path as quickly as possible. We also have concerns with any efforts to repress the voices of the Tunisian people, including the media, which we’ve seen some reports of in recent days. So our strong hope and expectation is that Tunisia will return to that democratic path, act consistent with the constitution, unfreeze the parliament, have a government in place to do the work of the people, to be responsive to their needs.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> What was the president’s response to you?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Well, I don’t want to speak for him. That – I’ll let him speak for himself. But he gave a lengthy explanation of both the actions he was – he had taken and his intentions going forward. And the intentions he expressed to me were to return Tunisia to that democratic path and to act in a way that was consistent with the constitution. But of course we have to look at the actions that the president takes, that Tunisia takes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Closing down Al Jazeera’s bureau immediately after the president’s decisions was very worrying, and we had solidarity with all the journalists, including the National Union of Tunisian Journalists. As a former journalist yourself and Secretary of State of United States, what are your comments?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> My comment is that we stand resolutely for freedom of the press and for the ability of journalists to do their jobs, including in Tunisia. And we look to the Government of Tunisia to uphold and respect the rights of journalists, and that’s one of the things that we expect of them.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> How vital is the security of the Gulf countries and the partnership with the Gulf countries to the interests of the United States?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Well, we have a strong partnership with countries in the Gulf. I’m here in Kuwait to reaffirm that partnership. It happens to be the 60th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the United States and Kuwait, and the 30th anniversary of the liberation of Kuwait after the invasion by Saddam Hussein. But as we’re looking at these partnerships we’re not only working to sustain them; we’re working to build on them and to build on them in new ways, not only dealing with many of the diplomatic challenges and security challenges that exist in the region, including in Yemen, including in different ways in Lebanon, in Syria, but also to work together on a whole variety of issues that will have an impact on the lives of citizens throughout the region and in the United States. Health security, food security, collaboration on science and technology, dealing with some of the emerging technologies that are shaping people’s lives – that’s also now part of the agenda with our partners in the Gulf.</p>
<p>But we remain very much engaged, very much present, working in partnership both with individual countries as well as with the, for example, the Gulf Cooperation Council. And I think this visit to Kuwait was a reaffirmation of that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> President Biden did say he was interested and would work to end the war in Yemen. Why hasn’t that happened? What are the obstacles?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Well, I wish it was like flipping a light switch, but it’s not. But from very early in the administration the President made clear that commitment. We appointed, very early on as well, a senior special envoy to lead our diplomacy, Tim Lenderking, who has been very actively engaged in trying to bring the war to an end with support and engagement from me, from the President himself.</p>
<p>We very much appreciate the plan that Saudi Arabia has put forward to move in that direction. Unfortunately, the reality is that the Houthis have not engaged in a meaningful way, and they need to demonstrate that they’re prepared to end the war, to enter into negotiations, to stop their offensive operations within Yemen, as well as their attacks on Saudi Arabia itself. And we’re resolutely in support of Saudi Arabia, in terms of defending its territory from these attacks.</p>
<p>This is about ending a war and it’s about ending the incredible suffering of the Yemeni people. Yemen, as you know, is perhaps the worst humanitarian crisis in the world. And I hope that the Houthis will demonstrate that they actually care about the people of Yemen, not simply in trying to gobble up more territory. So we’re looking to them to come to the negotiating table, to engage in a meaningful way, and to bring this war to an end.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You decided to withdraw from Iraq and Afghanistan, and this coincides with the Taliban gaining ground substantially. Is the United States prepared to accept a Taliban government in Afghanistan or a Taliban-dominated government in Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Well, with regard to Afghanistan, first, it’s important to remember why we went to Afghanistan in the first place. We were attacked on 9/11. We were determined to bring to justice those who attacked us and to make sure, to the best of the ability, that that couldn’t happen again. And we’ve largely succeeded in accomplishing those objectives. Osama bin Laden was brought to justice 10 years ago, and al-Qaida, in terms of its abilities to attack us or anyone else from Afghanistan, has been vastly diminished. And we will keep a very close eye on it to make sure that it doesn’t reemerge, and if it does we will do what’s necessary to prevent it from attacking us or from attacking anyone else.</p>
<p>We were there for 20 years, a trillion dollars. More than 4,500 Americans lost their lives. And it is time for Afghanistan to shape its own future. Having said that, even as we’re withdrawing our military forces, we remain very much engaged in Afghanistan with a strong embassy, with support for Afghanistan’s economy, humanitarian support, development support, support for security forces, as well as very active diplomatic engagement to try to bring an end to the conflict at the negotiating table with the Taliban and with the Afghan Government. There is no military solution to the conflict.</p>
<p>Now, if an Afghanistan emerges that does not respect the basic rights of its people, that abuses the rights of women and girls, that does not respect the basic gains of the last 20 years, that Afghanistan will be a pariah in the international community.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Final question is about Iran. What are you offering Iran? When you say the ball is in Iran’s court, what do you mean by that? I know you’re – we’re running out of time, so you’re going to have to be brief.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> So very quickly, we’ve engaged in multiple rounds of negotiations, indirect with Iran in Vienna, along with the Europeans, Russia, and China, to see if we can both come back into compliance with the nuclear agreement. And we have made very good faith efforts to do that. We’ve made clear everything that we’re prepared to do. Unfortunately, Iran has not yet made the basic decision about whether it is willing to do what’s necessary to come back into compliance with that agreement. So that’s what I mean when I say the ball is in Iran’s court. They’ve not yet made that decision.</p>
<p>We hope that they do make the decision. We are prepared to go back to Vienna at any time to focus on diplomacy and to return to compliance with the agreement. But there – this is not – this can’t be an indefinite process. At some point, if Iran continues to make the advances it’s made on its nuclear program, as it’s lifted the constraints imposed by the nuclear agreement, it will get to a point where we can’t deal with that simply by coming back into compliance with the nuclear agreement.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, I might add, we’re seeing significant protests in Iran that began in areas distant from Tehran, but now we’re seeing in Tehran, because people in the first instance are demanding that the government provide for its basic needs, including water, and we’ve seen tremendous mismanagement that has not addressed the needs of the Iranian people. And we’re also seeing them look to their broader aspirations for freedom, and we stand very much with the people who are trying to make their voices heard and call on the Iranian Government to respect the right to peaceful protest and not to repress it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Secretary Antony Blinken, thank you very much for talking to Al Jazeera.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (In Arabic.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Thank you. Good to be with you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you very much.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Kuwait City, Kuwait</p>
<p>The Sheraton Hotel</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Secretary Blinken, thank you for joining us.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Good to be with you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> At the moment, all eyes are on Tunisia. We know you had a conversation with the Tunisian President Kais Saied. So what did you say to him, if I may ask?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Tunisia’s been a remarkable demonstration of democracy, and it’s really, I think, been a strong example not just for the region but for the world. And we have concerns about deviating from that democratic map, taking actions that run counter to the constitution, including freezing the parliament. We very much recognize that Tunisians are suffering terribly with COVID-19 and a very, very challenging economy. They need a government, of course, that’s responsive to their needs, but that has to happen in a way that is consistent with, respectful of the constitution.</p>
<p>And so I had a long conversation with the president and urged him to make sure that Tunisia returns to the democratic path as quickly as possible. We also have concerns with any efforts to repress the voices of the Tunisian people, including the media, which we’ve seen some reports of in recent days. So our strong hope and expectation is that Tunisia will return to that democratic path, act consistent with the constitution, unfreeze the parliament, have a government in place to do the work of the people, to be responsive to their needs.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> What was the president’s response to you?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Well, I don’t want to speak for him. That – I’ll let him speak for himself. But he gave a lengthy explanation of both the actions he was – he had taken and his intentions going forward. And the intentions he expressed to me were to return Tunisia to that democratic path and to act in a way that was consistent with the constitution. But of course we have to look at the actions that the president takes, that Tunisia takes.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Closing down Al Jazeera’s bureau immediately after the president’s decisions was very worrying, and we had solidarity with all the journalists, including the National Union of Tunisian Journalists. As a former journalist yourself and Secretary of State of United States, what are your comments?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> My comment is that we stand resolutely for freedom of the press and for the ability of journalists to do their jobs, including in Tunisia. And we look to the Government of Tunisia to uphold and respect the rights of journalists, and that’s one of the things that we expect of them.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> How vital is the security of the Gulf countries and the partnership with the Gulf countries to the interests of the United States?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Well, we have a strong partnership with countries in the Gulf. I’m here in Kuwait to reaffirm that partnership. It happens to be the 60th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the United States and Kuwait, and the 30th anniversary of the liberation of Kuwait after the invasion by Saddam Hussein. But as we’re looking at these partnerships we’re not only working to sustain them; we’re working to build on them and to build on them in new ways, not only dealing with many of the diplomatic challenges and security challenges that exist in the region, including in Yemen, including in different ways in Lebanon, in Syria, but also to work together on a whole variety of issues that will have an impact on the lives of citizens throughout the region and in the United States. Health security, food security, collaboration on science and technology, dealing with some of the emerging technologies that are shaping people’s lives – that’s also now part of the agenda with our partners in the Gulf.</p>
<p>But we remain very much engaged, very much present, working in partnership both with individual countries as well as with the, for example, the Gulf Cooperation Council. And I think this visit to Kuwait was a reaffirmation of that.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> President Biden did say he was interested and would work to end the war in Yemen. Why hasn’t that happened? What are the obstacles?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Well, I wish it was like flipping a light switch, but it’s not. But from very early in the administration the President made clear that commitment. We appointed, very early on as well, a senior special envoy to lead our diplomacy, Tim Lenderking, who has been very actively engaged in trying to bring the war to an end with support and engagement from me, from the President himself.</p>
<p>We very much appreciate the plan that Saudi Arabia has put forward to move in that direction. Unfortunately, the reality is that the Houthis have not engaged in a meaningful way, and they need to demonstrate that they’re prepared to end the war, to enter into negotiations, to stop their offensive operations within Yemen, as well as their attacks on Saudi Arabia itself. And we’re resolutely in support of Saudi Arabia, in terms of defending its territory from these attacks.</p>
<p>This is about ending a war and it’s about ending the incredible suffering of the Yemeni people. Yemen, as you know, is perhaps the worst humanitarian crisis in the world. And I hope that the Houthis will demonstrate that they actually care about the people of Yemen, not simply in trying to gobble up more territory. So we’re looking to them to come to the negotiating table, to engage in a meaningful way, and to bring this war to an end.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> You decided to withdraw from Iraq and Afghanistan, and this coincides with the Taliban gaining ground substantially. Is the United States prepared to accept a Taliban government in Afghanistan or a Taliban-dominated government in Afghanistan?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Well, with regard to Afghanistan, first, it’s important to remember why we went to Afghanistan in the first place. We were attacked on 9/11. We were determined to bring to justice those who attacked us and to make sure, to the best of the ability, that that couldn’t happen again. And we’ve largely succeeded in accomplishing those objectives. Osama bin Laden was brought to justice 10 years ago, and al-Qaida, in terms of its abilities to attack us or anyone else from Afghanistan, has been vastly diminished. And we will keep a very close eye on it to make sure that it doesn’t reemerge, and if it does we will do what’s necessary to prevent it from attacking us or from attacking anyone else.</p>
<p>We were there for 20 years, a trillion dollars. More than 4,500 Americans lost their lives. And it is time for Afghanistan to shape its own future. Having said that, even as we’re withdrawing our military forces, we remain very much engaged in Afghanistan with a strong embassy, with support for Afghanistan’s economy, humanitarian support, development support, support for security forces, as well as very active diplomatic engagement to try to bring an end to the conflict at the negotiating table with the Taliban and with the Afghan Government. There is no military solution to the conflict.</p>
<p>Now, if an Afghanistan emerges that does not respect the basic rights of its people, that abuses the rights of women and girls, that does not respect the basic gains of the last 20 years, that Afghanistan will be a pariah in the international community.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Final question is about Iran. What are you offering Iran? When you say the ball is in Iran’s court, what do you mean by that? I know you’re – we’re running out of time, so you’re going to have to be brief.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> So very quickly, we’ve engaged in multiple rounds of negotiations, indirect with Iran in Vienna, along with the Europeans, Russia, and China, to see if we can both come back into compliance with the nuclear agreement. And we have made very good faith efforts to do that. We’ve made clear everything that we’re prepared to do. Unfortunately, Iran has not yet made the basic decision about whether it is willing to do what’s necessary to come back into compliance with that agreement. So that’s what I mean when I say the ball is in Iran’s court. They’ve not yet made that decision.</p>
<p>We hope that they do make the decision. We are prepared to go back to Vienna at any time to focus on diplomacy and to return to compliance with the agreement. But there – this is not – this can’t be an indefinite process. At some point, if Iran continues to make the advances it’s made on its nuclear program, as it’s lifted the constraints imposed by the nuclear agreement, it will get to a point where we can’t deal with that simply by coming back into compliance with the nuclear agreement.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, I might add, we’re seeing significant protests in Iran that began in areas distant from Tehran, but now we’re seeing in Tehran, because people in the first instance are demanding that the government provide for its basic needs, including water, and we’ve seen tremendous mismanagement that has not addressed the needs of the Iranian people. And we’re also seeing them look to their broader aspirations for freedom, and we stand very much with the people who are trying to make their voices heard and call on the Iranian Government to respect the right to peaceful protest and not to repress it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Secretary Antony Blinken, thank you very much for talking to Al Jazeera.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> (In Arabic.)</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong> Thank you. Good to be with you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you very much.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States to Co-Host the Indo-Pacific Business Forum 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-to-co-host-the-indo-pacific-business-forum-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 13:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1">The United States Government, in partnership with the Government of India, the U.S. Chamber of Commerce, the Confederation of Indian Industry, the Federation of Indian Chambers of Commerce and Industry, and the US-ASEAN Business Council (USABC), is sponsoring the fourth annual Indo-Pacific Business Forum (IPBF), which will take place this year as a fully online event on October 28-29, 2021, with a schedule that ensures participants from across the Indo-Pacific can all participate.</p>
<p class="p1">The IPBF advances a vision for an Indo-Pacific region that is free, open, and inclusive.  Government and business leaders from the United States, India, and across the Indo-Pacific region will<span class="s1"> exchange ideas through interactive discussions organized around three broad themes:  Economic Recovery and Resilience; Climate Action; and Digital Innovation. </span> Attendees will also be able to explore regional government and business partnerships and commercial opportunities.  The IPBF will showcase high-impact private sector investment and government efforts to support market competition, job growth, and high-standard development for greater prosperity and economic inclusion in the Indo-Pacific.  The event will be conducted via a secure online conferencing platform.</p>
<p class="p1">Registration for attendees and for the media will open soon.</p>
<p class="p1">For further information, please visit the Indo-Pacific Business Forum website at:<span class="s1"> <a href="https://www.indopacificbusinessforum.com/"><span class="s2">https://www.indopacificbusinessforum.com/</span></a></span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1">The United States Government, in partnership with the Government of India, the U.S. Chamber of Commerce, the Confederation of Indian Industry, the Federation of Indian Chambers of Commerce and Industry, and the US-ASEAN Business Council (USABC), is sponsoring the fourth annual Indo-Pacific Business Forum (IPBF), which will take place this year as a fully online event on October 28-29, 2021, with a schedule that ensures participants from across the Indo-Pacific can all participate.</p>
<p class="p1">The IPBF advances a vision for an Indo-Pacific region that is free, open, and inclusive.  Government and business leaders from the United States, India, and across the Indo-Pacific region will<span class="s1"> exchange ideas through interactive discussions organized around three broad themes:  Economic Recovery and Resilience; Climate Action; and Digital Innovation. </span> Attendees will also be able to explore regional government and business partnerships and commercial opportunities.  The IPBF will showcase high-impact private sector investment and government efforts to support market competition, job growth, and high-standard development for greater prosperity and economic inclusion in the Indo-Pacific.  The event will be conducted via a secure online conferencing platform.</p>
<p class="p1">Registration for attendees and for the media will open soon.</p>
<p class="p1">For further information, please visit the Indo-Pacific Business Forum website at:<span class="s1"> <a href="https://www.indopacificbusinessforum.com/"><span class="s2">https://www.indopacificbusinessforum.com/</span></a></span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with the Amir of Kuwait Sheikh Nawaf Al-Sabah</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-the-amir-of-kuwait-sheikh-nawaf-al-sabah/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 13:06:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263269</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p class="p1">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today in Kuwait City with His Highness the Amir of Kuwait Sheikh Nawaf Al-Ahmad Al-Jaber Al-Sabah, His Highness the Crown Prince Sheikh Mishal Al-Ahmed Al-Sabah, Prime Minister Sheikh Sabah Al-Khaled Al-Hamad Al-Sabah, Speaker of the National Assembly Marzouq al Ghanem, and Foreign Minister Sheikh Dr. Ahmed Nasser Al-Mohammed Al-Sabah to discuss regional security, joint efforts to distribute COVID-19 vaccines, and other key issues important to the bilateral relationship.  Secretary Blinken recognized two milestones in the U.S.-Kuwait relationship – the 30th anniversary of Operation Desert Shield and 60 years of diplomatic ties – and thanked the Amir for the enduring support that has enabled close cooperation in defense, counterterrorism, trade and investment, security, education, culture, and science.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p class="p1">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met today in Kuwait City with His Highness the Amir of Kuwait Sheikh Nawaf Al-Ahmad Al-Jaber Al-Sabah, His Highness the Crown Prince Sheikh Mishal Al-Ahmed Al-Sabah, Prime Minister Sheikh Sabah Al-Khaled Al-Hamad Al-Sabah, Speaker of the National Assembly Marzouq al Ghanem, and Foreign Minister Sheikh Dr. Ahmed Nasser Al-Mohammed Al-Sabah to discuss regional security, joint efforts to distribute COVID-19 vaccines, and other key issues important to the bilateral relationship.  Secretary Blinken recognized two milestones in the U.S.-Kuwait relationship – the 30th anniversary of Operation Desert Shield and 60 years of diplomatic ties – and thanked the Amir for the enduring support that has enabled close cooperation in defense, counterterrorism, trade and investment, security, education, culture, and science.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vanuatu’s National Day</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/vanuatus-national-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 13:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263266</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p class="p1">On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Vanuatu as you celebrate your National Day on July 30.</p>
<p class="p1">Our shared commitment to maritime security, good governance, and economic development has guided our friendship for forty-one years.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The strength of our relationship is embodied in our joint efforts to adapt and be resilient in the face of the challenges presented by COVID-19.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We look forward to the return of Peace Corps volunteers as circumstances permit and to continuing our productive virtual engagements until it is possible to meet again in person.</p>
<p class="p1">I wish all people of Vanuatu health and happiness, as you celebrate this significant day of independence.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p class="p1">On behalf of the United States of America, I congratulate the people of Vanuatu as you celebrate your National Day on July 30.</p>
<p class="p1">Our shared commitment to maritime security, good governance, and economic development has guided our friendship for forty-one years.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The strength of our relationship is embodied in our joint efforts to adapt and be resilient in the face of the challenges presented by COVID-19.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We look forward to the return of Peace Corps volunteers as circumstances permit and to continuing our productive virtual engagements until it is possible to meet again in person.</p>
<p class="p1">I wish all people of Vanuatu health and happiness, as you celebrate this significant day of independence.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>50th Anniversary of the Closing of Halki Seminary</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/50th-anniversary-of-the-closing-of-halki-seminary/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 12:48:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263257</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1">Today marks 50 years since the Turkish Constitutional Court ruled that all institutions of higher education must either nationalize or close, resulting in the closure of the Theological School of Halki, a seminary of the Ecumenical Patriarchate of the Eastern Orthodox Church.  The Halki Seminary had operated for 127 years, and its closing deprived the Ecumenical Patriarchate of a training school for Orthodox clergy in Turkey, its home for 1,690 years.  Since Halki’s closure, those wishing to become Orthodox clergy have been forced to go abroad for their training.</p>
<p class="p1">The United States continues to urge the Turkish government to respect the right to freedom of religion or belief as enshrined in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, and allow the reopening of the Halki Seminary.  Moreover, we call upon the government of Turkey to allow all religious groups to again train their clergy within the country.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1">Today marks 50 years since the Turkish Constitutional Court ruled that all institutions of higher education must either nationalize or close, resulting in the closure of the Theological School of Halki, a seminary of the Ecumenical Patriarchate of the Eastern Orthodox Church.  The Halki Seminary had operated for 127 years, and its closing deprived the Ecumenical Patriarchate of a training school for Orthodox clergy in Turkey, its home for 1,690 years.  Since Halki’s closure, those wishing to become Orthodox clergy have been forced to go abroad for their training.</p>
<p class="p1">The United States continues to urge the Turkish government to respect the right to freedom of religion or belief as enshrined in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, and allow the reopening of the Halki Seminary.  Moreover, we call upon the government of Turkey to allow all religious groups to again train their clergy within the country.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken with Indrani Bagchi of The Times of India</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-indrani-bagchi-of-the-times-of-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 03:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>New Delhi, India</p>
<p>The Leela Palace Hotel</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Welcome to <em>The</em> <em>Times of India</em>, and &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So let’s just start off right.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So what has – what have we achieved in the Quad so far?  And where do you think it’s (inaudible)?  You’ve got a summit coming up.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, first we had the first ever leaders-level meeting of the Quad.  That was in and of itself very significant, because it just underscored the importance that the four countries – India, the United States, Japan, and Australia – attach to the Quad.  And what we’ve achieved already is bringing together four likeminded democracies in common purpose to deal with some of the most important problems and challenges facing our countries, and in fact facing the region and even the world, starting with COVID-19, and a commitment to work together to finance, to produce, to distribute millions of vaccines.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Are you satisfied with the progress on the vaccine?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yeah, I think we’re making – we’re making progress on that.  I think the – when the leaders get together next, they’ll be able to assess that progress.  Of course, COVID-19 remains a huge challenge for all of us, and since the first virtual leaders meeting, the second wave hit India.  I’m proud that the United States was able to come to India’s assistance, as India came to our assistance early during the pandemic when we had real challenges.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  We’ve seen reports of a digital services tax that had been proposed by the U.S.  Is there something &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I’m sorry, digital services?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  A digital services agreement between countries – likeminded countries, I guess.  Is there something that you &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’re – there – we’re doing work in a wide variety of areas, to include not just COVID-19, but working together on the climate crisis, working together on infrastructure, on maritime security, on – and on emerging technologies.  And that includes in the digital space.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And if you would tell us, for Indian readers, because we are – we know the China challenge.  We’ve shed blood.  What – how would you describe the challenge of China to the world, to West and India &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  For the United States, in a way as for India, it’s both one of the most consequential and most complicated relationships that we have.  I think we’ve seen China – unfortunately, the government in Beijing act more repressively at home and more aggressively abroad in recent years.  That poses a challenge for all of us.  As we look at it, we see a relationship that is in parts adversarial, in parts competitive, and also in parts cooperative.  And I think what we’ve found is that whether it’s adversarial, whether it’s competitive, whether it’s cooperative, the most effective way to engage China is working with other countries that are similarly situated and that face similar challenges.  India, of course, is a strong partner for the United States.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Do you think the era of cooperation with China may be over?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  No.  As I said, I think the relationship has different elements in it.  Cooperation remains one of them because on some issues, it’s profoundly in our mutual interest to cooperate, and irrespective of the competition, irrespective of the adversarial nature of parts of the relationship, that’s – those interests remain.  Climate may be the best example.  That’s an issue that is important to all of us.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  With the troops withdrawal – U.S. troops withdrawal from Afghanistan, I have two questions.  One is:  Do you think it affects the U.S. credibility as a partner?  Second, as a woman, I have to ask this:  For 20 years, women have had a good run in Afghanistan.  Do you think we’re sort of feeding them to the wolves, so to speak?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Two things.  As you just said, 20 years.  It’s been 20 years.  We have to remember why we went to Afghanistan in the first place.  It’s because we were attacked on 9/11.  We went to do justice for – to those who attacked us and to try to make sure that it couldn’t happen again.  And we’ve largely succeeded in that effort.  Usama bin Ladin was brought to justice 10 years ago.  And al-Qaida, the organization that attacked us, in terms of its capacity to do that again from Afghanistan, that’s been vastly diminished.</p>
<p>It’s now 20 years later, a trillion dollars later, more than 4,500 American soldiers lost their lives later.  Afghanistan ultimately has to be able to shape its own future, but with our support.  Even as we withdraw our forces, we are staying very much engaged in Afghanistan with a strong embassy, with programs to support women and girls, economic development, humanitarian assistance, and the security forces.  So we’re remaining very much engaged – also with our diplomacy, because the only resolution to the conflict in Afghanistan is at the negotiating table, not at the battlefield.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Pakistan continues to support the Taliban.  And are we seeing the same effect in Afghanistan today that we saw for the last 20 years?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Pakistan has a vital role to play in using its influence with the Taliban to do whatever it can to make sure that the Taliban does not seek to take the country by force.  And it does have influence, and it does have a role to play, and we hope that it plays it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  What are your priority items with India?  And when do we expect a presidential visit to India?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, I can’t put a date on it, but I know that President Biden very much looks forward to visiting India, and similarly to having Prime Minister Modi in the United States.  But no date yet, but I’m sure that that will come.</p>
<p>Look, in terms of priorities, the relationship is both so wide and so deep there are – as we discussed today through several hours with Foreign Minister Jaishankar – a multiplicity of places where we’re working together.  But I would say, again, we’re obviously focused on COVID together.  We’re focused on climate together.  We’re focused on the role of emerging technologies together.  But we’re also focused on strengthening our trade and investment relationship, bringing our scientists and technologists and innovators together, strengthening people-to-people ties.  We look forward to welcoming nearly 70,000 Indian students to the United States for this next semester.</p>
<p>So it’s incredibly broad, and what we’ve seen over the last 20 years, 25 years through different administrations in both countries is a relationship that’s only gotten stronger and deeper.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Squeezing in one last &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Very short.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  The – India will probably take delivery of the S-400 from Russia later this year.  How will that impact, given what the Congress – CAATSA act?  What – how would that impact U.S.-India relations?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, we have – we have our laws.  We’ll – we apply our laws, but we shared our concerns with India about this.  But I’m not going to get ahead of myself.  We’ll see how things evolve in the coming months.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you so much, Secretary.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>New Delhi, India</p>
<p>The Leela Palace Hotel</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Welcome to <em>The</em> <em>Times of India</em>, and &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So let’s just start off right.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  So what has – what have we achieved in the Quad so far?  And where do you think it’s (inaudible)?  You’ve got a summit coming up.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, first we had the first ever leaders-level meeting of the Quad.  That was in and of itself very significant, because it just underscored the importance that the four countries – India, the United States, Japan, and Australia – attach to the Quad.  And what we’ve achieved already is bringing together four likeminded democracies in common purpose to deal with some of the most important problems and challenges facing our countries, and in fact facing the region and even the world, starting with COVID-19, and a commitment to work together to finance, to produce, to distribute millions of vaccines.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Are you satisfied with the progress on the vaccine?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Yeah, I think we’re making – we’re making progress on that.  I think the – when the leaders get together next, they’ll be able to assess that progress.  Of course, COVID-19 remains a huge challenge for all of us, and since the first virtual leaders meeting, the second wave hit India.  I’m proud that the United States was able to come to India’s assistance, as India came to our assistance early during the pandemic when we had real challenges.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  We’ve seen reports of a digital services tax that had been proposed by the U.S.  Is there something &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  I’m sorry, digital services?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  A digital services agreement between countries – likeminded countries, I guess.  Is there something that you &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  We’re – there – we’re doing work in a wide variety of areas, to include not just COVID-19, but working together on the climate crisis, working together on infrastructure, on maritime security, on – and on emerging technologies.  And that includes in the digital space.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  And if you would tell us, for Indian readers, because we are – we know the China challenge.  We’ve shed blood.  What – how would you describe the challenge of China to the world, to West and India &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  For the United States, in a way as for India, it’s both one of the most consequential and most complicated relationships that we have.  I think we’ve seen China – unfortunately, the government in Beijing act more repressively at home and more aggressively abroad in recent years.  That poses a challenge for all of us.  As we look at it, we see a relationship that is in parts adversarial, in parts competitive, and also in parts cooperative.  And I think what we’ve found is that whether it’s adversarial, whether it’s competitive, whether it’s cooperative, the most effective way to engage China is working with other countries that are similarly situated and that face similar challenges.  India, of course, is a strong partner for the United States.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Do you think the era of cooperation with China may be over?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  No.  As I said, I think the relationship has different elements in it.  Cooperation remains one of them because on some issues, it’s profoundly in our mutual interest to cooperate, and irrespective of the competition, irrespective of the adversarial nature of parts of the relationship, that’s – those interests remain.  Climate may be the best example.  That’s an issue that is important to all of us.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  With the troops withdrawal – U.S. troops withdrawal from Afghanistan, I have two questions.  One is:  Do you think it affects the U.S. credibility as a partner?  Second, as a woman, I have to ask this:  For 20 years, women have had a good run in Afghanistan.  Do you think we’re sort of feeding them to the wolves, so to speak?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Two things.  As you just said, 20 years.  It’s been 20 years.  We have to remember why we went to Afghanistan in the first place.  It’s because we were attacked on 9/11.  We went to do justice for – to those who attacked us and to try to make sure that it couldn’t happen again.  And we’ve largely succeeded in that effort.  Usama bin Ladin was brought to justice 10 years ago.  And al-Qaida, the organization that attacked us, in terms of its capacity to do that again from Afghanistan, that’s been vastly diminished.</p>
<p>It’s now 20 years later, a trillion dollars later, more than 4,500 American soldiers lost their lives later.  Afghanistan ultimately has to be able to shape its own future, but with our support.  Even as we withdraw our forces, we are staying very much engaged in Afghanistan with a strong embassy, with programs to support women and girls, economic development, humanitarian assistance, and the security forces.  So we’re remaining very much engaged – also with our diplomacy, because the only resolution to the conflict in Afghanistan is at the negotiating table, not at the battlefield.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Pakistan continues to support the Taliban.  And are we seeing the same effect in Afghanistan today that we saw for the last 20 years?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Pakistan has a vital role to play in using its influence with the Taliban to do whatever it can to make sure that the Taliban does not seek to take the country by force.  And it does have influence, and it does have a role to play, and we hope that it plays it.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  What are your priority items with India?  And when do we expect a presidential visit to India?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, I can’t put a date on it, but I know that President Biden very much looks forward to visiting India, and similarly to having Prime Minister Modi in the United States.  But no date yet, but I’m sure that that will come.</p>
<p>Look, in terms of priorities, the relationship is both so wide and so deep there are – as we discussed today through several hours with Foreign Minister Jaishankar – a multiplicity of places where we’re working together.  But I would say, again, we’re obviously focused on COVID together.  We’re focused on climate together.  We’re focused on the role of emerging technologies together.  But we’re also focused on strengthening our trade and investment relationship, bringing our scientists and technologists and innovators together, strengthening people-to-people ties.  We look forward to welcoming nearly 70,000 Indian students to the United States for this next semester.</p>
<p>So it’s incredibly broad, and what we’ve seen over the last 20 years, 25 years through different administrations in both countries is a relationship that’s only gotten stronger and deeper.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Squeezing in one last &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>MR PRICE:</strong>  Very short.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  The – India will probably take delivery of the S-400 from Russia later this year.  How will that impact, given what the Congress – CAATSA act?  What – how would that impact U.S.-India relations?</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Well, we have – we have our laws.  We’ll – we apply our laws, but we shared our concerns with India about this.  But I’m not going to get ahead of myself.  We’ll see how things evolve in the coming months.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong>  Thank you so much, Secretary.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Escalation of Violence along International Border between Armenia and Azerbaijan</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/escalation-of-violence-along-international-border-between-armenia-and-azerbaijan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 02:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=263183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States condemns the recent escalation of violence along the international border between Armenia and Azerbaijan.  We call on Armenia and Azerbaijan to uphold their ceasefire commitments by taking immediate steps to de-escalate the situation.</p>
<p>Continued tensions along the Armenia-Azerbaijan border underscore the fact that only a comprehensive resolution that addresses all outstanding issues can normalize relations between the two countries and allow the people of the region to live together peacefully.  The United States urges Armenia and Azerbaijan to return as soon as possible to substantive discussions under the auspices of the OSCE Minsk Group Co-Chairs to achieve a long-term political settlement to the conflict.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States condemns the recent escalation of violence along the international border between Armenia and Azerbaijan.  We call on Armenia and Azerbaijan to uphold their ceasefire commitments by taking immediate steps to de-escalate the situation.</p>
<p>Continued tensions along the Armenia-Azerbaijan border underscore the fact that only a comprehensive resolution that addresses all outstanding issues can normalize relations between the two countries and allow the people of the region to live together peacefully.  The United States urges Armenia and Azerbaijan to return as soon as possible to substantive discussions under the auspices of the OSCE Minsk Group Co-Chairs to achieve a long-term political settlement to the conflict.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
