<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 16:06:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>United States Announces Additional Humanitarian Assistance for the People of Yemen</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-announces-additional-humanitarian-assistance-for-the-people-of-yemen-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 16:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324927</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>During today’s 2022 High-Level Pledging Event for the Humanitarian Crisis in Yemen, I announced nearly $585 million in humanitarian assistance from the United States to the people of Yemen.  With this funding, the United States has provided nearly $4.5 billion to the Yemeni people since the crisis began more than seven years ago.  Amid all the humanitarian crises in the world, the generosity of the American people remains unwavering.  In keeping with the President’s commitment to help alleviate this suffering, today&#8217;s announcement is the largest single U.S. contribution to-date for the humanitarian response in Yemen. This announcement also reflects the scale of the crisis facing the Yemeni people.</p>
<p>The assistance includes more than $561 million from the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and more than $23 million from the State Department’s Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM).  This funding will enable our humanitarian partners to reach approximately 17 million people, including internally displaced and conflict-affected Yemenis, as well as refugees and asylum seekers in Yemen.  Our assistance helps reduce the risk of famine, prevent and treat severe malnutrition, stem the spread of disease, provide shelter to those in need, ensure children have access to education, provide families with access to clean water and sanitation, and support families to earn an income and rebuild their livelihoods.</p>
<p>The United States remains committed to delivering aid to the most vulnerable in Yemen, and we commend the generous pledges made by other donors at today’s event. However, more aid is desperately needed.  Funding gaps have forced significant cuts to life-saving humanitarian programs, depriving millions of Yemenis of the support they need.  As this conflict pushes Yemen deeper into crisis, we urgently call on donors to fulfill pledges quickly and to rapidly scale up assistance.  We also urge those who have not yet pledged to do so.</p>
<p>Additionally, this assistance is vital to saving lives and reducing suffering, but it must be able to reach the people who need it most.  We again call on all parties to cease interference in aid operations to ensure assistance is reaching its intended recipients.</p>
<p>Humanitarian assistance alone cannot address the roots of this crisis; we urge the parties to the conflict to halt hostilities to make way for a durable, inclusive political solution to this conflict for the sake of the people.  We welcome the launch of inclusive consultations by UN Special Envoy Hans Grunberg, and we call on all parties to participate fully in these consultations, which will inform a new, comprehensive UN framework for the peace process.</p>
<p>For the latest updates on U.S. humanitarian assistance in Yemen, visit: <a class="external-link" href="https://www.usaid.gov/humanitarian-assistance/yemen" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://www.usaid.gov/humanitarian-assistance/yemen</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> <wbr /></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>During today’s 2022 High-Level Pledging Event for the Humanitarian Crisis in Yemen, I announced nearly $585 million in humanitarian assistance from the United States to the people of Yemen.  With this funding, the United States has provided nearly $4.5 billion to the Yemeni people since the crisis began more than seven years ago.  Amid all the humanitarian crises in the world, the generosity of the American people remains unwavering.  In keeping with the President’s commitment to help alleviate this suffering, today&#8217;s announcement is the largest single U.S. contribution to-date for the humanitarian response in Yemen. This announcement also reflects the scale of the crisis facing the Yemeni people.</p>
<p>The assistance includes more than $561 million from the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and more than $23 million from the State Department’s Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM).  This funding will enable our humanitarian partners to reach approximately 17 million people, including internally displaced and conflict-affected Yemenis, as well as refugees and asylum seekers in Yemen.  Our assistance helps reduce the risk of famine, prevent and treat severe malnutrition, stem the spread of disease, provide shelter to those in need, ensure children have access to education, provide families with access to clean water and sanitation, and support families to earn an income and rebuild their livelihoods.</p>
<p>The United States remains committed to delivering aid to the most vulnerable in Yemen, and we commend the generous pledges made by other donors at today’s event. However, more aid is desperately needed.  Funding gaps have forced significant cuts to life-saving humanitarian programs, depriving millions of Yemenis of the support they need.  As this conflict pushes Yemen deeper into crisis, we urgently call on donors to fulfill pledges quickly and to rapidly scale up assistance.  We also urge those who have not yet pledged to do so.</p>
<p>Additionally, this assistance is vital to saving lives and reducing suffering, but it must be able to reach the people who need it most.  We again call on all parties to cease interference in aid operations to ensure assistance is reaching its intended recipients.</p>
<p>Humanitarian assistance alone cannot address the roots of this crisis; we urge the parties to the conflict to halt hostilities to make way for a durable, inclusive political solution to this conflict for the sake of the people.  We welcome the launch of inclusive consultations by UN Special Envoy Hans Grunberg, and we call on all parties to participate fully in these consultations, which will inform a new, comprehensive UN framework for the peace process.</p>
<p>For the latest updates on U.S. humanitarian assistance in Yemen, visit: <a class="external-link" href="https://www.usaid.gov/humanitarian-assistance/yemen" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://www.usaid.gov/humanitarian-assistance/yemen</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> <wbr /></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Virtual Remarks at the UN-Hosted High-Level Yemen Pledging Event</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-virtual-remarks-at-the-un-hosted-high-level-yemen-pledging-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 16:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324907</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  President Cassis, thank you very much.  It’s very good to see you today via video.  To Secretary-General Guterres, António, thank you for bringing us together.  Under Secretary Griffiths, thank you for the work you and your team are doing every single day, not only in Yemen but quite literally around the world.  And to my friend Ann Linde as well, thank you for everything you’re doing in leading this conference.  And I do want to say as well a special note of thanks to Special Envoy Jolie for doing something that’s so important, which is actually putting the focus on what this is all about – the men, the women, the children who are affected in so many ways by this ongoing crisis in Yemen.</p>
<p>And I hope that each of us just takes a minute as we’re thinking about this, thinking about our responsibilities, to try to put ourselves in their shoes, to imagine if this was your son or your daughter, your mother, your father, your sister, your brother, and think about what that actually means and maybe find some additional motivation to continue to take action.  As Martin said at the outset and as others have said, we’re faced with a multiplicity of challenges around the world, and it’s particularly difficult when the spotlight has moved elsewhere.  That’s when the real test comes.  Can we keep our focus?  Can we keep our engagement?  Can we keep our determination?  Can we run and chew gum at the same time?  That’s what we have to do here, because once again, we are meeting at what is a dire time for Yemen.</p>
<p>We’ve heard the numbers.  I won’t repeat all of them, but again, just to emphasize, two out of three Yemenis require humanitarian assistance for basic necessities.  That includes more than 17 million Yemenis who need food assistance, a number that, as we’ve heard, is expected to rise to 19 million in the second half of 2022.   The number of Yemenis facing famine conditions is predicted to increase fivefold to over 160,000, and right now, more than 2 million children suffer from life-threatening malnutrition.  And we’ve heard, again, people pay witness to that.</p>
<p>And yet, even as humanitarian needs in Yemen are rising, contributions are falling.  Funding shortfalls have already forced the UN to close or reduce two-thirds of its critical humanitarian programs in the country.  Food rations for 8 million Yemenis have been significantly reduced.  Without a significant surge in resources, those reduced rations will be eliminated entirely in the coming months, and again, I ask each of us to think about what that actually means in human terms.  If that’s not enough, the Russian Government’s unprovoked aggression in Ukraine threatens a significant source of Yemen’s imported wheat.  Just in the first week of this month alone, in March, many Yemenis saw bread prices shoot up 50 percent.</p>
<p>So to help meet the urgent needs, today the United States is announcing nearly $585 million in new humanitarian aid to Yemen.  That brings the total we’ve provided since the outset of the conflict to about $4.5 billion.  This is important.  It’s important for all of us to step up, but there are other things that are vital if we’re actually going to deal with the challenge that people are facing in Yemen.  To prevent a humanitarian catastrophe from fully unfolding, more support as needed, not just from us but from others.  And we welcome the commitments made today by other donors.  We urge everyone to step up, to do their part.</p>
<p>But as others have said, the humanitarian support is one side of the equation.  This doesn’t work fundamentally in the absence of peace, in the absence of a resolution.  So we have to work relentlessly to bring the conflict to an end, knowing that as long as it goes on so will the humanitarian crisis.  We can mitigate it, we can reduce it, we can address it, but in order to really deal with it, we have to have peace.  It’s as basic and as simple as that.  Absent that, misery will continue; suffering will continue.  We all know that.  So we have to redouble our efforts there too as well.</p>
<p>To that end, the United States strongly supports UN Special Envoy Grundberg’s efforts to launch a more inclusive, comprehensive peace process that will improve the lives of Yemenis and allow them to collectively determine their own future.  Our Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking is working to support that effort, including in his travel to Yemen and the Gulf over the past couple of weeks.</p>
<p>The first step toward resolution is de-escalation, and yet here too, in recent months, we have seen just the opposite.  That’s why we condemn the escalating attacks by the Houthis, including cross-border attacks in January that killed civilians in the United Arab Emirates, wounded civilians in Saudi Arabia.  It’s why we continue to work to help strengthen the defense of our Saudi and Emirati partners.  It’s also why we call on all parties to the conflict to respect international humanitarian law, stop attacks on civilians, stop attacks on civilian infrastructure.  Humanitarian assistance has to be allowed to flow into Yemen through all entry points throughout the country, freely, without interruption.  And attacks on the staff of humanitarian organizations have to stop immediately.  Every country has a responsibility to bring pressure to bear so that life-saving aid can actually get to those who need it.</p>
<p>For all the suffering that’s been wrought by this conflict, I have to say that it’s also demonstrated the remarkable heart, the remarkable courage of the Yemeni people.  There’s so many individual examples of this.  Some of them come to the fore through the spotlight that people like the special envoy bring to this, the media in its efforts to report what’s going on.  But I’m thinking of people like Ameen Jubran, who co-founded Jeel Albena, an organization that aids displaced Yemenis.  The group’s motto is: by Yemenis, for Yemenis.  It’s built more than 18,000 emergency shelters for displaced families.</p>
<p>To Ameen, a mean a shelter is more than a roof.  Here’s how he put it:  If they have adequate shelter, it protects the family’s dignity.  This is something that he knows intimately.  Like so many of his colleagues, he and his family have been displaced multiple times since the conflict began.  And yet, they continue to risk their lives in some of the most dangerous parts of Yemen to help others live with dignity.</p>
<p>So we have to do all we can to ensure that the United Nations and countless groups like Ameen’s can actually continue their life-saving work in Yemen.  That’s what today is all about, and even as we do that, we have to redouble our efforts to finally – finally – bring peace to this country. Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</b>  President Cassis, thank you very much.  It’s very good to see you today via video.  To Secretary-General Guterres, António, thank you for bringing us together.  Under Secretary Griffiths, thank you for the work you and your team are doing every single day, not only in Yemen but quite literally around the world.  And to my friend Ann Linde as well, thank you for everything you’re doing in leading this conference.  And I do want to say as well a special note of thanks to Special Envoy Jolie for doing something that’s so important, which is actually putting the focus on what this is all about – the men, the women, the children who are affected in so many ways by this ongoing crisis in Yemen.</p>
<p>And I hope that each of us just takes a minute as we’re thinking about this, thinking about our responsibilities, to try to put ourselves in their shoes, to imagine if this was your son or your daughter, your mother, your father, your sister, your brother, and think about what that actually means and maybe find some additional motivation to continue to take action.  As Martin said at the outset and as others have said, we’re faced with a multiplicity of challenges around the world, and it’s particularly difficult when the spotlight has moved elsewhere.  That’s when the real test comes.  Can we keep our focus?  Can we keep our engagement?  Can we keep our determination?  Can we run and chew gum at the same time?  That’s what we have to do here, because once again, we are meeting at what is a dire time for Yemen.</p>
<p>We’ve heard the numbers.  I won’t repeat all of them, but again, just to emphasize, two out of three Yemenis require humanitarian assistance for basic necessities.  That includes more than 17 million Yemenis who need food assistance, a number that, as we’ve heard, is expected to rise to 19 million in the second half of 2022.   The number of Yemenis facing famine conditions is predicted to increase fivefold to over 160,000, and right now, more than 2 million children suffer from life-threatening malnutrition.  And we’ve heard, again, people pay witness to that.</p>
<p>And yet, even as humanitarian needs in Yemen are rising, contributions are falling.  Funding shortfalls have already forced the UN to close or reduce two-thirds of its critical humanitarian programs in the country.  Food rations for 8 million Yemenis have been significantly reduced.  Without a significant surge in resources, those reduced rations will be eliminated entirely in the coming months, and again, I ask each of us to think about what that actually means in human terms.  If that’s not enough, the Russian Government’s unprovoked aggression in Ukraine threatens a significant source of Yemen’s imported wheat.  Just in the first week of this month alone, in March, many Yemenis saw bread prices shoot up 50 percent.</p>
<p>So to help meet the urgent needs, today the United States is announcing nearly $585 million in new humanitarian aid to Yemen.  That brings the total we’ve provided since the outset of the conflict to about $4.5 billion.  This is important.  It’s important for all of us to step up, but there are other things that are vital if we’re actually going to deal with the challenge that people are facing in Yemen.  To prevent a humanitarian catastrophe from fully unfolding, more support as needed, not just from us but from others.  And we welcome the commitments made today by other donors.  We urge everyone to step up, to do their part.</p>
<p>But as others have said, the humanitarian support is one side of the equation.  This doesn’t work fundamentally in the absence of peace, in the absence of a resolution.  So we have to work relentlessly to bring the conflict to an end, knowing that as long as it goes on so will the humanitarian crisis.  We can mitigate it, we can reduce it, we can address it, but in order to really deal with it, we have to have peace.  It’s as basic and as simple as that.  Absent that, misery will continue; suffering will continue.  We all know that.  So we have to redouble our efforts there too as well.</p>
<p>To that end, the United States strongly supports UN Special Envoy Grundberg’s efforts to launch a more inclusive, comprehensive peace process that will improve the lives of Yemenis and allow them to collectively determine their own future.  Our Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking is working to support that effort, including in his travel to Yemen and the Gulf over the past couple of weeks.</p>
<p>The first step toward resolution is de-escalation, and yet here too, in recent months, we have seen just the opposite.  That’s why we condemn the escalating attacks by the Houthis, including cross-border attacks in January that killed civilians in the United Arab Emirates, wounded civilians in Saudi Arabia.  It’s why we continue to work to help strengthen the defense of our Saudi and Emirati partners.  It’s also why we call on all parties to the conflict to respect international humanitarian law, stop attacks on civilians, stop attacks on civilian infrastructure.  Humanitarian assistance has to be allowed to flow into Yemen through all entry points throughout the country, freely, without interruption.  And attacks on the staff of humanitarian organizations have to stop immediately.  Every country has a responsibility to bring pressure to bear so that life-saving aid can actually get to those who need it.</p>
<p>For all the suffering that’s been wrought by this conflict, I have to say that it’s also demonstrated the remarkable heart, the remarkable courage of the Yemeni people.  There’s so many individual examples of this.  Some of them come to the fore through the spotlight that people like the special envoy bring to this, the media in its efforts to report what’s going on.  But I’m thinking of people like Ameen Jubran, who co-founded Jeel Albena, an organization that aids displaced Yemenis.  The group’s motto is: by Yemenis, for Yemenis.  It’s built more than 18,000 emergency shelters for displaced families.</p>
<p>To Ameen, a mean a shelter is more than a roof.  Here’s how he put it:  If they have adequate shelter, it protects the family’s dignity.  This is something that he knows intimately.  Like so many of his colleagues, he and his family have been displaced multiple times since the conflict began.  And yet, they continue to risk their lives in some of the most dangerous parts of Yemen to help others live with dignity.</p>
<p>So we have to do all we can to ensure that the United Nations and countless groups like Ameen’s can actually continue their life-saving work in Yemen.  That’s what today is all about, and even as we do that, we have to redouble our efforts to finally – finally – bring peace to this country. Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken With Wolf Blitzer of The Situation Room on CNN</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-with-wolf-blitzer-of-the-situation-room-on-cnn/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 01:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324685</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Let’s discuss what’s going on with U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken.  Mr. Secretary, thank you so much for joining us.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Hey, Wolf.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>So I – as you well know, obviously, the President will attend this truly extraordinary meeting of all the NATO leaders next week in Brussels.  Is this purely a show of NATO strength, NATO force, or will they take new concrete steps to stop the Russian aggression?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Wolf, it’s a continuation of what we’ve been doing all along, which is bringing allies and partners together in support of Ukraine in very concrete ways, and to exert maximum pressure on Russia to stop the aggression that it’s committing.  And so the President has been in constant contact with his counterparts – from throughout Europe, NATO leaders, the European Union, et cetera, and around the world – but this is an important opportunity to have everyone in the same room, in the same place to continue to map out the strategy – the strategy that has, as I said, exerted incredible pressure on Russia as well as showing incredible support for Ukraine.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>I assume all 30 leaders of NATO will be there.  Just moments ago, President Zelenskyy signaled that Ukraine won’t join NATO anytime soon, saying – and I’m quoting him now as saying: for years we have been hearing about how the door is supposedly open to NATO membership, but now we hear that we cannot enter, and it is true and it must be acknowledged.*  That’s a quote from President Zelenskyy.  Is that a direct concession to Putin?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>I don’t think that’s a concession.  I think, first of all, it’s a reflection of reality that even before this aggression by Russia, Ukraine was not going to get into NATO tomorrow.  All the more reason why, as we’ve seen, when Putin was saying that their concerns about Ukraine centered on its admission to NATO, that was wrong; that was a lie.  What this is about, what Putin’s demonstrated it’s about, is denying Ukraine its independent existence.  But what we’ve done in support of Ukraine is to provide extraordinary security assistance that continues as we speak to make sure that Ukraine has the means to defend itself.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>As the risk of miscalculation, though, grows, the UN secretary-general says that the prospect of nuclear – nuclear – conflict is now, and I’m quoting him now, “within the realm of possibility.”  How real is the risk of this spiraling into nuclear war?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, President Biden has been very clear that one thing is for sure, is that we’re going to avoid getting into any kind of conflict with Russia, and certainly avoiding anything that brings us to World War Three.  Some of Russia’s loose talk about its nuclear weapons is the height of irresponsibility and goes against everything that we’ve said, including that Russia has said over many years, about how a nuclear war is not winnable – something that was reaffirmed as recently as the meeting between President Biden and Putin back in – this summer in Geneva.</p>
<p>So we watch this very, very, very carefully.  There’s a lot of bad, loose talk and bluster.  At the same time, I have to tell you we have real concerns that Russia could use a chemical – a weapon, another weapon of mass destruction.  This is something we’re very focused on.  Unfortunately, we’ve seen them use or acquiesce to its use before in Syria, with Syria using these weapons, using them itself, trying to assassinate its opponents, including in the United Kingdom.  So this is something we are very focused on.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Well, if they do use chemical weapons, what will the U.S. and the NATO Allies do?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>We’ve been very clear, including with Russia, with others, that there would be a very serious response not just from us, but from the international community.  I’m not going to spell it out here, but the consequences would be severe.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Russia is also targeting civilians; they’re attacking hospitals, schools.  Why is the White House so far refusing to come right out and say what the Russian – what the Russians are doing right now, that that’s a war crime?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>We are documenting everything we’re seeing.  We welcome the efforts that are being made, including investigations conducted by NGOs and institutions to look at this, to put everything together to determine whether the acts that Russia is engaged in would constitute a war crime.  We’re looking at whether there are deliberate attacks on civilians.  There’s certainly very credible reports and evidence of that, but what we’re doing is putting it all together, documenting it, and the appropriate institutions will make that judgement.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>The U.S. believes China has signaled some openness to providing military support to Russia.  What’s your message, Mr. Secretary, to China as it weighs how much support it will actually provide to Putin?</p>
<p><b>SECRETAR BLINKEN:  </b>Well, Wolf, there are two things.  First, there is the rhetorical support, or at least the absence of clear rhetorical denunciation by China of what Russia is doing.  And this flies in the face of everything that China purports to stand for, including the basic principles of the UN Charter, including the basic principle of respect for sovereignty of nations.  And so the fact that China has not denounced what Russia is doing in and of itself speaks volumes.  And it speaks volumes not only in Russia or in Ukraine; it speaks volumes in Europe and in other places around the world.</p>
<p>Second, we are concerned at the prospect of China providing material support to Russia or undermining the sanctions that we put in place with countries around the world, something that we’ve communicated directly to China, including just this – in the past 24 hours when the National Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan, met with his Chinese counterpart Yang Jiechi.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>So if the Chinese do provide military support to the Russians, what will the U.S. do?</p>
<p><b>SECRETAR BLINKEN:  </b>Again, without going into specifics of what we’ll do, we’ve made very clear that that’s not something that we’re going to take sitting down.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>As you know, Putin is making truly outlandish and very, very offensive claims that he’s de-Nazifying Ukraine.  You and I both have family who survived the Holocaust; President Zelenskyy does as well.  Do you think the U.S. will look back on this time right now and wish the West had done more to stop Putin?</p>
<p><b>SECRETAR BLINKEN:  </b>Wolf, it’s hard to project into the future.  I can tell you a couple of things, though, that I’m confident of.  First of all, there’s going to be a Ukraine, an independent Ukraine, a lot longer than there’s going to be Vladimir Putin.  One way or the other, Ukraine will be there, and at some point Putin won’t.  The real question is how much death and destruction is wrought by Russia’s aggression in the meantime, and that’s what we’re working as hard as we can to limit, to stop, to put an end to this war of choice that Russia is committing.</p>
<p>And we’re doing that through the support we’re providing to Ukraine every single day.  We’re doing that by the pressure we’re exerting against Russia every single day.  And my hope is that we can end this sooner rather than later so that that death and destruction doesn’t continue.  But I can tell you how this is going to end ultimately:  It’s going to end with an independent Ukraine, and at some point, it’s going to end without Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>So what’s your message to Putin right now?</p>
<p><b>SECRETAR BLINKEN:  </b>Message to Putin is: end this war; stop this war that you’re committing; end the aggression that is unjustified, unprovoked.</p>
<p>We’ve looked over many months at giving President Putin appropriate offramps to end this before the aggression, since the aggression started.  Unfortunately, each and every time he’s pressed the accelerator.  It’s time to stop with the accelerator.  It’s time to stop the war, stop the killing, stop the destruction – that’s the message.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Sadly, he’s showing at least so far no sign of that.  But we will hope and pray. Secretary Blinken, thank you so much for joining us.</p>
<p><b>SECRETAR BLINKEN:  </b>Thanks, Wolf.  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Let’s discuss what’s going on with U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken.  Mr. Secretary, thank you so much for joining us.</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Hey, Wolf.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>So I – as you well know, obviously, the President will attend this truly extraordinary meeting of all the NATO leaders next week in Brussels.  Is this purely a show of NATO strength, NATO force, or will they take new concrete steps to stop the Russian aggression?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Wolf, it’s a continuation of what we’ve been doing all along, which is bringing allies and partners together in support of Ukraine in very concrete ways, and to exert maximum pressure on Russia to stop the aggression that it’s committing.  And so the President has been in constant contact with his counterparts – from throughout Europe, NATO leaders, the European Union, et cetera, and around the world – but this is an important opportunity to have everyone in the same room, in the same place to continue to map out the strategy – the strategy that has, as I said, exerted incredible pressure on Russia as well as showing incredible support for Ukraine.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>I assume all 30 leaders of NATO will be there.  Just moments ago, President Zelenskyy signaled that Ukraine won’t join NATO anytime soon, saying – and I’m quoting him now as saying: for years we have been hearing about how the door is supposedly open to NATO membership, but now we hear that we cannot enter, and it is true and it must be acknowledged.*  That’s a quote from President Zelenskyy.  Is that a direct concession to Putin?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>I don’t think that’s a concession.  I think, first of all, it’s a reflection of reality that even before this aggression by Russia, Ukraine was not going to get into NATO tomorrow.  All the more reason why, as we’ve seen, when Putin was saying that their concerns about Ukraine centered on its admission to NATO, that was wrong; that was a lie.  What this is about, what Putin’s demonstrated it’s about, is denying Ukraine its independent existence.  But what we’ve done in support of Ukraine is to provide extraordinary security assistance that continues as we speak to make sure that Ukraine has the means to defend itself.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>As the risk of miscalculation, though, grows, the UN secretary-general says that the prospect of nuclear – nuclear – conflict is now, and I’m quoting him now, “within the realm of possibility.”  How real is the risk of this spiraling into nuclear war?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>Well, President Biden has been very clear that one thing is for sure, is that we’re going to avoid getting into any kind of conflict with Russia, and certainly avoiding anything that brings us to World War Three.  Some of Russia’s loose talk about its nuclear weapons is the height of irresponsibility and goes against everything that we’ve said, including that Russia has said over many years, about how a nuclear war is not winnable – something that was reaffirmed as recently as the meeting between President Biden and Putin back in – this summer in Geneva.</p>
<p>So we watch this very, very, very carefully.  There’s a lot of bad, loose talk and bluster.  At the same time, I have to tell you we have real concerns that Russia could use a chemical – a weapon, another weapon of mass destruction.  This is something we’re very focused on.  Unfortunately, we’ve seen them use or acquiesce to its use before in Syria, with Syria using these weapons, using them itself, trying to assassinate its opponents, including in the United Kingdom.  So this is something we are very focused on.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Well, if they do use chemical weapons, what will the U.S. and the NATO Allies do?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>We’ve been very clear, including with Russia, with others, that there would be a very serious response not just from us, but from the international community.  I’m not going to spell it out here, but the consequences would be severe.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Russia is also targeting civilians; they’re attacking hospitals, schools.  Why is the White House so far refusing to come right out and say what the Russian – what the Russians are doing right now, that that’s a war crime?</p>
<p><b>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </b>We are documenting everything we’re seeing.  We welcome the efforts that are being made, including investigations conducted by NGOs and institutions to look at this, to put everything together to determine whether the acts that Russia is engaged in would constitute a war crime.  We’re looking at whether there are deliberate attacks on civilians.  There’s certainly very credible reports and evidence of that, but what we’re doing is putting it all together, documenting it, and the appropriate institutions will make that judgement.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>The U.S. believes China has signaled some openness to providing military support to Russia.  What’s your message, Mr. Secretary, to China as it weighs how much support it will actually provide to Putin?</p>
<p><b>SECRETAR BLINKEN:  </b>Well, Wolf, there are two things.  First, there is the rhetorical support, or at least the absence of clear rhetorical denunciation by China of what Russia is doing.  And this flies in the face of everything that China purports to stand for, including the basic principles of the UN Charter, including the basic principle of respect for sovereignty of nations.  And so the fact that China has not denounced what Russia is doing in and of itself speaks volumes.  And it speaks volumes not only in Russia or in Ukraine; it speaks volumes in Europe and in other places around the world.</p>
<p>Second, we are concerned at the prospect of China providing material support to Russia or undermining the sanctions that we put in place with countries around the world, something that we’ve communicated directly to China, including just this – in the past 24 hours when the National Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan, met with his Chinese counterpart Yang Jiechi.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>So if the Chinese do provide military support to the Russians, what will the U.S. do?</p>
<p><b>SECRETAR BLINKEN:  </b>Again, without going into specifics of what we’ll do, we’ve made very clear that that’s not something that we’re going to take sitting down.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>As you know, Putin is making truly outlandish and very, very offensive claims that he’s de-Nazifying Ukraine.  You and I both have family who survived the Holocaust; President Zelenskyy does as well.  Do you think the U.S. will look back on this time right now and wish the West had done more to stop Putin?</p>
<p><b>SECRETAR BLINKEN:  </b>Wolf, it’s hard to project into the future.  I can tell you a couple of things, though, that I’m confident of.  First of all, there’s going to be a Ukraine, an independent Ukraine, a lot longer than there’s going to be Vladimir Putin.  One way or the other, Ukraine will be there, and at some point Putin won’t.  The real question is how much death and destruction is wrought by Russia’s aggression in the meantime, and that’s what we’re working as hard as we can to limit, to stop, to put an end to this war of choice that Russia is committing.</p>
<p>And we’re doing that through the support we’re providing to Ukraine every single day.  We’re doing that by the pressure we’re exerting against Russia every single day.  And my hope is that we can end this sooner rather than later so that that death and destruction doesn’t continue.  But I can tell you how this is going to end ultimately:  It’s going to end with an independent Ukraine, and at some point, it’s going to end without Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>So what’s your message to Putin right now?</p>
<p><b>SECRETAR BLINKEN:  </b>Message to Putin is: end this war; stop this war that you’re committing; end the aggression that is unjustified, unprovoked.</p>
<p>We’ve looked over many months at giving President Putin appropriate offramps to end this before the aggression, since the aggression started.  Unfortunately, each and every time he’s pressed the accelerator.  It’s time to stop with the accelerator.  It’s time to stop the war, stop the killing, stop the destruction – that’s the message.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Sadly, he’s showing at least so far no sign of that.  But we will hope and pray. Secretary Blinken, thank you so much for joining us.</p>
<p><b>SECRETAR BLINKEN:  </b>Thanks, Wolf.  Good to be with you.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:  </b>Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Briefing with Senior Administration Officials on the U.S. Humanitarian Assistance Response to Russia’s Further Invasion of Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefing-with-senior-administration-officials-on-the-u-s-humanitarian-assistance-response-to-russias-further-invasion-of-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 01:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324682</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Thank you, Ryan, and thank you, everyone, for joining us this afternoon for this briefing on the U.S. humanitarian assistance response to Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>Here at the top, before we get started, I would like to remind everyone that this briefing is on background with attribution to senior administration officials, and that the contents of this call are embargoed until the end of the briefing.</p>
<p>For the purposes of your reporting, you can refer to our briefers as Senior Administration Official Number One, Senior Administration Official Number Two, and Senior Administration Official Number Three.</p>
<p>Now, for your information but not for your reporting, I’m going to go ahead and let you know who our briefers are this afternoon.  I’m very glad to have with us ;  be Senior Administration Official Number One.  ;  be Senior Administration Official Number Two.  And third, , or Senior Administration Official Number Three.</p>
<p>Okay, we’re going to start our briefing today just with some brief remarks from each of our speakers and then we’ll take a few of your questions.  Again, let me just say that this briefing this afternoon is on the U.S. humanitarian assistance in response to Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine.  I would like to go ahead and ask folks to please limit your questions to that topic.  We’ve already had excellent briefings today from Press Secretary Jen Psaki over at the White House and Spokesperson Ned Price here at State covering the full gamut of issues with regard to Russia and its invasion of Ukraine, so we’ll ask you again to limit your questions to humanitarian assistance and our response in that regard.</p>
<p>Okay.  And with that, I’m going to go ahead and turn it over to  to get us started.  ?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL NUMBER ONE:</b>  Thank you and good afternoon, everyone.  I appreciate the opportunity to speak with you today about USAID’s humanitarian response to the crisis in Ukraine following Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.</p>
<p>Since this senseless campaign of unprovoked violence has begun, 4.7 million people have been displaced in and out of Ukraine.  That’s over 10 percent of Ukraine’s population, but one that the UN thinks the real figures may be significantly higher.</p>
<p>Putin’s war has turned nearly 3 million Ukrainians into refugees, including 1 million children, some of whom are forced to flee without their parents.  Nearly 2 million people are displaced inside of Ukraine.  We are hearing distressing reports from our partners in cities like Mariupol, where people remain in dire conditions and lack safe drinking water, food, fuel, and electricity.  The extensive damage we are seeing also means that shelter may be inadequate at a time when people face cold weather.  All of this is compounded by the terror of living under bombardment.</p>
<p>As the war continues into its third week, as just one of the many examples of the horrors civilians face, we are seeing Russian forces target schools and hospitals with a campaign of terror that has interrupted the cancer treatment for 1,500 children who are now forced to flee as bombs rain down on them while crossing into foreign countries with compromised immune systems during a pandemic with only the supplies they can carry.</p>
<p>We call for an immediate end to this needless war of aggression.  Short of that, the United States strongly supports the United Nations’ call for the establishment of safe passage of civilians out of areas under Russian attack and safe passage for aid workers attempting to provide humanitarian and medical supplies.  Russia must negotiate in good faith on these issues immediately.</p>
<p>In the face of this catastrophic toll on the people of Ukraine, you are seeing the U.S. stand united with our allies to aid those who are suffering.  USAID’s Disaster Assistance Response Team, or DART, has been in the region since the early days of Russia’s unprovoked war, making up-to-the-minute assessments of humanitarian needs and quickly ramping up assistance in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Over the past week alone, USAID has rapidly deployed four planeloads of lifesaving supplies from our warehouse in Dubai and mobilized our partners to immediately stand up surge support.</p>
<p>This includes blankets, high energy biscuits, kitchen sets, water treatment supplies, which USAID partner International Organization for Migration, or IOM, will distribute to vulnerable Ukrainians.</p>
<p>We’ve also worked with our partner the World Health Organization to provide emergency health kits with vital medicines and medical supplies, as well as trauma and emergency surgery kits to support emergency surgeries.  These supplies, which serve upwards of 100,000 people, are directly supporting the Government of Ukraine’s health care system, which has been badly damaged since the war began.</p>
<p>USAID partner the UN World Food Program also transported 500 metric tons of wheat flour, enough to provide bread for 500,000 people for a week, to Kyiv.  A WFP-contracted bakery also delivered nearly 15 metric tons of bread – sent to meet the needs of 60,000 people – to hospitals in Kharkiv.</p>
<p>Through our partners, we also continue to provide critical psychosocial support to children, people with disabilities, and older people, operating mobile medical units and protection teams to reach remote, displaced, or homebound communities and conducting mine-risk education activities to minimize protection risk.</p>
<p>In total, the United States has provided nearly 293 million in additional humanitarian assistance in just the last two weeks, including nearly 81 million from USAID.  We will continue to stand with the Ukrainian people during this crisis and work to meet their needs.</p>
<p>However, despite this project – progress, the situation on the ground in Ukraine is rapidly getting worse.  Russian bombardment and shelling continues to damage the infrastructure needed to get aid to people, destroying roads, bridges, and railroads, and making it difficult for aid workers to reach people in need.  In the absence of a ceasefire, humanitarian safe passage must be assured in order to allow aid workers to reach those in need.  As humanitarian needs continue to rise, USAID is working closely with European allies and partners who are on the front lines of this response on how to support people displaced internally and other people affected by the conflict.  We will continue to coordinate closely with the UN, other donors and partners to urge that robust humanitarian assistance can continue to prevent gaps in basic service delivery.</p>
<p>Thank you for your time.  I’d now like to pass it to  for  remarks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b>  Hi.  Thank you, , and thank you everybody for being here this afternoon.</p>
<p>I’m from , and we really want to underscore that our partnership with and commitment to the people of Ukraine and their government is steadfast and enduring.  We will continue to support and stand with them.</p>
<p>Today I want to share with you more about the enormous humanitarian efforts underway to assist the 12 million people in need of assistance across Ukraine, and the nearly 3 million refugees throughout neighboring countries due to the Russian Federation’s unprovoked and unjustified attack against Ukraine.</p>
<p>We are working with the Government of Ukraine, neighboring governments in the region, the European Union, international organizations like the United Nations, and other partners around the clock to address the urgent humanitarian needs of this crisis.  We are closely coordinating with these partners to monitor developments, assess needs, and respond accordingly.</p>
<p>Historically, the United States is the largest single country donor of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  Since the start of the current crisis, we have announced nearly $293 million in additional assistance to those affected by Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, including more than 186 million announced today.  This includes nearly 81 million from USAID, and nearly 212 million from the Department of State, and we will continue to do even more.</p>
<p>With this new contribution, we will complement the tremendous efforts of neighboring countries generously welcoming refugees.  We will work through our international and nongovernmental partners who provide food, safe drinking water, shelter, emergency health care, and protection.  This assistance will also support vulnerable populations inside Ukraine, as our humanitarian organization partners work tirelessly to provide safe passage for evacuees trying to leave danger.</p>
<p>Since the conflict in Ukraine began eight years ago, the United States has provided over 644 million in humanitarian assistance to vulnerable communities across Ukraine.  We will continue to support our European allies and partners who are at the forefront of this response, as well as international organizations and nongovernmental organizations working to mitigate the humanitarian impacts of this crisis.</p>
<p>We are also committed to working with a range of partners and stakeholders, including the Ukrainian diaspora community, to ensure that humanitarian organizations are prepared to respond to existing and new needs that arise in Ukraine and the neighboring countries.  The courage of the people of Ukraine and the generosity of all who have stepped up in their time of need is inspiring, and we will continue to stand with Ukraine.</p>
<p>Thank you, and I will turn it over to .  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THREE:</b>  Thank you, .  Good afternoon, everyone.  I’m here representing  to share information about visa processing for Ukrainians.</p>
<p>But first, just for a second, I want to go off – slightly off-topic and reiterate the State Department Travel Advisory for Ukraine is at a Level Four – Do Not Travel due to increased threat of Russian military action.  Our recommendations to U.S. citizens currently in Ukraine is that they should leave now using available transportation options if it is safe to do so.  We continue to encourage U.S. citizens in Ukraine to fill out our online form to let us know where they are, what they’re doing.</p>
<p>Turning to visas, given the suspension of our operations in Ukraine, the State Department is not offering visa services in Ukraine at this time.  I’ll talk a little bit about immigrant visas first and then nonimmigrant visas.  We want to share this information to further clarify visa options and outline alternatives to visas that Ukrainians may consider.  It’s important to note that a visa is not a viable way to achieve refugee resettlement in the United States.</p>
<p>We understand that any U.S. citizens who leave Ukraine may have families with mixed immigration status, for example, a U.S. citizen whose spouse has not yet started or completed the immigrant visa process.  We are prioritizing consular support to U.S. citizens and their immediate family members in this regard.  The Immigration and Nationality Act defines immediate family members as spouse, unmarried children under 21, and parents, so that’s our focus for immigrant visas.</p>
<p>We have designated the U.S. Consulate General in Frankfurt as the processing post for all the immigrant visa applications that would have been processed in Kyiv, with the exception of adoption cases, which will be handled at the U.S. embassy in Warsaw.</p>
<p>Ukraine passport holders can enter Schengen countries without a visa.  U.S. citizens and their immediate family members should relocate to a safe place and then follow detailed guidance on visa processing on our website and the website of the nearest U.S. embassy or consulate.  U.S. citizens who are overseas with the immediate family members that I described and have not yet filed an immigrant visa petition with USCIS may request to file a petition at the nearest embassy or consulate that processes immigrant visas.  Again, this only applies to the spouses, unmarried children under 21, and the parents that I just described.  Individuals who already have a USCIS-approved current petition for an immigrant visa for their relatives of any kind who have not yet been scheduled for an immigrant visa interview may be able to request expedited processing through the National Visa Center.</p>
<p>Now turning to nonimmigrant visas, again, I want to reiterate that nonimmigrant visas are for temporary stays in the United States.  They’re not the appropriate tool to begin an immigrant, refugee, or resettlement process.  If a person applies for a B1/B2 visa, commonly called a tourist visa, but they are unable to demonstrate their intent to leave the United States after a defined period in order to return to a residence abroad, a consular officer will have to refuse the application.  Nonimmigrant visa applicants may apply at any embassy or consulate where they are physically present and where appointments are available.  A full list of embassies and consulates is available at <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMTYuNTQ5NzI0NjEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnVzZW1iYXNzeS5nb3YvIn0.8RPP8ZoGYD-2ses9AtgWMkKjHRi1q5jrrBKo11-fGjs/s/2171565732/br/128169588585-l" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMTYuNTQ5NzI0NjEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnVzZW1iYXNzeS5nb3YvIn0.8RPP8ZoGYD-2ses9AtgWMkKjHRi1q5jrrBKo11-fGjs/s/2171565732/br/128169588585-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1647479859904000&amp;usg=AOvVaw36USQPSUvWnH2OFSehB8Va">usembassy.gov</a>.</p>
<p>As a result of COVID – as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic, applicants may face extended visa interview wait times at some embassies and consulates, but once an interview appointment is made, applicants will have the ability to request an expedited appointment.  However, they must describe the unique circumstances that justify such a request, i.e. justify that they go get an appointment earlier than many of the other people in a similar situation.</p>
<p>Finally, a note on adoption.  The department is actively working with adoption service providers to provide guidance and answer questions during this critical time.  Our website address – addresses adoptions and intended adoptions at various stages of the process and provides guidance on whom to consult and clarifications on the department’s potential role and ability to assist.  Prospective adoptive parents should consult their adoption service provider about how the crisis in Ukraine may impact their adoption plans.  They can also email <a href="mailto:adoption@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">adoption@state.gov</a> with questions.</p>
<p>With that, I’ll turn it back to .  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Great.  Thank you to  and  and to  for that.  Operator, would you please give the instructions once again for getting into the question queue?</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Certainly.  Ladies and gentlemen, if you’d like to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 now – 1, 0.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Okay, let’s go to the line of Michelle Hackman.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Okay.  Please, go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi there, thanks for doing this call.  I’m wondering if I guess someone from the refugee division can speak to there’s been some reporting about creating an expedited program for Ukrainian refugees to come to the U.S., particularly those with family members already here.  Could you tell us what the latest thinking is about that?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b>  Sure, and I will echo or refer everybody back to Jen Psaki’s comments on this earlier today as well, but the department is continuing to work to explore all possible options to support those who may want to resettle to the United States and meet the qualifications of our resettlement program.  We are recognizing, though, that most people who are fleeing Ukraine are – prefer to stay in the region where they can travel visa-free and many have families and there are large diaspora communities, with the hope that they can return home soon.  And so we do want to commend our European allies for keeping their borders open and continuing to provide protection to those who are fleeing.</p>
<p>If refugees are identified as having protection needs that cannot be met in the country where they currently are – again, recognizing that their immediate safety is of paramount importance – we will work with our UN partners and other resettlement partners to identify those that would be safer resettling to other countries, including the United States, and then we’ll seek to help assist them through our U.S. Refugee Resettlement Program.  That program is not an emergency response program, so again, our goal would be to provide humanitarian assistance to keep people safe where they are for now while that process would continue.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  And let’s please go to the line now of Camilla Schick.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Okay.  Please, go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi.  Hi, thank you for this.  I was wondering if you could give a little bit more detail – and I understand the security concerns in providing detail on this, but any more detail about what the U.S. or USAID is doing to help particularly Ukrainian journalists, anti-corruption activists, ethnic minorities, members of vulnerable communities such as LGBTQ who want to leave the country because of the Russian advance and whether – given that they’re Ukrainian, whether there is some kind of special status or visa application process for them to be able to come to the United States or elsewhere.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b>  This is .  I can start off on that and then let others chime in, but I would say – so first, our humanitarian organization partners are doing everything they can to continue to operate on the ground inside Ukraine to provide safe passage for evacuees trying to flee from the dangerous situation, including – particularly those who are most vulnerable, such as the groups that you have mentioned.</p>
<p>I – once refugees get to the border crossings, again, our international organization partners for whom we have now contributed a significant amount of resources in the past two weeks particularly focus on the protection of those groups that are most vulnerable and will seek to provide them with information at the border and where to go on the other side, and then again, our partners are on the other side of the border as well and will be providing protection to all of those who are most vulnerable, whether it be, again, dissidents, journalists, those who are LGBTQI+ individuals, those with disabilities, as well as third-country nationals who may be having challenges returning back to their home countries.  So they are particularly attuned to those groups, and are focusing their protection efforts, including surging additional staff with explicit expertise at providing protection to vulnerable groups.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THREE:</b>  And this is .  On the very last part of that question regarding visas, the options for visa application are defined in statute.  You mentioned journalists, you mentioned a couple other groups.  As I had discussed in my remarks, the B1/B2 visa is just for general visits to the United States, business or tourism.  There is a particular visa category for journalists who are coming to the US to work as journalists, called the I visa.  Maybe you already – you guys may be very familiar.  But apart from that, there are no – there’s a wide variety of visa categories, but I don’t believe any that would apply to the groups that you just noted.  By far the vast majority of the nonimmigrant visa categories require a residence abroad and have a presumption of intending immigration that the applicant needs to rebut.  But as I said, we are processing many emergency visa applications.  We are not able to process the volume of the people who are thinking about that as an option.</p>
<p>I hope that answers your question.  Over.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Okay.  And let’s go to the line of Erin Durkin.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi.  Thank you so much for taking my question.  I just have a two-part question on the use of humanitarian corridors, particularly by the USAID team on the ground.  I first wanted to just ask a clarifying question – if and when these are established or agreed upon with Russia, if the focus of the USAID team is more about getting people out or if it’s also about getting supplies into the regions.  And then the second part of that is how you will balance that with the safety of your own team given Russia’s particularly bad history with humanitarian corridors.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:</b>  Hi.  Okay, thank you for that question.  I’d first start by saying we – both USAID and the State Department work through and with nongovernmental and UN partners on the ground.  Their safety and security is of the utmost importance to us, but this is not – these programs are not directly implemented by U.S. Government personnel.  It is through our partners.  Our focus is on both the evacuation of civilians who are seeking to leave these encircled cities, as well as getting critical food and medical supplies in along those same safe passages should they be negotiated by the parties to the conflict.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  And as a reminder, if you’d like to queue up for a question, it’s 1 then 0.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  And just on that last question, I would add that of course colleagues here, we want to do everything possible to save lives, which is why the U.S. Government, we of course support the establishment of humanitarian corridors.  I would point out that there’s been I believe at this point six successive agreements for humanitarian pauses in fighting in Mariupol which have broken down.  During one of those reported pauses on March 9th, a maternity hospital was targeted.  These corridors will only be as effective as Moscow’s willingness to maintain them, and the corridors, while they would be welcome in the short term, are certainly no substitute for ending the war.  And I know that the U.S. Government will continue to pull every lever to bring about that outcome.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Abigail Williams.  Abby.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi.  Thanks so much for doing this call.  A couple of questions.  One of them, I wondered if you could just address sort of where you’re starting at here in this process where you are trying to help Ukrainians now after the system has been affected by COVID, by cuts in previous administrations, by processing the 70,000 Afghans that are being brought in recently, and how that impacts your ability to process visas now.  And more specifically, I wondered what you would say to the Ukrainian American community here who obviously are very focused on their loved ones overseas trying to come over and may not be a direct family member, may not fit into that – the nuclear family category, maybe an adult sibling or something along those lines.  And what would you say to them?  How would you say they can help to bring their family over here, and how long would that process take?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THREE:</b>  Hi, yes.  Many thanks for this question.  So we – as you’ve been following, we have many – many, many things we need – we are doing with our limited resources.  We are throwing many, many resources at the assistance for U.S. citizens in this region as well as visa processing, but the demand, as you can imagine, is very high, which is why we’re trying to educate the appropriateness of the immigrant visa and nonimmigrant visa channels so that the people who are using those pathways do so knowing what the requirements are.</p>
<p>With that respect, we are engaging with the Ukrainian diaspora.  You’re exactly right, these are many of the questions.  There are processes to bring other non-immediate relatives through the immigrant visa process.  This might include your adult child of a U.S. citizen, it would include relatives of legal permanent residents, spouse and minor children chief among them.  It would include your – even your siblings.  This process is not immediate and it goes through U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Service, after which we would process that application overseas.  And some of the ones that we are processing in Frankfurt are those cases, it’s just we can’t process immediately sort of everything from the petition to the immigrant visa all as one package, only for those immediate relatives, spouse, minor children, and parents expeditiously.</p>
<p>Other than that, many people may very well qualify for a nonimmigrant visa, but it definitely depends on their situation.  Again, the statute requires a residence abroad to which they have no intention of abandoning.  It does not have to be their home in Ukraine.  They have to have a plan for what they’re doing after – how does this trip to the United States fit in with their plans forward.  Don’t – doesn’t have to be concrete; you have to rebut the presumption of intending immigration, that you have something else planned for after this trip of a defined period to the United States, which might make sense in some people’s cases, might not make sense depending on what their purpose of the travel is.</p>
<p>I want to emphasize each of those is a case-by-case analysis by the consular officer.  They look at the totality of circumstances, and so it’s not a – that you can’t use this, it’s just if your plan is to go to the United States and you have absolutely no idea what you’ll do after that – which I have to say on a human level is very understandable – as U.S. consular officers who are charged with executing U.S. immigration law, they would be well advised to have much more of a plan afterward – I’ll be – going to go visit my aunts and come back to Poland where I’m enrolling in school, or Germany, or wherever.  That’s all possible.</p>
<p>I hope that answers your question.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Okay, one more time, if you have a question and would like to ask that question, please dial 1 and then 0.</p>
<p>Looks like we have a follow-up from Abby.  Operator, would you please open up Abigail’s line again, please?</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Okay.  Please, go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Sorry, since no one else is jumping in, I thought I might toss out another question.  I recognize it’s difficult to give specific numbers, but I wondered if you might be able to say what the current backlog is in processing visas more broadly or speak to what that backlog looks like, or – and/or if you could give a little more specifics on what you’re seeing as far as applications for visas right now by Americans – by Ukrainians trying to come over to the U.S.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THREE:</b>  I don’t have numbers for you at all on the backlog.  We do – particularly, I assume you’re asking about nonimmigrant visas.  Each post is different.  I do want to emphasize, as I said at the top, we do have an expedite channel, so even if the wait time for a routine B1/B2 visa is lengthy, someone with exceptional circumstances – a medical or unique humanitarian need – can request an expedite.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Okay, great.  With that, I’d like to thank our briefers today – , , and also .  Again, thank you.</p>
<p>Once again, as a quick reminder, this call was on background today with attribution to senior administration officials.  With that, we are concluding today’s conference call and the embargo is now lifted.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Via Teleconference</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:  </b>Thank you, Ryan, and thank you, everyone, for joining us this afternoon for this briefing on the U.S. humanitarian assistance response to Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>Here at the top, before we get started, I would like to remind everyone that this briefing is on background with attribution to senior administration officials, and that the contents of this call are embargoed until the end of the briefing.</p>
<p>For the purposes of your reporting, you can refer to our briefers as Senior Administration Official Number One, Senior Administration Official Number Two, and Senior Administration Official Number Three.</p>
<p>Now, for your information but not for your reporting, I’m going to go ahead and let you know who our briefers are this afternoon.  I’m very glad to have with us ;  be Senior Administration Official Number One.  ;  be Senior Administration Official Number Two.  And third, , or Senior Administration Official Number Three.</p>
<p>Okay, we’re going to start our briefing today just with some brief remarks from each of our speakers and then we’ll take a few of your questions.  Again, let me just say that this briefing this afternoon is on the U.S. humanitarian assistance in response to Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine.  I would like to go ahead and ask folks to please limit your questions to that topic.  We’ve already had excellent briefings today from Press Secretary Jen Psaki over at the White House and Spokesperson Ned Price here at State covering the full gamut of issues with regard to Russia and its invasion of Ukraine, so we’ll ask you again to limit your questions to humanitarian assistance and our response in that regard.</p>
<p>Okay.  And with that, I’m going to go ahead and turn it over to  to get us started.  ?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL NUMBER ONE:</b>  Thank you and good afternoon, everyone.  I appreciate the opportunity to speak with you today about USAID’s humanitarian response to the crisis in Ukraine following Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.</p>
<p>Since this senseless campaign of unprovoked violence has begun, 4.7 million people have been displaced in and out of Ukraine.  That’s over 10 percent of Ukraine’s population, but one that the UN thinks the real figures may be significantly higher.</p>
<p>Putin’s war has turned nearly 3 million Ukrainians into refugees, including 1 million children, some of whom are forced to flee without their parents.  Nearly 2 million people are displaced inside of Ukraine.  We are hearing distressing reports from our partners in cities like Mariupol, where people remain in dire conditions and lack safe drinking water, food, fuel, and electricity.  The extensive damage we are seeing also means that shelter may be inadequate at a time when people face cold weather.  All of this is compounded by the terror of living under bombardment.</p>
<p>As the war continues into its third week, as just one of the many examples of the horrors civilians face, we are seeing Russian forces target schools and hospitals with a campaign of terror that has interrupted the cancer treatment for 1,500 children who are now forced to flee as bombs rain down on them while crossing into foreign countries with compromised immune systems during a pandemic with only the supplies they can carry.</p>
<p>We call for an immediate end to this needless war of aggression.  Short of that, the United States strongly supports the United Nations’ call for the establishment of safe passage of civilians out of areas under Russian attack and safe passage for aid workers attempting to provide humanitarian and medical supplies.  Russia must negotiate in good faith on these issues immediately.</p>
<p>In the face of this catastrophic toll on the people of Ukraine, you are seeing the U.S. stand united with our allies to aid those who are suffering.  USAID’s Disaster Assistance Response Team, or DART, has been in the region since the early days of Russia’s unprovoked war, making up-to-the-minute assessments of humanitarian needs and quickly ramping up assistance in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Over the past week alone, USAID has rapidly deployed four planeloads of lifesaving supplies from our warehouse in Dubai and mobilized our partners to immediately stand up surge support.</p>
<p>This includes blankets, high energy biscuits, kitchen sets, water treatment supplies, which USAID partner International Organization for Migration, or IOM, will distribute to vulnerable Ukrainians.</p>
<p>We’ve also worked with our partner the World Health Organization to provide emergency health kits with vital medicines and medical supplies, as well as trauma and emergency surgery kits to support emergency surgeries.  These supplies, which serve upwards of 100,000 people, are directly supporting the Government of Ukraine’s health care system, which has been badly damaged since the war began.</p>
<p>USAID partner the UN World Food Program also transported 500 metric tons of wheat flour, enough to provide bread for 500,000 people for a week, to Kyiv.  A WFP-contracted bakery also delivered nearly 15 metric tons of bread – sent to meet the needs of 60,000 people – to hospitals in Kharkiv.</p>
<p>Through our partners, we also continue to provide critical psychosocial support to children, people with disabilities, and older people, operating mobile medical units and protection teams to reach remote, displaced, or homebound communities and conducting mine-risk education activities to minimize protection risk.</p>
<p>In total, the United States has provided nearly 293 million in additional humanitarian assistance in just the last two weeks, including nearly 81 million from USAID.  We will continue to stand with the Ukrainian people during this crisis and work to meet their needs.</p>
<p>However, despite this project – progress, the situation on the ground in Ukraine is rapidly getting worse.  Russian bombardment and shelling continues to damage the infrastructure needed to get aid to people, destroying roads, bridges, and railroads, and making it difficult for aid workers to reach people in need.  In the absence of a ceasefire, humanitarian safe passage must be assured in order to allow aid workers to reach those in need.  As humanitarian needs continue to rise, USAID is working closely with European allies and partners who are on the front lines of this response on how to support people displaced internally and other people affected by the conflict.  We will continue to coordinate closely with the UN, other donors and partners to urge that robust humanitarian assistance can continue to prevent gaps in basic service delivery.</p>
<p>Thank you for your time.  I’d now like to pass it to  for  remarks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b>  Hi.  Thank you, , and thank you everybody for being here this afternoon.</p>
<p>I’m from , and we really want to underscore that our partnership with and commitment to the people of Ukraine and their government is steadfast and enduring.  We will continue to support and stand with them.</p>
<p>Today I want to share with you more about the enormous humanitarian efforts underway to assist the 12 million people in need of assistance across Ukraine, and the nearly 3 million refugees throughout neighboring countries due to the Russian Federation’s unprovoked and unjustified attack against Ukraine.</p>
<p>We are working with the Government of Ukraine, neighboring governments in the region, the European Union, international organizations like the United Nations, and other partners around the clock to address the urgent humanitarian needs of this crisis.  We are closely coordinating with these partners to monitor developments, assess needs, and respond accordingly.</p>
<p>Historically, the United States is the largest single country donor of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine.  Since the start of the current crisis, we have announced nearly $293 million in additional assistance to those affected by Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, including more than 186 million announced today.  This includes nearly 81 million from USAID, and nearly 212 million from the Department of State, and we will continue to do even more.</p>
<p>With this new contribution, we will complement the tremendous efforts of neighboring countries generously welcoming refugees.  We will work through our international and nongovernmental partners who provide food, safe drinking water, shelter, emergency health care, and protection.  This assistance will also support vulnerable populations inside Ukraine, as our humanitarian organization partners work tirelessly to provide safe passage for evacuees trying to leave danger.</p>
<p>Since the conflict in Ukraine began eight years ago, the United States has provided over 644 million in humanitarian assistance to vulnerable communities across Ukraine.  We will continue to support our European allies and partners who are at the forefront of this response, as well as international organizations and nongovernmental organizations working to mitigate the humanitarian impacts of this crisis.</p>
<p>We are also committed to working with a range of partners and stakeholders, including the Ukrainian diaspora community, to ensure that humanitarian organizations are prepared to respond to existing and new needs that arise in Ukraine and the neighboring countries.  The courage of the people of Ukraine and the generosity of all who have stepped up in their time of need is inspiring, and we will continue to stand with Ukraine.</p>
<p>Thank you, and I will turn it over to .  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THREE:</b>  Thank you, .  Good afternoon, everyone.  I’m here representing  to share information about visa processing for Ukrainians.</p>
<p>But first, just for a second, I want to go off – slightly off-topic and reiterate the State Department Travel Advisory for Ukraine is at a Level Four – Do Not Travel due to increased threat of Russian military action.  Our recommendations to U.S. citizens currently in Ukraine is that they should leave now using available transportation options if it is safe to do so.  We continue to encourage U.S. citizens in Ukraine to fill out our online form to let us know where they are, what they’re doing.</p>
<p>Turning to visas, given the suspension of our operations in Ukraine, the State Department is not offering visa services in Ukraine at this time.  I’ll talk a little bit about immigrant visas first and then nonimmigrant visas.  We want to share this information to further clarify visa options and outline alternatives to visas that Ukrainians may consider.  It’s important to note that a visa is not a viable way to achieve refugee resettlement in the United States.</p>
<p>We understand that any U.S. citizens who leave Ukraine may have families with mixed immigration status, for example, a U.S. citizen whose spouse has not yet started or completed the immigrant visa process.  We are prioritizing consular support to U.S. citizens and their immediate family members in this regard.  The Immigration and Nationality Act defines immediate family members as spouse, unmarried children under 21, and parents, so that’s our focus for immigrant visas.</p>
<p>We have designated the U.S. Consulate General in Frankfurt as the processing post for all the immigrant visa applications that would have been processed in Kyiv, with the exception of adoption cases, which will be handled at the U.S. embassy in Warsaw.</p>
<p>Ukraine passport holders can enter Schengen countries without a visa.  U.S. citizens and their immediate family members should relocate to a safe place and then follow detailed guidance on visa processing on our website and the website of the nearest U.S. embassy or consulate.  U.S. citizens who are overseas with the immediate family members that I described and have not yet filed an immigrant visa petition with USCIS may request to file a petition at the nearest embassy or consulate that processes immigrant visas.  Again, this only applies to the spouses, unmarried children under 21, and the parents that I just described.  Individuals who already have a USCIS-approved current petition for an immigrant visa for their relatives of any kind who have not yet been scheduled for an immigrant visa interview may be able to request expedited processing through the National Visa Center.</p>
<p>Now turning to nonimmigrant visas, again, I want to reiterate that nonimmigrant visas are for temporary stays in the United States.  They’re not the appropriate tool to begin an immigrant, refugee, or resettlement process.  If a person applies for a B1/B2 visa, commonly called a tourist visa, but they are unable to demonstrate their intent to leave the United States after a defined period in order to return to a residence abroad, a consular officer will have to refuse the application.  Nonimmigrant visa applicants may apply at any embassy or consulate where they are physically present and where appointments are available.  A full list of embassies and consulates is available at <a href="https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMTYuNTQ5NzI0NjEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnVzZW1iYXNzeS5nb3YvIn0.8RPP8ZoGYD-2ses9AtgWMkKjHRi1q5jrrBKo11-fGjs/s/2171565732/br/128169588585-l" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMjAzMTYuNTQ5NzI0NjEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwOi8vd3d3LnVzZW1iYXNzeS5nb3YvIn0.8RPP8ZoGYD-2ses9AtgWMkKjHRi1q5jrrBKo11-fGjs/s/2171565732/br/128169588585-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1647479859904000&amp;usg=AOvVaw36USQPSUvWnH2OFSehB8Va">usembassy.gov</a>.</p>
<p>As a result of COVID – as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic, applicants may face extended visa interview wait times at some embassies and consulates, but once an interview appointment is made, applicants will have the ability to request an expedited appointment.  However, they must describe the unique circumstances that justify such a request, i.e. justify that they go get an appointment earlier than many of the other people in a similar situation.</p>
<p>Finally, a note on adoption.  The department is actively working with adoption service providers to provide guidance and answer questions during this critical time.  Our website address – addresses adoptions and intended adoptions at various stages of the process and provides guidance on whom to consult and clarifications on the department’s potential role and ability to assist.  Prospective adoptive parents should consult their adoption service provider about how the crisis in Ukraine may impact their adoption plans.  They can also email <a href="mailto:adoption@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">adoption@state.gov</a> with questions.</p>
<p>With that, I’ll turn it back to .  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Great.  Thank you to  and  and to  for that.  Operator, would you please give the instructions once again for getting into the question queue?</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Certainly.  Ladies and gentlemen, if you’d like to ask a question, please press 1 then 0 now – 1, 0.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Okay, let’s go to the line of Michelle Hackman.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Okay.  Please, go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi there, thanks for doing this call.  I’m wondering if I guess someone from the refugee division can speak to there’s been some reporting about creating an expedited program for Ukrainian refugees to come to the U.S., particularly those with family members already here.  Could you tell us what the latest thinking is about that?</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b>  Sure, and I will echo or refer everybody back to Jen Psaki’s comments on this earlier today as well, but the department is continuing to work to explore all possible options to support those who may want to resettle to the United States and meet the qualifications of our resettlement program.  We are recognizing, though, that most people who are fleeing Ukraine are – prefer to stay in the region where they can travel visa-free and many have families and there are large diaspora communities, with the hope that they can return home soon.  And so we do want to commend our European allies for keeping their borders open and continuing to provide protection to those who are fleeing.</p>
<p>If refugees are identified as having protection needs that cannot be met in the country where they currently are – again, recognizing that their immediate safety is of paramount importance – we will work with our UN partners and other resettlement partners to identify those that would be safer resettling to other countries, including the United States, and then we’ll seek to help assist them through our U.S. Refugee Resettlement Program.  That program is not an emergency response program, so again, our goal would be to provide humanitarian assistance to keep people safe where they are for now while that process would continue.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  And let’s please go to the line now of Camilla Schick.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Okay.  Please, go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi.  Hi, thank you for this.  I was wondering if you could give a little bit more detail – and I understand the security concerns in providing detail on this, but any more detail about what the U.S. or USAID is doing to help particularly Ukrainian journalists, anti-corruption activists, ethnic minorities, members of vulnerable communities such as LGBTQ who want to leave the country because of the Russian advance and whether – given that they’re Ukrainian, whether there is some kind of special status or visa application process for them to be able to come to the United States or elsewhere.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL TWO:</b>  This is .  I can start off on that and then let others chime in, but I would say – so first, our humanitarian organization partners are doing everything they can to continue to operate on the ground inside Ukraine to provide safe passage for evacuees trying to flee from the dangerous situation, including – particularly those who are most vulnerable, such as the groups that you have mentioned.</p>
<p>I – once refugees get to the border crossings, again, our international organization partners for whom we have now contributed a significant amount of resources in the past two weeks particularly focus on the protection of those groups that are most vulnerable and will seek to provide them with information at the border and where to go on the other side, and then again, our partners are on the other side of the border as well and will be providing protection to all of those who are most vulnerable, whether it be, again, dissidents, journalists, those who are LGBTQI+ individuals, those with disabilities, as well as third-country nationals who may be having challenges returning back to their home countries.  So they are particularly attuned to those groups, and are focusing their protection efforts, including surging additional staff with explicit expertise at providing protection to vulnerable groups.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THREE:</b>  And this is .  On the very last part of that question regarding visas, the options for visa application are defined in statute.  You mentioned journalists, you mentioned a couple other groups.  As I had discussed in my remarks, the B1/B2 visa is just for general visits to the United States, business or tourism.  There is a particular visa category for journalists who are coming to the US to work as journalists, called the I visa.  Maybe you already – you guys may be very familiar.  But apart from that, there are no – there’s a wide variety of visa categories, but I don’t believe any that would apply to the groups that you just noted.  By far the vast majority of the nonimmigrant visa categories require a residence abroad and have a presumption of intending immigration that the applicant needs to rebut.  But as I said, we are processing many emergency visa applications.  We are not able to process the volume of the people who are thinking about that as an option.</p>
<p>I hope that answers your question.  Over.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Okay.  And let’s go to the line of Erin Durkin.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi.  Thank you so much for taking my question.  I just have a two-part question on the use of humanitarian corridors, particularly by the USAID team on the ground.  I first wanted to just ask a clarifying question – if and when these are established or agreed upon with Russia, if the focus of the USAID team is more about getting people out or if it’s also about getting supplies into the regions.  And then the second part of that is how you will balance that with the safety of your own team given Russia’s particularly bad history with humanitarian corridors.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL ONE:</b>  Hi.  Okay, thank you for that question.  I’d first start by saying we – both USAID and the State Department work through and with nongovernmental and UN partners on the ground.  Their safety and security is of the utmost importance to us, but this is not – these programs are not directly implemented by U.S. Government personnel.  It is through our partners.  Our focus is on both the evacuation of civilians who are seeking to leave these encircled cities, as well as getting critical food and medical supplies in along those same safe passages should they be negotiated by the parties to the conflict.</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  And as a reminder, if you’d like to queue up for a question, it’s 1 then 0.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  And just on that last question, I would add that of course colleagues here, we want to do everything possible to save lives, which is why the U.S. Government, we of course support the establishment of humanitarian corridors.  I would point out that there’s been I believe at this point six successive agreements for humanitarian pauses in fighting in Mariupol which have broken down.  During one of those reported pauses on March 9th, a maternity hospital was targeted.  These corridors will only be as effective as Moscow’s willingness to maintain them, and the corridors, while they would be welcome in the short term, are certainly no substitute for ending the war.  And I know that the U.S. Government will continue to pull every lever to bring about that outcome.</p>
<p>Let’s go to the line of Abigail Williams.  Abby.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Hi.  Thanks so much for doing this call.  A couple of questions.  One of them, I wondered if you could just address sort of where you’re starting at here in this process where you are trying to help Ukrainians now after the system has been affected by COVID, by cuts in previous administrations, by processing the 70,000 Afghans that are being brought in recently, and how that impacts your ability to process visas now.  And more specifically, I wondered what you would say to the Ukrainian American community here who obviously are very focused on their loved ones overseas trying to come over and may not be a direct family member, may not fit into that – the nuclear family category, maybe an adult sibling or something along those lines.  And what would you say to them?  How would you say they can help to bring their family over here, and how long would that process take?  Thanks.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THREE:</b>  Hi, yes.  Many thanks for this question.  So we – as you’ve been following, we have many – many, many things we need – we are doing with our limited resources.  We are throwing many, many resources at the assistance for U.S. citizens in this region as well as visa processing, but the demand, as you can imagine, is very high, which is why we’re trying to educate the appropriateness of the immigrant visa and nonimmigrant visa channels so that the people who are using those pathways do so knowing what the requirements are.</p>
<p>With that respect, we are engaging with the Ukrainian diaspora.  You’re exactly right, these are many of the questions.  There are processes to bring other non-immediate relatives through the immigrant visa process.  This might include your adult child of a U.S. citizen, it would include relatives of legal permanent residents, spouse and minor children chief among them.  It would include your – even your siblings.  This process is not immediate and it goes through U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Service, after which we would process that application overseas.  And some of the ones that we are processing in Frankfurt are those cases, it’s just we can’t process immediately sort of everything from the petition to the immigrant visa all as one package, only for those immediate relatives, spouse, minor children, and parents expeditiously.</p>
<p>Other than that, many people may very well qualify for a nonimmigrant visa, but it definitely depends on their situation.  Again, the statute requires a residence abroad to which they have no intention of abandoning.  It does not have to be their home in Ukraine.  They have to have a plan for what they’re doing after – how does this trip to the United States fit in with their plans forward.  Don’t – doesn’t have to be concrete; you have to rebut the presumption of intending immigration, that you have something else planned for after this trip of a defined period to the United States, which might make sense in some people’s cases, might not make sense depending on what their purpose of the travel is.</p>
<p>I want to emphasize each of those is a case-by-case analysis by the consular officer.  They look at the totality of circumstances, and so it’s not a – that you can’t use this, it’s just if your plan is to go to the United States and you have absolutely no idea what you’ll do after that – which I have to say on a human level is very understandable – as U.S. consular officers who are charged with executing U.S. immigration law, they would be well advised to have much more of a plan afterward – I’ll be – going to go visit my aunts and come back to Poland where I’m enrolling in school, or Germany, or wherever.  That’s all possible.</p>
<p>I hope that answers your question.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Okay, one more time, if you have a question and would like to ask that question, please dial 1 and then 0.</p>
<p>Looks like we have a follow-up from Abby.  Operator, would you please open up Abigail’s line again, please?</p>
<p><b>OPERATOR:</b>  Okay.  Please, go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
<p><b>QUESTION:</b>  Sorry, since no one else is jumping in, I thought I might toss out another question.  I recognize it’s difficult to give specific numbers, but I wondered if you might be able to say what the current backlog is in processing visas more broadly or speak to what that backlog looks like, or – and/or if you could give a little more specifics on what you’re seeing as far as applications for visas right now by Americans – by Ukrainians trying to come over to the U.S.</p>
<p><b>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THREE:</b>  I don’t have numbers for you at all on the backlog.  We do – particularly, I assume you’re asking about nonimmigrant visas.  Each post is different.  I do want to emphasize, as I said at the top, we do have an expedite channel, so even if the wait time for a routine B1/B2 visa is lengthy, someone with exceptional circumstances – a medical or unique humanitarian need – can request an expedite.  Thank you.</p>
<p><b>MODERATOR:</b>  Okay, great.  With that, I’d like to thank our briefers today – , , and also .  Again, thank you.</p>
<p>Once again, as a quick reminder, this call was on background today with attribution to senior administration officials.  With that, we are concluding today’s conference call and the embargo is now lifted.  Thank you.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2022 Turkmenistan Presidential Election</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/2022-turkmenistan-presidential-election/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 01:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States reaffirms our commitment to the people of Turkmenistan and their right to choose their leaders through free and fair elections and in a transparent manner.</p>
<p>We concur with the concerns described in the recent needs assessment conducted by the Office for Democratic Institutions and Human Rights (ODIHR) of the Organization for Security and Co-Operation in Europe.  The ODIHR assessment noted that Turkmenistan has not proved its election processes to be free, fair, or competitive.  We call on the Government of Turkmenistan to implement ODIHR recommendations in order to align its electoral system with the standards described in the needs assessment.</p>
<p>The growing partnership between the United States and Turkmenistan is based on respect for Turkmenistan’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, and shared objectives for security and prosperity in the Central Asia region.  We will continue to encourage political participation for the people of Turkmenistan, bolstering the role of civil society, and strengthening our shared interests.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p>The United States reaffirms our commitment to the people of Turkmenistan and their right to choose their leaders through free and fair elections and in a transparent manner.</p>
<p>We concur with the concerns described in the recent needs assessment conducted by the Office for Democratic Institutions and Human Rights (ODIHR) of the Organization for Security and Co-Operation in Europe.  The ODIHR assessment noted that Turkmenistan has not proved its election processes to be free, fair, or competitive.  We call on the Government of Turkmenistan to implement ODIHR recommendations in order to align its electoral system with the standards described in the needs assessment.</p>
<p>The growing partnership between the United States and Turkmenistan is based on respect for Turkmenistan’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, and shared objectives for security and prosperity in the Central Asia region.  We will continue to encourage political participation for the people of Turkmenistan, bolstering the role of civil society, and strengthening our shared interests.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Additional Humanitarian Assistance for the People of Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/additional-humanitarian-assistance-for-the-people-of-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 20:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is providing over $186 million in additional humanitarian assistance to support internally displaced persons and the more than three million refugees affected by Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war in Ukraine.  This will provide further support for humanitarian organizations responding to the crisis and complement the generosity of the neighboring countries that are welcoming and supporting refugees.</p>
<p>We call for an immediate end to Russia’s continuing war against Ukraine and for Russia to facilitate unhindered humanitarian access in Ukraine and safe passage for those who seek to leave the cities where they are trapped.  Humanitarian aid deliveries must be allowed to continue without interference, and humanitarian workers must have safe passage to deliver aid and assistance to those in need.</p>
<p>The United States is the largest single-country donor of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine, including providing nearly $293 million in humanitarian assistance both inside Ukraine and in the region since late February.  Our funding to-date amounts to nearly $644 million to vulnerable communities in the region since Russia first invaded Ukraine eight years ago.  Our humanitarian assistance flows through independent humanitarian organizations that deliver needs-based assistance with impartiality, humanity, neutrality, and independence.</p>
<p>The additional humanitarian assistance for refugees in Ukraine’s neighboring countries supports the provision of food, safe drinking water, protection, accessible shelter, and emergency health care through the support of our international and non-governmental partners. This funding will also help victims of this conflict maintain contact with family members who have been separated and promote family reunification when possible.</p>
<p>The United States commends the hospitality of the neighboring countries that are hosting those fleeing Ukraine.  As with any refugee situation, we call on the international community to respond to the needs of those seeking protection in a way that is consistent with the principle of non-refoulement and states’ respective obligations under international law.</p>
<p>We welcome the contributions of other donors toward this crisis response and urge still others to generously support the immediate humanitarian needs in Ukraine and the region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>The United States is providing over $186 million in additional humanitarian assistance to support internally displaced persons and the more than three million refugees affected by Russia’s premeditated, unprovoked, and unjustified war in Ukraine.  This will provide further support for humanitarian organizations responding to the crisis and complement the generosity of the neighboring countries that are welcoming and supporting refugees.</p>
<p>We call for an immediate end to Russia’s continuing war against Ukraine and for Russia to facilitate unhindered humanitarian access in Ukraine and safe passage for those who seek to leave the cities where they are trapped.  Humanitarian aid deliveries must be allowed to continue without interference, and humanitarian workers must have safe passage to deliver aid and assistance to those in need.</p>
<p>The United States is the largest single-country donor of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine, including providing nearly $293 million in humanitarian assistance both inside Ukraine and in the region since late February.  Our funding to-date amounts to nearly $644 million to vulnerable communities in the region since Russia first invaded Ukraine eight years ago.  Our humanitarian assistance flows through independent humanitarian organizations that deliver needs-based assistance with impartiality, humanity, neutrality, and independence.</p>
<p>The additional humanitarian assistance for refugees in Ukraine’s neighboring countries supports the provision of food, safe drinking water, protection, accessible shelter, and emergency health care through the support of our international and non-governmental partners. This funding will also help victims of this conflict maintain contact with family members who have been separated and promote family reunification when possible.</p>
<p>The United States commends the hospitality of the neighboring countries that are hosting those fleeing Ukraine.  As with any refugee situation, we call on the international community to respond to the needs of those seeking protection in a way that is consistent with the principle of non-refoulement and states’ respective obligations under international law.</p>
<p>We welcome the contributions of other donors toward this crisis response and urge still others to generously support the immediate humanitarian needs in Ukraine and the region.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Kuleba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-ukrainian-foreign-minister-kuleba-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 20:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324543</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke by phone today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to reiterate the United States’ ironclad commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and our resolve to provide security, economic, and humanitarian support to the people of Ukraine.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Kuleba discussed ongoing diplomatic efforts to stop President Putin’s war of choice. They shared deep concern regarding increasingly significant damage to infrastructure and buildings and resulting civilian deaths and injuries. The Secretary provided an update on the most recent U.S. and global efforts to hold Putin accountable for his unprovoked and brutal war.  He commended the bravery and determination of the Ukrainian people in the fight for their country in the face of the Russian forces’ callous disregard for civilian life.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke by phone today with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba to reiterate the United States’ ironclad commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and our resolve to provide security, economic, and humanitarian support to the people of Ukraine.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Kuleba discussed ongoing diplomatic efforts to stop President Putin’s war of choice. They shared deep concern regarding increasingly significant damage to infrastructure and buildings and resulting civilian deaths and injuries. The Secretary provided an update on the most recent U.S. and global efforts to hold Putin accountable for his unprovoked and brutal war.  He commended the bravery and determination of the Ukrainian people in the fight for their country in the face of the Russian forces’ callous disregard for civilian life.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Call with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General Delattre</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-call-with-french-foreign-ministry-secretary-general-delattre-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 16:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324477</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General François Delattre.  The Deputy Secretary and Secretary General Delattre reiterated their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Putin’s war of choice.  They agreed on the need for continued support for Ukraine and committed to continue to impose costs on Russia for its aggression.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman spoke today with French Foreign Ministry Secretary General François Delattre.  The Deputy Secretary and Secretary General Delattre reiterated their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Putin’s war of choice.  They agreed on the need for continued support for Ukraine and committed to continue to impose costs on Russia for its aggression.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Azerbaijani President Aliyev</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-azerbaijani-president-aliyev-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 16:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324470</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Azerbaijani President Ilham Aliyev.  Secretary Blinken emphasized the continuing importance of the U.S.-Azerbaijani bilateral partnership and the U.S. commitment to promoting a peaceful, democratic, and prosperous future for the South Caucasus region.  Noting recent reports of escalation between Armenian and Azerbaijani forces, the Secretary called for the sides to show restraint and intensify diplomatic engagement to find comprehensive solutions to all outstanding issues.  He also stressed the importance of respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms in Azerbaijan.  The Secretary highlighted the U.S. commitment, alongside other partners, to continue to hold Moscow and its supporters, including the Lukashenka regime in Belarus, accountable for the Kremlin’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Azerbaijani President Ilham Aliyev.  Secretary Blinken emphasized the continuing importance of the U.S.-Azerbaijani bilateral partnership and the U.S. commitment to promoting a peaceful, democratic, and prosperous future for the South Caucasus region.  Noting recent reports of escalation between Armenian and Azerbaijani forces, the Secretary called for the sides to show restraint and intensify diplomatic engagement to find comprehensive solutions to all outstanding issues.  He also stressed the importance of respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms in Azerbaijan.  The Secretary highlighted the U.S. commitment, alongside other partners, to continue to hold Moscow and its supporters, including the Lukashenka regime in Belarus, accountable for the Kremlin’s unprovoked and unjustified war against Ukraine.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the Occasion of the 11-year Anniversary of the Syrian Uprising</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-the-occasion-of-the-11-year-anniversary-of-the-syrian-uprising/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 16:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=324454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following statement was released by France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America on the occasion of the 11-year anniversary of the Syrian uprising:</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>Today marks 11 years since the Syrian people courageously and peacefully took to the streets to demand freedom, political reform, and a government that respects and upholds human rights.  The Assad regime met those demands with a brutal assault that continues today against the Syrian people.  After 11 years of death and suffering, it is past time for the regime and its enablers, including Russia and Iran, to halt their ruthless attack on the Syrian people.  The coincidence of this year’s anniversary with the appalling Russian aggression against Ukraine, which constitutes a breach of exceptional gravity to international law and the UN Charter, highlights Russia’s brutal and destructive behavior in both conflicts.  After more than a decade of conflict, the Syrian economic and humanitarian situation is bleak and millions of Syrian refugees hosted generously by Syria’s neighbors, as well as those internally displaced, cannot yet return home in line with UN standards, and without fear of violence, arbitrary arrest, and torture.  Continued conflict has also led to space for terrorists, particularly Daesh (ISIS), to exploit.  Preventing Daesh’s resurgence remains a priority.</p>
<p>We continue to support the UN-facilitated, Syrian-led process outlined within UN Security Council Resolution 2254.  We will continue to call for a nationwide ceasefire, respect for international humanitarian law, and unhindered aid access through all modalities, including through the continued authorization of the cross-border mechanism by the UN Security Council.  We additionally urge the immediate release of those arbitrarily detained and clarification of the fate and whereabouts of those who remain missing.  We do not support efforts to normalize relations with the Assad regime and will not normalize relations ourselves, nor lift sanctions or fund reconstruction until there is irreversible progress towards a political solution.  We encourage all parties, especially the Syrian regime, to participate in the March 21 meeting of the Constitutional Committee in good faith and call for the Committee to deliver on its mandate.</p>
<p>Impunity remains unacceptable.  We will therefore continue to actively promote accountability, including through support to the Commission of Inquiry, the International, Impartial and Independent Mechanism, and the Organization for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons (OPCW).  This also includes supporting organizations, many of which are Syrian-led, in collecting evidence and documenting the atrocities and serious violations of international law committed in Syria, including the use of chemical weapons.  The OPCW’s Investigation and Identification Team’s (IIT) efforts continue to attribute responsibility for the abhorrent use of chemical weapons in Syria.  Despite Syria’s lack of cooperation, the IIT has already confirmed the responsibility of the Assad regime in multiple chemical weapons attacks on the Syrian people. Those responsible for this disregard for the global norm against the use of chemical weapons must be held to account.</p>
<p>We welcome ongoing efforts by national courts to investigate and prosecute crimes within their jurisdiction committed in Syria and encourage increased support for these prosecutions.  As their harrowing testimonies show, justice for victims and their families is long overdue.  Pursuing accountability and justice is essential to building confidence in the political process called for in UNSCR 2254 and securing the stable, just, and enduring peace that Syrians need and deserve.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following statement was released by France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom, and the United States of America on the occasion of the 11-year anniversary of the Syrian uprising:</p>
<p><i>Begin Text:</i></p>
<p>Today marks 11 years since the Syrian people courageously and peacefully took to the streets to demand freedom, political reform, and a government that respects and upholds human rights.  The Assad regime met those demands with a brutal assault that continues today against the Syrian people.  After 11 years of death and suffering, it is past time for the regime and its enablers, including Russia and Iran, to halt their ruthless attack on the Syrian people.  The coincidence of this year’s anniversary with the appalling Russian aggression against Ukraine, which constitutes a breach of exceptional gravity to international law and the UN Charter, highlights Russia’s brutal and destructive behavior in both conflicts.  After more than a decade of conflict, the Syrian economic and humanitarian situation is bleak and millions of Syrian refugees hosted generously by Syria’s neighbors, as well as those internally displaced, cannot yet return home in line with UN standards, and without fear of violence, arbitrary arrest, and torture.  Continued conflict has also led to space for terrorists, particularly Daesh (ISIS), to exploit.  Preventing Daesh’s resurgence remains a priority.</p>
<p>We continue to support the UN-facilitated, Syrian-led process outlined within UN Security Council Resolution 2254.  We will continue to call for a nationwide ceasefire, respect for international humanitarian law, and unhindered aid access through all modalities, including through the continued authorization of the cross-border mechanism by the UN Security Council.  We additionally urge the immediate release of those arbitrarily detained and clarification of the fate and whereabouts of those who remain missing.  We do not support efforts to normalize relations with the Assad regime and will not normalize relations ourselves, nor lift sanctions or fund reconstruction until there is irreversible progress towards a political solution.  We encourage all parties, especially the Syrian regime, to participate in the March 21 meeting of the Constitutional Committee in good faith and call for the Committee to deliver on its mandate.</p>
<p>Impunity remains unacceptable.  We will therefore continue to actively promote accountability, including through support to the Commission of Inquiry, the International, Impartial and Independent Mechanism, and the Organization for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons (OPCW).  This also includes supporting organizations, many of which are Syrian-led, in collecting evidence and documenting the atrocities and serious violations of international law committed in Syria, including the use of chemical weapons.  The OPCW’s Investigation and Identification Team’s (IIT) efforts continue to attribute responsibility for the abhorrent use of chemical weapons in Syria.  Despite Syria’s lack of cooperation, the IIT has already confirmed the responsibility of the Assad regime in multiple chemical weapons attacks on the Syrian people. Those responsible for this disregard for the global norm against the use of chemical weapons must be held to account.</p>
<p>We welcome ongoing efforts by national courts to investigate and prosecute crimes within their jurisdiction committed in Syria and encourage increased support for these prosecutions.  As their harrowing testimonies show, justice for victims and their families is long overdue.  Pursuing accountability and justice is essential to building confidence in the political process called for in UNSCR 2254 and securing the stable, just, and enduring peace that Syrians need and deserve.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000001" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
