<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 08:45:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-Seal-of-the-U.S.-Department-of-State-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken Remarks to Mission India Staff</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-remarks-to-mission-india-staff/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 08:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=262765</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>New Delhi, India</p>
<p>U.S. Ambassador’s Residence </p>
<p><strong>MR KESHAP:  </strong>Hello, welcome.  Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Roosevelt House, the residence of the United States ambassador.  What a fantastic day we have today.  Thank you all for coming, especially you little ones.  Hello, how are you?  (Laughter.)  I love your mask.  Is that Colorado?</p>
<p><strong>GUEST:</strong>  Mm-hmm.</p>
<p><strong>MR KESHAP: </strong> It’s wonderful.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, you don’t want to hear from me.  You want to hear from our boss, the Secretary of State of the United States of America, who just flew in.  He also was raised in a Foreign Service family like me, and he knows what it’s like to serve overseas and to serve your country with distinction and honor, especially after the tough times we’ve had here at Embassy New Delhi.  I’m proud of all of you.  Thanks for all of the work.  Please give the Secretary of State a big round of applause.  (Applause.)<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.  Good morning.  It is wonderful to see all of you here.  I think we have some colleagues coming with us virtually hooked.  And hello, it’s good to see the youngest staff members are here today, too.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Atul, thank you so much not just for the kind words but for taking on the mission, taking on the leadership here at what is – we always say it’s a critical time.  This really is.  And you all know it; you’re living it every single day.  I am grateful for you for coming and taking this on, and I’m especially grateful to everyone on the team who worked to make this visit a success.  I know these visits are challenging in any time.  It’s especially challenging in this particular time.</p>
<p>And to start with the obvious and COVID-19, I know that of all of our missions around the world, this one has perhaps felt it more than any mission.  We’ve lost six employees, four different community members, to COVID.  So this is not just a professional challenge.  This has been a personal challenge and, in many cases, a personal loss.  I know many of you have felt this in your families, among your friends; and somehow, through it all, not only have you kept going, but you’ve kept going with remarkable distinction, remarkable results.  And I just want to tell you how grateful I am to each and every one of you for coming together as a team, coming together as a mission, and continuing to get the job done.</p>
<p>I’ve had a chance to stop in on a number of your colleagues and missions around the world.  COVID’s had an impact on everyone, but again, here maybe more than most.  But you’ve also found something if not positive at least incredibly hopeful to the overall enterprise and the work that you’ve done here developing measures to prevent, to detect, to control and treat COVID here in the mission.  Many of these protocols that you’ve come up with here we’ve been able to share across the entire State Department enterprise, and that’s been to the benefit of your colleagues around the world.</p>
<p>You spearheaded efforts to bring medical supplies and assistance here to India, and that’s been a remarkable achievement in and of itself.  We all remember well, and I think we’ll never forget, the extent to which India came to our assistance in the United States in the earlier days of COVID when we were being hit particularly hard.  And I am proud of the fact that we’ve been able to step up when it’s really mattered to India, but that just doesn’t happen.  It takes remarkable organization.  It takes remarkable enterprise.  And much of that was done right here by all of you actually organizing all of the assistance that was coming forward, assistance that the U.S. Government provided, but also in a very extraordinary way the private sector as well.  But that had to be – that had to be organized.  It had to be distributed.  It had to be coordinated with the Indian Government.  And you’ve done all of that.</p>
<p>I think that’s had a very meaningful impact in helping to turn the tide of the second wave here in India, and it’s not every day that you can say that the work you’ve done has quite literally saved lives, but you can say that.  You’ve done that.  And I am deeply grateful for that and our friends here in India are, too.</p>
<p>I also want to say a special thanks to the management team, who have made sure that critical operations continued under these extremely challenging circumstances.  I think it would be possible to look at pretty much every office in the mission and show ways that you’ve stepped up in the midst of COVID and getting your job done.  I just want to cite a couple of things because they really do stand out.</p>
<p>Really extraordinary work on visas in the last few months and repatriating some of our fellow citizens.  Nearly 6,000 U.S. citizens and legal residents, permanent residents, were repatriated, thanks to your work.</p>
<p>And students who are now going to be able to start classes or take part in summer session, they are on their way, or they are at colleges and universities in the United States, thanks to the remarkable work that you’ve done.  You made a major push this summer for visas.  As I understand it, by the end of August you will have conducted 68,000 student visa interviews, which is the highest in years.  And again, to do that during COVID is extraordinary.</p>
<p>We may end up sending more students to the United States this year than ever before as a result of your work.  And that’s important in so many different ways, but it’s particularly important, I think to all of us, because this is where enduring connections are made between the United States and India.  These are relationships that are going to be not just established now but will likely endure for years, for decades, for generations.  Nothing could be more important.</p>
<p>And let me just say a couple of words about the relationship more broadly, which is what brought me here and what brings you here.  It is, simply put, one of the most consequential relationships we have with any country on Earth.  We know and we say it’s vital for security, for prosperity, for the future of a free and open Indo-Pacific; but when you think about it, as I like to say, none of the really big challenges that we face as a country, challenges that have a direct impact on the lives of our fellow citizens, whether it’s COVID, whether it’s the climate crisis, whether it’s the impact of emerging technologies on all of our lives, not a single one of these problems can be addressed by any one country acting alone, even the United States.  And it’s manifestly true, in my judgment at least, that not a single one of these challenges can be met without the United States and India working closely together.  And that’s exactly what we’re trying to do.</p>
<p>One of the things that’s been a very powerful witness in my time in government over the last 25 years is the evolution of this relationship.  And it has grown stronger and deeper across successive administrations, Republican and Democrat, because I think there is a recognition that it’s profoundly in the national interest.  And you are a big part of continuing that evolution, making it stronger and deeper as we go forward.</p>
<p>So whether you work for the State Department, whether you’re one of the more than 20 other agencies here at this mission, whether you’re a direct hire, whether you’re locally engaged staff, an eligible family member, I really just wanted to say two very simple words:  Thank you.  Thank you for what you’re doing every single day to strengthen the relationship between our countries.  Thank you to the Americans here for what you’re doing for your fellow citizens back home in ways that they will never fully perhaps see or fully understand but that are actually going to have an impact on their lives.</p>
<p>One of the charge’s predecessors here, Ambassador Rich Verma, we were talking the other day.  And he reminded me of something you probably already know, but it’s worth citing.  When President Eisenhower came here in 1959, he visited the embassy, and he talked about the future that we were trying to build for Indian and American kids.  This is 1959.  And he said – say these children are nine years old now, maybe a little bit younger, maybe a little bit older.  Add 60 years to that.  In 2019, what is the world going to be then?  If we do our work well, he said, they will do theirs better.</p>
<p>So I think those words have real resonance over these many years.  And in thinking about the youngest members of our staff here, I hope that we do our work well so that they will have an even better world to inherit and hopefully to leave even better than we’re doing right now.  So again, thank you, thank you, thank you for everything that you’re doing every single day.  It’s great to see you.  It’s great to be with you.  And thanks for having us, and I hope that if nothing else there’s a very good wheels-up party later today.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>MR KESHAP:</strong>  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>New Delhi, India</p>
<p>U.S. Ambassador’s Residence </p>
<p><strong>MR KESHAP:  </strong>Hello, welcome.  Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Roosevelt House, the residence of the United States ambassador.  What a fantastic day we have today.  Thank you all for coming, especially you little ones.  Hello, how are you?  (Laughter.)  I love your mask.  Is that Colorado?</p>
<p><strong>GUEST:</strong>  Mm-hmm.</p>
<p><strong>MR KESHAP: </strong> It’s wonderful.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Ladies and gentlemen, you don’t want to hear from me.  You want to hear from our boss, the Secretary of State of the United States of America, who just flew in.  He also was raised in a Foreign Service family like me, and he knows what it’s like to serve overseas and to serve your country with distinction and honor, especially after the tough times we’ve had here at Embassy New Delhi.  I’m proud of all of you.  Thanks for all of the work.  Please give the Secretary of State a big round of applause.  (Applause.)<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Thank you.  Good morning.  It is wonderful to see all of you here.  I think we have some colleagues coming with us virtually hooked.  And hello, it’s good to see the youngest staff members are here today, too.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p>Atul, thank you so much not just for the kind words but for taking on the mission, taking on the leadership here at what is – we always say it’s a critical time.  This really is.  And you all know it; you’re living it every single day.  I am grateful for you for coming and taking this on, and I’m especially grateful to everyone on the team who worked to make this visit a success.  I know these visits are challenging in any time.  It’s especially challenging in this particular time.</p>
<p>And to start with the obvious and COVID-19, I know that of all of our missions around the world, this one has perhaps felt it more than any mission.  We’ve lost six employees, four different community members, to COVID.  So this is not just a professional challenge.  This has been a personal challenge and, in many cases, a personal loss.  I know many of you have felt this in your families, among your friends; and somehow, through it all, not only have you kept going, but you’ve kept going with remarkable distinction, remarkable results.  And I just want to tell you how grateful I am to each and every one of you for coming together as a team, coming together as a mission, and continuing to get the job done.</p>
<p>I’ve had a chance to stop in on a number of your colleagues and missions around the world.  COVID’s had an impact on everyone, but again, here maybe more than most.  But you’ve also found something if not positive at least incredibly hopeful to the overall enterprise and the work that you’ve done here developing measures to prevent, to detect, to control and treat COVID here in the mission.  Many of these protocols that you’ve come up with here we’ve been able to share across the entire State Department enterprise, and that’s been to the benefit of your colleagues around the world.</p>
<p>You spearheaded efforts to bring medical supplies and assistance here to India, and that’s been a remarkable achievement in and of itself.  We all remember well, and I think we’ll never forget, the extent to which India came to our assistance in the United States in the earlier days of COVID when we were being hit particularly hard.  And I am proud of the fact that we’ve been able to step up when it’s really mattered to India, but that just doesn’t happen.  It takes remarkable organization.  It takes remarkable enterprise.  And much of that was done right here by all of you actually organizing all of the assistance that was coming forward, assistance that the U.S. Government provided, but also in a very extraordinary way the private sector as well.  But that had to be – that had to be organized.  It had to be distributed.  It had to be coordinated with the Indian Government.  And you’ve done all of that.</p>
<p>I think that’s had a very meaningful impact in helping to turn the tide of the second wave here in India, and it’s not every day that you can say that the work you’ve done has quite literally saved lives, but you can say that.  You’ve done that.  And I am deeply grateful for that and our friends here in India are, too.</p>
<p>I also want to say a special thanks to the management team, who have made sure that critical operations continued under these extremely challenging circumstances.  I think it would be possible to look at pretty much every office in the mission and show ways that you’ve stepped up in the midst of COVID and getting your job done.  I just want to cite a couple of things because they really do stand out.</p>
<p>Really extraordinary work on visas in the last few months and repatriating some of our fellow citizens.  Nearly 6,000 U.S. citizens and legal residents, permanent residents, were repatriated, thanks to your work.</p>
<p>And students who are now going to be able to start classes or take part in summer session, they are on their way, or they are at colleges and universities in the United States, thanks to the remarkable work that you’ve done.  You made a major push this summer for visas.  As I understand it, by the end of August you will have conducted 68,000 student visa interviews, which is the highest in years.  And again, to do that during COVID is extraordinary.</p>
<p>We may end up sending more students to the United States this year than ever before as a result of your work.  And that’s important in so many different ways, but it’s particularly important, I think to all of us, because this is where enduring connections are made between the United States and India.  These are relationships that are going to be not just established now but will likely endure for years, for decades, for generations.  Nothing could be more important.</p>
<p>And let me just say a couple of words about the relationship more broadly, which is what brought me here and what brings you here.  It is, simply put, one of the most consequential relationships we have with any country on Earth.  We know and we say it’s vital for security, for prosperity, for the future of a free and open Indo-Pacific; but when you think about it, as I like to say, none of the really big challenges that we face as a country, challenges that have a direct impact on the lives of our fellow citizens, whether it’s COVID, whether it’s the climate crisis, whether it’s the impact of emerging technologies on all of our lives, not a single one of these problems can be addressed by any one country acting alone, even the United States.  And it’s manifestly true, in my judgment at least, that not a single one of these challenges can be met without the United States and India working closely together.  And that’s exactly what we’re trying to do.</p>
<p>One of the things that’s been a very powerful witness in my time in government over the last 25 years is the evolution of this relationship.  And it has grown stronger and deeper across successive administrations, Republican and Democrat, because I think there is a recognition that it’s profoundly in the national interest.  And you are a big part of continuing that evolution, making it stronger and deeper as we go forward.</p>
<p>So whether you work for the State Department, whether you’re one of the more than 20 other agencies here at this mission, whether you’re a direct hire, whether you’re locally engaged staff, an eligible family member, I really just wanted to say two very simple words:  Thank you.  Thank you for what you’re doing every single day to strengthen the relationship between our countries.  Thank you to the Americans here for what you’re doing for your fellow citizens back home in ways that they will never fully perhaps see or fully understand but that are actually going to have an impact on their lives.</p>
<p>One of the charge’s predecessors here, Ambassador Rich Verma, we were talking the other day.  And he reminded me of something you probably already know, but it’s worth citing.  When President Eisenhower came here in 1959, he visited the embassy, and he talked about the future that we were trying to build for Indian and American kids.  This is 1959.  And he said – say these children are nine years old now, maybe a little bit younger, maybe a little bit older.  Add 60 years to that.  In 2019, what is the world going to be then?  If we do our work well, he said, they will do theirs better.</p>
<p>So I think those words have real resonance over these many years.  And in thinking about the youngest members of our staff here, I hope that we do our work well so that they will have an even better world to inherit and hopefully to leave even better than we’re doing right now.  So again, thank you, thank you, thank you for everything that you’re doing every single day.  It’s great to see you.  It’s great to be with you.  And thanks for having us, and I hope that if nothing else there’s a very good wheels-up party later today.  (Laughter.)</p>
<p><strong>MR KESHAP:</strong>  Thank you very much, Mr. Secretary.  (Applause.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opening Remarks at a Civil Society Roundtable</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/opening-remarks-at-a-civil-society-roundtable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 06:11:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=262745</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>New Delhi, India</p>
<p>The Leela Palace Hotel </p>
<p><strong>MR KESHAP:  </strong>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen.  Nice to see all of you.  Thank you for joining us this morning.  It is a very great pleasure for me to participate in this morning’s discussion on inclusive development with the United States Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken and our distinguished guests from these civil society organizations.</p>
<p>The theme selected for discussion today, “Advancing Equitable, Inclusive, and Sustainable Growth and Development,” is central to addressing the challenges that we face throughout the world, including in the United States and India.  We cherish the rich diversity of our societies and see this as a source of our strength.  Another great pillar of our strength is the roles of civil society in both the United States and India.</p>
<p>Today it is indeed my great honor to welcome Secretary of State Antony Blinken to Delhi and for what I am sure will be a very vibrant discussion.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, welcome.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you, well thank you so much.  Everyone, thank you very, very much.  It is a great pleasure to be with all of you.  This is actually the first event on our first day in India.  I’ve been here many times before, but this is my first visit in this capacity as Secretary of State, and I wanted to start the day with all of you.  And I’m really here to underscore the importance of the relationships between our countries, to try to deepen our ties and extend our cooperation.  I think it’s hard to find countries with more – who do more together in more different areas than with the United States and India.</p>
<p>Later today, I’ll have a chance to see Prime Minister Modi, External Affairs Minister Jaishankar, an old friend and colleague.  We’ll talk about many of the critical issues our countries are working on together, from COVID-19 to climate change, defense, mutual security, trade and investment, education, energy, science, technology.  The list goes on and on.</p>
<p>When you put it all together, the relationship between our countries is one of the most important in the world.  And I think that’s because not only is it a relationship between governments when we’re working between our governments, but critically it’s through relationships between the Indian and the American people.  We’re connected in so many different ways – business ties, university ties, religious and spiritual ties, and of course, millions of family ties.</p>
<p>Perhaps most important, we’re connected by shared values, and I believe shared aspirations, that are common to our people.  The Indian people and the American people believe in human dignity, in equality of opportunity, the rule of law, fundamental freedoms, including freedom of religion and belief.  We believe that all people deserve to have a voice in their government and be treated with respect no matter who they are.  These are fundamental tenets of democracies like ours, and our purpose is to give real meaning to these words and constantly renew our commitment to these ideals.</p>
<p>And of course, both of our democracies are works in progress.  As friends, we talk about that, because doing the hard work of strengthening democracy and making our ideals real is often challenging.  We know that firsthand in the United States, where we aspire to be, in the words of our founders, a more perfect union.  That’s an acknowledgement from day one of our country that in a sense we will always fall short of the mark, but that the way to make progress is by constantly trying to achieve those ideals.  As I said before, sometimes that process is painful, sometimes it’s ugly, but the strength of democracy is to embrace it.</p>
<p>At the same time, we celebrate our achievements.  Here in India, that includes the free media, independent courts, a vibrant and free and fair electoral system – the largest expression of free political will by citizens anywhere in the world.  At a time of rising global threats to democracy and international freedoms – we talk about a democratic recession – it’s vital that we two world leading democracies continue to stand together in support of these ideals.</p>
<p>We also know that successful democracies include thriving civil societies.  That’s how citizens become more fully engaged in the life of their communities.  It’s how we organize and provide the resources to respond to emergencies.  And we’ve seen people and organizations come together throughout COVID-19 in creative and incredibly generous ways, and civil society is also where we’re able to build meaningful connections across our social, religious, and cultural differences.</p>
<p>In short, if we want to make our democracies more open, more inclusive, more resilient, more equitable, we need vibrant civil society.  As leaders in your respective communities, I think you know this better than anyone.  I am proud of all the connections that already exist between civil society organizations in our countries.  I want to support more of those connections to make the overall partnership between our democracies even stronger.</p>
<p>So what I hope we can do in our time today is do a little bit of that to continue to strengthen the connections among civil society and between civil society and government.  I need to learn more about the work that you’re doing in your communities, especially during this pandemic.  I want to know what more we can do to strengthen the ties between our civil society, and I want to hear your ideas, your ideas about how to drive inclusive, equitable development, because that’s something that democracies all over the world are called upon to do.</p>
<p>So thank you again for taking the time to have this conversation.  I’m especially eager to hear from you.  And with that, we can get started.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>New Delhi, India</p>
<p>The Leela Palace Hotel </p>
<p><strong>MR KESHAP:  </strong>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen.  Nice to see all of you.  Thank you for joining us this morning.  It is a very great pleasure for me to participate in this morning’s discussion on inclusive development with the United States Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken and our distinguished guests from these civil society organizations.</p>
<p>The theme selected for discussion today, “Advancing Equitable, Inclusive, and Sustainable Growth and Development,” is central to addressing the challenges that we face throughout the world, including in the United States and India.  We cherish the rich diversity of our societies and see this as a source of our strength.  Another great pillar of our strength is the roles of civil society in both the United States and India.</p>
<p>Today it is indeed my great honor to welcome Secretary of State Antony Blinken to Delhi and for what I am sure will be a very vibrant discussion.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary, welcome.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you, well thank you so much.  Everyone, thank you very, very much.  It is a great pleasure to be with all of you.  This is actually the first event on our first day in India.  I’ve been here many times before, but this is my first visit in this capacity as Secretary of State, and I wanted to start the day with all of you.  And I’m really here to underscore the importance of the relationships between our countries, to try to deepen our ties and extend our cooperation.  I think it’s hard to find countries with more – who do more together in more different areas than with the United States and India.</p>
<p>Later today, I’ll have a chance to see Prime Minister Modi, External Affairs Minister Jaishankar, an old friend and colleague.  We’ll talk about many of the critical issues our countries are working on together, from COVID-19 to climate change, defense, mutual security, trade and investment, education, energy, science, technology.  The list goes on and on.</p>
<p>When you put it all together, the relationship between our countries is one of the most important in the world.  And I think that’s because not only is it a relationship between governments when we’re working between our governments, but critically it’s through relationships between the Indian and the American people.  We’re connected in so many different ways – business ties, university ties, religious and spiritual ties, and of course, millions of family ties.</p>
<p>Perhaps most important, we’re connected by shared values, and I believe shared aspirations, that are common to our people.  The Indian people and the American people believe in human dignity, in equality of opportunity, the rule of law, fundamental freedoms, including freedom of religion and belief.  We believe that all people deserve to have a voice in their government and be treated with respect no matter who they are.  These are fundamental tenets of democracies like ours, and our purpose is to give real meaning to these words and constantly renew our commitment to these ideals.</p>
<p>And of course, both of our democracies are works in progress.  As friends, we talk about that, because doing the hard work of strengthening democracy and making our ideals real is often challenging.  We know that firsthand in the United States, where we aspire to be, in the words of our founders, a more perfect union.  That’s an acknowledgement from day one of our country that in a sense we will always fall short of the mark, but that the way to make progress is by constantly trying to achieve those ideals.  As I said before, sometimes that process is painful, sometimes it’s ugly, but the strength of democracy is to embrace it.</p>
<p>At the same time, we celebrate our achievements.  Here in India, that includes the free media, independent courts, a vibrant and free and fair electoral system – the largest expression of free political will by citizens anywhere in the world.  At a time of rising global threats to democracy and international freedoms – we talk about a democratic recession – it’s vital that we two world leading democracies continue to stand together in support of these ideals.</p>
<p>We also know that successful democracies include thriving civil societies.  That’s how citizens become more fully engaged in the life of their communities.  It’s how we organize and provide the resources to respond to emergencies.  And we’ve seen people and organizations come together throughout COVID-19 in creative and incredibly generous ways, and civil society is also where we’re able to build meaningful connections across our social, religious, and cultural differences.</p>
<p>In short, if we want to make our democracies more open, more inclusive, more resilient, more equitable, we need vibrant civil society.  As leaders in your respective communities, I think you know this better than anyone.  I am proud of all the connections that already exist between civil society organizations in our countries.  I want to support more of those connections to make the overall partnership between our democracies even stronger.</p>
<p>So what I hope we can do in our time today is do a little bit of that to continue to strengthen the connections among civil society and between civil society and government.  I need to learn more about the work that you’re doing in your communities, especially during this pandemic.  I want to know what more we can do to strengthen the ties between our civil society, and I want to hear your ideas, your ideas about how to drive inclusive, equitable development, because that’s something that democracies all over the world are called upon to do.</p>
<p>So thank you again for taking the time to have this conversation.  I’m especially eager to hear from you.  And with that, we can get started.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Department Press Briefing &#8211; July 27, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/briefings/department-press-briefing-july-27-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 20:59:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?post_type=state_briefing&#038;p=262710</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:06 p.m. EST</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Good afternoon and Happy Tuesday. Thank you for joining today’s department press briefing. I have a few announcements to make at the top, and I’ll proceed with your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-GUATEMALA"></a> The United States has made clear to the highest levels of Government of Guatemala our view that the fight against corruption is essential to our shared goals of strengthening the rule of law, increasing economic opportunity, and addressing the root causes of irregular migration. The message has been delivered consistently, without equivocation, by our ambassador in Guatemala and during recent visits of high-level U.S. Government officials that reaffirmed the partnership of our two nations, including the visit of Vice President Kamala Harris, USAID Administrator Samantha Power, and Homeland Security Secretary Alejandro Mayorkas.</p>
<p>Guatemalan Attorney General Consuelo Porras’ July 23rd decision to remove Special Prosecutor Against Impunity, or FECI, Chief Juan Francisco Sandoval fits a pattern of behavior that indicates a lack of commitment to the rule of law and independent judicial and prosecutorial processes. As a result, we have lost confidence in the attorney general and their decision – and intention to cooperate with the U.S. Government and fight corruption in good faith. We understand the removal of the FECI Chief was a decision by a Guatemalan official acting within the official’s authority, but our concern is with the implications with this decision for the rule of law and regional stability.</p>
<p>As a result of the attorney general’s actions, the U.S. Government is temporarily pausing programmatic cooperation with the Public Ministry while it conducts a review of our assistance to activities the attorney general leads. We’re watching closely for additional actions that would undermine the rule of law or judicial independence in Guatemala.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-ERITREA"></a> Next, we are deeply concerned about credible reports of attacks by military forces affiliated with the Tigray People’s Liberation Front and Tigrayan militias against Eritrean refugees in the Tigray region, particularly reports of violence in refugee camps.</p>
<p>We call on all armed actors in Tigray to stop attacks and intimidation against Eritrean forces and all refugees, asylum seekers and people displaced by the ongoing violence, as well as against the aid workers attempting to respond to the humanitarian disaster more broadly.</p>
<p>This is not the first time Eritrean populations have been targeted in Tigray. In January, credible reports indicated that Eritrean refugees suffered killings, targeted abductions, and forced returns to Eritrea at the hands of Eritrean forces.</p>
<p>We call on all parties to adhere strictly to their obligations under international humanitarian law, and for those responsible for violations of international humanitarian law and human rights abuses to be held accountable through independent and transparent international processes.</p>
<p>And finally, the State Department’s 12th Annual EducationUSA Forum opened yesterday and will run through Friday of this week.</p>
<p>Addressing the open Plenary, Secretary Blinken and Education Secretary Cardona announced a Joint Statement of Principles in support of international education, emphasizing our shared commitment to promoting international education at home and abroad and highlighting the benefit to all Americans.</p>
<p>International education makes critical contributions to U.S. diplomacy, national security, economic prosperity, and leadership in research and innovation.</p>
<p>Held virtually this year, the EducationUSA Forum organized by the Department’s Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs, or ECA, showcases our global network of over 430 student advising centers in more than 175 countries.</p>
<p>Approximately 2,000 registrants for the Forum represent hundreds of accredited U.S. colleges and universities along with other higher education sector stakeholders. Participation will explore strategies to strengthen the United States’ status as a top study destination for international students from around the globe.</p>
<p>As international students study at U.S. colleges and universities, they participate in a world-class education while enriching their classrooms and communities with diverse perspectives and developing ties with their American peers. These ties form the basis of our country’s success in business and trade, science and innovation, and government relations. International students also contributed over $39 billion to the U.S. economy in 2020, representing a top service sector export, and supporting an estimated 415,000 U.S. jobs. Supporting international education is important to our national effort to achieve a strong, durable economic recovery from the pandemic.</p>
<p>And with that, I will start taking your questions. Let’s go to the line of Pearl Matibe.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> I do apologize. Could you please repeat the name?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Pearl Matibe.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hello, Jalina. Good &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Pearl, your line is open. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-ZAMBIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you very much. Good morning, Jalina. My question is on Zambia. They have elections in about three weeks, and now we are already seeing that this is going to be an unlevel playing field. And observers from the European Union already have a strong team ahead of the elections, which is great, but there have been criticism of the international community failing to identify manipulation ahead of an election. So I wondered does the U.S. have a close eye on the upcoming Zambian election and if you have anything to share about worries right now. Watch dogs are being silenced and so on, three weeks left to go. Thanks, Jalina.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Pearl. What I can say more broadly is that the United States certainly supports free and fair elections, and we know that’s the way of upholding democratic institutions not only in Zambia but around the world. I don’t have anything other than that for you. Anything else, we’ll have to take that question back for you.</p>
<p>Casey O’Neill, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Casey, your line is open. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. Hi, Jalina. I was wondering if we can turn to Tunisia. So yesterday at the White House press briefing, Jen Psaki was asked about whether or not the U.S. has made a determination on whether or not a coup took place in Tunisia. Jen Psaki stated that the State Department had not made a legal determination. But then yesterday evening, Secretary Blinken, as I’m sure you’re aware, sent out two tweets regarding Tunisia, the first essentially saying that he had a, quote, “good phone call” with President Saied of Tunisia. And then hours later, he appeared to attempt to backpedal on that tweet, outlining essentially a conversation saying he encouraged the president to adhere to the principles of democracy, human rights, et cetera.</p>
<p>So just a couple questions for you. The first: Has the State Department made a legal determination as to whether or not a coup has taken place in Tunisia? And secondly, if not, why did Secretary Blinken tweet out that he had a, quote, “good phone call” with a president who is being investigated, for lack of a better word, for potentially inciting or carrying out a coup in his country? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks for your questions. Well, I’ll just start off by saying that we are closely monitoring the situation in Tunisia. And we encourage all political actors to comply with the Tunisian constitution, as well as to respect democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>To your questions on the Secretary and his tweets, listen, Secretary Blinken spoke at great length with the Tunisian president, President Saied, yesterday. And the Secretary urged the President Saied to maintain open dialogue with all political actors and the Tunisian people. And I’ll just, again, just reiterate that the events in Tunisia are currently still ongoing, and we are closely monitoring the situation.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Daphne Psaledakis.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks for doing this. I wanted to follow up on that question on Tunisia. Can you say whether the U.S. is determining whether a military coup has taken place and therefore whether the U.S. Government is required to cut off all assistance to the country other than democracy-related assistance?</p>
<p>And then separately, if I may, there are reports that a swastika was found yesterday etched into the wall of the State Department elevator near the Office of the Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Anti-Semitism. Can you confirm this? And if so, how is the State Department responding to this? Has Blinken addressed it, and what was his message to staff, if so?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> I’m sorry. Can you repeat your – the first part of your second question on the special envoy?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh, sorry. There are reports that a swastika was found yesterday etched into the wall of a State Department elevator near the office of the Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Anti-Semitism. Could you confirm that? And what will the State Department – how will the State Department handle this? Has Blinken addressed it?</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-department"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So thank you for your question. And yes, unfortunately, late yesterday a swastika was found carved in an elevator in our building here at the State Department. This hateful graffiti has been removed and this incident will be investigated. As the Secretary has shared with a message to all of our employees, this is completely abhorrent. It’s a painful reminder, and anti-Semitism isn’t a relic of the past; it’s still a force that we’re dealing with in the world, and unfortunately, we’re dealing with it close to home. It has to be said that anti-Semitism has no place in the United States and certainly has no place in the State Department. We can and must be relentless in standing up and rejecting this type of hate and hate in all forms.</p>
<p>We also know that from our history and from history of other nations that anti-Semitism often goes hand in hand with racism, homophobia, xenophobia, and any other hatred that you can name. None of these ideologies have a place in our workplace and they certainly have no place in the United States.</p>
<p>As far as any personnel updates, we don’t have any specific update to share outside of that Secretary Blinken, when he spoke to members of Congress last month, that we are working very diligently to – on the nomination of a special envoy to combat anti-Semitism, and we surely hope that the person is in place soon.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-tunisia"></a> Again, outside of – going back to your first question on Tunisia, I’ll just continue to underscore that the situation in Tunisia is evolving and we’re closely monitoring the situation. We certainly encourage all political actors to comply with the Tunisian constitution and as well as to respect democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Shaun Tandon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> More on Tunisia. In the mention of the Secretary saying that there should be the adherence to democratic principles, what specifically is he looking for the Tunisian president to do? Does he want him to reverse the decision to suspend parliament, to un-sack, if you will, the prime minister without further conversation? And what pressure points, if any, were listed there in terms of ways to get him to move in that direction?</p>
<p>And secondly, if you don’t mind, North and South Korea. They announced a restoration of communications, of cross-border communications. Do you have any reaction to that? And how does that impact the United States? Does this pave the way at all for dialogue with North Korea potentially? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Shaun. So we did issue a readout of the Secretary’s call with the Tunisian president. I won’t go anything beyond the readout.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-Northkoreasouthkorea"></a> And to your second question, I’ll say that the U.S. supports inter-Korean dialogue and engagement, and of course welcomes today’s announcement of restoration of inter-Korean communication lines, and we certainly believe that this is a positive step. I’ll also say that diplomacy and dialogue are essential to achieving complete denuclearization and establishing permanent peace on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Hiba Nasr. Do we have Hiba Nasr?</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Your line is now open. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-lebanon"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for taking my question. My first question is on Lebanon. Yesterday we had a new prime minister-designate, Najib Mikati. Do you have any comment on that and a new message to the Lebanese leaders?</p>
<p>And my second question, on Iraq. We saw the statement yesterday. And till now, there are many officials that are emphasizing – who are emphasizing that this is a withdrawal, U.S. withdrawal from Iraq. Can you elaborate a little bit on that? Is it a withdrawal or not?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Hiba. I’ll take – start with your first question. We’re certainly aware of the president of Lebanon’s appointment as Lebanon’s prime minister-designate as on June – I’m sorry, on July 26th, the U.S. renews its calls to quickly form a government that’s empowered and a government that’s also committed to implementing critical reforms.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-iraq"></a> To your question on Iraq, our countries issued a joint communique which outlines our bilateral agreements and outcomes from our fourth strategic dialogue. We also released a fact sheet, if you haven’t seen that – we released that on Friday – which outlines the depth of our partnership. I’d have to refer you to that readout for more details.</p>
<p>Hiba, I’m sorry. If we still have you, I wanted to answer your question about the withdrawal too. Frankly, no, the key point here is that we agreed with the Iraqis that U.S. forces, military forces, will remain in Iraq to focus on training, enabling, and advising our Iraqi partners.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Matt Lee, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Happy Tuesday. Two things real quick. One, do you have anything more to say about tomorrow’s strategic talks in Geneva that Deputy Secretary Sherman is leading? By “more to say,” I mean anything more than the announcement of it from Friday, like are you expecting any kind of a significant announcement out of it.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-department2"></a> And then secondly, really briefly on this swastika incident, can – the report that this was found near the office of the anti-Semitism envoy is part of the question that I’m interested in getting an answer to, because not to make any kind of light of this, but if it was in an elevator, doesn’t – the proximity of it to any number of offices depending on what floor the elevator is on is a question. So my question is: Is the department treating it at the moment, pending an investigation, as something that was directly related to that office? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Matt. Well, I’ll say again that the situation with the swastika is currently being investigated, and as far as proximity, I mean, anywhere inside or nearby the State Department or inside or nearby – in the United States is just unwelcome, and we will continue to condemn it.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-russia"></a> To your first question on the strategic stability dialogue, not much to say outside of what you’ve already seen. Of course, no specific announcements, but for people who may be listening and would like to know that the United States and Russia have agreed to convene a strategic stability dialogue in Geneva on the 28th, so tomorrow. Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman will lead the U.S. delegation. She’ll also be joined by our newest under secretary, Under Secretary of State for Arms Control and International Security Bonnie Jenkins, who will provide additional leadership for the delegation.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Laura Kelly.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-israel"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. Human Rights Watch issued a report today that concludes the Israeli military attacks on the Gaza Strip in May apparently amount to war crimes and that the Israeli military used U.S.-made GBU-31 precision-guided bombs during at least one particular attack on al-Wehda Street. And the human rights group says that while the Israeli military said it was a legitimate target, Human Rights Watch had not received details to support that claim. Do you have any comment on the Human Rights Watch report and are you concerned about reports of U.S. missiles or bombs being used or being implicated in deaths of civilians?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Laura. I have not seen the report, so I have nothing to share at this time. We’ll have to take that question back for you.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Laura Rozen.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Laura, your line is open. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-oman"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. Thanks for taking this. Do you have a readout of Deputy Secretary Sherman’s trip to Oman? And also, can you say if she’s using her visit there to send messages to Iran, including on detained U.S. citizens in Iran? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Laura. So Deputy Secretary Sherman did meet in – I’m sorry, she met in Oman with Deputy Foreign Minister Khalifa Al Harthy in Muscat. They discussed advancing peace and security in the region as well as our shared commitment to bolstering the U.S.-Oman bilateral relationship, which includes advancing new opportunities for trade and investment. The deputy secretary also thanked the deputy foreign minister for Oman’s role in mediating peace in the region and also underscored the importance of an immediate and comprehensive ceasefire to help bring the war to an end – the war in Yemen to an end.</p>
<p>We’ll take one last question from Muhammad El Ahmed.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong>And your line is open. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hello? Yes, hi. Thank you, Jalina, for taking my question. I have actually two questions – or actually, three questions.</p>
<p>First, what leverage does the U.S. – sorry, what leverage is the U.S. planning to exercise on President Kais Saied to avoid the Egyptian scenario, and how concerned that any miscalculation in the fragile Tunisia could backfire in the already-hot region, especially in Libya?</p>
<p>My second question, the other question is about Yemen. Today, State Department issued a statement about new trip to – Special Envoy Lenderking to the region. This is, I believe, the first trip there. Is there any updates about the possibilities of reaching an agreement, or it’s just part of regular consultations that the SE is doing there?</p>
<p>And finally, on Deputy Secretary Sherman’s visit to Oman, would her schedule include other meetings with regional players or it would take only two meetings with Omani official? Thank you so much.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Muhammad. To the deputy secretary’s meeting in Oman, I would have to refer you to the readout.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-yemen"></a> To your question on Special Envoy Lenderking, we can confirm that our U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking arrived in Saudi Arabia today and he’ll be meeting with senior officials from Saudi as well – and the Republic of Yemen governments. He will discuss the growing consequences of the Houthi offensive on Marib which is exacerbating the humanitarian crisis as well as triggering instability elsewhere in the country. He’ll also address the need for efforts by the Republic of Yemen Government and Saudi Arabia to stabilize Yemen’s economy, and also to facilitate the timely import of fuel to northern Yemen and the need for the Houthis to end their manipulation of fuel imports and prices inside of Yemen.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-tunisia2"></a> To your first question, I believe that was on Tunisia, and any leverage, again, I’ll just repeat that Secretary Blinken spoke, again, at great length with Tunisian President Saied yesterday, and he urged the president – President Saied to maintain an open dialogue with all political prisoners – I’m sorry, political actors and the Tunisian people.</p>
<p>That concludes today’s press briefing. Thank you all for joining. I hope you have a great rest of your day.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:32 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jalina Porter, Principal Deputy Spokesperson</p>
<p>2:06 p.m. EST</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Good afternoon and Happy Tuesday. Thank you for joining today’s department press briefing. I have a few announcements to make at the top, and I’ll proceed with your questions.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-GUATEMALA"></a> The United States has made clear to the highest levels of Government of Guatemala our view that the fight against corruption is essential to our shared goals of strengthening the rule of law, increasing economic opportunity, and addressing the root causes of irregular migration. The message has been delivered consistently, without equivocation, by our ambassador in Guatemala and during recent visits of high-level U.S. Government officials that reaffirmed the partnership of our two nations, including the visit of Vice President Kamala Harris, USAID Administrator Samantha Power, and Homeland Security Secretary Alejandro Mayorkas.</p>
<p>Guatemalan Attorney General Consuelo Porras’ July 23rd decision to remove Special Prosecutor Against Impunity, or FECI, Chief Juan Francisco Sandoval fits a pattern of behavior that indicates a lack of commitment to the rule of law and independent judicial and prosecutorial processes. As a result, we have lost confidence in the attorney general and their decision – and intention to cooperate with the U.S. Government and fight corruption in good faith. We understand the removal of the FECI Chief was a decision by a Guatemalan official acting within the official’s authority, but our concern is with the implications with this decision for the rule of law and regional stability.</p>
<p>As a result of the attorney general’s actions, the U.S. Government is temporarily pausing programmatic cooperation with the Public Ministry while it conducts a review of our assistance to activities the attorney general leads. We’re watching closely for additional actions that would undermine the rule of law or judicial independence in Guatemala.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-ERITREA"></a> Next, we are deeply concerned about credible reports of attacks by military forces affiliated with the Tigray People’s Liberation Front and Tigrayan militias against Eritrean refugees in the Tigray region, particularly reports of violence in refugee camps.</p>
<p>We call on all armed actors in Tigray to stop attacks and intimidation against Eritrean forces and all refugees, asylum seekers and people displaced by the ongoing violence, as well as against the aid workers attempting to respond to the humanitarian disaster more broadly.</p>
<p>This is not the first time Eritrean populations have been targeted in Tigray. In January, credible reports indicated that Eritrean refugees suffered killings, targeted abductions, and forced returns to Eritrea at the hands of Eritrean forces.</p>
<p>We call on all parties to adhere strictly to their obligations under international humanitarian law, and for those responsible for violations of international humanitarian law and human rights abuses to be held accountable through independent and transparent international processes.</p>
<p>And finally, the State Department’s 12th Annual EducationUSA Forum opened yesterday and will run through Friday of this week.</p>
<p>Addressing the open Plenary, Secretary Blinken and Education Secretary Cardona announced a Joint Statement of Principles in support of international education, emphasizing our shared commitment to promoting international education at home and abroad and highlighting the benefit to all Americans.</p>
<p>International education makes critical contributions to U.S. diplomacy, national security, economic prosperity, and leadership in research and innovation.</p>
<p>Held virtually this year, the EducationUSA Forum organized by the Department’s Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs, or ECA, showcases our global network of over 430 student advising centers in more than 175 countries.</p>
<p>Approximately 2,000 registrants for the Forum represent hundreds of accredited U.S. colleges and universities along with other higher education sector stakeholders. Participation will explore strategies to strengthen the United States’ status as a top study destination for international students from around the globe.</p>
<p>As international students study at U.S. colleges and universities, they participate in a world-class education while enriching their classrooms and communities with diverse perspectives and developing ties with their American peers. These ties form the basis of our country’s success in business and trade, science and innovation, and government relations. International students also contributed over $39 billion to the U.S. economy in 2020, representing a top service sector export, and supporting an estimated 415,000 U.S. jobs. Supporting international education is important to our national effort to achieve a strong, durable economic recovery from the pandemic.</p>
<p>And with that, I will start taking your questions. Let’s go to the line of Pearl Matibe.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> I do apologize. Could you please repeat the name?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Pearl Matibe.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hello, Jalina. Good &#8212;</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Pearl, your line is open. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-ZAMBIA"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you very much. Good morning, Jalina. My question is on Zambia. They have elections in about three weeks, and now we are already seeing that this is going to be an unlevel playing field. And observers from the European Union already have a strong team ahead of the elections, which is great, but there have been criticism of the international community failing to identify manipulation ahead of an election. So I wondered does the U.S. have a close eye on the upcoming Zambian election and if you have anything to share about worries right now. Watch dogs are being silenced and so on, three weeks left to go. Thanks, Jalina.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Pearl. What I can say more broadly is that the United States certainly supports free and fair elections, and we know that’s the way of upholding democratic institutions not only in Zambia but around the world. I don’t have anything other than that for you. Anything else, we’ll have to take that question back for you.</p>
<p>Casey O’Neill, please.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Casey, your line is open. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. Hi, Jalina. I was wondering if we can turn to Tunisia. So yesterday at the White House press briefing, Jen Psaki was asked about whether or not the U.S. has made a determination on whether or not a coup took place in Tunisia. Jen Psaki stated that the State Department had not made a legal determination. But then yesterday evening, Secretary Blinken, as I’m sure you’re aware, sent out two tweets regarding Tunisia, the first essentially saying that he had a, quote, “good phone call” with President Saied of Tunisia. And then hours later, he appeared to attempt to backpedal on that tweet, outlining essentially a conversation saying he encouraged the president to adhere to the principles of democracy, human rights, et cetera.</p>
<p>So just a couple questions for you. The first: Has the State Department made a legal determination as to whether or not a coup has taken place in Tunisia? And secondly, if not, why did Secretary Blinken tweet out that he had a, quote, “good phone call” with a president who is being investigated, for lack of a better word, for potentially inciting or carrying out a coup in his country? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks for your questions. Well, I’ll just start off by saying that we are closely monitoring the situation in Tunisia. And we encourage all political actors to comply with the Tunisian constitution, as well as to respect democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>To your questions on the Secretary and his tweets, listen, Secretary Blinken spoke at great length with the Tunisian president, President Saied, yesterday. And the Secretary urged the President Saied to maintain open dialogue with all political actors and the Tunisian people. And I’ll just, again, just reiterate that the events in Tunisia are currently still ongoing, and we are closely monitoring the situation.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Daphne Psaledakis.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thanks for doing this. I wanted to follow up on that question on Tunisia. Can you say whether the U.S. is determining whether a military coup has taken place and therefore whether the U.S. Government is required to cut off all assistance to the country other than democracy-related assistance?</p>
<p>And then separately, if I may, there are reports that a swastika was found yesterday etched into the wall of the State Department elevator near the Office of the Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Anti-Semitism. Can you confirm this? And if so, how is the State Department responding to this? Has Blinken addressed it, and what was his message to staff, if so?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> I’m sorry. Can you repeat your – the first part of your second question on the special envoy?</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Oh, sorry. There are reports that a swastika was found yesterday etched into the wall of a State Department elevator near the office of the Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Anti-Semitism. Could you confirm that? And what will the State Department – how will the State Department handle this? Has Blinken addressed it?</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-department"></a><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> So thank you for your question. And yes, unfortunately, late yesterday a swastika was found carved in an elevator in our building here at the State Department. This hateful graffiti has been removed and this incident will be investigated. As the Secretary has shared with a message to all of our employees, this is completely abhorrent. It’s a painful reminder, and anti-Semitism isn’t a relic of the past; it’s still a force that we’re dealing with in the world, and unfortunately, we’re dealing with it close to home. It has to be said that anti-Semitism has no place in the United States and certainly has no place in the State Department. We can and must be relentless in standing up and rejecting this type of hate and hate in all forms.</p>
<p>We also know that from our history and from history of other nations that anti-Semitism often goes hand in hand with racism, homophobia, xenophobia, and any other hatred that you can name. None of these ideologies have a place in our workplace and they certainly have no place in the United States.</p>
<p>As far as any personnel updates, we don’t have any specific update to share outside of that Secretary Blinken, when he spoke to members of Congress last month, that we are working very diligently to – on the nomination of a special envoy to combat anti-Semitism, and we surely hope that the person is in place soon.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-tunisia"></a> Again, outside of – going back to your first question on Tunisia, I’ll just continue to underscore that the situation in Tunisia is evolving and we’re closely monitoring the situation. We certainly encourage all political actors to comply with the Tunisian constitution and as well as to respect democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Shaun Tandon.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> More on Tunisia. In the mention of the Secretary saying that there should be the adherence to democratic principles, what specifically is he looking for the Tunisian president to do? Does he want him to reverse the decision to suspend parliament, to un-sack, if you will, the prime minister without further conversation? And what pressure points, if any, were listed there in terms of ways to get him to move in that direction?</p>
<p>And secondly, if you don’t mind, North and South Korea. They announced a restoration of communications, of cross-border communications. Do you have any reaction to that? And how does that impact the United States? Does this pave the way at all for dialogue with North Korea potentially? Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Shaun. So we did issue a readout of the Secretary’s call with the Tunisian president. I won’t go anything beyond the readout.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-Northkoreasouthkorea"></a> And to your second question, I’ll say that the U.S. supports inter-Korean dialogue and engagement, and of course welcomes today’s announcement of restoration of inter-Korean communication lines, and we certainly believe that this is a positive step. I’ll also say that diplomacy and dialogue are essential to achieving complete denuclearization and establishing permanent peace on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Hiba Nasr. Do we have Hiba Nasr?</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Your line is now open. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-lebanon"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thanks for taking my question. My first question is on Lebanon. Yesterday we had a new prime minister-designate, Najib Mikati. Do you have any comment on that and a new message to the Lebanese leaders?</p>
<p>And my second question, on Iraq. We saw the statement yesterday. And till now, there are many officials that are emphasizing – who are emphasizing that this is a withdrawal, U.S. withdrawal from Iraq. Can you elaborate a little bit on that? Is it a withdrawal or not?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Hiba. I’ll take – start with your first question. We’re certainly aware of the president of Lebanon’s appointment as Lebanon’s prime minister-designate as on June – I’m sorry, on July 26th, the U.S. renews its calls to quickly form a government that’s empowered and a government that’s also committed to implementing critical reforms.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-iraq"></a> To your question on Iraq, our countries issued a joint communique which outlines our bilateral agreements and outcomes from our fourth strategic dialogue. We also released a fact sheet, if you haven’t seen that – we released that on Friday – which outlines the depth of our partnership. I’d have to refer you to that readout for more details.</p>
<p>Hiba, I’m sorry. If we still have you, I wanted to answer your question about the withdrawal too. Frankly, no, the key point here is that we agreed with the Iraqis that U.S. forces, military forces, will remain in Iraq to focus on training, enabling, and advising our Iraqi partners.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Matt Lee, please.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Happy Tuesday. Two things real quick. One, do you have anything more to say about tomorrow’s strategic talks in Geneva that Deputy Secretary Sherman is leading? By “more to say,” I mean anything more than the announcement of it from Friday, like are you expecting any kind of a significant announcement out of it.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-department2"></a> And then secondly, really briefly on this swastika incident, can – the report that this was found near the office of the anti-Semitism envoy is part of the question that I’m interested in getting an answer to, because not to make any kind of light of this, but if it was in an elevator, doesn’t – the proximity of it to any number of offices depending on what floor the elevator is on is a question. So my question is: Is the department treating it at the moment, pending an investigation, as something that was directly related to that office? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Matt. Well, I’ll say again that the situation with the swastika is currently being investigated, and as far as proximity, I mean, anywhere inside or nearby the State Department or inside or nearby – in the United States is just unwelcome, and we will continue to condemn it.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-russia"></a> To your first question on the strategic stability dialogue, not much to say outside of what you’ve already seen. Of course, no specific announcements, but for people who may be listening and would like to know that the United States and Russia have agreed to convene a strategic stability dialogue in Geneva on the 28th, so tomorrow. Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman will lead the U.S. delegation. She’ll also be joined by our newest under secretary, Under Secretary of State for Arms Control and International Security Bonnie Jenkins, who will provide additional leadership for the delegation.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Laura Kelly.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-israel"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Hi, Jalina. Thank you for taking my question. Human Rights Watch issued a report today that concludes the Israeli military attacks on the Gaza Strip in May apparently amount to war crimes and that the Israeli military used U.S.-made GBU-31 precision-guided bombs during at least one particular attack on al-Wehda Street. And the human rights group says that while the Israeli military said it was a legitimate target, Human Rights Watch had not received details to support that claim. Do you have any comment on the Human Rights Watch report and are you concerned about reports of U.S. missiles or bombs being used or being implicated in deaths of civilians?</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thanks, Laura. I have not seen the report, so I have nothing to share at this time. We’ll have to take that question back for you.</p>
<p>Let’s go to Laura Rozen.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR:</strong> Laura, your line is open. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-oman"></a><strong>QUESTION:</strong> Thank you. Thanks for taking this. Do you have a readout of Deputy Secretary Sherman’s trip to Oman? And also, can you say if she’s using her visit there to send messages to Iran, including on detained U.S. citizens in Iran? Thanks.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER:</strong> Thank you, Laura. So Deputy Secretary Sherman did meet in – I’m sorry, she met in Oman with Deputy Foreign Minister Khalifa Al Harthy in Muscat. They discussed advancing peace and security in the region as well as our shared commitment to bolstering the U.S.-Oman bilateral relationship, which includes advancing new opportunities for trade and investment. The deputy secretary also thanked the deputy foreign minister for Oman’s role in mediating peace in the region and also underscored the importance of an immediate and comprehensive ceasefire to help bring the war to an end – the war in Yemen to an end.</p>
<p>We’ll take one last question from Muhammad El Ahmed.</p>
<p><strong>OPERATOR: </strong>And your line is open. Please, go ahead.</p>
<p><strong>QUESTION: </strong>Hello? Yes, hi. Thank you, Jalina, for taking my question. I have actually two questions – or actually, three questions.</p>
<p>First, what leverage does the U.S. – sorry, what leverage is the U.S. planning to exercise on President Kais Saied to avoid the Egyptian scenario, and how concerned that any miscalculation in the fragile Tunisia could backfire in the already-hot region, especially in Libya?</p>
<p>My second question, the other question is about Yemen. Today, State Department issued a statement about new trip to – Special Envoy Lenderking to the region. This is, I believe, the first trip there. Is there any updates about the possibilities of reaching an agreement, or it’s just part of regular consultations that the SE is doing there?</p>
<p>And finally, on Deputy Secretary Sherman’s visit to Oman, would her schedule include other meetings with regional players or it would take only two meetings with Omani official? Thank you so much.</p>
<p><strong>MS PORTER: </strong>Thanks, Muhammad. To the deputy secretary’s meeting in Oman, I would have to refer you to the readout.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-yemen"></a> To your question on Special Envoy Lenderking, we can confirm that our U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking arrived in Saudi Arabia today and he’ll be meeting with senior officials from Saudi as well – and the Republic of Yemen governments. He will discuss the growing consequences of the Houthi offensive on Marib which is exacerbating the humanitarian crisis as well as triggering instability elsewhere in the country. He’ll also address the need for efforts by the Republic of Yemen Government and Saudi Arabia to stabilize Yemen’s economy, and also to facilitate the timely import of fuel to northern Yemen and the need for the Houthis to end their manipulation of fuel imports and prices inside of Yemen.</p>
<p><a id="post-262710-tunisia2"></a> To your first question, I believe that was on Tunisia, and any leverage, again, I’ll just repeat that Secretary Blinken spoke, again, at great length with Tunisian President Saied yesterday, and he urged the president – President Saied to maintain an open dialogue with all political prisoners – I’m sorry, political actors and the Tunisian people.</p>
<p>That concludes today’s press briefing. Thank you all for joining. I hope you have a great rest of your day.</p>
<p>(The briefing was concluded at 2:32 p.m.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States Announces New Humanitarian Aid for the People of Somalia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-announces-new-humanitarian-aid-for-the-people-of-somalia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ned Price, Department Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 19:10:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=262671</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The United States is providing nearly $199 million in additional humanitarian assistance for the people of Somalia who have faced decades of chronic food insecurity, violence, and cycles of drought and flooding—the impacts of which have all been compounded by desert locusts and the COVID-19 pandemic. This additional funding, through the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and the U.S. Department of State, brings the total U.S. humanitarian assistance for the people of Somalia to more than  $408 million for Fiscal Year 2021.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">This assistance will help many of the nearly six million people of Somalia in need of humanitarian aid, including three million displaced people inside Somalia as well as nearly 500,000 Somali refugees in Djibouti, Ethiopia, and Kenya.  This new funding will provide emergency food and nutrition assistance, safe drinking water, sanitation, and hygiene, shelter, protection, education, and health care, as well as logistics and other support, in the face of worsening environmental, humanitarian, and conflict related challenges.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The United States is the largest single donor of humanitarian aid in Somalia and for Somali refugees in the regio</span><span class="s2">n</span><span class="s3">,</span><span class="s2"> </span><span class="s1">and we welcome efforts by the UN to draw attention to the plight of the people of Somalia.  We remain concerned about the continuing increase in humanitarian needs, and we urge other donors to contribute to the international response and provide the support needed to save lives.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">For the latest updates on U.S. humanitarian assistance for the people of Somalia, visit:  <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/humanitarian-assistance/somalia"><span class="s4">https://www.usaid.gov/humanitarian-assistance/somalia</span></a>.  For media inquiries, please email <a href="mailto:PRMPress@state.gov"><span class="s4">PRMPress@state.gov</span></a> and <a href="mailto:press@usaid.gov"><span class="s4">press@usaid.gov</span></a>.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Price, Department Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The United States is providing nearly $199 million in additional humanitarian assistance for the people of Somalia who have faced decades of chronic food insecurity, violence, and cycles of drought and flooding—the impacts of which have all been compounded by desert locusts and the COVID-19 pandemic. This additional funding, through the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and the U.S. Department of State, brings the total U.S. humanitarian assistance for the people of Somalia to more than  $408 million for Fiscal Year 2021.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">This assistance will help many of the nearly six million people of Somalia in need of humanitarian aid, including three million displaced people inside Somalia as well as nearly 500,000 Somali refugees in Djibouti, Ethiopia, and Kenya.  This new funding will provide emergency food and nutrition assistance, safe drinking water, sanitation, and hygiene, shelter, protection, education, and health care, as well as logistics and other support, in the face of worsening environmental, humanitarian, and conflict related challenges.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The United States is the largest single donor of humanitarian aid in Somalia and for Somali refugees in the regio</span><span class="s2">n</span><span class="s3">,</span><span class="s2"> </span><span class="s1">and we welcome efforts by the UN to draw attention to the plight of the people of Somalia.  We remain concerned about the continuing increase in humanitarian needs, and we urge other donors to contribute to the international response and provide the support needed to save lives.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">For the latest updates on U.S. humanitarian assistance for the people of Somalia, visit:  <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/humanitarian-assistance/somalia"><span class="s4">https://www.usaid.gov/humanitarian-assistance/somalia</span></a>.  For media inquiries, please email <a href="mailto:PRMPress@state.gov"><span class="s4">PRMPress@state.gov</span></a> and <a href="mailto:press@usaid.gov"><span class="s4">press@usaid.gov</span></a>.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry’s Visit to the United Kingdom and Italy</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/special-presidential-envoy-for-climate-john-kerrys-visit-to-the-united-kingdom-and-italy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 17:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=262588</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry traveled to the United Kingdom and Italy from July 20 to July 26, 2021, to engage with G20 and international counterparts.  This effort raises the climate ambition ahead of the 26th Conference of the Parties (COP26) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) this November in Glasgow, UK.</p>
<p align="left">Secretary Kerry delivered <a href="https://www.state.gov/remarks-on-the-urgency-of-global-climate-action/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MjcuNDM3NTU3OTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvcmVtYXJrcy1vbi10aGUtdXJnZW5jeS1vZi1nbG9iYWwtY2xpbWF0ZS1hY3Rpb24vIn0.N9pIcMH67wXNEQpmjubdl-aJ_-gNN8G2t6YG4D21KXk/s/1039202793/br/109977073166-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1627491109414000&amp;usg=AFQjCNF5nNcUtf11ORmpYa3o2YjJ27RXHQ">remarks</a> on the urgency of global climate action in London at the Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew, on July 20.  A video of his remarks is available <a class="external-link" href="https://www.chathamhouse.org/events/all/members-event/john-kerry-urgency-global-climate-action" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">here</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.  Secretary Kerry then attended the G20 Ministerial Meeting on Environment, Climate, and Energy in Naples, Italy from July 21 to July 23, where he participated in a series of bilateral and multilateral discussions on the need for increased action to address the climate crisis <wbr />and the importance of a successful G20 Leaders’ Summit and COP26.  The <a class="external-link__pdf" href="https://www.g20.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/2021_G20-Energy-Climate-joint-Ministerial-Communique.pdf" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">G20 Energy-Climate Joint Ministerial Communique</span><span class="filesize icon-pdf"> </span></a> included positive progress in key areas, including: the recognition of the leadership role of the G20 with respect to addressing climate; the importance of keeping the 1.5 degree Celsius temperature rise limit within reach; the recognition of the 2020s as a critical decade for climate action; the submission of enhanced Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) by COP26; the development of net-zero long-term strategies by COP26; and the importance of green COVID-19 recoveries featuring clean energy innovation and deployment, among others.</p>
<p align="left">Returning to the United Kingdom, Secretary Kerry participated in a ministerial meeting from July 25 to July 26 hosted by COP26 President Alok Sharma to discuss key elements of climate ambition and negotiations under the Paris Agreement.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left">Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry traveled to the United Kingdom and Italy from July 20 to July 26, 2021, to engage with G20 and international counterparts.  This effort raises the climate ambition ahead of the 26th Conference of the Parties (COP26) to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) this November in Glasgow, UK.</p>
<p align="left">Secretary Kerry delivered <a href="https://www.state.gov/remarks-on-the-urgency-of-global-climate-action/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA3MjcuNDM3NTU3OTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5zdGF0ZS5nb3YvcmVtYXJrcy1vbi10aGUtdXJnZW5jeS1vZi1nbG9iYWwtY2xpbWF0ZS1hY3Rpb24vIn0.N9pIcMH67wXNEQpmjubdl-aJ_-gNN8G2t6YG4D21KXk/s/1039202793/br/109977073166-l&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1627491109414000&amp;usg=AFQjCNF5nNcUtf11ORmpYa3o2YjJ27RXHQ">remarks</a> on the urgency of global climate action in London at the Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew, on July 20.  A video of his remarks is available <a class="external-link" href="https://www.chathamhouse.org/events/all/members-event/john-kerry-urgency-global-climate-action" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">here</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a>.  Secretary Kerry then attended the G20 Ministerial Meeting on Environment, Climate, and Energy in Naples, Italy from July 21 to July 23, where he participated in a series of bilateral and multilateral discussions on the need for increased action to address the climate crisis <wbr />and the importance of a successful G20 Leaders’ Summit and COP26.  The <a class="external-link__pdf" href="https://www.g20.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/2021_G20-Energy-Climate-joint-Ministerial-Communique.pdf" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">G20 Energy-Climate Joint Ministerial Communique</span><span class="filesize icon-pdf"> </span></a> included positive progress in key areas, including: the recognition of the leadership role of the G20 with respect to addressing climate; the importance of keeping the 1.5 degree Celsius temperature rise limit within reach; the recognition of the 2020s as a critical decade for climate action; the submission of enhanced Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) by COP26; the development of net-zero long-term strategies by COP26; and the importance of green COVID-19 recoveries featuring clean energy innovation and deployment, among others.</p>
<p align="left">Returning to the United Kingdom, Secretary Kerry participated in a ministerial meeting from July 25 to July 26 hosted by COP26 President Alok Sharma to discuss key elements of climate ambition and negotiations under the Paris Agreement.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Lenderking’s Travel to Saudi Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/u-s-special-envoy-for-yemen-lenderkings-travel-to-saudi-arabia-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 15:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=262499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking arrived in Saudi Arabia today, where he will meet with senior officials from the Saudi and Republic of Yemen Governments.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Special Envoy Lenderking will discuss the growing consequences of the Houthi offensive on Marib, which is exacerbating the humanitarian crisis and triggering instability elsewhere in the country.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The Special Envoy will address the urgent need for efforts by the Republic of Yemen Government and Saudi Arabia to stabilize Yemen’s economy and to facilitate the timely import of fuel to northern Yemen, and the need for the Houthis to end their manipulation of fuel imports and prices inside of Yemen.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Finally, Special Envoy Lenderking will meet with representatives from the international community and the UN Office of the Special Envoy for Yemen to discuss the importance of an inclusive peace process and a rapid appointment of a new UN Envoy.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Now is the time to stop the fighting and enable Yemenis to shape a more peaceful, prosperous future for their country.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">For any questions, please contact <a href="mailto:NEA-Press@state.gov">NEA-Press@state.gov</a> and follow us on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/StateDept_NEA">@StateDept_NEA</a>.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">U.S. Special Envoy for Yemen Tim Lenderking arrived in Saudi Arabia today, where he will meet with senior officials from the Saudi and Republic of Yemen Governments.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Special Envoy Lenderking will discuss the growing consequences of the Houthi offensive on Marib, which is exacerbating the humanitarian crisis and triggering instability elsewhere in the country.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The Special Envoy will address the urgent need for efforts by the Republic of Yemen Government and Saudi Arabia to stabilize Yemen’s economy and to facilitate the timely import of fuel to northern Yemen, and the need for the Houthis to end their manipulation of fuel imports and prices inside of Yemen.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Finally, Special Envoy Lenderking will meet with representatives from the international community and the UN Office of the Special Envoy for Yemen to discuss the importance of an inclusive peace process and a rapid appointment of a new UN Envoy.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Now is the time to stop the fighting and enable Yemenis to shape a more peaceful, prosperous future for their country.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">For any questions, please contact <a href="mailto:NEA-Press@state.gov">NEA-Press@state.gov</a> and follow us on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/StateDept_NEA">@StateDept_NEA</a>.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States and India: Deepening our Strategic Partnership</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-united-states-and-india-deepening-our-strategic-partnership/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 14:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=262443</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left"><em>“The United States and India are working together on so many of the most important challenges of our time and ones that are having a profound impact on the lives of our citizens. The partnership between the United States and India is vital, it’s strong, and it’s increasingly productive.”</em></p>
<p style="text-align: right;" align="left">– <em>Secretary Antony J. Blinken, May 28, 2021</em></p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to New Delhi, India, July 27-28 to reaffirm the United States’ commitment to strengthening our partnership and underscore cooperation on our shared priorities. Secretary Blinken<wbr /> will meet with Prime Minister Narendra Modi and External Affairs Minister Dr. S. Jaishankar to discuss a wide range of issues, including continued cooperation on COVID-19 response efforts, Indo-Pacific <wbr />engagement, shared regional security interests, shared democratic values, and addressing the climate crisis.</p>
<p align="left"><strong>Deepening the U.S.-India Partnership</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States and India have a strong strategic partnership founded on shared values and a commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific region. The United States supports India’s emergence as a leading global power and vital partner in efforts to ensure that the Indo-Pacific is a region of peace, stability, and growing prosperity and economic inclusion.</li>
<li>The United States and India cooperate on a wide range of diplomatic, economic and security issues, including defense, non-proliferation, regional cooperation in the Indo-Pacific, shared democratic values, counterterrorism, climate change, health, energy, trade and investment, peacekeeping, the environment, education, science and technology, agriculture, space, and oceans.</li>
<li>In 2008, the United States and India signed an agreement, making India a full partner in the governance and funding of the Fulbright Program. An increase in exchanges under the agreement has allowed for the development of new and innovative programs, and India now has the largest Fulbright Scholar (faculty) program in the world. In FY 2019, this funding provided opportunities for 61 U.S. Scholars, 66 Indian Scholars, 80 U.S. students, including 29 English Teaching Assistants, and 55 Indian students, including 13 Foreign Language Teaching Assistants.</li>
<li>The United States and India are working to expand cooperation in international organizations. The United States welcomed India joining the UN Security Council in January 2021 for a two-year term.</li>
<li>In October 2020, India hosted the third 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue, and the United States looks forward to the next 2+2 later this year.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The Indo-Pacific Front and Center</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>India is a leading global power and a key U.S. partner in the Indo-Pacific and beyond. At the inaugural Quad Leaders’ Summit in March, President Biden and Prime Minister Modi joined their Japanese and Australian counterparts in pledging to respond to the economic and health impacts of COVID-19, combat the climate crisis, and address shared challenges, including in cyber-space, critical technologies, counterterrorism, quality infrastructure investment, humanitarian assistance and disaster relief, and maritime security.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Deterring Our Adversaries and Defending Our Interests</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>U.S.-India defense cooperation is reaching new heights, including through information sharing, liaison officers, increasingly complex exercises like Malabar, and defense enabling agreements, such as the secure communications agreement COMCASA. As of 2020, the United States has authorized over $20 billion in defense sales to India.</li>
<li>Through the U.S.-India Defense Technology and Trade Initiative, the United States and India work together on co-production and co-development of defense equipment.</li>
<li>The United States and India are also closely coordinating on regional security issues, such as Afghanistan.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Combating the Covid-19 Pandemic</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States stands with the people of India as they continue to battle the COVID-19 pandemic. The United States has contributed more than $200 million for India&#8217;s COVID-19 relief and response efforts since the pandemic began, including more than $50 million in <a class="external-link" href="https://www.usaid.gov/news-information/press-releases/may-6-2021-united-states-delivers-six-planes-india-emergency-medical-supplies" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">emergency supplies</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> and training for more than 218,000 frontline health workers on infection prevention and control, benefitting more than 43 million Indians.</li>
<li>Earlier this year, the United States and India initiated renewal of a memorandum of understanding to collaborate through an International Center of Excellence in Research focused on infectious diseases, including COVID-19 and other emerging threats.</li>
<li>The United States and India are partnering to strengthen the global response to COVID-19, on issues ranging from addressing infectious disease outbreaks to strengthening health systems to securing global supply chains.</li>
<li>U.S. pharmaceutical companies have coordinated with Indian companies since the beginning of the pandemic. This cooperation includes voluntary licensing and technology transfer agreements to increase global manufacturing capacity for COVID-19 vaccines, therapies, and conducting clinical trials.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Tackling the Climate Crisis</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="letter-spacing: -0.2px;">U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry traveled to India in April of this year and met with Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi. They discussed the importance of two of the world’s largest economies leading together to address the climate crisis.</span></li>
<li>At the Leaders’ Summit on Climate in April, President Biden and Prime Minister Modi launched the U.S.-India Climate and Clean Energy Agenda 2030 Partnership to strengthen cooperation on strong actions in the current decade to meet the goals of the Paris Agreement and to help each country achieve its respective climate and clean energy goals.</li>
<li>Under the new Agenda 2030 Partnership, the United States and India look forward to launching the new Climate Action and Finance Mobilization Dialogue, led by Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry, and relaunching the Strategic Clean Energy Partnership, led by Secretary of Energy Jennifer Granholm, later this year.</li>
<li>The United States looks forward to further cooperation with India on tackling the climate crisis and raising global ambition ahead of the 26th UN Climate Change Conference of the Parties (COP26) in Glasgow, UK, in November.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p align="left"><em>“The United States and India are working together on so many of the most important challenges of our time and ones that are having a profound impact on the lives of our citizens. The partnership between the United States and India is vital, it’s strong, and it’s increasingly productive.”</em></p>
<p style="text-align: right;" align="left">– <em>Secretary Antony J. Blinken, May 28, 2021</em></p>
<p align="left">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to New Delhi, India, July 27-28 to reaffirm the United States’ commitment to strengthening our partnership and underscore cooperation on our shared priorities. Secretary Blinken<wbr /> will meet with Prime Minister Narendra Modi and External Affairs Minister Dr. S. Jaishankar to discuss a wide range of issues, including continued cooperation on COVID-19 response efforts, Indo-Pacific <wbr />engagement, shared regional security interests, shared democratic values, and addressing the climate crisis.</p>
<p align="left"><strong>Deepening the U.S.-India Partnership</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States and India have a strong strategic partnership founded on shared values and a commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific region. The United States supports India’s emergence as a leading global power and vital partner in efforts to ensure that the Indo-Pacific is a region of peace, stability, and growing prosperity and economic inclusion.</li>
<li>The United States and India cooperate on a wide range of diplomatic, economic and security issues, including defense, non-proliferation, regional cooperation in the Indo-Pacific, shared democratic values, counterterrorism, climate change, health, energy, trade and investment, peacekeeping, the environment, education, science and technology, agriculture, space, and oceans.</li>
<li>In 2008, the United States and India signed an agreement, making India a full partner in the governance and funding of the Fulbright Program. An increase in exchanges under the agreement has allowed for the development of new and innovative programs, and India now has the largest Fulbright Scholar (faculty) program in the world. In FY 2019, this funding provided opportunities for 61 U.S. Scholars, 66 Indian Scholars, 80 U.S. students, including 29 English Teaching Assistants, and 55 Indian students, including 13 Foreign Language Teaching Assistants.</li>
<li>The United States and India are working to expand cooperation in international organizations. The United States welcomed India joining the UN Security Council in January 2021 for a two-year term.</li>
<li>In October 2020, India hosted the third 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue, and the United States looks forward to the next 2+2 later this year.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The Indo-Pacific Front and Center</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>India is a leading global power and a key U.S. partner in the Indo-Pacific and beyond. At the inaugural Quad Leaders’ Summit in March, President Biden and Prime Minister Modi joined their Japanese and Australian counterparts in pledging to respond to the economic and health impacts of COVID-19, combat the climate crisis, and address shared challenges, including in cyber-space, critical technologies, counterterrorism, quality infrastructure investment, humanitarian assistance and disaster relief, and maritime security.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Deterring Our Adversaries and Defending Our Interests</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>U.S.-India defense cooperation is reaching new heights, including through information sharing, liaison officers, increasingly complex exercises like Malabar, and defense enabling agreements, such as the secure communications agreement COMCASA. As of 2020, the United States has authorized over $20 billion in defense sales to India.</li>
<li>Through the U.S.-India Defense Technology and Trade Initiative, the United States and India work together on co-production and co-development of defense equipment.</li>
<li>The United States and India are also closely coordinating on regional security issues, such as Afghanistan.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Combating the Covid-19 Pandemic</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States stands with the people of India as they continue to battle the COVID-19 pandemic. The United States has contributed more than $200 million for India&#8217;s COVID-19 relief and response efforts since the pandemic began, including more than $50 million in <a class="external-link" href="https://www.usaid.gov/news-information/press-releases/may-6-2021-united-states-delivers-six-planes-india-emergency-medical-supplies" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">emergency supplies</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a> and training for more than 218,000 frontline health workers on infection prevention and control, benefitting more than 43 million Indians.</li>
<li>Earlier this year, the United States and India initiated renewal of a memorandum of understanding to collaborate through an International Center of Excellence in Research focused on infectious diseases, including COVID-19 and other emerging threats.</li>
<li>The United States and India are partnering to strengthen the global response to COVID-19, on issues ranging from addressing infectious disease outbreaks to strengthening health systems to securing global supply chains.</li>
<li>U.S. pharmaceutical companies have coordinated with Indian companies since the beginning of the pandemic. This cooperation includes voluntary licensing and technology transfer agreements to increase global manufacturing capacity for COVID-19 vaccines, therapies, and conducting clinical trials.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Tackling the Climate Crisis</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="letter-spacing: -0.2px;">U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry traveled to India in April of this year and met with Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi. They discussed the importance of two of the world’s largest economies leading together to address the climate crisis.</span></li>
<li>At the Leaders’ Summit on Climate in April, President Biden and Prime Minister Modi launched the U.S.-India Climate and Clean Energy Agenda 2030 Partnership to strengthen cooperation on strong actions in the current decade to meet the goals of the Paris Agreement and to help each country achieve its respective climate and clean energy goals.</li>
<li>Under the new Agenda 2030 Partnership, the United States and India look forward to launching the new Climate Action and Finance Mobilization Dialogue, led by Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry, and relaunching the Strategic Clean Energy Partnership, led by Secretary of Energy Jennifer Granholm, later this year.</li>
<li>The United States looks forward to further cooperation with India on tackling the climate crisis and raising global ambition ahead of the 26th UN Climate Change Conference of the Parties (COP26) in Glasgow, UK, in November.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Nepali Prime Minister Deuba</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-nepali-prime-minister-deuba/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 14:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=262444</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Nepali Prime Minister Sher Bahadur Deuba today.  Secretary Blinken and Prime Minister Deuba emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Nepal partnership and discussed the recent U.S. donation of 1.5 million vaccines and other COVID-19 assistance to Nepal.  The Secretary and the Prime Minister also discussed our cooperation to combat the effects of climate change.</span></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Nepali Prime Minister Sher Bahadur Deuba today.  Secretary Blinken and Prime Minister Deuba emphasized the importance of the U.S.-Nepal partnership and discussed the recent U.S. donation of 1.5 million vaccines and other COVID-19 assistance to Nepal.  The Secretary and the Prime Minister also discussed our cooperation to combat the effects of climate change.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Meeting with Omani Deputy Foreign Minister Al Harthy</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-meeting-with-omani-deputy-foreign-minister-al-harthy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 12:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=262424</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today in Muscat with Deputy Foreign Minister Sheikh Khalifa Al Harthy to discuss advancing peace and security in the region and our shared commitment to bolstering the U.S.- Oman bilateral relationship, including advancing new opportunities for trade and investment. The Deputy Secretary also thanked the Deputy Foreign Minister for Oman’s role in mediating peace in the region and underscored the importance of an immediate, comprehensive ceasefire to help bring the war in Yemen to an end.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p align="left">Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman met today in Muscat with Deputy Foreign Minister Sheikh Khalifa Al Harthy to discuss advancing peace and security in the region and our shared commitment to bolstering the U.S.- Oman bilateral relationship, including advancing new opportunities for trade and investment. The Deputy Secretary also thanked the Deputy Foreign Minister for Oman’s role in mediating peace in the region and underscored the importance of an immediate, comprehensive ceasefire to help bring the war in Yemen to an end.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Peru President-Elect Castillo</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-peru-president-elect-castillo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=262360</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Peruvian President-Elect Pedro Castillo and offered congratulations to the people of Peru for an electoral process indicative of a strong and vibrant democracy.  He thanked Peru for its support in addressing the Venezuela crisis and expressed his hope that Peru would continue to play a constructive role in addressing the deteriorating situations in Cuba and Nicaragua.  Secretary Blinken offered continued U.S. support for pandemic recovery and highlighted our donation of two million vaccine doses, as well as hospitals, ventilators, cold storage units, and protective equipment.  He emphasized the United States remains a steadfast economic partner to Peru and reinforced our shared commitment to promoting inclusive economic prosperity, protecting the environment, addressing the climate crisis, improving public health, and ensuring educational opportunities for all.  He applauded Peru’s efforts to combat illegal logging, illegal mining, narcotics smuggling, human trafficking, and corruption.  Secretary Blinken celebrated the enduring partnership and long history of close cooperation between our two nations during Peru’s bicentennial.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Peruvian President-Elect Pedro Castillo and offered congratulations to the people of Peru for an electoral process indicative of a strong and vibrant democracy.  He thanked Peru for its support in addressing the Venezuela crisis and expressed his hope that Peru would continue to play a constructive role in addressing the deteriorating situations in Cuba and Nicaragua.  Secretary Blinken offered continued U.S. support for pandemic recovery and highlighted our donation of two million vaccine doses, as well as hospitals, ventilators, cold storage units, and protective equipment.  He emphasized the United States remains a steadfast economic partner to Peru and reinforced our shared commitment to promoting inclusive economic prosperity, protecting the environment, addressing the climate crisis, improving public health, and ensuring educational opportunities for all.  He applauded Peru’s efforts to combat illegal logging, illegal mining, narcotics smuggling, human trafficking, and corruption.  Secretary Blinken celebrated the enduring partnership and long history of close cooperation between our two nations during Peru’s bicentennial.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
