<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.state.gov/rss-feed/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 17:29:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cropped-dos_seal-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases &#8211; United States Department of State</title>
	<link>https://www.state.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>United States Pledges $600 Million to Combat Global Environmental Threats</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/united-states-pledges-600-million-to-combat-global-environmental-threats/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 17:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is being released jointly by the U.S. Department of State and the U.S. Department of the Treasury.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>On April 8, the United States pledged $600.8 million over the next four years to support the eighth replenishment of the Global Environment Facility (GEF-8).  This is the United States’ largest GEF pledge ever.  This pledge aligns with continuing U.S. priorities and supports the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to addressing climate change, conserving global carbon sinks and other critical ecosystems, and restoring the health of our ocean.  The United States joined 28 other donors in collectively pledging more than $5 billion to support GEF-8, a nearly 30 percent increase over GEF-7.</p>
<p>The U.S. pledge will help protect tropical rainforests and other critical carbon sinks; address ocean plastics pollution; combat wildlife trafficking and illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing; and reduce hazardous transboundary pollutants such as PCBs and mercury that can affect Americans’ health.  In its Fiscal Year 2023 Budget, the Administration has requested $150.2 million for the GEF, as the first of four planned installments for the U.S. contribution to GEF-8.</p>
<p>The GEF is one of the world’s largest dedicated funders of projects and programs to improve the global environment.  The United States supported the establishment of the GEF in 1991 and has contributed to all seven replenishments.  Since its launch in 1991, the GEF has provided nearly $22 billion in grants and mobilized another $119 billion in co-financing to safeguard the global environment.  The GEF is the world’s primary multilateral source of biodiversity finance and is the only multilateral environmental fund whose mandate is to achieve global environmental benefits across a diverse set of focal areas that also includes chemicals and waste, climate change mitigation, land degradation (including desertification and deforestation), and international waters.  The GEF Partnership spans 184 member governments, 18 implementing agencies, more than 500 civil society organizations, international bodies and funds, and businesses from every major sector.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p><em>The following is being released jointly by the U.S. Department of State and the U.S. Department of the Treasury.</em></p>
<p><em>Begin text:</em></p>
<p>On April 8, the United States pledged $600.8 million over the next four years to support the eighth replenishment of the Global Environment Facility (GEF-8).  This is the United States’ largest GEF pledge ever.  This pledge aligns with continuing U.S. priorities and supports the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to addressing climate change, conserving global carbon sinks and other critical ecosystems, and restoring the health of our ocean.  The United States joined 28 other donors in collectively pledging more than $5 billion to support GEF-8, a nearly 30 percent increase over GEF-7.</p>
<p>The U.S. pledge will help protect tropical rainforests and other critical carbon sinks; address ocean plastics pollution; combat wildlife trafficking and illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing; and reduce hazardous transboundary pollutants such as PCBs and mercury that can affect Americans’ health.  In its Fiscal Year 2023 Budget, the Administration has requested $150.2 million for the GEF, as the first of four planned installments for the U.S. contribution to GEF-8.</p>
<p>The GEF is one of the world’s largest dedicated funders of projects and programs to improve the global environment.  The United States supported the establishment of the GEF in 1991 and has contributed to all seven replenishments.  Since its launch in 1991, the GEF has provided nearly $22 billion in grants and mobilized another $119 billion in co-financing to safeguard the global environment.  The GEF is the world’s primary multilateral source of biodiversity finance and is the only multilateral environmental fund whose mandate is to achieve global environmental benefits across a diverse set of focal areas that also includes chemicals and waste, climate change mitigation, land degradation (including desertification and deforestation), and international waters.  The GEF Partnership spans 184 member governments, 18 implementing agencies, more than 500 civil society organizations, international bodies and funds, and businesses from every major sector.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman to Participate in a Conversation Hosted by Friends of Europe</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-sherman-to-participate-in-a-conversation-hosted-by-friends-of-europe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 15:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335388</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman will participate in a conversation hosted by the Friends of Europe at 9:00 a.m. EDT on Thursday, April 21, 2022, in Brussels, Belgium.  Deputy Secretary Sherman will discuss U.S.-EU cooperation on a range of topics, including our shared approach to the People’s Republic of China, our cooperation in the Indo-Pacific region, assistance to Ukraine, and sanctions on Russia.</p>
<p>This event will be livestreamed at <a class="external-link" href="https://www.friendsofeurope.org/events/in-conversation-with-wendy-sherman/#about" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://www.friendsofeurope.org/events/in-conversation-with-wendy-sherman/#about</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p>For further information, please contact the Public Affairs Office of the U.S. Mission to the EU at <a href="mailto:useupressteam@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">useupressteam@state.gov</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary Sherman will participate in a conversation hosted by the Friends of Europe at 9:00 a.m. EDT on Thursday, April 21, 2022, in Brussels, Belgium.  Deputy Secretary Sherman will discuss U.S.-EU cooperation on a range of topics, including our shared approach to the People’s Republic of China, our cooperation in the Indo-Pacific region, assistance to Ukraine, and sanctions on Russia.</p>
<p>This event will be livestreamed at <a class="external-link" href="https://www.friendsofeurope.org/events/in-conversation-with-wendy-sherman/#about" target="_BLANK" rel="noopener"><span class="external-link-title">https://www.friendsofeurope.org/events/in-conversation-with-wendy-sherman/#about</span><span class="icon-external"> </span></a></p>
<p>For further information, please contact the Public Affairs Office of the U.S. Mission to the EU at <a href="mailto:useupressteam@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">useupressteam@state.gov</a></p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Jordanian Foreign Minister Safadi</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-jordanian-foreign-minister-safadi-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 13:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Jordanian Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Ayman Safadi yesterday regarding increased tensions and recent violence in Israel and the West Bank, including at Jerusalem’s Haram al-Sharif/Temple Mount. The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed the importance of Israelis and Palestinians working to end the cycle of violence by refraining from actions and rhetoric that further escalate tensions. Secretary Blinken emphasized the importance of upholding the historic status quo at the Haram al-Sharif/Temple Mount, and appreciation for the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan’s special role as custodian of Muslim holy places in Jerusalem. The Secretary reaffirmed the U.S. commitment to stability in the region and support for a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The following is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke with Jordanian Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Ayman Safadi yesterday regarding increased tensions and recent violence in Israel and the West Bank, including at Jerusalem’s Haram al-Sharif/Temple Mount. The Secretary and Foreign Minister discussed the importance of Israelis and Palestinians working to end the cycle of violence by refraining from actions and rhetoric that further escalate tensions. Secretary Blinken emphasized the importance of upholding the historic status quo at the Haram al-Sharif/Temple Mount, and appreciation for the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan’s special role as custodian of Muslim holy places in Jerusalem. The Secretary reaffirmed the U.S. commitment to stability in the region and support for a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The U.S. Government and Transparency International Announce 20th Edition of the International Anti-Corruption Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/the-u-s-government-and-transparency-international-announce-20th-edition-of-the-international-anti-corruption-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 13:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Government, coordinated by the Department of State’s Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs (INL), is partnering with Transparency International (TI) to support the 20th edition of the International Anti-Corruption Conference (IACC) to be held in Washington, DC, December 6-10, 2022, with a theme of “Uprooting Corruption: Defending Democratic Values.”</p>
<p>Corruption undermines democracy and respect for human rights, impedes investment, stifles economic growth, hampers government services, and allows criminality to flourish.  Responding to this transnational threat, President Biden established fighting corruption as a core U.S. national security interest, releasing the first-ever U.S. Strategy on Countering Corruption, and elevating the fight against corruption as a pillar of the Summit for Democracy.  His Administration is expanding and leveraging diplomatic and foreign assistance tools to advance these efforts.</p>
<p>The U.S. Government’s partnerships with international organizations, governments, civil society, and the private sector have been critical to anti-corruption efforts around the world.  Through the IACC, the U.S. Government and TI will bring together over 10,000 people from 180 countries to continue building momentum for landmark anti-corruption initiatives.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact <a href="mailto:INL-PAPD@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">INL-PAPD@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The U.S. Government, coordinated by the Department of State’s Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs (INL), is partnering with Transparency International (TI) to support the 20th edition of the International Anti-Corruption Conference (IACC) to be held in Washington, DC, December 6-10, 2022, with a theme of “Uprooting Corruption: Defending Democratic Values.”</p>
<p>Corruption undermines democracy and respect for human rights, impedes investment, stifles economic growth, hampers government services, and allows criminality to flourish.  Responding to this transnational threat, President Biden established fighting corruption as a core U.S. national security interest, releasing the first-ever U.S. Strategy on Countering Corruption, and elevating the fight against corruption as a pillar of the Summit for Democracy.  His Administration is expanding and leveraging diplomatic and foreign assistance tools to advance these efforts.</p>
<p>The U.S. Government’s partnerships with international organizations, governments, civil society, and the private sector have been critical to anti-corruption efforts around the world.  Through the IACC, the U.S. Government and TI will bring together over 10,000 people from 180 countries to continue building momentum for landmark anti-corruption initiatives.</p>
<p>For more information, please contact <a href="mailto:INL-PAPD@state.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">INL-PAPD@state.gov</a>.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Trip to Panama:  Commitments to a Regional Approach to Hemispheric Migration and to Anti-Corruption Efforts</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-trip-to-panama-commitments-to-a-regional-approach-to-hemispheric-migration-and-to-anti-corruption-efforts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 12:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335332</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Panama City, Panama April 19-20 to co-lead a Ministerial Conference on Migration and Protection and meet with President Laurentino Cortizo Cohen and Foreign Minister Erika Mouynes, as well as other leaders from across the hemisphere.  The U.S. delegation will deepen our ongoing efforts to improve bilateral and regional cooperation on irregular migration and forced displacement, and lay the groundwork for a successful Summit of the Americas in June.  The Secretary will also speak with civil society leaders about the challenge of corruption in the hemisphere.</p>
<p><b>A Deep and Lasting Relationship</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Panama remains a highly valued partner to the United States. Our governments work side-by-side to advance common goals for our peoples and for the region.  This includes collaboration on regional security, strengthening democratic institutions, and advancing inclusive economic growth, especially in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic.  The United States donated more than 500,000 safe and effective vaccine doses as a contribution to Panama’s efforts.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Regional Cooperation</b></p>
<ul>
<li>We thank Panama for hosting this ministerial and welcome Panama’s important leadership role in the region, including as a member of the Alliance for Development in Democracy, a regional alliance between Costa Rica, the Dominican Republic, and Panama.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>At the April 19-20 Ministerial on Migration and Protection the United States will join with ministers from twenty Western Hemisphere countries in working toward a collaborative and humane approach to managing migration and protection through the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Through this ministerial, we join nations across the hemisphere in support of: sustainable integration for refugees and other migrants and in support of the communities that host them; increased access to international protection for those in need; expanded legal pathways; and support for humane migration management.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The Panama Ministerial builds towards the Ninth Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles, California on June 6-10, 2022. The Summit is the only hemisphere-wide meeting of the leaders of North, South, Central America and the Caribbean, and this is the first time the United States has served as host since the inaugural summit in Miami in 1994.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The summit’s theme, “Building a Sustainable, Resilient, and Equitable Future,” responds to our hemisphere’s most pressing issues, including the COVID-19 pandemic and the cracks it exposed in health, economic, educational, and social systems; threats to democracy; the climate crisis; and a lack of equitable access to economic, social, and political opportunities.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Bilateral Partnership</b></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States is Panama&#8217;s top economic partner. We are the largest direct investor in Panama. We have more than 13 billion dollars in bilateral trade in goods and services and we are the main beneficiary of the Panama Canal, with 72 percent of all transits through the Canal carrying goods to or from the United States. Exports of goods and services from Panama to the United States contribute to having more and better jobs here.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States supports Panama&#8217;s economic recovery and helps Panama attract more U.S. investment.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States is the largest humanitarian donor to international organizations in Panama, whose work complements the Government of Panama’s efforts to provide humanitarian assistance and protection to vulnerable migrants and refugees.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States donated over 500,000 Pfizer vaccines to Panama to support Panama&#8217;s response to COVID-19. We also provided over 18 million dollars in assistance and delivered more than 100 ventilators, 14 hospital tents, and 170,000 COVID-19 test kits, as well as hundreds of thousands of masks and other personal protective equipment.</li>
</ul>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken will travel to Panama City, Panama April 19-20 to co-lead a Ministerial Conference on Migration and Protection and meet with President Laurentino Cortizo Cohen and Foreign Minister Erika Mouynes, as well as other leaders from across the hemisphere.  The U.S. delegation will deepen our ongoing efforts to improve bilateral and regional cooperation on irregular migration and forced displacement, and lay the groundwork for a successful Summit of the Americas in June.  The Secretary will also speak with civil society leaders about the challenge of corruption in the hemisphere.</p>
<p><b>A Deep and Lasting Relationship</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Panama remains a highly valued partner to the United States. Our governments work side-by-side to advance common goals for our peoples and for the region.  This includes collaboration on regional security, strengthening democratic institutions, and advancing inclusive economic growth, especially in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic.  The United States donated more than 500,000 safe and effective vaccine doses as a contribution to Panama’s efforts.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Regional Cooperation</b></p>
<ul>
<li>We thank Panama for hosting this ministerial and welcome Panama’s important leadership role in the region, including as a member of the Alliance for Development in Democracy, a regional alliance between Costa Rica, the Dominican Republic, and Panama.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>At the April 19-20 Ministerial on Migration and Protection the United States will join with ministers from twenty Western Hemisphere countries in working toward a collaborative and humane approach to managing migration and protection through the region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Through this ministerial, we join nations across the hemisphere in support of: sustainable integration for refugees and other migrants and in support of the communities that host them; increased access to international protection for those in need; expanded legal pathways; and support for humane migration management.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The Panama Ministerial builds towards the Ninth Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles, California on June 6-10, 2022. The Summit is the only hemisphere-wide meeting of the leaders of North, South, Central America and the Caribbean, and this is the first time the United States has served as host since the inaugural summit in Miami in 1994.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The summit’s theme, “Building a Sustainable, Resilient, and Equitable Future,” responds to our hemisphere’s most pressing issues, including the COVID-19 pandemic and the cracks it exposed in health, economic, educational, and social systems; threats to democracy; the climate crisis; and a lack of equitable access to economic, social, and political opportunities.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Bilateral Partnership</b></p>
<ul>
<li>The United States is Panama&#8217;s top economic partner. We are the largest direct investor in Panama. We have more than 13 billion dollars in bilateral trade in goods and services and we are the main beneficiary of the Panama Canal, with 72 percent of all transits through the Canal carrying goods to or from the United States. Exports of goods and services from Panama to the United States contribute to having more and better jobs here.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States supports Panama&#8217;s economic recovery and helps Panama attract more U.S. investment.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States is the largest humanitarian donor to international organizations in Panama, whose work complements the Government of Panama’s efforts to provide humanitarian assistance and protection to vulnerable migrants and refugees.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The United States donated over 500,000 Pfizer vaccines to Panama to support Panama&#8217;s response to COVID-19. We also provided over 18 million dollars in assistance and delivered more than 100 ventilators, 14 hospital tents, and 170,000 COVID-19 test kits, as well as hundreds of thousands of masks and other personal protective equipment.</li>
</ul>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Meeting with Moldovan Foreign Minister Popescu</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-meeting-with-moldovan-foreign-minister-popescu/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 23:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Moldovan Minister of Foreign Affairs and European Integration Nicu Popescu today in Washington, D.C.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Popescu commended the relaunch of the U.S.-Moldova Strategic Dialogue to further strengthen bilateral relations and continue our close cooperation to support Moldova’s reform agenda.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister discussed Moldova’s humanitarian response to Russia’s brutal war against Ukraine.  Secretary Blinken emphasized continued U.S. support to assist Moldova in addressing the economic impacts of the crisis and advancing democratic reforms.  The parties also discussed ongoing efforts to strengthen Moldova’s energy security.  Since February 24, the United States has committed more than $30 million in humanitarian assistance to support the humanitarian response in Moldova and $100 million in development assistance to strengthen its long-term democratic and economic resiliency.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken met with Moldovan Minister of Foreign Affairs and European Integration Nicu Popescu today in Washington, D.C.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Popescu commended the relaunch of the U.S.-Moldova Strategic Dialogue to further strengthen bilateral relations and continue our close cooperation to support Moldova’s reform agenda.  The Secretary and the Foreign Minister discussed Moldova’s humanitarian response to Russia’s brutal war against Ukraine.  Secretary Blinken emphasized continued U.S. support to assist Moldova in addressing the economic impacts of the crisis and advancing democratic reforms.  The parties also discussed ongoing efforts to strengthen Moldova’s energy security.  Since February 24, the United States has committed more than $30 million in humanitarian assistance to support the humanitarian response in Moldova and $100 million in development assistance to strengthen its long-term democratic and economic resiliency.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Antony J. Blinken and Moldovan Foreign Minister Nicu Popescu Before Their Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-and-moldovan-foreign-minister-nicu-popescu-before-their-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 23:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a pleasure to be able to receive Foreign Minister Popescu, to return some of the very warm hospitality that the foreign minister, the president, the prime minister showed me and our team when we were in Moldova just a couple of months ago.  And needless to say, this is an especially timely visit given the ongoing Russian aggression against Ukraine and the challenge that it poses to other countries in the region.</p>
<p>We in the United States strongly support Moldova’s independence, its sovereignty, its territorial integrity, and we continue to work very closely together in practical support of all of those things.  I have to say, Nicu, that the humanitarian response that you’ve provided to the Russian aggression in Ukraine is extraordinary, something like 400,000 refugees from Ukraine going to and through Moldova, about 100,000 or so will remain in Moldova.  And the generosity that Moldova is showing – the Moldovan people are showing – is really exceptional.  We have tried to be as helpful as we can be, including at the most recent conference that took place to help support the efforts that you’re undertaking, and we’ll continue to do that.</p>
<p>I’m very pleased much more broadly, though, that we are actually coming together as a result of our strategic dialogue.  We welcome you for that, glad that you had an opportunity to meet with other colleagues and for the dialogue to go forward so that our partnership could even strengthen, especially in these challenging times.  So welcome.  It’s great to have you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER POPESCU:  </strong>Thank you very much for this – for these kind words.  And this year the United States and Moldova have 30 years of diplomatic relations.  This is happening around with – in these first few months of the year.  And in this period, the United States has been a strong supporter of Moldovan independence, of Moldovan reforms, of Moldovan democracy.</p>
<p>And we are very grateful for this support, and this occasion of my visit to Washington with strategic dialogue that we are relaunching now is focused on key elements that would allow Moldova to continuously strengthen its resilience, its capacity to perform as a democratic state and society.  And today I met your colleagues, and we have been – we’ve structured our dialogue on three – on three pillars, if you want.  One working group was on energy and economic issues; the second working group on rule of law and anti-corruption; and the third group on political and security cooperation.  And all – on all of these three fronts, we think that our relation is excellent.  We have a very good interaction with your colleagues, and we’ve always felt U.S. support for Moldova.</p>
<p>Of course, we are in a very difficult region at a very difficult time.  And everyone in Europe is affected by this war.  Everyone in Europe feels less secure than just two months ago, but that is a new situation that is challenging also us in Moldova.  As you mentioned, we have had a huge wave of refugees.  Almost 4 percent of our population are refugees today.  Half of them are minors under 18 years old, so this represents 10 percent of our population of minors in Moldova.  With that dramatic numbers, we have been handling the situation reasonably well, but of course that affects us all and that will continue to affect our region and our society for a long time.</p>
<p>Of course, we from the first days and hours of the war, we have strongly condemned the Russian aggression of Ukraine – against Ukraine, and we’re looking forward for a peaceful resolution of this war which is completely unjustified and is making whole of Europe less secure.  And just this last thing that matters for us and for our government is to continue our strong focus on reforms, strong focus on delivering of the mandate given by our population, and this mandate presupposes a fight against corruption, economic progress, modernization of our country, because I think it’s important for us but it’s also important for everyone else in the region to show that democracy works in our part of the world and that the reforms pay off and that people can feel the results of these reform efforts.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Thomas Jefferson Room</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:  </strong>Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a pleasure to be able to receive Foreign Minister Popescu, to return some of the very warm hospitality that the foreign minister, the president, the prime minister showed me and our team when we were in Moldova just a couple of months ago.  And needless to say, this is an especially timely visit given the ongoing Russian aggression against Ukraine and the challenge that it poses to other countries in the region.</p>
<p>We in the United States strongly support Moldova’s independence, its sovereignty, its territorial integrity, and we continue to work very closely together in practical support of all of those things.  I have to say, Nicu, that the humanitarian response that you’ve provided to the Russian aggression in Ukraine is extraordinary, something like 400,000 refugees from Ukraine going to and through Moldova, about 100,000 or so will remain in Moldova.  And the generosity that Moldova is showing – the Moldovan people are showing – is really exceptional.  We have tried to be as helpful as we can be, including at the most recent conference that took place to help support the efforts that you’re undertaking, and we’ll continue to do that.</p>
<p>I’m very pleased much more broadly, though, that we are actually coming together as a result of our strategic dialogue.  We welcome you for that, glad that you had an opportunity to meet with other colleagues and for the dialogue to go forward so that our partnership could even strengthen, especially in these challenging times.  So welcome.  It’s great to have you.</p>
<p><strong>FOREIGN MINISTER POPESCU:  </strong>Thank you very much for this – for these kind words.  And this year the United States and Moldova have 30 years of diplomatic relations.  This is happening around with – in these first few months of the year.  And in this period, the United States has been a strong supporter of Moldovan independence, of Moldovan reforms, of Moldovan democracy.</p>
<p>And we are very grateful for this support, and this occasion of my visit to Washington with strategic dialogue that we are relaunching now is focused on key elements that would allow Moldova to continuously strengthen its resilience, its capacity to perform as a democratic state and society.  And today I met your colleagues, and we have been – we’ve structured our dialogue on three – on three pillars, if you want.  One working group was on energy and economic issues; the second working group on rule of law and anti-corruption; and the third group on political and security cooperation.  And all – on all of these three fronts, we think that our relation is excellent.  We have a very good interaction with your colleagues, and we’ve always felt U.S. support for Moldova.</p>
<p>Of course, we are in a very difficult region at a very difficult time.  And everyone in Europe is affected by this war.  Everyone in Europe feels less secure than just two months ago, but that is a new situation that is challenging also us in Moldova.  As you mentioned, we have had a huge wave of refugees.  Almost 4 percent of our population are refugees today.  Half of them are minors under 18 years old, so this represents 10 percent of our population of minors in Moldova.  With that dramatic numbers, we have been handling the situation reasonably well, but of course that affects us all and that will continue to affect our region and our society for a long time.</p>
<p>Of course, we from the first days and hours of the war, we have strongly condemned the Russian aggression of Ukraine – against Ukraine, and we’re looking forward for a peaceful resolution of this war which is completely unjustified and is making whole of Europe less secure.  And just this last thing that matters for us and for our government is to continue our strong focus on reforms, strong focus on delivering of the mandate given by our population, and this mandate presupposes a fight against corruption, economic progress, modernization of our country, because I think it’s important for us but it’s also important for everyone else in the region to show that democracy works in our part of the world and that the reforms pay off and that people can feel the results of these reform efforts.  Thank you.</p>
<p><strong>SECRETARY BLINKEN:</strong>  Thank you very much.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Acting Coordinator for the Global Engagement Center Bray’s Trip to Belgium</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/acting-coordinator-for-the-global-engagement-center-brays-trip-to-belgium/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 19:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335211</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Acting Coordinator for the Global Engagement Center Leah Bray will travel to Brussels, Belgium from April 19 to 22 as part of the U.S. delegation for the third High Level Meeting of the U.S.-EU Dialogue on China on April 21.  Acting Coordinator Bray will meet with NATO Allies and EU partners to discuss our continued close coordination on identifying and exposing the Kremlin’s use of disinformation in support of Putin’s war of choice against Ukraine and other State Department efforts to counter disinformation around the globe.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Acting Coordinator for the Global Engagement Center Leah Bray will travel to Brussels, Belgium from April 19 to 22 as part of the U.S. delegation for the third High Level Meeting of the U.S.-EU Dialogue on China on April 21.  Acting Coordinator Bray will meet with NATO Allies and EU partners to discuss our continued close coordination on identifying and exposing the Kremlin’s use of disinformation in support of Putin’s war of choice against Ukraine and other State Department efforts to counter disinformation around the globe.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deputy Secretary Sherman’s Travel to Belgium</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/deputy-secretary-shermans-travel-to-belgium/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 19:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335207</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman will travel to Brussels, Belgium from April 19 to 22 to lead the U.S. delegation for the third High Level Meeting of the U.S.-EU Dialogue on China on April 21 and the U.S.-EU Consultations on the Indo-Pacific on April 22.  On April 21, the Deputy Secretary will give remarks and participate in a moderated discussion at an event hosted by the Friends of Europe think tank about U.S.-European relations and our close partnership and collaboration on a wide range of shared challenges.  The Deputy Secretary will also meet with NATO Allies and EU partners to discuss our continued close coordination on Putin’s war of choice against Ukraine and other global issues.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman will travel to Brussels, Belgium from April 19 to 22 to lead the U.S. delegation for the third High Level Meeting of the U.S.-EU Dialogue on China on April 21 and the U.S.-EU Consultations on the Indo-Pacific on April 22.  On April 21, the Deputy Secretary will give remarks and participate in a moderated discussion at an event hosted by the Friends of Europe think tank about U.S.-European relations and our close partnership and collaboration on a wide range of shared challenges.  The Deputy Secretary will also meet with NATO Allies and EU partners to discuss our continued close coordination on Putin’s war of choice against Ukraine and other global issues.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secretary Blinken’s Call with Romanian Foreign Minister Aurescu</title>
		<link>https://www.state.gov/secretary-blinkens-call-with-romanian-foreign-minister-aurescu-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Office of the Spokesperson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 19:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.state.gov/?page_id=335204</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Romanian Foreign Minister Bogdan Aurescu.  They underscored the importance of Transatlantic unity in the face of the Kremlin’s brutal war against Ukraine.  The Secretary emphasized the need for NATO Allies to continue to work tirelessly to support Ukraine’s efforts to defend against Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified aggression.  The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Romania’s tremendous welcoming of nearly 700,000 refugees from Ukraine.  Both reaffirmed our steadfast support for the Ukrainian people and their historic fight for freedom, democracy, and the ability to chart their own course.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Aurescu highlighted the importance of our bilateral relationship as signified by the 25th anniversary of the United States-Romania Strategic Partnership.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Office of the Spokesperson</p>
<p>The below is attributable to Spokesperson Ned Price:</p>
<p>Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken spoke today with Romanian Foreign Minister Bogdan Aurescu.  They underscored the importance of Transatlantic unity in the face of the Kremlin’s brutal war against Ukraine.  The Secretary emphasized the need for NATO Allies to continue to work tirelessly to support Ukraine’s efforts to defend against Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified aggression.  The Secretary thanked the Foreign Minister for Romania’s tremendous welcoming of nearly 700,000 refugees from Ukraine.  Both reaffirmed our steadfast support for the Ukrainian people and their historic fight for freedom, democracy, and the ability to chart their own course.  Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Aurescu highlighted the importance of our bilateral relationship as signified by the 25th anniversary of the United States-Romania Strategic Partnership.</p>
<p><input type="hidden" data-filter="111000000100" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
